# Transcript
ID: 7cc9c8fb-ea36-4d87-a422-f686c6871f29
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4229105823382667159/-6147488093135834579/s93290-US-3597s-1710230436.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz choose their picks for The Vergecast Streaming Draft of 2024 in front of a live audience at SXSW.
Watch video version with a scoreboard on YouTube
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (3 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Learn how to unleash the potential of your team@atlassian.com.
Speaker 1:  That's A-T-L-A-S-S-I-A
Speaker 1:  n.com. Atlassian,
Speaker 3:  Hello And Welcome to the Bcast, the flagship podcast of South by
Speaker 3:  Southwest.
Speaker 4:  Suck it. It's true. Other South by Southwest podcast. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We're the only one. Yeah. You
Speaker 3:  Just gotta take it. Yeah, you just gotta take it and have it. I'm your friend.
Speaker 3:  NELI. That's Alex. Cranz.
Speaker 5:  Hey, I'm your friend who's very happy to be in Texas. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Woo hoo. Alex is from Texas. It's
Speaker 5:  True. That's why I wear my little cowboy boots today.
Speaker 3:  Where's your hat?
Speaker 5:  It's, it's up in Fort Worth. Where's
Speaker 3:  Your pickup truck?
Speaker 5:  Also in Fort Worth. Sorry.
Speaker 3:  Very good. David Pierce
Speaker 4:  Is here. I have no cowboy hats. I wore a cowboy hat one time and literally
Speaker 4:  a stranger told me I looked stupid in it. That's a true story.
Speaker 5:  I think you look cute in
Speaker 4:  Water. It was. They were like trying to be nice, but it was very much a like
Speaker 4:  honey, like that's not for you. Take it off kind of vibe. And I just, that
Speaker 4:  was the end of my cowboy hat face. It's fair.
Speaker 3:  That's fair. Were you wearing it in a cowboy hat? Appropriate situation?
Speaker 4:  Evidently not. Were you
Speaker 3:  Like at the bank? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I was in Austin. That's cowboy hat appropriate. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like, well, it depends on where the bank is. Yeah, that's
Speaker 5:  True. New York. No, no. Austin kind of Fort
Speaker 5:  Worth. Definitely. See,
Speaker 3:  You can see the Texas is coming out Alex now. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We're learning things here. This is good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. All right. So here's what we're gonna do for this live bird chat. By
Speaker 3:  the way, if you're listening to this in your car, we have an audience here
Speaker 3:  at South by Southwest makes noise audience. Woo.
Speaker 3:  Very good. I'm very excited for this
Speaker 3:  ridiculous gimmick that David has come up with. It's very, very complicated.
Speaker 3:  Explain what we're gonna do and we're gonna, we're gonna play this game that
Speaker 3:  David's come up with it at the end, we'll have some questions, but explain
Speaker 3:  the game.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So about a year ago, we were trying to figure out
Speaker 4:  how to talk about the Streaming world and like who's up, who's down, who's
Speaker 4:  winning, who's losing? So we did this Draft and we all basically picked a
Speaker 4:  bunch of Streaming services that are like hours for the year. And then everything
Speaker 4:  changed. Like immediately between recording that episode and putting out
Speaker 4:  that episode, the whole Streaming world changed. So now we're gonna do it
Speaker 4:  again. We're gonna go back. I've made it more complicated and it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be much more work for everybody and I'm the only one who can see everything.
Speaker 4:  So I'm gonna win for sure.
Speaker 3:  David's gonna cheat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he's cheating.
Speaker 4:  But we, we need help from all of you a few times throughout this first
Speaker 4:  telling us who is going to pick first. I'm gonna explain the rules of
Speaker 4:  the Draft in a second, but the first thing we need to do is I'm gonna recap
Speaker 4:  last year and then y'all are gonna decide who won last year's Draft
Speaker 4:  and thus gets to go first. Does that sound good? Okay. Cool. So last year,
Speaker 4:  NELI Patel ended up, we each ended up with five things. NELI had
Speaker 4:  TikTok, the Disney bundle, YouTube TV with Sunday
Speaker 4:  Ticket. I don't know why we gave you both of the This is outrageous. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I murdered, in retrospect, outrageous. There's
Speaker 3:  0% chance that anyone did better than me in this drive. Go ahead.
Speaker 4:  Apple Music. Yep. And his friend Bin's. Plex Server
Speaker 4:  AKA a choice
Speaker 5:  Right To jail. Like not even mine. Vi.
Speaker 3:  I didn't pick Alex's weirdo Plex Server.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Way better.
Speaker 4:  Alex. Cranz picked HBO Max Wwo. aw.
Speaker 4:  Paramount Plus slash Showtime. Aw channels
Speaker 4:  the app for watching the internet. It rules still exists. That one's good.
Speaker 4:  Criterion.
Speaker 5:  It still exists.
Speaker 4:  Apple One
Speaker 5:  Still
Speaker 3:  Exists. But that that, I don't know how you got away with that one because
Speaker 5:  You got Disney Bundle.
Speaker 3:  So you picked the bundle that includes iCloud and
Speaker 4:  Well, no, she got, it was basically music and Apple TV plus. Yeah. Is the,
Speaker 4:  that was the idea. And then Alex got a bonus pick because she spent the least
Speaker 4:  money. Yes. And she picked Xbox Cloud Gaming, which was a
Speaker 4:  choice.
Speaker 5:  It was a very entertaining pick. Like everything I would, I would, I would
Speaker 5:  pick all of those again in 2023.
Speaker 4:  I don't recommend that. My picks were YouTube, premium Peacock, Netflix,
Speaker 4:  discovery plus W, WAMP and Hulu with live tv.
Speaker 4:  So I won. I know I just said a lot of things all in a row.
Speaker 4:  Who thinks NELI won the Draft? Obviously
Speaker 3:  Nothing dead silent in this
Speaker 4:  Room. In your
Speaker 3:  Face. 'cause I talked too much shit.
Speaker 4:  Who thinks Alex won the Draft? Yes.
Speaker 5:  Come on. Cheer. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Are
Speaker 4:  You? I saw that. I
Speaker 5:  Brought Ringers.
Speaker 3:  Oh my God. He's def David's definitely.
Speaker 4:  Who thinks David won the Draft?
Speaker 4:  Katie Drummond clapped for me. So I won the Draft. Okay, so
Speaker 4:  the rules of this Draft Alex, you're gonna get to go first 'cause I think
Speaker 4:  you actually won the Draft. Thank you. Neela. I NELI can in last is what
Speaker 4:  Neil, I lost now. That's the most important part. NELI
Speaker 3:  Lost. It's brutal.
Speaker 4:  So for this year, the, the new addition to the Draft is we have categories
Speaker 4:  and you can't just pick anything. You have to fill the categories with
Speaker 4:  Draft picks. And we have six categories. Like I said, this is gonna be very
Speaker 4:  complicated. You both have this on your phone, so you can check it as you'd
Speaker 4:  like to. I like,
Speaker 5:  Can I have my phone out?
Speaker 4:  The categories are cheap, which means it has to have a tier that costs
Speaker 4:  under 10 bucks awards, which means the Streaming service has to have won
Speaker 4:  an Oscar. An Oscar, not something else. An Oscar. There's 4K,
Speaker 4:  which is pretty self-explanatory. It has to have seven in 4K, which rules
Speaker 4:  out a surprising number, but we can talk about that live, which means
Speaker 4:  it has to have some live stuff niche, which means it has to be something
Speaker 4:  very specific. And we can litigate that as we, this is
Speaker 3:  The Alex Cranz memorial category.
Speaker 4:  And then there's Wild Card, which is anything you want. Yeah. So we're not
Speaker 4:  going in category order, but there are going to be six rounds of the Draft.
Speaker 4:  And it is your job to fill out all six categories over the course of the
Speaker 4:  Draft. Oh my God. Sound good? Everybody feel good? Do this? Yeah. All right.
Speaker 4:  Alex Cranz. All right, you're up first. So you have to pick a service and
Speaker 4:  a category.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I'm gonna go 4K for my first one, and I'm gonna choose
Speaker 5:  Netflix. Okay. Because I've gotten really into KDRs. All right.
Speaker 5:  And they've got a lot on there. Strong and also other, it's Netflix.
Speaker 3:  So here's my proposed wild card edition to this Draft. Oh, good. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Every time anyone says a Streaming service, we have to rank how close to
Speaker 3:  death the Streaming service is on the go. 90 scale
Speaker 3:  of Doom Streaming, because
Speaker 4:  It turns out several of them last year were very close to
Speaker 3:  That. Very close to that. Yeah. So If, you are in our audience. you know
Speaker 3:  what the Go 90 scale of Doom Streaming services is Verizon,
Speaker 3:  which is a cell phone carrier, launched just important fact
Speaker 3:  along this road, launched a competitor YouTube called Go 90. This is
Speaker 3:  ages ago. The competitor featured the ability to turn your phone
Speaker 3:  sideways to watch videos and landscape, which Verizon tried to brand going
Speaker 3:  90. This is a real thing that happened from one of our nation's largest
Speaker 3:  companies. They also had features in it called like, join a Crew because
Speaker 3:  they thought the youth would like gang related terminology in their video
Speaker 3:  apps. This, this is all real. I'm not making this up. No, it qui
Speaker 3:  it quickly failed. Like I, I can't even tell you how fast it failed. It went
Speaker 3:  90. Yeah. Much like Quibi, another service that was
Speaker 3:  predicated upon turning your phone to watch videos and landscape. So we have
Speaker 3:  the Go 90 scale of Zoom Streaming services. So Zero is
Speaker 3:  Alive, 90 is dead. So Alex, where
Speaker 3:  is Netflix on the go? 90 scale of Doom Streaming services.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I'm about, to be really honest, I mainly picked it so neither of you
Speaker 5:  could pick it because I actually,
Speaker 3:  There's a lot of gamesmanship in this stream. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's all about beating them and feeling good about myself. So,
Speaker 5:  I actually think it's like a 40 because I a 40 because I think they have
Speaker 5:  a lot of programming problems and they need to improve it. Yeah. Like, I
Speaker 5:  like the K dramas, but I don't know if everyone else likes to
Speaker 4:  Wait. But Alex, I would remind you that the scale is not like the the
Speaker 4:  suckiness scale of its program. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 4:  But it, the scale of doesn't exist
Speaker 5:  In a year. Yeah. Okay. You
Speaker 3:  Don't have to say in a year.
Speaker 5:  Is it like, yeah. Does it exist?
Speaker 3:  How, how close to death in this moment? Right?
Speaker 5:  Hmm. I still think like 40. I kind wanna say 40.
Speaker 5:  I, I, I'm, I'm out there. Like, I think Netflix has some issues.
Speaker 3:  Feel, feel like it. This moment in time, it's appropriate to do our disclosures.
Speaker 3:  Where are you at? I produced a Netflix show.
Speaker 3:  Very good about The. future of You should watch it. Our company has a significant
Speaker 3:  investment in it from NBCUniversal, which is owned by Comcast.
Speaker 3:  They don't like us very much at all, given our coverage of Comcast.
Speaker 3:  We make other television shows for other services at our company.
Speaker 3:  And I personally watch television.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Quite a bit.
Speaker 4:  Alex does you but only illegally, so it's fine. Yeah, yeah, yeah. We don't
Speaker 4:  have to disclose that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We all have Apple products. It's a very important disclosure. Go ahead.
Speaker 4:  All right, I'll let you go next because I'm feeling magnanimous today.
Speaker 4:  What's your first thought?
Speaker 3:  Reverse serpentine order? Yeah. All right. I'm start, I'm starting where
Speaker 3:  I started last year. TikTok,
Speaker 4:  Which category?
Speaker 3:  Cheap, famous
Speaker 4:  Oscar winning
Speaker 3:  TikTok is notably cheap. Okay. It's funded entirely by subsidies
Speaker 3:  from the Chinese government and extremely crap
Speaker 3:  garbage that is sold on the TikTok
Speaker 4:  Shop. You, you did see the band bill that was passed. Oh
Speaker 3:  Yeah. TikTok currently is in the last s about, it's
Speaker 3:  TikTok is about it in 89. Okay. It is the clo it is the most
Speaker 3:  alive thing that has ever been that close to death in the history of stream
Speaker 3:  Streaming services. The
Speaker 4:  Most alive. Th Okay. Right. Sure. It is the whole go 90 scale
Speaker 4:  all at once. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. but it, it just, it is the full spectrum of go 90.
Speaker 3:  Have you ever seen those tiktoks where it's like, turn your phones slowly,
Speaker 3:  is the plane flies? It's that, it's that thing. Can I,
Speaker 3:  this fact about TikTok today is to me, very funny. The SE
Speaker 3:  Forge just had this reporting. So TikTok had a full screen
Speaker 3:  un killable splash screen load that said, call your representative
Speaker 3:  yesterday. And the only things you could do were
Speaker 3:  force quit the app or call your representative. You had no other choices
Speaker 3:  like If, you wanted to engage with TikTok. Those were your choices. So Capitol
Speaker 3:  Hill was flooded with calls from angry teens and there was one quote
Speaker 3:  from one congressional office. We, our offices are flooded with calls from
Speaker 3:  angry teens and boomers who spend all day on the app.
Speaker 3:  Really expands the definition of TikTok
Speaker 4:  There. I just love a bunch of teens being like, this is the first phone call
Speaker 4:  I've made in my life. Yeah. Give me TikTok.
Speaker 3:  I need this. So you would think that this would work. Other apps have
Speaker 3:  famously done this. Uber famously did this to get, you know, preferential
Speaker 3:  treatment in cities around the world during the uber time. This utterly
Speaker 3:  backfired on TikTok, congressional Republicans. The bill
Speaker 3:  sailed through to basically punish app stores that they carry TikTok. That's
Speaker 3:  how they're how're gonna do it. They're saying this is an, you know, the
Speaker 3:  stuff that congressional Republicans say China's bad. And in the accent,
Speaker 3:  and the quote they gave to se for was, we're worried the Chinese government
Speaker 3:  is programming our teenagers minds. And this is proof
Speaker 3:  because they got all the teens to call. They made
Speaker 4:  Phone calls.
Speaker 3:  I mean, it's very good.
Speaker 4:  The teens did call.
Speaker 3:  They did,
Speaker 4:  They did program the teens
Speaker 3:  To call. And for some reason they're all speaking Mandarin. Right. It's very
Speaker 3:  confusing. Yeah. It's crazy. Anyway, so it's, it's in 89, but I'm taking
Speaker 3:  it first off the board. I feel good about it.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Fair enough. What about you? I'm, I'm torn.
Speaker 4:  Apple TV won an Oscar. It did. That's a thing that happened. Yeah. For quota.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna take Apple TV plus in the awards category, Ooh for my first
Speaker 4:  pick. I hate you, but good. I think there's a decent chance that is going
Speaker 4:  to be the most complicated category. 'cause it turns out not a lot of
Speaker 4:  Oscars in those. So I'm taking that one on the go. 90 scale.
Speaker 4:  It's like a six. Yeah. Like it's, apple just has all the money in the
Speaker 4:  universe and Eddie Q just like hangs out in LA and does
Speaker 4:  whatever he wants. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Tim Cook likes Ted Lasso. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  He's like friends with Lion o Messi now that's like, it's great. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say that Apple keeps claiming that its movies make money and they
Speaker 3:  definitely don't. Well,
Speaker 4:  It was great 'cause there was, there was a, they do make money,
Speaker 5:  Just they don't, not enough profit. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  And it was one of those things where they were like, we spent all this money
Speaker 4:  on, you know, a handful of huge movies, killers of Flower Moon, and a couple
Speaker 4:  of others famously invested like $700 million into a few movies. And
Speaker 4:  they're like, but they're super profitable. And there were a bunch of people
Speaker 4:  who are like, you know, we can see the box office data, right? Like, it's
Speaker 4:  just, it's just right there. And, and it's just adding three numbers
Speaker 4:  that don't come anywhere near 700 million. But like, whatever.
Speaker 4:  It's Apple's fine. Apple's
Speaker 3:  Fine. I'm
Speaker 4:  Not worried about Apple TV plus making a profit for Apple.
Speaker 3:  I will say that everyone says it's the best one. Like people are like it.
Speaker 3:  It's the new HBO. And my fundamental belief is like, some things are very
Speaker 3:  good and then the things that are very bad are some of the most comically
Speaker 3:  bad things anyone has ever spent money on. Like Apple. You can't open an
Speaker 3:  Apple TV right now without it being like, you're gonna watch Argyle. And
Speaker 3:  it's like, no, I'm not Like I read the reviews
Speaker 3:  of Argyle. I've seen other people react to the concept of Argyle.
Speaker 4:  I saw Argyle in theaters. What is wrong? I don't know.
Speaker 3:  You have a child.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  He was asleep. It was,
Speaker 5:  Did you, did you pay for a babysitter?
Speaker 4:  No, I, the honest, I went alone. The honestly true story is
Speaker 4:  alone. I did,
Speaker 3:  Oh my God,
Speaker 4:  My wife is in, is doing grad school again because she collects Master's
Speaker 4:  degrees. I had nothing to do while she was
Speaker 4:  in class and my child was asleep. And So I was like, I'm gonna go to a movie.
Speaker 4:  And the literal only thing playing at the time that I wanted to see it was
Speaker 4:  ar Kyle,
Speaker 3:  Should I watch it for free? And Apple TV plus this is what I mean, the hit
Speaker 3:  rate is, is, is is good.
Speaker 4:  Argyle is a movie to
Speaker 3:  Watch solid,
Speaker 4:  Consistent in like the last 25 minutes of a plane ride when you
Speaker 4:  land and you're kind of like, oh, I should finish that eventually. And then
Speaker 4:  you never do. Like, that's Argyle. So
Speaker 3:  The, okay, I've had this idea. Tell me if this is good about Ed or bad. We
Speaker 3:  review movies thing we do with The Verge and that's fine. And most movies
Speaker 3:  are reviewed on like the tomato meter scale, like five stars. I have
Speaker 3:  long thought. We need to build a product that just tells you where
Speaker 3:  to watch a movie. Right. That's the actual ranking. It's like,
Speaker 3:  should you spend money on this in The future? You mean
Speaker 4:  Like physically in
Speaker 3:  The world? You physically take your body to Argyle alone while your child
Speaker 3:  is sleeping. No, see, answered right there. Yeah. Should you wait to pay
Speaker 3:  for it when you can buy it or rent it in the, in the first window? No
Speaker 3:  answer for, it's like a hard nose. What's
Speaker 4:  At the bottom of that lit, like on airplane phone seat. Back five minutes.
Speaker 4:  Delta at a time at Starbucks. Yeah. That's the
Speaker 3:  In one minute clips on TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Perfect.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like, wouldn't this be like vastly more useful than Star Ratings
Speaker 3:  if I was just like, this movie is good enough to watch on a JetBlue flight
Speaker 3:  where you're a little bit hungover. Like that's, that's
Speaker 3:  all the, and we're gonna, yeah, we're gonna roll this out.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Wait. Now I wanna know, what is the movie that you've seen the most
Speaker 4:  of exclusively in one minute? TikTok clips.
Speaker 3:  Moneyball. Okay. The TikTok algorithm is like, you are gonna watch Moneyball
Speaker 3:  today.
Speaker 5:  Is it, is it Sully? Is that what it's called? The one where Sully lands
Speaker 4:  The plane with the plane? I think it is Sully. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Never learned that. Is because only
Speaker 3:  See, that is a hard movie to watch in one minute. Clip
Speaker 5:  Only. Yeah. They only wanna show me like the plane landing. I get
Speaker 3:  Actually
Speaker 5:  Over and over again.
Speaker 3:  Similarly, I get a lot of flight with Denzel Washington Ooh, which is a very
Speaker 3:  intense movie to watch in the form of one minute. TikTok. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm just gonna call this,
Speaker 4:  Mine is Real Steel, by the way. The one Hugh Jackman Flights Robots. Perfect.
Speaker 4:  TikTok.
Speaker 3:  Can I call it just my, my favorite new podcast right now? There's a, a producer
Speaker 3:  explanation who has a podcast called the Irishman. I don't know If you ever
Speaker 3:  finished this project, but he was watching all of the
Speaker 3:  Irishman, which is a three and a half hour movie in one minute increments,
Speaker 3:  and then making a four minute podcast about that every single day.
Speaker 4:  That's fantastic.
Speaker 3:  And he, and he calls the mins and he is like, this Min was really hard to
Speaker 3:  watch. And it like, he only watched a min,
Speaker 3:  it, it is unclear whether he's gonna do Killers of the Flower Min.
Speaker 5:  I want that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It'll take six months to do that. It's very good. I love that. Okay. Are
Speaker 4:  we, are we snake drafting or are we going back to the top?
Speaker 3:  That snake drafting
Speaker 4:  Snake Draft. Right. So I. Get to go again. Wait, I hate this. I know. This
Speaker 4:  is great news for me. Let's see. I'm gonna go to the live category and I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna pick Amazon Prime Video Ooh, which has football, which is live So I
Speaker 4:  know.
Speaker 3:  That's good. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Wait, are you doing the, with the 3 99?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You're doing ads or no ads? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Ads or No
Speaker 4:  Ads. Ads. I'm fine with ads. Okay.
Speaker 3:  It's 'cause you're, you're buying it for football,
Speaker 4:  Not fine. The ads one
Speaker 3:  Mediocre
Speaker 4:  Football on the fire tv where you turn on your TV and it's like, would you
Speaker 4:  like to watch some ads? No, thank you.
Speaker 3:  But you're, you're taking it for football?
Speaker 4:  No, I get it because of football, but I'm taking it because frankly of Mr.
Speaker 4:  And Mrs. Smith, which I kicks and I would like that show. Okay. So you're,
Speaker 3:  You're like backing into the category. Yeah. Because there's like one low
Speaker 3:  rent a FC game a week. Yeah. And that's okay.
Speaker 4:  Perfect. Al Michaels gets me this one. This is So I'm happy. There
Speaker 3:  You go. I'll allow it. Thank
Speaker 4:  You. And I now have the two that are never gonna die because they're funded
Speaker 4:  by billionaires who don't care. It's perfect. That's fair.
Speaker 3:  Fair enough.
Speaker 4:  Okay. There's only one more of those left on this list. We'll come back to
Speaker 4:  that. It's gonna be all right.
Speaker 5:  Wait, how does the serpentine, does this mean that that
Speaker 4:  Means NELI eyes up. I hate this. And then you get to in a row. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Do you get ever any in a row?
Speaker 3:  Huh? No.
Speaker 5:  You get none in a row. Yeah. So you really
Speaker 4:  Do. We actually deliberately did this to screw over Eli. Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Then it's all great. But
Speaker 4:  Don't tell him we said that.
Speaker 3:  I'm still gonna win this Draft. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We'll
Speaker 3:  See. I'm gonna do it with my next pick. Okay. Which is the Disney bundle,
Speaker 3:  which is unbeatable.
Speaker 5:  Wait, what is the Disney bundle? Is it Disney and ESPN and Hulu.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And in India. Hot Star. Okay. Where the cricket sands out there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Do we allow bundles?
Speaker 5:  Hmm. I feel like bundles shouldn't be allowed this time.
Speaker 3:  It's hard to buy Disney without Bob Iger coming to your house and be like,
Speaker 3:  you're gonna get Hulu. Just take it.
Speaker 4:  That's actually sort of true. It is genuinely easier to get the bundle. Also,
Speaker 3:  Hulu is now integrated into the Disney app itself. you know, the app for
Speaker 3:  families. It's like, here's the Handmaid's Sale. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But what are you taking it for? Are you taking it for live or are you taking
Speaker 5:  it? Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What's your category?
Speaker 3:  We're taking it for bluey, like dead ahead blue.
Speaker 5:  That's not a category.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What category do
Speaker 3:  Remember? I just built like an insane home theater in artist. Can I talk
Speaker 3:  about this? For Bluey? For Bluey. Bluey. Like what is watched in this thing
Speaker 3:  is Bluey.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. Okay.
Speaker 4:  All right. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So can I, max rolls up to the tv, huge TV on the wall,
Speaker 3:  and she tries to scroll it, which is wild. 'cause it's bigger than
Speaker 3:  her. Oh, wow. So she's just like, come on, what
Speaker 4:  Does she think is gonna happen? She's,
Speaker 3:  It'll scroll. She thinks I'm gonna use the remote and then I'll get what
Speaker 3:  she wants. That's she's five. Yeah, that's good. Fair enough.
Speaker 3:  By the way, Disney is, I believe at a 30 on the go. 90 scale.
Speaker 4:  The whole bundle.
Speaker 3:  Disney, I'm putting on all of Disney. Oh, just the company. Just company.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Company. And it, that's 10 for no one knows what's going
Speaker 3:  on with Marvel. Okay. Just some weird stuff there.
Speaker 3:  10 for no one. They've got a big debt load with Hulu and all this other stuff.
Speaker 3:  They gotta do that. And then 10, because Max made me watch a
Speaker 3:  series of movies called The Descendants.
Speaker 5:  They're
Speaker 3:  So bad. It's the villains of Disney movies all have had
Speaker 3:  children and then they dance, fight to bring their cities together.
Speaker 3:  No, that
Speaker 5:  Sounds great.
Speaker 3:  And they made three of these things.
Speaker 4:  Wait, is that the one they made after the Hunger Games? And they were like,
Speaker 4:  this is kind of like that. And then it was awful. And they were like, don't
Speaker 4:  worry, we're gonna make
Speaker 3:  A bunch. I don't wanna talk about it.
Speaker 5:  That's the rest of this podcast. It's just,
Speaker 3:  It's more hard pivoting to descendants. More good. We've been waiting
Speaker 3:  for it. It's very bad. And that to me, I think moves Disney closer to death
Speaker 3:  than not.
Speaker 4:  I do feel like you have to add like five or six more points for just like,
Speaker 4:  Bob Iger might literally just burn it down. Lay out. Yeah. You might be like,
Speaker 4:  I'm actually retiring this time and just torch Disney. Yeah. Okay. Well,
Speaker 4:  what category do you want that in? I believe it qualifies for
Speaker 4:  everything you have available except for niche. Because not,
Speaker 3:  So, yeah. It's definitely not niche. No. I'm gonna, I'm gonna put Disney.
Speaker 3:  The, the, the bundle in awards. I think the awards category is the hardest
Speaker 3:  to fill is my, my feeling.
Speaker 4:  Hulu won an Oscar. You can have it there.
Speaker 3:  I believe Disney, the Disney Corporation has not
Speaker 4:  Disney Plus, though.
Speaker 3:  I don't think any Disney
Speaker 4:  Plus originals are tearing it up at the award shows. Right.
Speaker 3:  Oh, come on.
Speaker 4:  High school. Musical. The musical, the series, the Crushing it. Give
Speaker 3:  It a sound Design
Speaker 3:  fan's not like
Speaker 4:  Candy. That's probably true. Yeah. Yeah. All right. Alex, you get two picks
Speaker 4:  now. Okay.
Speaker 5:  I get two picks. I've done 4K. Correct. So, I need cheap.
Speaker 5:  So for cheap, I'm gonna go Peacock. Okay. Because they, they got the
Speaker 5:  live stuff. Yep. You could watch the State of the Union. If, you wanted to
Speaker 5:  on Peacock, you got the, the Olympics are coming and stuff like that.
Speaker 4:  That's true. It's actually a good year to have Peacock
Speaker 5:  And it's like, it's mad cheap. Okay. It is very affordable, but for,
Speaker 4:  It's also where I watch Parks and Recreation, so it's very important to my
Speaker 4:  life.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I know. I, it was, this was, again, I knew you had picked it last year.
Speaker 5:  So I wanted to,
Speaker 4:  It was gonna be my next pick. You're welcome. That was right there. Thank
Speaker 4:  you for that. You're welcome.
Speaker 5:  I got you. And then Ooh, what are the other categories again?
Speaker 4:  You still have awards? Live Niche, and wild card.
Speaker 5:  See, those are also easy to fill. I feel like
Speaker 4:  One substantially less so. Mm.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna save awards for last. I've, I've got a, I've got a good, I've got
Speaker 5:  one in the pocket for awards. Okay. But I'm gonna go niche.
Speaker 5:  Okay. This time I'm gonna go crunchy Roll Ooh.
Speaker 3:  Wait, did you rank your last one?
Speaker 5:  Oh, no, I have to rank it. You're right, you're right. Peacock. Ooh. I think
Speaker 5:  that's like a, like a 2020.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You think
Speaker 4:  Netflix is more likely to die than Peacock?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You think Disney is more likely to die in Peacock?
Speaker 3:  Peacock is in danger of just directly being forgotten about. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But it's, it's growing
Speaker 3:  Just straight up. The Roberts family, they owned this. Comcast is like, we
Speaker 3:  did Peacock. Who named this? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Nobody knows it exists, but it's still like there. I think it's like the
Speaker 5:  sixth most subscribed like platform right
Speaker 5:  now for, or Streaming platforms. So like, people are doing it. Mainly it's
Speaker 5:  David and other people who wanna watch Parks and Rec. Yeah. And so, so
Speaker 5:  yeah. And I feel like Parks and Rec is really gonna like, let us survive
Speaker 5:  in a way that Netflix can't 'cause Netflix Doesn
Speaker 3:  Own it. Just a direct, direct subscription to Parks and Rec. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. First
Speaker 4:  Of all, I would pay for that for the rest of my life. Same. Yeah. But also
Speaker 4:  Netflix has Suits. N Eli's favorite show on television.
Speaker 3:  I start hissing at you.
Speaker 3:  I don Dunno if I've told this story on a podcast. I have a niece, nephew,
Speaker 3:  they're in college, they're doing great. And they, they hit their first exams
Speaker 3:  in their freshman year of college. And my niece, who wants to be a, she wants
Speaker 3:  to do forensics, so she's a chem major. She texted me and said,
Speaker 3:  what's law school like? Because she had encountered her first like
Speaker 3:  chem exams. And I was like, what is going on here? Like, this is a hard,
Speaker 3:  don't go to law school, first of all, just like blanket advice. And she's
Speaker 3:  like, well, I've been watching a lot of suits. And I was like, this is a
Speaker 3:  danger to America. Like this dumb show.
Speaker 3:  But wait, isn't is like single-handedly taking women outta stem.
Speaker 5:  The point of the show is that the guy doesn't go to law school. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So why would you wanna go to law school? That's a good school
Speaker 3:  Watching point. The point of the show don't to is also that it rots your
Speaker 3:  brain and soul with every passing minute.
Speaker 3:  Sorry, I just like suits. I don't have to True.
Speaker 5:  You love it.
Speaker 3:  I've watched several episodes of the show and I, the other thing
Speaker 4:  Everybody should know is NELI auditioned for Suits. I didn't
Speaker 3:  Get it. We're the Meghan Markle role. Actually, actually, it was a weird
Speaker 3:  callback. I could see, can you fit in this dress? And I was like, not at
Speaker 3:  all.
Speaker 5:  Just a little.
Speaker 3:  All right. So that was, yeah.
Speaker 5:  I, all right.
Speaker 3:  So we like hard diverged in
Speaker 5:  This space. Yeah. Sorry. Sorry. So
Speaker 3:  Peacock you think is close, less close to death than Netflix. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because Peacock is an entertainment company. Like, like I, I,
Speaker 5:  I fully believe that companies that are built on entertainment are going
Speaker 5:  to have their Streaming services probably survive longer than the companies
Speaker 5:  who are built around tech. Because the tech companies are
Speaker 5:  trying to make art like technology. Yeah. And that's just,
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of similarities between those two. But there's a lot of things
Speaker 5:  that are not
Speaker 3:  Similar. Yeah. Netflix is like, can we algorithmically recreate a movie?
Speaker 5:  Right. And that's dumb. Yeah. Whereas like, peacock's, like, can we
Speaker 5:  make poker face? And that's cool. I mean, four people watched it.
Speaker 5:  I was one of them. But I bet a bunch of people in the crowd. It's very good
Speaker 5:  though. Yeah. Poker face was great. That's the only one that I hear Anybody
Speaker 5:  know for
Speaker 3:  The audience in the car, there was dead silence from the crowd.
Speaker 3:  Sh,
Speaker 5:  We can put that in post. We can put that in post. Yeah. Standing Ovation.
Speaker 5:  Believe in Peacock.
Speaker 3:  All right. Crunchy roll. Go. 90 Scale Crunchy
Speaker 5:  Roll. Ooh. That one's harder because they, they just are like, they're killing
Speaker 5:  off a lot of stuff over there. Right. Every time Lov like notices, he
Speaker 5:  owns a company. He's like,
Speaker 3:  No, crunch Roll is Sony. That's the anime.
Speaker 5:  Is it owned by Sony? Sony.
Speaker 3:  Sony, okay. So, and Sony merged it with a company. This is a real name of
Speaker 3:  a company. Fun animation.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Fun animation's from my town.
Speaker 3:  Super cool. And then they, can you
Speaker 4:  Imagine the meeting where they had to decide whether to keep crunchy roll
Speaker 4:  or fun animation?
Speaker 3:  Very good. So yeah, Sony owns both of them. They merged 'em together. They
Speaker 3:  got rid of the, the digital purchases. That was a big out Outroar
Speaker 3:  one of those words. So
Speaker 5:  Crunchy roll. but it, it, they're just on max then they just like have a
Speaker 5:  license. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They're doing the distribution thing.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Well Ooh that, that changes it a little on the Go 90 scale, right?
Speaker 5:  If there doesn't have the specter. Well,
Speaker 3:  It depends on how much you think touching HBO Max
Speaker 3:  immediately brings you closer to death. Like If, you acknowledge HBO
Speaker 3:  Max. Like, are you closer to death?
Speaker 5:  That's true. That's true. So, so 10 Points, because it was on HBO max.
Speaker 5:  So it's been like, acknowledged by that 10 points because it's owned by Sony.
Speaker 5:  And Sony also often forgets it owns things. And then
Speaker 5:  10 points for the Weeps. I'm a weep. I'm sorry. I, I hope
Speaker 5:  that's not a whole So
Speaker 3:  You, you're, you're you're coming to 40?
Speaker 5:  No, I'm at 30. That's just 30. 30. Okay. So it's a 30. It's not 30.
Speaker 4:  So still less likely to die than Netflix. Yeah, exactly. This all makes perfect
Speaker 3:  Enemy fans are hardcore. Yeah, they
Speaker 5:  Are hardcore.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Like you're, we just had that, we just had the president of Crunch
Speaker 3:  Roll and Decoder, and he was like, we're ready to go. He was, he was very
Speaker 3:  excited about anime.
Speaker 5:  Like that, that that thing started for just like people who wanted a pirate,
Speaker 5:  an anime Yeah. From overseas. And then they were like, what if we just make
Speaker 5:  ourselves legit?
Speaker 3:  If we sold, sold it to them instead.
Speaker 5:  And, and they did. And it's like, cool. That's awesome. I support you. Crunchy
Speaker 5:  roll.
Speaker 3:  All right. I'd love it. All right. Nila, you're up. And now I'm looking at
Speaker 3:  my list here. All right. I'm, I'm gonna fill out 4K last, oh, I
Speaker 3:  feel very confident that I can fill out 4K last and get ahead. So I'm
Speaker 3:  gonna go with Wild Card. Okay. And I am
Speaker 3:  picking HBO Max. my friends,
Speaker 4:  First of all, it's just called Max. Well, If, you wanna pick HBO Max? That's
Speaker 4:  fine. I refuse. Yeah. Yeah. I'm actually good with that. I take it back.
Speaker 4:  You can pick hbo.
Speaker 3:  I refuse to call the Streaming service by the name of my dog. We're going
Speaker 3:  full Warner Brothers owned and affiliated
Speaker 3:  HBO Max. Okay. you know the whole name by the way, Dave and I Do You have
Speaker 3:  your tote bags when you come to South by Southwest, you register and they
Speaker 3:  give you a tote bag. The tote bags are sponsored by Paramount Plus
Speaker 3:  and by HBO Max. Yeah. Other, so you get to pick other, everybody has to pick
Speaker 3:  one. Who picked the Paramount plus one in this room? All
Speaker 5:  Right. I think you know who on stage
Speaker 3:  Five people who picked the HBO Max one. That's everybody. Wow.
Speaker 5:  Of people holding them up.
Speaker 3:  So David and I got our tote bags, like
Speaker 4:  90% for
Speaker 3:  Max. So we asked all of the people getting on the tote bags, and they all
Speaker 3:  tried to be really diplomatic. They're like, it's about half and half with
Speaker 3:  the show. Max one really good. And then one woman, this is a real
Speaker 3:  thing. This is reporting. You cannot cancel me for this. This is a quote.
Speaker 3:  I'm a little worried about this quote. Oh no,
Speaker 4:  I was there for this. I can, I can drop.
Speaker 3:  This is a true thing that was said to us. And then I just backed away from
Speaker 3:  this situation. one of them said to us, the ladies are taking the
Speaker 3:  Paramount one because the logo is prettier Ooh.
Speaker 5:  See,
Speaker 3:  I didn't say that. I didn't make that up. Someone else said that to me. I'm
Speaker 3:  just reporting to you what was said. And I guarantee you this was said to
Speaker 3:  us just to even out the idea that everyone was taking the HBO
Speaker 3:  max.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Ooh. 'cause the first person was like, oh yeah, it's the max ones. And
Speaker 4:  then was like, well, no. I mean, it's like, it's fine. They're both great.
Speaker 4:  It's like 50 50. Don't worry, even worry about it. And then there was somebody
Speaker 4:  two seats down who was like, what
Speaker 3:  If I make some shit up about the logo being right here? That was like very
Speaker 3:  much how this was going. Anyway, I, I took the HBO max bag to give it to
Speaker 3:  my daughter Max, and then promptly forgot it, so. Aw, that's fine. Oh, she'll
Speaker 3:  be fine. She knows.
Speaker 5:  I hope so.
Speaker 3:  HBO max, by the way, also Ed in 80 on the go 90 scale of
Speaker 3:  Doom Streaming Services.
Speaker 5:  How do you, how do you measure that? How do you get those points?
Speaker 3:  Well, I don't think you have to add 'em up that that 80 is a real vibe. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's just the looming presence of David's LOV and his decision making.
Speaker 3:  He
Speaker 5:  Just looks over and he's like, what's that? She
Speaker 3:  HBO Max, as you know, a product of a doomed merger
Speaker 3:  with at and t in which at and t convinced a federal judge
Speaker 3:  that this was quote, a vision deal. And that the vision was they would put
Speaker 3:  short versions of Game of Thrones on Android phones. Oh
Speaker 3:  yeah.
Speaker 5:  That would've
Speaker 3:  Ruled. And our nation's justice system looked at this and was like, sick.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause it would've been cool.
Speaker 3:  It's like a real thing that
Speaker 4:  Happened. Do you ever say a sentence out loud and be like, that can't possibly
Speaker 4:  be true. Like there's no way. That thing I just said is real.
Speaker 3:  It super happened. They're like, the division is, we're gonna preload
Speaker 3:  stuff on mid-range Android phones, and it's gonna be Game of Throne slips.
Speaker 3:  That didn't pan out, as many of you may have noticed at all.
Speaker 3:  Fall apart. They've got a enormous amount of debt. And what they
Speaker 3:  have is a lot of at and t customers who can't quit HBO
Speaker 3:  Max. I'm one of these people. I'm grandfathered into an HBO Max plan.
Speaker 3:  And So I cannot put this in the 4K category. Ah, because
Speaker 3:  my at and t account no longer knows about HBO Max and I can't
Speaker 3:  leave whatever version of the service I'm currently subscribed to,
Speaker 3:  which no longer has 4K.
Speaker 4:  That sounds right. This
Speaker 3:  Is com These are some of the, the, the biggest, most sophisticated
Speaker 3:  companies in our country. And they're like, our database forgot about you,
Speaker 4:  But they'll keep charging You. Don't worry about that. Yeah. They will keep
Speaker 3:  Charging you. They're definitely gonna keep charging me. So. I believe. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The Wild Card. Would
Speaker 5:  The 4K have even been good though, coming from Max?
Speaker 3:  I,
Speaker 5:  Excuse me. HBO Max?
Speaker 3:  No, no, no, no, no. Definitely
Speaker 5:  Not. It would've been bad.
Speaker 3:  I watched what's the, what's the one where they fight, let them fight.
Speaker 3:  Godzilla.
Speaker 5:  Godzilla.
Speaker 3:  That's how my brain works. I'd watched that in their version of Atmos
Speaker 3:  and Vision. Yeah. And it was like, what if we do this at two bits per second?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It was just like a series of shapes and colors and noises. you know.
Speaker 3:  Beautiful. Like a baby toy was just like happening. And then the one guy
Speaker 3:  was like, let them fight. It's good. That's how you wanna experience that.
Speaker 4:  Love that. Yeah. Yeah. Alright. I can't believe no one has picked YouTube
Speaker 4:  yet. I feel obligated to pick YouTube, which I'm YouTube. Wait,
Speaker 3:  YouTube TV or YouTube Premium? Well, So,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna put YouTube in cheap. So neither. Oh, I'm getting you full.
Speaker 4:  I'm getting YouTube with ads. All the ads, like every single ad you can imagine.
Speaker 4:  I'm just
Speaker 3:  Watching. That is the worst choice on this list I'm gonna watch. I love it.
Speaker 3:  YouTube with ads is the worst choice on this list.
Speaker 5:  No, I disagree. We'll see, that's a good choice. That's, that's how I watch
Speaker 5:  YouTube now
Speaker 4:  I'm logged in So I get recommendations. All right. But I have to watch
Speaker 4:  all the ads. I get mad at people who have ads now on YouTube.
Speaker 4:  That's the thing that has happened to me recently. Yeah. But I, I'll get
Speaker 4:  over it. Win the Draft. I will over, I think bringing
Speaker 3:  Is the best deal in Streaming.
Speaker 4:  Yes, I agree with that. Just, but don don't get to have it.
Speaker 3:  You're going ads.
Speaker 4:  I'm going, I'm going YouTube.
Speaker 3:  You're just going straight American cheese. It's, yeah. Other cheeses are
Speaker 3:  available, but just Nope. Slices in the mouth. All right.
Speaker 4:  Just want it. Just give it to me. Okay. So that's the end of round three.
Speaker 4:  YouTube is a zero on the go. 90 scale. Yeah. Yeah, it's fine. Feel very good
Speaker 4:  about
Speaker 3:  That. It's the only, it's the only part of Google that feels like a enough
Speaker 3:  what us
Speaker 4:  Doing. It might be the only thing left on the internet at the end of all
Speaker 4:  of this. Like it's just
Speaker 1:  or whether your team is around the corner or on another continent altogether.
Speaker 1:  At Lian. Software like Jira, confluence and Loom are built to
Speaker 1:  help keep you all on the same page from start to finish. So
Speaker 1:  say goodbye to the org chart. It's time to accomplish those big ideas that
Speaker 1:  would be impossible to achieve alone. Because individuals were great, but
Speaker 1:  together we're so much better. Learn how to unleash the potential of your
Speaker 1:  team@atlassian.com. That's
Speaker 1:  A-T-L-A-S-S-I-A n.com Atlassian.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So we are at the end of round three. We're halfway through the Draft
Speaker 4:  Alex so far has Peacock Netflix and Crunchy roll. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  NELI has TikTok, the Disney bundle. And Max I have YouTube
Speaker 4:  Apple TV and Prime Video. I think it's very clear who is
Speaker 4:  currently in third place, but we'll leave that alone for now. I'm in
Speaker 4:  first. Wow.
Speaker 3:  Just wait. Just wait. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We're doing fine. I'm crush. Okay. So for round four, I get to go again,
Speaker 4:  which I am not prepared for. What do
Speaker 5:  You what What are your, are your
Speaker 3:  Leftovers? I don't, haven't you been cheating this whole time? No. Is this
Speaker 3:  just like, you like hustling us? You're like, I don't know how to play pool.
Speaker 5:  He's just moving everything around. He is giving himself Netflix, giving
Speaker 5:  himself Netflix. I did
Speaker 4:  Briefly give NELI two of my picks, so that was confusing. You're doing great.
Speaker 4:  So I have 4K Niche and wild card left.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  And I think
Speaker 4:  I can't do any of the 4K ones I know of anymore. So that's bad.
Speaker 4:  Does Tuby count as niche? What do we think? No,
Speaker 3:  No. Two Tuby is like what happens when you turn on?
Speaker 4:  I got a Yes from the audience. That's
Speaker 3:  Just, you know, tuby.
Speaker 3:  Well, tuby is like, like mainstream free. Yeah. Ad
Speaker 3:  supported. It's just Alex loves these things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just free ad supported television. It's got all of the stuff
Speaker 4:  You just made that sound very boring and very niche. That's kind of my point.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 5:  No, because it's got you. Well, no way I can describe it as gonna
Speaker 5:  support. Well,
Speaker 3:  I'm I'm just saying like, If, you damn
Speaker 4:  It. No,
Speaker 3:  You're right. If you're one of these boomers and you get off TikTok, you,
Speaker 3:  you on your eight hours of TikTok in the day Yeah. And you go turn on your,
Speaker 3:  the cheapest TV that you bought at at Best Buy, you're watching Tuby. Like
Speaker 3:  it's just happening to you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that is probably true.
Speaker 3:  I don't mean that to denigrate If. you choose Pluto, TikTok riddled boomers
Speaker 3:  that populate the middle of the country. I am one of them. I mean to say
Speaker 3:  that that is a thing that happens on TVs by default and that makes it not
Speaker 3:  mainstream.
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. All right, well then I won't take that. I will take Criterion
Speaker 3:  In. Yeah, that's, see, that's, that's much more
Speaker 4:  Appropriate. Yeah, that feels right. Yeah. Criterion is like, I don't know,
Speaker 4:  it's like a in the twenties on the scale, I would say. Yeah. Like I want
Speaker 4:  it to continue to exist and so do lots of people.
Speaker 5:  I think Criterion wants it to
Speaker 4:  Continue to exist, but maybe all of Criterion will not exist forever.
Speaker 5:  No, it feels pretty sustainable. Yeah. There was a really great story recently
Speaker 5:  about just kind of how sustainable it is and its whole business. but it isn't
Speaker 3:  Sustainability like James Cameron wants it to exist.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Yeah. That
Speaker 5:  Therefore it will exist. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's fair.
Speaker 4:  It's like the letterbox app where like, it'll be fine because Martin Scorsese
Speaker 4:  uses it. So like push comes to shove, it's gonna be all right. All right.
Speaker 4:  So I'm taking a criterion. That's my pick. NELI, you're up, you have
Speaker 4:  three categories remaining. You have 4K live and each, those are your three
Speaker 4:  YouTube
Speaker 3:  TV with Sunday Ticket. I don't think you understand that. I'm just
Speaker 3:  recapitulating my Draft that already won this thing. And
Speaker 3:  YouTube nerds are like, what do I do with Discovery? Plus? Like, I'm just
Speaker 3:  like straight America. but it didn't win. I picked. Huh?
Speaker 5:  You didn't win.
Speaker 4:  Well, yeah, you objectively did.
Speaker 5:  In fact, I won. It's so, I'm, I'm just coming in again. I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  Alex, I like to think that we have a good relationship in, in this situation.
Speaker 3:  I would like to just directly gaslight you and say that I won.
Speaker 5:  All right. What are you gonna do? No, you chose YouTube
Speaker 3:  YouTube TV Sunday Ticket is a straight zero. Yeah. Yeah. Like you can't,
Speaker 3:  you're fighting the service that delivers Taylor Swift and Travis Kel. Millions
Speaker 3:  of Americans every week. Like you're, it's fine. Yeah. It is the fastest
Speaker 3:  growing cable service in America. It has the most cha it has the most stuff.
Speaker 3:  'cause it's a cable service and it has the, the full backing of our
Speaker 3:  nation's military slash LI
Speaker 4:  Mean, it bought a decade of football, which means it bought a decade of existing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  You, you did So for 10 years. It's a zero, 11
Speaker 3:  Years or un or un un until they break up. But yeah, from the reports I've
Speaker 3:  read, it suggests that he's in Singapore right now. So, I think think that
Speaker 3:  that's true and that, you know, they both discuss taking the next step.
Speaker 3:  What do you think? I'm not following this m like crazy. I'm
Speaker 5:  Culture vibe. I get it.
Speaker 4:  Alright, so that's yours. And, and I want you to know that I'm giving you
Speaker 4:  YouTube tv because it is a separate product from YouTube.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  But If, you now try to just be like YouTube tv, but not Sunday. Take it.
Speaker 4:  No. Yeah. NELI. No,
Speaker 3:  I don't, I don't dunno what you're arguing with or who you're arguing with.
Speaker 3:  But you saw I,
Speaker 4:  I have played these games with you before.
Speaker 3:  Yes. And I guess I'm now directly gaslighting.
Speaker 4:  There we go. Okay. Alex, you're up. You get two now.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I get two. I get to go two in a row. You get two picks. Wow. What,
Speaker 5:  what's left for me? How do
Speaker 4:  You not know how this works? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Didn't, your three left are awards Live and Wild card.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I'm saving awards for less. Okay. I've got a good one for that
Speaker 4:  One. I know you're very excited about this. I
Speaker 5:  Know. So I've got Live
Speaker 4:  Live and Wild Card
Speaker 5:  And Wild Card Ooh. That's tricky. So
Speaker 5:  Live, I'm gonna go channels again. Okay. It worked last time. Explain
Speaker 4:  To the people what channels.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So Channels is an app. It's like a DVR app. You can, you can plug
Speaker 5:  it into your cable If, you still subscribe to Cable, you can plug
Speaker 5:  it into an antenna and then you just DVR everything. It
Speaker 4:  Also gets all the Fast
Speaker 5:  Channels. Yeah. It gets all the fast channels. So you can go and like, just
Speaker 5:  have your Pluto and have your Tube Tuby and then have your
Speaker 5:  A, B, C and all of your other,
Speaker 4:  I think it was you that described it to me as like an RSS reader for tv,
Speaker 4:  which I found very compelling.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's
Speaker 4:  Kind true. It likes a nerdiest possible thing, but it's awesome.
Speaker 5:  And it's sick. The guy's like very actively developing it. It's got a really
Speaker 5:  pretty ui. I just, I just dig the hell out of it. I use it a lot. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So I'm, I'm gonna go with that for my live, because it gets me all of my
Speaker 5:  lives. And then my Wild Card, I think this one's really obvious.
Speaker 5:  It, it, it's gonna be paramount because, you know, somebody had to, it's
Speaker 5:  like it's an 89 on the Go 90 scale.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The most
Speaker 5:  89 channels. Yeah. Channels is like a zero. 'cause I, I, I don't think you,
Speaker 5:  you
Speaker 3:  Can't kill R Rss s Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You can't kill R Ss. Yeah. But, but, but Paramount Plus is
Speaker 5:  definitely like an 89. It's as close as you can get
Speaker 5:  until like, they sell it in a couple of weeks or whatever. So,
Speaker 5:  but yeah. I I think it's a good wild card. It's, it's a fun, I I,
Speaker 5:  I enjoy the Cowboys and I enjoy the, the live stuff and
Speaker 5:  I enjoy the, the Star Trek. So it, like, it gets everything for
Speaker 5:  me.
Speaker 3:  And that wasn't enough to keep a Streaming service alive. No. Cowboy Cowboys
Speaker 3:  and Star Trek.
Speaker 5:  You would think it would've been in 1966.
Speaker 5:  And unfortunately me and the Boomers are the only ones that still watch it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But, but you know, it'll get merged with Peacock or something. So I'll
Speaker 5:  have it all together again.
Speaker 3:  There is a really good article about the demise of Paramount Plus that
Speaker 3:  just talks about the, the sheer hubris, which was this product was launched.
Speaker 3:  It's beautiful. Where they're like, well, we don't have a lot of a lot of
Speaker 3:  stuff, but we've got CBS, we've got Star Trek and we have Taylor Sheridan.
Speaker 3:  And everyone's like, that's not enough stuff. Like, do you know how much
Speaker 3:  stuff Netflix has? They're like, no, no, no. CBS. It
Speaker 3:  turned out that the great,
Speaker 5:  I mean, it worked for them for like, what, 30 years as, as a broadcast network.
Speaker 5:  CBS was the most watched broadcast network. So they're like, yeah. And you're
Speaker 4:  One of only three things that exists to watch Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Crush. Yeah. When they had like a monopoly crush it kinda like a pseudo
Speaker 5:  monopoly. They crushed it. Yeah. And then more competition came and they,
Speaker 5:  they're in 89 on. Yeah. It gets
Speaker 4:  Tougher when you're 80 Channel two.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. One thing single handedly keeping CBS alive. This is a true story.
Speaker 3:  Alex is addicted to 60 Minutes. Yes. She walks into our newsroom
Speaker 3:  at least twice a week and is like, I saw this thing in 60 Minutes. And all
Speaker 3:  of us have to be like, well, definitionally Alex, that means it happened
Speaker 3:  eight months ago. It's true.
Speaker 5:  I love it. It's my favorite show. It just gives you a really good insight
Speaker 5:  into what CBS once boomers to think about. Yeah. And I
Speaker 5:  love that. I wanna know that too.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's a good time.
Speaker 5:  All right. Leslie Stall, I mean, oh my, my God. 89. I could talk about her
Speaker 5:  for hours, but, but we, we don't have that much time to go, so
Speaker 4:  We don't Yeah,
Speaker 3:  You're up next. I think about South by Southwest. I think about Leslie Stall.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Leslie Stall fangirling
Speaker 3:  Specifically. We, yeah, exactly. David, you're up next. Oh, it's me.
Speaker 3:  Crap. All right, well I've got, I've got two left, right? Yeah. Yes.
Speaker 3:  4K. 4K and Niche Niche. Well, this next one can go into
Speaker 3:  either one. Okay. I'm picking my new favorite Streaming service Bravia
Speaker 3:  Core. Oh God. The Streaming service only available on select Sony Top. Neil,
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 4:  Just instantly lost the Draft. Congratulations.
Speaker 3:  It has four movies on it and they all look amazing. They're all
Speaker 5:  Spiderman
Speaker 3:  Streams of 80 megabits per second is out of control. Sony owns no movies.
Speaker 3:  It owns no ip. It's just like old Spider-Man movies. You have to set the
Speaker 3:  TV to allow it to stream it like this level of bandwidth.
Speaker 3:  Do you have to
Speaker 4:  Like call your cable company? You're like, listen, it's about to get weird
Speaker 3:  Two hours. So this is a true fact about Sony is like such a big
Speaker 3:  disconnected company. They make the TVs, only the TVs support the Streaming
Speaker 3:  service. They did not put an ethernet port on the TVs that is
Speaker 3:  fast enough to support the Streaming service. So you either have
Speaker 3:  to use wifi or you have to buy a USB ethernet adapter like a us
Speaker 3:  This is a trip. So I did it. It's great. I love it. I've never had
Speaker 3:  more fun in my life, not watching movies and instead configuring the settings
Speaker 3:  of my tv. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  So where is it on the go nineties? It's like a zero, right? Oh,
Speaker 3:  It's, Sony loves this thing. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're never getting rid of that.
Speaker 3:  They, yeah. I, if you've ever wanted to watch Ghostbusters two in the most
Speaker 3:  pristine quality of your entire life, like you can see every four, which
Speaker 3:  I did. I did it So I watched the shit outta Ghostbusters two and then I showed
Speaker 3:  it to other people and they were like, why are we watching Ghostbusters two?
Speaker 3:  I would just like 4K IMAX right now. You don't
Speaker 4:  Have to pick this. you know that, right? Yeah. No one, no one from
Speaker 4:  Sony is like back there.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 4:  Have choices. No pointing anything at you.
Speaker 3:  There's a lot in the free, the glorious state of Texas. I'm
Speaker 3:  exercising my free market rights as an American to pick
Speaker 3:  Bravia core, the best Streaming service. That is the weirdest to use,
Speaker 3:  that has a credit system that makes no sense. Sometimes it just forgets.
Speaker 3:  It gave you, it's all very bad, but it's all
Speaker 3:  glorious. Like, I want every one of these services to offer me like stream
Speaker 3:  a Blu-ray to me. And that's, that's what David's just looking at me. He's
Speaker 3:  like, you should stop talking.
Speaker 5:  He's horrified.
Speaker 3:  It's good.
Speaker 4:  I just always thought it was a bit when you would come in and be like, I
Speaker 4:  watched a movie on Bravia court and
Speaker 3:  Now I'm like, oh no,
Speaker 4:  Neela loves Bravia court.
Speaker 3:  I do like
Speaker 5:  You have like a little monitor to show it so that it always shows you what
Speaker 5:  the bit rate is.
Speaker 3:  Do you think I don't have the Arrow app on my phone open showing me how fast
Speaker 3:  internet speed is going on the TV while, while I watch something like Zero
Speaker 3:  Dark 30 again? Is that what I'm
Speaker 4:  Like I usually don't watch zero Dark 30. It's just up there while you watch
Speaker 4:  your Euro app. It's very
Speaker 3:  Good. Yeah. And then I've, I've told this story before. If, you watch zero
Speaker 3:  dark 30 and then you have a small child who is not compliant about eating.
Speaker 3:  You start accidentally like saying torture words to your small child.
Speaker 3:  She's like zero, dark 30 is like very intense. And then the next day I was
Speaker 3:  like, your behavior determines how you're treated. She's like, I'm not eating
Speaker 3:  the apples. Don't do that. Just like, don't do that to your child.
Speaker 4:  All right, now it's me. We've got one left too. I have two left, but I get
Speaker 4:  to do 'em both right now. Oh wow. Serious. Which feels like a lot of pressure.
Speaker 4:  So I'm gonna pick two B for 4K because I just now this second confirmed that
Speaker 4:  there is at least one 4K thing on two B and it's a fireplace video.
Speaker 4:  Like, it's like a ule log situation, but it counts.
Speaker 4:  It's 4K and it's on two B So. I get to have it. So that's going in
Speaker 4:  4K. Okay. Okay. Pretty psyched about it. That works. I should have picked
Speaker 4:  Tuby for a different one. I did this Draft poorly. Yeah. Has it has turned
Speaker 4:  out
Speaker 3:  Here're at the end. We're just picking stuff,
Speaker 4:  But we're coming around. It could have been long. That'll be fine. I just
Speaker 4:  realized all of my wild cards were gone two rounds ago. So it's been like
Speaker 4:  kind of messing with me for a while. Yeah. But it's okay. So, I'm picking
Speaker 4:  Tuby. Okay. Which I actually think is like 30,
Speaker 4:  somewhere in that range. On the scale. It's like
Speaker 4:  doing really well. It's like sneakily very popular. Also Fox has no
Speaker 4:  other Streaming anything to do. Yeah. So they just give everything to Tuby.
Speaker 4:  But also toy's whole thing was, it's free and there's ads
Speaker 4:  and that's where everybody else is going. Yep. So
Speaker 4:  that could be bad. Yeah. And so now they're like, what If you? Yeah. They're
Speaker 4:  like, now they're like, well we have to get some good content. How do we
Speaker 4:  do that? It's like, oh no, welcome to everyone else's
Speaker 4:  hell from the last 12 days.
Speaker 5:  Well, they just go to like Z Love and they're like, Hey, is there any show
Speaker 5:  you wanna cancel? And can we just like, we
Speaker 4:  Just like have it. He's like, no tax cuts.
Speaker 5:  Like absolutely not. I gotta put it in the vault. Can't have it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. No,
Speaker 5:  This is, that was my slo.
Speaker 4:  That was good. I'm sorry. That
Speaker 3:  Was perfect. you know, it's, it was great because I actually don't dunno
Speaker 3:  what David Slo sounds like
Speaker 4:  She that Exactly. It's like that nailed. It was, yeah. She, she was working
Speaker 4:  on it.
Speaker 3:  Put it in the vault. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  What's the other one? I think for, for my wild card.
Speaker 4:  I think I'm taking Instagram reels,
Speaker 3:  Which feels
Speaker 4:  Insane as I say it out loud.
Speaker 3:  I just want, you can't, you know, he can't If you choose
Speaker 3:  TikTok. He can absolutely choose the TikTok doesn't have pictures.
Speaker 3:  Instagram famously.
Speaker 4:  Hey, TikTok has slideshows. Now
Speaker 3:  The slide shows are effectively a form of video Videos are just pictures
Speaker 3:  all in a row.
Speaker 3:  When,
Speaker 4:  When do, when does the slide show become a video? Neil, hi. Let's talk about
Speaker 4:  this.
Speaker 3:  Like what is it? What is it
Speaker 4:  Mean if I go through my PowerPoint really fast? Better a
Speaker 3:  Video. You were swipe a TikTok OL in 24 frames for a second. It's called
Speaker 3:  Persistence of Vision here. Tech Journalist.
Speaker 4:  No, I'm giving it to me. I think I'm taping here. Think
Speaker 3:  By the way, taking to be an Instagram rails back to back is
Speaker 3:  just the saddest man. It feels
Speaker 4:  Great. No,
Speaker 3:  It's, those are the last two cars in the
Speaker 4:  Rental lot. Do you know how much content I have now?
Speaker 3:  All the good stuff stuff. Do you know how much repurposed garbage from other
Speaker 3:  people's
Speaker 1:  that your organization is working together with the same shared language
Speaker 1:  and goals across all departments. Atlassian software like Loom
Speaker 1:  provides instant asynchronous video communication across teams
Speaker 1:  while Atlassian Confluence helps connect teams with a single source of
Speaker 1:  truth. And Atlassian, JIRA helps teams plan, track and
Speaker 1:  deliver shared work, whether you're a team of two, 200 or
Speaker 1:  2 million, or whether your team is around the corner or on another
Speaker 1:  continent altogether. Atlassian software like Jira, confluence, and
Speaker 1:  Loom are built to help keep you all on the same page from start
Speaker 1:  to finish. So say goodbye to the org chart. It's time to accomplish those
Speaker 1:  big ideas that would be impossible to achieve alone, because individuals
Speaker 1:  were great, but together we're so much better. Learn how to unleash the
Speaker 1:  potential of your team@atlassian.com. That's
Speaker 1:  A-T-L-A-S-S-I-A n.com
Speaker 1:  Atlassian.
Speaker 3:  All right. Who's next? NELI. Crap. I wasn't prepared. I was, this is
Speaker 4:  Why. I don't know, sir, your last one is Niche. This is all you have left.
Speaker 3:  So David just updated the spreadsheet with the word Sony Bravia Court, and
Speaker 3:  somehow Google Docs transmitted his disdain.
Speaker 3:  Alright. So my, the last category I have left is Niche. Correct.
Speaker 3:  Which is tough here.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 4:  You are not allowed to pick
Speaker 3:  A flex service. I have to think of a stream. Yeah. Okay. I know, I know
Speaker 3:  what I'm gonna do. I feel weird about it. I'm gonna say it. It's only
Speaker 3:  because my, my father-in-law's at my house, and he has been watching this
Speaker 3:  Streaming service nonstop since he arrived.
Speaker 3:  Motor Trend tv.
Speaker 4:  Tell us about Motor Trend tv.
Speaker 3:  A Motor Trend TV is an app that plays motor trend content at you.
Speaker 3:  If. you are interested in older cars being turned into nicer cars. Do I have
Speaker 3:  an app for you? my friends? Have you ever thought about watching a show where
Speaker 3:  some dudes go to a car auction?
Speaker 4:  That's it. That's the whole
Speaker 5:  Do they, do they bid or do they just go
Speaker 3:  Well, they, they talk about whether they would bid. Is it worth it? It's
Speaker 3:  very much like PBS but with cars and, you know, I
Speaker 3:  I also find it, cap it. I'm not a car nerd, I just can't, the duration
Speaker 3:  it is currently being displayed in my home is really quite something. And
Speaker 3:  So, I just for the family. I'm doing this niche
Speaker 4:  For the family. Family. And this is like a thing you can turn on and it just
Speaker 4:  keeps happening at you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it is like a full grid guide of MotorTrend content. Fair enough.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It is niche.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's the
Speaker 4:  Most, yeah. Counts. I
Speaker 5:  Would say that is the most, I'm
Speaker 3:  Pretty certain my father-in-Law is keeping this service afloat. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's just him. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Is this MotorTrend one word or two
Speaker 3:  Words? It's one word. I think One word, but two word. Like TV is a different
Speaker 3:  word. you know what
Speaker 4:  I'm saying? MotorTrend tv. Yeah. Got it. That's right. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  That's not what I thought you were gonna say. All right. What did
Speaker 3:  You think I was gonna say?
Speaker 4:  I something other than that, so many choices.
Speaker 5:  I was really excited to find out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I was really thinking about like, what's at the bottom of my Apple
Speaker 3:  TV grid and then, dude. Oh, that's
Speaker 4:  Interesting.
Speaker 3:  None of it's just a, it's a wasteland of Gone nine.
Speaker 4:  Mine is like BBC America. Yeah. And like a PBS app
Speaker 4:  that won't let me log in anymore because I canceled my account when I
Speaker 4:  moved. Yeah. And they were like, no, you hate PBS in America. You can't get
Speaker 4:  in anymore.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They get really mad when you move.
Speaker 4:  Very upset.
Speaker 5:  PBS is
Speaker 4:  Just so upset. Yeah. NPR is mad at me now. It's a whole thing. I'm so, all
Speaker 4:  right, Alex, you're up Last Right. Awards.
Speaker 5:  Last awards. I'm gonna go Moy. That's
Speaker 4:  How you say it. Which has won an Oscar. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It, it's one because it If
Speaker 3:  You say the name of the thing again.
Speaker 5:  Muy M So Alex's line.
Speaker 3:  M-U-B-I-M-U-B. Okay. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It's real. It's real. And it's,
Speaker 3:  That's not Tubi?
Speaker 5:  No, it's
Speaker 3:  Mui. Got it. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It's real. I I swear it's real. I saw it when I was walking in. They had
Speaker 5:  some signs outside and I went and I, you like,
Speaker 3:  Were like, in case I need to think of a fifth Streaming service. I
Speaker 5:  Forgot about movie.
Speaker 3:  And, and then you check to make sure they'd won an Oscar. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because because movie is all independent films
Speaker 5:  from the last few decades. That's a
Speaker 4:  Good one. What? Oscar? Did it win a
Speaker 5:  Lot?
Speaker 4:  No, no, no, no, no, no. Hold
Speaker 5:  On. No, no, no.
Speaker 4:  Hold on. This is not a movie that won. An Oscar is available on this
Speaker 4:  service. Yeah. That's nothing. This is a, this is a
Speaker 4:  movie original. She chose
Speaker 5:  Disney Plus as his award
Speaker 3:  One. 'cause they paid for the movies. An Oscar. What did like, Disney.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 4:  Oscar. A documentary Oscar, thanks to Questlove. Alex. Cranz.
Speaker 4:  And then I made a whole Disney plus original joke. Where have you been? Alex?
Speaker 4:  Wait,
Speaker 5:  Wait, where have you been? This? But you're saying that I can't just choose
Speaker 5:  like No,
Speaker 4:  That's all of them.
Speaker 5:  So I couldn't have you.
Speaker 4:  It has a movie available that has won an Oscar. Is is is
Speaker 4:  TikTok in one minute? Increment.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. That's all of those. Exactly. I was, I was all ready for it.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 3:  You were just gonna pick, like it has a movie available that has one of Oscar.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Hundred percent Reddit.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. All right.
Speaker 3:  Hmm. This was the hardest category because of, for the, for because of this
Speaker 3:  rule. This exact reason. Because if not for the rule, it would be the easiest
Speaker 3:  category. Right.
Speaker 4:  Because it is
Speaker 5:  The easiest category. It's all of them. All right.
Speaker 3:  Twitter has movies on it that everyone wants.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 3:  Know, by the way, he says it's a video first platform. Does Twitter count?
Speaker 3:  You could pick Twitter
Speaker 4:  If If, you can. If Tucker Carlson has won an Oscar while on X,
Speaker 4:  he can have it. Yeah, sure.
Speaker 5:  So it has to have been a Streaming service very specifically.
Speaker 4:  Yes. The, the company that hosts it has to
Speaker 4:  have made it and it has to have won an Oscar.
Speaker 5:  Then I'll choose Hulu.
Speaker 3:  She can do that. 'cause she's not in the bundle.
Speaker 4:  That is true. Okay. Bam. That's fair.
Speaker 5:  But movie's better.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 3:  It's, you heard about movie just now? I
Speaker 5:  Know. And it looks really sick. I'm gonna go subscribe. It's got 4K.
Speaker 5:  There you go. It's got a lot of old movies,
Speaker 3:  Many of which have won Oscars. So
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's it's got award-winning content on it. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 4:  I. Think I won ISN and Theatrically distributes films by emerging and established
Speaker 4:  filmmakers. Unlike everything else that does that exact same thing. I
Speaker 3:  Feel like the best case scenario for buying display advertising at South
Speaker 3:  by Southwest is people on a stage Googling what your company is in front
Speaker 3:  of an audience.
Speaker 4:  I legitimately was like 40% search,
Speaker 3:  Like zero people have signed up, but we have definitely Googled it now. Alex
Speaker 4:  Cranz. Where is movie on the go nineties.
Speaker 3:  This is the worst case scenario.
Speaker 5:  Advertising.
Speaker 3:  So by
Speaker 5:  Southwest, wait, no, it's a Hulu now, right?
Speaker 3:  Well,
Speaker 4:  I'd like you to do
Speaker 5:  Both. Okay. You want me to do both? Okay. Movie is,
Speaker 5:  it feels like it's gonna be pretty low on the go. 90 scale. It feels like,
Speaker 5:  like a 20 because a lot of you like, like it was, it was just like you
Speaker 3:  Put a movie year
Speaker 4:  20, 28, Netflix is gone. Yeah, but
Speaker 4:  movie, movie
Speaker 5:  Curse this because like, nobody knows about movie and movie's just
Speaker 3:  Like, yeah, they can't kill it. If you can't find it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's just, it's just like, it's just thriving over there in a corner.
Speaker 5:  Oh good. And periodically you're like, you know what, I'll turn on movie
Speaker 5:  and Netflix though. Everybody's gonna like flip on it. Yeah. Netflix has
Speaker 3:  Like public company like Reed's gotta get out there and explain its content.
Speaker 3:  Movies just like, I don't know, we just licensed Oscar winning independent
Speaker 3:  film.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they could do whatever
Speaker 3:  You want. Hard. I buy it. I buy it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Hulu on the other hand,
Speaker 5:  I chose a lot of 80 nines on this one. Huh? Yeah, because that's definitely
Speaker 5:  like an 89. Like it's, it doesn't have a lot of time left in this world.
Speaker 4:  Hulu might be the most 89 of
Speaker 5:  More than Paramount Plus.
Speaker 3:  No. Yeah. In no way.
Speaker 4:  Hulu is already actively dying. The person who owns Hulu has said he's guilty.
Speaker 4:  Well,
Speaker 3:  So saying like try to rank different 80 nines. That's
Speaker 3:  actually why you have other numbers.
Speaker 4:  I didn't give anything at 89. This is
Speaker 3:  A new problem. What is the most 89? It's like a question that has long been
Speaker 3:  solved by the
Speaker 5:  Existence of other. Paramount Plus is now an 87. Okay. And then we'll put
Speaker 5:  Hulu at
Speaker 4:  89. Okay. There I, I can.
Speaker 5:  And then TikTok is at eight.
Speaker 3:  TikTok is 89. Like that's straight up. 88. You think it's 88.
Speaker 5:  Which do you think is more likely to not be here at the end of the year?
Speaker 5:  Paramount Plus
Speaker 3:  Or TikTok might not be here at the end of the week.
Speaker 5:  That's fair.
Speaker 3:  We'll see. I mean maybe, probably Will. The
Speaker 5:  Teens are strong. The teens are strong. People love their TikTok.
Speaker 3:  They they do. And they will VPN into China immediately. The teens
Speaker 3:  get me on the other side of that firewall. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  A lot of people are learning about VPNs. So, I. I think it, I think it'll
Speaker 5:  persist. I'm putting it into 88.
Speaker 3:  All right. Again, what is the most, 89 is a baffling question.
Speaker 3:  I think TikTok is right now at this moment. Who knows what's gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think TikTok is 89. I think Paramount Plus is in 88. I think Hulu
Speaker 3:  is in 87. Okay. Hulu is famously un killable.
Speaker 3:  Like many, many, many people have tried to kill Hulu and they can't do it.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 5:  Would love if Bob was just like, couldn't do it. Just let it persist.
Speaker 3:  That's his next press conference. Somehow
Speaker 4:  Someone Don
Speaker 3:  Owns, I've been trying to kill this thing. He's like,
Speaker 5:  Hulu keeps going. We're gonna enjoy it.
Speaker 3:  I think, but I think they want to merge it into Disney. I think they want
Speaker 3:  that to be the brand. Like all this stuff. Yeah. It's gone on.
Speaker 3:  It's my my feeling. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Hulu is not going to be around for very long.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna be so wrong. Like it's gonna be Hulu and movie. I'm so excited
Speaker 3:  to next
Speaker 4:  Year and Netflix has just gone out of business and Alex is like I told you,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna be so vindicated. Plus is still around. Hulu is still around and
Speaker 5:  Netflix is gone.
Speaker 3:  Please watch my show on Netflix before.
Speaker 5:  Alright. You can watch it in a one minute Sections on Instagram reels.
Speaker 3:  Please watch The future up in one minute Increments on Instagram reels. That's
Speaker 3:  gonna go great for
Speaker 4:  Us. It's perfect. All right. That is the end of the Draft. Would you like
Speaker 4:  to read
Speaker 3:  That? The end of the Draft? Yeah. Yes,
Speaker 4:  Please. We've done it. Okay. Alex Cranz one first. Yes. And you picked
Speaker 4:  Peacock Movie slash Hulu. I'm actually gonna
Speaker 4:  give you both. Yes. I just feel like you should have both. Thank you. I
Speaker 5:  Appreciate
Speaker 4:  It. Fine. Netflix channels Crunchy Roll and
Speaker 4:  Paramount Plus,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna have a great time watching all of my content.
Speaker 4:  I think there's legitimate,
Speaker 3:  There was just a dismissive his laugh from over there. I just wanna be very
Speaker 3:  clear. I think there's, that didn't come through in
Speaker 4:  Election. Only two of yours still exist by the time we do this next NELI
Speaker 4:  and I picked TikTok, the Disney bundle. Nailed it. Sony Bravia
Speaker 4:  Co. Which is a real, real tank. YouTube TV with
Speaker 4:  Sunny Ticket MotorTrend tv. Yeah. And Max,
Speaker 3:  I just wanna point out, this is, you were
Speaker 4:  All over the place today.
Speaker 3:  This is breath, this is depth. This is Oscar winning MotorTrend
Speaker 3:  TV At this point, if they don't win an Oscar, what are you doing?
Speaker 3:  Everyone else has Moy. Yeah. Yeah. I would say the range here is
Speaker 3:  unparalleled. The quality is unparalleled. The 4K is available.
Speaker 3:  If, you can get off your at t plan. There's no fight in it. Is
Speaker 5:  Is, is MotorTrend tv in 4K?
Speaker 3:  No, no, no.
Speaker 4:  It's not
Speaker 3:  Just
Speaker 4:  360 p
Speaker 3:  Dave. That that is being shot on a GoPro from 1994. It's, that's
Speaker 3:  the, that's the situation.
Speaker 4:  I love it. David, what did you choose? I picked YouTube. Okay. With ads.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All the ads. Apple tv,
Speaker 4:  tuby, prime Video, criterion Collection and Instagram reels. Honestly,
Speaker 4:  that's fine. Which I'm still having a lot of feelings.
Speaker 5:  I think you won actually thinking about it. I'm like, no,
Speaker 3:  I'm sorry. You picked YouTube with ads and Instagram res and you're gonna
Speaker 3:  W
Speaker 4:  You picked Ravi Co and Mo.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  80
Speaker 3:  Mega.
Speaker 4:  You can't all have winners man.
Speaker 3:  Why do, why do you have a gigabit in Inter Connection? What
Speaker 4:  Was the new movie that just came to Bravia Chord? The
Speaker 3:  Anyone but you a movie, which does not contain any sequences of action
Speaker 3:  fast enough to require 80 megabits per second. Like that movie can be compressed
Speaker 3:  into a series of still frames.
Speaker 4:  Glen, how I'll taking your shirt off looking great.
Speaker 3:  Here's Glen Powell. Here's Glen Powell next to another Jack Guy. Like
Speaker 3:  just one frame at a time. It's barely, it's just a series of pictures going
Speaker 3:  by very quickly
Speaker 4:  That you could watch in one minute increments on TikTok and probably get
Speaker 4:  the vibe. Yeah. Oh,
Speaker 3:  Easily. And I'm confident that that will be like tiktoks entire content
Speaker 3:  strategy is a copyright infringement. Yeah. And also Chinese, these propaganda.
Speaker 3:  And you can just see, I, I maintain a list of tiktoks that I think should
Speaker 3:  be media studies, PhDs happy to share. And all of them
Speaker 3:  are just layers upon layers of copyright infringement.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's good stuff. Alright. That's it. Hey, David's like that's, that's
Speaker 4:  the Draft
Speaker 3:  We did. We won. Who won?
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. Let's, let's, let's
Speaker 3:  Declare yourself winner.
Speaker 4:  I have done it.
Speaker 5:  I him a winner. Two, two out
Speaker 3:  Three. We have an audience. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Okay. No, you're right. Who thinks NELI won the Draft? Yeah, that's correct.
Speaker 4:  It a brutal
Speaker 5:  One person did raise their hands.
Speaker 3:  That guy runs Bravia.
Speaker 4:  That was really nice of you. Yeah, that's
Speaker 3:  Steve. Sony right there
Speaker 4:  Thinks won the Draft Alex Cranz.
Speaker 5:  Look at that Crunchy Roll fans out there.
Speaker 4:  And who thinks I won the Draft
Speaker 3:  With YouTube with ads?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Gross. Yeah. I'm one of the, I'm one of the people You can you
Speaker 5:  Go to the bathroom doing the
Speaker 3:  Ads. We gotta end this. That's it. That's The Verge everybody. Thank you
Speaker 3:  all for coming here at South by Southwest. Tell the people in the cars that
Speaker 3:  you're here. Thank you for listening to our show. Send us your
Speaker 3:  own Draft orders. We'd love to hear from you. Dave and I have received
Speaker 3:  a number of emails from people showing us photos of decorative plates in
Speaker 3:  their homes. Yes. After an offhand dimension of a decorative plate that's
Speaker 3:  very confusing. But continue to send us your parents' silverware. Yes, please.
Speaker 3:  That's very good. And we'll be back next week. Yeah. That's every week for
Speaker 3:  the rest of our lives. We'll be talking about these issues. Yes. That's for
Speaker 3:  just rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One. The Verge Cast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 1:  Support for this show comes from Atlassian. What do you think of when you
Speaker 1:  hear the word flow? How about a smooth river of collaboration culminating
Speaker 1:  in a shared ocean of positive outcomes across your organization?
Speaker 1:  Atlassian software like Loom, confluence, and Jira can help you achieve maximum
Speaker 1:  flow across your teams by enabling fast and easy communication
Speaker 1:  and connection no matter what time zone you're in, because individually we
Speaker 1:  are great, but together we're so much better. Learn how to unlock flow across
Speaker 1:  your teams@atlassian.com. That's
Speaker 1:  A-T-L-A-S-S-I-A n.com. Atlassian.