# Transcript
ID: 6d376c5f-f1f2-46ee-bae8-059c0cec30ea
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8645463677328878416/-6184909495639193662/s93290-US-5653s-1711324053.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, Lauren Feiner and Nilay Patel discuss the breaking news about the the US Department of Justice accusing Apple of operating an illegal monopoly in the smartphone market in an expansive new antitrust lawsuit.
Speaker 3:  Welcome
Speaker 4:  To. The Vergecast. The flagship podcast of the performance smartphone market.
Speaker 4:  Neil, which means something.
Speaker 3:  It means Neil.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we're gonna spend the whole show figurine out what the performance
Speaker 4:  smartphone market is because that's what we do here on The Vergecast, I'm
Speaker 4:  your friend David Pierce. Alex Cranz is here. Hi Alex. I'm your
Speaker 5:  Friend who is so excited to talk about the news we've got today. Oh my
Speaker 4:  God. Pure unadulterated chaos. NELI Patel is not
Speaker 4:  here he is. I think last we heard in an airport
Speaker 4:  somewhere, somewhere Florida, maybe Florida. I don't know. NELI is gonna
Speaker 4:  come on the show in a little while because he could not possibly
Speaker 4:  ditch The Vergecast. But for now, Lauren Feiner here. Hi Lauren.
Speaker 6:  Hi.
Speaker 4:  You've had what I would call a couple of days. How are you holding up?
Speaker 6:  I truly have. I'm hanging in there. It's been busy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, I believe it. So we have a lot to talk about and almost
Speaker 4:  all of it is just about Apple. Huge antitrust lawsuit against
Speaker 4:  Apple. We're gonna talk about that, then we're gonna talk about that more.
Speaker 4:  And then we're gonna do a lighting round and not talk about antitrust law
Speaker 4:  for once. But let's just dive right in. There is lots to get to here and
Speaker 4:  I think the first thing we should try to do is just like explain this
Speaker 4:  messy, long, complicated complaint as well as we can.
Speaker 4:  So Lauren at the risk of totally setting you up to do something
Speaker 4:  impossible here. Just start at the beginning. What, what happened here today?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so this morning the DOJ and 16 state and District
Speaker 6:  attorney's general sued Apple for maintaining an illegal
Speaker 6:  monopoly in the smartphone market. So basically what they're saying here
Speaker 6:  is that Apple has basically made
Speaker 6:  consumers and developers more reliant on their ecosystem
Speaker 6:  through a series of actions. So they say they've done things like
Speaker 6:  disrupt super apps that could encompass a bunch of different
Speaker 6:  programs that would make the stickiness of iOS
Speaker 6:  less for consumers and developers or suppressing
Speaker 6:  the quality of messaging between iPhones and Androids,
Speaker 6:  you know, those infamous green bubbles. So there's all
Speaker 6:  sorts of things in this lawsuit that the DOJ is going after. And
Speaker 6:  basically just saying that Apple has
Speaker 6:  a abused its dominant position in the smartphone market.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I feel like I, I've been trying to think how I would summarize all
Speaker 4:  of this and there's a ton of details and I actually think one very useful
Speaker 4:  thing this suit did was sort of divide itself into five categories. And I
Speaker 4:  wanna talk about each of those five categories, but I feel like
Speaker 4:  in a lot of cases it's basically like you either
Speaker 4:  bought your way into a monopoly, which is allowed, not allowed,
Speaker 4:  or you have done some kind of shady stuff in order to
Speaker 4:  remain in a monopoly, which is also not allowed. This is neither of those
Speaker 4:  things. This
Speaker 5:  Is, this is basically like they took all of my complaints about
Speaker 5:  iOS and said, actually that's illegal.
Speaker 4:  I mean, kind of. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, I was reading it, I was like, yes, yes. You get it. I hate
Speaker 5:  the green bubbles. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I should off should
Speaker 5:  Be able to use a different watch. I was like, get it Cantor. I had
Speaker 5:  the best time reading it. I don't know if it's actually illegal, but I guess
Speaker 5:  that's why we have a court system, huh? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We're we're gonna get to that because I too have that question. But
Speaker 4:  I feel like Lauren, tell me what you think of this. This read that I've been
Speaker 4:  workshopping over the last few hours, which is that basically what the DOJ
Speaker 4:  is saying is that Apple has done a
Speaker 4:  series of things to keep competitors
Speaker 4:  and users from getting the most outta their iPhone
Speaker 4:  or the most out of all the experiences they have in the iPhone. And so what
Speaker 4:  consumers are getting is worse products for more money
Speaker 4:  that are harder to walk away from in any way, shape or form. and
Speaker 4:  that that is how Apple has abused its monopoly, that it is so powerful.
Speaker 4:  Not that it is explicitly doing something
Speaker 4:  nefarious to one of its competitors, but that it is just
Speaker 4:  making everything worse for everybody and that that shouldn't be
Speaker 4:  allowed. How far off am I?
Speaker 6:  That's essentially the argument. you know, they're basically saying, you
Speaker 6:  know, apple has through many different actions across
Speaker 6:  different areas, you just made it so that
Speaker 6:  it's just a little bit worse to
Speaker 6:  use its products or use someone else's products in combination.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, just making it so it's, there's more incentive to stay
Speaker 6:  on the Apple platforms than to try to
Speaker 6:  combine it with something else or move to something else,
Speaker 5:  Which is like by design. Like we talk about it all the time on the show.
Speaker 5:  Apple does all of this because it likes money.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's not illegal to like money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Apparently it is a little illegal.
Speaker 4:  Well and that's the, that's the like crazy mental gymnastics
Speaker 4:  of this suit to me. Which I think it's gonna be so interesting to see how
Speaker 4:  all of this goes. 'cause it's basically saying the iPhone
Speaker 4:  is bad. It's like a fundamental part of this argument. Or like
Speaker 4:  at least if it's not bad, it's not nearly as good as it could be. And
Speaker 4:  Apple is doing that on purpose. And the only reason Apple
Speaker 4:  would do that on purpose is to prevent people from leaving, which If you
Speaker 4:  think about it and just say it like that is bananas
Speaker 5:  It, but like,
Speaker 4:  But also it it like, it sort of holds and this is where we should probably
Speaker 4:  get into like each of the five things that that Apple
Speaker 4:  is being sort of accused of doing this to. And there's a much longer list
Speaker 4:  of, of like actual accusations here. But
Speaker 4:  the DOJ really boils it down to five things. And I'm just gonna read the
Speaker 4:  five things. So it's basically super apps, which Lauren you mentioned
Speaker 4:  cloud streaming services by which it mostly means game streaming services.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Messaging apps, smartwatches and digital wallets.
Speaker 4:  What a fivesome.
Speaker 4:  But let's, let's just do these one at a time and I think we should basically
Speaker 4:  do it in the order in which the suit does it. And Alex, you and I
Speaker 4:  have been talking about the super apps thing all day. Yeah. So explain the
Speaker 4:  case for the super apps here.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so they are saying that super apps, which are super, super popular
Speaker 5:  in Asia to the point that Apple, they have like notes
Speaker 5:  from Apple being like, yeah those are super popular in Asia. That would be
Speaker 5:  super bad if they got super popular here in the United States.
Speaker 4:  And by super apps it's like, I mean WeChat ca like canonical
Speaker 5:  Example, right? Yeah. WeChat, cacao talk a lot. Like most
Speaker 5:  countries in Asia have some sort of app that like you can do just everything
Speaker 5:  in and, and we don't have that, we have iOS right at Android here
Speaker 5:  and, and so they're saying that these apps have been consistently like
Speaker 5:  kind of deprioritized and made worse on iOS and
Speaker 5:  they go through a lot of it. And it's kind of true, like
Speaker 5:  we don't know quite if people don't like super apps in the United States
Speaker 5:  because we just don't like Super apps or if it's because the experience is
Speaker 5:  kind of crummy on iOS and we all use iOS, well not all,
Speaker 5:  but a big chunk of us, 60 something percent of the market I think is
Speaker 5:  what the DOJ said.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And, and they, they kept saying things like 75% of new phones are
Speaker 4:  bought are our iPhones and even that probably underrepresents the
Speaker 4:  monopoly number and it's like, well then tell me what the monopoly number
Speaker 4:  is. But anyway, I digress. Lauren, I'm really curious what your read
Speaker 4:  on this one was to me because I think the other four here are
Speaker 4:  things we've heard everybody yell at Apple about for a
Speaker 4:  very long time, right? Like it was pretty obvious this was gonna be about
Speaker 4:  game streaming. It was pretty obvious this was gonna be me messaging apps,
Speaker 4:  smart watches was a little bit of a right turn, but so was digital
Speaker 4:  wallets. But we can come back to this super apps. I would not, in a million
Speaker 4:  years If, you had been like, David, what are the 50 things in this lawsuit
Speaker 4:  gonna be about? I would not have picked super apps. What what's your
Speaker 4:  read on all this?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that was surprising to me too. I think it just seems to fit
Speaker 6:  this general theme that the DOJ is going after that
Speaker 6:  super apps that basically they're saying that
Speaker 6:  Apple is trying to lock down its ecosystem
Speaker 6:  so that you know, developers can only do so much and you know, you
Speaker 6:  can't interoperate to a great degree and they don't wanna do things
Speaker 6:  that will take away from Apple's
Speaker 6:  own services and its own ecosystem. That that this
Speaker 6:  is how the DOJ is characterizing it. So I think it just fits the theme.
Speaker 6:  And so that's something that they decided to go with. I think
Speaker 6:  it, it is kind of surprising given given that, you know, we don't really
Speaker 6:  see a lot of super apps here in the US so it's kind of
Speaker 6:  like, is that a chicken or the egg problem? Is it, would we have more super
Speaker 6:  apps if Apple was open to them or are they just not that popular
Speaker 6:  here for other reasons?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I've spent a decade talking to people about that question and over
Speaker 4:  and over, the answer from people has been, well we just don't want it in
Speaker 4:  the us. But I do think it's true that it is also,
Speaker 4:  we've never really tested the theory in the US like WeChat is on the
Speaker 4:  app store, which I suspect Apple will be happily reminding lots and lots
Speaker 4:  of people of in the very near future. But it's not the same app. No,
Speaker 4:  and like the thing about WeChat is that like ESP
Speaker 4:  in a place like China and I have not lived in China. So, I can't
Speaker 4:  say this for sure, but I've heard that this is true. Is that like WeChat
Speaker 4:  is more important than your phone, right? Yeah. Like WeChat is the
Speaker 4:  thing and as long as it's there, you're good. Like the
Speaker 4:  hardware doesn't matter as much. So on the one hand A that has made China's
Speaker 4:  smartphone market like incredibly cool and competitive because all you
Speaker 4:  need is something that runs WeChat. So they all have to compete on something
Speaker 4:  else. So they build all this wacky hardware. There are a million different
Speaker 4:  brands out there doing stuff. They were early on Foldables, they were early
Speaker 4:  on flip phones, they were early on big new F phones. Like
Speaker 4:  the China market is thriving kind of as hardware in part because
Speaker 4:  WeChat is the thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is kind of proving the point that the DOJ makes, which is that
Speaker 5:  we can't do all the cool stuff here because Apple is standing in the way
Speaker 5:  of it. And that's,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, that always feels true to me that that that that has felt like
Speaker 5:  a complaint. We're all like, yeah, I really want a folding phone. Well I'm
Speaker 5:  gonna wait until Apple Banks one.
Speaker 4:  No, I I think that's totally fair. Also, have you ever used WeChat?
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 4:  That app is a nightmare. Yeah, it's, it's just, and this is, this is
Speaker 4:  kind of what we're talking about. Like it's either a cultural difference
Speaker 4:  and there are a lot of people who make the case that it is a cultural difference
Speaker 4:  that in the US we like, we like cleaner, simpler,
Speaker 4:  more sort of straightforward and siloed off software. That is, that is, I
Speaker 4:  don't know how you prove that, but that is a thing you say, I
Speaker 5:  Mean Apple
Speaker 4:  Like that and has been true for a long time, right? Yeah. Whereas in
Speaker 4:  China, the idea of having every
Speaker 4:  possible thing that exists in the world just sort of shoved in one
Speaker 4:  place works. That's just what folks are used to and
Speaker 4:  yeah, like the counterfactual of like if it were just as easy to do in the
Speaker 4:  us would we have it? We'll never know. But I do agree with you that like
Speaker 4:  there is something in that logic that holds that If, you make the app
Speaker 4:  then the app has all kinds of fascinating antitrust things and would probably
Speaker 4:  be getting sued for the same thing. But at least like if If you wanna make
Speaker 4:  the case that that is what is keeping the hardware market from thriving China
Speaker 4:  seems like it would prove that case. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I, I think like what we see again and again in this complaint from
Speaker 5:  the US government is that they feel the united,
Speaker 5:  they feel Apple has become dominant. Apple dominates the market in the
Speaker 5:  United States specifically. Right. and that has totally warped how we
Speaker 5:  use different apps. and that is like just straight up true.
Speaker 5:  Right? Every single time we write a story about a green bubble, some of our
Speaker 5:  international colleagues are like, why are you writing about Green Bubbles?
Speaker 5:  Do you know WhatsApp exists? And it's like, for sure. Yeah. And we don't
Speaker 5:  use it because we use iMessage because it is the dominant platform in the
Speaker 5:  United States because Apple is the dominant smartphone maker in the United
Speaker 5:  States.
Speaker 4:  I see. But then If you like rewind back further.
Speaker 4:  We adopted things earlier in the United States. So what we
Speaker 4:  actually did was we got hooked on SMS and, and WhatsApp came
Speaker 4:  up because SMS was really expensive in places where people couldn't
Speaker 4:  afford sms and in the US, by and large we could. And so
Speaker 4:  we just, we got hooked on SMS and then WhatsApp like end rounded it. And
Speaker 4:  the thing that iMessage did that was so smart was built on top of it, right?
Speaker 4:  Which is also in the same antitrust suit.
Speaker 4:  But Lauren, the thing I kept thinking about was I expected this first thing
Speaker 4:  that's actually about super apps to be about web apps. And, and this is the
Speaker 4:  thing we've been hearing a lot of is that like there's been this big fight
Speaker 4:  over the PWAs progressive web apps and this idea that like actually what
Speaker 4:  Apple is doing is systematically making the web worse. And this has been
Speaker 4:  a big part of the fight in the EU over how to make sort of these
Speaker 4:  cross platform web apps work better on the iPhone. Whether Apple
Speaker 4:  allows it or not. There wasn't really that much of
Speaker 4:  like the web in this complaint. Was that
Speaker 4:  as surprising to either of you as it was to me that I shocked me. Honestly,
Speaker 6:  I guess it's because they're focusing on this, you know, iPhone mobile device
Speaker 6:  ecosystem and it, it seems like everything is really focused on,
Speaker 6:  you know, how they've been able to advance this iPhone
Speaker 6:  platform to, you know, maintain their monopoly.
Speaker 5:  They do talk about web apps in this and what was interesting was they were
Speaker 5:  like, basically we considered web apps that is part of this, but that's already
Speaker 5:  part of the monopoly because it all has to be built on like
Speaker 5:  it's part of the bigger complaint, which is that Apple forces people to do
Speaker 5:  things in the Apple way, thus limiting development. Limiting
Speaker 5:  limiting
Speaker 5:  progress, right?
Speaker 4:  It's in sort of a tangential way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it's like tangential, but it's like, well you have to use WebKit
Speaker 5:  to do anything on an iPhone, right? So you are, you like,
Speaker 5:  you're stuck in it. We can't even talk about web apps because
Speaker 5:  WebKit exists is kind of like how they, they treat it.
Speaker 4:  My theory is also that whoever wrote and filed
Speaker 4:  this lawsuit decided that trying to explain the concept of
Speaker 4:  PWAs and browser engines Nope. And all of this was just like not
Speaker 4:  worth the hassle. Whereas you can just say super app out loud and people
Speaker 4:  like sort of understand what it is. Yeah. Where you're like the, the progressive
Speaker 4:  web app on my phone doesn't have access to the local C like everybody just
Speaker 4:  falls asleep. So they
Speaker 5:  Specifically say that's my right theory. They specifically say in it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Nobody knows how to use web apps on iOS because it's really complex and
Speaker 5:  weird and hard and I was like that. That's all. Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 4:  Do you even know how to find the ad to home screen button? Like no, no one
Speaker 4:  knows
Speaker 5:  Sometimes
Speaker 6:  I think you really can't underestimate how much the DOJ is going to have
Speaker 6:  to like really simplify this when they get to court.
Speaker 6:  Because having gone to the DOJ Google trial,
Speaker 6:  you know, there's a lot, you know, the judge at times would be like,
Speaker 6:  you know, what are these things? And sometimes they're simple
Speaker 6:  things, sometimes they're complicated terms, but these are judges
Speaker 6:  that, you know, for one thing aren't usually taking antitrust
Speaker 6:  cases a lot of the time, especially not anti-monopoly cases. And second
Speaker 6:  of all, definitely don't know the ins and outs of such
Speaker 6:  a technical ecosystem. So, you know, I think there is
Speaker 6:  something to like, wanting to have a simple story to tell.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And speaking of that, I think the, the next thing on the list, the
Speaker 4:  second one in the five was the game streaming services, which is another
Speaker 4:  one that I think is like a, a sort of viscerally understandable
Speaker 4:  thing. Like why can't I play Fortnite on my iPhone is actually like a
Speaker 4:  sort of universally understood question at this point. Alex, do you wanna
Speaker 4:  explain that one?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So back in 2019 everybody said cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  is gonna be a thing and Apple said not on my watch.
Speaker 5:  And like that's, that's really what happened. Everybody was rolling it out,
Speaker 5:  it worked. You could get these apps on an Android and Apple was like, no,
Speaker 5:  we're not gonna put that on on our stuff. I remember talking to Google
Speaker 5:  and Microsoft and, and Nvidia at the time being like, do you guys wanna
Speaker 5:  give a comment on, on, on this? And then Epic sued Apple
Speaker 5:  saying, you know, you're, it was all related, right? Every, all of this was,
Speaker 5:  was related and Apple kind of like, would walk it back very occasionally
Speaker 5:  they'd be like, okay, well you can have cloud gaming, but it can only be
Speaker 5:  on those web apps that nobody knows how to use and that's,
Speaker 5:  that's one way you can do it or you can put it on the store, but we have
Speaker 5:  to approve every single game. And like no one
Speaker 5:  was gonna do that. If you've got 200 games, you have to get all 200 games
Speaker 5:  approved. If you've got three games, you have to get 'em all. Like, nobody
Speaker 5:  wants to do that. Right? You, you have to get every update approved. And
Speaker 5:  so it was really, really onerous and it really, it wasn't
Speaker 5:  the only reason Cloud gaming has not become just the, the
Speaker 5:  the new hot thing and everybody doesn't care about the PS five.
Speaker 4:  But it didn't help. It did
Speaker 5:  Not help. Yeah. It, it really hurt. It really hurt things and like, well,
Speaker 5:  and
Speaker 4:  I actually, I really liked this one in particular because I felt like that
Speaker 4:  was where the DOJ did the best job of explaining just like what a
Speaker 4:  gigantic pain in the ass Apple inflicts upon its
Speaker 4:  developers who wanna make things for iOS where it was basically like you,
Speaker 4:  like you said, you have to go through, you have to get every single game
Speaker 4:  approved. You have to run each one of them differently. These games get updated
Speaker 4:  constantly. Most of them are like service games that are just
Speaker 4:  running all the time. These live services games are everywhere now you
Speaker 4:  have to get every single update approved through this like opaque,
Speaker 4:  occasionally nonsensical Apple review process. Or
Speaker 4:  you have to like carve out a completely different game for
Speaker 4:  Apple and run everything over there elsewhere and then have a specific game
Speaker 4:  for the iPhone that it was just like, and this was kind of the point that
Speaker 4:  they're continuing to make is it doesn't necessarily matter whether
Speaker 4:  it's possible, but it is such a gigantic hassle
Speaker 4:  and pain and awful process for everyone involved that
Speaker 4:  no reasonable developer can be asked to do it. Yeah. And this is again where
Speaker 4:  I feel like we're in this weird sort of legal juujitsu thing that the DOJ
Speaker 4:  is trying to do, where it's like, if Apple had just
Speaker 4:  kept going to Epic and saying never game streaming on the app
Speaker 4:  store ever, that's a thing you can
Speaker 4:  poke at, right? Like that is a fight that you can actually pick in this way.
Speaker 4:  But what it's actually saying is like, okay, sure, good
Speaker 4:  luck assholes. Like, and that's, that's so much the vibe of like
Speaker 4:  a lot of what happens in the app store and we've all heard from developers
Speaker 4:  over the years who go through this awful process. Your app gets banned for
Speaker 4:  reasons you don't understand. Updates don't get approved for days or weeks
Speaker 4:  or months or ever. And so much of this just boils
Speaker 4:  down to this thing where like Apple is running its whole process
Speaker 4:  in such an awful way that it can't possibly be doing it for
Speaker 4:  anyone's benefit. It must be monopoly maintenance,
Speaker 4:  which is like, I don't know, slightly hard for me to wrap my head around,
Speaker 4:  but it it feels true in a certain way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It passes the stiff test
Speaker 4:  It does. I agree with that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like, like it it, it has a big whiff and we, we talked about this a
Speaker 5:  lot in the past few weeks because of what's going on in Europe where they're
Speaker 5:  like, oh yeah, yeah, we're gonna, we're gonna do what you ask in the most
Speaker 5:  obnoxious way possible and just, just make it as
Speaker 5:  painful as possible. You will hate yourself for it and you're probably not
Speaker 5:  gonna do it. And the government's like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  stop. Well,
Speaker 4:  And that's what we've heard from all the developers in the eu, right? Like
Speaker 4:  all the browser makers we're like, oh, that's so nice of you. We can use
Speaker 4:  our own rendering engine, but now we have to build two versions of our app
Speaker 4:  inside one version of our app that just sort of automatically selects like,
Speaker 4:  no, we're not doing that. And they've all, they've all basically been like,
Speaker 4:  no, this is actually worse than it was before. Yep. You've made our lives
Speaker 4:  harder in the name of pretending to make it easier. and that
Speaker 4:  feels like if I were to boil all of these accusations down, it
Speaker 4:  would be that Yeah. That Apple, apple keeps claiming it's trying to do good
Speaker 4:  things for its users and all it does is make everything worse for everybody.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Lauren how do you feel few times?
Speaker 6:  I think this one is interesting 'cause it, I think If, you look at the streaming
Speaker 6:  games claims, it kind of helps you understand the super apps claims in a
Speaker 6:  way because, you know, If you think about it like the way that David, you
Speaker 6:  were saying WeChat in China is like more important
Speaker 6:  than the phone itself. you know, the DOJ is saying here,
Speaker 6:  like Apple looked at cloud gaming and was like,
Speaker 6:  oh, if that is the North Star then the hardware
Speaker 6:  doesn't matter as much and we can't have the hardware not matter,
Speaker 6:  right? Because we want to make superior hardware and we want
Speaker 6:  that to be valuable to people. So I think that seems to be
Speaker 6:  like the theme that I'm seeing between those two claims
Speaker 4:  That strikes me as way less compelling than the super app example. Like I,
Speaker 4:  I do think in theory the super app thing holds, and again, like in China
Speaker 4:  it seems to be real. I just don't think there are that many people
Speaker 4:  out there who are like, if I can't play my two games,
Speaker 4:  I'm switching phone operating systems. No, I, maybe I'm wrong. I don't
Speaker 4:  think that was the argument. And maybe there's a whole generation of kids
Speaker 4:  who are like growing up on Roblox and Roblox will be more important to them
Speaker 4:  than what phone they use. I don't know. But for right now, like it it does
Speaker 4:  seem like, yeah, like, like you're saying Lauren If, you go through the argument,
Speaker 4:  it's like, okay, if I can play cloud games, I all of a sudden realize, oh,
Speaker 4:  I can play cloud cloud games anywhere, I'm gonna switch phones.
Speaker 4:  I just, is that how that works? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  See this is where David, you're your gadget love
Speaker 5:  is, is shining through. Okay. And, and like Lauren, are you a giant
Speaker 5:  gadget nerd? It's okay if you're not,
Speaker 6:  I'm not the biggest gat nerd, but I like some gadgets. Okay,
Speaker 4:  Well that's Lauren Feiner everybody. I'm sorry you never be on the first
Speaker 4:  cast again.
Speaker 5:  No, but I think, I think this is a great moment for Lauren because David
Speaker 5:  and I we're gadget nerds. We know what the processor
Speaker 5:  is called in the iPhone and we care a lot about that and we care about that
Speaker 5:  speed and we care about that performance and the stuff outside of the apps.
Speaker 5:  Lauren, if If, you didn't have to like If, you could just get the cheapest
Speaker 5:  phone and would do all the stuff you needed it to do because it was all based
Speaker 5:  in the cloud. Would you save, would you not spend
Speaker 5:  $1,600 on a new phone?
Speaker 6:  Probably.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And a lot of people are that way and not like us and probably
Speaker 5:  most of our listeners are probably like Lauren. How dare you And guys I know,
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. There's a lot, there's a lot of people around you who are just
Speaker 5:  like Lauren, many of your friends and family are probably like Lauren.
Speaker 5:  It's hard to understand. I'm, I'm working to process it as well. Please
Speaker 4:  Send all gadget recommendations to Lauren dot he@thebirch.com. She'd love
Speaker 4:  to hear from you. The more expensive, the better. No, I think, I think you're
Speaker 4:  right as a whole, yeah, right. Like on that theory, like I think about this
Speaker 4:  with like Chrome os, right? What Chrome OS proved is that
Speaker 4:  most people want the cheapest thing that kind of works. And this
Speaker 4:  has become a huge problem for Google because they can't sell you good things
Speaker 4:  that make money because all anybody wants is the cheapest thing that kind
Speaker 4:  of works. Yep. I think that's also true to an extent with a
Speaker 4:  lot of smart phones. And I think, I mean it, it's, it's surely not an accident
Speaker 4:  that Apple has not sold $400 phones because I think a lot of people would
Speaker 4:  buy them and that's actually pretty bad for business if you're Apple, right?
Speaker 4:  Like that's
Speaker 5:  You have a 30% markup on a phone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Granted, I'm just saying I don't think games are that thing. I think the
Speaker 4:  idea if I could have an exact, like an equivalent smartphone experience,
Speaker 4:  and to be fair, I think like if, again, a lot of this argument from
Speaker 4:  the DOJ adds up to what you're saying, like, I should be able to have an
Speaker 4:  equivalent smartphone experience anywhere and Apple is preventing me from
Speaker 4:  that. And if I could, a lot of people would leave the iPhone. I think that's
Speaker 4:  true and I think it's, it's gonna be really interesting to see to what extent
Speaker 4:  we actually get to see that bear out. Yeah. I'm just saying I don't think
Speaker 4:  games are that thing.
Speaker 5:  I would agree with that. Totally. And I say that as a gamer who used
Speaker 5:  every single one of those cloudy gaming services. Did you know Luna? Still
Speaker 5:  around? Oh,
Speaker 4:  Luna.
Speaker 5:  I remember Luna. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Is better at having products you forgot about but are still just kicking
Speaker 4:  than Amazon. Yeah, Google
Speaker 5:  Kills them. And the ones you like, Amazon leaves the ones you've never heard
Speaker 5:  of Alive for
Speaker 4:  20. Yeah. Amazon just puts it like further down in the menu system on amazon.com
Speaker 4:  and that's, that's all that happens to them. All right, we should go to the
Speaker 4:  next one, which is messaging apps. Lauren, do you wanna explain this one?
Speaker 4:  This one feels like the most like mainstream
Speaker 4:  relevant of the five. Do you wanna explain what's going on here? Totally,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This is one that I think everyone is gonna be like, oh yeah, I've been
Speaker 6:  complaining about this for years. Which is that, you know,
Speaker 6:  it's basically the green bubble problem that when you are
Speaker 6:  messaging someone from an iPhone to an Android, you're seeing a
Speaker 6:  green bubble on your screen instead of blue. And so
Speaker 6:  basically the DOJ is saying like, this is very intentional
Speaker 6:  and this is really just another way to lock users
Speaker 6:  into the iPhone iOS ecosystem.
Speaker 6:  and that it's not just that it's like annoying, it's also that
Speaker 6:  there's just worse functionality when you're doing these, this
Speaker 6:  messaging between iPhone and Android. And they even
Speaker 6:  reference Tim Cook's comment of Buy your Mom
Speaker 6:  an iPhone where he told someone, you know,
Speaker 6:  oh, someone was complaining at a conference that,
Speaker 6:  you know, his mom, when he's texting with his mom, he
Speaker 6:  is getting green texts and they said, he just said, buy your mom
Speaker 6:  an iPhone. That was the, that was the solution.
Speaker 4:  My hottest take about all of this is that I think that sentence is
Speaker 4:  going to come back to haunt Tim Cook. Like I, I think that sentence will
Speaker 4:  haunt Tim Cook maybe for the rest of his career.
Speaker 5:  I like when that happened when we, because it was at code 2022
Speaker 5:  and it was Tim Cook, it was Joni Ives, it was Lauren Powell
Speaker 5:  jobs. They were all hanging out with Kara Swisher was, was her last one.
Speaker 5:  And, and this guy gets up and is like, I can't text my mom. And
Speaker 5:  just, there's like a level of almost, I think we, we talked about it on the
Speaker 5:  show after that. He came off a little smug and
Speaker 5:  yeah, the DOJ noticed.
Speaker 4:  I mean, it was a funny line at the time. It was very funny. Like, I think
Speaker 4:  it it, but it was like Ooh, it played very well in the room if I remember
Speaker 4:  correctly. But I think like the, I I was rereading
Speaker 4:  a bunch of stuff from the Microsoft antitrust trial from whatever, 25 years
Speaker 4:  ago. And there was this thing that a Microsoft executive said, I think in
Speaker 4:  an email, I could be wrong, but very early on, said something to the effect
Speaker 4:  of we have to cut off Netscapes air supply. and that
Speaker 4:  phrase became like the mantra of the case that
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is this nefarious company out to destroy anyone who would possibly
Speaker 4:  compete with it and is just going to squeeze everyone to death, I think
Speaker 4:  by your mom and iPhone is going to do that. Not
Speaker 5:  Barbarians at the gate.
Speaker 4:  No, that's like slightly too esoteric, I think, which is, it's like a cool
Speaker 4:  line. We should, I, I, I wrote that line down, we should read it. But
Speaker 5:  That, that line came when they were talking about the super apps and apparently
Speaker 5:  an Apple exec was like, we can't let the super apps in the United States
Speaker 5:  and onto our platforms. It would be like the barbarian.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So this is from the, the complaint. It says as, as one apple manager
Speaker 4:  put it, allowing super apps to become the main gateway where people play
Speaker 4:  games, book a car, make payments, et cetera, would quote let the barbarians
Speaker 4:  in at the gate. Why? Because when a super app offers popular mini programs,
Speaker 4:  iOS stickiness goes down like lesson number one, everybody
Speaker 4:  don't send emails. But anyway,
Speaker 5:  That's the first lesson.
Speaker 4:  Just send emails to Lauren dot Feiner at the virgin.com with all of your
Speaker 4:  gadget recommendations.
Speaker 5:  Only emails allowed.
Speaker 4:  But no, I I think the messaging apps one I thought was
Speaker 4:  both, again, like you're saying Lauren the most sort of understandable to
Speaker 4:  the most people, but also maybe the most compelling if
Speaker 4:  your argument is that Apple is willfully making its products worse to make
Speaker 4:  it harder to leave. Like we talked about Beeper a ton on this show earlier
Speaker 4:  this year, right. And the case Beeper, so
Speaker 5:  Did the DOJ.
Speaker 4:  So did the DOJ. Yeah, it was, it was in the complaint, like there were a
Speaker 4:  few companies that were very clearly being talked about but didn't get named.
Speaker 4:  Beeper was one of them. There's a section about, you know, a company promising
Speaker 4:  to make the security of the iPhone better for everybody. There was
Speaker 4:  also one about like a company that canceled a smartwatch and it's just like
Speaker 4:  obviously Meta. But anyway, the, the Beeper
Speaker 4:  story was essentially they went around all of Apple's
Speaker 4:  systems in order to make your green bubbles blue. Even If you, you're on
Speaker 4:  an Android phone, apple said no, it was the whole thing. Everybody listening
Speaker 4:  to the show I'm sure knows, but what Bieber kept saying
Speaker 4:  is we are making text messaging more secure for
Speaker 4:  iPhone users because now instead of using SMS, which is
Speaker 4:  awful technology, bad user experience and fundamentally
Speaker 4:  insecure all of those things, undeniably true. Like if you've ever sent a
Speaker 4:  video over SMS, it sucks and it should not be allowed. and
Speaker 4:  that was the case they kept making and Apple basically shut it off because,
Speaker 4:  because they're like, well we're Apple, we can, and so the DOJ is coming
Speaker 4:  and saying, no, the fact that you are willingly and obviously
Speaker 4:  making your product worse, not just for other people but for your users
Speaker 4:  is pretty strong proof that you are not just doing
Speaker 4:  things with your customers in mind. Yeah. That If you were, what you
Speaker 4:  would've given them is either access to more messaging
Speaker 4:  tools and competition and let other apps like WhatsApp and whoever else
Speaker 4:  access SMS, which is one of the things that this argues should be allowed
Speaker 4:  or you have to actually give your
Speaker 4:  customers the best product available to them. And they have, I mean there's
Speaker 4:  like this, the famous email from Tim Cook now shooting down the idea of putting
Speaker 4:  iMessage on Android because the, his argument was that it would be worse
Speaker 4:  for Apple than it would be good to, you know, have this platform set, which
Speaker 4:  is again, like you just cannot make the argument that that is good for users.
Speaker 4:  You just can't. So you come back from it and say this is purely
Speaker 4:  monopoly maintenance to use their term.
Speaker 4:  I think this is going to end up being the one we talk about a lot in the
Speaker 4:  course of this trial. Personally.
Speaker 5:  I I, yeah, it's the most indefensible, apple has never been able to
Speaker 5:  adequately defend this and they try all the time, right? And every single
Speaker 5:  time, no, I don't think anyone believes them. I, I
Speaker 5:  like, I would struggle to think of someone who's like, yeah, apple has totally
Speaker 5:  got it right? I am totally fine with garbage green bubbles and if
Speaker 5:  I don't like it, I can go use WhatsApp. Well,
Speaker 4:  The argument against it is that Apple doesn't have to, right? Like it's Apple's
Speaker 4:  platform. Apple can do what it wants. And, and the, and this is like what
Speaker 4:  the DOJ is saying is though, like, no, actually that's not how this works
Speaker 4:  and we're gonna prove it in court. And I assume all of apple's
Speaker 4:  extremely well-paid lawyers are like, bring it on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. The people really winning in this case are, are the lawyers.
Speaker 4:  Oh, as
Speaker 5:  Always. A lot of billable hours as their
Speaker 4:  Way as always. It's gonna be great. Alright, let's blow through these last
Speaker 4:  two and then we, we need to take a break because this is going to be a
Speaker 4:  19 hour long forecast. Alex, you wanna explain the smartwatches one? That's
Speaker 4:  the next one, Luis.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Smartwatches. This
Speaker 4:  One feels easy actually. This one is very easy in terms of like what the
Speaker 4:  problem is. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The, the, the problem is If, you wanna have a good smartwatch experience
Speaker 5:  on iOS, you have to have an Apple watch. There's nothing else,
Speaker 5:  nothing else competes and If, you want a good
Speaker 5:  smartwatch experience on Android, you would probably want an an
Speaker 5:  Apple watch because it is in fact the best smartwatch right now. And you
Speaker 5:  can't do that either because it's gonna be a garbage experience on Android.
Speaker 5:  And it's just that I thought you
Speaker 4:  Were about to say you'd found some way to hack a on Apple watch onto Android
Speaker 4:  and I was like, let's talk about that for a while.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, that's, that's, that's sad. That's next episode. But, but yeah,
Speaker 5:  it, it is very straightforward. It's a crummy experience and
Speaker 5:  I would've loved if they'd also brought in Bluetooth headphones here because
Speaker 5:  I got a lot, lot of feelings.
Speaker 4:  So I mean did explicitly mentioned that Bluetooth is bad, which I very much
Speaker 4:  appreciated. That was, it was like, If, you wanna use a non-Apple smartwatch,
Speaker 4:  you have to use Bluetooth. And it's, and just sort of leaves unsaid that
Speaker 4:  like, well that's a real bummer,
Speaker 4:  but I, I appreciated that and it was, yeah, I mean it was little things that
Speaker 4:  they brought up, like quick responses to messages, which came up like
Speaker 4:  enough times in this complaint that I feel like someone at the DOJ has like
Speaker 4:  a personal issue with not being able to send quick response from
Speaker 5:  Someone. Someone was using a pixel watch with their iPhone and they are
Speaker 5:  pissed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, right. Like there's some, some like deputy ag somewhere who's like,
Speaker 4:  I just wanna send my text messages, what hell Apple? Like, it was very strange.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, I mean that, that's essentially the crux of it, right? Lauren that
Speaker 4:  it's like If, you want a good Apple experience,
Speaker 4:  you have to buy an Apple watch, which again, once you bought an Apple Watch
Speaker 4:  brings you even further into the iPhone ecosystem,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. It just goes back to Apple wanting you to
Speaker 6:  just use Apple products and making it just de
Speaker 6:  disincentivizing you, like mixing and matching
Speaker 6:  between Apple products and other products or just switching all together.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which is I think a very funny way of looking
Speaker 4:  at exactly the same thing that Apple has always said, right? Like
Speaker 4:  Apple on its face shouldn't disagree with any of this,
Speaker 4:  right? Like for Apple to say like, oh yeah, the Apple watch is better If,
Speaker 4:  you also have an iPhone. Like Apple's been making commercials about that
Speaker 4:  for decades. That's the whole pitch is that like we integrate
Speaker 4:  the hardware to the software and the services so that it's better apple's.
Speaker 4:  Like yeah, that's the point. And now the DOJ is saying, you know,
Speaker 4:  actually what you're doing is you're not making it better when those things
Speaker 4:  are together, you're just making everything else worse. And again, this is
Speaker 4:  where I come back to like, I'm not a lawyer, so don't take any of this
Speaker 4:  seriously, but I, it seems to me that that is a much harder
Speaker 4:  like argument to pull and a like a string to pull on over the course
Speaker 4:  of a trial.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's just a, it's a, it's a major philosophical difference and it,
Speaker 5:  I it sounds like, I mean, Lauren correct me if I'm wrong, but this is gonna
Speaker 5:  be down to the judge to decide like who's right because both are right. And,
Speaker 5:  and in the cases of vertical integration, vertical integration always makes
Speaker 5:  things much more smooth and, and, and, and
Speaker 5:  seamless. It also makes things much more difficult. If you wanna change and,
Speaker 5:  and we can see that in the healthcare industry. We can see it in a lot of
Speaker 5:  industries where they say, yeah, we vertically integrated everything. And
Speaker 5:  repeatedly they've been like, actually you ver you did too much.
Speaker 5:  There's like, there's some, and, and we don't know what that line is, but
Speaker 5:  it feels like the courts eventually find it. Is that right? Lauren?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's basically right. I mean, I think the judge is gonna have to
Speaker 6:  weigh like, was there a legitimate business reason that Apple did these things?
Speaker 6:  Or you know,
Speaker 6:  or like, is the effect of these things taken
Speaker 6:  together because of its dominant position in the market?
Speaker 6:  Is it too much? And you know, does it fall into the category of
Speaker 6:  becoming a legal monopolistic behavior?
Speaker 5:  And that's kind of the key difference here, between like
Speaker 5:  2000 when you could only use an iPod on an Apple
Speaker 5:  device. That was because it was fine then because Apple didn't have
Speaker 5:  a huge section of the market for laptops. It didn't have
Speaker 5:  a huge section of any markets really. And so it was like, okay, cool, you're,
Speaker 5:  you're, you're making new things, you're innovating and now the difference
Speaker 5:  is that now Apple is huge. Is that right?
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right. And that's why you see Apple saying
Speaker 6:  that they don't think that the US smartphone market is the relevant market.
Speaker 6:  It's really the global smartphone market. And that's really like the
Speaker 6:  go-to response in pretty much ev any monopoly
Speaker 6:  lawsuit is to say like, this is the wrong market. Look at this much bigger
Speaker 6:  market where we're just like a speck on the map.
Speaker 4:  Does Apple know that the United States Department of Justice is not like
Speaker 4:  a global organization? Is that No, I believe
Speaker 6:  They're probably aware. Okay,
Speaker 4:  Cool. Just checking in case you're not, Tim, I know you're listening. Just
Speaker 4:  Ffy. I that's how that works. All right, one more and then we should take
Speaker 4:  a break. Alex you, you explained this one because you've been sitting at
Speaker 4:  your desk just like muttering about banks all day. Yeah. So explain the digital
Speaker 4:  wallets one. This
Speaker 5:  One Lauren agree. Like, correct me if I'm wrong, this one was the most surprising
Speaker 5:  one for me. That, that it popped up here and then the more I read about it
Speaker 5:  I was like, oh, someone at the banks was in the, the Attorney
Speaker 5:  General's ear being like,
Speaker 4:  Do either of you ever spend any time thinking about your digital wallet?
Speaker 4:  No. Like I feel like on the list of like things I care about on my phone,
Speaker 4:  I would rank digital wallets so low.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and I I I would chase feel that way or
Speaker 5:  some of the other large banks, I don't know. I I think they feel
Speaker 5:  differently. And, and, and that's what that was like
Speaker 5:  me reading between the lines on this part of the complaint and the complaint
Speaker 5:  is that digital wallets, you can really can't use any other digital wallet
Speaker 5:  on Apple devices because of how the NFC chip works and how their
Speaker 5:  APIs work. Nothing else works on it. So you have to partner
Speaker 5:  with Apple, you have to pay their fees, If, you wanna do transaction,
Speaker 5:  you, you basically have to engage with them in a, in the same way that you
Speaker 5:  have to engage with the app store. And crucially you have
Speaker 5:  share data that you might not otherwise share. Both the consumer and the
Speaker 5:  banks have to share data that they wouldn't normally share with Apple in
Speaker 5:  order to make all of this work.
Speaker 4:  Well, because Apple's sitting there in the middle.
Speaker 5:  Right? Right. And, and so the DOJ is basically saying Apple has inserted
Speaker 5:  itself into this process and is refusing to allow anybody else to do that
Speaker 5:  and that is wrong. And
Speaker 5:  like, I was like, oh, that's, that's, I never thought about that, but yeah,
Speaker 5:  that's 'cause I don't think about my digital wallet because I'm not Chase
Speaker 5:  bank, right? So, so, and then I look, I was like, yeah, that, that actually
Speaker 5:  makes sense and is probably not great. Well,
Speaker 4:  And this is like, I, the only thing I can think is that every
Speaker 4:  FinTech company has been in the DOJs ear over the last year
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Talking to 'em about this because part of the point that they're making
Speaker 4:  is that you don't think about your digital wallet because your digital wallet
Speaker 4:  sucks because no one else is allowed to compete with Apple, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That if you're If you wanna build some kind of payment
Speaker 4:  product on the iPhone, you are required to integrate it with the Apple Wallet
Speaker 4:  app. You can't use tap to pay, you're just hamstrung in all of these ways
Speaker 4:  that actually go out of their way to promote Apple Wallet specifically. Yep.
Speaker 4:  So If, you wanted to do something like, and it actually mentioned digital
Speaker 4:  Car keys as a version of this that has been kind of under innovated as a
Speaker 4:  result because there's no good way to do it.
Speaker 5:  And they specifically said they had a bunch of examples, they didn't name
Speaker 5:  names, but they had a bunch of examples of where like app developers and
Speaker 5:  banks and in car companies would just had to give up on developing
Speaker 5:  certain applications and c certain features because it wouldn't work with
Speaker 5:  iOS because Apple wouldn't allow it to use the parts of the phone that it
Speaker 5:  would need to make it all work. And like Ooh,
Speaker 5:  that's not a great look for Apple. That's a really bad look.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. You just think of it, and this one feels like probably
Speaker 5:  one of the biggest slam dunks, but also the least
Speaker 5:  interesting one for 99.9% of people who don't work at Chase Bank.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This one has the fewest sort of sympathetic victims. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like, oh no, poor Goldman Sachs can't do what it wants on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  That sounds awesome. Aw.
Speaker 5:  And they, they try to make it about the consumer by saying, you know, you
Speaker 5:  have to share this data, you have to share stuff that you wouldn't normally
Speaker 5:  share. And and that's also true and, and not great. And I,
Speaker 5:  I loved just, I know we're, we're, we're gonna take a break here in a second,
Speaker 5:  but I did love, there was this through line throughout the thing that was
Speaker 5:  like, you know what? Everything Apple says about privacy and security is
Speaker 5:  absolute bullshit. And every single time they are,
Speaker 5:  they are making the privacy and security worse by, by doing
Speaker 5:  this. and that I'm not entirely sure of, right? Because the digital
Speaker 5:  wallet, a big part of that is they've got the secure enclave on the device
Speaker 5:  and they don't want anybody else interacting with that. and that from a security
Speaker 5:  standpoint, that makes sense. Like Apple's argument there makes sense, but
Speaker 5:  at the same time,
Speaker 5:  green Bubbles, there's all these other places where they have made it less
Speaker 5:  secure.
Speaker 4:  Right? Even I, and I think this is part of what the DOJ is trying to do,
Speaker 4:  is that say even if individually these things are
Speaker 4:  sort of gross but not illegal, put them all together and it
Speaker 4:  adds up to something bigger. And they had a bunch of other ones that there's
Speaker 4:  like a list at the end of just like all the other crappy things Apple has
Speaker 4:  ever done, which I thought was very funny. And it names, let's see, it names
Speaker 4:  FaceTime, third party, iOS web browsers,
Speaker 4:  eims Cloud Storage, iCloud sales
Speaker 4:  Channels, and Siri, which is my favorite. They
Speaker 5:  Don't basically,
Speaker 4:  Basically like Siri sucks and it's Apple's fault and it's illegal. And I
Speaker 4:  think it's, I think it should be illegal for Siri to be as bad as it is.
Speaker 4:  So I'm in full support of that. Lauren, before we let you go,
Speaker 4:  you've, you've been talking to folks all day, there was a DOJ
Speaker 4:  briefing right after this went out. There was an Apple briefing right after
Speaker 4:  this went out. What's the, what are the vibes like in the hours after this
Speaker 4:  comes out? What are you hearing? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well, I, I haven't gotten a chance to catch up with too many people yet,
Speaker 6:  but, you know, coming out of the briefing and you know, just seeing
Speaker 6:  what's out there right now, I think, you know, developers that have been
Speaker 6:  complaining about this for a while are really excited.
Speaker 6:  They're happy to see the US finally take on Apple
Speaker 6:  in this really big way.
Speaker 4:  Is this big enough for those people? Like are they, are they, I feel like
Speaker 4:  a lot of times folks get mad and they yell and they want big action
Speaker 4:  and then they get small action and they get frustrated. But the little bit
Speaker 4:  that I've heard is folks saying like, this is the big swing we've been waiting
Speaker 4:  for. Is that what you're hearing too? I think it's
Speaker 6:  A pretty big case. you know, I think everyone
Speaker 6:  is gonna want to see like their, their little piece of the
Speaker 6:  complaint that they've had for years in this. But I think it's a, it's a
Speaker 6:  pretty sweeping complaint. So I think that a lot of
Speaker 6:  developers will be happy to see this And Welcome it. I think,
Speaker 6:  you know, the problem with cases like this and you know, every
Speaker 6:  antitrust case in the US is that it takes a long time to see
Speaker 6:  them play out. So, you know, I I think it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  maybe a little bit disappointing to people who have wanted to see action
Speaker 6:  for a really long time to see that, you know, it's gonna take a while.
Speaker 6:  you know, the DOJ filed its first Google lawsuit
Speaker 6:  back in 2020. It went to trial in 2023. So this is
Speaker 6:  gonna take a long time to resolve.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right. Before we let you go here and we go take a break, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  put the over under at 2030. Is this resolved before or
Speaker 4:  after? Are we going over or are we under, do
Speaker 6:  We mean like past, like exhausting the Supreme Court
Speaker 6:  option and
Speaker 4:  Everything over? We, the, the last pieces of paperwork have been filed,
Speaker 4:  whatever that turns out to mean 2030,
Speaker 6:  I think over, but it might be close.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Okay. That's good. So, I've set the odds correctly. This is, this is
Speaker 4:  good. I feel good about it. Alright. Alright, we gotta take a break. Lauren,
Speaker 4:  thank you so much. We're gonna come back and just talk more about this.
Speaker 4:  We'll
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back and we have a guest, our good friend
Speaker 4:  Vacation NELI. What up? Who is a whole other guy than
Speaker 4:  normal NELI? How you doing buddy?
Speaker 8:  I'm good. I haven't been on vacation like this since 2019 and of course,
Speaker 8:  of course the DOJ suited Apple for being in Monopoly while I was in
Speaker 8:  the air to Mexico.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there was no chance something was, everything was just gonna be chill
Speaker 4:  for a week while you were gone. Just no chance. Yeah, I assume we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do like four or five emergency forecasts over the next eight days or so.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be great. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Tim Cook is gonna overthrow the government. Brooklyn, here's Max. Max is
Speaker 8:  just running around. Hey Max, come say hi to the, there she
Speaker 4:  Goes. Yeah, perfect. That's, that's, that's the energy we're looking for
Speaker 4:  for Max. So we just talked with Lauren, we went through kind of the, the
Speaker 4:  bones of the complaint. We talked about like the five big sections of what's
Speaker 4:  going on. And, honestly, I'm just curious for,
Speaker 4:  for NELI vibes, we have a lot of like legal thinking questions about
Speaker 4:  how this case differs and is similar to some of the old cases we've
Speaker 4:  seen, especially the Microsoft one from, you know, 25 years ago. But
Speaker 4:  I'm sure you read the complaint on the plane, like all cool vacation people.
Speaker 4:  What do you make of it? Where's your head so far?
Speaker 8:  So I, you know, I interviewed Jonathan Canter on Decoder a few weeks
Speaker 8:  ago and I asked him about this case and he was very pagey
Speaker 8:  about then my impression of this whole
Speaker 8:  Jonathan Andrew is the assisting attorney general for antitrust in Pharmac
Speaker 8:  Justice. He was on
Speaker 8:  my read on it, is that they are explicitly
Speaker 8:  trying to link Apple to Microsoft in the nineties, right? They're trying
Speaker 8:  to say there was a big bad in the nineties, there was Microsoft. Microsoft
Speaker 8:  tried to kill Netscape and tried to kill Java and we stopped them from
Speaker 8:  doing that. and that is what let a bunch of other innovative companies
Speaker 8:  do. All
Speaker 4:  Including Apple.
Speaker 8:  Including specifically including Apple. Yeah, right. Microsoft
Speaker 8:  tried to kill QuickTime on Windows. They, they, they basically nerfed it.
Speaker 8:  Microsoft probably didn't wanna let iTunes be a first class application on
Speaker 8:  Windows and letting 'em do that is what let the iPod tick off, right? When
Speaker 8:  they finally were bring the iPod windows. So they're, they're making that
Speaker 8:  comparison very explicitly in the complaints. But then also I think just
Speaker 8:  from like a vibes perspective, the attitude of
Speaker 8:  the DOJ is, okay, well Microsoft
Speaker 8:  itself was built on IBM compatibility, right?
Speaker 8:  Like there was an IBM platform that allowed Microsoft to go on popular
Speaker 8:  Microsoft. We stopped Microsoft from being the big, big bad that allowed
Speaker 8:  Apple Resurgents guests. but it also created the opportunity for Google to
Speaker 8:  exist because Google is a browser company. The application
Speaker 8:  layer moved from Wintel to the web because of the web
Speaker 8:  and that allowed Google to this. And then they even go so far as to, you
Speaker 8:  know, when you, when you hear them make the argument, you're like, and then
Speaker 8:  Amazon was built on top of Google, which is Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's a theory.
Speaker 8:  Sure. But the idea that people were searching for products and they landed
Speaker 8:  on Amazon and Amazon became the best retailer 'cause had the most selection.
Speaker 8:  Their point is the natural evolution of technology is for one
Speaker 8:  platform to provide a boost to the next one
Speaker 8:  and for people to move sort of like higher and higher up levels of
Speaker 8:  extraction. And what Apple has done is they basically forbidden that
Speaker 8:  from happening. So If you think like they keep talking about super apps in
Speaker 8:  the complaint, the comparison that they, they make, I
Speaker 8:  think they were gonna make it more loudly. In the Windows case
Speaker 8:  they called it middleware, which is a deeply funny word. And I think they
Speaker 8:  were gonna try to use that word again. It's still in this complaint a little
Speaker 8:  bit. But the idea is like
Speaker 8:  Java was middleware on Windows. So you don't have to write to Windows, you
Speaker 8:  can write to Java and you could deploy an app anywhere. You don't have to
Speaker 8:  write to Windows, you can write to the web and you can deploy anywhere. Flash
Speaker 8:  is a type of middleware, which the people are gonna have a lot of feelings
Speaker 8:  on. But Apple is basically forbidden. All of these things
Speaker 8:  from being actual competitors to running natively on the phone.
Speaker 8:  So like web apps, they're not a good competitor for real apps on the phone
Speaker 8:  even that they were intended to be in the beginning. If you remember which
Speaker 8:  Steve Jobs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And I, I think people have a lot of feelings about that, like on both sides,
Speaker 8:  right? And I think they went away from like web apps and middleware,
Speaker 8:  the super apps and here's my hottest take. I think they're talking about
Speaker 8:  super apps so much 'cause they know Elon Musk wants X to be a
Speaker 8:  super app. And so if they get Elon Musk to say Apple's the monopoly,
Speaker 8:  like that's good for them.
Speaker 4:  Is it?
Speaker 8:  That's just like, that's too pin lines man. That's, that's just me staring
Speaker 8:  at the ocean and being like, why do you wanna keep talking about super
Speaker 8:  apps? It's to get Elon to tweet about it.
Speaker 4:  I love the political theory that getting Elon on your side is, is the
Speaker 4:  surest way to winning in the courts right now?
Speaker 8:  It sure is. If, you think maybe Trump might win, right? Fair
Speaker 8:  If. you think Trump is trying to woo Elon and you think there might be a
Speaker 8:  change of regime at the Department of Justice? You, you probably want
Speaker 8:  this to appear to be really bipartisan. You probably want to say
Speaker 8:  the richest man, the most innovative triangle car man in the world
Speaker 8:  thinks that the case's a good idea. 'cause then he can make the super app
Speaker 8:  that all innovative guys who Mely Ken Funnel
Speaker 8:  and robots wanna do. I don't know, like I
Speaker 8:  think that's a better argument politically than web app
Speaker 8:  could be as powerful as Native app, which is I I
Speaker 8:  which is what I believe, but don don't Yeah, I'm not allowed. Like
Speaker 5:  That's probably part of the reason that the digital wallet stuff is in here.
Speaker 5:  It's because you, it is bipartisan. Like the banks
Speaker 5:  want wanna get rid of that. They, they wanna be able to put their own wallets
Speaker 5:  on the phone and, and now the the DOJ is
Speaker 5:  saying, yeah, we want you to do that too. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Also, just in case you're wondering, Elon Musk has tweeted twice today about
Speaker 4:  the Woke Mind virus and Zero Times about Apple and the GOJ.
Speaker 4:  So not great so far.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean, look, the man does not love, does not love a government regulator.
Speaker 8:  They're not his favorite. But I'm just saying like, If, you can use some
Speaker 8:  vocabulary that is more popular over there in Crazy
Speaker 8:  Town. You're better off than talking about middleware or whatever
Speaker 8:  nonsense they were gonna talk about before. Yeah. I also think, yeah,
Speaker 8:  there are So I think Apple's response to this is like, bear, they're like,
Speaker 8:  this is our business model. We make products that work really well together.
Speaker 8:  I'm sorry if Janie Diamond and Elon Musk are mad at us, like
Speaker 8:  we stand between you and the, you know, capricious avaricious banks.
Speaker 8:  Like that's a pretty good argument. I I don't, yeah. I'm not sitting here
Speaker 8:  being like, man, I wish I could deal with my bank more directly. I, but
Speaker 8:  I I I do think there's like a political coalition that they're trying to
Speaker 8:  make out of it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well we were talking a little bit about this with Lauren in the last segment,
Speaker 4:  but the, the fact that what Apple is being accused
Speaker 4:  of is the same thing that Apple has always said that it does,
Speaker 4:  which is build hardware, software and services that work best
Speaker 4:  together. And so like the argument that the Apple Watch is the best way to
Speaker 4:  use a smartwatch with an iPhone, like every single person at Apple Park is
Speaker 4:  like, yep, that's right. And it's just a question of, and I feel like this,
Speaker 4:  this to me reminds me a little bit of like, when I was at the
Speaker 4:  Google Antitrust trial and they were arguing about basically Google's
Speaker 4:  bigness and why Google has so much market share and Google was like,
Speaker 4:  no, it's 'cause we're very good and we make good products. Yeah. And the
Speaker 4:  government was like, well no.
Speaker 4:  And it just like that proving the opposite of that point seems
Speaker 4:  very difficult to me in a way that like the DOJ set itself up with
Speaker 4:  this really interesting narrative that kind of starts at
Speaker 4:  the iPhone isn't very good and ends at Monopoly. And I think you
Speaker 4:  can sort of get there, but it just seems to me that like legally speaking
Speaker 4:  jump, like proving the case from hoop to hoop there seems very complicated.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I don't know that they start with the iPhone isn't very good. I think
Speaker 8:  they're more or less like the iPhone's great. And we
Speaker 8:  have all of this evidence that Apple actually doesn't feel
Speaker 8:  any competitive pressure on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Right. But I think, but part of that is Apple saying the iPhone is not as
Speaker 4:  good as it could be. That like what they're saying is your experience would
Speaker 4:  be better if there was more competitive, if there was more competition in
Speaker 4:  this space.
Speaker 8:  Right. And even so we don't have all the evidence. They haven't seen all
Speaker 8:  it, it sounds like there's just like oceans of Apple discovery, right?
Speaker 8:  Like that exists. God yeah, it's pretty good.
Speaker 8:  And but even in this complaint, there's the marketing manager for the iPhone
Speaker 8:  saying, we made the phone too good. Like the the features are good enough
Speaker 8:  already. Right? We didn't have to put more expense into the phone.
Speaker 8:  We, we made the phone too good. We should, especially if the features are
Speaker 8:  gonna be expensive. I think the quote is like, we could challenge expensive
Speaker 8:  features going to the consumer phone, right?
Speaker 4:  'cause like it would be good enough today what we did a while ago. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Right? Like we were making things better for no reason. That's bad.
Speaker 8:  Right. What you want is Apple saying Samsung is on our ass, like
Speaker 8:  Lenovo is on our ass, whoever, like Motorola, right? Yeah. And we should
Speaker 8:  make the phone as good as possible to win market share, otherwise people
Speaker 8:  will switch. And the argument that the DOJ is making again
Speaker 8:  comes back to just like where is the application layer with, because the
Speaker 8:  application layer moves up one level
Speaker 8:  super apps or the web, instantly the
Speaker 8:  iPhone gets disintermediated and they have to compete. And this is by the
Speaker 8:  way, exactly what happened through Windows. I, we
Speaker 8:  just had Dylan Field at South by Southwest with us talking about Figma and
Speaker 8:  he was like, the app, the best way to deploy applications to desktop computers
Speaker 8:  today is the web. Yep. Right? No one writes Native
Speaker 8:  window. Binary is not, you're writing games or you need some other specific,
Speaker 8:  very specific access to the hardware, which some, some people do. I'm not
Speaker 8:  saying it's completely dead, but there's a reason that like Windows apps
Speaker 8:  aren't the hotness desktop apps. All right? Like, or
Speaker 8:  I, the reason Windows apps aren't the hotness web apps all, and they all
Speaker 8:  live in the cloud and some of 'em have innovative access. Like big one does
Speaker 8:  a lot of cool stuff in web assembly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean Electron is like the new middleware, right? Like it is, it is
Speaker 4:  a thing that let let you run write one app that runs lots and lots of places
Speaker 8:  And people can have a lot of feelings about, like Electron is not great and
Speaker 8:  a lot of like electron destroys your compute and like they try to make it
Speaker 8:  better. But all that means is, in particular for Apple,
Speaker 8:  when the application layer moved to the web, they were able to
Speaker 8:  ship the iMac and take market share away from Windows.
Speaker 8:  and that is a that right? That created the opportunity for Apple to exist.
Speaker 8:  And so if the DOJ is basically saying, look, apple is
Speaker 8:  restricting the natural evolution of technology and they're not letting the
Speaker 8:  application layer move to Super app or the web or wherever ai wherever it
Speaker 8:  might go. and that means the next generation of competitors is not
Speaker 8:  forming. And here's the evidence, which is Apple is artificially keeping
Speaker 8:  the price of the phone high and they're not trying very hard. And here's
Speaker 8:  some quotes in the complaint where they're explicitly not on one of them.
Speaker 8:  They gotta prove all this, this is a complaint. Right? But I see the argument
Speaker 8:  'cause it is exactly the argument that allowed the iMac to exist.
Speaker 4:  Well, and to that point, like Apple understands better than
Speaker 4:  anybody the consequences of this because Apple exists because of those consequences.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like it is, I think the, the
Speaker 4:  basically like the Microsoft antitrust trial led to the success of the
Speaker 4:  iPod is like a slightly wild take.
Speaker 8:  I think that's going too far. I-I-I-I-I think it it led to the success of
Speaker 8:  the web, which allowed the imex
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I think that's a better argument. But the complaint says the iPod
Speaker 4:  did it. Well it's,
Speaker 5:  It's going the, the complaints is the iPod because they wanted to connect
Speaker 5:  QuickTime where they had all these quotes from Apple executives talking about
Speaker 5:  QuickTime and how it was hindered on, on windows. So like
Speaker 5:  that, that they had, they wanted to stay in theme and make and reuse Apple
Speaker 5:  quotes to be like, yeah, suck it Apple. Right?
Speaker 8:  And all those people are like rich or gone doesn, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 8:  But that thing, like I I I, I just, we've talked
Speaker 8:  enough about like in many ways the complaint reads like a bird cast episode.
Speaker 4:  It kind of does. Which I,
Speaker 8:  It's like fascinating to me. It's like bringing bubbles and like NFC
Speaker 8:  excess, like it's very wonky. Like I, you know, I,
Speaker 8:  I did just spend an hour with Danter on a stage. Like the dude is a nerd.
Speaker 8:  We, he, I think he gets it in a way that, you know, I think it's, it's
Speaker 8:  very tempting to say like I York computer something like I spent
Speaker 8:  some time with him recently. I, I think he gets it. I think the point he's
Speaker 8:  trying to make is
Speaker 8:  make like over and over again what happens in technology is the
Speaker 8:  application layer moves up one level of abstraction. I'll
Speaker 8:  give you an example that's totally unrelated. This is more peanut water thoughts,
Speaker 8:  but I'll give you more, one more example. It's totally unrelated. This Jensen
Speaker 8:  Wong from Nvidia, like he just on
Speaker 8:  stage said, I don't think people are gonna have to know how to code anymore.
Speaker 8:  Right? Because they'll just tell the AI what to do and the AI will generate
Speaker 8:  applications for them. That's a huge step up in levels
Speaker 8:  of abstraction. It's massively inefficient to say,
Speaker 8:  I will no longer know how to program a computer. I will tell
Speaker 8:  a data center full Nvidia unique views to write programs
Speaker 8:  for another computer. Like massively inefficient.
Speaker 8:  But that's, everyone believes in, and I, I I, you know, I think If you believe
Speaker 8:  that that is the arc of technology then you, you, it's hard
Speaker 8:  to look at the iPhone and say, well where are the really interesting
Speaker 8:  electron is at where are the really interesting super abstinence
Speaker 8:  punches? We have had a coverage of super apps are coming on the
Speaker 8:  word for five years. Like ever since anybody woke up and
Speaker 8:  saw WeChat in China and said, oh look, the Chinese market, there's a lot
Speaker 8:  of switching between phones. It was like, it's a more vibrant market over
Speaker 8:  there and smartphones because this one app is actually the operating system.
Speaker 8:  Right? Right. Why doesn't that kind of thing happen inside that Google doesn't
Speaker 8:  want that to exist? Not that meta wouldn't do that tomorrow with Facebook
Speaker 8:  if that Apple is basically for the king.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's functionally what Facebook has been trying to do for a decade
Speaker 4:  now is, is build more and more of that stuff in. And ironically on the web
Speaker 4:  for a long time it worked really well. And then, yeah, and this is, we were
Speaker 4:  talking about the, the super app thing and whether it's like a function
Speaker 4:  of the way Apple works or just a genuine cultural difference. And it, this
Speaker 4:  hadn't occurred to me until now, but I think maybe the best argument you
Speaker 4:  could make for why it's just a cultural difference is that everybody hated
Speaker 4:  when Facebook got really cluttered. Oh my goodness. Like ran away from the
Speaker 4:  app and, and Facebook like pretty nakedly and loudly.
Speaker 4:  Like tried to learn from WeChat and just pull more and more of that in. And
Speaker 4:  it got messy and it got weird and it got complicated. And then, you know,
Speaker 4:  politics happened and people started to like flee Facebook. But
Speaker 4:  still people use marketplace in groups and like Facebook is in a very real
Speaker 4:  way a super app. It is the closest thing we have in the United States to
Speaker 4:  a super app, I would say.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, but it's not close enough. It's not,
Speaker 4:  No, and it can't do it on mobile,
Speaker 8:  Right. It's not, I do everything with app. So. I can switch to a Samsung
Speaker 8:  phone or whatever kind of other phone a pixel and
Speaker 8:  basically recreate my experience. and that the point is, If,
Speaker 8:  you could If you can switch your services or you can switch your
Speaker 8:  application environment easily. You'll be very likely to switch your
Speaker 8:  hardware. Yeah. And the, there's a line in the complaint that another
Speaker 8:  Apple quote, this is the one that led me to believe there's a mountain of
Speaker 8:  evidence in this case where it's an email from an unnamed Apple
Speaker 8:  executive who says, if we let this cloud stuff happen, anyone can just
Speaker 8:  buy a $25 Android and have a great experience.
Speaker 4:  He said Bucks and it and spelled bucks with an X. That's the best. Which
Speaker 4:  I hate part hate so much. That's good.
Speaker 8:  And I believe you said that that's the barbarians at the gate.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's pretty good. Right? And
Speaker 8:  That's like Apple, like openly being afraid of
Speaker 8:  Android in that way. Not because it's better, but because it's deeper
Speaker 8:  and saying we have to make sure it's not a good experience over there.
Speaker 8:  Not by making our phone great, but by letting, making sure that
Speaker 8:  application developers can't do things over there that can do here. Or making
Speaker 8:  sure that if they do things over here, it's costly. Like cloud gaming. Right?
Speaker 8:  I think that was the example there. We allowed cloud gaming. Anyone can buy
Speaker 8:  cheap and Android. I thought I have a great experience 'cause we'll just
Speaker 8:  be cloud gaming that's bad. Like I can't
Speaker 8:  stress enough how bad that is. And again, I'll come back to Figma just 'cause
Speaker 8:  we had Dylan on the phone recently. I know a lot of designers who have given
Speaker 8:  up their MacBooks because they spend all day using Figma on a
Speaker 8:  Chromebook and then they, they, you know, they allocate their dollars elsewhere.
Speaker 8:  That's fascinating. It's just a, a fascinating turn of events that just
Speaker 8:  happened in that market. It's crazy that nothing has gotten
Speaker 8:  in between phone. Now, just for the sake of the argument, I will make all
Speaker 8:  of Apple's arguments without having really read their responses. Because
Speaker 8:  again, I don't think sleep can
Speaker 4:  They are what you think they are. Yeah. I'll tell you that. Like there was,
Speaker 4:  there's, they, they did a background briefing with a bunch of reporters and
Speaker 4:  have put out a couple of statements and nothing in it will remotely surprise
Speaker 4:  you. None
Speaker 5:  Of it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I I do love that the briefing was on background by the way.
Speaker 8:  We are mad said no one.
Speaker 8:  Cool. Anyhow, I'm guessing they're like, the
Speaker 8:  security is really important. These things, we are in pockets all the time.
Speaker 8:  We craft integration of hardware, software and services that no else does.
Speaker 8:  Like that's actually the business, not this other stuff
Speaker 4:  That is alarmingly close. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Sure. Yeah. But we've covered this company for a long time and then I'm wondering
Speaker 8:  if they brought up Battery Life because that, that's the one to me that's
Speaker 8:  like
Speaker 8:  our producer, Liam was just at my house and we were on a Google meet with
Speaker 8:  my 2015 iMac and he was like, what's that noise? And I was like, that's the
Speaker 8:  iMac, that's the fans from the iMac trying to run this web app
Speaker 8:  right now. And he was like, I thought that was your fur.
Speaker 5:  It was your 2015 iMac.
Speaker 8:  There are a lot of arguments, especially on a mobile phone, power constraints,
Speaker 8:  ball device, blah, blah blah. Network constrained where you want to be in
Speaker 8:  tight control of what an application can do. I I totally,
Speaker 8:  I totally buy it there. I don't think those arguments are wrong. I just think
Speaker 8:  Apple probably ever since Tim Cook said
Speaker 8:  like services revenue and a, a call five years ago
Speaker 8:  has been actively protecting the business as opposed to growing it.
Speaker 8:  And I think there, I think there's a bunch of evidence to that, to that effect.
Speaker 5:  So Apple didn't mention Battery Life on super apps instead all on
Speaker 5:  background again. So we don't know who actually said any of this. Maybe it
Speaker 5:  wasn't even Apple. Maybe it was orange, but, but they said that
Speaker 5:  super apps exist already and, and that anything they do is for privacy
Speaker 5:  and security reasons, which is the big theme.
Speaker 8:  What do countries do? They call out to grab existing in
Speaker 4:  China and India. Yep.
Speaker 5:  WeChat and Tata.
Speaker 8:  Right. So two countries that
Speaker 8:  regulate the shit out of Apple.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 8:  I just wanna be blunt, like China basically is like, you're gonna give our
Speaker 8:  user data to the state. And China and Apple's like cool China
Speaker 8:  from John Gruber I think reported this. China's the one that said
Speaker 8:  you're gonna do RCS and Apple finally caved. Wow. Probably for bad reasons,
Speaker 8:  right? I think China wants Apple to move to RCS. The people will stop using
Speaker 8:  encrypted I Cap or I method. Yeah, that's bad. But they're gonna do it.
Speaker 8:  India also extraordinarily interested in regulating Apple
Speaker 8:  also. I don't know If, you saw the pictures of Rihanna performing at a wedding
Speaker 8:  in India lately. Psh Ban's son's
Speaker 8:  wedding. Shaima owns Reliance. Gia the largest carrier
Speaker 8:  in India. He's the major benefactor of the government. And when the
Speaker 8:  wireless carrier in India says, we wanna make sure people can switch easily,
Speaker 8:  apple gives up. Right? And like that's a big thing. My
Speaker 8:  favorite fact that the Indians farm from the market is they're like 10 phone
Speaker 8:  launches a week or some insane number like that. That's the dream. 'cause
Speaker 8:  people are switching, people are switching so hard all over the place because
Speaker 8:  the application layer, the network layer is actually to some extent on
Speaker 8:  reliance. Like reliance via the network is actually the application
Speaker 8:  layer there, which is utterly fascinating. Yeah. So I would just point out
Speaker 8:  like Apple's saying it, super Rapids exists and not mentioning that in the
Speaker 8:  two countries that regulates Apple the hardest in various ways. It's pretty
Speaker 8:  funny man. It's how it appears to be on background.
Speaker 8:  So we don't even know because someone whispered this Yeah. In a
Speaker 8:  meeting and, and no one was allowed to ask that person. Who knows
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 5:  Fell asleep and I woke up and had these arguments
Speaker 4:  In I knew it. My head So I knew in my head. Yeah. Yeah. Neil, why do you
Speaker 4:  think they didn't talk about the web more in this complaint? The, the, the
Speaker 4:  thing that surprised me the most was that all of the arguments that we've
Speaker 4:  been talking about on The Vergecast for months now, about what the
Speaker 4:  open web could be like. I just imagine Dieter bone reading this and like
Speaker 4:  screaming about progressive web apps and he's like, this
Speaker 4:  solves all problems. The Palm pri knew it, everything would've been great,
Speaker 4:  but the open web wasn't really a thing. Like they, they didn't talk about
Speaker 4:  web browsers except sort of obliquely. There were not big discussions about
Speaker 4:  what web apps could do to make these things better. Like why, what's your
Speaker 4:  read on why that was not part of this complaint?
Speaker 8:  One, I, I texted Dieter today and I said, I miss you. The United
Speaker 8:  States government says web apps are
Speaker 8:  important. He was just like, go on vacation. Like stop this.
Speaker 4:  He texted you back from messages.google.com the web app.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, good call out there. I so again, I, I think this is
Speaker 8:  a political thing. I I think that that stuff is in there. I
Speaker 8:  I know for a fact the DOJ has been paying a lot of attention
Speaker 8:  to Apple's compliance, the DMA in Europe and their move to,
Speaker 8:  you know, disallow web apps. Yeah. And then like bring them back
Speaker 8:  because the Regor by the way, that web app thing, you know,
Speaker 8:  I'm not like a crypto per thing, but there is
Speaker 8:  a huge freak out because there are crypto apps that store web that are web
Speaker 8:  apps that store the data locally. And Apple was about to wipe out people's
Speaker 8:  wallets by disallowing web apps. 'cause they were just gonna get rid of the
Speaker 8:  functionality.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Literally the, the local data on their phone that was stored there
Speaker 4:  with their money would've just been gone insane.
Speaker 8:  Which is, I mean, hilarious. It's So I. I know the DOJ has been paying
Speaker 8:  a lot of attention to everything there. I really think this comes down
Speaker 8:  to who is the audience for this, for this complaint.
Speaker 8:  I was talking to Sarah John about it. This complaint is a press release.
Speaker 8:  It's fundamentally press, it's written like a press release. It's a story.
Speaker 8:  It begins with like, it's Steve Jobs in Media Red, like doing
Speaker 8:  a thing. you know, it's like, it, it's a story.
Speaker 4:  It starts with a Kindle ad. Like truly what a win for the Kindle
Speaker 4:  today.
Speaker 4:  The Kindle is the bastion of openness.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And I I think telling people the, we,
Speaker 8:  you know, the web apps are gonna do it on a phone. It's like people know
Speaker 8:  what websites look like on a phone. We have no good ones.
Speaker 8:  The only good ones. Yeah. That is true. All the rest of them are, are trying
Speaker 8:  to mug you in a dark alley. IIII think they had to move on and say like,
Speaker 8:  there's a next generation of products that's being held back. By the way,
Speaker 8:  Elon Musk proprietor Triangle Cars wants to build one right now,
Speaker 8:  doesn't it? And I think that's a, it's a much better story to,
Speaker 8:  it's a story about The future and that story about the path. But I think
Speaker 8:  fundamentally, you know, the recent history of technology
Speaker 8:  suggests the web is actually the best application platform. Yeah. Yep. It
Speaker 8:  distributes us widely. And it has in fact taken over on
Speaker 8:  Deca like in a real way, a lot of the native apps that you think you're
Speaker 8:  using on a macro PC are in fact electronics. Yep. They're
Speaker 8:  just wrappers around web apps.
Speaker 4:  I've been covering browsers more in the last 12 months than I have in like
Speaker 4:  the previous decade because again, the, the, the layer of
Speaker 4:  applications is moving and all these browsers are starting to realize like,
Speaker 4:  oh, your operating system isn't actually the place that can do all this stuff
Speaker 4:  for you online. It's your browser. Yep. So we're, we're going to give you
Speaker 4:  more cross-platform tools. We're gonna rethink the way extensions work.
Speaker 4:  Arc is one of a bunch of browsers doing it at bunch of interesting stuff
Speaker 4:  with ai. And so like that's the same sort of layer of
Speaker 4:  app abstraction that you're talking about. And it's making browsers at least
Speaker 4:  on desktops, like really interesting and important. Again,
Speaker 5:  It's all about Microsoft Edge.
Speaker 4:  Well, and even again, like Microsoft now is like, edge is a crucially
Speaker 4:  important thing to Microsoft in a way that like, remember the last time
Speaker 4:  browsers were important to Microsoft. I know.
Speaker 5:  Well that, that's, that's for 2040. 2040 Microsoft Edge is gonna
Speaker 5:  be a horrible monopoly. Just you Wait,
Speaker 4:  That's a good take. Yeah, I appreciate
Speaker 8:  That. I mean this is just a circle of life, right? Yeah. I would just
Speaker 8:  like, the thing I would say is like a bunch of these quote unquote middleware,
Speaker 8:  it was like, did turn out to be garbage. Like I don't, like Java did not
Speaker 8:  turn out the excellent application environment and Flash
Speaker 8:  I think somewhat famously was a piece of crap. But If, you don't
Speaker 8:  allow the things to like take hold in the market then you are gonna
Speaker 8:  be stuck with one vendor kind of controlling everything. And I, I
Speaker 8:  I wonder how much of a shotgun gun approach this complainant? Again, it's
Speaker 8:  everything. It's iMessage, it's applications, it's super apps, it's
Speaker 8:  wallet wallets, it's, I mean smart watch. It's everything. And I
Speaker 8:  wonder how much of this is like, let's put it out there so people grab onto
Speaker 8:  and then Yeah. And then follow up on that one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. How
Speaker 5:  Much of the case when it finally goes is just gonna be spicy Apple
Speaker 5:  quotes and then being like, look how spicy this is. Destroy them.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I think what we've learned from all of these recently is
Speaker 8:  there's nothing more fun than putting a powerful executive on a
Speaker 8:  stand and just reading their email to them.
Speaker 8:  You, you read this email that you're not certain. They're like, I don't recall.
Speaker 8:  That's pretty good. Like I'll watch that. you know,
Speaker 4:  We have seen a lot of that.
Speaker 8:  The thing I warn everybody
Speaker 8:  is the Microsoft case in the nineties took a a decade,
Speaker 8:  right? It was like three or four years in trial, then three or four years
Speaker 8:  of appeal, then I got kicked back then there was a settlement at one point.
Speaker 8:  I have this very distinct memory of standing in the Target and
Speaker 8:  we're seeing Wisconsin, it's like a child teenager
Speaker 8:  reading the Newsweek that was describing how Microsoft could be
Speaker 8:  split up into something called Apps Co and Osco. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Because
Speaker 8:  They were gonna split windows from application business. I don't know why
Speaker 8:  this happened in Target and we're seeing, I mean I know why I think we're
Speaker 8:  seeing Wisconsin that I grew up, but I don know why this memory specific
Speaker 8:  to standing in a project reading Newsweek print. but it is, that's
Speaker 8:  what I got for you. I can't remember anyone's names today. I remember that.
Speaker 8:  That's who I am. Yeah. You go and like it got all the way to the
Speaker 8:  DOJ is gonna break up Microsoft. It came all the way back down and that took
Speaker 8:  10 years. And So I think this is a decade, but
Speaker 8:  this is a gravitational Well that will last a decade. Like the
Speaker 8:  entire industry is gonna bend around this case for a decade.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We, we gave Lauren the over under of 2030 and for
Speaker 4:  this to be like fully all the way done and dusted and she sort of
Speaker 4:  gently took the over it sounds like you're, you're like hard over on
Speaker 4:  2030.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean, unless
Speaker 8:  I think the only difference to me in my mind is that the DNA exists
Speaker 8:  in the EU now and Apple is making these changes anyway. And so it's gonna
Speaker 8:  collect some data about how much money it can make in the meantime
Speaker 8:  and what that would be like here each other. There's a possibility that
Speaker 8:  that breaks this case and makes it go shorter, but they're
Speaker 8:  mad. Like this is a company that is idealistically ideologically
Speaker 8:  upset at the note thing, but we can't do whatever it wants.
Speaker 8:  And I get it. Like, I I don't like being told what to do. No one does. I
Speaker 8:  dunno if anyone has ever noticed, but I think in this case, like again, I
Speaker 8:  to some extent this complaint reads like To Vergecast. It's like why, why,
Speaker 8:  why did it take so long for Apple to allow games Finn the app than iPhone?
Speaker 8:  Oh. 'cause they wanna protect the app store. Right. It's as simple as that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. So one more thing and then we should let you go because you have
Speaker 4:  many more pina coladas to drink
Speaker 8:  So many. How do you feel like I'm never coming home that's,
Speaker 4:  This is Mexico NELI is gonna be a whole new addition to The Vergecast. I
Speaker 4:  love this.
Speaker 4:  Talk to me about how you feel about this. Like as a, as a lawyer who would
Speaker 4:  have to argue this case, because one of the things Alex and I have been arguing
Speaker 4:  about all day is my feeling is that one of the big things that happened
Speaker 4:  in the Microsoft case was that you had Netscape, which was this like one
Speaker 4:  party that had been like viciously loudly wronged.
Speaker 4:  And it actually ended up not being the most important part of that case.
Speaker 4:  but it, it was like, it was a very helpful victim that you could argue this
Speaker 4:  is the bad thing that was done to someone and it crushed them.
Speaker 4:  And, and maybe it's just too early to know the answer to this question, but
Speaker 4:  my argument has been that there isn't a version of that in this complaint.
Speaker 4:  Alex's response, which I think is fair, is that basically the, the
Speaker 4:  victim in this is us, the people who use these devices, but like
Speaker 4:  if If you were a lawyer standing up in front of people trying to argue this
Speaker 4:  case, how does it feel to you from seeing the complaint? It
Speaker 4:  it you in terms of just like handicapping your chances of being able to prove
Speaker 4:  this in court?
Speaker 8:  I, I, I wish I knew what evidence they were sitting on. What I would say
Speaker 8:  is Netscape was a very convenient victim
Speaker 8:  because it was the web, it represented the thing that people liked.
Speaker 8:  Here's the exciting new thing, like why are you getting on the internet to,
Speaker 8:  to use this? And Microsoft wants to crush it and
Speaker 8:  own it. And that's a good story to tell. I think in this case,
Speaker 8:  it's much more like look at Apple looking at any threats to
Speaker 8:  its business and sending emails saying we can't let that buy. Look at Apple
Speaker 8:  saying we cannot allow people to buy cheaper things.
Speaker 8:  I, you know, we, we've talked a lot really just talking about, about like
Speaker 8:  theories of antitrust law on this show and like
Speaker 8:  trying to change them from like the consumer welfare standard to blah, you
Speaker 8:  know, like all this stuff. And one thing that's really notable about this
Speaker 8:  complaint is there's no esoteric new antitrust,
Speaker 8:  new brand. It's Apple kept prices high.
Speaker 8:  That's the argument. Yep. Yep. Apple won't by by by
Speaker 8:  not allowing or these new application model to take take hold. Apple
Speaker 8:  gets to keep that price and high. And I think that actually
Speaker 8:  that's what I would focus on is you don't need this. Right?
Speaker 8:  Like yeah, the Gmail app runs everywhere. Why doesn't Xbox run
Speaker 8:  everywhere? Well, it's because Apple won't let it. Like what are the number
Speaker 8:  of things we can see in this industry that basically don't happen
Speaker 8:  because Apple won't let that happen on the iPhone. Like for lock thinking,
Speaker 8:  blah, blah. There's a lot. And I, I think the funny thing
Speaker 8:  is all those victims are also companies. The DOJ is suing.
Speaker 8:  Like, like Google is like writing out lists of the bare villain. Villain.
Speaker 8:  Meta is in that list. They're a villain. So I think it's gonna be much more
Speaker 8:  about painting Apple as a villain rather than trying to find a victim.
Speaker 2:  Hmm.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 4:  we're back. We're gonna do an actual lightning round. Yes. Because NELI is
Speaker 4:  not not here. So we can do this quickly as we like to do from time to time.
Speaker 4:  NELI, by the way, If, you see him on the beach somewhere in Mexico?
Speaker 4:  Pour him a tequila shot. He'll like that very much. Yes. All right, let's
Speaker 4:  do, we're gonna do two things each because there's been a lot of like little
Speaker 4:  news, so let's just bounce through some of it and then we'll get outta here.
Speaker 4:  You go first. What do you got?
Speaker 5:  All right. First up, YouTube is, is is bringing
Speaker 5:  their multiview that they do for sports and stuff. They're bringing it to
Speaker 5:  the iPad and iOS, which is very exciting.
Speaker 4:  Oh wait, really? Yeah. Oh, that's awesome. Yeah. I think
Speaker 4:  one of the hot takes I've developed recently is that split screen is a thing
Speaker 4:  that should exist in every app on every device. Yes. For everything all the
Speaker 4:  time. Yes. Like the more I use it on like the, the Samsung phones or the
Speaker 4:  pixels where they're getting better at sort of letting you drag apps up and
Speaker 4:  down. It's just great. It's, it's such a, and all the arguments are like,
Speaker 4:  oh, the screen's too small. You don't, no, screw that. My phone's enormous.
Speaker 4:  Let me look at two apps. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They aren't the only ones doing multiview. The other MULTIVIEW news this
Speaker 5:  week was from Peacock, which is gonna be doing multiview up to four streams
Speaker 5:  for the Olympics. And then they are planning to have that stick around
Speaker 5:  for sports, maybe even like scripted content. So you can watch
Speaker 5:  Below deck on like four streams at once. If, you wanted to theoretically
Speaker 5:  and that's, I wouldn't want to,
Speaker 4:  So there's this sports podcast I listen to shout out to the Bill
Speaker 4:  Simmons podcast and he always talks about
Speaker 4:  being able to watch basketball on one screen and movies
Speaker 4:  on another screen. And his argument is essentially if he like looks
Speaker 4:  over at the movie and it's a good part, he'll flip the volume to that and
Speaker 4:  just like watch it for a few minutes. Or if the game goes to commercials.
Speaker 4:  And I used to think that was ridiculous. And now every single time he mentions
Speaker 4:  it, I'm my God, that sounds awesome. Yeah. Like one thing hits commercials,
Speaker 4:  you just flip to the other one, go back and forth. You're like, oh, well
Speaker 4:  I don't care about the next five minutes of this dads, I'm gonna watch 10
Speaker 4:  minutes of The Godfather. Like that rules. Yeah. The
Speaker 5:  Cool dads in the nineties, they just did that. They just had like picture
Speaker 5:  and picture and for some reason computers were like, we can do that,
Speaker 5:  but we're not gonna,
Speaker 4:  Or the back button on a TV remote A plus choice.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. YouTube TV should have this, but they should have it for everything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I should just be able to have four screens of whatever the hell I wanna
Speaker 4:  watch at any time. And Peacock
Speaker 5:  Important is gonna work on every everywhere. So it's not just gonna, it's
Speaker 5:  gonna work on the apps, it's gonna work in the smart tv. Like they're rolling
Speaker 5:  it out across the board, not
Speaker 4:  Just, I say I love that you're a peacock convert now. I I'm a peacock convert.
Speaker 4:  We should disclose here now. NBC Universal, which is a, a division
Speaker 4:  of Comcast, is a minority investor in Vox Media. NELI
Speaker 4:  will happily come home from Mexico and tell you that he executive produced
Speaker 4:  a show for Netflix called The future of It's very good. Everybody should
Speaker 4:  watch it. Alex loves Peacock now, apparently. Yeah. I have always loved Peacock.
Speaker 4:  You think Netflix is gonna die. Which is weird. It's on a 40.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  On 40. That's enough.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's, I didn't say 90. Like it's gonna die eventually. Everything
Speaker 5:  does.
Speaker 4:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  All right. My first one is, which one of these do I wanna do first?
Speaker 4:  Let's talk about Beeper. So we mentioned Beeper a few minutes ago as one
Speaker 4:  of the apps that has actually become like embroiled in this whole Apple
Speaker 4:  antitrust saga gave up on the idea of trying to replace iMessage.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which good idea. Someday you might be able to, but that's a
Speaker 4:  very long time from now. And it's just back to building like a kick ass cross
Speaker 4:  platform messaging app. Which rules? They just rolled out a new app for Android
Speaker 4:  in, I think it's in public beta now. Okay. It's really good. Is it?
Speaker 4:  It's like the thing that they got back to, which I appreciate is
Speaker 4:  they're like, what if we just took Signal and WhatsApp and your Instagram
Speaker 4:  dms and LinkedIn and XI think still works. even that,
Speaker 4:  that API has been weird. I could be wrong. I'm not sure. I haven't used that
Speaker 4:  in a long time. So don't believe anything I say about X. Yeah. But basically
Speaker 4:  all the messages you get and just sort of put them all into one Organizable
Speaker 4:  inbox. That makes sense. Which with or without SMS and I message
Speaker 4:  terrifically used service.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I want that. And the app is, has always been like a little
Speaker 4:  funky at times. More janky. It's, it's sort of just built on
Speaker 4:  a series of elaborate hacks. Yeah. But they're getting very good at it
Speaker 4:  now. And the new app is really nice. So If, you use Beeper and are on Android
Speaker 4:  It Rules and it is the rare app that is way better on Android than
Speaker 4:  on iOS. So for all the Android using Verge staffers and Vergecast listeners,
Speaker 4:  this is a victory for You. Don't
Speaker 5:  Worry. I'm gonna wait till 20, 20, 30 maybe
Speaker 5:  2032 it sounds like. And and I'll have this app too.
Speaker 4:  There you go. Dude. The messaging app is about to get, or the messaging app
Speaker 4:  world in general is about to get real weird. Yeah. WhatsApp is doing the
Speaker 4:  thing where it's interoperating, the EU is forcing everybody to interoperate.
Speaker 4:  Like it's gonna get very strange. But I think in mostly really good ways
Speaker 4:  you're gonna be able to just like get all your messages, all the places,
Speaker 4:  which is how this should have worked forever.
Speaker 5:  So the 2002 is gonna come back, but instead of like Adio
Speaker 5:  and whatever the Windows version of that was called, start with a T.
Speaker 4:  Trillion. Trillion,
Speaker 5:  That was it.
Speaker 4:  There was also Pigeon. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which I,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's good. Give, inject all those apps back into my van. Go just right
Speaker 4:  into your vans. All right. What's your second one?
Speaker 5:  Okay, my second one is, Allison wrote a really cute piece this
Speaker 5:  week and it just felt appropriate. We talked so much about super apps. I
Speaker 5:  kind of think SGO Mini is like a super app, but for babies
Speaker 4:  Now we're talking. Tell me so much more.
Speaker 5:  Well, you know, she, she, she was like, she, she compared it
Speaker 5:  to, to like Blippy but not Blippy. Oh. She was just like, it gives
Speaker 5:  a bunch of little games that kids can play. It's all in one place.
Speaker 5:  They're all like good games for small children, for babies.
Speaker 5:  'cause she has a baby like two years of babies. Right.
Speaker 4:  You said super app for babies. And I started imagining like my 15 month
Speaker 4:  old son running around being like, I got Goodnight Moon in here. I got a
Speaker 4:  bunch of trucks in here. Ah, sick Honey Nut Cheerios. Got that in here.
Speaker 5:  Like I can message
Speaker 4:  My mom. Yeah. The rules. I'm into this. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  Not quite their yet. I don't know if that's their, that's 2.0 Yeah. That,
Speaker 5:  yeah. I don't know if that's actually their ambitions, but it feature
Speaker 4:  Cheerios like
Speaker 5:  That's, they, they, it's, it's a lot of structured games and it's for, it's
Speaker 5:  for really small children instead of, because like If, you go on YouTube
Speaker 5:  If, you go to to the app store and you try to find
Speaker 5:  games for babies, you'll have a time
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's a mess. Yeah. It's a total mess. And I will say this is, I'm, I'm
Speaker 4:  glad you brought this up because we get a surprising amount of emails
Speaker 4:  and calls to the hotline basically all asking
Speaker 4:  variations of the same question, which is just like, what do I do with my
Speaker 4:  kid on screens and devices and computers? 'cause we're like
Speaker 4:  at this point where I, when kids are like, I don't know, eight.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You have to start having like a really real series of complicated conversations
Speaker 4:  about like what it means to use the internet younger than that. It's just
Speaker 4:  like, I I I'm just gonna plant you in front of something and something's
Speaker 4:  gonna happen. But this question of like, is YouTube kids a safe place to
Speaker 4:  be is increasingly kind of fraught because there's all kinds of weird stuff
Speaker 4:  on YouTube kids. Yeah. It gets weird and like there's been this stuff recently
Speaker 4:  with AI generated videos going in front of kids that is spooking a lot of
Speaker 4:  people I think for totally good reasons. So there's this sense of like,
Speaker 4:  what is the right call here? And we're having all these complicated que discussions
Speaker 4:  about screen time and what it means to be put in front of these devices.
Speaker 4:  And so for stuff like this that's just like cool, silly,
Speaker 4:  low stakes, fun stuff. Like Yeah. There's so little of that in
Speaker 4:  the world right now. I honestly, I'm very glad,
Speaker 5:  I wish I'd known about this before all of this because
Speaker 5:  when I saw my, my godson recently, I was like, I don't know what to do. And
Speaker 5:  like pulled up one of those videos where like the squirrel eats nuts that's
Speaker 5:  supposed to distract cats. And I was like, does this work for a
Speaker 5:  6-year-old? It doesn't
Speaker 4:  It I bet. I bet it doesn't. I will say I found an hour long video that's
Speaker 4:  just people feeding red pandas and you know
Speaker 4:  who that super worked for is both me and my son. Yeah. We sat like
Speaker 4:  wrapped in front of that thing for an entire hour.
Speaker 5:  Like you watch those animals eat and you're like, wow, look at them. Go,
Speaker 5:  yeah, that's great. I wanna do that. It was,
Speaker 4:  Oh it was so nice. I have known notes. My son's also very into trains,
Speaker 4:  so we just watch a lot of videos. I just wanna say there is a, there is a
Speaker 4:  man on the internet who just makes hour
Speaker 4:  long videos of trains. Yeah. And it just cuts from train to
Speaker 4:  train and he travels the world and does all the trains. His name is Mike
Speaker 4:  something and I love him. He, you are my favorite.
Speaker 4:  Let's be friends.
Speaker 5:  I love a train guy. I love a train guy.
Speaker 4:  And they all have like 10 million views. Yeah. Which is so funny. Yeah, it's
Speaker 4:  great. Alright, my second one is that I saw the Humane
Speaker 4:  pin this morning. Ooh. This is the reason I'm in New York. What? So
Speaker 4:  the Humane pin is coming out
Speaker 5:  Someday. We waited until now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We have two to three more hours of this to do. Yes. Get ready
Speaker 4:  and a Humane put out a video yesterday Wednesday
Speaker 4:  that I think was the single most useful piece of content Humane
Speaker 4:  has ever published. Okay. It's like almost 20 minutes long. And they're basically
Speaker 4:  just like, here's what the AI pin is, here's what it does and here's how
Speaker 4:  it works. Okay. Very helpful. And then I got to go see it this morning and
Speaker 4:  talk to Iran and Bethany, the co-founders of the company spent like 90 minutes
Speaker 4:  just like goofing around with the thing. I still have
Speaker 4:  lots of questions. We're gonna get to review it at some point. I'm very excited
Speaker 4:  about it, but I actually got to like, hold the thing in my hand and use it.
Speaker 4:  And I will say I have, I have said a lot of mean things about the AI
Speaker 4:  pin on this podcast. It's a very cool piece of technology. Is it
Speaker 4:  a good product that is worth the money? I, no, I just still feels like
Speaker 4:  probably not, but like they made the thing like it works.
Speaker 5:  I wanna point out, I I, I'm now a Peacock fan and
Speaker 5:  you're now, oh
Speaker 4:  My God, what have we become? Well
Speaker 5:  Who are we? Like I know NELI goes
Speaker 4:  Tonik Nico
Speaker 5:  Hate. Oh my God.
Speaker 4:  This is where we are. This is life now. Every, but no, I, I'm actually very
Speaker 4:  excited about it because we're, we're in this phase now where we're gonna
Speaker 4:  get the Humane AI pin and then I think sometime like in
Speaker 4:  weeks, not months later, we're gonna get the Rabbit R one. Yeah. And then
Speaker 4:  there's also this company Brilliant Labs, which makes the frame glasses.
Speaker 4:  And I was talking to their CEO yesterday, they're about to ship in April.
Speaker 4:  And so we're getting this first run of like, real
Speaker 4:  honest to God AI gadgets. Yes. And it's gonna be really
Speaker 4:  interesting. And we're like, the big question is basically like,
Speaker 4:  are any of these better than a smartphone? Do I need this if I have
Speaker 4:  a smartphone? Shouldn't these have just been smartphone apps? Like super
Speaker 4:  fun, interesting questions. Like what does a smartphone mean in my life?
Speaker 4:  Is I think like a big question of 2024 for a lot of people. It certainly
Speaker 4:  has been for me so far. And like, I'm just very excited to try all of these
Speaker 4:  gadgets and just playing with the pen, it was like, okay, I have big questions
Speaker 4:  about how this fits into my life. And whether, yeah, $700 and a pretty
Speaker 4:  expensive monthly subscription is a pretty steep
Speaker 4:  price tag that this thing meets TBD. But like
Speaker 4:  how did it feel? The thing works, it feels really good. Does it just from
Speaker 4:  like a pure, like they made a gadget thing,
Speaker 4:  it just feels good. It hits, got a charging case that feels like one of those
Speaker 4:  sort of worry stones and has a really nice hinge. Like it's, it's made
Speaker 4:  by people who love hardware in a way that I very much appreciate. Did they
Speaker 4:  make a good product? I don't know, but boy did they make a cool thing that
Speaker 4:  I'm like the laser projector. I'm so spectacularly
Speaker 4:  unconvinced by. Yeah. But it's kind of fun to like do the thing
Speaker 4:  and you like tip your hand forward to scroll down and it's like deeply silly.
Speaker 4:  but it was kind of fun. I
Speaker 5:  Loved watching you do this just now.
Speaker 4:  That's literally what you do. You hold it up and it's like kind of right
Speaker 4:  at this level. And then If, you wanna scroll down, you literally just tilt
Speaker 4:  your hand towards you. So, and If, you wanna scroll up, you tilt your hand
Speaker 4:  away like a segue and you, and then you click to click. It's, it's a, it's
Speaker 4:  a hand segue. It's a, it's a virtual segue
Speaker 4:  for your poem. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Of course. That's how they actually marketing pitched it to everyone
Speaker 4:  Market. Yeah. That's perfect. But yeah, I, I suspect if, if Humane is
Speaker 4:  right about when it's gonna ship, that should happen very soon. They've been
Speaker 4:  saying like, end of March, it was supposed to be earlier in March. They've
Speaker 4:  been saying end of March, I think into April potentially.
Speaker 4:  So like all of this is happening and we've been talking about these gadgets
Speaker 4:  for months. Yeah. And we're actually gonna get to like, use them in the world
Speaker 4:  and I'm very excited about
Speaker 5:  It. I am so excited for you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's gonna be good stuff. I'm so excited. My goal is for my review
Speaker 4:  of the AI pin to be longer than Eli's 8,500
Speaker 4:  word review of the Vision Pro.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna put
Speaker 4:  A, I'm really excited. Word
Speaker 5:  Count. Like maximum long.
Speaker 4:  Just close the Google doc. Yeah. At 2,500 words. That feels right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Alright. We have gone on way too long. We've had a great time as we are want
Speaker 4:  to do this has been very fun. Yeah. Yeah. Thank you for doing this. Thanks
Speaker 4:  to Lauren for being here. She's lovely. Meli for joining from the beach.
Speaker 4:  We are also going to be talking so much about this. Like, I
Speaker 4:  think it's, it's gonna be a weird case because it's going to ebb and flow
Speaker 4:  pretty aggressively. Like, I think my guess would be that we're gonna have
Speaker 4:  a bunch more news in the next few days as reactions start to come in and
Speaker 4:  we start to get more reporting on what people are thinking and where some
Speaker 4:  of this evidence comes from. And who are the other companies that are being
Speaker 4:  kind of obliquely referred to in the complaint.
Speaker 4:  Big lull. Like big lull.
Speaker 5:  a cool, a regular smartphone.
Speaker 4:  It's a cool smartphone. It's
Speaker 5:  A cool smartphone.
Speaker 3:  us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is the production
Speaker 3:  of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced by Andrew
Speaker 3:  Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.