# Transcript
ID: 0376376a-fc94-4b6c-b841-483be4437f40
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/165604127018391832/522953423619683794/s93290-US-2500s-1721554357.mp3
Description: On this episode of The Vergecast, senior producer Will Poor explores the AI-tinged worlds of Dries Depoorter. Depoorter has built all manner of quirky and provocative installations and online experiments. There’s a clock that tells you how much of your life you’ve already lived; a phone charger that only works when your eyes are closed; a mobile chat app that you can only use when your phone has less than 5% battery.
His most eyebrow-raising work, though, is around AI and surveillance. In his projects Depoorter takes publicly available webcam footage from around the world, and uses it to stalk celebrities, catch jaywalkers in the act, keep politicians honest, and generally make you wonder about your own privacy and anonymity.
We talked with Depoorter about how he creates his work, how he thinks about the future of AI, and how he responds to the people who see his art and want to turn it into commerce. It’s a wild conversation, so check it out above. To see all of Dries’ work, head over to his portfolio.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (21 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  let's, let's see where AI is being used that isn't just to like
Speaker 3:  write slightly better business emails. Yeah. What'd you find?
Speaker 4:  I went as far afield as I could go. I wanted to get
Speaker 4:  away from the hype and skepticism cycle around all
Speaker 4:  the AI tools that we're talking about, get away from all the product announcements
Speaker 4:  that we're following. I wanted to make AI
Speaker 4:  kind of unfamiliar to myself again and
Speaker 4:  a coworker as I was chatting about this reminded me of this thing that got
Speaker 4:  shared around The Verge a ton a couple of years ago. It was a project
Speaker 4:  that was called The Follower and it used facial
Speaker 4:  recognition to match social media photos
Speaker 4:  to open webcam footage. So basically this thing
Speaker 4:  looked at unsecured webcams in like Times Square
Speaker 4:  and then it looked at public Instagram photos taken at the same time in the
Speaker 4:  same place and used facial recognition to match up
Speaker 4:  the people that appeared in both feeds. So you got this creepy
Speaker 4:  second angle on social media posts that came from these
Speaker 4:  unsecured webcams. Oh
Speaker 3:  Man, that's one of those things that it's like you put all this information
Speaker 3:  on the internet and you sort of exist in the world knowing that there are
Speaker 3:  lots of cameras around, but I feel like nobody ever thinks about it And like
Speaker 3:  we've talked about this a lot on this show that like having
Speaker 3:  computers collect information about you is one thing and it feels bad, but
Speaker 3:  you don't really think about it. But then when it shows it back to you, yes
Speaker 3:  it becomes, it, it feels different, right? Like it becomes visceral in a
Speaker 3:  way that feels almost like horrifying even though you're like, well yeah,
Speaker 3:  I took that picture and put it on the internet
Speaker 4:  Completely. And for it to be paired with, as you say, these webcam
Speaker 4:  feeds that you know in the abstract are out there everywhere and
Speaker 4:  following you around, but you just don't have evidence of
Speaker 4:  you out there in them. And that's what this does. So if you
Speaker 4:  scroll through this project, I I, I saw this one photo of
Speaker 4:  a guy in a leather jacket who's casually leaning against this famous
Speaker 4:  bar in Dublin. It's a very standard sort of social media
Speaker 4:  post, but then in the camera footage you get to watch him try
Speaker 4:  out different poses and angles. He, he ab tests jacket or
Speaker 4:  no jacket. When he is taking this picture, you, you see how the social media
Speaker 4:  post came to be. There's this other shot of these
Speaker 4:  very two cool hip guys strolling through Times Square.
Speaker 4:  It's really epic looking, but then in the webcam footage
Speaker 4:  you see them just walking through busy times Square, they almost bump into
Speaker 4:  someone who's wheeling luggage around. It is just like, it totally changes
Speaker 4:  your view on social media posts and how they came
Speaker 4:  to be.
Speaker 3:  That thing is like a shtick of some social media posts. Like I saw a
Speaker 3:  TikTok the other day that was a person explaining how to
Speaker 3:  sleep in an airport and she like, you know, put her bags on and
Speaker 3:  attached everything to her in such a way that it would be hard to get off
Speaker 3:  of her. Puts on her eye mask and puts up her hood and goes to sleep. And
Speaker 3:  then it was stitched by somebody who like walks over waves in her face and
Speaker 3:  then just steals her phone. And it's like the, the the like pulling
Speaker 3:  back the curtain on how this stuff actually works is like part of how this
Speaker 3:  all works on the internet but the people doing it are still the ones in control.
Speaker 3:  This is just like the world is telling on you in a way
Speaker 3:  that it kind of like, like there are people who would make those behind the
Speaker 3:  scenes video of them doing the 10 different tries, the blooper reel and whatever,
Speaker 3:  but when it's somebody else doing it to you because they saw it happen,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's like if that person stitching the TikTok was actually there for
Speaker 4:  the recording of the first TikTok and messing with the person as they were
Speaker 4:  doing it, which is just next level weird and creepy. Seriously
Speaker 4:  that's what I gravitated towards. 'cause it's all of this very
Speaker 4:  publicly available data plus AI equals
Speaker 4:  weird disconcerting stuff and I, I just, I figured whoever made
Speaker 4:  made that, whoever made the follower would have a lot of
Speaker 4:  very different, very interesting thoughts on ai. So I called him up and talked
Speaker 4:  to him about it.
Speaker 4:  Just to get started, I'll start with the hardest question first, just tell
Speaker 4:  me your name and what you do.
Speaker 6:  My name is DRIs Porter and I'm an artist working with
Speaker 6:  technology.
Speaker 4:  DRIs is 33 years old. He lives in Belgium and for
Speaker 4:  more than a decade he's been using technology in ways that are
Speaker 4:  inspiring silly and kind of disturbing his
Speaker 4:  work is this unique mix of technical proficiency and outlandish
Speaker 4:  ideas. So
Speaker 6:  I have a background in electronics. I
Speaker 6:  studied electronics for six years. Really
Speaker 6:  loved it.
Speaker 6:  I was really enjoying experimenting with the the
Speaker 6:  electronics but I missed a sort of creativity.
Speaker 6:  So after I was graduated
Speaker 6:  I went to an art school and that was like a, a really
Speaker 6:  weird switch. I was studying media arts
Speaker 6:  and I really loved it. It was something
Speaker 6:  totally different. After that I went to an
Speaker 6:  advertising company and I worked for two years as an net concept
Speaker 6:  provider. That's someone that's come up with with IDs
Speaker 6:  for the, for the agency. So
Speaker 4:  That's the fuel mixture for this guy. Electronics plus art
Speaker 4:  plus weird concepts. When I scrolled through Dre's portfolio,
Speaker 4:  the first concepts that caught my eye weren't actually AI powered.
Speaker 4:  Lots of his ideas are these simple, clever conceits brought to
Speaker 4:  life. They're little bobble universes that play by one or two really simple
Speaker 4:  rules like he built this interactive exhibit called Recharge.
Speaker 4:  It's a phone charger that only works when your eyes are closed
Speaker 4:  in the gallery. You lie back in a lawn chair and plug your phone into an
Speaker 4:  outlet, but there's a camera pointed at your head and a computer
Speaker 4:  running face tracking software. So the exhibit only sends
Speaker 4:  electricity to the outlet if your eyes are closed. He also made a
Speaker 4:  website that You can take over and post anything you want, but only
Speaker 4:  if you have more followers on X than the last person To do that.
Speaker 4:  The latest person to post is a guy named Kev Adams who just wrote Subscribe
Speaker 4:  to Kev Adams. One other project that I still can't
Speaker 4:  get outta my head is a little gadgety looking LED clock in
Speaker 4:  a classy wooden frame that dries actually makes and sells.
Speaker 6:  So I have a project called Short Life. It's
Speaker 6:  a clock. It's a clock that shows a percentage
Speaker 6:  and that's a personal percentage because it shows
Speaker 6:  how much of your life that is already completed based on
Speaker 6:  your life dependency in your country. I have like different people
Speaker 6:  that order it, like sometimes I have
Speaker 6:  fathers that bought it for the newborn or
Speaker 6:  this year I sold a clock for someone that has more than
Speaker 6:  120% so that that person was
Speaker 6:  108 years old.
Speaker 4:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 6:  And I will only sell 1 million,
Speaker 4:  Just one, just 1 million.
Speaker 6:  It's a limited edition, only 1 million
Speaker 4:  Order Now before it's too late if it's not clear from all these
Speaker 4:  projects, DRIs loves the elegance of a good simple idea
Speaker 4:  brought to life through lots of tinkering.
Speaker 6:  The first idea is most of the time really complex,
Speaker 6:  but then I try to
Speaker 6:  make them really small. For me it's important that I can explain the
Speaker 6:  ID in one sentence. I also have this notes app
Speaker 6:  in my phone and I note a lot of random ideas.
Speaker 6:  Most of the time they're really bad ID
Speaker 6:  and what I do is I always go back
Speaker 6:  to the list and what I do is combining two bad ideas
Speaker 6:  with together that makes like a better idea.
Speaker 4:  Do you have an example of two bad ideas that made one good idea?
Speaker 6:  I think a good example here was an app that I
Speaker 6:  developed named Die With Me And Die
Speaker 6:  With Me is an app which You can only use when you have less than
Speaker 6:  5% battery on your phone. If you have less than 5% battery
Speaker 6:  on your phone, You can start chatting to other people
Speaker 6:  having a a battery below 5%. How I came up with
Speaker 6:  this idea, I was in a city where I was not able to
Speaker 6:  find my way back
Speaker 6:  to my hotel because my phone died. And for me that
Speaker 6:  was really inspiring and I was like, okay. I'm like really?
Speaker 6:  I really, really depended on on my phone. I am even not
Speaker 6:  able to find, find my way, my way back.
Speaker 6:  And then I, I had this idea like, okay, I'll make an app
Speaker 6:  that You can only use when you have a low battery. And I
Speaker 6:  noted that later that night in my phone and I
Speaker 6:  think it was on my phone for like more than a year because
Speaker 6:  I was not able to find like a good ID with it
Speaker 6:  because I had like only this concept of, okay, let's
Speaker 6:  build an app which You can only use when you have less than 5% battery.
Speaker 6:  But I was like, really? Okay, it needs to be like a dating app
Speaker 6:  or sort of a game. But that was really not
Speaker 6:  perfect for me. It didn't click or something.
Speaker 6:  And then I had like a vague idea of like a chat app
Speaker 6:  and then I just, one day I was reading through all the
Speaker 6:  ideas and then it clicked like, okay Die With Me is like, and
Speaker 6:  chat app. That's the best concept
Speaker 4:  Of all the ideas that DRIs mixes and matches in his work. There are
Speaker 4:  two that just seem to keep coming up over and over again,
Speaker 4:  AI and surveillance. He says he got started down
Speaker 4:  this path after making a discovery on one of the sketchier corners of the
Speaker 4:  internet.
Speaker 6:  During my work at the advertising
Speaker 6:  agency, I was really into exploring
Speaker 6:  open cameras. When I talk about open cameras, I'm talking about
Speaker 6:  cameras that are connected to the internet with a standard password
Speaker 6:  or no password at all.
Speaker 4:  How did you discover them and what was so exciting about
Speaker 4:  that resource?
Speaker 6:  I discovered them through website called show them.
Speaker 6:  It's sort of a search engine
Speaker 6:  but it doesn't index website
Speaker 6:  but it index machines on the internet. So with
Speaker 6:  this tool you are able to find open cameras,
Speaker 6:  you find cameras and living rooms and and places where people
Speaker 6:  I think don't want to, to have that publicly open.
Speaker 4:  I checked out this website Shodan and it is exactly how
Speaker 4:  DRIs describes it. After just a couple of clicks I found
Speaker 4:  myself browsing webcams that definitely aren't supposed to be public.
Speaker 4:  Some were innocuous, like closeup bird feeder cams, but I
Speaker 4:  also watched people playing with dogs inside a doggy daycare
Speaker 4:  business. There was another camera in a living room that I could
Speaker 4:  control, like pan it around. I got really weirded out
Speaker 4:  and closed all the tabs. Shoan is a site that you could do deeply
Speaker 4:  sketchy things with. And this is a personal nightmare
Speaker 4:  of mine that I don't know enough about how my own gadgets
Speaker 4:  work or have enough of a handle on the tech around me generally
Speaker 4:  that I'm somehow broadcasting myself out into the world without realizing
Speaker 4:  it. Like I'm a sticky note on my webcam person.
Speaker 4:  I'm superstitious about all of it.
Speaker 3:  Okay, but wait, hold on. Will hang on. Let's talk about how
Speaker 3:  superstitious this actually is, right? Because there is a thing
Speaker 3:  happening with all of these AI companies that there is this incredible race
Speaker 3:  to get tons of data, a vast amount of that data that is just like
Speaker 3:  a thing that someone made that is finished on the internet, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We kind of know what to do with an article or even like a
Speaker 3:  YouTube video. But the idea of all of these webcams around
Speaker 3:  just collecting data all the time, like if you think about live video as
Speaker 3:  just a live stream of data, it feels very different to me. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like you're saying, like you're, you're finding these things where I think
Speaker 3:  lots of people are setting up webcams and don't know, like you, we've all
Speaker 3:  heard the horror stories over the years about people who are hacking into
Speaker 3:  other people's like baby monitors and all kinds of stuff. And so part of
Speaker 3:  me is, I'm not really a tinfoil hat kind of person, but the idea of
Speaker 3:  these are unbelievable fountains of data, plus there
Speaker 3:  are more and more compelling reasons for people to want to get access to
Speaker 3:  and store forever. All of that data feels kind of terrifying.
Speaker 3:  Especially then if You can figure out how to ask kind of the right
Speaker 3:  questions of all of that stuff. Like maybe that's the challenge there is
Speaker 3:  we're gonna end up with just a hundred years of Times Square and then the
Speaker 3:  question is like, well what do we, what do we do with any of this? But it's
Speaker 3:  all there, you just have to know what to do with it, right? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's, well first of all, thank you for co-signing my paranoia
Speaker 4:  because
Speaker 3:  This is, I mean it's funny, I'm not, I'm not a sticky note on the webcam
Speaker 3:  convers, yeah. Like it's, I never really have been. My sense is like I'm
Speaker 3:  not quite in the, I have nothing to hide camp, but
Speaker 3:  I'm in the, like, as long as I'm reasonably responsible, it's probably gonna
Speaker 3:  be fine camp. But like I've been to Times Square, there is
Speaker 3:  probably's, lots of footage of you there. Footage of you
Speaker 4:  In
Speaker 3:  Times, times Square or some Yeah. And I, that is where it's like, okay, it's,
Speaker 3:  it's no longer just like a thing that I'm in relative control of and
Speaker 3:  should avoid making mistakes. It's just like being a person in the world.
Speaker 3:  You become training data.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I mean that just fans. I, I don't, I think you're right that that
Speaker 4:  the vulnerability of my MacBook camera probably has not
Speaker 4:  changed dramatically with the advent of all of these AI companies who bring
Speaker 4:  up data, but it just fans the flames so much
Speaker 4:  more. Totally. And so like these are when I, when I look
Speaker 4:  through all of Dre's projects, this is all what comes up for
Speaker 4:  me. And so that's like, that's my reaction to it. And I'm so interested in
Speaker 4:  his work because I think he has all of the same questions
Speaker 4:  that we are asking, but instead of putting sticky notes on
Speaker 4:  his webcams, he made a lot of really fascinating stuff around
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 6:  I was really inspired by this and it and it started a lot of
Speaker 6:  my projects around surveillance.
Speaker 4:  We need to take a quick break, but when we come back, DRE starts
Speaker 4:  mashing together. AI and sketchy webcam feeds and things
Speaker 4:  get real weird fast.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I was exploring a lot, but
Speaker 6:  I'm, I always explored with open source too. So if I
Speaker 6:  need in a project and face recognition, I don't start writing
Speaker 6:  it from zero. I use something that is out there that I'm able
Speaker 6:  to use and, and, and I combine all those
Speaker 6:  tools that are out there. So most of the time
Speaker 6:  I don't need to write everything from zero.
Speaker 4:  Do you have ideas first and then you go and find the tools
Speaker 4:  that will help you? Or do you learn about a new tool and have an
Speaker 4:  idea? Which comes first?
Speaker 6:  Hmm. Yeah, it's, most of the time it's me
Speaker 6:  exploring new, new technologies and just playing
Speaker 6:  around, even checking out
Speaker 6:  documentation of software documentation of a new
Speaker 6:  API. That is really interesting. Checking out the documentation of the
Speaker 6:  GPT, the, the API that's, that sparks a lot of ideas for
Speaker 6:  me.
Speaker 4:  In this case, he taught himself how to use some computer vision algorithms
Speaker 4:  from an open source library called Open cv, which
Speaker 4:  by the way is a dizzyingly huge and powerful set of tools.
Speaker 4:  Chat GPT might get more attention these days, but open source
Speaker 4:  libraries like Open CV are putting things like facial recognition into
Speaker 4:  a lot more hands for better or worse.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, DRIs gave himself a crash course in Python and then
Speaker 4:  used OpenCV to hack together this funny little machine.
Speaker 6:  I selected an area where the traffic light is
Speaker 6:  and then it sort of counts up all
Speaker 6:  the, the pixels and it searches for the, the main color
Speaker 6:  in that area. If that main color is red
Speaker 6:  or if it's more red than green, then
Speaker 6:  the software thinks it's like, okay, this is a green or red light
Speaker 6:  and then it checks in a specific zone
Speaker 6:  if someone is crossing over with the yeah, person detection.
Speaker 4:  But he still needed something to do with his auto jaywalk detector.
Speaker 4:  He needed the second idea to combine with this one. So
Speaker 4:  he added a few more steps and debuted jaywalking.
Speaker 6:  It's an interactive installation where You can report
Speaker 6:  jaywalkers from all over the world with the help of
Speaker 6:  open cameras that are pointed to crossroads
Speaker 4:  Visitors to the installation stand in a dark room in front of a bright screen
Speaker 4:  playing a stream from an unsecured traffic camera. The
Speaker 4:  screen also displays a big graphic showing whether the stoplight in view
Speaker 4:  is red or green. So participants stand and they watch
Speaker 4:  live as unsuspecting people cross the street, the street.
Speaker 4:  But all the while there's one other thing in front of them, a big
Speaker 4:  round button on a pedestal, the kind of button that looks so
Speaker 4:  satisfying to hit. What happens if it identifies a Jay
Speaker 4:  walker? What happens next?
Speaker 6:  You get the question, would you like to report to Jay Walker?
Speaker 6:  And then the, the visitor of the, the interactive installation
Speaker 6:  can report the jaywalker by pressing the
Speaker 6:  emergency button and then it'll send an email to the closest police
Speaker 6:  station Okay. With a screenshot of the jaywalker. And
Speaker 6:  that email address only exists for 10 minutes.
Speaker 4:  Gotcha. Okay. The system is automatically
Speaker 4:  detecting Jay walker's and it's, you're, you're forcing a decision
Speaker 4:  by the viewer of the the installation. Yes. What they want to
Speaker 4:  do with that, if you've like done any machine vision on the installations
Speaker 4:  to know how many people press the button of, of all the viewers,
Speaker 6:  In the beginning it was not saving this data. Then later,
Speaker 6:  I mean like the last couple of years I saved this data and
Speaker 6:  it was a lot exhibited in Belgium and the Netherlands.
Speaker 6:  And what I saw that is that more people in the Netherlands
Speaker 6:  presses than in Belgium.
Speaker 4:  AI plus surveillance turned out to be a pretty deep well for
Speaker 4:  Drees. He made an exhibit that tracks celebrities using
Speaker 4:  unsecured camera footage. Another that constantly searches
Speaker 4:  webcams for an anonymous man that his sister met once by chance.
Speaker 4:  Both of those are physical installations that are built to run indefinitely
Speaker 4:  in galleries. They're these little purpose-built boxes of
Speaker 4:  electronics with screens that are forever showing live webcam footage.
Speaker 4:  They're constantly on the lookout for whatever their algorithms have been
Speaker 4:  trained to track. They look harmless and contained on their
Speaker 4:  own until you think about what they're actually doing.
Speaker 4:  My favorite DRE project though is the entirely virtual
Speaker 4:  Flemish scrollers.
Speaker 6:  So the Flemish Scrollers is a project that checks the live
Speaker 6:  stream of my government. They have meetings and they
Speaker 6:  live stream this on YouTube and I made
Speaker 6:  software that is constantly checking the live stream to
Speaker 6:  find as a politician is on their phone. If there for
Speaker 6:  a certain amount of minutes on their phone, it'll tweet them
Speaker 6:  and tag them with the help of face recognition and the
Speaker 6:  tweets look like, Hey dear, distracted, please
Speaker 6:  stay focused. Then you have like a short video of of that
Speaker 6:  person.
Speaker 4:  The idea of using these creepy tools for accountability is just
Speaker 4:  so surprising and hilarious to me. I, I want this in America, I
Speaker 4:  want congress fully surveilled by AI while they're debating tech
Speaker 4:  policy. It's, it's just too good. So that's my
Speaker 4:  personal favorite. But the piece I wanted to talk the most about
Speaker 4:  was the follower, the one one that matches social media posts with
Speaker 4:  camera footage. Dre says that one day he and his
Speaker 4:  friends were hanging out on a terrace in a touristy area in Portugal
Speaker 4:  and they were watching people on the street take selfies and they
Speaker 4:  thought, well we know where and when those photos are being taken,
Speaker 4:  can we go find them on social media? They poked around for a while
Speaker 4:  and came up empty, but it gave drees an idea
Speaker 6:  And then actually I did the same but automated the whole thing. So
Speaker 6:  I found cameras again, open cameras where
Speaker 6:  people are taking a lot of photos and I saved videos
Speaker 6:  for I think two or three weeks, something like that.
Speaker 6:  And then at the same time I saved all the images
Speaker 6:  from that location on Instagram. So all the
Speaker 6:  photos that were tagged with the location
Speaker 6:  around the camera was saved. And then the hardest part of
Speaker 6:  course was finding that the, the people in the videos at
Speaker 6:  the right moment,
Speaker 4:  The system did its best to match faces between the camera footage and the
Speaker 4:  Instagram photos. Dre says he went through and weed out false
Speaker 4:  positives and then he cut the best examples together into a video
Speaker 4:  and he posted it online. And what was the response to it?
Speaker 6:  I mean, a lot of people were checking it out the day I, I launched
Speaker 6:  it, people were really surprised
Speaker 4:  It was a hit. And I get why it is this one, two
Speaker 4:  punch of a reminder that anonymity is not what you
Speaker 4:  think it is, especially if you're on social media, but
Speaker 4:  increasingly if you're just alive in the world,
Speaker 4:  the whole thing started a conversation that DRIs wasn't totally
Speaker 4:  prepared for.
Speaker 6:  There was also like a lot of false information. Like there was
Speaker 6:  a video saying like, okay, it's an open source
Speaker 6:  tool that works perfectly and you
Speaker 6:  just need to upload an Instagram photo and it'll check all
Speaker 6:  the cameras in the world. Yeah. That was really not, I mean
Speaker 6:  that's not the tool I produced, right? It's only
Speaker 6:  working with like specific
Speaker 6:  cameras.
Speaker 4:  Although if part of your goal is to make people think about what's possible,
Speaker 4:  the version in their head that's bigger and more powerful
Speaker 4:  is also possible technically. So in some senses do you feel like
Speaker 4:  you're, you're making people think about the bigger scarier tool even if
Speaker 4:  the one that you made is smaller?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, and I think what is also important to to
Speaker 6:  remember is that I am only one person
Speaker 6:  producing this. I have limited
Speaker 6:  resources. My skillset is just a basic one.
Speaker 6:  I mean like, I'm not, it's not a team that built this. It's just like a
Speaker 6:  bit of playing around I guess.
Speaker 4:  I mean do, do you want people to think, well, alright, if this was just one
Speaker 4:  person who built this, imagine what a whole team of people
Speaker 4:  can do. Are those questions that you think about?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that was something that I saw a lot in the
Speaker 6:  reaction. Like, okay, it's just only one
Speaker 6:  person. Imagine what a government can do.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Wait, will I have, I have just a really quick thought on this, which
Speaker 3:  is there's this thing that Dres is doing where he's making all this sound
Speaker 3:  really like theoretical and sort of, I just did a project. Yes. What if other
Speaker 3:  people do this project, but like this stuff is happening, this is so like
Speaker 3:  ingrained in the product of all of this stuff. I mean we spent all this time
Speaker 3:  talking about Clearview ai, which was just a search engine of people's faces.
Speaker 3:  Like that's, that is what he's talking about here. Like it's the same kind
Speaker 3:  of thing and used for I would say largely
Speaker 3:  terrifying purposes. We think about, like Neli on the show always
Speaker 3:  talks all the time about how his favorite use case for AR is
Speaker 3:  to have it identify people when he's walking past them. So
Speaker 3:  it can be like, oh, who is this person that I met before? Like, that's the
Speaker 3:  same thing, right? It's a, it's a less nefarious version of exactly the same
Speaker 3:  thing, just reminding you of who a person is. It's like
Speaker 3:  it, these are all two sides of the same coin, but this is the kind of stuff
Speaker 3:  that like isn't just happening on, on
Speaker 3:  Andres's computer to make us wonder about who we are in the world. This is
Speaker 3:  like, this is the product in so many ways and
Speaker 3:  he is right that I think he's at, at the like edge of it in
Speaker 3:  certain ways, but also is like, dude is just building an app that
Speaker 3:  other people are gonna want to use.
Speaker 3:  Is he thinking about the, the, how this all feels to him? Like he's
Speaker 3:  accidentally becoming like a pretty impressive tech developer. Somebody's
Speaker 3:  gonna like want to download his apps on the app store here at some point.
Speaker 3:  How does he feel about all that? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's so this is what is so fascinating and kind of frustrating
Speaker 4:  to talk to him is he's doing all of this incredibly relevant stuff with a
Speaker 4:  lot of parallels to things that we talk about daily,
Speaker 4:  but when you talk to him, he likes to talk exclusively
Speaker 4:  about how other people respond to this stuff or what other people
Speaker 4:  read into it. And this is where I feel like I completely
Speaker 4:  failed as an interviewer. 'cause after an hour of talking to this guy, I
Speaker 4:  couldn't get him to say why he's so interested in surveillance
Speaker 4:  or what he finds so powerful,
Speaker 4:  scary, interesting about these tools, what he wants
Speaker 4:  to say about ai. That's just not where he's at as an
Speaker 4:  artist.
Speaker 6:  I think it's me exploring. I think the most important thing is, I
Speaker 6:  don't want to put like a big message on the projects itself. Like
Speaker 6:  you need to, to, to find, I know which
Speaker 6:  kind of questions it raises, but
Speaker 6:  yeah, I don't answer them.
Speaker 4:  DRIs is so circumspect about his own intentions that he doesn't
Speaker 4:  always seem to know how to handle the response to his work.
Speaker 4:  Take for example, that project that shows Belgian politicians on their phones.
Speaker 6:  There was a person from France,
Speaker 6:  the person had a company and that person wanted to
Speaker 6:  buy the software to, to use on their employees.
Speaker 4:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 6:  And I was so surprised about this email. Like, I mean,
Speaker 6:  just showing what is possible. But then there was a
Speaker 6:  long email, I I, I think it was not a joke at first at thought,
Speaker 6:  like this is a joke, but he had like a lot of cameras in the
Speaker 6:  offices and it like, can I buy your software because I want to
Speaker 6:  use this in my company. That was pretty crazy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What did you tell him?
Speaker 6:  I I, to be honest, I didn't reply on this email because
Speaker 6:  I didn't know what to react.
Speaker 4:  I I have to imagine that was not the,
Speaker 4:  the idea that you wanted to give people necessarily or
Speaker 4:  do you not think in those terms?
Speaker 6:  Well, I
Speaker 1:  your fingertips. Expand your world with
Speaker 1:  meta ai.
Speaker 4:  you. It just in the, in the sense that there are
Speaker 4:  many, many tools being
Speaker 4:  refined all the time. New, new AI related
Speaker 4:  tools coming out, people talking about them, people interested in
Speaker 4:  them, people scared of them. What tools are you interested in?
Speaker 4:  What are you playing around with right now?
Speaker 6:  I'm playing around with voice cloning a lot. I think that's really
Speaker 6:  interesting. For the last couple of months, I'm exploring a lot of
Speaker 6:  open source models that I can run
Speaker 6:  locally. Sometimes they're better than commercial
Speaker 6:  tools. You are way more able to
Speaker 6:  configurate them in your style or something. You,
Speaker 6:  you have more parameters. That's something I'm exploring
Speaker 4:  Most of his work with generative AI is still in the tinkering stage
Speaker 4:  though. He posted one very funny demo to his site.
Speaker 6:  I did a project named the selfie
Speaker 6:  coach. I, I don't want to call it a project, I don't see
Speaker 6:  it as a final project. It's more like an experiment
Speaker 6:  and it's a tool that I developed
Speaker 6:  where You can take selfies
Speaker 6:  but it'll give you advice in what to change
Speaker 6:  in the photo. So it takes a photo and then
Speaker 6:  you are smiling and then you get advice from Kylie
Speaker 6:  Jenner with her voice.
Speaker 7:  Alright babe, let's get another angle. Okay, ready? 3, 2, 1
Speaker 7:  pose.
Speaker 4:  DRIs posted a video of himself testing this out. He poses in front of
Speaker 4:  his webcam wearing big headphones and looking out of his window. The
Speaker 4:  camera snaps a shot. There's a short pause and then
Speaker 4:  robot Kylie Jenner does her thing.
Speaker 7:  Okay, love the candid vibe, but let's add some drama, turn towards the light,
Speaker 7:  lose the headphones and think mysterious thoughts to spice it up. 'cause
Speaker 7:  lighting is everything babe.
Speaker 6:  It uses Chachi PT and a voice cloning service.
Speaker 6:  So first it takes a photo and then
Speaker 6:  the prompt is you are a selfie coach and
Speaker 6:  you are also Kylie Jenner
Speaker 6:  and say, what I need to change in the,
Speaker 6:  the photo in a really funny way. And then
Speaker 6:  I have text and then it sends it to this voice cloning service.
Speaker 6:  I trained it on I think half an hour of
Speaker 6:  voice. So you give the system like half an hour
Speaker 6:  of that person talking and then
Speaker 6:  it's able to produce any
Speaker 6:  sentence in audio with, with that person's
Speaker 6:  voice. It's quite spectacular. Add
Speaker 7:  A pop of color by holding some bright fashion accessories. It'll draw more
Speaker 7:  eyes babe.
Speaker 6:  Just me exploring a bit how those tools work
Speaker 6:  and it's quite fun. Also, the intonation is really good and
Speaker 6:  also the way she talks is it's in there. For example, she
Speaker 6:  is using a lot vape, so sometimes Chachi PT
Speaker 6:  reacts with like, ba,
Speaker 7:  Let's snap another one. You're gonna kill it.
Speaker 4:  Next up Dre says he's working on some kind of generative
Speaker 4:  dating app. Knowing him Lord only knows what that'll turn into.
Speaker 4:  But beyond that, he's pretty coy. Do you think that the fundamentals
Speaker 4:  here, the voice cloning tools will lead to some
Speaker 4:  bigger project?
Speaker 6:  Not, I don't have any good ideas at this moment with voice cloning.
Speaker 6:  It's me again, exploring a bit, and
Speaker 6:  this is something I put online.
Speaker 4:  So you're waiting, you've got lots of bad ideas and you're waiting to combine
Speaker 4:  them into some, some good ideas with voice cloning.
Speaker 6:  Yes, exactly.
Speaker 4:  Dre's work is undeniably relevant right now and it's
Speaker 4:  showing there are lots more AI themed exhibitions popping up.
Speaker 4:  He's asked to give a lot more talks these days. His ideas are just
Speaker 4:  generally around more. And I get it, I watch
Speaker 4:  as each new AI service blows up the internet and I
Speaker 4:  fret about what it's gonna do to my work, my identity.
Speaker 4:  and more than anything, I want someone who's not Sam
Speaker 4:  Altman to tell me what to think about all these hairy questions.
Speaker 4:  I probably shouldn't admit that as a tech reporter, but it's so true.
Speaker 4:  Sadly, for Meris is emphatically not here to
Speaker 4:  clear anything up. As you do more talks and do
Speaker 4:  more exhibitions, are lots of people coming to you and saying,
Speaker 4:  what do you think? What? How should I feel about all this?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, sometimes after a talk there's like the small q
Speaker 6:  and a and that's one of the most asked questions because after
Speaker 6:  a talk, I leave this open. Like I, I, yeah, here are my
Speaker 6:  projects. I explain them all. I do live experiments
Speaker 6:  on stage. I make sure it's like entertaining and fun,
Speaker 6:  but then they're like, Hey, but what's, what's your message? And
Speaker 6:  I'm like, okay, I, there's really no message at all.
Speaker 6:  I don't have any clue why I am interested in this.
Speaker 4:  I honestly can't tell if I buy that or not. It's
Speaker 4:  possible that Dres is focused on finding unique raw material like
Speaker 4:  webcam footage and dreaming up clever ways to look at it.
Speaker 4:  All the inevitable questions around privacy and anonymity.
Speaker 4:  He might have just stumbled into those, but I think
Speaker 4:  there's a clue to be found in who he's choosing to watch
Speaker 4:  celebrities, politicians, social media users,
Speaker 4:  the pettiest possible scoff laws. That's just too
Speaker 4:  interesting and provocative. A spread of people, at least
Speaker 4:  that's where my brain goes. The AI tools he's playing with,
Speaker 4:  they're powerful but agnostic on their own. They need a subject
Speaker 4:  or a target and training them to keep politicians
Speaker 4:  honest versus prosecute Jay Walkers versus tail famous
Speaker 4:  people. Each example changes my emotional
Speaker 4:  response to the whole concept of ai. Not just the one example of it,
Speaker 4:  which makes the body of his work greater than the sum of its parts.
Speaker 4:  But again, that's just me. You're not gonna get
Speaker 4:  anything like that from DRIs. I hope he forgives me for this
Speaker 4:  metaphor, but he's like a crow that leaves a weird
Speaker 4:  shiny trinket at your doorstep. Is it a gift,
Speaker 4:  a challenge, a threat? He just
Speaker 4:  drops these funny and slightly upsetting tech mysteries at
Speaker 4:  our feet and the only note he ever leaves is,
Speaker 4:  look what You can do.
Speaker 4:  The rest is up to us.
Speaker 3:  All right, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to Will Andres for
Speaker 3:  putting this whole story together. And thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 3:  There's lots more on all of the AI stuff we've been talking about at The
Speaker 3:  Verge dot com. It turns out kind of a newsy week in the
Speaker 3:  AI universe, like seemingly every week. So we'll put something in the show
Speaker 3:  notes, but as always, go read the website. We'll have some links to Dre's
Speaker 3:  work too if you wanna go check it out. As always, if you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 3:  or feelings or AI art projects you'd like us to check out or
Speaker 3:  surveillance footage of me in Times Square, you'd like me to see, You can
Speaker 3:  always email us Vergecast