# Transcript
ID: bf88ccfb-6130-49d5-81af-4570ccf5768b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5737265934328429244/-4662017448900315629/s93290-US-5318s-1716880788.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of open smart home standards:
03:25 - Microsoft’s Pavan Davuluri, leader for Windows and Devices, joins the show to discuss the future of the AI PC and what’s next for Microsoft’s hardware
Microsoft’s new Windows chief on the future of the OS, Surface, and those annoying ads
Microsoft’s big bet on building a new type of AI computer
Microsoft Build 2024: everything announced
30:25 - The Verge’s Jen Tuohy and David Pierce discuss the latest updates in the smart home world in a segment called “Does Matter matter yet?”
The Dyson WashG1 is the company’s first dedicated mop
Amazon’s Matter Casting is shaping up so nicely, I want to use it everywhere
Matter 1.3 arrives with new device type and features
Smart lighting company Brilliant is looking for a buyer
Google launches new Home APIs and turns Google TVs into smart home hubs
01:13:20 - David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about AI-powered search engines.
Google is redesigning its search engine — and it's AI all the way down
Google CEO Sundar Pichai on AI-powered search and the future of the web
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (37 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 3:  To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Open Smart Home Standards.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am cooped up inside. It's a
Speaker 3:  holiday weekend, but it's like hot and rainy all at the same
Speaker 3:  time, and it's just like a nasty time to be outside. But the upside of that
Speaker 3:  is it means I have an incredible built-in excuse to just spend
Speaker 3:  three days playing video games. And that is essentially what has happened.
Speaker 3:  I don't know if I've mentioned this on the show before, but the game over
Speaker 3:  probably the last decade that has eaten up the most of my time is fifa. The
Speaker 3:  soccer game, it's not even called FIFA anymore, it's EA Sports FC now,
Speaker 3:  but who cares? It's FIFA and I play arguably too much
Speaker 3:  fifa. I'm like pretty good at it in a way that I'm not good at a lot of the
Speaker 3:  Battle Royale games. I just get crushed at Fortnite and War Zone and all
Speaker 3:  of those. But I'm pretty good at FIFA and I have become alarmingly
Speaker 3:  into it, especially over the course of this year, and now it's
Speaker 3:  May, it's almost June, which means it's the end of the soccer season, which
Speaker 3:  means it's almost the end of the FIFA season and I'm, I'm too deep in it
Speaker 3:  at this point. I am in the subreddits, I'm in the Trading Discords.
Speaker 3:  I spent 20 bucks on a guide to trading players inside of
Speaker 3:  FIFA to get more coins, to buy more players. It's a lot. I'm deep in it.
Speaker 3:  It's a whole thing. I can tell you who all the leakers are. If you ever want
Speaker 3:  to talk about FIFA and compare ultimate teams, get at me. It's the only
Speaker 3:  thing I ever want to talk about. Luckily, for most of you, that is not what
Speaker 3:  we are here to talk about on this show today, we're gonna do two things.
Speaker 3:  One, we're gonna talk more about what has gone on with Microsoft.
Speaker 3:  The last couple of weeks. It was Build, it was the Surface launch,
Speaker 3:  and we have the person who runs Windows and Surface at
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Pavan Dava Lure on the show to talk about both the beginning
Speaker 3:  and end of this project that Microsoft has been on for a long time
Speaker 3:  and what he sees coming for the next decade too. Super fun, really
Speaker 3:  interesting. Then Gen two is gonna come on and we're gonna do a bit of a
Speaker 3:  round robin of Smart Home News because a bunch of stuff has happened, some
Speaker 3:  of which I think is actually bigger than I realized, and we're just gonna
Speaker 3:  dig into all of it and see what's really going on. Then we're gonna get to
Speaker 3:  the hotline. We're gonna talk about search engines, search engines on everybody's
Speaker 3:  mind right now. All that is coming up in just a minute. But first,
Speaker 3:  fifa, it's Champions. If you know what that means, you know
Speaker 3:  that's a big deal. If you don't know what that means, stay that way. It's
Speaker 3:  for the best But anyway. I gotta go play a bunch of fifa for some reason
Speaker 3:  that feels very important to me right now. This is The Vergecast. We'll be
Speaker 3:  right back.
Speaker 3:  few episodes, but it's because I think this is
Speaker 5:  leader for Windows and Devices.
Speaker 3:  Pavin currently runs all things Windows and Surface inside of Microsoft.
Speaker 3:  He's been in that job for a few months, but he's actually been at the company
Speaker 3:  for more than two decades and as a result has seen just about everything
Speaker 3:  in the Windows and Surface world in that time. So we started our
Speaker 3:  conversation by going back in time all the way to 2012 to the first ever
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Surface and Surface rt. Back then, we weren't talking
Speaker 3:  about ai, we weren't even really talking about laptops. That was the time
Speaker 3:  when everybody kind of thought PCs were dead and phones were going to be
Speaker 3:  the only thing you remember that like this was supposed to be the end of
Speaker 3:  computers, not the beginning of some grand project for Microsoft. But you
Speaker 3:  can draw a line from that moment in 2012 with the
Speaker 3:  Surface rt, which was bad all the way to this one
Speaker 3:  without trying very hard. So 2012, let's go back, what was
Speaker 3:  the big bet behind the Surface, particularly the Surface rt?
Speaker 5:  So our core thesis, you know, at that point in time, you're right, we
Speaker 5:  made an arm bet. The ARM bet was around modernizing
Speaker 5:  the platform at the end of the day and bringing modern architectures to Windows
Speaker 5:  arm was a part of it for sure. You know, instruction sets matter obviously
Speaker 5:  for the core operating system and the app experiences, but really the theory
Speaker 5:  of the case for Arm was a modern system, you know, in
Speaker 5:  its in its entirety. And so what we wanted was
Speaker 5:  yes, great, you know, performance. We wanted great battery life, we wanted,
Speaker 5:  you know, security, all the other aspects of modern platforms at the in in
Speaker 5:  that window of time. And so arm Arm was a big bet. And as you
Speaker 5:  recall for sure, Surface RD did bring a new user experience sort of,
Speaker 5:  you know, paradigm to the table for sure. And you know, in that window of
Speaker 5:  time we were seeing Confluence certainly across what was happening in the
Speaker 5:  PC space and the tablet space. And in mobile it was early days of, you know,
Speaker 5:  tablet iteration back then. Yeah. So a lot of those constructs
Speaker 5:  I think, you know, are still true today for sure. And the way I think about
Speaker 5:  kinda this kinda where your thought was going to bridge that from back then
Speaker 5:  to today is the arm journey as an example, has been a
Speaker 5:  multi-generation exercise for us for sure. And we
Speaker 5:  certainly learned many lessons, especially on the Surface team, between the
Speaker 5:  work we did in Surface Pro X and Surface Pro nine 5G for instance.
Speaker 5:  And now I think we're in a place where we brought the totality of what was
Speaker 5:  needed to be just building great product for customers at the end of the
Speaker 5:  day to the table. And so, so I feel much more confident now in terms
Speaker 5:  of the work that we have done. Did
Speaker 3:  You know, 12 years ago, how long that list
Speaker 3:  of things you just described was, 'cause I think part of the reason I ask
Speaker 3:  is it feels like, you know, the, the running joke is next year has been the
Speaker 3:  year of Windows on Arm for a decade now. And, and it seems like at the
Speaker 3:  very least, you and Microsoft are substantially more confident that
Speaker 3:  that is the case now than ever. But if you rewind
Speaker 3:  12 years, do you think your sense of the project was
Speaker 3:  actually as big as the project turned out to be?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there, you know, this is a great example of the breadth and
Speaker 5:  diversity of the Windows ecosystem. I think our superpower is the diversity
Speaker 5:  of the ecosystem,
Speaker 3:  Which is such a great euphemism in such like a good and bad way. Like it
Speaker 3:  makes everything wonderful and massively complicated all at the same time.
Speaker 3:  Massive.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. So you kind of have to get your arms around enough of the massive
Speaker 5:  components, I think, to be meaningful at the end of the day. And that has
Speaker 5:  been, in fact, the reason why we took for this iteration of it,
Speaker 5:  frankly David, I think we could have done individual bits and pieces sooner
Speaker 5:  and then kind of done them on an asynchronous basis. We could have done some
Speaker 5:  of the dev pla stuff kind of out of band and, and kind of got, got those
Speaker 5:  pieces out. We could have done parts of the CoreOS and then released them
Speaker 5:  as, you know, incremental updates in Windows. But we chose to go ahead, take
Speaker 5:  the time needed to go do the entire thing. You know, one good example of
Speaker 5:  that is our partnership on the Silicon platform. To me, the Silicon platform
Speaker 5:  is a foundation for what, you know, the OSS and app experiences are and what
Speaker 5:  they can, you know, take advantage of. And it takes time to go rebuild the
Speaker 5:  entire silicon. In this case, our partnership with Qualcomm took us to a
Speaker 5:  place and quite frankly, with Arm Holdings to a place where we had to go
Speaker 5:  back and address some fundamentals. And you know, silicon design lifecycle
Speaker 5:  takes time when you are rebuilding an entire ship for the exercise. So, so
Speaker 5:  I think we, we certainly appreciated the magnitude of it in the more recent
Speaker 5:  years and I think we decided to take the time to address the, the completion
Speaker 5:  of it perhaps, versus doing another sort of incremental take on it. Is
Speaker 3:  It easy then in that process to sort
Speaker 3:  of find the moment where you're, or like identify the moment where you're
Speaker 3:  like, okay, we're we're there, we've done the thing and instead of, 'cause
Speaker 3:  my sense was something like this is you could tinker with app compatibility
Speaker 3:  until the heat death of the universe and never actually solve every
Speaker 3:  problem in every edge case. How do you pick the moment where you're like,
Speaker 3:  okay, we have kind of over promise and under-delivered a couple of times,
Speaker 3:  we know we have to get this right and we have like what, how do you put that
Speaker 3:  flag in the ground?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a great question. You know, I think to me there isn't a single
Speaker 5:  one answer thing here. You, I typically as a team, we collectively
Speaker 5:  look for a set of signals. I would say in this instance,
Speaker 5:  there were some things that we clearly learned by way of customer feedback.
Speaker 5:  In fact, you know, feedback from folks like you for sure who are looking
Speaker 5:  at our products. And so that to me, there's some front and center things
Speaker 5:  that, you know, we just had to make sure we were, we were delivering on emulator
Speaker 5:  performance was one, in such example, it was, you know, kind of, sort of
Speaker 5:  apparent to us what the, the benchmark industry competition, et cetera. So
Speaker 5:  we had some clear benchmarks that we had to go hit that were kind of markers
Speaker 5:  that we set for ourselves. The second part of it I think was we had some
Speaker 5:  expectations of, you know, when we take another iteration doing this, we
Speaker 5:  do have to be kind of meaningful and world class in this context. And so
Speaker 5:  that was kind of a moving target for us and we had to go as you know, it's
Speaker 5:  a function of time obviously, and time to market and so on. So, so some of
Speaker 5:  those we just decided we're gonna take a quantum leap kind of in that sense.
Speaker 5:  And then you will have to kind of wait and watch and decide and see if, if
Speaker 5:  that's a meaningful exercise or not. The other big component is we do, you
Speaker 5:  know, get a chance to talk to customers. We, we do that for consumers for
Speaker 5:  sure. We talk to commercial customers, we get a chance to do, you know, iterations
Speaker 5:  and you know, trials and deployments with them. And so we learn through actual
Speaker 5:  dialogue and data and telemetry from our commercial customers to see if we've
Speaker 5:  addressed the core issues. Like, you know, a great example of that is, you
Speaker 5:  know, on the emulator itself, as much as we did tremendous work on the emulator
Speaker 5:  on this iteration, there are some things that you can't emulate. And so,
Speaker 5:  you know, kernel com mode components and windows and you know, malware type
Speaker 5:  stuff that, and VPN applications that commercial customers do rely on,
Speaker 5:  you have to get them native. So some of those things we do, we took time
Speaker 5:  to go get the data, get customer feedback, and you know, do the trials, do
Speaker 5:  some deployments, get their feedback, and then, then I think you look at
Speaker 5:  the, the culmination of 'em all and then see if you've done enough of the
Speaker 5:  critical mass to decide that you've, you know, kind of met that expectation.
Speaker 5:  The one thing that is kind of a gift for us in this context is the AI
Speaker 5:  stuff that happened. I think the, the one real inflection point for us,
Speaker 5:  David, was knowing that we could use this opportunity in a more general
Speaker 5:  sense. Certainly ARM is a big piece of it for us and, and the first wave
Speaker 5:  of copilot plus PCs are on Qualcomm series X
Speaker 5:  components. But really using the AI point in time as an inflection
Speaker 5:  for us to kind of go after a, a bigger vector for
Speaker 5:  what, you know, value we could serve at the end of the day was another thing
Speaker 5:  where, you know, timing figured into our decision making for both value and
Speaker 5:  and timing for the exercise.
Speaker 3:  So it makes sense. That's actually a good segue into the next thing I wanted
Speaker 3:  to talk about, which is that it feels like to some extent in 2012,
Speaker 3:  the Surface's job in particular was to sort of remind people that
Speaker 3:  PCs matter. Like we were in the, the era when, you know, smartphones were
Speaker 3:  gonna kill everything, laptops are dead, who needs any of this stuff anymore?
Speaker 3:  Like the, that's the old way. And that was, I think obviously never the case,
Speaker 3:  but that was, I think part of what Surface existed to do was
Speaker 3:  continue to, you know, push that along. It feels like the
Speaker 3:  job now seems to have shifted a bit where you're, you're trying to, and I
Speaker 3:  even noticed this sort of as you're on stage talking about this stuff, like
Speaker 3:  you have to make the case for these devices in a new way. And it's not just
Speaker 3:  these things still matter because typing is annoying on your phone. You have
Speaker 3:  to like describe a different way to think about my
Speaker 3:  computer than it has. So I'm curious, give me sort of the big
Speaker 3:  philosophical vision of like the job to be done of a PC
Speaker 3:  in this era that we're just starting right now. Has it changed at all?
Speaker 5:  It has and I think to be tr honest with you on that exercise of
Speaker 5:  my own learning and journey, I would say the last four years I've been
Speaker 5:  particularly instrumental. 'cause to your point, I think people go through
Speaker 5:  that thought process periodically. They're like, you know, what is the job
Speaker 5:  of the pc? And one thing we learned through the pandemic and coming outta
Speaker 5:  the pandemic on the other side was how Vital PCs were yeah.
Speaker 5:  For people and just how fundamental Windows is in that context of serving
Speaker 5:  the breadth of education customers through commercial
Speaker 5:  customers, through frontline workers, through, you know, consumers at large.
Speaker 5:  And so I think it, it reinforced for people in a way that obviously
Speaker 5:  it took a pandemic, but I think in a way it also forced us
Speaker 5:  to kind of go through the introspection of how are we making sure we are
Speaker 5:  thinking deeply about the promise of the platform, the ecosystem that
Speaker 5:  Windows is on the role for Surface in that context
Speaker 5:  as we go forward. I think for me there's two constructs. One, to your point
Speaker 5:  earlier, I think the deep rooted value proposition of Windows, I think just,
Speaker 5:  it is a, it is a great reminder. It is kind of a humbling thing and an inspiring
Speaker 5:  experience at the same time for how important and foundational and, and key
Speaker 5:  windows is across all of kind of work and play for people in, in life. As
Speaker 5:  we think about the world going forward, I think for me, my sense of
Speaker 5:  orientation in this space is this AI journey that the world is going through
Speaker 5:  our industry, at least for sure is, is a tremendous gift for us.
Speaker 5:  And you know, I think it gives us a sense of agency for what is
Speaker 5:  possible on a PC and to kinda reimagine what was possible from, you know,
Speaker 5:  10 years ago, you know, 2012 for sure. We were not thinking about this
Speaker 5:  in a way that I think is somewhat of a title, you know,
Speaker 5:  shift for us. To me, what I love about this is especially
Speaker 5:  with, with the ability to build an entire system stack, you know, kind of
Speaker 5:  be thoughtful. And this is also in part why this project took, you know,
Speaker 5:  kinda longer perhaps than others would've expected, is it needed us to kind
Speaker 5:  of go through the deep thinking on how do we deliver this proposition in
Speaker 5:  a way that is somewhat durable. And I think we're the infancy of this journey,
Speaker 5:  David. I think there's gonna be, you know, iteration and refinement and learning
Speaker 5:  and evolution in that sense. And so, so it required us to go think deeply
Speaker 5:  about how do we go integrate AI into our products across the board. It took
Speaker 5:  us down the path of, of making sure we were building the hardware platform
Speaker 5:  and capability and that's a statement across the entire Windows ecosystem.
Speaker 5:  We have a whole modern generation of SOCs that I'm actually very
Speaker 5:  excited about that are gonna start showing up for Windows. It's gonna be
Speaker 5:  great across our partners because I think that modern platform is what then
Speaker 5:  we can build on top of both from an operating system standpoint and as
Speaker 5:  a device maker in Surface.
Speaker 3:  But I think, I mean, just to that point actually, one of the things I think
Speaker 3:  you could have done, and you should tell me if you did do this and 'cause
Speaker 3:  I think it's very interesting is say, you know, Microsoft's kind of
Speaker 3:  lost in, in mobile the AI thing is happening, this is our moment.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna relaunch the Surface Duo as an AI device and take over the
Speaker 3:  universe. That is one like perfectly rational version of that thing.
Speaker 3:  But you, you went another way and you went, you went all in on on PCs. Like
Speaker 3:  even the fact that the Surface pro itself is the same size as the last one,
Speaker 3:  but is in such a meaningful way, like a fundamentally different device, I
Speaker 3:  think is so interesting. And it's like there, there's something about what
Speaker 3:  happens when you put AI inside of a PC that I feel like
Speaker 3:  consumers just have not seen yet. This stuff is so new. Correct. But you've,
Speaker 3:  you've had to like think ahead about what that will look like and how we'll
Speaker 3:  use it. And I'm sure you've just used these devices longer than the rest
Speaker 3:  of us. So like what, what is it about the size and shape
Speaker 3:  and form factor of a PC that you can add AI to and it changes it
Speaker 3:  meaningfully? That's
Speaker 5:  A really good question. As somebody who worked on Duo, you know, we definitely
Speaker 5:  did think deeply about that. You know, in terms of vectors and options.
Speaker 3:  I love Duo by the way. I have a duo right over there and I I love it to pieces,
Speaker 5:  Warms my heart, love hearing that
Speaker 5:  I, you know, my sense on that topic first, I think AI is gonna
Speaker 5:  show up in, in a variety of different forms for us. You know, you know, Microsoft
Speaker 5:  sort of our, we, we are the copilot company and we're going to, you know,
Speaker 5:  deliver copilot as a set of services and experiences
Speaker 5:  on a variety of different devices, a variety of different form factors, you
Speaker 5:  know, different platforms. So you, you're seeing that from us. We talked
Speaker 5:  about it on Monday as well. So that I think is a, is a certainly a thrust
Speaker 5:  for the company, you know, across the board I think it is, we're seeing tremendous
Speaker 5:  momentum with things like the M 365 copilot for example, in terms of
Speaker 5:  embedding agent capabilities, copilot capabilities and productivity suite
Speaker 5:  and applications and services. In terms of the device form factor, the thing
Speaker 5:  that I, I'm particularly excited about with the PC orientation around it,
Speaker 5:  by the way, one thing we should to mention mobile, you the one reason why,
Speaker 5:  you know, the value of the neural engine and efficiency and just matrix math
Speaker 5:  computation and performance per watt and all this stuff. We do inherit a
Speaker 5:  lot of those capabilities of mobile platforms into these next generation
Speaker 5:  mobile SSCs. Obviously we have the sensibilities because anyway, so I
Speaker 5:  think that, I think you know this of course, and you're seeing this, it's
Speaker 5:  happening in industry, you know, broadly, and we are a pole position when
Speaker 5:  it comes to taking advantage of those ips, those capabilities and then bringing,
Speaker 5:  you know, the largest possible neural engines at scale in, into Windows
Speaker 5:  on, on the, on the, on the devices themselves. The thing
Speaker 5:  for us when it comes to large screen form factors, you know, pro devices,
Speaker 5:  laptops, and by the way, I think Surface is one great embodiment of it, but
Speaker 5:  what was kind of magical for us with this copilot PC moment is it was not
Speaker 5:  just Surface. We had the, our, you know, lean in from our entire ecosystem
Speaker 5:  partners and the signals we got from, from all of our OEM partners
Speaker 5:  here was super strong. So it kind of gave us conviction on thinking about
Speaker 5:  this, you know, broad and holistic and making sure we're, we think of it
Speaker 5:  as a transition for a class of devices versus, you know, one particular form
Speaker 5:  factor. The couple of things that make AI kind of meaningful for me in
Speaker 5:  PCs, one of them is by definition Windows
Speaker 5:  is a multi-platform, multi app operating system. And one of the things that
Speaker 5:  I think that makes these AI experiences powerful is the fact that these
Speaker 5:  models can reason across things happening, you know, on your, across your
Speaker 5:  screen, across multiple applications, across workflows. And I think in
Speaker 5:  a world where a lot of what we do is task flow across applications and
Speaker 5:  so on, having the ability for having AI help you both in your own
Speaker 5:  app but also be able to help with workflows across apps is
Speaker 5:  huge I think. And totally for us with the idea of recall the
Speaker 5:  notion of search and search becoming semantic. I think that, you
Speaker 5:  know, today most people don't interact with their devices in a natural language
Speaker 5:  sense. Like I think intuitively we are able to do or would like to go do.
Speaker 5:  And so for, but for search to be semantic, you know, you do need to
Speaker 5:  flatten what that information architecture and data schema looks like. 'cause
Speaker 5:  you know, if you, again, you don't wanna be app specific, you want to search
Speaker 5:  the way you know your memories would work for instance and how you recall
Speaker 5:  things. And so, so that way for us pc, that was one powerful thing, the
Speaker 5:  ability for us to be able to bring AI across applications. The second big
Speaker 5:  thing is multimodality on a pc you are looking at content,
Speaker 5:  you're typing on a screen, you have the opportunity for voice interactions,
Speaker 5:  you have touch, you have ink. And so these AI models are
Speaker 5:  increasingly going to become multimodal for us. And so the fact that we are
Speaker 5:  a, you know, multimodal operating system, we are multitasking operating system,
Speaker 5:  it gives us a fertile ground to go, you know, bring these capabilities.
Speaker 5:  And quite frankly, I think my sentiment is we have a point of view on where
Speaker 5:  that value starts. The fact is people are going to do things with them that
Speaker 5:  we start with as a point of view and then they are gonna bring their own
Speaker 5:  ideas and I think that's gonna be powerful. The last thing I'll say, David,
Speaker 5:  is you know, the power of the Windows ecosystem is our app catalog and
Speaker 5:  what developers do on top of it. And the beautiful thing with AI now
Speaker 5:  is we are finding a strong pull from traditional, you know, windows
Speaker 5:  applications as well as a set of folks who are traditionally sort of web
Speaker 5:  apps if you will, and build websites and stuff who are very interested in
Speaker 5:  knowing what they can do with the AI capabilities local on
Speaker 5:  device. And so the pull from them of reimagining what apps can
Speaker 5:  be and that's full spectrum quite frankly from I wanna change the UI 'cause
Speaker 5:  I don't need, you know, as many radial buttons, dials and so on. 'cause the
Speaker 5:  agents can start understanding what's happening all the way through. I want
Speaker 5:  to do net new things where I need local models and I want those local models
Speaker 5:  to have a set of attributes that we can, you know, kind of from Windows platform
Speaker 5:  standpoint, build platform capabilities to serve them. That's another strong
Speaker 5:  signal, which is why I think, you know, windows devices are a great place
Speaker 5:  'cause we have a rich catalog that exists at scale today and they have
Speaker 5:  a very broad Surface area for taking advantage of ai.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you just brought up my favorite user experience
Speaker 3:  thing to think about right now and I can't stop thinking about it and I'm
Speaker 3:  curious how you're thinking about it, which is this sort of UI of AI also
Speaker 3:  feels very uncertain. 'cause a lot of what you just described is what I would
Speaker 3:  call like infrastructural ai, it's sort of underlying technology
Speaker 3:  in service of something that shouldn't really feel like AI as you do it,
Speaker 3:  right? It just makes it faster or smarter or whatever else. When we talk
Speaker 3:  about AI a lot, we talk about chatbots, right? Like that is, that is I think
Speaker 3:  the, the sort of accidental synonym of AI in a way that I really hate and
Speaker 3:  hope we get past. But I am curious, I mean I think ai it sounds
Speaker 3:  like for you sort of runs that whole spectrum, but as you're thinking about
Speaker 3:  like what this stuff should look like and where people should see
Speaker 3:  AI and sort of how loudly it should scream AI at them when they see it.
Speaker 3:  How are you thinking about that right now?
Speaker 5:  You know that as a company, David, we are, there's a
Speaker 5:  variety of teams who are looking broadly and deeply at that topic.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  'cause nobody knows anything. It's so fun. It's all so new.
Speaker 5:  I think honestly that's kind of the beauty of it right now. It's a place
Speaker 5:  for innovation. We are early in the life cycle, like you said. I think my
Speaker 5:  sense is people are looking for a paradigm and for a period of time at least,
Speaker 5:  I think there's gonna be iteration evolution, there's gonna be different
Speaker 5:  people with different points of view. It, the value's gonna Surface itself
Speaker 5:  in different ways. And then I think perhaps there'll be some patterns that
Speaker 5:  are more stickier in a certain set of use cases than others.
Speaker 3:  Can you get away with that on Windows though? Like Windows is not,
Speaker 3:  I would say famously a place where you can do a lot of
Speaker 3:  experimentation without immediately infuriating millions of people around
Speaker 3:  the world. Can you play like that in something as big and important
Speaker 3:  as Windows?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, let me actually, let me try to complete response for you in the previous
Speaker 5:  thing and I'll come back to your iteration question. Okay, the question,
Speaker 5:  where does it Surface itself? You know, we shared a little bit, we shared
Speaker 5:  a glimpse of this at the bill conference. You know, I, one of our big
Speaker 5:  learnings, at least in the canvas of windows, is using AI for
Speaker 5:  serving kind of customers where they're at in their workflows. And so we
Speaker 5:  have a lot of very highly used surfaces, very high traffic
Speaker 5:  surfaces and windows right now. And one of the things we're thinking about
Speaker 5:  is how do we have these agentic experiences just help people get to their
Speaker 5:  intent faster, easier, quicker. And so that's one
Speaker 5:  sort of thought process where I think in, in terms of UI evolution, you'll
Speaker 5:  see the UI evolve itself to a place where you'll see copilot showing up in
Speaker 5:  more diffuse but infuse manner across the operating system. It's not
Speaker 5:  gonna be screaming at you, but I think it's the subtle ways of being able
Speaker 5:  to do things that you perhaps do today, but it'll just get you through 'em
Speaker 5:  faster and more efficient, kinda more intentful way. There's another big
Speaker 5:  thought process, which is around the idea of recall that we just introduced
Speaker 5:  features and preview the notion that you can bring net new capabilities,
Speaker 5:  I think is gonna create new shell surfaces is gonna create new experiences
Speaker 5:  and they'll become a place where we'll refine and iterate and add new value
Speaker 5:  as well. Once you have a semantic index to your point, that's sort of a
Speaker 5:  structural notion that is gonna Surface itself in, in a variety of different
Speaker 5:  ways. And so I think that, you know, that's a, that's another way to think
Speaker 5:  about it. And of course then there's the app experiences and how do those
Speaker 5:  app experiences in themselves take advantage of copilot capabilities. We
Speaker 5:  introduced the, the new copilot, you know, thinking yes on Monday as well.
Speaker 5:  And so, and then I think you'll see a, we think of a hybrid ai,
Speaker 5:  there's gonna be a pattern I think where you'll see these large models in
Speaker 5:  the cloud working with models on the edge, the model on the edge will bring
Speaker 5:  context and understanding and these large models will do reasoning, you know,
Speaker 5:  at a scale that's not possible. And I think that concert is gonna open up
Speaker 5:  some new experiences about the OS and app layer anyway. So I think that's
Speaker 5:  kinda our three vectors of, of thought process right now in terms of where,
Speaker 5:  you know, ui you know, affordances and constructs will, will take themselves
Speaker 5:  and then we'll see, you know, a year from now. I'm sure if we talk you, you'll
Speaker 5:  see you can be smarter across the board. I think the, the point on these
Speaker 5:  interfaces can be minimalist over time because of the reasoning capabilities
Speaker 5:  is certainly a, a deep call. I know you've, you've talked about it in a couple
Speaker 5:  of different places. I think that's kind of on on our minds. Your
Speaker 5:  experimentation iteration point is a great one. And I think that is a thing.
Speaker 5:  We are on a learning journey ourselves, quite frankly. And how do we go do
Speaker 5:  that? We'll continue to use the Windows Insider program. It's been powerful
Speaker 5:  for us to learn in kinda what works and what doesn't. What I love with the
Speaker 5:  insider community is we're able to do a bunch of different experiments. We're
Speaker 5:  able to do them asynchronously, you know, and get individual signals at at,
Speaker 5:  at the level that matters for individual features in themselves. But we also
Speaker 5:  have a variety of other learning tools and experimentation methods. We are
Speaker 5:  able to talk to customers. We certainly, you know, get the chance to go experiment
Speaker 5:  with commercial customers. And then I think from a window standpoint,
Speaker 5:  you know, we get to learn at the rate of the entire company. And so
Speaker 5:  for me, the fact when it comes to the, the idea of responsible ai, for example,
Speaker 5:  Microsoft is leading responsible AI in the cloud. We are learning a bunch
Speaker 5:  there. And certainly we take those lessons and we apply them to customers
Speaker 5:  in Windows context. 'cause at end the day they're, you know, the same person,
Speaker 5:  they're the same corporation, same set of customers. And so, so I find in
Speaker 5:  fact in this AI world, I have more learning tools because the way
Speaker 5:  AI capabilities and services and even, you know, social experiments and how
Speaker 5:  people are experiencing them is actually pretty broad brushed across the
Speaker 5:  company than than features and windows in the past by themselves.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I've always enjoyed the, the sort of pros and cons of being Microsoft
Speaker 3:  in this ecosystem. On the one hand you have this incredibly long
Speaker 3:  history and a lot of people who are very accustomed to certain workflows
Speaker 3:  and the sort of cost of change is very high, but on the
Speaker 3:  upside you can put that kind of stuff in front of huge numbers of
Speaker 3:  different kinds of people pretty quickly. Yeah. And I just, that that tension
Speaker 3:  I feel like I see everywhere across Microsoft and it is always really interesting
Speaker 3:  to watch.
Speaker 5:  It is a great balance. Yeah. I don't know if I have a recipe for sort of
Speaker 5:  an an answer that as a result of this to, to success. Like you said, it's
Speaker 5:  a, it's a tension and we have to kinda work, you know, work the balance there
Speaker 5:  for sure.
Speaker 3:  Totally. So I know I have to let you go here in a minute. So one last question.
Speaker 3:  We started 12 years ago. Fast forward 12 more years for me. Is
Speaker 3:  the bet now the same one you feel like you were making
Speaker 3:  with Surface 12 years ago? Or is it, has it shifted?
Speaker 3:  Like is this a sort of inflection point in the life of what you think these
Speaker 3:  devices are and what you're pushing towards with them?
Speaker 5:  Our, okay, it's a great question. Let me, I, let me try to do this in two.
Speaker 5:  The, the philosophy and our strategy and mission
Speaker 5:  with Surface has been around, you know, driving, leading
Speaker 5:  innovation in the Windows ecosystem in a way that we think
Speaker 5:  allows Windows itself to move the needle for what is possible, but to
Speaker 5:  do it in a way that is actually responsible for
Speaker 5:  end customers. And as a business within Microsoft. I think that aspect
Speaker 5:  of Surface is going to be instrumental for us to continue to move the
Speaker 5:  needle of what is possible, both in a technology sense, in a product
Speaker 5:  making sense, in a sense of how do we deliver these capabilities to customers
Speaker 5:  and to businesses in a way that, you know, actually is credible for them
Speaker 5:  at the end of the day. I think that aspect of Surface will continue. It is,
Speaker 5:  it has been powerful for us quite frankly. I think the copilot wave copilot
Speaker 5:  plus wave of PCs was only possible with the deep work that happened in Surface
Speaker 5:  over the last, you know, four or five years. And so that will continue to
Speaker 5:  be instrumental for us. And I, and I expect and believe that will continue
Speaker 5:  to be great for us going forward in terms of the devices themselves.
Speaker 5:  You know, time will tell, I think, you know, we've grown our portfolio, we've,
Speaker 5:  we've played, we've added, we've tried, we've learned, I think that that
Speaker 5:  spirit will continue with the team. We will continue to drive innovation.
Speaker 5:  We will learn through those experiments. I'm excited many of them are gonna
Speaker 5:  be successful, but I'm also, you know, clear-eyed. Some of those experiments
Speaker 5:  and learnings may or may not result in, you know, in products in themselves.
Speaker 5:  But I, in either case, I think they serve the, the outcome and the mission
Speaker 5:  for what, what's critical for Surface and quite frankly Microsoft I think
Speaker 5:  at the end of the
Speaker 3:  Day. Fair enough. All right, well I've made you late for a meeting so I'll
Speaker 3:  let you go but someday we're just gonna talk about like hinges and stuff
Speaker 3:  for several hours and I'm very much looking forward to that. It's gonna be
Speaker 3:  better.
Speaker 5:  Sounds lovely. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we have to take a break and then we're gonna do a big smart home
Speaker 3:  catch up. 'cause there's a lot to get to.
Speaker 3:  It
Speaker 7:  Has David, it's always a pleasure to be back though.
Speaker 3:  I feel like we haven't had enough time to yell about Matter on this show
Speaker 3:  recently. It feels like it's time.
Speaker 7:  I know. Well I got to yell about Matter with with Neli on the other show
Speaker 7:  so we
Speaker 3:  We don't talk about the other show. How, how dare you. Okay, so
Speaker 3:  I, I have come up with a little game for us and I didn't tell you about it
Speaker 3:  because I'm a very cruel and unhelpful podcast host. I
Speaker 7:  Have no idea what's about to happen.
Speaker 3:  So I have five topics for you. They're all based on
Speaker 3:  stories you've written recently and I'm gonna throw them at you one
Speaker 3:  by one and you're gonna have to tell me whether this thing is a big deal,
Speaker 3:  a medium deal or a small deal. And then we're gonna talk about it. Okay,
Speaker 3:  I have these, but I wanna know what you think about all of these. Does that
Speaker 3:  sound good? We're just gonna dive in. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 7:  Sounds good.
Speaker 3:  The first one, big deal, medium deal, small deal. The
Speaker 3:  Dyson Wash G one Dyson's first mop. People are
Speaker 3:  very excited about this thing. Jen, big deal, medium deal, small deal. What
Speaker 3:  do we think from
Speaker 7:  A smart home perspective? Jeanie? Tiny deal.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Because it's not a smart thing, it's, well
Speaker 7:  it depends on your definition. It's not smart, but it's not internet connected
Speaker 7:  in any way. It is not an iot device from the world of floor
Speaker 7:  washing. However, I would say it's kind of a big deal
Speaker 7:  because you know, it's very expensive. But
Speaker 7:  Dyson love them or hate them. They are innovative. They do
Speaker 7:  come up with some interesting solutions for common problems in
Speaker 7:  our home. And whilst there are lots of great ways to mop your floor, this
Speaker 7:  does actually seem like it has an interesting construct
Speaker 7:  that's going to take a lot of the hard work outta mopping. I mean frankly
Speaker 7:  I, I have never mopped my floors in years because I use robot mops,
Speaker 7:  but that's part of my job. But when I used to have to pull the mop out with
Speaker 7:  the bucket, oh
Speaker 3:  It's the worst.
Speaker 7:  It's the worst. And this does actually seem like a good solution and I have
Speaker 7:  used some of the automated versions of there. So it's a
Speaker 7:  mop that does not have any kind of motor in it or any kind of
Speaker 7:  fan. So it's very different from any of the products that Dyson's brought
Speaker 7:  out prior. You know, it's known for its fans, it's known for its hair dryers,
Speaker 7:  it's known for its vacuum cleaners. This does not suck or blow. Oh, interesting.
Speaker 7:  Although it sucks in a different way.
Speaker 7:  And that's the kind of neat engineering trick here, which I think is, I think
Speaker 7:  is interesting in terms of cleaning your floors. But people love Dyson
Speaker 7:  products and people are prepared to pay a lot of money for them. I do think
Speaker 7:  it's ridiculously over-engineered and ridiculously overpriced. But
Speaker 7:  I'm quite confident that it will work well. So that makes it a big deal I
Speaker 7:  suppose. Okay. What do you think about this?
Speaker 3:  I feel exactly the same way. Every Dyson thing I've ever tried or
Speaker 3:  owned I think is wonderful and preposterous at the same time.
Speaker 3:  Like I bought my wife an air wrap for Christmas a couple of years ago.
Speaker 3:  Oh you
Speaker 7:  Wonderful husband?
Speaker 3:  Oh it is hands down the most successful gift I have ever bought. My wife,
Speaker 3:  she loves it and it's an awesome thing, but it is also like
Speaker 3:  ludicrously expensive and it involves a lot of like, let's be clear, you're
Speaker 3:  not getting any more gifts for several years after this. Like this is, it
Speaker 3:  was like your engagement ring and this like, these are the two big gifts
Speaker 3:  you're ever getting from me. But the stuff they make tends to be great. And
Speaker 3:  I think part of the reason I'm fascinated by the mop thing is I think as
Speaker 3:  someone who has had a robot vacuum running around for a long
Speaker 3:  time, the robot mop thing seems like it ought to
Speaker 3:  be the next thing. But at least from the, the little bit of experience I
Speaker 3:  have with them, they're not nearly as good as the robot vacuums.
Speaker 3:  And you're, you're shaking your head like, like you agree with me
Speaker 7:  On that. I agree. Yes. They're not, they've, they've got better but you have
Speaker 7:  to pay an awful lot for the really good ones. And yeah, it's just nowhere
Speaker 7:  near the same as actually mopping your floor and this thing will
Speaker 7:  actually mop your floor because it uses water. Like the water is
Speaker 7:  constantly flowing onto the mop and to a big mop. Most
Speaker 7:  of the mops on robot mops are small and maybe, you know,
Speaker 7:  have a very small Surface area so you're not really getting a lot of clean
Speaker 7:  for your, for your motion. Whereas this uses like a
Speaker 7:  two large roller mops that constantly spray
Speaker 7:  clean water onto them and then sucks up with
Speaker 7:  agitation the dirt. So it doesn't, like I said, it doesn't have a mo so it's
Speaker 7:  not a vacuum but it uses agitation to kind of get up the dirt. So yeah,
Speaker 7:  it, you know, the pictures they sent and the demo they showed me, I mean
Speaker 7:  they're very excited about this. This was big enough that they even rolled
Speaker 7:  out, you know, sir James Dyson himself to the press.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. Which is pretty rare these days. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So they were very excited by it. But 700 I know up,
Speaker 3:  I just, I'm sort of in the position of like when in the early days of the
Speaker 3:  Roomba it was like, yes, this is a good idea, I hope everybody decides to
Speaker 3:  work on this. And they kind of did. And robot vacuums got to be pretty good.
Speaker 3:  I'm hoping that's where we are with MOPS now because it feels like if I could
Speaker 3:  solve that problem robotically, it would be amazing. Even if
Speaker 3:  I bought this Dyson one, I would use it like twice and then be like, mopping
Speaker 3:  is a lot of work. I don't, I don't care. It's a lot of, but I'm hoping this
Speaker 3:  is the like a spark for people to work on this stuff.
Speaker 7:  Yes, I think that's true. I'm just surprised they haven't come out with a
Speaker 7:  robot mop. You know, they came out with their robot vacuum but they've yet
Speaker 7:  to come up with a robot mop, which seems like a natural progression for them.
Speaker 7:  I don't know, maybe this was their sort of shock to say actually we don't
Speaker 7:  think the robot version is ever gonna work. You know, you still need to do
Speaker 7:  the manual part. But we've taken a lot of the hard work out. I mean
Speaker 7:  the main, the good thing about this compared to, so there are other options
Speaker 7:  out there from, from companies like Robo Rock that make robot vacuums that
Speaker 7:  are handheld wet dry vacuums so they can
Speaker 7:  mop and vacuum as you go, but they're huge and bulky and you know, it's like
Speaker 7:  a workout pushing them around the floor. Totally. Whereas this is
Speaker 7:  much more lightweight and apparently kind of you, you know, has the motion,
Speaker 7:  it's doing the hard work, you are just guiding it eventually, you know,
Speaker 7:  we'll have the full size Android in the house Android
Speaker 7:  robot that can come around and push it for you. Maybe that's their plan
Speaker 3:  Sold that will upgrade to big deal. But for now we'll leave it at small deal.
Speaker 3:  I think that's fair. Small deal.
Speaker 7:  Alright,
Speaker 3:  Next thing on the list, you tested out Amazon's matter casting
Speaker 3:  a, I wanna know about your experience and B matter casting in general,
Speaker 3:  big deal, medium, small deal. What do you think?
Speaker 7:  I think it's a big deal. Okay. I do, but it's, it's stymied at the
Speaker 7:  moment because I just don't see that Apple or Google are going to
Speaker 7:  embrace it because they already have their own proprietary
Speaker 7:  solutions for casting content to your TV
Speaker 3:  And matter casting is is like we, it's like Amazon's working on it
Speaker 3:  the most right now it seems like. But in theory it's like an open standard
Speaker 3:  for sending content around between devices basically, right?
Speaker 7:  Yes. So it is, it's part of the matter standard. It actually came out with
Speaker 7:  the first iteration of Matter so 1.0. But it's been very
Speaker 7:  sort of under the radar. I have written about it, but it's not, not many,
Speaker 7:  there's not much adoption. It has been driven by Amazon. So the way
Speaker 7:  matter works there's working groups and you have sort of a lead of each
Speaker 7:  ahead of each working group and the head of that working group is an Amazon
Speaker 7:  engineer and he's pushing this and he's working with from,
Speaker 7:  they're, they're not allowed to tell me exactly who's in the group, but he
Speaker 7:  implied it's mainly TV manufacturers and app makers. So like
Speaker 7:  Hulu or, and I'm, I don't know that Hulu's there but that kind of,
Speaker 7:  sure those kind of people are working on developing it. So, but yes, just
Speaker 7:  to clarify, so matter casting is a way of casting content from
Speaker 7:  one device to another at its core. But what it's been
Speaker 7:  used for here is casting content from your phone
Speaker 7:  or tablet to a screen IE or tv, but
Speaker 7:  it could be to any screen in your home. So Amazon's using it as
Speaker 7:  a way to cast prime video content to the fire TV stick
Speaker 7:  or an echo show. 15 matter casting has to be enabled on both
Speaker 7:  ends. And if you are familiar with Fire TVs and
Speaker 7:  right now they do not have a native way of casting content. So
Speaker 7:  this is a, this is really the first time Amazon's had something like this
Speaker 7:  and it's been kind of a frustrating experience for people that use Fire TVs
Speaker 7:  not to have, you can mirror but mirroring is never great. But right now it
Speaker 7:  only works on Prime video though they say they have a number of app makers
Speaker 7:  who are, who are going to enable it, including Plex and Sling. So
Speaker 7:  they're really pushing it hard. The thing that's different about it
Speaker 7:  versus Google cast or Apple Airplay is, and
Speaker 7:  this is where the app makers come in, is you actually, it's an app to
Speaker 7:  app communication. So you are replicating the app on your phone
Speaker 7:  and on your TV. So you can control everything you can do in the Prime
Speaker 7:  video app or the Hulu app or which other Netflix app mirrors exactly
Speaker 7:  on your tv. So you're not kind of like, when I use Apple Airplay I'm like,
Speaker 7:  I wanna fast forward but I can't, like the controls aren't intuitive
Speaker 7:  and app makers are like, we've made these great experiences for you on our
Speaker 7:  phone apps, let's just make that what you use on the tv. So it's
Speaker 7:  simplifying the process basically. And I think it works really well. My
Speaker 7:  experience was just limited to prime video 'cause that's the only one that
Speaker 7:  works. But it worked great. It was much easier for me than other forms of
Speaker 7:  casting. So I think it's gonna be a big deal for Fire
Speaker 7:  TV at the moment. But in the smart
Speaker 7:  home in general matter casting means any device can
Speaker 7:  cast to any device so your washing machine
Speaker 7:  can cast to your tv. I know that's the stuff of nightmares for some people,
Speaker 7:  but I like getting an alert on my TV when my washing's done.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it, you could also, once matter brings cameras
Speaker 7:  in theory to the standard, you know, you could have an a
Speaker 7:  non-proprietary way of viewing your video doorbell on your tv
Speaker 7:  so you wouldn't have to have a certain tv, you wouldn't have to have a certain
Speaker 7:  video doorbell for that to work, which is the way it is today. And it's a
Speaker 7:  universal, you know, standard open protocol. Anyone
Speaker 7:  can use it. You know, that's a good thing In the smart home we like these
Speaker 7:  open standards as opposed to the closed infrastructure of, you
Speaker 7:  know, airplay or Google cast. You know, there's, there's a lot of
Speaker 7:  potential here. Yeah. Right now though it's, yeah,
Speaker 7:  it's all Amazon and no one else. I've spoken to Apple and I've spoken
Speaker 7:  to Google about it and they're all like, nope, not saying anything,
Speaker 7:  we're not using this yet. And this is one of the problems with Matter.
Speaker 7:  Not all platforms are required to use or implement every
Speaker 7:  part of the matter standard. And for example, one of the problems
Speaker 7:  right now, I love the idea of being able to cast to my TV from any matter
Speaker 7:  device, but Samsung, one of the major TV
Speaker 7:  manufacturers, even though they're fully on board with Matter, they have
Speaker 7:  not committed to their TVs or any of their appliances being matter
Speaker 7:  enabled. Hmm. So with, we're going back to this issue of,
Speaker 7:  you know, there's these great open standards and open protocols that you
Speaker 7:  can use, but not everyone's adopting them. So that kind of, you know,
Speaker 7:  kneecaps the whole initiative from day one.
Speaker 3:  Right. Well and with matter casting in particular, it seems like if I'm Google
Speaker 3:  or Apple, I'm looking at it saying, okay, at least matter in general
Speaker 3:  solves problems, right? Like you can understand why eventually you're going
Speaker 3:  to want to be part of this broader ecosystem that
Speaker 3:  you don't have to control all of by yourself. Yeah. Whether they want to
Speaker 3:  now or not. Spoiler alert we're gonna get to in a minute. But the question
Speaker 3:  of like is it a long-term good idea sort of makes sense. My sense is
Speaker 3:  for casting, if I'm running Airplay or Google Cast,
Speaker 3:  I'm like eh, we've kind of solved this problem. And like sure, it might be
Speaker 3:  nice to have a bigger, broader thing to do, but what most people
Speaker 3:  want to do is they want to tap a thing on their phone and have it play on
Speaker 3:  their television and we've done that. Yeah. So to me it's like, I'm curious
Speaker 3:  to see if anybody can sort of build a use case that is so
Speaker 3:  much more useful for matter casting than that.
Speaker 3:  And then I think you might start to see everybody get on board, but until
Speaker 3:  then, my sense is Apple looks at airplane and is like, yeah we, we did that.
Speaker 3:  Like we're, we're good. Yeah we want to get it on more screens like in hotels
Speaker 3:  and whatever, but like airplane works, it's fine. We we're not gonna invest
Speaker 3:  more resources.
Speaker 7:  But there, the advantage there that hotel TV screens is a great example.
Speaker 7:  Hotel TVs would not need all new hardware to work with apps. That
Speaker 7:  is true with matter casting. That is true. Yeah. All they need is an update
Speaker 7:  to an app. So, you know, instead of waiting till what, 2050 when we can
Speaker 7:  go into a Hilton and an airplay to our LG TV
Speaker 7:  or whichever, I forget who it is that made the deal with, but you'd be
Speaker 7:  able to do it tomorrow. It, it would just, all you need to do is update the
Speaker 7:  software on the app, on the TV and the software on the app on your phone.
Speaker 7:  I mean you can have it built into the TV itself, but it, you
Speaker 7:  don't have to have a matter enabled TV for this to work necessarily.
Speaker 7:  So it's, it would be an easier solution. And I think where the momentum
Speaker 7:  might shift is if Amazon is successful in getting the app
Speaker 7:  manufacturers on board here and the TV manufacturers, because
Speaker 7:  yes the TV can have airplay and Google cast, but if it also has matter casting
Speaker 7:  it sh it would be a, a more seamless experience for the user because
Speaker 7:  it's very, you know, you don't have to figure out if it supports this or
Speaker 7:  that. It will just work, which is the whole promise of matter. It
Speaker 7:  will just work. Big air quotes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. Alright, so while, while we're on the subject of matter matter
Speaker 3:  casting, big deal. I I agree. I think long term big deal,
Speaker 3:  short term,
Speaker 7:  Not so much. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Big deal for Prime video, fire TV owning customers. Sure. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Matter 1.3 came out a couple of weeks ago, you wrote a story about
Speaker 3:  it matter 1.3, big deal, medium deal, small deal,
Speaker 7:  Big deal.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  Big deal. A lot of momentum. I was very not
Speaker 7:  excited by matter. 1.1 matter 1.2 was a little bit
Speaker 7:  more interesting 'cause there was a lot more device types added but Matter
Speaker 7:  1.3 just brought a whole load of more
Speaker 7:  potential with it because more device types, not the device types
Speaker 7:  weren't that exciting. It was kind of what we expected. Like we got washing
Speaker 7:  machines last time, so now we had tumble dryers like woo. Sure
Speaker 7:  there were a few, a few interesting additions there. But I think the big,
Speaker 7:  big deal here, well matter casting came updates to matter casting came with
Speaker 7:  1.3, which I was excited about. That was the ability to cast from device
Speaker 7:  to device, not just the app to app. But the
Speaker 7:  big deal I think is the energy reporting, energy management features, which
Speaker 7:  we've been waiting for. We knew it was coming, but we've been waiting for
Speaker 7:  this. And this is, you know, to me energy management in the smart home
Speaker 7:  really takes the smart home from sort of niche to
Speaker 7:  almost necessary. Because today, you know,
Speaker 7:  conserving resources, using less energy in our homes, saving
Speaker 7:  money are all things that, you know, many people are worried about,
Speaker 7:  concerned about trying to do. And the smart home makes can make it
Speaker 7:  so much easier to do all of this stuff automatically to
Speaker 7:  one of the main sort of showcase pieces that came out with Matter
Speaker 7:  1.3 that exemplifies this is electric vehicle management, so
Speaker 7:  Oh sure. EVSE chargers. So electrical vehicle
Speaker 7:  supply equipment is now a device type in matter
Speaker 7:  as is the ability to control and
Speaker 7:  create management of the way it charges. So for
Speaker 7:  example, you could use your matter app or matter enabled app to
Speaker 7:  tell your ev I want to have 80 miles
Speaker 7:  of range by 2:00 PM this evening or this afternoon and
Speaker 7:  I want you to use the least expensive energy to get there between now and
Speaker 7:  then and you just, you know, hit button and it will do that for you as opposed
Speaker 7:  to you having to go in and like check, you know, is there clean energy now
Speaker 7:  or, and some electrical vehicle supply equipment can do
Speaker 7:  this today, but it's proprietary so it you have to have, you know,
Speaker 7:  the Tesla charger and the Tesla app or the Kia charger and the Kia app. Whereas
Speaker 7:  this will open this ability to any smart home app that uses
Speaker 7:  matter. So if in theory your Apple Home app or your
Speaker 7:  Samsung Smart Things app could do this kind of management for your
Speaker 7:  ev for you. In fact Samsung already does have some electric vehicle
Speaker 7:  management, but again it's specific brands and specific cars and
Speaker 7:  so you have to have the right equipment whereas bringing this type of
Speaker 7:  management to matter will open it up so that it should work
Speaker 7:  with anything that can work with matter. and it works locally obviously,
Speaker 7:  which is, which isn't a bonus but it, we will need to use the cloud obviously
Speaker 7:  to get things like energy prices. But beyond EVs, you know,
Speaker 7:  you could see this applying to using your tumble dryer, your,
Speaker 7:  your washing machine, making sure your fridge and freezer uses Defrost,
Speaker 7:  does a defrost cycle at a, you know, at a time when energy's low, like if
Speaker 7:  you connected everything in your home and appliances, almost all appliances
Speaker 7:  are now part of matter, which is what came with 1.3. We are mainly just waiting
Speaker 7:  on heat pumps, which they say are coming next and that's obviously a
Speaker 7:  big part. And there was one other appliance, I can't remember off the top
Speaker 7:  of my head.
Speaker 3:  It was water heaters, right? Water
Speaker 7:  Heaters. So both of those obviously are big energy consumers, although
Speaker 7:  heat pumps less than traditional HVAC. So, but still
Speaker 7:  being able to manage the energy use, energy reporting,
Speaker 7:  and this is where I think it's gonna get interesting with the platforms like
Speaker 7:  Apple Home, Google Home, because this gives them
Speaker 7:  the opportunity to start differentiating, right? So to date a
Speaker 7:  lot of people have said well matter just commodifies everything, everything
Speaker 7:  works with everything. So why is there a benefit for Right for
Speaker 7:  these platforms and for anyone that wants to create something in the smart
Speaker 7:  home and how you manage the energy, what kind of service you
Speaker 7:  can provide on top of this type of reporting that the
Speaker 7:  system is now providing is going to help
Speaker 7:  differentiate. So if Apple Home comes up with a great way of
Speaker 7:  managing energy throughout your home with your connected appliances, you
Speaker 7:  might be more inclined to use their app. Samsung already has a pretty good
Speaker 7:  Samsung energy system in place, so I think it's got the headstart there
Speaker 7:  and Google Home will see, Alexa
Speaker 7:  already has some energy management built in if your device supports it.
Speaker 7:  So I think in the next few months, and I've already seen a few come
Speaker 7:  out, we're gonna see a lot more devices adopting matter in order
Speaker 7:  to, because this is a reason to put matter in your device, having
Speaker 7:  energy management is, is a huge sort of push for the smart home.
Speaker 7:  It's not the sexy fun stuff, but it's really important. Well
Speaker 3:  I I think back to like the days of the Nest thermostat and,
Speaker 3:  and to some extent that thing that it was just like we will will help you
Speaker 3:  lower your heating and cooling bill for your house is maybe still
Speaker 3:  to this day the single like simplest, most compelling smart home use case
Speaker 3:  for most people. And I think this, this just adds to that in really interesting
Speaker 3:  ways but also seems like it's sets up this cool
Speaker 3:  flywheel potentially where it's like okay and not only are you able to
Speaker 3:  control more and more of your stuff, but the stuff that you're controlling
Speaker 3:  can feed more data back to the system. Which means like you're saying the
Speaker 3:  system can start to do better and the people building these systems can do
Speaker 3:  more stuff with that information and you can actually start to like improve
Speaker 3:  upon itself over time as opposed to just
Speaker 3:  a lot of what we've had so far is just sort of increasingly elaborate
Speaker 3:  controllers and that's fine as far as it goes, but like the job of the smart
Speaker 3:  home should be to do most of this on its own right. And we're like,
Speaker 3:  we're slowly getting to the point of it feels like the puzzle pieces for
Speaker 3:  that are starting to get into place, which is very exciting.
Speaker 7:  It is. And this is something I've been talking to companies about for years
Speaker 7:  and it takes the, has taken them years to, you know, get the
Speaker 7:  partnerships, get the electric companies on board, you know, get it. It's,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's a huge project whereas this should make it a lot easier
Speaker 7:  to push us forward. And the really exciting part I think, and this is also
Speaker 7:  something I wrote about last in the last couple weeks, is that it
Speaker 7:  could help shift not just your home but
Speaker 7:  energy use in the entire country or world
Speaker 7:  by promoting and helping push forward the idea of virtual power plants.
Speaker 7:  And this is something, so Nest Renew you mentioned Nest. So Nest Renew
Speaker 7:  has turned into a new program now called Renew Home,
Speaker 7:  but Google's still involved but Google kind of shifted its Nest Renew, which
Speaker 7:  is the service that helps you save energy when you use your Nest thermostat
Speaker 7:  to a new sort of platform that merged with a company that had already been
Speaker 7:  doing demand response programs in select states
Speaker 7:  in the country. But now it's working towards sort of creating virtual power
Speaker 7:  plants using every smart house and every house that has
Speaker 7:  smart appliances as virtual power plants. And that's
Speaker 7:  something that could really help reduce the strain on the grid, you know,
Speaker 7:  and create a better experience for everyone. So
Speaker 7:  it's for the greater good.
Speaker 3:  Totally. I think that's really exciting. What you, you mentioned
Speaker 3:  heat pumps and water heaters. Are there other like huge categories still
Speaker 3:  missing in matter? What, what's kind of still on the, on the to-do list there
Speaker 3:  cameras
Speaker 7:  Is is a big one they said said that's definitely coming. Although it
Speaker 7:  will come from what I understand in a very limited fashion, it will really,
Speaker 7:  it'll just be that you can view your stream and control your stream in any
Speaker 7:  platform. But if you want recorded video, you want the added things like
Speaker 7:  ai, identification of people, animals, that's all gonna
Speaker 7:  be from your, from the manufacturer still. So it'll just be though that you'll
Speaker 7:  be able to in theory, view your video anywhere or use it
Speaker 7:  for hopefully for triggering automations like motion detection or if you
Speaker 7:  spot an animal, turn the siren on. This is for my chicken coop.
Speaker 7:  So the, I think, I think people want cameras there because you want one app
Speaker 7:  to see everything but you're still going and this is a theme with matter,
Speaker 7:  you're still going to need to use manufacturer apps if you
Speaker 7:  want the added benefits, if you want the added features. But if you just
Speaker 7:  want the basic use case of smart home, that's one one that's really
Speaker 7:  requested. People really want cameras. And then the other, which I don't
Speaker 7:  think we're ever going to get is security systems.
Speaker 3:  Oh sure.
Speaker 7:  So you know, your smart home security system, I think those may
Speaker 7:  bridge into matter because most of them are Z-Wave based,
Speaker 7:  but there's just too much around the ul. So all,
Speaker 7:  all security systems most, you know, if you have a certificate, most of them
Speaker 7:  are UL certified and that requires a lot of
Speaker 7:  certification. It's a tough certification to get. It is an important
Speaker 7:  one. Yeah. It ensures your security system is gonna work and the way you
Speaker 7:  expect it to and I just don't see much, I think the
Speaker 7:  meshing between security systems and matter is just not likely to happen
Speaker 7:  anytime soon. But I think we may get to the point where you can bridge it
Speaker 7:  so you can still control everything in one app. But those are the
Speaker 7:  main things that we're at now
Speaker 3:  That feels like an okay outcome to me with both of those actually to say,
Speaker 3:  you know, you can sort of take what's happening inside of those systems
Speaker 3:  and use it in the broader system. Yeah. But the idea that like in theory
Speaker 3:  everything in my matter home should have perfect
Speaker 3:  access to everything I've ever recorded on my security camera actually feels
Speaker 3:  kinda weird. So like right, it maybe, maybe at least at the
Speaker 3:  very least taking that one slightly slowly makes some sense to
Speaker 3:  me. Yeah, so I'm, I'm, I'm actually for once I will give the matter folks
Speaker 3:  some credit for going slowly here that that feels, that feels good. And
Speaker 7:  Then there is one more though. Sorry. Adaptive lighting. We're still waiting
Speaker 7:  for better control of lighting. Mm. They say that's coming soon,
Speaker 7:  but again this is gonna be one of the things you need to use your apps for,
Speaker 7:  but I still, I want to be able to use, I want every light in my house no
Speaker 7:  matter which manufacturer it's from to be able to sink to the scene that
Speaker 7:  I've chosen and they say that's coming. So hopefully in the
Speaker 7:  next update, but sorry. Yes, I could keep going.
Speaker 3:  Got it. Alright, two more. So one, I think I know
Speaker 3:  where both of these will fall, so we'll do the, we'll do the less exciting
Speaker 3:  one First you wrote about brilliant, this smart home company that was, I
Speaker 3:  would say once sort of high flying and now seems to
Speaker 3:  be in, in very rough shape. Brilliant kind of collapsing
Speaker 3:  for lack of a better term, big deal, medium deal or small deal.
Speaker 3:  I can sense you wanting to be nice to brilliant here.
Speaker 7:  It's not surprising. I kind of saw it coming. It
Speaker 7:  was a great idea. I have written a lot about wanting better controllers in
Speaker 7:  my home and it worked very well as that type of controller I had
Speaker 7:  been looking for, but only with certain products and that
Speaker 7:  was, you know, it, it was almost, it's almost like a symbol of the
Speaker 7:  problems the smart home have had to date. It's, they've been around a long
Speaker 7:  time. They launched, you know, almost 10 years ago. I think they've, they've
Speaker 7:  been around a long time. It's a good product, good hardware, but
Speaker 7:  unfor so they, they've basically gone outta business. I mean they're still
Speaker 7:  keeping the lights on so the system still works. I have one in my
Speaker 7:  house and it's not stopped working. They're looking for a buyer.
Speaker 7:  I did actually check in with the CEO just last, just a few days ago and
Speaker 7:  he said no news yet, but it's looking promising and he's hoping that users
Speaker 7:  of the system, which is a smart light switch that's installed
Speaker 7:  wire to your house but can also be used as a smart home controller to control
Speaker 7:  your, like your sono system, view your video doorbell control your
Speaker 7:  lights, your thermostat. It's sort of an all-in-one smart home controller,
Speaker 7:  but it had very limited integrations. And the company
Speaker 7:  said to me over the years when I'd asked 'em about this, it's like, it's
Speaker 7:  not that we don't want these integrations, it's that companies won't work
Speaker 7:  with us. And this is one of the reasons that Matter came about because of
Speaker 7:  this issue with interoperability and having to make individual integrations
Speaker 7:  with every device out there. And they, they've been trying to
Speaker 7:  do this for years, but they'd hardly added any new integrations in the last
Speaker 7:  few years and they weren't adopting matter. And I had asked them, they said
Speaker 7:  they were, they said they were, but they hadn't done it yet and Right.
Speaker 7:  Didn't really feel like it was, it was coming down the pipeline. Aaron, the
Speaker 7:  CEO told me that they did have a new generation
Speaker 7:  ready to roll better hardware, better
Speaker 7:  integration not, not better integrations yet, but they had sort of more there
Speaker 7:  that it was gonna make on-device processing ai, it was gonna be
Speaker 7:  a much improved device and less expensive because oh my gosh, I forgot
Speaker 7:  to mention how expensive these devices were starting at $400 for a light
Speaker 7:  switch was just too much and that was always their problem too
Speaker 7:  expensive. But when I asked they, it doesn't sound like they'd added thread
Speaker 7:  or matter yet even to this next generation. And I think there's some
Speaker 7:  potential for a buyer who does, if someone does come and take this
Speaker 7:  product and sort of keep it as it is but improve upon it,
Speaker 7:  that's really where I think it has a lot of potential to be a decent
Speaker 7:  smart home controller if it can work with everything. But yeah, it's, I mean
Speaker 7:  it's kind of a medium deal. It's, it is a symbol I think of with, of the
Speaker 7:  churn of the smart home. Like we're a decade or so
Speaker 7:  into this sort of DIY smart home now and we are seeing,
Speaker 7:  you know, some of the early pioneers kind of drop off.
Speaker 7:  They've either been bought or they've sort of become
Speaker 7:  somewhat boring, like Ring Fair, they're not really innovating anymore but
Speaker 7:  they're, you know, they have a core customer group that they have a great
Speaker 7:  business but it's not exciting anymore. Brilliant is an example. I
Speaker 7:  think they were an independent company and they kept independent until the
Speaker 7:  very end. But it's hard now for these startups. And I'm guessing, I don't
Speaker 7:  know if this next question is gonna be about a startup 'cause I think it
Speaker 7:  might be it's not actually. Oh, okay. Well I was
Speaker 7:  Quilt was the startup there. Oh yeah, the other one that I wrote about, which
Speaker 7:  is a heat pump company. But yeah, it's, it's not an easy space right now
Speaker 7:  for, for startups and it hasn't been for, for the last few years and,
Speaker 7:  and Brilliant was kind of sadly a, a victim of that. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Brilliant Is is always going to have a sort of special place in my heart.
Speaker 3:  I tried a very early version of it that just sucked. I mean it was so
Speaker 3:  broken and bad I put it in my wall and then the light
Speaker 3:  on the balcony of my apartment wouldn't turn off
Speaker 3:  until I took it out of the wall. But eventually they fixed it and I got a
Speaker 3:  working version of it that was like an early prototype that I just thought
Speaker 3:  was hilarious. But eventually I got a thing that worked. It was really great,
Speaker 3:  they got a lot of things right but it always felt like, like a touchscreen
Speaker 3:  on your wall can't possibly be the correct answer to this problem. Yeah and
Speaker 3:  and it does seem like the thing that Brilliant was was always going to be
Speaker 3:  sort of a transition into how this smart home is actually supposed to work.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. and it feels like good for us but bad for brilliant. That is the
Speaker 3:  transition that's happening right now. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. No I think you're right. The smart home needs to be smarter.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, agreed. Alright, last one. Google launched a bunch of new
Speaker 3:  home APIs at Google io and I
Speaker 3:  confess I'm torn between either this is a huge deal that might actually change
Speaker 3:  a lot of things and this is nothing and no one will adopt these APIs and
Speaker 3:  no one cares. So where are you? Big deal, medium deal, small deal.
Speaker 7:  Oh I think it's a huge deal. Okay, good. I think it's huge. I think it's
Speaker 7:  huge. Huge. I hope it's not, I hope it's not Google
Speaker 7:  just saying we have had enough of this someone else deal with it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So wait, what is sort of the idea behind the APIs that they're launching
Speaker 3:  here?
Speaker 7:  So they have launched Home a their home APIs, which is giving
Speaker 7:  access to developers, device makers at Makers to
Speaker 7:  any device connected to Google Home including Google's devices.
Speaker 7:  So thermostats presumably smoke alarms, cameras
Speaker 7:  they've said not necessarily initially, but that may be coming.
Speaker 7:  But one of the key parts is it's also giving access to the automation engine.
Speaker 7:  So now essentially, so with these APIs
Speaker 7:  a device maker can create an app from scratch
Speaker 7:  for their device or for any device that connects to Google Home
Speaker 7:  and create a smart home experience for you. So you wouldn't have to use Google
Speaker 7:  Home but you would that the Google Home app. But you could use
Speaker 7:  any automation system that the Google Home app
Speaker 7:  provides and any devices that connect to it and with Matter, there are
Speaker 7:  many devices to connect to it. So both works with Google and Matter
Speaker 7:  devices will be accessible through these APIs and it
Speaker 7:  basically is similar in some ways to how Apple Homes Home
Speaker 7:  Original Home Kit worked. If you've ever used like an Eve app or nano Leaf
Speaker 7:  app, you could access every device that was connected to Apple Home Kit
Speaker 7:  in the Eve app or the Nano Leaf app on iOS. This Google
Speaker 7:  Home API will work on both iOS or Android and
Speaker 7:  could basically mean people can create an entire smart home platform
Speaker 7:  from scratch on an app that you could use that isn't
Speaker 7:  Google Home but uses Google's smarts in the
Speaker 7:  background, which are good. They just have been
Speaker 7:  stymied because I feel like perhaps not enough
Speaker 7:  resources are going into developing Google Home at Google.
Speaker 7:  I mean Google's got its fingers in many pies and it's always felt like Google
Speaker 7:  Home is a bit of an afterthought. I think it's really only still here because
Speaker 7:  of the hardware. So I think this is big. I think it's
Speaker 7:  also really big because open APIs are really the
Speaker 7:  sort of lifeblood of the smart home when things are closed and locked down,
Speaker 7:  like brilliant, you know, when it shuts down it no longer works.
Speaker 7:  But if Brilliant had a local API like, you know, if
Speaker 7:  like Google Homes opening its APIs, then even if they
Speaker 7:  go outta business, the device is still gonna work in your home. That it's
Speaker 7:  like the lifeblood of the smart home APIs and opening this to anyone
Speaker 7:  to be able to use I think is, is really exciting. But you are right,
Speaker 7:  it does depend on people actually picking up and using
Speaker 7:  it. So far though, there are a number of big companies that, that
Speaker 7:  are using it. A DT is using the facial recognition on Google Nest
Speaker 7:  cameras. The facial recognition is going to let your system
Speaker 7:  disarm when it recognizes someone that you've authorized to come into your
Speaker 7:  home. It's called Trusted Neighbor. It's a new service that they're rolling
Speaker 7:  out later this year and that's all using Google Home APIs. So, and
Speaker 7:  it, it's again, going back to what I mentioned before, what this gives is
Speaker 7:  the potential for companies to build better experiences
Speaker 7:  than say Google Home has been doing today, but using the tools that are
Speaker 7:  already there, rather than having to reinvent the wheel or develop
Speaker 7:  individual partnerships with all of these companies to have access to their
Speaker 7:  devices. But Google is like Alexa in that it works with
Speaker 7:  pretty much everything but just in a limited way. And now you're
Speaker 7:  gonna have, I think much you're gonna see more innovation from
Speaker 7:  manufacturers and device makers and that is exciting if if
Speaker 7:  it happens.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, well part of what I wonder about the home API thing is if it means
Speaker 3:  we can get a bunch of new kinds of devices with
Speaker 3:  new capabilities, like the a DT thing you're talking about is is a really
Speaker 3:  good example of that. And again, it goes back to this idea of sort of making
Speaker 3:  the system work with itself in really cool ways, which I think is super exciting.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But then I just keep thinking about one of the examples that they gave
Speaker 3:  where they're like, DoorDash can make it so that
Speaker 3:  when the delivery person comes to your house it like automatically
Speaker 3:  unlocks for them and turns the front light on or whatever. And I, on the
Speaker 3:  one hand I think there are probably really cool, exciting versions of that
Speaker 3:  that exist in the world. On the other hand, I think that might be the most
Speaker 3:  like solution in search of a problem thing I've ever heard in my entire life.
Speaker 3:  So do you think, do you think there's anything to that idea that like maybe
Speaker 3:  this is how the smart home sort of invades the rest of the online ecosystem?
Speaker 3:  Or is this just a smart home thing?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so that was the way they were selling it. In fact, it was very not
Speaker 7:  smart home. They were like now any developer can from with any
Speaker 7:  app can, can use smart home devices and and I get where they were coming
Speaker 7:  from there. I do think that this to date the smart home has kind of
Speaker 7:  felt niche enclosed and like you need all of these devices to
Speaker 7:  get any benefit out of it. And this, whilst it is a,
Speaker 7:  it does seem like a, a solution in such a problem. The DoorDash
Speaker 7:  idea is, you know, you don't have to be a smart home device maker to
Speaker 7:  take advantage of what we can, what what you can do with these APIs.
Speaker 7:  And I think that was an important message to get out there just to show,
Speaker 7:  to maybe get people thinking about what they could do with this type of technology
Speaker 7:  because it isn't, it shouldn't just be limited to, you know, goodnight
Speaker 7:  routines or welcome home routines. There, there is so much more that we could
Speaker 7:  be doing with our homes. I think that was a slightly uninspired
Speaker 7:  example, but I, I think that people that are gonna be taking
Speaker 7:  advantage of this really it will be the smart home device makers. I'd be
Speaker 7:  interested to see if you know Uber or Airbnb
Speaker 7:  I could see potentially taking some real advantage of this
Speaker 7:  and companies that are sort of home related if not necessarily
Speaker 7:  smart home related. So I think, I think there's a lot of potential but
Speaker 7:  like all of these developer conferences, it, you know, these announcements
Speaker 7:  we get, it really is gonna depend on how much this has inspired
Speaker 7:  developers to go out and and do something. So we will, we'll have
Speaker 7:  to wait and see.
Speaker 3:  It feels like a fun moment in that sense that there's actually a lot
Speaker 3:  of sort of new fun toys for anyone working in the smart home
Speaker 3:  to play with between all the new stuff coming in matter and what
Speaker 3:  Google's up to and obviously Amazon is continuing to invest in Alexa and
Speaker 3:  it's like it, there's just sort of more stuff to work with
Speaker 3:  than there has been. Yeah. Which I guess means we're probably due for some
Speaker 3:  more chaos in the near term but also maybe means a lot
Speaker 3:  of this stuff that has just been sort of theory waiting for
Speaker 3:  infrastructure is like starting to become real, which I think is really cool.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think you're right and it is, it is an exciting time and you know,
Speaker 7:  we mentioned that this was sort of the end of a cycle for one load lot of
Speaker 7:  startups in the smart home, but it is the potential beginning of a cycle.
Speaker 7:  I mean there's a couple smart, smart home startups I've been talking with
Speaker 7:  over the last few months who have some great products that they're ready
Speaker 7:  to launch, but they're still just been waiting on this type of infrastructure
Speaker 7:  to come along to make it possible. And whilst the
Speaker 7:  signs are there, and this is one thing that I was quite disappointed about
Speaker 7:  with Matter 1.3, is that we still don't have the support
Speaker 7:  from platforms. I mean Google's opening up its APIs was a, was a nice
Speaker 7:  step in the right direction, but they still don't support half of the
Speaker 7:  new device types that are in matter 1.3. Apple hasn't, hasn't gone
Speaker 7:  beyond matter 1.0. I mean if we are lucky, we may get 1.2
Speaker 7:  devices, which are robot vacuums, washing machines,
Speaker 7:  fridges in Apple home with iOS 18 if we're lucky.
Speaker 7:  But that means another whole year until we get tumble dryers, right.
Speaker 7:  So I just, I really hope that the platforms and Amazon's been very
Speaker 7:  slow here. Samsung's been a little faster and I get why they're being
Speaker 7:  slow to some extent they don't wanna break people's homes, but if we
Speaker 7:  don't start getting this out there and the consumers get to use it
Speaker 7:  and get excited about it, then we are not gonna get the developers coming
Speaker 7:  on board and making these good experiences. You know, we need, we
Speaker 7:  need both sides of, of the solution here to, to get people
Speaker 7:  excited. So I really wanna see Apple, Google, Amazon,
Speaker 7:  Samsung, just go all in on what this, this platform,
Speaker 7:  this protocol, this smart home standard that they've developed to
Speaker 7:  solve this problem. They can't just leave it there now that
Speaker 7:  they've, yeah, now they brought it to life. They've really got to put the
Speaker 7:  work in and see this through and so far
Speaker 7:  it's been pretty limited and that's been quite disappointing. So I'm hoping
Speaker 7:  that we'll hear something exciting at WWC next month. I'm not
Speaker 7:  holding my breath, I think it's just gonna be all about ai but
Speaker 7:  yeah, I may be wrong. I
Speaker 3:  Suspect, I suspect you're right.
Speaker 7:  Prove me wrong, apple. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Fingers crossed. All right, before we go, you've been playing with tons of
Speaker 3:  new smart home gadgets. What give me, give me your favorite coolest thing
Speaker 3:  you've been playing with recently. Oh,
Speaker 7:  Well actually I have, I have to go with my smart chicken coop.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Do tell.
Speaker 7:  Yes, I am been testing a new smart chicken coop, it's
Speaker 7:  called Coop and it is a startup based out
Speaker 7:  in California and it has, it is very well designed chicken
Speaker 7:  coop, but the main kind of smart features, it has two cameras in with
Speaker 7:  really impressive AI capabilities. So it can tell me
Speaker 7:  if the door of the coop is open, it can tell me if there's an egg laid,
Speaker 7:  it can count how many chickens are in my coop. So in case one's gone
Speaker 7:  missing. and it will also tell me if it's spots like a fox or coyote or if
Speaker 7:  it's spots a, a cat or a bobcat. Like different
Speaker 7:  predators, different nuisance animals. Like it has some really interesting
Speaker 7:  AI capabilities as well as the automatic door that will
Speaker 7:  open and close at the right time based on sunrise or sunset
Speaker 7:  so that the chicks go in and out. I have baby chicks right now. I got new
Speaker 7:  ones to test out this coop 'cause my, my ladies were too big to fit in this
Speaker 7:  coop. It's quite small, but it's been a lot of fun. It's just, I
Speaker 7:  mean, baby chicks, I mean it's, that's fun.
Speaker 3:  You can't, you can't beat it,
Speaker 7:  You can't beat that. It's very expensive. I think. I wanna say it's like
Speaker 7:  $2,500, but having built my own chicken coop with
Speaker 7:  wood, well having watched my husband build our own
Speaker 7:  chicken coop and helped buy the stuff at Lowe's,
Speaker 7:  they're not cheap. You know, it's an expensive product
Speaker 7:  whether you buy one or build one. So it's interesting to see this kind of
Speaker 7:  innovation, smart home innovation, sort of moving outside of the
Speaker 7:  home and into the garden and you know, homesteading with
Speaker 7:  McChickens.
Speaker 11:  ARC browser is AI generating whole kind of webpages every time you search
Speaker 11:  something on your phone. And then I'm one of the 12 people that uses
Speaker 11:  Edge at Work and I actually use BIN to search because then it will
Speaker 11:  auto generate a response with copilot first and then kind give me all
Speaker 11:  the web results. So when you know Google was telling Eli that that's actually
Speaker 11:  something they're experiencing, that the people have higher click through
Speaker 11:  rates from those generated responses. I mean I can really back that up because
Speaker 11:  that's exactly what I do and, and so I'm wondering is the problem just that
Speaker 11:  Google's doing it, is the problem that they're so large that if they're
Speaker 11:  doing this, this impacts the way that the search world works?
Speaker 11:  You know, because obviously they're top dog and that when the Edge browser
Speaker 11:  and when the ARC browser are doing this, that doesn't really matter because
Speaker 11:  they're just not the dominant search. I feel like that's maybe the argument
Speaker 11:  here. So I was just wondering what your guys' thoughts were on that. If
Speaker 11:  it's just a matter of scale, not a matter of what they're doing or if there's
Speaker 11:  more to this. Thanks guys.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I think the answer to this question is mostly yes,
Speaker 3:  but kind of yes and no. I think on the one hand, the scale
Speaker 3:  of Google is the thing you just can't overstate the
Speaker 3:  extent to which Google is the center of the internet. For anyone who makes
Speaker 3:  a website, whether it's a cooking blog or a news site or just a
Speaker 3:  place to show off your photography, Google is the internet. It is
Speaker 3:  the main discovery tool of the internet. So what you've seen
Speaker 3:  is everything over the last, I don't know, 15 years really
Speaker 3:  has reshaped in order to work the way that Google has asked it to work.
Speaker 3:  You see cooking blogs just to keep harping on that, they
Speaker 3:  have changed the way that they make their pages in order to suit Google.
Speaker 3:  The thing where at the bottom you have the recipe, but at the top you have,
Speaker 3:  you know, 2000 words of stories about the person and there's a bunch of photos
Speaker 3:  and there's a bunch of sub headlines that are all kind of questions that
Speaker 3:  don't really fit but are questions people might be Googling. All of that
Speaker 3:  is designed for Google. The SEO search engine optimization
Speaker 3:  has completely reshaped the web. This is a thing we've talked a lot about
Speaker 3:  on the show. This is a thing we've written a lot about on the site. I'll
Speaker 3:  put some links in the show notes, but Google has fundamentally reshaped the
Speaker 3:  web because it is so important because when people want to find
Speaker 3:  things on the internet, they don't go other places. And I think the Arc
Speaker 3:  search and Bing are instructive examples here actually because
Speaker 3:  it's true that Bing has been doing this longer than Google. You could
Speaker 3:  already AI your way through the internet with Bing. And
Speaker 3:  it's not that no one noticed, but no one really cared because Bing is not
Speaker 3:  meaningful to the traffic and revenue and
Speaker 3:  existence of websites in the way that Google is. It just
Speaker 3:  does not matter what everybody else does cumulative
Speaker 3:  in the same way that it does what Google does. Google has something like
Speaker 3:  90% of the search on the internet. That's
Speaker 3:  a crazy number. That is one of the things that has brought Google into the
Speaker 3:  antitrust scrutiny that it has because it is so powerful because it
Speaker 3:  has no real meaningful competitor. The flip side of that is
Speaker 3:  that I think the things that we're talking about apply just as much
Speaker 3:  to these other things you're talking about. When Arc, for instance, rolled
Speaker 3:  out the browse for me feature where you type in a search query, you hit
Speaker 3:  browse for me and instead of giving you a bunch of search results, it sort
Speaker 3:  of compiles a webpage for you, which is a lot like what the AI overviews
Speaker 3:  on Google are doing. It gives you the summary and then some links and some
Speaker 3:  multimedia stuff. People had the same kind of visceral
Speaker 3:  reaction, which is that it felt like this exchange of value
Speaker 3:  that people who make websites have with Discovery tools
Speaker 3:  was gone. Right? The idea for two decades has been that
Speaker 3:  I am going to make something and I'm going to let Google
Speaker 3:  access it and index it and cache it on its servers and make ads when people
Speaker 3:  try to find it in exchange for sending traffic to my
Speaker 3:  website and the idea that I could monetize or in other
Speaker 3:  ways benefit from the traffic to my website. That was the trade Google
Speaker 3:  gets to have and have access to. And in some ways sort of
Speaker 3:  intermediate how people find my website because it sends people to my
Speaker 3:  website. That is the trade, that is the trade people have made on the internet
Speaker 3:  for 20 years. That feels different when it's ai.
Speaker 3:  And I think the way people reacted to Arc, there have been people who said
Speaker 3:  this with Bing, there have been people who worried about this with perplexity.
Speaker 3:  All of these tools run into the same thing, which is they shortcut that
Speaker 3:  they, they completely end around that exchange of value and just say,
Speaker 3:  don't worry, I went and visited all those webpages for you and brought back
Speaker 3:  the information that you need. Nevermind that the crawler on that
Speaker 3:  webpage doesn't accrue me any advertising money. It's not going to click
Speaker 3:  my affiliate links, it's not going to be impressed with my stuff
Speaker 3:  and read more articles. It's not going to make the cookies
Speaker 3:  that I suggested and then save it and tell friends about it and bring more
Speaker 3:  traffic. It doesn't do any of that. It just pulled it into a
Speaker 3:  database and spat out the information with essentially no link
Speaker 3:  back to the original source of the information and certainly no reason
Speaker 3:  to go find the source of that information because I've already given you
Speaker 3:  everything you need right here in the summary. On the one hand, cool user
Speaker 3:  experience for lots of things, on the other hand totally breaks the value
Speaker 3:  exchange of the internet, right? So I think the thesis is not that different
Speaker 3:  between what you're seeing from all of these AI companies and what you're
Speaker 3:  seeing from Google. The difference is just the scale. And
Speaker 3:  Google has been existentially important to
Speaker 3:  websites for two decades in a way that I think has been problematic for a
Speaker 3:  really long time. There is this sense that Google won in
Speaker 3:  some way that Google became the arbiter of the internet and that the only
Speaker 3:  thing to do as a media company or as a cooking
Speaker 3:  blog or as a person with a website of any kind was to
Speaker 3:  play Google's game or try to find a way to get money from Google
Speaker 3:  directly. And so you've seen a lot of these fights over the years of companies
Speaker 3:  like News Corp picking fights with Google and saying, you have to
Speaker 3:  pay us for our content or we're going to
Speaker 3:  disappear. And I think what has been true forever is that these websites
Speaker 3:  have needed Google more than Google has needed these websites. And that has
Speaker 3:  been a challenge. And one thing you've heard us talk about, and Neli in particular
Speaker 3:  talks about this is that Google doesn't actually owe these
Speaker 3:  websites anything. And I think Google would tell you that it
Speaker 3:  cares about them and believes in the web and wants to preserve the open web.
Speaker 3:  That's all really easy to say out loud. And it's also
Speaker 3:  not particularly meaningful when Google is able to do the
Speaker 3:  things that it's doing now, which is say, well, our responsibility is actually
Speaker 3:  to get users to the information that they want as quickly as possible. And
Speaker 3:  again, that's actually an interesting product argument. It subverts a huge
Speaker 3:  amount of the way that the internet has worked in part because all of these
Speaker 3:  websites are so reliant on Google and what Google has meant to them for so
Speaker 3:  long. This is what we went through with Facebook when Facebook made everybody
Speaker 3:  pivot to video with the promises of huge amounts of traffic and tons of money
Speaker 3:  and then that all sort of dried up and everybody kind of got used to Facebook's
Speaker 3:  wishy washiness and back and forth on supporting websites and caring
Speaker 3:  about traffic outside and eventually just realized, well, okay, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  treat Facebook as kind of a a value add, right? If we get traffic from Facebook,
Speaker 3:  terrific, but I'm not going to bend over backwards in order to get traffic
Speaker 3:  from Facebook. And that hurt a lot of websites traffic. There are a lot of
Speaker 3:  websites that went away when Facebook stopped sending them traffic. And
Speaker 3:  the same has never really happened with Google in part because Google
Speaker 3:  more or less remained a good citizen of that value
Speaker 3:  exchange we're talking about until now. And there's a lot left
Speaker 3:  to be seen. I think it's possible, as Nathan says, that really great
Speaker 3:  content is going to be more prioritized. And the
Speaker 3:  question will be what happens to the folks who write this
Speaker 3:  sort of commodity stuff? Like I think a lot about the articles years ago
Speaker 3:  that every time John Oliver would post anything, every website on the internet
Speaker 3:  would be like John Oliver roasts the whoever, right? Like he gets mad about
Speaker 3:  hotdog and lots of people cared about what John Oliver did, so they would
Speaker 3:  google John Oliver on a Monday morning after the Sunday night show and whoever
Speaker 3:  was at the top of search results made a ton of money and got a lot of traffic.
Speaker 3:  That was always kind of a weird game. And I think you could reasonably argue
Speaker 3:  that the best outcome is actually just that you get to John Oliver much more
Speaker 3:  quickly instead of a website talking about John Oliver. But
Speaker 3:  what if there's really great unique context added or lots
Speaker 3:  of interesting new information or somebody did good reporting on top
Speaker 3:  of the reporting that John Oliver did. This question of that sort of sliding
Speaker 3:  scale between what is commodity information that
Speaker 3:  everyone should know and no one has particular claim to. Like when was Abraham
Speaker 3:  Lincoln born? That is just a question. It doesn't matter who has the answer.
Speaker 3:  There are not particularly interesting reasons to go to one place or another
Speaker 3:  for the answer. I just want to know when Abraham Lincoln was born all the
Speaker 3:  way down to like truly great original stuff, whether
Speaker 3:  it's a new recipe or new art that somebody made or
Speaker 3:  a new essay from somebody smart that you like or original
Speaker 3:  reporting in the news business, Google is now in a position of having to
Speaker 3:  decide where one of those things ends and the other begins and
Speaker 3:  is also just making this bet, or at least this promise to publishers that,
Speaker 3:  oh, we're going to get so much better at giving people information that they're
Speaker 3:  actually going to be more curious and they're gonna wanna know more stuff.
Speaker 3:  I'm very suspicious of that argument to be totally honest. Google is like,
Speaker 3:  if we just Surface better stuff to more people, more people will click on
Speaker 3:  it. As somebody who makes their living making things on the internet, I sure
Speaker 3:  hope that's true. I'm not confident that that's true, but it does put
Speaker 3:  Google back in this position of once again being the arbiter
Speaker 3:  of all of this stuff. And I think you'll see us talk a lot more in the
Speaker 3:  near future about different kinds of search engines because I think search
Speaker 3:  engines are great, right? Like what Google was for a really long time
Speaker 3:  was really valuable to a lot of people and I think Google has shifted away
Speaker 3:  from that to something else. That new thing might be great, it might be
Speaker 3:  different, it might be terrible, who knows? But I think there's going to
Speaker 3:  be interesting competition in this space for a long time because Google is
Speaker 3:  kind of running away from the thing that people loved about it. And
Speaker 3:  that is weird to me to be totally honest, that there are a lot
Speaker 3:  of companies that you can understand why they pivot. Google is taking this
Speaker 3:  beloved, wildly successful business and kind of pivoting
Speaker 3:  away from it. And I think you're gonna see a lot of folks come in and say,
Speaker 3:  well actually search was both a good product and a good business and maybe
Speaker 3:  what we need to do is be part of that because Google is going to just leave
Speaker 3:  that gap open in the market again. So I think all of this is gonna get
Speaker 3:  more interesting and more competitive, but also the immediate threat to
Speaker 3:  publishers and bloggers and anyone who makes a website on the internet is
Speaker 3:  that all of a sudden it could just dry up traffic. Google
Speaker 3:  has made changes before that. People have turned around and said, oh, Google
Speaker 3:  made a small algorithm change and my website essentially disappeared
Speaker 3:  from the internet. That's a real thing that happens. and it happens to bad
Speaker 3:  websites that probably should have their spammy stuff removed from Google
Speaker 3:  search. and it applies to really great websites that don't deserve
Speaker 3:  that and just get caught up in Google's changes for whatever reason. And
Speaker 3:  we're already seeing with these AI overviews, lots of unintended
Speaker 3:  weirdness. There's, there's always people out there posting stuff about,
Speaker 3:  I think there was one that it was like add glue to your pizza sauce to make
Speaker 3:  it stickier. Like don't do that. But that's the stuff that's out
Speaker 3:  there now. So we're at the beginning of a thing that Google has just
Speaker 3:  turned on and is making a
Speaker 3:  our best. As always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, Surface
Speaker 3:  and Wil Poor The. Vergecast is a VERGE production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 3:  podcast network. Neli, Alex, and I'll be back on Friday to talk
Speaker 3:  about presumably more open AI shenanigans, all the stuff
Speaker 3:  that's to come at WWDC and lots more. See you then. Rock and roll.