# Transcript
ID: 8de9ad83-f18e-42f4-b6c2-8ec5dbd34c24
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4705264774626627651/4959835184873712387/s93290-US-4015s-1705483301.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of endlessly looping sounds:
02:33 - David Pierce dives into one piece of music that has taken over "North Sea TikTok"
20:45 - Alex Cranz joins the show to preview new TV shows coming to streaming in 2024, and gives predictions about which streaming service will come out on top this year.
55:36 - This week's Vergecast Hotline question about E Ink at CES.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Endlessly Looping
Speaker 2:  Sounds. I'm your friend David Pierce and I'm inside. All
Speaker 2:  I've been is inside these last few days because I'm in Washington DC
Speaker 2:  where it's freezing cold and snowing and not only is it
Speaker 2:  nasty to be outside, but this seems to be one of those cities where
Speaker 2:  everyone just forgets how to drive as soon as any kind of
Speaker 2:  precipitation happens, like even the idea that it might rain and
Speaker 2:  everybody just starts driving a thousand miles an hour into medians for some
Speaker 2:  reason. So basically, not only is it just kind of gross to go
Speaker 2:  outside right now, it's legitimately dangerous to my health.
Speaker 2:  So the last few days I've gone out to walk the dog and grow grocery shopping
Speaker 2:  and that's pretty much it. Here's hoping for better weather
Speaker 2:  both for me and for a lot of folks really soon. Anyway, we have a
Speaker 2:  great show for you today. Now that the holidays and CES are over, we are
Speaker 2:  back to our regularly scheduled Vergecast programming and we have a bunch
Speaker 2:  of good stuff for you. Today we're gonna talk about TikTok, specifically
Speaker 2:  one part of TikTok and even more specifically one sound that has taken
Speaker 2:  over that one specific part of TikTok in a totally fascinating way.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna talk about streaming services because this is going to be
Speaker 2:  another big year for streaming services and not everyone is gonna
Speaker 2:  survive it. All. That's coming up in just a sec, but first I have to find
Speaker 2:  the space heater because even just looking out the window is making me cold.
Speaker 2:  This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Hi, we're visible ringing in 2024 with a two years resolution to help you
Speaker 3:  save on wireless. Get one line with unlimited 5G data on Verizon's network.
Speaker 3:  Just $20 a month for 24 whole months with no annual contracts. That's 20
Speaker 3:  for 24 in 2024. Yep, we're pretty proud of that. Your gym
Speaker 3:  goals, you're on your own. A two years resolution. To save on wireless, we've
Speaker 3:  got you Switch and save@visible.com. Use code visible 24. Hurry ends
Speaker 3:  January 31st. New members only promotional rate with service on the visible
Speaker 3:  plan. For additional terms in network management practices, see visible.com.
Speaker 4:  Introducing Kia's first, all electric SUV, the 2024
Speaker 4:  Kia EV nine. Remarkably luxurious and relentlessly capable.
Speaker 4:  The Kia EV nine has something for everyone impressive. Zero to 60
Speaker 4:  speed off-Road agility, a spacious three row cabin, even
Speaker 4:  available mood lighting. Get premium comfort and rugged capability
Speaker 4:  all in one sleek, spacious package. The all new, all
Speaker 4:  electric three row Kia EV nine electric like you've never seen.
Speaker 4:  The 2024 Kia E nine is available now. Inventory limited. Check
Speaker 4:  the dealer for availability and visit kia.com/e nine for more
Speaker 4:  details.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back so a few weeks ago I noticed I started
Speaker 2:  hearing this one song on TikTok over and over and
Speaker 2:  over and over again. That itself is not
Speaker 2:  surprising or interesting, right? I mean there's a new viral thing on TikTok
Speaker 2:  once a week and I think at this point I know 30 seconds of every popular
Speaker 2:  song on earth just because of TikTok, but this song just
Speaker 2:  immediately jumps out as different. It's not the backing track
Speaker 2:  for a dance challenge and nobody's using it to make like cute videos of their
Speaker 2:  kids. It's the opposite. Actually. This song seems to be
Speaker 2:  the official soundtrack of terrifying TikTok videos,
Speaker 2:  like videos showing Bigfoot sightings and deep Sea
Speaker 2:  monsters captured through all of those always blurry camera shots.
Speaker 2:  You know what I'm talking about? Videos with captions like things they didn't
Speaker 2:  want you to know about, but mostly it's videos about the North
Speaker 2:  Sea
Speaker 2:  North Sea TikTok has been booming the last couple of months and
Speaker 2:  this song is the soundtrack. Big ships
Speaker 2:  crashing down into huge waves, workers dangling
Speaker 2:  from oil rigs while the water roils around them deep
Speaker 2:  dark water capsizing ships or tossing a bunch of shipping
Speaker 2:  containers overboard into the Sea. This trend seemed to take off
Speaker 2:  really in late November and early December and is still going
Speaker 2:  strong now and it seems like practically every one of those videos
Speaker 2:  has this song Underneath
Speaker 6:  Yo.
Speaker 6:  Oh, all Hands.
Speaker 2:  This song is called Hoist the Colors. It was originally written by Han
Speaker 2:  Zimmer for the not very good movie, pirates of the Caribbean. At
Speaker 2:  World's End, it's this early scene in the movie where a bunch
Speaker 2:  of pirates or people accused of consorting with pirates are about to
Speaker 2:  be hanged and they start to sing a song together at the Gallows.
Speaker 2:  Here's what it sounds like in the movie.
Speaker 2:  The version going viral on TikTok is by a group called the Bass Singers
Speaker 2:  of TikTok and the story of this song starts with this guy, so
Speaker 7:  You can enter me as Bobby Waters, also known as Bobby Bass.
Speaker 7:  My real name is not Bobby Bass, that's just my stage name.
Speaker 2:  If you're a regular TikTok viewer, there's a decent chance you've heard of
Speaker 2:  Bobby too or at least seen some of his videos. He's gone pretty viral
Speaker 2:  a few times. He started posting on the platform a couple of years ago during
Speaker 2:  the pandemic.
Speaker 7:  I was in my junior year of college and everyone went home. So I just had
Speaker 7:  all this time on my hand. I was only taking like one online class over the
Speaker 7:  summer.
Speaker 2:  Bobby's friend showed him a TikTok of this emerging trend at the time
Speaker 2:  where bass singers would add bass to other songs on TikTok.
Speaker 8:  Where did I go wrong? I lost a
Speaker 8:  friend somewhere along in the bitterness.
Speaker 2:  They just give them some real like low end energy. You know
Speaker 2:  Bobby, as I'm confident you can tell by his voice, is a bass singer.
Speaker 2:  He dug the trend and he started doing the same thing. Dueting a song on
Speaker 2:  TikTok and adding a deep boomy bass to it.
Speaker 9:  I'm So
Speaker 9:  I, confident
Speaker 9:  I'm unstoppable today.
Speaker 2:  This group of Bass adders became kind of a community on TikTok.
Speaker 7:  TikTok was a great way for bass singers to kinda like add what they
Speaker 7:  do, whether it be a duet or whether it would be singing a song like an octave
Speaker 7:  lower or just doing their bass thing. It drew a lot of attention to bass
Speaker 7:  singing in general. So a bunch of young bass singers were like, oh, I didn't
Speaker 7:  know I could do this. So they would hop on the app and kind of do a similar
Speaker 7:  thing. And so now we have all this like new generation of bass singers coming
Speaker 7:  up and then around the end of 2020 I was saying like the
Speaker 7:  Sea shanty craze started happening.
Speaker 2:  You remember the Sea shanty craze, right? Especially the one song. Soon
Speaker 2:  may the weatherman come, it was like completely ubiquitous
Speaker 2:  for a while.
Speaker 10:  Soon may the weatherman come to bring a sugar and tea
Speaker 10:  and rum one day when the tongue is done will take on
Speaker 10:  even go.
Speaker 2:  Everybody including these bass singers was making Sea shanty videos for a
Speaker 2:  while. Things got weird during the Pandemic, you guys, this particular video
Speaker 2:  from a singer named Nathan Evans and a bunch of other folks was probably
Speaker 2:  the apex of the whole thing. The Sea shanty trend got so big that
Speaker 2:  Bobby and a few other singers formed a group called The Weatherman. They
Speaker 2:  got a record deal and they made an album of these Sea shanties.
Speaker 11:  The whales tale came up and caught her hands to the side
Speaker 11:  when shed down low
Speaker 2:  On his own. TikTok though Bobby kept making stuff dueting other songs to
Speaker 2:  add bass and just seeing what worked. Part of being on TikTok is you
Speaker 2:  just try stuff and you see what works and a super bassy cover
Speaker 2:  that he had done of Hoist the Colors did pretty well.
Speaker 9:  Yo,
Speaker 9:  oh and
Speaker 2:  Bobby also just happened to really love the song.
Speaker 7:  Just like one person just starts singing and then everyone joins in, all
Speaker 7:  the pirates join in and it's kind of like this, it's almost like scary. It's
Speaker 7:  like they're singing, dude. Like just imagine if everyone who you're about
Speaker 7:  to execute just starts singing the whole song and literally the whole see
Speaker 7:  can hear it. It lends itself very, very well. Songs like
Speaker 7:  that. Songs like Misty Mountains, they're, they're very like Bass anthem,
Speaker 7:  these like slow minor songs that just kind of almost
Speaker 7:  folky, almost like working. See shanty like io hoist. The
Speaker 7:  colors a couple of different things because the first one that I did that
Speaker 7:  really blew up was with a, an amazing singer called Melinda.
Speaker 2:  That video Bobby told me took him from 200,000 followers on
Speaker 2:  TikTok to over a million. Bobby and Melinda ended up making and
Speaker 2:  releasing a full version, which is really cool, but that's not the one we're
Speaker 2:  talking about. Neither are the other experiments and duets that Bobby did
Speaker 2:  of hoist the colors, all of which kept doing well. There's something about
Speaker 2:  this song that people on TikTok really like. But then
Speaker 7:  So one morning, as soon as I woke up I was like, screw it, let's do
Speaker 7:  it. And So I just went over to my computer, started planning it, started
Speaker 7:  a session, started reaching out to some people. He ended
Speaker 2:  Up with a handful of different bass singers, most of whom he'd either worked
Speaker 2:  with or duetted or both.
Speaker 7:  There were seven vocalists on the track that we ended up making. It was me,
Speaker 7:  Bobby, it was Davide. He was one of the soloists,
Speaker 7:  Eric Holloway who is one of the lowest voices on the planet
Speaker 7:  and he has the third very, very, very deep solo. And then
Speaker 7:  for the other background singers, we had Danny Brek, also known as Big Brev.
Speaker 7:  He had like all the baritone parts. Luke Taylor who we both know,
Speaker 7:  one of the dudes from the Wellman, other super low bass. We had eBucks also
Speaker 7:  named whose real name is Nelson. And then we had this Nyle
Speaker 7:  whose real name is Jesse. I kind of just put together this kinda like
Speaker 7:  dream team of singers. Bobby
Speaker 2:  Spent a couple of weeks arranging the song, sent out all the individual parts
Speaker 2:  to the singers and then had them record themselves a bunch of times each.
Speaker 7:  So just made a whole Google folder with documents and folders to put like
Speaker 7:  your audio files and videos. They weren't just recording like one line
Speaker 7:  for one part. I gave each of them like a couple different parts to sing like
Speaker 7:  base one and base two. I gave Danny three or four
Speaker 7:  different baritone parts and had them all record probably
Speaker 7:  two or three takes of each part because if we just had seven
Speaker 7:  voices on this and layered it sound cool, but it wouldn't sound
Speaker 7:  like as grand as like all of them like layered with like a ton of
Speaker 7:  different voices, kind of like a choir. We don't have a choir. We all couldn't
Speaker 7:  sing together because we were all over the world. So we just recorded a
Speaker 7:  ton of different tracks. I put them all together and I produced the rest
Speaker 7:  of the session.
Speaker 2:  Bobby also got some help mixing the track and had some friends add violin
Speaker 2:  and cello at the beginning and put this whole thing together. A few weeks
Speaker 2:  later the song is done. Bobby makes a quick music video for it and he
Speaker 2:  uploads it to one of those sites that distributes your song to basically
Speaker 2:  all the platforms everywhere. The song did well from the beginning, not like
Speaker 2:  massively viral well but solidly growing fast. Good
Speaker 2:  song, people are listening and that's what it did for most of 2023.
Speaker 2:  Then North Sea TikTok happened.
Speaker 2:  I can't prove this because tiktoks search tools are terrible and incredibly
Speaker 2:  underpowered and basically useless, but I think, I think you can
Speaker 2:  trace the beginning of this trend to a video from an account called UK
Speaker 2:  Towns in late November. This account had been around for a while, mostly
Speaker 2:  posting videos about cool unknown places around the uk, but
Speaker 2:  then kind of out of nowhere it posted a video about this beautiful
Speaker 2:  pure water from a glacier which blew up. It has
Speaker 2:  14.3 million views on TikTok right now. There's a decent chance you've seen
Speaker 2:  it. And then the next day, November 27th, 2023, that
Speaker 2:  same account UK towns posted a video with the text The
Speaker 2:  North Sea, the most treacherous Sea in the world written over top of it.
Speaker 2:  It was all the stuff you now see everywhere, this huge
Speaker 2:  aircraft carrier looking ship rolling in the waves,
Speaker 2:  waves crashing up on a dock and almost knocking someone in the water. Big
Speaker 2:  storms, big water. You get the idea that video now has
Speaker 2:  118 million views and it had this sound playing
Speaker 2:  underneath he
Speaker 2:  North Sea. TikTok took off in a huge, huge way. From
Speaker 2:  there I asked TikTok to pull some data for me and the numbers are pretty
Speaker 2:  wild. The North Sea hashtag has 2.9 billion
Speaker 2:  global views on TikTok. 2.2 of them coming just since the
Speaker 2:  beginning of November. That was a 315% increase in
Speaker 2:  views in those two months. The North Sea TikTok hashtag
Speaker 2:  109.5 million views, 98.9 of them in the last
Speaker 2:  two months. That's a 920% increase. This just
Speaker 2:  happened out of nowhere. There were older TikTok videos about the North
Speaker 2:  Sea and scary stuff in general, but they tended to sound like this
Speaker 2:  or this,
Speaker 2:  oh or this
Speaker 2:  different vibes, am I right? But as the North
Speaker 2:  Sea trend took off, the bass singers became the unofficial
Speaker 2:  official soundtrack of North Sea. TikTok TikTok told me there have been more
Speaker 2:  than 130,000 videos using that 62nd clip and
Speaker 2:  that number was from a couple of weeks ago. It's still going up really fast
Speaker 2:  for his part. Bobby says he doesn't remember the first time he noticed how
Speaker 2:  hoist the colors was being used, but he definitely didn't see it coming.
Speaker 7:  I had so many friends and family send me these videos where they're like,
Speaker 7:  because the sound starts off with my voice and they're like, it's Bobby.
Speaker 7:  And so they send it to me
Speaker 2:  And it turns out that when you blow up on TikTok you tend to blow up
Speaker 2:  elsewhere too.
Speaker 7:  Right now the video is and everywhere streaming is doing like
Speaker 7:  almost quadruple as it normally does, which is really, really
Speaker 7:  great for all of us.
Speaker 2:  The song in particular and the North Sea TikTok trend in general
Speaker 2:  actually got so big it became kind of a parody of itself, which honestly
Speaker 2:  I love. There were people like Chris Olsson who were like enough
Speaker 2:  hoist the colors.
Speaker 16:  Why is TikTok make me feel like the North Sea is something I should be fearing
Speaker 16:  daily in my everyday life? Like it's a present threat that I'm going to
Speaker 16:  somehow end up in
Speaker 2:  The north. And then there were people making fun of the song,
Speaker 17:  Yo
Speaker 17:  oh ha hoist, the
Speaker 17:  colors high.
Speaker 2:  That jokey version of hoist the colors itself also has gone kind of viral.
Speaker 2:  It's ridiculous. My favorite one of these videos by the way is just like
Speaker 2:  a person in the bathtub slowly splashing the water back and
Speaker 2:  forth while playing that nasally version of the song. It kills me every
Speaker 2:  time. But wait, I've come this far and I have not answered the real question
Speaker 2:  here. Why this song, this version, this clip?
Speaker 2:  The honest truth is it turns out it's a little hard to know when Bobby added
Speaker 2:  the song to TikTok to be used as a sound, he didn't pick the
Speaker 2:  62nd clip that everybody now uses and he didn't go in and tag it.
Speaker 2:  Scary and North Sea and big deep bass that
Speaker 2:  makes you feel feelings every time you see it. Somebody just picked that
Speaker 2:  song and made a video and now everybody else does it too. That's just
Speaker 2:  kind of how it happens. But mostly though I think it's just that it
Speaker 2:  fits in a funny way. North Sea TikTok is almost a perfect
Speaker 2:  representation of what Bobby says he was originally going for
Speaker 2:  with the song.
Speaker 7:  I wanted this song essentially to sound like
Speaker 7:  you've got a giant ship full of mountains just rowing
Speaker 7:  through like treacherous Sea and stuff like that. Just essentially
Speaker 7:  like if earthquakes were singing, I just wanted everyone to like
Speaker 7:  feel how much bass you can actually put in something because if
Speaker 7:  you listen to those courses, it's just so full
Speaker 7:  and the bass just cuts so hard and it's just you feel it right in your
Speaker 7:  Chest. So having all these big voices to like envelop
Speaker 7:  like just the vastness of the Sea and what's in it because the
Speaker 7:  Sea is big and so we have some big voices to, to add on
Speaker 7:  to that
Speaker 2:  Anecdotally, at least on my for you feed North Sea TikTok is
Speaker 2:  starting to slow down a tiny bit, but hoist the colors is showing up
Speaker 2:  in all kinds of new places. Now I'm seeing it on those
Speaker 2:  videos that try to test whether you have different phobias, which is
Speaker 2:  horrifying. Some have strange natural phenomenons. Many,
Speaker 2:  many, many videos of monsters that I used to think were fake but
Speaker 2:  don don't know. Those videos are very convincing, all sorts of things
Speaker 2:  in every case. The sound does one thing. It increases this feeling
Speaker 2:  of unease like you're headed towards disaster but you have
Speaker 2:  no choice but to accept your fate. You're a deep dark
Speaker 2:  stormy wave crashing basey fate.
Speaker 2:  As for Bobby, he seems to be enjoying the run but is also cognizant of not
Speaker 2:  wanting to be the hoist the colors guy or the Sea shanty guy forever.
Speaker 2:  There's
Speaker 7:  Always that part of me when I see something's blowing up or if it's around
Speaker 7:  a holiday time and I have a holiday tune that I'm like, I just feel like
Speaker 7:  I need to put as much stuff out about this as possible. Like every time
Speaker 7:  it would like reach a new milestone, I would share it, add the sound, and
Speaker 7:  then sometimes we create old videos that we've done to try and like boost
Speaker 7:  it for lack of a better term. Or maybe it's the best term milking it for
Speaker 7:  what it is or what we got. But essentially the next thing
Speaker 7:  that is the big question for us and we don't have control
Speaker 7:  over how long a trend will last on TikTok because
Speaker 7:  many people have tried to continue trends, but
Speaker 7:  it's one person cannot do that. It's the mass of people
Speaker 7:  subconsciously decide whether a trend is over or not. So
Speaker 7:  this North Sea trend, much like many before, it will die down at some point,
Speaker 7:  but I'm, I'm really glad that a lot of people are because they're, they're
Speaker 7:  fun videos too. Just watching
Speaker 2:  There will always be a next trend and a next dance craze and
Speaker 2:  Bobby's gonna go find something else entirely to sing about. He's busy
Speaker 2:  right now actually both with the Weatherman's next album and some other projects
Speaker 2:  he's working on. But if you wanna post something that scares the heck
Speaker 2:  out of everyone who swipes to it in their feed, you're just not beaten. This
Speaker 2:  one don, don't think it's going anywhere.
Speaker 6:  Yo
Speaker 6:  all hands.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break but when we come back we're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  the life and death of streaming services in 2024. We'll be
Speaker 6:  Right back.
Speaker 6:  Fox Creative.
Speaker 19:  This is advertiser content from Zelle.
Speaker 20:  The recruiter said all I needed to do was send $500 to
Speaker 20:  cover mandatory safety training and the job was mine.
Speaker 19:  In a world where financial crimes are more and more sophisticated,
Speaker 19:  there's a team that's got your back
Speaker 18:  Yha
Speaker 19:  Come in safe squad. We got a ten three.
Speaker 18:  Copy that. Dispatch, we are on it. Hop in Skip.
Speaker 18:  We got a phony recruiter
Speaker 19:  Safe squad. The crime drama everyone is talking about.
Speaker 21:  I know it's only my first day but that sounds like a pretty cut and dry
Speaker 21:  job. Scam
Speaker 18:  Strap in rookie these days criminals can even make it look like it's
Speaker 18:  your bank call. But that's where we come in. My what?
Speaker 22:  It's my savings account. Compromised.
Speaker 22:  No, I won't hold.
Speaker 22:  No I didn't authorize a $12,000 withdrawal. That's my life savings.
Speaker 21:  Why don't you come with me? I'll show you how to report to the FTC. What
Speaker 21:  payment platform did you use? Let's contact them too.
Speaker 19:  Don't miss the TV event of the season. Safe Squad.
Speaker 21:  Hey Ace.
Speaker 18:  Yeah
Speaker 21:  Kid, you are right. That was one hell of a first day.
Speaker 19:  Learn how you can spot the size of a scam so you don't have to call the
Speaker 19:  safe squad by visiting
Speaker 19:  www.vox.com/safe squad hq.
Speaker 18:  Remember, never send money online to people You don't
Speaker 18:  already know and trust.
Speaker 3:  Hi, we're visible ringing in 2024 with a two years resolution to help you
Speaker 3:  save on wireless. Get one line with unlimited 5G data on Verizon's network.
Speaker 3:  Just $20 a month for 24 whole months with no annual contracts. That's 20
Speaker 3:  for 24 in 2024. Yep. We're pretty proud of that.
Speaker 3:  Your gym goals, you're on your own. A two years resolution to save on wireless
Speaker 3:  we've got you Switch and save@visible.com. Use code visible 24 Hurry
Speaker 3:  ends January 31st. New members only promotional rate with service on the
Speaker 3:  visible plan for additional terms and network management practices. See visible.com.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back last year was a huge and messy one for the
Speaker 2:  streaming industry. There were strikes, there were huge mergers, there was
Speaker 2:  a lot of CEO bickering, there were layoffs, everybody was selling
Speaker 2:  everything to everybody and it just all got very complicated and it just
Speaker 2:  seems like this whole industry is trying to figure out what it is
Speaker 2:  and I think 2024 is going to be a lot more of the same. So to
Speaker 2:  preview all of it with me, I brought in Alex, Cranz, Who knows all this stuff
Speaker 2:  and also holds the title of I think the world's last Paramount plus
Speaker 2:  subscriber. Hi Alex.
Speaker 23:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so here's what we're gonna do. Okay, we're gonna talk about streaming.
Speaker 2:  We talk about streaming a lot. I feel like we need more ways to be
Speaker 2:  loudly wrong about the streaming industry. So that's what we're gonna do
Speaker 2:  here. Basically I've set this up, I went through and came up with I think
Speaker 2:  it's either eight or nine of like the streaming services people care about
Speaker 2:  and you can quibble whether there should be ones. I don't care. This is the
Speaker 2:  list that came up with Here we are. Which is sort of fun. It's like
Speaker 2:  I went through and just wrote down all the ones I could think of. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  then went and looked at a list and all the other ones were ones that I was
Speaker 2:  like, ah, I don't really care about that. So it worked out well and we're
Speaker 2:  just gonna go through and basically try to figure out if this is going to
Speaker 2:  be a good year or a bad year for that streaming service. So we're just, we're
Speaker 2:  just gonna go up and down. No nuance, no scores out of
Speaker 2:  10. It's just good year, bad year. That's all we're doing. Does that sound
Speaker 2:  good? I love it. Okay, so we should probably start with Netflix just
Speaker 2:  because Netflix is Netflix. Yeah. And my guess is this is going
Speaker 2:  to be one of the least complicated ones for the two of us to figure out here.
Speaker 2:  What's your sense on what's coming from Netflix in 2024
Speaker 23:  As far as new stuff goes? I think the big one is three Body Problem.
Speaker 23:  There's a lot of weirdness there. I'm both excited about it and terrified
Speaker 23:  of it. This is like the second and a half adaptation of this story.
Speaker 23:  It's already been adapted once for TV and it was made into a
Speaker 23:  film by the same people making the Netflix show.
Speaker 2:  It feels like a bad sign that I didn't know that
Speaker 23:  The movie never came out. Oh okay. They shot it in 2015 and were like, nevermind.
Speaker 23:  Oh boy. But we need to make something. So they, that's why the whole Netflix
Speaker 23:  deal happened and like they, they split characters up. Like if you're a
Speaker 23:  big loyalist and love the books, there's a lot of confusion going on, but
Speaker 23:  I feel like, like you've got that but then you've got returning stuff like
Speaker 23:  Bridgeton, which I personally am very excited about Bridgeton. I don't know
Speaker 23:  how much of our audience at The Vergecast is, but I'm pumped for it.
Speaker 23:  And it's got the, like the chick from Dairy Girls. Like that is her big
Speaker 23:  moment. It's gonna be great. Love her. There's newer stuff like the the
Speaker 23:  new Michelle Yo show that's on tv. A lot of the reality
Speaker 23:  shows are returning. We're gonna like have this final season of
Speaker 23:  Queer Eye. Oh yeah, that's gonna be just have all of the weird
Speaker 23:  Bobby drama lingering behind it. The drama's probably more
Speaker 23:  interesting than the show itself. Agreed. So I feel like Netflix has got
Speaker 23:  some returning shows that are gonna be really big this year. Stranger Things
Speaker 23:  I don't think is one of 'em. I think that's 2025. Oh I think they're shooting
Speaker 23:  it this year. Okay. And so we're gonna have to wait for Stranger Things,
Speaker 23:  but they've got some other returning shows and this is gonna be the year.
Speaker 23:  Like we find out if, if Netflix is learning anything about how to program
Speaker 23:  their channel and not just throw everything at the wall and see what, see
Speaker 23:  what sticks.
Speaker 2:  But it also seems like don don't know I just, I keep thinking about these
Speaker 2:  like award shows where the guys from Suits come up to present
Speaker 2:  awards and everybody's like, oh my God, suits is my favorite show. And it's
Speaker 2:  like Suits is like an old show. Yeah, this is not a new thing but it had
Speaker 2:  this new life on Netflix. To me it feels like Netflix is like the most slam
Speaker 2:  dunk winner of 2024. Unless it does something
Speaker 2:  monumentally stupid. It's like the password thing seems
Speaker 2:  to be working, they can just license shows from everybody now because they're
Speaker 2:  the only ones with money. It just seems like it's gonna work.
Speaker 23:  I'm hesitant to call it the winner. Okay. Because I think this is gonna
Speaker 23:  be the year where we start to see a lot of its strategy like
Speaker 23:  solidify and we start to see if audiences actually like that strategy because
Speaker 23:  they did a lot of, they made a lot of moves last year and this year they
Speaker 23:  kind of like they, they have a very different programming slate than they've
Speaker 23:  had from years past. And this is the year where we see if that programming
Speaker 23:  slate works. 'cause it's a lot of reality tv which is
Speaker 23:  doing well for Max and has done really well for Netflix. And then it's a
Speaker 23:  lot of like these prestige shows like Three Body Problem. And I could very
Speaker 23:  easily see three Body Problem like Cratering doing
Speaker 23:  really, really badly. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's an interesting point I think I was going through. So Variety did this
Speaker 2:  list of like the shows people are most excited about this year and Netflix
Speaker 2:  had more of of them than any other service, which is not really surprising
Speaker 2:  but you're right. I hadn't really thought about it until you said it, but
Speaker 2:  Netflix is doing like ultra cheap reality stuff and then like ultra
Speaker 2:  expensive prestige culture
Speaker 2:  shaping kinds of shows and then nothing in the middle anymore, which used
Speaker 2:  to be where Netflix lived was in the middle, right? Where they're just like,
Speaker 2:  here's a hundred shows. Do you like any of them? And they're not doing that
Speaker 2:  at all anymore.
Speaker 23:  They're not doing it. They're, they're relying on suits, they're relying
Speaker 23:  on,
Speaker 2:  They think they can buy those shows now. Yeah,
Speaker 23:  They can buy those shows and I'll be curious to see if that actually works.
Speaker 23:  I would say they're not the winner as much as like the most consistent probably
Speaker 23:  like, like I think they're gonna do well they're not gonna bomb where we're
Speaker 23:  all being like, oh man, Netflix really screwed the pooch this year. But
Speaker 23:  they're not gonna be like, but we're not gonna be like, man Netflix had
Speaker 23:  episode for episode hour for hour. The best streaming service out
Speaker 23:  there. I don't think that's true.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But we're still thumbs up on Netflix for 2024. Thumbs
Speaker 23:  Up, thumbs up.
Speaker 2:  All right, I like it. Next one. Disney plus this one I think might be the
Speaker 2:  most complicated.
Speaker 23:  I'm gonna be horrible person to say thumbs down.
Speaker 2:  Oh maybe not complicated. I'm also thumbs down on Disney plus. I think this
Speaker 2:  might be a terrible year for Disney plus.
Speaker 23:  Yeah, like Echo just came out, they released all five episodes at once.
Speaker 23:  It was a great show. I really enjoyed it. Like Best Time I've had it Marvel
Speaker 23:  in a while because they didn't have to care about the rest of the Marvel
Speaker 23:  universe to enjoy it. And then they've got Agatha,
Speaker 23:  which is like a spinoff of
Speaker 2:  Wand Visions, right? Yeah,
Speaker 23:  Right. It was a spinoff of Wand Visions that's coming way at the end of
Speaker 23:  the year. And then they've got a Star Wars show. I think they've only got
Speaker 23:  one Star Wars show this year, which is the acolyte, which is set
Speaker 23:  before all the Star Wars stuff. We know. It's basically like we're just
Speaker 23:  gonna tell a cool story about Jedi and that could be really, really cool.
Speaker 23:  But there is a lot of fatigue with dis Disney. Yeah. And it is
Speaker 23:  holding fast and they've held a bunch of shows. There's a bunch of shows
Speaker 23:  like Ironheart that are just getting punted to 2025 'cause they realized
Speaker 23:  they were making bad TV. Daredevil's another one. It was supposed to I think
Speaker 23:  come out this year got punted to 2025. So Disney
Speaker 23:  is not in a great place. But there's big
Speaker 23:  asterisks because Hulu, which we're also gonna talk about Yep. Is
Speaker 23:  coming into like gonna be a great year for Hulu and at some point
Speaker 23:  it's probably gonna merge with Disney and all of that content will be in
Speaker 23:  one place. So it's like Disney plus bad year
Speaker 23:  asterisk until Hulu gets merged into it.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's fair. So let's just jump to Hulu 'cause I agree on Disney plus.
Speaker 2:  I think going through the list of stuff people are excited about Disney Plus
Speaker 2:  was kind of alarmingly low and and you're right it's, it's all Marvel and
Speaker 2:  it's all Star Wars and then it's like random cool documentaries
Speaker 2:  that Disney Plus has more of than people think but is still not how you
Speaker 2:  get a thumbs up on this podcast
Speaker 23:  They're doing under the National Geographic brand. They're doing like an
Speaker 23:  adaptation of the story of Martin Luther King and Right. And Malcolm
Speaker 23:  X and Cool cast in that. That could be really, really cool. The National
Speaker 23:  Geographic shows are neat, but they're also not winning awards,
Speaker 23:  not starting conversations.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You don't win the streaming award. The streaming awards with that,
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry to say sorry, but to your point, the The asterisk is a big one
Speaker 2:  because the next one on my list is Hulu. Yeah. Which is kind of a funny thing.
Speaker 2:  Hulu is now like the most reliable dumping
Speaker 2:  ground for stuff on linear television. And it seems like that's
Speaker 2:  just where a lot of that stuff lives. Now we're gonna get to Peacock in a
Speaker 2:  minute, but other than the stuff that's on Peacock, Hulu is just gobbling
Speaker 2:  up these shows on broadcast television and on FX and on
Speaker 2:  some of these other channels, the people really like Hulu is eventually going
Speaker 2:  to be Disney Plus. Do we think that's this year? Like does Hulu just get
Speaker 2:  wiped off the board Because it's not even gonna be a thing at the end of
Speaker 2:  2024.
Speaker 23:  I see it happening unless there's like weird contract stuff because it's
Speaker 23:  like the exclusive streamer for I believe A, B, C and fx.
Speaker 23:  'cause they're both owned by Disney So. I could see contractual stuff
Speaker 23:  meaning it, it happens another year. But I think it's probably gonna happen
Speaker 23:  this year. And the stuff is really good. Like we've got a new season of
Speaker 23:  Feud, which is just gonna be a whole bunch of women in their fifties. Somethings
Speaker 23:  being absolutely horrible to this guy playing Truman Capote and Perfect.
Speaker 23:  I personally like I've wanted nothing more than Calista flock art and
Speaker 23:  Dimmi Moore like being mean to someone on TV together while we're
Speaker 23:  like seventies couture. That sounds great to me personally. But
Speaker 23:  you've got old stuff like Grey's Anatomy, which is coming into season
Speaker 23:  2020. I think it's going into season 20 or season
Speaker 23:  19. Yes. Wild. Which is insane.
Speaker 2:  I gave up after season two, but I'm, I'm told people still watch Grey's Anatomy
Speaker 2:  for couple
Speaker 23:  Time. Oh you gotta watch like season six had a really good episode.
Speaker 23:  Just, you just gotta watch that one episode from that one season. You're
Speaker 23:  fine, you're fine. You'll be all caught up.
Speaker 2:  All right, cool. I'm into it and
Speaker 23:  It's still an old standby. It's still, you're seeing a lot of young people
Speaker 23:  watch it. Like I'm seeing it increasingly on my TikTok and like teens.
Speaker 23:  Oh. Ing watching it and getting into it. 'cause they grew up kind of it
Speaker 23:  with it in the background and now they wanna pay attention and they're like,
Speaker 23:  oh damn mom, watch this. And like I was five was I allowed to watch this?
Speaker 23:  Shouldn't have been.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Definitely not. No.
Speaker 23:  And then you've got like 9 1 1, which is another of those kind of shows
Speaker 23:  where like I can just put that on and do my laundry and have a good time.
Speaker 23:  And that's personally the kind of stuff I want. Yeah. I feel like there's
Speaker 23:  a bunch of stuff coming to Hulu this year that's gonna be really, really
Speaker 23:  good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think that's right. Hulu doesn't seem to have the one kind
Speaker 2:  of giant thing everybody is hoping for. Like maybe season two of Feud
Speaker 2:  is that that kind of penetrates into this is the show everybody is
Speaker 2:  talking about, but that's never really been Hulu's thing. Right. Hulu's thing
Speaker 2:  is is it's the place you go to watch the shows. You
Speaker 2:  kind of like Yeah. Guiltily and don't really tell anybody about like that's,
Speaker 2:  that's Hulu's thing and it's a very good thing and
Speaker 23:  It is. And it's benefiting from the fact that it's got all of the FX content
Speaker 23:  and FX is still like making TV in a way that a lot of
Speaker 23:  other of those like basic cable channels stopped doing. Yeah. FX is still
Speaker 23:  doing it. Which is why you're getting Feuded. Which is why you're getting
Speaker 23:  Shogun, which is a remake of a Richard Chamberlain
Speaker 23:  like miniseries from the eighties Okay. That they're doing. And I keep
Speaker 23:  seeing it everywhere and I like the cast in it. So I'm like, all right,
Speaker 23:  I'll watch this. even that the original was boring as hell, but like
Speaker 23:  FX is really thoughtful about programming and I think we're gonna see that
Speaker 23:  in Hulu and and they're gonna benefit from that in a way that Netflix just
Speaker 23:  doesn't have that, those chops.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean I, funny enough, I think Hulu is probably a thumbs up for this
Speaker 2:  year and I think the extent to which it is a thumbs up, I think
Speaker 2:  you're right, will probably determine whether Disney Plus is a thumbs up
Speaker 2:  or not. Like yeah, Hulu feels very important to Disney this year because
Speaker 2:  Disney otherwise is in kind of a weird place where it's so reliant
Speaker 2:  on just a couple of things like we've been talking about. But Hulu is the
Speaker 2:  one where they're just like, we just have this sort of giant slate of cool
Speaker 2:  stuff that a lot of people like and Disney is like, dear God we need that.
Speaker 2:  Because if we keep making Marvel stuff people will leave.
Speaker 23:  Yes. I mean I'll watch Marvel too, but I wanna mix it up. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent. Alright, so we're thumbs up for Hulu but it is, I would
Speaker 2:  say possible that we will not get to give Hulu a score at the end of the
Speaker 2:  year because it will just be part of Disney plus.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. Asterisk. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Alright, next up Max, which to me Max
Speaker 2:  is the most split between, there's a content story
Speaker 2:  and there's a corporate story and they are complete opposites of each other,
Speaker 2:  which has made me very torn on how to rule on this company this year.
Speaker 2:  What do you think?
Speaker 23:  The content story is good, right? Yeah. Like the content story is good.
Speaker 23:  You've got all of this stuff. I personally don't watch a lot of reality
Speaker 23:  tv but everybody knows David loves it. I do
Speaker 2:  Just HGTV forever. I'm fine with it. There's a new kid's baking championship
Speaker 2:  on Max right now. It's very exciting. Yeah,
Speaker 23:  My sister-in-Law loves the Naked Dating Show. Like oh yeah, we had to watch
Speaker 23:  so much of it at Christmas. But
Speaker 2:  Cool. Family friendly show it seems like. Yeah,
Speaker 23:  It's great. It's great. I love that. Watching that with the mom but real
Speaker 23:  like they've got good stuff Mac Max the content wise, they've got something
Speaker 23:  that's hitting every one of those markets, right? It's hitting the people
Speaker 23:  who just wanna go and you know, you can watch friends and and do your laundry,
Speaker 23:  you can watch reality TV shows and you've got your big prestige stuff
Speaker 23:  and it's got a lot of prestige stuff coming this year. A new season of House
Speaker 23:  of the Dragons, I think the Last of Us isn't until 2025. I think that's
Speaker 23:  another one. Oh yeah, they're just casting it now. So I think that's getting
Speaker 23:  punted but But there's a bunch of stuff that's gonna be coming from by benefit
Speaker 23:  of having HBO. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  There's like a dune show coming this year.
Speaker 23:  That's right. There's
Speaker 2:  A true detective already started. Have you watched the First of the New True
Speaker 2:  Detectives?
Speaker 23:  True Detective is one of my favorite shows of the year so far. Like I've
Speaker 23:  watched all of it. You ha I think I'm only allowed to say it's really good.
Speaker 23:  I really like it. I think people are gonna really like it. It's, it's a
Speaker 23:  fun time.
Speaker 2:  I have not watched it yet, but I promise I will catch up by the time we do
Speaker 2:  this again so we can talk about
Speaker 23:  It. Yeah, you've just got the rest of the year. Exactly. It'll be fun. But
Speaker 23:  yeah, I, I think, I think they've got really, really good taunt there. I
Speaker 23:  think they're still struggling with their, their user interface and I think
Speaker 23:  honestly for me that's gonna be the big story of the year is if people get
Speaker 23:  their user interfaces like in a place that's usable consistently,
Speaker 23:  they're one of the worst at it. Yes. Right now they're slowly improving,
Speaker 23:  but we'll see. They're, they're doing a lot more sports this year. I know.
Speaker 23:  And we'll curious to see how that goes for them. You know, the sports side
Speaker 23:  better than I do. Well they've been
Speaker 2:  Kind of delaying this in a weird way. Like Bleacher Report is part of
Speaker 2:  Max, it's its own, you know, tab in the app, which makes you think it's a
Speaker 2:  big deal. It's right there on the road with HBO and it was supposed to be
Speaker 2:  kind of an add-on with a lot of stuff and they've kind of delayed that and
Speaker 2:  delayed it and it's not super clear what that's gonna look like yet
Speaker 2:  or whether it's gonna really work, but obviously Warner Brothers Discovery
Speaker 2:  has rights to lots of NBA games and lots of other sports. So it,
Speaker 2:  it'll, I would assume it'll start to happen 'cause that is the plan. But,
Speaker 2:  and this is the corporate story, Warner Brothers Discovery, the company that
Speaker 2:  owns Max seems to be less and less invested in the idea
Speaker 2:  of Max as like the future of the company. David dlo has been
Speaker 2:  talking about this all the time. They're back to, they're big on theaters,
Speaker 2:  they're back to selling content to other streamers. Like I'm not confident
Speaker 2:  that this company caress a lot about Max anymore.
Speaker 23:  The other side of the content story is we're seeing a lot of stuff that's
Speaker 23:  gonna come that was made for hbo. Yeah. Not for Max. There's only about
Speaker 23:  like, there's only a couple of shows that are exclusively Max that are still
Speaker 23:  around Harley Quinn hacks and I think the Secret
Speaker 23:  Sex Lives of College Girls, right. That show is, is if not ending
Speaker 23:  is gonna be in a bad place, it's Big Star Renee Rap is leaving Hacks,
Speaker 23:  this is its third season and I think it's pretty probably done. Harley
Speaker 23:  Quinn is probably gonna be the only one of those like Max Originals that
Speaker 23:  survives a very long time. It's doing well. Everybody likes it critically
Speaker 23:  acclaimed and it's gonna just keep going. You
Speaker 2:  Can always gritty reboot Batman. That's what we've always learned, right.
Speaker 2:  Nitty gritty reboot of a Batman show is gonna do just fine. You're gonna
Speaker 2:  be all right. Yeah.
Speaker 23:  Just redo it and you're good to go. But as far as like its other big stuff.
Speaker 23:  All the other programming is really dependent on, on its, its linear channels.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. And and and pulling it from there. So like the regime and House of
Speaker 23:  the Dragons, those are all HBO first shows. So
Speaker 23:  I'm curious to see what happens with Max don. Don't think it goes away entirely.
Speaker 23:  I think it sticks around, but I think like that moment we had where Max
Speaker 23:  was the best streaming service, I think that's done.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, it's gonna be so interesting to see if we get to the end of this
Speaker 2:  year, Warner Brothers Discovery still has a ton of debt, is still kind of
Speaker 2:  hemorrhaging money trying to make all of this work. And it's gonna get
Speaker 2:  to a point where either David Zaslav and the rest of the executives there
Speaker 2:  are gonna have to just like hold their nose and say, we believe Max is the
Speaker 2:  future we are all in. Even if it gets us fired and runs outta of business.
Speaker 2:  Or they're gonna say, you know, nevermind, let's have this be a nice thing
Speaker 2:  on the side, but not worry too much about it.
Speaker 2:  And we're gonna go back to mostly being a place that makes things and sells
Speaker 2:  it to other people. And if you do that, yeah, you're not gonna beat Netflix.
Speaker 2:  It's just, I just don't see it happening. Like I'm a very light thumbs down
Speaker 2:  on Max for that reason because I just don't believe it's, they, they have
Speaker 2:  not burned the boats on streaming, you know what I mean? Well
Speaker 23:  They put all their films, all their films are on Netflix now. Right, right.
Speaker 23:  Like that's who they sold all their films to. And that's
Speaker 2:  A fine and good thing and more companies should do that, but that's not
Speaker 2:  how you make Max win.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. Max, I think I'm a little thumbs up. Okay. Just because
Speaker 23:  it does have so much content and it is pro it's gonna stick around,
Speaker 23:  but I see like I can see 2025 being thumbs down on it. Okay. But
Speaker 23:  2024 I'm still like shaky thumbs up. Alright,
Speaker 2:  That's good. This is the, we we disagree. This is good. Yeah. And next up,
Speaker 2:  this is, I just switched the order around because this actually matters a
Speaker 2:  lot both to its own story and to the Max story is Paramount Plus,
Speaker 2:  which there are rumors flying that Paramount plus
Speaker 2:  may someday not be a thing and be a part of Max. There's rumors that
Speaker 2:  Warner Brothers Discovery or someone else is very interested in buying
Speaker 2:  Paramount Global or National Amusements. The corporate intrigue is
Speaker 2:  confusing and strange, but none of it seems to end in Paramount
Speaker 2:  plus being a going concern for much longer.
Speaker 23:  See I am probably the most bullish on Paramount plus
Speaker 2:  I a hundred percent believe that you may be the only person left. I said
Speaker 2:  in the intro, you may be the only person left on Paramount Plus at the end
Speaker 2:  of this.
Speaker 23:  I think that of all of the big streaming companies, it is the most
Speaker 23:  thoughtful. It's been doing it as long as anybody. Right. Like it originally
Speaker 23:  started as CBS all Access, it was doing it before Max. And, and a lot of
Speaker 23:  these other companies thought about doing this, this strategy and it's been
Speaker 23:  a slow and steady like winner. And they, they already knew the advertising
Speaker 23:  business. They were, they were serving ads before anybody else and and doing
Speaker 23:  well with it. They're, they're doing sports before anybody else and doing
Speaker 23:  well with it. They were live streaming before. Like Max still
Speaker 23:  struggles with live streaming and Paramount Plus has been doing it for a
Speaker 23:  while. Tech Stack wise, they're in a really good position content wise.
Speaker 23:  They have like solid content that's that's makes them money. Right. You've
Speaker 23:  got the Star Trek stuff that nobody talks about, but you've got Star Trek.
Speaker 2:  But people do seem to watch, I will say I have heard, I have heard enough
Speaker 2:  people say I love the Star Trek shows. Why does nobody talk about it? That
Speaker 2:  it has kind of entered the, actually people do talk about it category, it's
Speaker 2:  kind of a little bit of a thing.
Speaker 23:  You've got all the Taylor Sheridan stuff that's also happening. Sure. You've
Speaker 23:  got, this is probably just for me and the three other people that have been
Speaker 23:  subscribing to Paramount Plus since it was CVS All Access, but Elspeth,
Speaker 23:  which is gonna be the second spinoff of The Good Wife. Oh.
Speaker 23:  So we've got that coming A new season of Evil, which is from the same like
Speaker 23:  team
Speaker 2:  I will say Evil is great. I make a lot of fun of Paramount Plus Evil is Great.
Speaker 23:  Legits such a good show.
Speaker 2:  It's so weird in the best possible way.
Speaker 23:  And then I assume there's another NCIS just because every
Speaker 23:  year there's another NCIS Yeah. And people watch that. I don't
Speaker 23:  watch it. So many people watch it though. So I like I
Speaker 23:  I am kind of bullish on it because they didn't stop yet.
Speaker 23:  So why would they suddenly stop now just to be acquired? Like this is a
Speaker 23:  company that's owned by primarily a single person. It's got one big
Speaker 23:  stockholder and it's been owned by this family for a fairly decent amount
Speaker 23:  of time. And yeah, she might wanna say, okay, I'm gonna check out, but I
Speaker 23:  can't see her just wanting to go and be part of like the Max
Speaker 23:  amalgamation. Right. Like, like that's fair. And a lot of that stuff we
Speaker 23:  heard where Warner Brothers Discovery was thinking about buying it and kicking
Speaker 23:  the tires that has since disappeared. We've heard quiet there could still
Speaker 23:  happen. I'm not gonna say it's not gonna happen. I'll just be really, really
Speaker 23:  surprised. But I think it's just kinda like these are the, it's still
Speaker 23:  the whole same crew that had the number one network on
Speaker 23:  television for like a bajillion years. Yeah. They know how to do that
Speaker 23:  once. And I think they're starting to figure streaming out better. And I
Speaker 23:  don't think they're ever gonna be Netflix, but I think they're gonna still
Speaker 23:  persist. I could see them being very comfortable with being in fourth place
Speaker 23:  if they can get there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, IIII totally buy that logic. I'm still thumbs down on
Speaker 2:  Paramount Plus I think it's fair as a bundle of content, I think
Speaker 2:  Paramount Plus is gonna make for a giant thumbs up on Peacock
Speaker 2:  or HB or Max or wherever it ends up. I just don't
Speaker 2:  think this company is going to stay interested in
Speaker 2:  having its own streaming service. Like I just don't know what fourth place
Speaker 2:  gets you at this point anymore. No,
Speaker 23:  It, I that's, that's the thing is that're comfortable with it because it
Speaker 23:  gets them monthly. Like it just gets them additional revenue. Well
Speaker 2:  Sure it makes Sherry Redstone rich, which is something that's that's fair.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. Like, like they're still making money off of it. They weren't as kind
Speaker 23:  of a victim of zero interest rates as a lot of other people. A lot of people
Speaker 23:  put a lot of money into that. Yeah. And they certainly did too. There was
Speaker 23:  the, the Grease prequel, which me and one other person watched and we
Speaker 23:  had a great time. But that was a dumb move to ever make that show.
Speaker 23:  Correct. Why did you do that? And they, they have fewer
Speaker 23:  of those misses. Yeah. Like they, they generally are much more
Speaker 23:  bullish on the shows they do have and those shows and they're much more
Speaker 23:  thoughtful about how they spend money on stuff. They're not throwing money
Speaker 23:  around.
Speaker 2:  That is true Paramount. Plus there's a good case to be made and you're
Speaker 2:  making me rethink my thumbs down that Paramount Plus is like the cockroach
Speaker 2:  of the streaming industry. It's like it's never gonna win, but it's also
Speaker 2:  never gonna die. Yes. They're not doing the big swings that
Speaker 2:  make you Netflix, but they're also not doing the dumb things that kill your
Speaker 2:  streaming service. So. I think that, I think that's fair. I still think they're
Speaker 2:  more likely to get bought this year than not. So I'm sticking with my thumbs
Speaker 2:  down. But you, you make a convincing case and I, I sort of hope I'm wrong
Speaker 2:  for your sake.
Speaker 23:  See, I would've, until last week, I would've said, it's not gonna be them.
Speaker 23:  It's gonna be Peacock and then Peacock. If you wanna move on to
Speaker 23:  Peacock, let's do it. Peacock just absolutely crushed it with sports. Right?
Speaker 23:  Like they kept one of the biggest streaming moments ever in the history
Speaker 23:  of the world. And so it's like, oh damn.
Speaker 2:  And it worked. They had like, what was it, 23 million people watched
Speaker 2:  the playoff game on, on Peacock
Speaker 23:  Still less than who watched Mash season finale. But,
Speaker 2:  But still the fact that that many people watched it and it worked and people
Speaker 2:  were happy. It's like that's a big win for streaming in general, I think.
Speaker 23:  And can Peacock parlay that into long-term success
Speaker 23:  is anybody's guess? Agreed. I would generally say no
Speaker 23:  because otherwise when you think about their, their, their scripted programming,
Speaker 23:  it's not very good when you think about their scripted
Speaker 23:  programming that's not sports. It's not very good. It's all, first of
Speaker 2:  All, that's, that is Twisted Metal erasure and I will not stand for it. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  Twisted Metal is the best terrible show I watched in 2023.
Speaker 23:  More people watch that than Paramount Plus. Yeah.
Speaker 23:  But they've got sports going for them. Yeah. And maybe, maybe that's,
Speaker 23:  that has been enough for many channels, including ESPN for pretty years.
Speaker 23:  So I don't wanna knock it for that, but I, I was kind of blown away by that
Speaker 23:  and I'm still processing the fact that Peacock had a win because I I was
Speaker 23:  ready. It was, it was at, it was at a 90 on my go. 90. I was like,
Speaker 23:  the fact that it isn't getting snapped up by Max right now shocked me
Speaker 23:  and I still think it could happen. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It it, I mean there there is an interesting thing of, you have,
Speaker 2:  you have Max, you have Paramount Plus and you have Peacock and
Speaker 2:  I would be absolutely shocked if all three of those are three
Speaker 2:  separate companies at the end of 2024. Yeah. Who
Speaker 2:  buys like, it's there, there have been lots of rumors that Comcast, which
Speaker 2:  owns NBC Universal and I guess disclosure is a n BBC Universal is a, an
Speaker 2:  investor in Vox Media. We make a Netflix show. It's pretty good. Alex
Speaker 2:  loves Paramount Plus there's all of our
Speaker 23:  Displays I subscribed to Paramount Plus
Speaker 2:  There's been some rumors that Comcast is interested in buying Paramount Plus,
Speaker 2:  which I think is directly to solve what you're talking about, which is that
Speaker 2:  Peacock has rights to really cool things and just doesn't
Speaker 2:  seem to be able to make a show that breaks through to save its life. Like
Speaker 2:  Poker Face was the closest it got, but when was the last time you talked
Speaker 2:  about Poker Face? You know what I mean? It
Speaker 23:  Went on an Emmy.
Speaker 2:  It did. And it's a great show. People should watch it. It's, but it's Peacock
Speaker 2:  has not broken through yet. Yeah, it has, it has lots of like singles and
Speaker 2:  doubles, but it has not had sort of the giant wind that you need.
Speaker 23:  Paramount Plus had Emmys like five years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. Like I'm sure CBS All Access was out here winning awards. Like that's
Speaker 2:  not how you get here.
Speaker 23:  The good Fight baby. The good fight.
Speaker 2:  But yeah. And then so there's been rumors that, you know, Warner Brothers
Speaker 2:  Discovery, which owns Max might be in acquisition mode. Paramount Plus might
Speaker 2:  be selling to everybody. So I, think there's some mix of
Speaker 2:  stuff there that just seems like it's gonna get
Speaker 2:  sorted out over the next 12 months. Yeah, but I'm gonna, I'm gonna thumbs
Speaker 2:  up on Peacock just because personally it's very important to me as the place
Speaker 2:  where I watch the Office and Parks and Recreation and Brooklyn Nine nine,
Speaker 2:  but also because Comcast just seems to have gone
Speaker 2:  all in on this. Like in the way that I don't see Warner's, Warner Brothers
Speaker 2:  Discovery saying we need streaming to work. Comcast is saying we
Speaker 2:  need streaming to work. Yeah. And it might kill it in the long run, but I
Speaker 2:  don't think it kills it this year. I think Comcast is more likely to be a
Speaker 2:  buyer than a seller this year, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 23:  Yeah, that's, that's right. Comcast is facing an existential crisis
Speaker 23:  because everybody's stopping. And, and the same thing with, with Paramount,
Speaker 23:  a lot of these people who are highly dependent on broadcast TV and basic
Speaker 23:  cable are facing an existential crisis of what do we do next? We need a
Speaker 23:  good streaming service. Yep. And so they're gonna be very, very motivated
Speaker 23:  in a way that Max and Netflix and some of these other, like the tech
Speaker 23:  focused, more tech oriented streaming services don't have to be.
Speaker 2:  Totally All right, so Peacock thumbs up or thumbs down?
Speaker 23:  Ugh, thumbs up. But it's like, I'm shocked to
Speaker 23:  do that.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 23:  It's all, it's all the sports. It's all the sports. It's, it's
Speaker 2:  A begrudging. Thumbs up for Peacock. Yeah, I like it. All right. Two more
Speaker 2:  to go Apple TV plus
Speaker 23:  Ooh. Thumbs up. But that's just because I've been watching a bunch of the
Speaker 23:  shows that are coming. Palm Royale incredible. I don't know what all I'm
Speaker 23:  allowed to say about that. It's great. Awesome. Yeah, if you like Feud,
Speaker 23:  you'll probably have a great time with it. Manhunt, which is about the
Speaker 23:  hunt for John Wilkes Booth after the assassination of
Speaker 23:  Lincoln is certainly a show. And, and it's
Speaker 23:  coming and people are going, some people are going to watch it, some people
Speaker 23:  are not. It's still got stuff like for all Mankind just finished, wrapped
Speaker 23:  its fourth season, the fifth season is coming. Foundation is still doing
Speaker 23:  really strong for them. They continue to be like the best place to watch
Speaker 23:  science fiction. Another season of Severance should be coming in 2024. It's,
Speaker 23:  it's shooting as we speak. So I'm, I'm really bullish on
Speaker 23:  it. It exists entirely at like the permission of Tim
Speaker 23:  Cook. Yeah. I think it is one of those things where if Tim Cook leaves and
Speaker 23:  we get another CEO in and he doesn't care or she doesn't care as
Speaker 23:  strongly about science fiction and weird, like catty shows,
Speaker 23:  it could be in dire straits, but for now it's, it's doing really strongly.
Speaker 23:  It's got some of the best programming out there. I
Speaker 2:  Agree. I I actually think other than Netflix, apple TV plus would be my bet
Speaker 2:  to be kind of the big winner of the streaming wars of 2024. Yeah. Apple has
Speaker 2:  all the money in the universe. Its hit rate is, I would say the best of
Speaker 2:  anyone in the streaming game right now. It's gotten
Speaker 23:  Really good. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So it's gotten to the point where like, I will watch the first episode of
Speaker 2:  almost anything that comes out on Apple TV plus, just because the odds of
Speaker 2:  it being good seem to be higher than almost any other service. So I think
Speaker 2:  you're right that I would, it, it wouldn't be shocking if all of a sudden
Speaker 2:  they just canceled the whole thing because it's sort of immaterial to Apple.
Speaker 2:  But at the same time, apple is relying on Apple TV plus to sell Vision
Speaker 2:  Pros and give you stuff to do in your Vision Pro. It's a way to sell iPhones.
Speaker 2:  It's a way to get people into the service business. Like, I, I just don't,
Speaker 2:  I don't see that being a problem. So, I'm, I'm with you. I'm a heart of thumbs
Speaker 2:  up. I believe the, almost exact opposite about the last one on our list,
Speaker 2:  which is Amazon Prime video. This is, I would say my hardest thumbs down
Speaker 2:  of the year really because Amazon is in a place of
Speaker 2:  trying to be more thoughtful about where it
Speaker 2:  invests. It has invested an enormous amount of money in a
Speaker 2:  lot of things that don't work on Prime video. And I think
Speaker 2:  this service is going to look more and more like Amazon sports
Speaker 2:  streaming and less and less like Netflix over time. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think this is not going to be a good year for Prime video.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. They haven't had, like Amazon Prime History have not had a lot of
Speaker 23:  hits. You've had, you have the voice, you have reacher, which I just started
Speaker 23:  watching yesterday. It's fine. You've got Jack Ryan, you've got a lot of
Speaker 23:  like manly shows,
Speaker 2:  Football dudes. Like that's the dynamic here, right?
Speaker 23:  And then you got Wheel of Time, which I'm told I really need to watch season
Speaker 23:  two. It's a delight, but I'm being told that I haven't felt the urge to
Speaker 23:  watch it. Right?
Speaker 2:  Same with Lord of the Rings. The rings of power, like Lord
Speaker 23:  Of the Rings is an absolute boondoggle, the most expensive TV show ever
Speaker 23:  made. And how many people watched it and how many people Dr. It certainly
Speaker 23:  isn't driving subscriptions. Like, and you
Speaker 2:  Know what's wild is the second biggest boondoggle I can think of is probably
Speaker 2:  Citadel the other. Yes. Massively high budget flop on Prime video.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 23:  They have spent money stupidly, they are probably the after
Speaker 23:  Netflix, the most guilty of, of embracing 0%
Speaker 23:  interest rates to make garbage. Yes. They've got a leadership crisis as
Speaker 23:  far as the streaming service goes. They can print money though. That's,
Speaker 23:  that's the one thing they can do because they just, they, they're forcing
Speaker 23:  ads on every single subscriber, which means they're gonna be able to print
Speaker 23:  money anytime you, you decide to say, check out that, read your show because
Speaker 23:  everybody keeps talking about the large man, you're gonna be stuck watching,
Speaker 23:  like you're going to make them money. So it is definitely one of those
Speaker 23:  things where I think it is going to rapidly become something that
Speaker 23:  Amazon forgets they own.
Speaker 2:  Right.
Speaker 23:  And the sports will do well and those, those couple shows that rise to
Speaker 23:  the top will do well and that's all we're gonna see. They, they, they're
Speaker 23:  really good at buying movies that are already out in the marketplace. They've
Speaker 23:  gotten really smart about that. Saltburn is an example of that. So I suspect.
Speaker 23:  We're gonna see more of that and then just going and buying other people's
Speaker 23:  stuff and putting it on rather than trying to program it themselves, which
Speaker 23:  is probably for the best because they haven't been very good at programming
Speaker 23:  it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Amazon going back to being essentially a, a subscription
Speaker 2:  like movie rental thing. Fine. Right. Like when I rent movies, I rent
Speaker 2:  it mostly through Amazon because it's easy and the application works pretty
Speaker 2:  well and like that's all fine and good, but as a cultural powerhouse
Speaker 2:  streaming service, I just don't see it. And I think if, if I'm an Amazon
Speaker 2:  executive looking for ways to pull back, like,
Speaker 2:  oh, all of that money we spent on these shows that no one likes and watches,
Speaker 2:  maybe that's a good place. Like it's,
Speaker 23:  And and they've they've started doing that, right? Yeah. Like they canceled
Speaker 23:  a ton of stuff last year. They, they renewed stuff and then went back and
Speaker 23:  they canceled it. They they pulled a couple, I believe they pulled some
Speaker 23:  stuff from their services. Well like, like they themselves know
Speaker 23:  that nobody's really watching it and, and they need to just kinda like,
Speaker 23:  that's why they added the ads. It's, it's a win-win for them. Yeah. The
Speaker 23:  few people who are watching, they can make some extra money off of a
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And if you wanna pay three more dollars a month to watch their bad
Speaker 2:  shows to not see ads, Amazon wins again. Yeah. Alright, so just
Speaker 2:  to recap before we wrap up here, we're both thumbs up on
Speaker 2:  Netflix. You can change your mind now. This is your last chance.
Speaker 23:  I'm still tentatively thumbs up on Netflix. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Disney Plus we're two thumbs down with a Hulu sized asterisk.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Hulu. We are two thumbs up with a Disney plus sized asterisk
Speaker 2:  Max. Your thumbs up I'm thumbs down Paramount plus your thumbs up. I'm thumbs
Speaker 2:  down. You're very optimistic about streaming this year. I like this for you.
Speaker 2:  This is
Speaker 23:  Gonna be a fun year for streaming business wise.
Speaker 2:  Well, what's interesting is I, I think the thing that might make me most
Speaker 2:  wrong is that because of the strike last year, there's just going to be a
Speaker 2:  glut of good stuff this year and next year that, so
Speaker 2:  like I think all of my potential doomsday predictions, I might just be
Speaker 2:  a year or two two early on, which is the thing I'm most nervous about, but
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm holding fast to my beliefs here. Peacock, we're both thumbs up.
Speaker 2:  I would say me slightly more aggressively than you. Yes. Mine is just a Michael Scott
Speaker 2:  size thumbs up at all times. Apple TV plus we're both thumbs up
Speaker 2:  and Prime video. It sounds like we're both thumbs down.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. Okay. That's right.
Speaker 2:  All right, I like it. All right. Rapid fire. And then we're gonna get outta
Speaker 2:  here. Give me two other predictions You have anything at all about the streaming
Speaker 2:  world this year that I can hold you against at the end of the year? I
Speaker 23:  Think Hulu is gonna be merged into Disney Plus this year. Yeah.
Speaker 23:  don don't know what the name of that that service is gonna be. Presumably
Speaker 23:  Disney plus, maybe it'll be Star who can say, but I think that's gonna happen
Speaker 23:  this year. Okay. And the other one is
Speaker 23:  we're gonna not be talking about ads as much this year. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay.
Speaker 23:  I think ads is a huge part of this deal and I think you, and I'll probably
Speaker 23:  be talking about it much a lot, but I think the general public is not gonna
Speaker 23:  be thinking about ads on their streaming services this year. It's rolled
Speaker 23:  out, it's happening. Everybody's, everybody's got it. They're all gonna
Speaker 23:  be making a lot of money off of it and they're all gonna start behaving
Speaker 23:  more like broadcast TV in order to make those advertising dollars
Speaker 23:  sing. But I think you and I like the general public is not gonna notice
Speaker 23:  much, much of that this year. We'll notice it in a couple years. I
Speaker 2:  Think that's probably right and that's actually kind of related to my first
Speaker 2:  prediction, which is that the fast, the, the ad supported channels like
Speaker 2:  Tubi and Freebie and Pluto, Pluto and that stuff that's out there now,
Speaker 2:  I think that's gonna have another huge year that's been growing a lot. We've
Speaker 2:  talked about it a bunch, but I think now that ads are gonna be everywhere,
Speaker 2:  you're gonna see advertisers say, oh well we're advertising all over streaming.
Speaker 2:  Let's put even more into some of these fast channels that are growing really
Speaker 2:  fast. And also viewers are going to say, oh well
Speaker 2:  I'm looking at ads everywhere. What difference does it make? I'm gonna go
Speaker 2:  find these other services that are free and don't make me log in. And all
Speaker 2:  of a sudden that ease of user experience, if there's ads anyway,
Speaker 2:  it's, it's a big win. So, I think that stuff is gonna continue to grow. It's
Speaker 2:  a mess right now. Like there's tons of channels and there's actually a lot
Speaker 2:  of good stuff out there, but trying to find it is bad. And So,
Speaker 2:  what I think might happen is one of these big services
Speaker 2:  might as a way to get into the ad business even more, adopt a lot of these
Speaker 2:  fast channels and actually make a good interface out of it. So, I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  hopeful that that's what happens this year and I think it's gonna be big.
Speaker 23:  I think it's gonna be paramount. Plus I'm just saying out that they own
Speaker 23:  Pluto. They've already got a bunch of kind of fast channels already on
Speaker 23:  their service. I can see them being really smart about that in a way
Speaker 23:  everybody else isn't. That's a good take.
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 23:  The guy who founded Pluto is now running Paramount Plus as well. Oh yeah,
Speaker 23:  yeah. He's running both now. So, so like I said, I'm, I'm still very
Speaker 23:  bullish on that one, otherwise I think it would be Max and Max would be
Speaker 23:  dumb not to.
Speaker 2:  Well I'm excited for all of that to become a peacock feature in 2024. It's
Speaker 2:  gonna be sick. And then my other prediction is that someone don
Speaker 2:  don't know who, but someone is going to actually build a universal
Speaker 2:  streaming guide that is useful and good and will probably
Speaker 2:  cost money but will be absolutely worth every penny.
Speaker 2:  don don't know. Maybe it'll be the Apple TV app. Maybe it'll be one of the
Speaker 2:  like just watches are real goods of the world, but like this is such a big
Speaker 2:  problem and as all these companies go to ads, they want you to find their
Speaker 2:  stuff better. So like Netflix now has an actual incentive
Speaker 2:  for me to be finding Netflix shows more easily
Speaker 2:  and So I think somebody is gonna figure out how to put all this stuff together
Speaker 2:  in a way that I can actually find the stuff I wanna watch more easily. That
Speaker 2:  might be a pipe dream, but boy am I hoping that's right.
Speaker 23:  Yeah, I I I love this for you. I think if it happens, it's
Speaker 23:  not happening this year, I think it's gonna take Netflix a little time to
Speaker 23:  realize they need everybody else. So like 25, 26 I
Speaker 23:  can see them finally being like, oh yeah, we should play nice with everybody
Speaker 23:  else. But until then Netflix is gonna be like, nah, screw you guys.
Speaker 23:  We got Stranger Things. It's coming back, don't worry about it.
Speaker 2:  I get 11 months to believe in this before. Yeah, it becomes very obvious
Speaker 2:  how wrong I was. Let me have
Speaker 23:  This, I I'm everybody root for David, I'm rooting for you. I want this so
Speaker 23:  I'm rooting for
Speaker 2:  You. I appreciate that, I appreciate that. Alright, we gotta take a break
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna do a Hotline question. Actually
Speaker 2:  Alex, will you stick around for a minute? This Hotline question is kind of
Speaker 2:  exactly for you.
Speaker 23:  I love it. Let's do it.
Speaker 2:  All right, we'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Can a vehicle be two things at once, remarkably luxurious and
Speaker 4:  relentlessly capable? Can it be all electric but agile off grid?
Speaker 4:  It can. Now introducing Kia's first three row all
Speaker 4:  electric SUV, the 2024 Kia V nine with
Speaker 4:  a sleek silhouette that reveals a spacious three row cabin with available
Speaker 4:  mood lighting that elevates yours with a pulse pounding zero to 60 speed
Speaker 4:  that thrills you one minute and available reclining lounge seats that unwind
Speaker 4:  you the next with a cabin so quiet you can almost hear a jaw
Speaker 4:  drop with all the premium comfort you crave and the off-road
Speaker 4:  capability you desire with a striking design that makes your heart
Speaker 4:  stop and race at the same time. It's the most beautiful
Speaker 4:  contradiction you've ever seen and it's everything you've ever wanted in
Speaker 4:  one amazing electric SUV, the all new all electric
Speaker 4:  three row Kia EV nine electric like you've never seen.
Speaker 4:  The 2024 Kia E nine is available now. Inventory limited. Check
Speaker 4:  with dealer for availability and visit kia.com/ EV nine for more
Speaker 4:  details.
Speaker 24:  Something strange is happening in Hollywood. I'm not talking
Speaker 24:  about that guy that got to host the Golden Globe. Yo,
Speaker 1:  I got the gig 10
Speaker 24:  Days ago. I'm talking about the secret musicals.
Speaker 1:  What's that? The Lord is the Queen Bee Regina George. Don't look her in
Speaker 1:  the eye.
Speaker 25:  You could be really hot if we change like everything.
Speaker 24:  A new Mean Girls movie comes out today. It promises it is not your
Speaker 24:  Mother's Mean Girls, which rude. But also what does that mean?
Speaker 24:  The trailer never tells you. But check out this footage from a recent screening
Speaker 24:  that audience groaning when not Lindsay Lowen, Katie
Speaker 24:  Heron starts singing. They're bummed because they didn't want a musical,
Speaker 24:  they didn't necessarily know they were getting a musical but they got
Speaker 24:  a musical. And it's not just Mean Girls Why Hollywood
Speaker 24:  is hiding its musicals. This week on today. Explain.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast Hotline. As
Speaker 2:  a reminder New Year, new Hotline. You can always email Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com and ask us your questions or call 8 6 6 Verge one one to reach us.
Speaker 2:  We try and answer at least one question on the show every week. We got a
Speaker 2:  ton of good ones over the holidays actually. So I think we're gonna have
Speaker 2:  to do like an all Hotline episode here in the very near future. But for This
Speaker 2:  week we have a question that Alex, this could not be more
Speaker 2:  you centric, so let's hear it.
Speaker 27:  Hey Vir team, this is Wess from Texas. I'm calling to see if
Speaker 27:  Krantz found any cool e Ink tech at CES. Would love to get the
Speaker 27:  rundown. Thanks
Speaker 2:  Ooh.
Speaker 23:  I did see some some e Ink tech while I was at CES.
Speaker 2:  Tell us more.
Speaker 23:  So some of it, it was a lot of concept stuff. There was obviously the e
Speaker 23:  Ink toilet Oh yes. That we all saw from Kohler,
Speaker 23:  which I think was a surprise to everyone, including e Ink,
Speaker 2:  Including potentially Kohler. Like you get the sense some one person made
Speaker 2:  that and they were just like, is this something? And they're like, CES, let's
Speaker 2:  do
Speaker 23:  It. Just bolted it on right when they got there and like, this is fine,
Speaker 23:  nobody will notice. Yeah, So, I got, I got to go to the E Inc booth. They
Speaker 23:  they, they don't actually have like a show floor presence anymore. They
Speaker 23:  mainly just taking meetings. But I went into their meeting room and got
Speaker 23:  to see all of their stuff and they had like all of the new, all of their
Speaker 23:  different displays there. It's a lot of signage stuff. They're still very,
Speaker 23:  very focused on the signage in a way the rest of us aren't. But there was
Speaker 23:  some phones from, I believe it's like the fifth largest smartphone maker
Speaker 23:  in the world. Have you heard of ics? No. With an x
Speaker 2:  Fifth largest. Jesus,
Speaker 23:  Not in America but in other places. They had the back of their, one of their
Speaker 23:  phones has the Prism e Ink technology on it, which is what we saw
Speaker 23:  from BMWA couple of years back. And what we also saw, Lenovo had a cool
Speaker 23:  laptop with the same tech on the front of it this year,
Speaker 2:  Like once every four years somebody tries the, what if we put an Ink screen
Speaker 2:  on a smartphone thing and I'm here for it every single time.
Speaker 23:  And in both cases, instead of being like, what if you could read a book
Speaker 23:  on the back of your phone? Both companies are like, what if you could just
Speaker 23:  make the back of your laptop or the back of your phone look really cool?
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. It's like a wallpaper thing more than anything. Yeah, a
Speaker 23:  Hundred percent because it does like three to four colors but it doesn't
Speaker 23:  really, really well including white. It makes like a really vibrant white,
Speaker 23:  which you usually don't get from E Inc. And then you get like you choose
Speaker 23:  a couple other colors, you have to pre-program it. It's not gonna just let
Speaker 23:  you read a book and scroll or anything like that. It's really signage technology
Speaker 23:  and it looked cool and you'd be able to charge your phone with wireless
Speaker 23:  charging and just have the back look however you want it. Instead of being
Speaker 23:  like, oh I need a green phone. You'd be like, oh, I can have a stupid
Speaker 23:  person on the back of my phone. don don't know Homer Simpsons. I was
Speaker 23:  like, what's a cartoon character I want on the back of my phone? Homer.
Speaker 23:  So that, that was really cool. I was really excited about that. The Lenovo
Speaker 23:  was obviously really, really cool. Other than that there was a lot
Speaker 23:  of sm, a lot of the smart home people are tossing e inc in as like
Speaker 23:  kinda little displays for sensors and things like that. We saw a couple
Speaker 23:  of those from smaller brands. That's not a new thing. Eve's been doing that
Speaker 23:  for a while. But it's nice to see other people adopt it. And
Speaker 23:  as much as I begged v to suddenly have seen a really
Speaker 23:  cool e Ink watch, she didn't, to my knowledge,
Speaker 23:  So I blame V entirely for that. Not the smart watch makers. It's all
Speaker 23:  Victoria's fault. Please tell her to to fix that. But,
Speaker 23:  but yeah, the phone was really cool and, and the way that they, these companies
Speaker 23:  were just like, wait, EIN doesn't need to be about reading. It doesn't have
Speaker 23:  to be a display. It can just be really cool wallpaper and give you customization
Speaker 23:  on a device where you traditionally haven't had it. And I want that.
Speaker 23:  That's
Speaker 2:  Kind of less ambitious than what we've heard from e Inc over the years. but
Speaker 2:  it is also probably more practical. They're like, this isn't gonna be the
Speaker 2:  year E Inc becomes a television. Like it's just, it's not, this isn't
Speaker 2:  gonna be that year either, but they're like, this is a thing it's actually
Speaker 2:  useful for and this is something you can do now. And that actually that tracks
Speaker 2:  for me. Yeah.
Speaker 23:  And, and you know, I spoke with the e Inc folks and they're still very focused
Speaker 23:  on signage. That's, that's where they make the most of their money. That's
Speaker 23:  what's doing really, really well for them. That's what they're bullish on
Speaker 23:  and they're like, we get really excited when people experiment and put it
Speaker 23:  in other things, toilets and, and, and tablets and, and phones.
Speaker 23:  But this is our focus. And so watching these companies be like, oh, maybe
Speaker 23:  we should also lean into that signage. Part of it is nice.
Speaker 23:  Hopefully next year we get something with really cool refresh rate. That's
Speaker 23:  what I really want.
Speaker 2:  Finally, give us full color and fast refresh rate and, and I will, I will
Speaker 2:  buy all Ink, all e Ink, everything. That's the life I wanna live.
Speaker 23:  I will note Onyx Books, who, who makes a lot of the e Ink tablets that I
Speaker 23:  really like. I love that company. They weren't at CES
Speaker 23:  so they'll they'll probably announce in, I, I would expect in the next couple
Speaker 23:  of weeks probably be ahead of Mobile World Congress is where we'll see their
Speaker 23:  announcements and so we'll probably get some really cool stuff then.
Speaker 2:  I like it. So thumbs up, thumbs down, Ian to 2024. How do we feel?
Speaker 23:  I mean I'll always thumbs up. I wish I could be thumbs down. Like, like
Speaker 23:  that's just, that's just bias. Like it's, it's totally biased on my
Speaker 23:  part. We saw a lot of cool technology announced last year that's getting
Speaker 23:  a little more mature and companies have had a year to figure out what to
Speaker 23:  do with it. So we're gonna see some of that in the marketplace, particularly
Speaker 23:  around color e Ink and color E Ink readers. I saw a really cool one that
Speaker 23:  was using Color Ink in that e Ink booth. I can't remember the name of it
Speaker 23:  right now. I think it was the big me one. Onyx books also had one and
Speaker 23:  it looked really, really cool. But I wanna see it not in a booth. I wanna
Speaker 23:  like spend more than a minute with it to say how cool it is. But the
Speaker 23:  color E Ink is getting a lot less goofy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like the amount of time I have spent waiting for just this one
Speaker 2:  little thing thing. That's thing. Just give me a color. Kindle.
Speaker 23:  We're so close to like Amazon or I'm really hoping Amazon.
Speaker 23:  Amazon noticed like we think Got Panos now. Panos, get out there. You
Speaker 23:  better have taken like 40,000 meetings with EE and get CES. I wanna see
Speaker 23:  some color Kindles. Let's do it
Speaker 2:  Man. If Panos fixes the Kindle after making the whole surface line of thing,
Speaker 2:  he he'll be a legend forever.
Speaker 23:  A
Speaker 2:  Legend Panos, I know you're listening. Do it for us. Do it for the first
Speaker 2:  cast.
Speaker 23:  Please. Please.
Speaker 2:  All right Alex, we gotta get outta here. Thank you as always.
Speaker 23:  You're welcome
Speaker 2:  As always. There is tons more on everything we talked about TikTok streaming
Speaker 2:  the works at The Verge dot com and we'll put lots of links in the show notes
Speaker 2:  to look out for that. This show is produced by Angel Marino Will Pour, and
Speaker 2:  Liam James The. Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 2:  podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, favorite
Speaker 2:  TikTok sounds or just Ian gadgets you want us to know about, you can always
Speaker 2:  email Vergecast at The Verge dot com Alex NELI and I'll be back on Friday
Speaker 2:  to talk about AI elections. The Apple watch, the Vision Pro, and a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  Hi. We're visible ringing in 2024 with a two years resolution to help you
Speaker 3:  save on wireless. Get one line with unlimited 5G data on Verizon's network.
Speaker 3:  Just $20 a month for 24 whole months with no annual contracts. That's 20
Speaker 3:  for 24 in 2024. Yep. We're pretty proud of that. Your
Speaker 3:  gym goals, you're on your own. A two years resolution To save on wireless,
Speaker 3:  we've got you Switch and save@visible.com. Use code visible 24. Hurry
Speaker 3:  ends January 31st. New members only promotional rate with service on the
Speaker 3:  visible plan. For additional terms and network management practices, see
Speaker 3:  visible.com.
Speaker 4:  Introducing Kia's first. All electric SUV. The 2024
Speaker 4:  Kia EV nine. Remarkably luxurious and relentlessly capable.
Speaker 4:  The Kia E nine has something for everyone. Impressive. Zero to 60
Speaker 4:  speed off-Road agility. A spacious three row cabin, even available
Speaker 4:  mood lighting. Get premium, comfort and rugged capability. All
Speaker 4:  in one sleek, spacious package. The all new, all-electric
Speaker 4:  three row Kia EV nine electric like you've never seen.
Speaker 4:  The 2024 Kia E nine is available now. Inventory limited. Check the dealer
Speaker 4:  for availability and visit kia.com/e nine for more details.