# Transcript
ID: 1883e16b-4334-4bac-bbdb-cb8ebba97fe9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-298828691265574928/-6558360280728599402/s93290-US-3465s-1711706659.mp3
Description: Today we're sharing an episode of a new podcast called Power User, which explores how technology and the internet are upending our lives and the world around us, hosted by tech journalist Taylor Lorenz.
Follow Power User with Taylor Lorenz wherever you get your podcasts: https://link.chtbl.com/poweruserpod
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (18 ads detected)
Speaker 4:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the TikTok Ban.
Speaker 4:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am the only one here with
Speaker 4:  vacations and sickness and stuff. We are not doing a normal Friday
Speaker 4:  episode this week. Everybody's back next week we will be back to our regularly
Speaker 4:  scheduled programming, but for Today we have something much better than NELI
Speaker 4:  and Alex. Taylor Lorenza here. Hi Taylor.
Speaker 5:  Hi.
Speaker 4:  You're a podcaster now. Last time we did this you had like ear pods on. Now
Speaker 4:  you have a light, you have a mic. Like this is a whole thing.
Speaker 5:  I know. I have the Vox Media setup. Shout out to
Speaker 5:  the producers that sent me all this gear. I have the official mic.
Speaker 4:  Is there just like a box that they sent you that's like Welcome To podcast?
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It was a box. They sent someone over to put up a lights in my kitchen, which
Speaker 5:  is where I am.
Speaker 4:  So you just launched a podcast. It's called Power User. Tell the people about
Speaker 4:  your podcast.
Speaker 5:  It's a weekly tech news show, but it focuses more on
Speaker 5:  the things that I cover, which is, is the user side of tech. A lot of
Speaker 5:  internet culture, media, landscape stuff, you know, some
Speaker 5:  creator industry stuff. Mr. Beast. Also touching on things like
Speaker 5:  Netflix, you know, Disney's some entertainment media
Speaker 5:  business and just wild, weird internet stories and trends. This week we're
Speaker 5:  talking about kindness influencers, which are a plague on TikTok. I don't
Speaker 5:  know, If. you see those? The guys that exploit unhoused people for
Speaker 5:  content basically. Yeah. And there's this feud between two big kindness
Speaker 5:  influencers over who's essentially helping this one family in West Virginia
Speaker 5:  more. you know, we're talking about the Andrew Huberman expose as well.
Speaker 5:  And so yeah, it's, I think that's a good, listen, we just launched it last
Speaker 5:  week.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you picked an interesting time to do this. There is like not a shortage
Speaker 4:  of weird stuff happening on the internet at this moment.
Speaker 5:  No, and I want people to better understand it. I think we talk so much about
Speaker 5:  big tech and sort of the traditional Silicon Valley side of tech and there's
Speaker 5:  not as many, I think tech podcasts focused on the tech world outside Silicon
Speaker 5:  Valley and just more of the cultural side of things. So
Speaker 5:  that's what I'm hoping to get into.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, this is actually one of the things I was thinking about as, as you
Speaker 4:  were, you know, we talked a little bit as you were getting ready to launch
Speaker 4:  the podcast and it seems like we're in this weird space where there are a
Speaker 4:  ton of creators who have podcasts, right? Like it's, I feel like it's the
Speaker 4:  same way in like the sports world, right? Where there used to be lots of
Speaker 4:  people who talked about athletes and now the athletes are just doing the
Speaker 4:  talking. But I feel like they're in this sort of space of like
Speaker 4:  people talking about this business. It's either the people who are in it
Speaker 4:  every day living it or nobody really talks about it. It's very weird. And
Speaker 4:  I feel like this has been like the needle, you've been threading for a really
Speaker 4:  long time where you're like, no, this matters. But also if it's just
Speaker 4:  a creator talking about their own life, that's not the quite, not quite the
Speaker 4:  same thing as like doing journalism about it. Exactly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I think also, I mean, I have a big content creator on
Speaker 5:  this week. Yeah. So, you know, I've, I've love creators and I wanna talk
Speaker 5:  to them, but I, I think it's worth giving a little bit more critical thought.
Speaker 5:  I think a lot of times when you're in an industry one, you can't speak as
Speaker 5:  freely about it sometimes. 'cause you're actually in this industry, you know,
Speaker 5:  a lot of their podcasts focus more on sort of like interpersonal drama, like
Speaker 5:  drama sort of stuff. Or they do culture. I mean, there's a lot of internet
Speaker 5:  culture YouTuber podcasts that I listen to all the time. I think I'm coming
Speaker 5:  at it more from like a business and cultural and journalistic angle. But
Speaker 5:  I love those YouTubers and I hope to have them on. And I'm a big commentary
Speaker 5:  channel fan, so,
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, it, there's lots of good stuff out there, don't get me wrong. There's
Speaker 4:  lots of different ways to come at this. So the episode we're gonna play here
Speaker 4:  is about the TikTok band. We picked this one because we talked a bunch about
Speaker 4:  the TikTok ban on The Vergecast two weeks ago. And everyone got
Speaker 4:  very mad at us. We, we disagreed vehemently about what should happen
Speaker 4:  here. Everybody got very upset. We got a lot of emails. I'm being accused
Speaker 4:  of being a a Chinese communist basically. And a lot of people think Mila
Speaker 4:  hates free speech and that think Alex is also
Speaker 4:  mad at everybody. It's really good times. I'm just curious how you feel about
Speaker 4:  where we are with the TikTok ban right now. We're gonna hear a bunch about
Speaker 4:  this in the episode, but where is your head with what you're thinking about
Speaker 4:  the TikTok ban kind of right in this moment?
Speaker 5:  Oh gosh. I said very earnestly to a friend the other day. I was like, we're
Speaker 5:  living in an era of mass censorship. And she was like, okay, you're starting
Speaker 5:  to sound like Elon Musk,
Speaker 5:  But as a journalist, and I would imagine you guys feel the same way, but
Speaker 5:  it, you know, I care a lot about civil liberties. I've always cared a lot
Speaker 5:  about civil liberties. I've spent a enormous time reporting on TikTok, and
Speaker 5:  not just TikTok, but musically. And I remember when there
Speaker 5:  was this fight when Facebook was driving musically into the ground
Speaker 5:  and they had to sell. And Viacom, you know, there was a minute that
Speaker 5:  we thought Viacom might buy, ance came in and sort of bought it and, and
Speaker 5:  just the la you know, of course no one cared back then that the fast
Speaker 5:  one of the, I would've called it one of the most relevant, fast growing video
Speaker 5:  social networks on the planet was being bought by Ance. And then now there's
Speaker 5:  this panic five years later. It's a little hard for me to take it quite as
Speaker 5:  seriously. Not that I'm like, where was this energy when you allowed
Speaker 5:  this deal to happen five years ago? But also I write a lot
Speaker 5:  about a lot of other up and coming apps and there's just Chinese influence
Speaker 5:  in so many things, gaming particularly. And you know, so I find a lot
Speaker 5:  of these arguments that these lawmakers are making, it doesn't seem like
Speaker 5:  the ban as it currently stands, the current bill would address any of these
Speaker 5:  issues, right. Doesn't address, address any of the problems with data brokers.
Speaker 5:  Doesn't address a lot of the civil liberties free speech stuff. And as I've
Speaker 5:  said before, and I was also accused of being a communist and I understand
Speaker 5:  making this comment, but even if TikTok was a Chinese propaganda app,
Speaker 5:  we're supposed to have a free and open internet. What if I am a communist
Speaker 5:  and I wanna consume Chinese propaganda all day, it's this is America. I should
Speaker 5:  be allowed to do that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We got a lot of emails from people after the episode a couple of weeks ago
Speaker 4:  that were basically like, well, China bans it.
Speaker 5:  Oh, so we should mimic an authoritarian state. Oh, well this
Speaker 5:  authoritarian should more like China State over there. China, yeah. What?
Speaker 5:  No, I actually don't want the government to control our app store. It's so
Speaker 5:  funny the way this is split around political lines, and I think, I mean,
Speaker 5:  I'm planning a future episode about this, so I really hope people tune in.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if anyone's been following the Jonathan Haight Anti phone
Speaker 5:  press tour recently. A little bit, yeah. But there's just this, you can push
Speaker 5:  a lot of bad legislation and dangerous things through and sell people
Speaker 5:  on things when you tell them it's protecting children and you know, here's
Speaker 5:  what your children are up to and they're being brainwashed, you know, by
Speaker 5:  this Chinese communist app or whatever. And it's just
Speaker 5:  not true. I, I mean, I'm very skeptical of all of the, the Save the Children
Speaker 5:  type messaging around phones generally, and especially around TikTok because
Speaker 5:  TikTok is quite, you know, liberating for a lot of kids. It's not like Instagram
Speaker 5:  and a lot of other apps which have actually done the things that they're
Speaker 5:  accusing TikTok of doing, like manipulate, you know, affecting our elections,
Speaker 5:  causing a lot of self harm, eating disorders, whatever. Not to say,
Speaker 5:  you know, TikTok is a very different TikTok iss much more akin to YouTube.
Speaker 5:  I always call say it's a, it's a combination of Twitter and YouTube.
Speaker 4:  I think that's right. All right, well before we get into the episode, how
Speaker 4:  can people find the show? It's all the places you get podcasts, right? It's
Speaker 4:  called Power User. You're also on YouTube, right? Doing video stuff?
Speaker 5:  Yes, it's on my YouTube channel, so please subscribe. Taylor Lorenz. I'm
Speaker 5:  doing lots more videos, lots more tech videos. It's just Taylor Lorenz on
Speaker 5:  YouTube. And you can find us on Spotify Apple podcast. Please review it.
Speaker 5:  If you like it. And Instagram. I'm gonna be sharing your Power User pod on
Speaker 5:  Instagram. There
Speaker 4:  You go. Awesome. All right, well here is the first episode of Power User.
Speaker 4:  Thanks Taylor.
Speaker 5:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 5:  This week we're talking about the TikTok ban, how shrimp Jesus is taking
Speaker 5:  over Facebook and Mr. Beast's record breaking new reality show.
Speaker 5:  I'm Taylor Lorenz. And that's all coming up right now on Power. User
Speaker 6:  Welcome
Speaker 5:  To Power User. I'm Taylor Lorenz, a technology journalist, and I'm so excited
Speaker 5:  to be launching this show today. I've been covering internet culture, online
Speaker 5:  creators, and the tech world for over a decade. Every week I'm gonna be breaking
Speaker 5:  down the biggest stories in tech and online culture. And this week the big
Speaker 5:  story is definitely TikTok. Recently the House of
Speaker 5:  Representatives moved a bill forward that would effectively ban the app and
Speaker 5:  The future of the platform is looking dicey. So I'm bringing in Evan Greer,
Speaker 5:  the director of Fight for The future, a nonpartisan nonprofit organization
Speaker 5:  that fights for civil liberties online. We're gonna break down the concerns
Speaker 5:  around TikTok, what lawmakers are hoping to achieve by banning it, and whether
Speaker 5:  this app is really something we should all be worried about. Hi Evan, thank
Speaker 5:  you so much for joining me on the first episode of Power User.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, for sure. Taylor, thanks so much for having me on. You've
Speaker 5:  Been super critical of this legislation, so I wanna talk about some of the
Speaker 5:  concerns with this bill and what you feel like Congress could actually be
Speaker 5:  doing to make our lives better online. First of all, a lot of lawmakers are
Speaker 5:  trying to claim that this is not a real ban, it's a forced sale, and there's
Speaker 5:  some sort of big distinction between the two things. Is it fair to characterize
Speaker 5:  this legislation as a forced sale or is this an effective ban?
Speaker 8:  This bill is a ban by any other name.
Speaker 8:  I'm not a a business lawyer. I've never tried to buy or
Speaker 8:  sell a multi-billion dollar company, but it doesn't take an
Speaker 8:  expert to understand that. Like those types of things don't tend to happen
Speaker 8:  overnight. And all of the experts that I've talked to have
Speaker 8:  suggested that the six month timeline that's laid out
Speaker 8:  in this bill that would attempt to force TikTok to effectively sell
Speaker 8:  itself or get banned is just completely
Speaker 8:  impractical and ridiculous.
Speaker 5:  Well, yeah, it's actually 180 days, right? Within that six
Speaker 5:  month timeline, they have to sell within 180 days, which as my
Speaker 5:  colleague Drew reported, would be one of the thorniest and most complicated
Speaker 5:  transactions in all of corporate history. And it would almost
Speaker 5:  certainly pose insurmountable financial, technical and geopolitical challenges
Speaker 5:  making this sale basically untenable.
Speaker 8:  That's exactly right. That's what I've heard from every expert that I've
Speaker 8:  talked to about it as well, which is why the A CLU and many other
Speaker 8:  civil liberties organizations have said clearly that this does amount
Speaker 8:  to a ban. And because of that, it's clearly
Speaker 8:  unconstitutional. In the United States, we have the first amendment, it
Speaker 8:  prohibits the government from engaging in acts of censorship unless
Speaker 8:  they can prove they have no other option, no other way to
Speaker 8:  address the concerns that they're raising. And you know, we'll get
Speaker 8:  into it a little bit more later, but they have many options, many ways that
Speaker 8:  they could address legitimate concerns with TikTok and other big tech
Speaker 8:  companies short of actually banning them outright.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, and also, I mean you mentioned these lawmakers themselves have been
Speaker 5:  referring to it as ban. I just wanna read a couple quotes from some of those
Speaker 5:  lawmakers. These are the people that championed the bill and ushered it through
Speaker 5:  Representative Elise Deon says quote, I'm proud to join Chairman
Speaker 5:  Mike Gallagher to finally ban TikTok in the United States.
Speaker 5:  And then representative Bob Lata says, I'm proud to help lead the bipartisan
Speaker 5:  act, which will ban the app from the United States. Representative Chip
Speaker 5:  Roy says, I'm proud to partner with the representatives on this bipartisan
Speaker 5:  bill to ban the distribution of TikTok in the us. These lawmakers might
Speaker 5:  try to sort of spin it in the media like, oh, it's not a real ban, but this
Speaker 5:  is an effective ban and that is how they themselves are
Speaker 5:  promoting it.
Speaker 8:  That's exactly right. And I think in their minds, you know, I don't know
Speaker 8:  that they've actually like gamed this out until the end, right? They may
Speaker 8:  very much end up as the dogs who caught the car because I think they
Speaker 8:  perhaps really are hoping to bully TikTok into selling themselves to a US
Speaker 8:  company or something like that. But the timeline that they've laid out is
Speaker 8:  so ridiculous that they might end up sort of accidentally banning TikTok
Speaker 8:  and then dealing with the political consequences of that since we
Speaker 8:  know it is an app that is wildly popular, especially with young
Speaker 8:  people, which both parties are struggling to speak to in
Speaker 8:  terms of what the issues that they care about. So I think unfortunately this
Speaker 8:  is a lot of like tech policy made for tv and I think it's bad politics
Speaker 8:  on both sides all around.
Speaker 5:  Not to mention that musically, which is what TikTok was named before they
Speaker 5:  rebranded it as TikTok was sold to Bite Dance in 2017.
Speaker 5:  None of these lawmakers had any issue with that sale at the time, of course.
Speaker 5:  But the reason that Musically sale went through and bite dance was the one
Speaker 5:  to buy it as well is because there were no viable
Speaker 5:  US purchasers. Google and Meta were essentially written out
Speaker 5:  because of antitrust concerns. So I just think
Speaker 5:  it's very telling that like who is this app gonna sell to? you know, if this
Speaker 5:  alleged forced sale is supposed to happen, any major
Speaker 5:  company that it would sell to, I think there would be serious antitrust concerns.
Speaker 5:  So it's just totally unfeasible.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's exactly right.
Speaker 5:  Alright Evan, so let's get into some of the civil liberties concerns with
Speaker 5:  the ban. How is this a free speech and First Amendment issue?
Speaker 8:  So what this really comes down to is do you believe that your government
Speaker 8:  should be able to tell you where you can get news from and where
Speaker 8:  you can express yourself? In the United States, we have the First Amendment.
Speaker 8:  The First Amendment prohibits the government from telling me I can't give
Speaker 8:  an interview to Al Jazeera, even though Al Jazeera is not
Speaker 8:  owned by a US company. Just like the government can't stop me from writing
Speaker 8:  an op-ed, or a letter to the editor to a newspaper,
Speaker 8:  TikTok is a platform that millions of Americans use to express themselves.
Speaker 8:  So banning it would amount to silencing the voices of
Speaker 8:  millions of people. The First Amendment requires that if the US
Speaker 8:  government is going to engage in that type of act of restricting speech,
Speaker 8:  they have to prove that they have no other way to
Speaker 8:  address their concerns. Now, the concerns the US government has stated in
Speaker 8:  this case, as they say, TikTok is collecting your data. It could be shared
Speaker 8:  with the Chinese government and or the Chinese government could be manipulating
Speaker 8:  tiktoks algorithm to spread propaganda. Let's take both of those concerns
Speaker 8:  at face value. Let's say it's true.
Speaker 5:  I mean, my feeling is even if it was a Chinese propaganda app say
Speaker 5:  it was, don't we have the right to consume that if we want? Isn't that supposed
Speaker 5:  to be a freedom that we're allowed?
Speaker 8:  Absolutely. you know, there's nothing that says we shouldn't be able to read
Speaker 8:  lies. And you know, unfortunately there's more
Speaker 8:  of them floating around on the internet than any of us would perhaps like.
Speaker 8:  But yes, absolutely. Even if we take the government's concerns completely
Speaker 8:  at face value and they believe the Chinese Communist Party is literally has
Speaker 8:  their their hand on the lever and is like controlling tiktoks algorithm at
Speaker 8:  a granular level. And let's be clear, there's no actual evidence
Speaker 8:  to suggest that that is happening. But it's a valid concern.
Speaker 8:  Governments do things, the Chinese government certainly does engage in
Speaker 8:  authoritarian acts, you know, worth asking. That
Speaker 8:  said, there's absolutely ways to address that. We could pass algorithmic
Speaker 8:  transparency legislation and require that companies like TikTok
Speaker 8:  open up their algorithms to third party auditors that would
Speaker 8:  catch a government that was engaging in that kind of manipulation. We could
Speaker 8:  pass privacy legislation to prevent them from collecting so much data about
Speaker 8:  all of us in the first place and using that data to recommend us content.
Speaker 8:  Those are meaningful ways that we could address the types of concerns that
Speaker 8:  the government is raising without banning an app that millions of people
Speaker 8:  use to express themselves. That's why banning TikTok is blatantly
Speaker 8:  unconstitutional and frankly a huge distraction from the types
Speaker 8:  of real measures that would actually lead to a better internet with more
Speaker 8:  free expression and more human rights for everyone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, I just think it's so telling that while these lawmakers claim,
Speaker 5:  you know, concerns around national security and everything, and we'll definitely
Speaker 5:  get into that. When you listen to what they said at the hearing,
Speaker 5:  you realize that repeatedly they express issue with the
Speaker 5:  content they believe to be on the app
Speaker 9:  From the data it collects to the content it controls.
Speaker 9:  TikTok is a grave threat of foreign influence
Speaker 9:  in American life. It's been said, it's like allowing the Soviet Union the
Speaker 9:  power to produce Saturday morning cartoons during the Cold War,
Speaker 9:  but much more powerful and much more dangerous.
Speaker 9:  Banning your platform will address the immediate threats.
Speaker 5:  And that to me is really scary and dystopian because once we have these lawmakers
Speaker 5:  starting to sort of legislate around the content that they
Speaker 5:  think is okay, you know, to expose people to online or the news and information,
Speaker 5:  you know, that young people have access to through apps like TikTok or other
Speaker 5:  social media platforms, it just feels scary. Like that feels very
Speaker 5:  much like an infringement on our ability to freely
Speaker 5:  consume information and express ideas.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And unfortunately that kind of authoritarian
Speaker 8:  impulse of going after online speech and content is
Speaker 8:  not just limited to TikTok and it's unfortunately very bipartisan in
Speaker 8:  DC right now. Both Democrats and Republicans have really leaned into this
Speaker 8:  idea that it's like online content and
Speaker 8:  speech that is driving these harms in our society rather than
Speaker 8:  the underlying business practices of these companies that we can actually
Speaker 8:  regulate. And so what you see is Republicans sort of being like, look at
Speaker 8:  all this content that our kids are consuming and they're talking about like
Speaker 8:  RuPaul's Drag race videos or whatever. But then you see Democrats leading
Speaker 8:  into it and saying, look at these Andrew Tate videos and like they're being
Speaker 8:  recommended to kids and like, that's terrible. And like they're right. That's
Speaker 8:  terrible. The way that we address that is by addressing
Speaker 8:  patriarchy in our society, by attacking the underlying business
Speaker 8:  model that makes it profitable for companies to artificially amplify
Speaker 8:  the most extreme content. We cannot address this issue
Speaker 8:  through government censorship that just leads to more harm, particularly
Speaker 8:  for young people.
Speaker 5:  And say China did wanna interfere with America through, you know,
Speaker 5:  programming social media. Is there anything that TikTok
Speaker 5:  specifically allows that other American owned apps like Facebook and
Speaker 5:  Twitter and YouTube don't allow?
Speaker 8:  No, these companies operate in almost the exact same manner. They
Speaker 8:  all employ the same basic surveillance capitalist business
Speaker 8:  model, which is about collecting your data, monitoring what you do
Speaker 8:  on the app, and then using that information to recommend you content in order
Speaker 8:  to keep you clicking and scrolling and generating advertising revenue. They're
Speaker 8:  all basically the same app and they all sort of increasingly become more
Speaker 8:  and more like the same app as they just sort of copy each other.
Speaker 5:  Although one thing I'll say about that is that there has been this
Speaker 5:  refrain from a lot of people of, oh well because these are just the same
Speaker 5:  apps. If we delete TikTok, everybody can just go use, you know,
Speaker 5:  Instagram or Twitter or whatever. And I do think that there's
Speaker 5:  something that's different about TikTok, which is that it's not owned by
Speaker 5:  an American company. And also these other platforms have made very
Speaker 5:  aggressive moves to censor speech. I mean, I'm just thinking of
Speaker 5:  meta Instagram's recent policies saying that any content that touches on
Speaker 5:  political issues or social issues will be down ranked. And that is the type
Speaker 5:  of stuff that they're trying to deprioritize on Instagram, Facebook, and
Speaker 5:  threads. So it's really hard to talk about things like
Speaker 5:  revenge porn or the election or just these really critical issues that we
Speaker 5:  should be talking about in society on meta owned apps. Look at Twitter, right?
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk has spent the past week banning any journalists that reported on
Speaker 5:  this Nazi comic book writer. And YouTube is much more of an
Speaker 5:  entertainment platform in the sense that I don't think a lot of average users
Speaker 5:  post on there. It's also not a great place for politics. So
Speaker 5:  I do think that TikTok allowed a certain group of people, especially young
Speaker 5:  progressives, a space to really have these urgent political conversations
Speaker 5:  about things like the war on Gaza or climate change and things like that.
Speaker 5:  And it seems that seems to have really irked these lawmakers.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think that's definitely a part of the picture here. Although I think
Speaker 8:  in the long run we just have to recognize that like TikTok may be a
Speaker 8:  friendlier space for some of the politics that we care about right now,
Speaker 8:  but in the end, as long as we're reliant on a very small handful
Speaker 8:  of privately owned companies, whether they're owned by US
Speaker 8:  companies or companies based in other countries to be
Speaker 8:  the kind of digital public square, we're always going to be sort of at the
Speaker 8:  whim of whoever our digital landlord is, whether it's Elon Musk or Mark
Speaker 8:  Zuckerberg or by dance. And so I think again, that's why
Speaker 8:  we need more thoughtful and comprehensive policies that get us past the current
Speaker 8:  era that we're in and toward The future where we have meaningful choices
Speaker 8:  so that If, you are concerned about TikTok or Instagram or any
Speaker 8:  other company and their business practices, you can actually go find somewhere
Speaker 8:  else. And just to your other point of this idea that like, oh, well if we
Speaker 8:  ban TikTok, everyone can just immediately switch. Big tech companies have
Speaker 8:  intentionally made it as difficult as possible to switch
Speaker 8:  from one platform to another to bring your followers with you.
Speaker 8:  And you know, that really affects marginalized people the most. Maybe if
Speaker 8:  you're a big celebrity and you, you know, the app you're on gets banned,
Speaker 8:  you can switch to a different app, everyone's gonna follow you there. If
Speaker 8:  you're an L-G-B-T-Q content creator or a musician or someone
Speaker 8:  who's spent a lot of time building an audience on one platform and then
Speaker 8:  that platform gets ripped out from underneath you, that can have a profound
Speaker 8:  impact on your ability to make living your ability to make rent that month,
Speaker 8:  your ability to express yourself and connect with your community and your
Speaker 8:  audience. So I think we shouldn't dismiss or ignore the real
Speaker 8:  human impacts of, you know, these types of measures or
Speaker 8:  thinking about banning an entire app or the impact it has on people when
Speaker 8:  an app gets bought or sold. I mean, you know it, it personally impacted
Speaker 8:  me when Elon Musk bought Twitter, it was someplace I spent a fair amount
Speaker 8:  of time building an audience and speaking particularly to other L-G-B-T-Q
Speaker 8:  people and then it became a much less friendly place for my community.
Speaker 8:  That's a reality that you know, many people have had to deal with and we
Speaker 8:  should take it seriously.
Speaker 5:  And I think a lot of people also misunderstand the ownership structure of
Speaker 5:  TikTok. TikTok is not majority owned by dance, okay? This is
Speaker 5:  not how TikTok is owned. TikTok was in a company that was incorporated in
Speaker 5:  America, and it is based in Los Angeles
Speaker 5:  and Singapore. It does not operate in China. It is owned
Speaker 5:  60% by foreign investors, including many Americans,
Speaker 5:  20% owned by employees, including over 7,000 American
Speaker 5:  employees and 20% owned by the company's founders. So
Speaker 5:  does Bite Dance have a stake in TikTok? Yes, but this is
Speaker 5:  not an app that is solely owned by a Chinese corporation. So back in
Speaker 5:  2019, the US government forced another Chinese company to give
Speaker 5:  up a 60% stake in Grindr, a gay dating app.
Speaker 5:  It's bothers me a little bit when people try to make these comparisons because
Speaker 5:  Grindr is not a media platform, it is not a social media platform. It's a
Speaker 5:  completely different product. Also, the ownership structure is
Speaker 5:  completely different. In that case, a Chinese company had majority
Speaker 5:  ownership. I it's truly apples to oranges and it is
Speaker 5:  very frustrating to sort of debunk all the different ways. This is different.
Speaker 5:  Grinder had a completely different corporate ownership structure.
Speaker 8:  Well and even more absurdly when the US
Speaker 8:  government forced Grindr to sell itself to US company, which they did,
Speaker 8:  it wasn't that long ago that data brokers were caught
Speaker 8:  collecting and selling information from Grindr to a right wing
Speaker 8:  religious group that was using it to track down priests that they thought
Speaker 8:  might be gay. So here's an example of where if what we're really
Speaker 8:  concerned about is like bad actors might get this data from
Speaker 8:  TikTok, then we need to regulate the
Speaker 8:  industry of collecting and selling people's data because the Chinese government,
Speaker 8:  if you're concerned about them, could just go buy a lot of the same data
Speaker 8:  from data brokers in the US that they could get from TikTok if that's even
Speaker 8:  happening, which again, there's no evidence to suggest that it actually is.
Speaker 8:  So
Speaker 5:  Let's dig into some of the national security concerns because I think a lot
Speaker 5:  of people are scared about the data privacy. TikTok has said
Speaker 5:  repeatedly that US user data is stored in Texas on Oracle
Speaker 5:  controlled servers. So in order for TikTok to make changes
Speaker 5:  or access that data or the Chinese government was gonna try to access this
Speaker 5:  data, it would have to go through Oracle, which is a US based company to
Speaker 5:  access that data, which again is housed in the us. There is no evidence that
Speaker 5:  any Chinese entity has even tried to gain access to that data.
Speaker 5:  Meanwhile, we know that back in 2016 and many other times,
Speaker 5:  foreign governments actually were able to manipulate our social media landscape
Speaker 5:  not through any sort of secret data obtaining but
Speaker 5:  through buying things like public Facebook ads or buying data publicly.
Speaker 5:  So tell me a little bit about these concerns about data privacy and
Speaker 5:  TikTok and whether you think that any of this is warranted.
Speaker 8:  Sure. So people are right to be concerned about TikTok collecting their
Speaker 8:  data. They should just also be as concerned about
Speaker 8:  companies like Instagram and Uber and Postmates and your
Speaker 8:  dog walking app and almost every other free online
Speaker 8:  service that you use collecting your data. And what we know is that
Speaker 8:  once a company collects your data, it doesn't necessarily
Speaker 8:  stay with that company. There is a massive unregulated data
Speaker 8:  broker industry in the us. Companies collect your data and then sell it
Speaker 8:  to other companies who will then sell it to the highest bidder. It's a
Speaker 8:  national embarrassment that we do not have basic data privacy laws
Speaker 8:  here in the us. So it's almost sort of a funny talking point for TikTok I
Speaker 8:  would say to be like, our data is housed in Texas where there's basically
Speaker 8:  no privacy protections or laws to protect your data. And we
Speaker 8:  have like the Attorney General of Texas, Ken Paxton is like making lists
Speaker 8:  of trans people. So it doesn't make me feel particularly safer that my
Speaker 8:  data is stored there than if it restored anywhere else. In the end, what
Speaker 8:  we need is policies that protect everyone's data, which would start
Speaker 8:  with a strong national privacy law here in the US and ideally
Speaker 8:  laws like that all around the world.
Speaker 5:  Why hasn't a law like that been passed? Because it seems like such a no-brainer.
Speaker 5:  This is something that consumers have repeatedly asked for.
Speaker 8:  It is, and it's where there's so much consensus between human
Speaker 8:  rights experts and the business community and others. Like
Speaker 8:  everyone agrees a privacy law would be a good idea. The reason it hasn't
Speaker 8:  moved forward is basically the same reasons that a lot of other
Speaker 8:  legislation doesn't move. It's about corruption, corporate
Speaker 8:  influence, and congressional dysfunction. So the corporate
Speaker 8:  influence part is probably the biggest factor here. Certainly big tech
Speaker 8:  companies have been very active in lobbying against strong privacy
Speaker 8:  legislation, but it's not just the like Metas and Instagrams
Speaker 8:  and YouTubes of the world that care about this, it's Bank of America and
Speaker 8:  Walmart and Target and effectively every other large
Speaker 8:  US company that at this point has some interest in being able
Speaker 8:  to conduct the type of commercial surveillance that allows them
Speaker 8:  to gain a competitive edge. So unfortunately, because of a
Speaker 8:  lack of regulation, almost every big company in the US has sort of
Speaker 8:  become a surveillance capitalist company in some capacity
Speaker 8:  or other. And that's a big reason why privacy legislation
Speaker 8:  hasn't moved forward because it's not just opposed by the tech industry,
Speaker 8:  it's sort of posed by Wall Street and the broader
Speaker 8:  behemoths of the American economy. And that's what needs to be overcome
Speaker 8:  to get something done on this, even though it's overwhelmingly supported
Speaker 8:  people from across the political spectrum. Overwhelmingly agree, we
Speaker 8:  don't want companies to be able to collect so much of our private information
Speaker 8:  and use it to enrich themselves at the cost of our basic rights
Speaker 8:  and safety.
Speaker 5:  I'm curious what you think about Biden's reversal and all this. you know,
Speaker 5:  back in 2020 it was Trump pushing this ban. Trump has now recognized correctly
Speaker 5:  that a ban would actually embolden Facebook, which I
Speaker 5:  guess is his enemy now. And now we have Biden saying that he would sign a
Speaker 5:  bill into law. What do you think led to that flip flop?
Speaker 8:  I think it just shows that, again, this is really all about politics, right?
Speaker 8:  More than it's about the substance, more than it's about any specific business
Speaker 8:  practice. and more than it's about any legitimate concerns, TikTok
Speaker 8:  has become a bit of a political football that's being kicked back and forth
Speaker 8:  between two parties that are sort of trying to outcompete each other on who
Speaker 8:  can be the toughest on China. And all of us in our basic
Speaker 8:  rights and free expression are sort of caught in the middle of this
Speaker 8:  political football game. But I think, you know, just to say it like, look,
Speaker 8:  I am an advocate. I run a nonpartisan nonprofit. We focus
Speaker 8:  on advocating for people's rights. So I don't get involved in
Speaker 8:  electoral politics, but just it doesn't take an expert to sit back and be
Speaker 8:  like, it would be bad politics for any lawmaker
Speaker 8:  or certainly any sitting president or presidential hopeful
Speaker 8:  to get on board with the idea of banning an app that is disproportionately
Speaker 8:  used by young people who are the voters that both parties are desperately
Speaker 8:  trying to court. And so it just strikes me as like deeply
Speaker 8:  silly and absurd, and especially now that Trump has come out and
Speaker 8:  said that he's against a TikTok ban, Biden would just be walking into the
Speaker 8:  most obvious trap ever. If he were to sign a bill banning
Speaker 8:  TikTok and hand Trump this talking point to beat him over the head with,
Speaker 8:  especially with the young voters that he is really struggling to
Speaker 8:  keep support from, especially given his ongoing support of
Speaker 8:  the violence in Gaza and a lot of other issues that young people
Speaker 8:  are concerned about and talking about on TikTok primarily.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you know, speaking of playing politics, TikTok was also accused of
Speaker 5:  playing politics by quote unquote forcing users to contact their
Speaker 5:  representatives and express their opinion on the van. Just to be clear,
Speaker 5:  TikTok didn't force users to do anything despite what Congress people are
Speaker 5:  claiming. How do you think that push alert that they sent helped or hurt
Speaker 5:  them? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  You know, I mean I think it's hard to say, right? Certainly many members
Speaker 8:  of Congress have leaned into that talking point and said like, see, look,
Speaker 8:  here's the proof that they have all this power to manipulate people. I
Speaker 8:  mean, I'm old enough to remember the SOPA blackout when Wikipedia and
Speaker 8:  thousands of other websites blacked out their homepage to protest internet
Speaker 8:  censorship legislation that could have led to widespread harm
Speaker 8:  online. So this is not a brand new thing that said,
Speaker 8:  you know, I couldn't tell you whether it was, you know, helpful or hurtful
Speaker 8:  to their case in Washington DC because in the end, I think this does come
Speaker 8:  down to politics and sort of what lawmakers think is gonna help or
Speaker 8:  hurt them in the election. I should have mentioned this earlier, but just
Speaker 8:  like the timeline that has been laid out in this bill of when a
Speaker 8:  sale would have to be forced is suspiciously timed to be
Speaker 8:  before the election, right? And so I think again, that does show us that
Speaker 8:  like more than this is about China and more than this is about data
Speaker 8:  more than this is about speech, this is about 2024,
Speaker 8:  and politicians sort of jockeying for position with TikTok as
Speaker 8:  a ball that they're kicking back and forth.
Speaker 5:  I'm so glad you brought up SOPA and that blackout because there's been so
Speaker 5:  many efforts over the years from tech companies and startups
Speaker 5:  to push certain pieces of legislation through Congress and otherwise. I'm
Speaker 5:  also thinking of all of the work that companies did around net neutrality.
Speaker 5:  I mean, for a while you couldn't log onto Tumblr back in the day without
Speaker 5:  being hit with this big message about this net neutrality legislation that
Speaker 5:  Congress wanted to pass. More recently, other tech companies have pushed
Speaker 5:  messaging to users about legislation they felt would threaten their businesses
Speaker 5:  directly. Instacart, Uber, Lyft, Postmates, DoorDash have all engaged in
Speaker 5:  this type of behavior. In 2020, Uber users in California had to confirm
Speaker 5:  that they'd seen a message before calling the ride, which told them that
Speaker 5:  wait times and prices would rise if this legislation called Prop
Speaker 5:  22 wasn't passed. And Uber actually sent repeated push
Speaker 5:  notifications to users warning them about Prop 22.
Speaker 5:  Instacart workers were also even instructed to insert stickers and flyers
Speaker 5:  endorsing a pretty controversial California ballot measure into
Speaker 5:  customers shopping bags at grocery stores. I really agreed with The Verge
Speaker 5:  as Miato who said, you know, it's really weird to act like this type of behavior
Speaker 5:  isn't standard. And I think that these lawmakers trying to spin it as like
Speaker 5:  China pushing its agenda on the American public are ignoring a
Speaker 5:  long history of tech companies and startups doing exactly this.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, absolutely. And look like this is how companies operate
Speaker 8:  in a capitalist system. We should reckon with that and then
Speaker 8:  decide what we want to do as a society and what sorts of rules should be
Speaker 8:  governing technology and recognize that companies are gonna
Speaker 8:  try to influence that. And it's up to us as a society to push
Speaker 8:  back on that influence and do what actually needs to be done.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, and I certainly would never argue, well Uber did something, therefore
Speaker 5:  it's totally fine that TikTok is to it. I think it's pretty dark that it
Speaker 5:  is so common. But to sort of ignore that history to me is
Speaker 5:  disingenuous. What should average users do who are against
Speaker 5:  this type of bill?
Speaker 8:  You know, I actually think it's still really important that people do
Speaker 8:  call and email their members of Congress about this. And I would even encourage
Speaker 8:  you to call and say, I am not calling from that TikTok push notification.
Speaker 8:  I really care about this because I care about free speech
Speaker 8:  and human rights. I want you to pass privacy legislation instead of
Speaker 8:  banning TikTok. We have a campaign, my organization fight for The future
Speaker 8:  at don't ban TikTok dot com that has that exact messaging. So it's not just
Speaker 8:  saying, Hey, Congress, don't do anything. It's saying pass
Speaker 8:  privacy laws if you're concerned about this, rather than banning TikTok.
Speaker 8:  And I think that that is really important because again, there's some of
Speaker 8:  this that is just about political posturing and stoking
Speaker 8:  xenophobia and you know, kind of saying whatever politicians think
Speaker 8:  is gonna sound good on Fox News and M-S-N-B-C. But there's some
Speaker 8:  amount of it that is like lawmakers having genuine concerns. And to the
Speaker 8:  extent there are lawmakers with genuine concerns, it's important that we
Speaker 8:  tell them that there are alternatives, that there are things that they can
Speaker 8:  do to address those concerns, but that banning TikTok is not one of them.
Speaker 8:  So I would encourage everyone to write an email their senators since
Speaker 8:  this is now really a Senate issue, and tell them to
Speaker 8:  pass a privacy law instead of banning TikTok. The more they hear from people,
Speaker 8:  it does matter. I know sometimes it sounds, it feels like they're just ignoring
Speaker 8:  you, they never listen. But I can tell you that congressional staffers,
Speaker 8:  when their phone starts ringing off the hook, it does make a difference.
Speaker 8:  It does give them pause. It may not always translate into what their boss
Speaker 8:  says on tv, but it does have an impact on how they end up voting or
Speaker 8:  whether the legislation even goes to the floor. The more that
Speaker 8:  particularly Chuck Schumer Senate majority leader gets the sense that this
Speaker 8:  is controversial and would be a bad look, the less likely
Speaker 8:  he is to move it forward. I could very much see a scenario where they just
Speaker 8:  to kind of decide, yeah, we'll keep talking about this TikTok thing, but
Speaker 8:  we're just gonna kind of like hope that people forget about it and never
Speaker 8:  bring it to the floor. I wouldn't be surprised if that happens, but
Speaker 8:  if people don't speak out, we could end up in a really dangerous
Speaker 8:  situation here and I could see an environment where they sort of accidentally
Speaker 8:  actually succeed in banning TikTok and the political consequences of that
Speaker 8:  could be really dire.
Speaker 5:  I think a lot of the conversations around this app and the way that people
Speaker 5:  have talked about China, and I'm thinking of when Tiktoks
Speaker 5:  CEO was hauled in front of Congress and was repeatedly asked if he was an
Speaker 5:  agent of the Chinese Communist Party, despite the fact that he's Singaporean
Speaker 5:  and served in the Singaporean military.
Speaker 8:  Have you ever been a member of the Chinese Communist Party?
Speaker 10:  Senator? I'm Singaporean, no.
Speaker 11:  Have you ever been associated or affiliated with the Chinese Communist Party?
Speaker 10:  No. Senator, again, I'm Singaporean.
Speaker 5:  It just makes it seem like a lot of this stuff is motivated by
Speaker 5:  xenophobia. How much of a role do you think that's playing in the way that
Speaker 5:  these conversations are happening?
Speaker 8:  I think it plays a huge role and I think it's unserious
Speaker 8:  to pretend that it doesn't, right? Like there are legitimate
Speaker 8:  concerns and they can be separated from this kind of
Speaker 8:  generalized xenophobia and anti-Chinese
Speaker 8:  anti-Asian sentiment. But it's just foolish and ridiculous to
Speaker 8:  pretend that that's not a huge factor that is
Speaker 8:  animating this attack on TikTok. And let's be real that it's not
Speaker 8:  just Republicans. There are unfortunately many
Speaker 8:  Democrats that are happy to lean into those types of xenophobic
Speaker 8:  and anti-Asian narratives so that they can again kind of be one-upping
Speaker 8:  their Republican opponents on who's tougher on China.
Speaker 8:  And look, you know, I'm an anti-authoritarian. I care a
Speaker 8:  lot about civil liberties and civil rights. I have a lot of concerns about
Speaker 8:  the Chinese government and their policies. Just like I have a lot of concerns
Speaker 8:  about most other governments and their policies. So this doesn't
Speaker 8:  mean you can't criticize the Chinese government or that you can't raise
Speaker 8:  concerns about the Chinese government's very small stake
Speaker 8:  in by dance, which has a stake in TikTok. But there are ways to
Speaker 8:  do that without leaning into these xenophobic and anti-Asian
Speaker 8:  narratives. But unfortunately that's not what lawmakers have been doing.
Speaker 8:  They're very much pouring gasoline on those types of flames.
Speaker 8:  And we should be honest about the fact that that has deadly consequences.
Speaker 8:  We know there has been a massive uptick in anti-Asian hate crimes
Speaker 8:  here in the United States over the last number of years as more and more
Speaker 8:  lawmakers have leaned into this type of rhetoric. And we should be honest
Speaker 8:  about the fact that folks that are kind of jumping on this bandwagon of
Speaker 8:  let's ban TikTok because China are either knowingly
Speaker 8:  or or unwittingly helping pour gasoline on those flames.
Speaker 8:  And it could really have terrible consequences for some really
Speaker 8:  vulnerable communities here in the US and around the world.
Speaker 5:  We were talking about corporate lobbying, and I just think back to
Speaker 5:  the story my colleague Drew Harwell and I did a year or two ago about meta
Speaker 5:  hiring this Republican political firm to go out and smear
Speaker 5:  TikTok in local news across the country, which they were able to do quite
Speaker 5:  successfully. We know that they are one of the biggest lobbyists in
Speaker 5:  DC political reported that they had outspent many other companies, most
Speaker 5:  other tech companies in terms of lobbying dollars. What role
Speaker 5:  is meta playing in all of this? Because they love to say, well, we haven't
Speaker 5:  actually asked for an outright ban, but I can't imagine what else this
Speaker 5:  type of lobbying would lead to.
Speaker 8:  Absolutely. I mean, meta has been incredibly aggressive at
Speaker 8:  trying to attain total monopoly status. Their
Speaker 8:  MO has been, they either buy or try to kill off
Speaker 8:  any competitor that comes along that poses a meaningful challenge to their
Speaker 8:  dominance. And they have absolutely been behind some of this
Speaker 8:  sentiment and attacks on TikTok. I just saw on TV the other day,
Speaker 8:  the head of the Chamber of Progress, which is one of the sort of lobbying
Speaker 8:  front groups that works for Meta and other big tech companies coming
Speaker 8:  out in support of this bill that would ban TikTok even though they push
Speaker 8:  back against basically every other type of regulation that
Speaker 8:  could actually meaningfully address this issue like antitrust laws for
Speaker 8:  example. And so again, that really just exposes the fact that
Speaker 8:  this is not really about addressing concerns, it's about
Speaker 8:  entrenching US dominance. And frankly, it could lead to a world where
Speaker 8:  we have an even more concentrated tech market in the us which would
Speaker 8:  be insane. And again, exposes some of the hypocrisy here. Joe Biden
Speaker 8:  has been very outspoken about how there's too much power in the
Speaker 8:  hands of these big corporations and we should break them up and you know,
Speaker 8:  pass antitrust reforms and take on big tech. And in the meantime, he's
Speaker 8:  basically saying he's gonna sign a bill that would kill off
Speaker 8:  one of Facebook's biggest competitors and lead to even less
Speaker 8:  choice and less options for us consumers who wanna find a place
Speaker 8:  online to express themselves.
Speaker 5:  And a huge reason why musically was forced to sell to Bite Dance in
Speaker 5:  2017 is because it was having an increasingly difficult time going up
Speaker 5:  against Meta and Instagram musically was being run dry
Speaker 5:  by Instagram, who was poaching all of music, Lee's top talent, cloning a
Speaker 5:  lot of their video features, and musically at that time
Speaker 5:  did not have the resources to compete with Meta part. That is part of the
Speaker 5:  reason it sold to such a big company. And you know, as the Wall Street Journal
Speaker 5:  reported, TikTok spent a billion dollars in app download marketing just to
Speaker 5:  sort of get that initial traction and boost after the rebranded 2018.
Speaker 5:  So that is the level of resources that you have to have
Speaker 5:  to go up against these tech giants. And I think it's quite telling that
Speaker 5:  the only app that can even remotely give meta and Google a
Speaker 5:  run for their money has to be backed by another giant
Speaker 5:  multi-billion dollar tech conglomerate because that's the level of resources
Speaker 5:  that you need to compete with this duopoly.
Speaker 8:  Well, what's even funnier too is that, you know, tiktoks format of
Speaker 8:  these short form videos is not actually brand new. That some of
Speaker 8:  you may be old enough to remember Vine, right, which was
Speaker 8:  basically killed off by meta when they revoked their
Speaker 8:  API access to intentionally crush a
Speaker 8:  competitor, right? And so we could have had a American owned
Speaker 8:  version of TikTok as apparently lawmakers say they want,
Speaker 8:  but because we have no meaningful anti-monopoly protections here in the
Speaker 8:  us, we allowed meta to kill off what could have become the US version of
Speaker 8:  TikTok. And so I think again, that just exposes that like these
Speaker 8:  discussions are not very serious right now, that there are real
Speaker 8:  measures we could take to address the concerns we have about the current
Speaker 8:  social media ecosystem. That's not what's being talked about in Washington
Speaker 8:  DC right now, unfortunately.
Speaker 5:  I think that is such a good point about Vine and I did a lot of reporting
Speaker 5:  on Instagram's aggressive moves to crush Vine
Speaker 5:  Court, their talent steal all of their video features. That was wild.
Speaker 5:  All right, Evan, well thank you so much for chatting with us today. I really
Speaker 5:  appreciate you taking your time. Where can people follow the work that you're
Speaker 5:  doing?
Speaker 8:  You can follow me on Twitter, blue sky
Speaker 8:  mastodon, Instagram, just find my name, Evan
Speaker 8:  Greer, E-V-A-N-G-R-E-E-R, and then go to fight for The
Speaker 8:  future dot org, which is the organization I help run. And you can learn about
Speaker 8:  our various campaigns protecting people's basic rights in the digital age.
Speaker 5:  Thanks Evan. Thank
Speaker 8:  You.
Speaker 5:  When we come back, we are gonna find out why Shrimp Jesus has taken over
Speaker 5:  Facebook and more
Speaker 5:  and we're gonna run through some stories from the week.
Speaker 15:  All right, hey, let's, let's do it. I put
Speaker 17:  100 people inside of a giant circle and whoever leaves the
Speaker 17:  circle last wins $500,000. But If, you touch the red line,
Speaker 17:  it's game
Speaker 5:  Over. I wrote a story about this this week, but Mr. Beast struck a deal with
Speaker 5:  Amazon MGM to produce a massive reality TV competition show.
Speaker 5:  This is pretty big news because it's Jimmy Donaldson's first foray into
Speaker 5:  traditional entertainment. The show is gonna be called Beast Games and it'll
Speaker 5:  feature a thousand contestants competing for a $5 million cash payout,
Speaker 5:  which is actually the biggest prize offered in TV history.
Speaker 5:  The Hollywood reporter said that Amazon outbid at least one other major streaming
Speaker 5:  service to land this deal. Mr. Beast has become the most subscribed to
Speaker 5:  individual on YouTube in recent years, and he has a massive audience of children.
Speaker 5:  He's really known for these outrageous stunts like burying himself alive
Speaker 5:  or recreating the show Squid Game as this reality TV style competition.
Speaker 5:  I think this is a really notable moment for the entertainment industry because
Speaker 5:  it shows how these streaming platforms are willing to pay a lot of money
Speaker 5:  to court these big online content creators in an effort to absorb some
Speaker 5:  of their audience. I think what remains to be seen is whether Jimmy
Speaker 5:  Donaldson's audience will actually hop over and watch this show on Amazon.
Speaker 5:  There's been a lot of other efforts to take internet talent and move them
Speaker 5:  into more traditional forms of entertainment, mostly linear TV or
Speaker 5:  traditional movies. And that has always flopped. He set his channel between
Speaker 5:  makes between 600 million and $700 million a year, and he
Speaker 5:  reinvests most of that back into his stunts, building
Speaker 5:  his channel and his media empire even more. So, who knows? I doubt that Amazon
Speaker 5:  will give him exactly the same production budget as he usually has, but maybe,
Speaker 5:  you know, they're, they're investing quite a lot in him and I'm sure they
Speaker 5:  want the show to be successful.
Speaker 15:  Amazon famously spends a lot of money on their shows
Speaker 15:  and really does a poor job of promoting them. I
Speaker 15:  haven't seen them with any like breakout reality or game shows.
Speaker 15:  A lot of their scripted stuff has, has just not done that well. They've,
Speaker 15:  they spent like a billion dollars on Lord of the Rings and it just
Speaker 15:  didn't really make a, make a splash. So I think a lot of stuff tends to
Speaker 15:  get buried on Amazon. Netflix has had quite a bit of success with
Speaker 15:  reality shows, game shows, stuff like that, that that seems like it probably
Speaker 15:  would've been a better fit for him audience wise. I'm sure Amazon
Speaker 15:  outbid whoever they were up against. But you know, the thing
Speaker 15:  that happens over and over again is when your audience is in one place,
Speaker 15:  it's really hard to get them to another place.
Speaker 5:  Well, he's also not stopping production on YouTube, right? So he's gonna
Speaker 5:  continue to post on YouTube throughout this deal. And
Speaker 5:  so yeah, it just remains to be seen whether the audience will hop over
Speaker 5:  and also watch on Amazon. That said, I mean, other, other
Speaker 5:  children's shows have had success. Coco Mellon jumped over.
Speaker 5:  It's more of a sort of cartoon children's
Speaker 5:  series and Mr. Beast audience is also children. So, you know, If, you can
Speaker 5:  plop your child down in front of the TV and turn on the Mr. Beast game show
Speaker 5:  for an hour and distract them. I, you know, maybe,
Speaker 15:  And I, I do feel like every parent I know has Amazon, like If. you have
Speaker 15:  kids, you probably have an Amazon subscription, so it,
Speaker 15:  it's, it's all right there for you potentially.
Speaker 5:  If you've been on Facebook at all recently, you might have noticed that more
Speaker 5:  and more AI generated images are creeping into your feed. These images can
Speaker 5:  be strange, bizarre sometimes they're very beautiful and they're usually
Speaker 5:  posted by anonymously run pages. But since last week, one
Speaker 5:  specific type of image has become pervasive and that is AI generated
Speaker 5:  portrayals of Jesus Christ made out of live shrimp. These pictures
Speaker 5:  are really crazy and slightly grotesque, and they've been generating a massive
Speaker 5:  amount of likes and shares every single time they're posted shrimp. Jesus
Speaker 5:  is actually just the latest engagement hack by these spammy types of pages,
Speaker 5:  doing what's called engagement farming. Basically they're posting something
Speaker 5:  so bad and crazy and absurd that it makes people stop, comment, or
Speaker 5:  share. This then pushes that page's reach up and allows them
Speaker 5:  to get other content more easily into your feed. After they
Speaker 5:  boost their reach with shrimp Jesus, they start pushing other low quality
Speaker 5:  content into your feed, like fake news websites full of Google ads, or
Speaker 5:  they try to sell you low quality products. This is how they effectively monetize.
Speaker 5:  So when you see these really weird AI generated images all over, you might
Speaker 5:  just think that they're fun or weird or being shared all in good fun.
Speaker 5:  This is all actually part of a big moneymaking scheme that's increasingly
Speaker 5:  common on Facebook.
Speaker 15:  Honestly, I get the rubber necker approach to this. Like, you're, you're
Speaker 15:  cruising through Facebook and then you just halt and you, you share or you
Speaker 15:  comment. What the fuck is going on? Seeing Jesus as a shrimp, is
Speaker 15:  it, it is uncomfortable to look at this image.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's quite terrifying. I think scammers are always ahead of the game
Speaker 5:  when it comes to what performs online. I've seen a lot of other AI
Speaker 5:  character driven pages as well on Facebook, which are essentially
Speaker 5:  anonymously run pages that purport to be a specific person. I saw
Speaker 5:  one woman saying, I'm 120 1-year-old baker
Speaker 5:  and I love to bake these peachy confections, and it's just
Speaker 5:  AI generated images of this old woman
Speaker 5:  and various types of cakes. Yeah. And this whole Facebook page
Speaker 5:  is ostensibly supposed to be run by this
Speaker 5:  120 1-year-old woman, which I think would make her the oldest woman in the
Speaker 5:  world. Yeah, and it's, it looks so obviously fake, but the comments
Speaker 5:  on the post make it seem like, I don't even think people really care.
Speaker 5:  I'm currently reporting on a similar phenomenon on Instagram, so my story
Speaker 5:  will be out soon. But I really do think that we're just seeing more and more
Speaker 5:  of this AI engagement bait all over the internet.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. Boomer bait
Speaker 5:  Also happening on Facebook. Meta redesigned aspects of the app to
Speaker 5:  emphasize the poke button, again, for people that don't remember Poke was
Speaker 5:  this really popular feature back in the aughts where you could really just
Speaker 5:  send little pokes to people, which just, you'd just get a little message
Speaker 5:  saying, I poked you. Or, so-and-so poked you. This redesign
Speaker 5:  apparently works 'cause there's been a 13 x jump in use of the feature. I
Speaker 5:  think this is just Facebook trying to bait people into engaging on the
Speaker 5:  app in any way that they can. I think there's tons of nostalgia
Speaker 5:  for the aughts, especially among millennials. Nostalgia stuff plays really
Speaker 5:  well. This is a feature that a lot of millennials associate with their
Speaker 5:  youth back when we had Facebook in college and would poke each other and
Speaker 5:  things in our dorm, and so I think this is kind of a, a naked
Speaker 5:  play for engagement. Zuckerberg posted after they announced the uptick
Speaker 5:  in the feature that quote, nature is healing.
Speaker 15:  I don't know why we need this. I, I don't use Facebook anymore, so
Speaker 15:  it's not for me, but I don't know why we need this. And it, it just feels
Speaker 15:  like an excuse for more notifications and I'm just like
Speaker 15:  pretty Anti notification at these at this point.
Speaker 5:  Me too. I have all my notifications turned off.
Speaker 15:  Same
Speaker 5:  LinkedIn, which recently surpassed a billion users and is primarily known
Speaker 5:  as a place to find your next job, is now trying to court gamers in an effort
Speaker 5:  to boost time on the platform. They're rolling out in-app games. The company
Speaker 5:  is testing three puzzle type games so far, and I think this
Speaker 5:  move is really smart because it taps into the puzzle mania that helped other
Speaker 5:  platforms like the New York Times Boost engagement with things like Wordle
Speaker 5:  and Connections. I know people that play every day. Facebook also launched
Speaker 5:  Farmville back in 2009, and time spent on the platform skyrocketed.
Speaker 5:  I think a lot of these social media companies have integrated gaming aspects
Speaker 5:  over the years with quite positive results. It's also worth noting
Speaker 5:  that the company is owned by Microsoft, a gaming giant that made over
Speaker 5:  $7 billion last quarter in gaming alone. So this just
Speaker 5:  seems like smart synergy and if people can spend a little bit more time on
Speaker 5:  LinkedIn playing Word games or whatever, that's good for the company.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. I totally get why LinkedIn would wanna do this
Speaker 15:  and why it makes business sense, but if you're spending a ton of time
Speaker 15:  on LinkedIn playing games, I don't think you're using LinkedIn correctly.
Speaker 15:  You're probably not finding that new job you're after, you know?
Speaker 5:  But that's not really what LinkedIn is anymore. I mean, LinkedIn is a pretty
Speaker 5:  robust social network. People spend a lot of time on their
Speaker 5:  learning and yeah, talking with people and sharing news.
Speaker 5:  Since Twitter declined, LinkedIn has become a huge hub for news and
Speaker 5:  information. People go there in the morning, you check in on your LinkedIn,
Speaker 5:  see what your connections are up to. It's not only looking for work, obviously
Speaker 5:  that's sort of was the initial point of the platform, but I do think
Speaker 5:  it's sort of just this robust professional networking platform
Speaker 5:  now.
Speaker 15:  Yeah, I, I've had LinkedIn probably 12 years. I don't think I've
Speaker 15:  ever had a shred of fun on that platform, and I think
Speaker 15:  it's useful. I think it's like super useful and yeah, I wouldn't
Speaker 15:  associate it with games.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think it's smart because it keeps people engaged. Yeah. You might
Speaker 5:  be on LinkedIn, networking, chatting, sending some
Speaker 5:  messages, waiting for some messages to come through and wanna play a
Speaker 5:  crossword or puzzle or something, you know? Yeah. I think it makes sense.
Speaker 5:  As you mentioned, it's not always the most entertaining platform. Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has a lot of staking in gaming and this makes sense.
Speaker 15:  Yeah. This reminds me of a tweet I saw that was like the New York Times.
Speaker 15:  You mean that place where I play my little games? It's like maybe that's
Speaker 15:  LinkedIn's future.
Speaker 5:  Alright, that's the show. If. you like this episode, give us a rating and
Speaker 5:  review on Apple Podcast, Spotify, or wherever you listen. Power User
Speaker 5:  is produced by Travis Uch and Jelani Carter. We were mixed and mastered by
Speaker 5:  Brendan McFarland. Our video producer is Brandon Keefer. You can watch full
Speaker 5:  episodes on my YouTube channel at Taylor Lorenz. Our executive producers
Speaker 5:  are Zach Mack and Nisha Kwa. Power User is part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 5:  network. We'll be back next week. See you then.