# Transcript
ID: e950ce8c-21d3-442d-ae68-2567a8b469db
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4917376285661670513/-1981826924065510981/s93290-US-5063s-1714721567.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss this week's tech and gadget news.
Speaker 5:  Hello And Welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast of David. Finally
Speaker 5:  admitting it's just a three.
Speaker 5:  That's what we're known for here. Just being broken down
Speaker 5:  and saying, you know what three, I'm your friend Neli. This
Speaker 5:  is Alex Cranz. I'm thinking
Speaker 7:  What a two is.
Speaker 5:  That's on fire.
Speaker 5:  David Pierce is here. My The Verge is very own three. David Pierce.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  That's, listen, I've heard worse, I'll take
Speaker 5:  It. No, David, you're attending all of our hearts,
Speaker 5:  especially now that you've admitted the truth
Speaker 5:  Lots. Talk about the show. David reviewed The Rabbit R one, which, that's
Speaker 5:  the whole show. That's two hours right there. Yeah. We have what we're calling
Speaker 5:  a money round. There's a bunch of money news to be talked
Speaker 5:  about, including LinkedIn adding games. When you think
Speaker 5:  about money, a bunch of gadget stuff. There's some Pixel eight A leaks, there's
Speaker 5:  an iPad event next week or what we assume is an iPad event next week.
Speaker 5:  We gotta talk about that. Can do some preview of that. And then of course
Speaker 5:  the lightning round.
Speaker 5:  The Verge is very enlightening round
Speaker 8:  Still woefully unsponsored, very upsetting.
Speaker 7:  Pixar should sponsor it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. See any, any number of
Speaker 7:  Companies. Lightning the Queen Round. Come on. It's right there
Speaker 5:  As a man who for obvious financial reasons needs to
Speaker 5:  sell his raptor. The Ford Lightning is right there.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 7:  True. Just right there.
Speaker 5:  Alex, I haven't talked to you about this yet. I, we, we have to get rid of
Speaker 5:  the pickup truck. It was my Mountain Adventure pandemic binky pickup truck.
Speaker 5:  And that's
Speaker 7:  Gotta go. And now you're like, you live far too close to New York now to
Speaker 7:  own a pickup truck
Speaker 5:  Basically. Yeah, it is incompatible with my neighborhood.
Speaker 7:  It's Can you, can you, like how many points is a turn in
Speaker 7:  in the street?
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's, I'm just knocking over houses.
Speaker 5:  I'm just like, whatever. I'll pay the fine.
Speaker 7:  It's fine. No one has a post off post box anymore.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's all, it's all over. But I'm just saying we, we
Speaker 5:  didn't call it the wrapped around
Speaker 5:  we could Jim Farley, CEO Ford,
Speaker 5:  who's clearly in charge of the podcast marketing budget,
Speaker 8:  We will name the lightning round after any car. That's, I'm not, I'm not
Speaker 8:  above that for a price. I would call this the Kia Forte round
Speaker 8:  and it would be no problem.
Speaker 7:  Okay, nevermind. Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 5:  Again, the, the conceit of the lightning round is, it goes fast. It actually
Speaker 5:  never goes fast. Anyway, we're gonna get to it. The Kia
Speaker 8:  Forte round. I'm telling me
Speaker 5:  It, it's right there. That's a music term. I think that it
Speaker 7:  Goes. Okay. And then we have to this
Speaker 5:  If you can steal it to. We have, you can steal the lightning round,
Speaker 5:  but, but yeah, we're gonna be there in like 45 minutes. If you. If between
Speaker 5:  now and then you can convince your CMO to sponsor it. Give us a call. There
Speaker 5:  we go. Liam is waiting for you. Alright, let's start with the news. The
Speaker 5:  news. The Rabbit R one was released. David, you went to the
Speaker 5:  party, you talked about it last week on the show, how you felt about the
Speaker 5:  thing this week. You've written a review. I don't think if people in the
Speaker 5:  Vergecast audience are paying attention to the gadget ecosystem, I don't
Speaker 5:  think your review is surprising because there was no embargo. People
Speaker 5:  just got them. It was only people who bought them that had them. They were
Speaker 5:  just talking about it. The, the problems have been obvious the whole time,
Speaker 5:  but the, and I think Marquez was like, this product is almost
Speaker 5:  unreviewable. It is so broken. But you did it, you actually reviewed it,
Speaker 5:  you gave it the score. The whole, the full VERGE organized review
Speaker 5:  treatment.
Speaker 5:  It didn't seem to go well.
Speaker 8:  It didn't go well. It's been a very funny experience because I think
Speaker 8:  coming at this after the Humane experience, which was sort of a
Speaker 8:  normal like high-end gadget review experience where they give it to a
Speaker 8:  group of people, it's under embargo. It's a very sort of secretive thing.
Speaker 8:  People are not talking about it on social. There's like not tons of
Speaker 8:  sort of real time feedback coming from people. And then this comes out and
Speaker 8:  Rabbit just hands it out to hundreds. And then the day after, what seemed
Speaker 8:  to be thousands of people, like I picked mine up at that event last Tuesday
Speaker 8:  night and people started getting theirs in the mail like on
Speaker 8:  Wednesday. And these are just users. Like I bought one, I
Speaker 8:  bought one in order to get it to review everybody who has one bought one.
Speaker 8:  And it turns out a bunch of people who have spent
Speaker 8:  months being really excited about this thing that has been super hyped as
Speaker 8:  like a cool way to use AI to get stuff done and feels like the future. And
Speaker 8:  a Star Trek communicator. And then you take it out and you say, order me
Speaker 8:  a ride. And it says this app is gonna take a long time to load and then fails.
Speaker 8:  Turns out that sucks. And so it's been a really interesting experience over
Speaker 8:  the last, what, nine days since it came out, watching people
Speaker 8:  go through basically the same process I have, which is you start with, oh
Speaker 8:  this thing is fun, it's cute, it's whimsical, it's adorable. And then
Speaker 8:  you use it for a couple of very straightforward things and it does those
Speaker 8:  things. Okay.
Speaker 8:  For days it didn't know what time it was. Mine would tell me
Speaker 8:  the time if I asked, but it was, was three hours off. And because rabbit's
Speaker 8:  AI is like trying to be very clever, it wouldn't let you set the time zone
Speaker 8:  manually. It also you would ask at the weather and it would just invent
Speaker 8:  a place for it to be. There were a couple of people in the office at The
Speaker 8:  Verge who have seen this and were asking it. And I at one point asked three
Speaker 8:  times in a row sitting in my basement in Washington DC and it
Speaker 8:  gave me the weather for New York, Philadelphia and Budapest.
Speaker 5:  No, three
Speaker 8:  Times in
Speaker 5:  A row. The third one's a wild card. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's like, alright.
Speaker 5:  At least the other ones were former capitals of the United States.
Speaker 7:  Maybe it just really like
Speaker 5:  Budapest never, I think George Washington never went to Budapest as
Speaker 5:  far as I'm aware,
Speaker 8:  As far as I can tell. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I can't even think of what the, the similarity between those three
Speaker 7:  cities is.
Speaker 5:  Well I'm saying there is one. Three of them are former Capitals seats of
Speaker 5:  the United States government. Two of them.
Speaker 8:  No, no.
Speaker 5:  That that thing
Speaker 8:  You just did ascribes way too much thought and intelligence to what is
Speaker 8:  actually happening on this
Speaker 5:  Place. There're just places where Ben Franklin was hammered. That's fine.
Speaker 9:  Ben. Ben Franklin hammered in Bud. That's
Speaker 5:  All I said.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, so I go through this whole process and, and by the, by the time
Speaker 8:  I'm actually sitting down to be like, what is the story of this
Speaker 8:  device? It's both that it is
Speaker 8:  so woefully under baked. Like they've been promising really
Speaker 8:  interesting stuff since the beginning. Right. And we, we made a lot of fun
Speaker 8:  of Humane for a year for just the weirdness of that device.
Speaker 8:  But Rabbit just kind of came out and they were just like, here's the thing,
Speaker 8:  here's what it does. It's a fun toy, it's $200. And it's like, okay, that
Speaker 8:  actually, that might be something. And they just didn't do it. Yeah. They
Speaker 8:  just didn't build the thing. They told us they were gonna build it.
Speaker 5:  So I'm gonna ask the same question I asked about the Humane pin, which
Speaker 5:  a lot of listeners have just been asking us as though we know
Speaker 5:  why did they ship this this way?
Speaker 8:  I I have a lot of theories about this. Yeah, I
Speaker 8:  don't, the answer is I don't know. And I, I will say the, the most
Speaker 8:  specific answer is I don't know why they shipped it now and not
Speaker 8:  in three months. Like I can tell you why they shipped it now and not in 12
Speaker 8:  months because inventory is expensive. You have to make
Speaker 8:  decisions on what you buy and when way in advance.
Speaker 8:  And actually to like, make a bunch of stuff and then stick it in a warehouse
Speaker 8:  and then update it, repackage it and ship it is like wildly expensive.
Speaker 8:  And so the, like, once you've started the logistics train, it's really, really,
Speaker 8:  really hard to stop it. So I think that's the simplest reason. It's like
Speaker 8:  everybody made this date call a long time ago
Speaker 8:  and didn't finish building the thing before it had to ship. And
Speaker 8:  rather than eat the like very real cost of
Speaker 8:  delaying it a few months, they just shipped the unfinished thing and said
Speaker 8:  big stuff coming this summer. But both Humane and Rabbit have
Speaker 8:  been out there being like, oh yeah, tons of stuff coming. Jesse
Speaker 8:  Lou, the CEO of Rabbit stood in front of the screen showing the roadmap and
Speaker 8:  it has this big long list of stuff that absolutely needed to be there on
Speaker 8:  day one that is coming, quote unquote this summer, while I was using the
Speaker 8:  device on Tuesday, they shipped a big software update that
Speaker 8:  fixed the time zone thing. So my Rabbit now reliably knows what time it
Speaker 8:  is, which is very exciting and like kind of fixed the weather. It doesn't
Speaker 8:  give me Budapest anymore, but it also gives me like 20 miles from my house.
Speaker 8:  So we're like, we're getting there and that, but that's the kind of stuff,
Speaker 8:  oh, it also fixed the unbelievably disastrous battery life that
Speaker 8:  this thing had. Like if I sat here and just used it for 60 minutes, it
Speaker 8:  died. And if I just turned it on, put it on my desk and didn't touch it,
Speaker 8:  it would die in six hours. It, I mean it was unbelievably bad
Speaker 8:  and it's much better now. The the, it still is like a one day
Speaker 8:  device. Even If, you don't touch it at all, which is still pretty bad, but
Speaker 8:  it's better. But this is the stuff that is just like literally inexcusable
Speaker 8:  to ship to people who paid for your device. And
Speaker 8:  I'm, I'm sensitive to all of the business reasons that that is hard to
Speaker 8:  guess. AI's changing really fast. These companies don't have infinite
Speaker 8:  amounts of money and supply chain victories. But you
Speaker 8:  just can't, you just can't do it.
Speaker 7:  I mean, people have lobbed a lot of like really negative
Speaker 7:  assessments at Jesse Lou since this thing came out and has been kind of a
Speaker 7:  boondoggle for him, right? Like a lot of people are bringing resurfacing
Speaker 7:  the fact that he was formerly CEO of a company that promised NFTs
Speaker 7:  in the Metaverse
Speaker 7:  didn't deliver on that and then kind of moved over, which is not a,
Speaker 7:  not a really great look for him. And, and it is just like,
Speaker 7:  and I've heard, I've heard the accusations on Reddit just flying fast,
Speaker 7:  right? Saying that, that this was a grift, that everybody was just kind of
Speaker 7:  like misled into this thing that was clearly like a beta product
Speaker 7:  that they had no intention of thinking was real. And I don't, like, there's
Speaker 7:  no reporting behind any of this. This is just rumors, but the rumors are
Speaker 7:  furious.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. The, like Jesse is a grifter thing is a very real
Speaker 8:  thing that is floating out there. I think I, I forget what the name of the
Speaker 8:  law is, but it's never ascribed to malice what can be described by
Speaker 8:  incompetence. Right? Like that's what this is to me. Yeah. Like this is just
Speaker 8:  a startup that made a bunch of really big promises and didn't pull it off
Speaker 8:  that explains everything that is happening here. Right. Whether, and I think
Speaker 8:  frankly like that was the NFT thing. Everybody got really excited about this
Speaker 8:  huge thing that was happening. Thought it was gonna be really
Speaker 5:  Cool, thought they could buy it. No, that was grifting that I just,
Speaker 8:  Some of it was
Speaker 5:  Grifting that almost all of it. I just came from an event where they had
Speaker 5:  an NFT wall and everyone was like, ew.
Speaker 5:  Sure. Like were like
Speaker 8:  Now a lot of people
Speaker 5:  Were not. But back then
Speaker 8:  Saying you back then back I,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, because they're at the top of the pyramid.
Speaker 5:  I mean we were, I would, yes, I would point out that The Verge staff almost
Speaker 5:  universally was saying
Speaker 8:  Yes. Oh, I agree.
Speaker 5:  You. And then there was Richard Lawler who was saying you, but also in a
Speaker 5:  way that suggested I told you so. Like he, he was like pre I tell, I told
Speaker 5:  you so
Speaker 7:  Before they even announced what NFT meant. Yeah. Richard was
Speaker 5:  Like, I told you. So
Speaker 5:  those were the two reactions on our staff. Look, I I I
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm much more inclined to believe this is some Yeah. Like hardware
Speaker 5:  startup disaster at 1 99. It's like hard to grift
Speaker 5:  anyone.
Speaker 7:  Well, I mean if you're, if you're broke ass and you were like, this is gonna
Speaker 7:  be my cool gadget. Yeah. At 1 99, like, like a lot. Some people
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying if If you, if you're like in the Grifter game, you're, you're
Speaker 5:  trying to make more money than that's Yeah. At a pop. You know, the thing
Speaker 5:  that gets me is a lot of that conversation is related to
Speaker 5:  just the reality of these products. There were teardowns of the Humane AI
Speaker 5:  pin and The Rabbit R one from, I fix it this week. They're Android phones.
Speaker 5:  That's what they are. And people took that to be a
Speaker 5:  sign of the Grift.
Speaker 7:  That's not a
Speaker 5:  Sign. This thing is just running Android on a chip set that you can get
Speaker 5:  the Rabbit,
Speaker 7:  But so is your tv.
Speaker 5:  Right. But the and the Rabbit interface is really just an Android app and
Speaker 5:  you like smash those ideas together. Like this thing is broken, doesn't quite
Speaker 5:  work and it's really just Android phone. This is a grift and I, I think it's
Speaker 5:  actually quite important to pull those ideas apart. I agree. Because
Speaker 5:  like you just said, Alex almost everything is an Android phone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like your fridge probably is also an Android phone.
Speaker 5:  Everything is a time bomb. Everything is just
Speaker 5:  waiting to unleash Bixby upon you. Everything
Speaker 7:  Can run an a PK If. you try hard enough.
Speaker 5:  That's actually what whatever that, that's a law. Yeah. Alex's
Speaker 7:  Law, that's Alex's
Speaker 5:  Law. You can horsepower an AP k in almost anything these days. It would be
Speaker 5:  shocking to me if this thing wasn't running Android or
Speaker 5:  some commodity smartphone hard. Like that's what's cheap
Speaker 5:  at a, at a buck 99. Again, like maybe an
Speaker 5:  easier thing for them to have done would've been to buy a bunch of like
Speaker 5:  used Galaxy AER phones and put their app on it
Speaker 5:  because then at least they would've told the time reliably. Well
Speaker 5:  like it's, it's weird. Like the thing that I can't quite wrap my head around
Speaker 5:  is like if you're gonna build on top of the existing thing, which almost
Speaker 5:  everybody does, why didn't you get the easy parts for free?
Speaker 5:  Like why didn't you get, I know what time it is or I can do a GPS
Speaker 5:  lookup to pull the weather. That stuff is all in the operating
Speaker 5:  system. Yeah. Like not being able to tell the time is actually like I can't
Speaker 5:  quite wrap my head around. Even If you install like
Speaker 5:  the most open source version of A OSP Android open source
Speaker 5:  project on the most open dev hardware that exists.
Speaker 5:  It's not like clock doesn't come for the ride. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  that's the part I don't get. It's like all the energy got focused on the
Speaker 5:  hard part and they didn't take the free stuff for free. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It was like they're doing too much. Like nobody was there just going, no,
Speaker 7:  y'all we're doing too much. Let's, let's just, let's scale it back. We got
Speaker 7:  this really kick ass hardware. 'cause like in in your piece you talked about
Speaker 7:  it that the hardware is is is nice. It's, it's cool.
Speaker 7:  I tried one this week. It was really cool to handle. I expected the buttons
Speaker 7:  to be more, I expected everything to be softer. Yeah. Like the soft touch
Speaker 7:  plastic. But it wasn't, that was a bummer. I forgot where I was
Speaker 5:  Going. My new startup is 100% buying used Galaxy Aeries phones
Speaker 5:  installing chat GPT on them and being like, this is the future. Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  is more or less the piece Allison wrote this week. Right, right. But that's
Speaker 5:  the part. David, did they talk to you about this? Has Jesse said anything
Speaker 5:  about it? I know they put out one statement in response to people
Speaker 5:  leaking their A PK saying like, this isn't gonna work on your Android
Speaker 5:  phone calls, our cloud services, our open sourced version
Speaker 5:  of Android is heavily custom. All the stuff you would say. But there's just
Speaker 5:  a part where like not getting the basics for free is just really weird To
Speaker 5:  me. There's
Speaker 8:  A real fake it till you make it thing happening with this that I think
Speaker 8:  is what a lot of people on the internet are responding to. Right. Like would
Speaker 8:  that, that quote unquote source code leak basically showed that
Speaker 8:  rather than use some fancy AI thing,
Speaker 8:  Rabbit is actually just using this software called playwright, which is a
Speaker 8:  very well-known automation software. It's like If. you have a website that
Speaker 8:  you want tested out to see what works and what doesn't. And if all the
Speaker 8:  links go to the right place and so on and so forth. That's just like a thing
Speaker 8:  a business can run. I think it's owned by Microsoft. This is well-known
Speaker 8:  technology. It is like not hard to teach a computer to use a website.
Speaker 8:  Right. And and the idea that that's all Rabbit is doing really rubbed some
Speaker 8:  people the wrong way. But I think in general these
Speaker 8:  companies feel like they have to do the whole thing and really
Speaker 8:  reinvent the wheel or else you're just a smartphone and, and
Speaker 8:  we're in this moment now where I think the
Speaker 8:  next phase of this will be starting to push the two things back towards each
Speaker 8:  other a little bit more. We're gonna get smartphones that do more sort of
Speaker 8:  one touch AI stuff. We're gonna get devices that are more connected to your
Speaker 8:  phone. But if I'm Rabbit or Humane, you rewind
Speaker 8:  even a couple of years and what they're all saying is we have to do our own
Speaker 8:  thing, build our own platform, own the whole experience ourselves. Because
Speaker 8:  that's the only way for us to be successful. And I think If, you start with
Speaker 8:  that assumption. That is how you run into Holy
Speaker 8:  God, this is so much harder to do all of this than we thought. And it's how
Speaker 8:  you end up with devices like these. Like I think you can't take the Android
Speaker 8:  clock because people look at it and be like, that's the Android clock. Why
Speaker 8:  don't I just use my phone?
Speaker 5:  You could just not show the clock to people. Yeah. You
Speaker 7:  Change the ui. The Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm not talking about the old HTC flippy clock widget. Although if they
Speaker 5:  brought that back, that would be sick. That would be sick. It, I mean that
Speaker 5:  thing was iconic. So good. What is the most iconic Android widget of all
Speaker 5:  time? It's the HTC flippy clock. You cannot convince me otherwise. I would
Speaker 5:  agree. Or the circle clock from the T-Mobile G one. No, no, it's
Speaker 7:  The flippy
Speaker 5:  Clock. The flippy clock. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  When I think Android I think of that with like the background and everything
Speaker 7:  they
Speaker 5:  Had. Yeah. That weird cartoony vibe. Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Oh beautiful.
Speaker 5:  Let's just talk about all the Android phones now and how you could start
Speaker 5:  a start shipping little Android phones. But honestly I think
Speaker 5:  part of that is related, right? You're two years ago you're starting this
Speaker 5:  thing. You could say, all right, we're gonna ship an AI app
Speaker 5:  for people's phones and then you're run right into and then Apple and Google
Speaker 5:  won't let us 'cause that threatens their business. Right?
Speaker 8:  Right. And we're now in literal direct, exact precise competition with
Speaker 8:  those companies and the other best funded companies on planet earth.
Speaker 5:  Right. But now you can, like all the antitrust, that stuff that has happened,
Speaker 5:  alternative app stores, all this stuff. Now you can, like I kind of fully
Speaker 5:  expect to see a wave of startups that are like
Speaker 5:  Rabbit but an app.
Speaker 8:  Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Right. Without all the hardware noise to say like, look, you can just run
Speaker 5:  this on iPhone now 'cause Apple can't stop me. Or at least in the eu
Speaker 5:  I don't, you know, I don't know what's gonna happen with Google in that particular
Speaker 5:  way, but at least in the eu, apple now has to allow these alternative app
Speaker 5:  stores all stuff. And that is interesting to me. I dunno if it'll work, I
Speaker 5:  dunno if Apple's just gonna Sherlock everybody at WWC this year. But it
Speaker 5:  feels like the Rabbit and the Humane caught a moment and a vibe when they
Speaker 5:  were, no one could build an app like this on the app. Like Apple just
Speaker 5:  wouldn't let you ship that app. I'm confident,
Speaker 5:  especially 'cause they probably buy stuff and Apple wouldn't get a cut of
Speaker 5:  that money. Like there's a million reasons why Apple wouldn't let you ship
Speaker 5:  that app.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think that's right. Well
Speaker 7:  Also it would've been a crappy app. Like
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It wouldn't have worked for
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Right. Like, like the, the the the talent and, and what we really saw
Speaker 7:  the real success of the R one, the reason it's a three
Speaker 7:  and not a one or a two is because the hardware is nice.
Speaker 7:  Like because the hardware is Yeah. Like they, they did this go and the user
Speaker 7:  interface is pretty, it's not always pleasant. Yeah, it's fine.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But
Speaker 8:  It's like, it's fine. Yeah, it's fine. But
Speaker 7:  No, you're right. Yeah. Right. Like, like there was some some genuinely good
Speaker 7:  stuff there and it one had nothing to do with Rabbit. It frankly seems
Speaker 7:  primarily a teenage engineering did the good parts and,
Speaker 7:  and Yeah. Why like they just never would've made it as an app. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And their whole, their whole thing was we wanna be the next Apple, which
Speaker 7:  is enormously ambitious on, on an an easy day and
Speaker 7:  and their climate is like godly ambitious.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The fact that DoorDash just doesn't work on this thing and
Speaker 5:  Uber just doesn't work and Spotify is broken. It's like
Speaker 5:  you're Yeah. You could say it could, it should just be an app. But those
Speaker 5:  apps tend to work on phones. Yeah. But you can get food
Speaker 5:  from DoorDash on phones. You, you pretty
Speaker 8:  Successfully
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent of the time. DoorDash is like here your order is completed.
Speaker 5:  The fact that they shipped it broken with those integrations.
Speaker 5:  Jesse, I think he tweeted, he's like, my hope for this round of reviews is
Speaker 5:  a six. He actually tweeted the number that you was opening and it's
Speaker 5:  like, wow,
Speaker 7:  Did you use your product before you shipped it?
Speaker 5:  Like not giving yourself the seven is incredible. Right.
Speaker 5:  You're like world of no sevens. I'm not an eight, I'm a six.
Speaker 8:  It's tough. That's
Speaker 5:  Rough.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well I think about it like the Phil Libin who used to be the,
Speaker 8:  the CEO of Evernote and then was an investor now running, which is that cool
Speaker 8:  like video chat app. He said to me once a couple of years
Speaker 8:  ago, and I may have said this on the show before, but I think about it all
Speaker 8:  the time. He said, when I look at a product, my question is always
Speaker 8:  is this primitive or is this stupid? Because you can't fix
Speaker 8:  stupid, but primitive usually gets better. Right? He was like, if
Speaker 8:  If you and he was like the, the first iPhone like perfect, primitive, the
Speaker 8:  thing barely worked. But the minute you looked at it you were like, oh there
Speaker 8:  is, there is something inside of this. But if he was like, if I don't have
Speaker 8:  that reaction to this, if there is no
Speaker 8:  good version of this, it's just stupid. And I think where
Speaker 8:  I've come to is like, I think Rabbit
Speaker 8:  might be stupid in a way that I think Humane is just kind of primitive. Right.
Speaker 8:  Really. And I'm happy to have this argument with you and I would love to
Speaker 8:  have this argument with you. Yeah. I am still convinced that the idea of
Speaker 8:  a like an a wearable on body device that is
Speaker 8:  easier to access than your phone is something, I don't know how big that
Speaker 8:  something is gonna be. I would bet money it doesn't have a laser projector
Speaker 8:  involved at all. But like there is, there is some teeny tiny nugget of
Speaker 8:  AI wearable that I still find compelling. A handheld device
Speaker 8:  that isn't my phone that does everything my phone tries to do, but worse
Speaker 8:  I don't see it. And and there maybe there is some technological
Speaker 8:  AI miracle coming that makes these like large action model agents
Speaker 8:  work. And if so I look forward to being proven wrong on
Speaker 8:  this one. But like I don't see the runway for the R
Speaker 8:  one from what it is now to something that is like
Speaker 8:  genuinely interesting and different from my phone. So
Speaker 8:  that I will carry both of them. I just don't see it. Let
Speaker 5:  Me pull apart one idea in there and then I can disagree with you about the
Speaker 5:  rest. Okay. You mentioned large action models, which we have not really talked
Speaker 5:  about in the context of the R one, but when you think about these products
Speaker 5:  and how their companies are talking about them, Humane
Speaker 5:  are a bunch of stargazy, Naval Gazy
Speaker 5:  phones are ruining your life. Yeah. Right. Like just
Speaker 5:  stuff, just whatever, whatever that vibe is from Humane
Speaker 5:  big thinks thought leader stuff. Rabbit
Speaker 5:  is like, we made a large action model that we'll use computers for you on
Speaker 5:  your behalf, If, you give us your long end information, which is a very
Speaker 5:  like small idea in practicality.
Speaker 5:  It's a huge idea in the world, right? Right. It's the idea of you will have
Speaker 5:  an agent, but the actual idea is really quite small, which is why they could
Speaker 5:  fake it with playwright, which is just like user
Speaker 5:  testing software, right? Yeah. They're running a bot farm, they got a hundred
Speaker 5:  sausages waving at a hundred Android phones somewhere just used in computers
Speaker 5:  for you. I
Speaker 8:  Mean like that is so much closer to true than it should be. Like I just
Speaker 8:  like, that's a joke. But you're not all that far from describing
Speaker 8:  what Rabbit is actually doing here. What,
Speaker 5:  Right. But I'm saying on the, on the, on the split, right? If you,
Speaker 5:  if your idea is
Speaker 5:  is it primitive or stupid, the idea that okay, we're gonna automate the use
Speaker 5:  of a bunch of websites and we're starting with like a commercially existing
Speaker 5:  tool that already automates websites for you and we're gonna just try to
Speaker 5:  like fake it there until this large action model idea is ready. And then
Speaker 5:  we're just like gonna do a bunch of computer vision and horsepower our way
Speaker 5:  through the web.
Speaker 5:  Sure. That's the point. Right. But they're nowhere on that journey
Speaker 5:  except to have used some commercially available like user testing
Speaker 8:  Software poorly. But I would add like they attempted to use it but they didn't
Speaker 8:  do it. And that, that's where I land. Right. It's not there, there's one
Speaker 8:  thing where it's like, okay, we, we tried to do something and didn't quite
Speaker 8:  do it and then there's another one that's we promised you we we were gonna
Speaker 8:  do it and just didn't. And like yeah, that's, that's pretty hard to come
Speaker 8:  back from.
Speaker 5:  And then, but I'm saying then what Humane is selling is like you do not need
Speaker 5:  a phone. Your phone's killing you and we know it 'cause we
Speaker 5:  invented it. Which is an amazing thing. Beautiful. That's, you want to
Speaker 5:  be there, you're like those cigarettes were ruining you. I know this 'cause
Speaker 5:  I am Doctor Tobacco,
Speaker 5:  Please try this. Juul, which is the story of Juul, right? A
Speaker 5:  hundred percent. by the way, the story of JUUL is they hired a bunch of tobacco
Speaker 5:  scientists,
Speaker 5:  but Humane is like, we're we got you hooked and now we're gonna break it
Speaker 5:  by selling you our pin. That
Speaker 5:  promise is like even more nascent, right? Like the technology doesn't work,
Speaker 5:  but it also might be the wrong promise. That's like what I'm hammering on
Speaker 5:  here, right? Like the idea of the software agent will go use software in
Speaker 5:  your behalf seems more achievable than
Speaker 5:  we're gonna fully replace your phone.
Speaker 8:  Oh, I think that's right. I, I think I have in the course
Speaker 8:  of several weeks of talking to people kind of in and around Humane and
Speaker 8:  reviewing this device, I think even Humane is
Speaker 8:  slowly starting to give up on that vision. Interesting. I I think If,
Speaker 8:  you gave them a time machine and let them go back 12 months ago, they would
Speaker 8:  not start to tell the story about how your phone is killing you
Speaker 8:  and we need to take away from your phone. I think they
Speaker 8:  realize how deeply weird their entire
Speaker 8:  like marketing strategy was for a long time. And even If, you look at what
Speaker 8:  they've done publicly, like they've tried to sort of chill a little bit,
Speaker 8:  which I think is been good. But again, I, I do agree and this is, I think
Speaker 8:  the most consistent piece of feedback we get every time we cover one of these
Speaker 8:  devices is people saying, why would I use this over my phone? And the answer
Speaker 8:  is, you wouldn't and you're not going to anytime soon. And that just
Speaker 8:  is what it is. Right? And so I think if, if we just assume that as like ground
Speaker 8:  truth and at this point I do. Right. And I think that's why the Humane
Speaker 8:  price is so absurd. 6 99 plus a subscription
Speaker 8:  for a phone number and a text messaging system,
Speaker 8:  neither of which are attached to your actual phone number is like preposterous,
Speaker 8:  but still like boil it down even further. And it's just like the thing that
Speaker 8:  device is seems closer to being something to me
Speaker 8:  than what the R one is.
Speaker 7:  I I just, I think they're both stupid.
Speaker 8:  That honestly might be Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like, like I think like, like I don't think either one is primitive. I think
Speaker 7:  they're both,
Speaker 5:  I think David is just trying to justify giving one a four and one a three.
Speaker 7:  No, I, I get, I totally understand the three and the four. I was telling
Speaker 7:  somebody at the office earlier today 'cause I edited that review and I looked
Speaker 7:  at that through and I was like, Hmm, well you know, the Humane pen like promised
Speaker 7:  a bunch of stuff and badly delivered
Speaker 7:  Rabbit promised a bunch of stuff and didn't deliver at
Speaker 5:  All and nothing didn't do
Speaker 8:  Any of it, but it
Speaker 7:  Didn't catch on fire or physically harm David. That's
Speaker 8:  True. True.
Speaker 5:  I feel like we gotta recalibrate.
Speaker 8:  No, I think, I think you could make a fair argument that they both should
Speaker 8:  have been threes. There's no Yeah. Version of the argument that they both
Speaker 8:  should have been four, which is why I gave it a three. Like I, there's no,
Speaker 8:  I I hemmed and hawed on the AI pin and this one was easier. And
Speaker 8:  frankly, I think that simplest way to look at it is just
Speaker 8:  price and realistically for what these things do, they're both
Speaker 8:  too expensive. And I think what $200 means to somebody versus what $700
Speaker 8:  means to somebody, I don't know if you're buying one of these things, you
Speaker 8:  have disposable income anyway. Like, I don't know. I am perfectly
Speaker 8:  happy for everyone to yell at me about the score. I feel very good about
Speaker 8:  this score.
Speaker 5:  I feel fine about this score. Yeah. What I'm getting at is the, the Rabbit,
Speaker 5:  it's like a toy, right? It's 1 99. You can have it, it's broken. I buy so
Speaker 5:  much broken tech garbage all the time. Same. Sure. But the
Speaker 5:  idea of the human that you're gonna wear it, it's gonna be in your body.
Speaker 5:  This is the part where it's just like disagree with you. Right. That's fine.
Speaker 5:  Like, I think that will just be a watch.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  I, if any, if it's gonna be anything else, it'll be the meta glasses.
Speaker 5:  But like the little Star Trek communicator badge on my
Speaker 5:  curve of wearable bullshit, it's like, boy, I better hope
Speaker 5:  I'm wearing a shirt today. That's like,
Speaker 7:  Star Trek exists in a world where there are no toilets.
Speaker 5:  I'm also always wearing a shirt. I dunno why I picked that one. Like, I'm
Speaker 5:  not, like, I'm not doing Baywatch, you know,
Speaker 7:  Slow run
Speaker 5:  Run. But it's just like that thing, like, it, it is demanding in a
Speaker 5:  particular way that you adjust your wardrobe around it.
Speaker 5:  And I, there's just a part of me, it's like that's the part that's destined
Speaker 5:  to fail maybe, right? Is it, it goes here
Speaker 8:  Maybe. I think the answer is it's gonna be lots of things. Like I, I think,
Speaker 8:  I think a watch is gonna work for lots of people. I think glasses will work
Speaker 8:  for some people. They're not gonna work for me as somebody who doesn't wear
Speaker 8:  glasses or contact, the idea of wearing a pair of glasses all day is just
Speaker 8:  a non-starter for me. Like, I'm not gonna do it.
Speaker 7:  All right, Mr. Fancy pants with the nice eyeballs. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It's good. Sorry. Sorry y'all.
Speaker 5:  The next time I see you I'm shining my iPhone flashlight.
Speaker 5:  I dunno if that's gonna hurt you or anything. I just, just just will feel
Speaker 5:  good. Yeah, I appreciate
Speaker 8:  That. But no, I think, I think the answer can be lots of things, right? And
Speaker 8:  I, I think the, the, like the breast pin communicator thing is
Speaker 8:  also kind of weird. My honest bet is that the first thing
Speaker 8:  is gonna be headphones. Like I really sincerely believe that we're due for
Speaker 8:  like a giant explosion of AI stuff into your headphones
Speaker 8:  and it's gonna solve a lot of problems. Apple is, I think we're gonna get
Speaker 8:  to that faster.
Speaker 7:  Taking notes as you say that,
Speaker 8:  I said this on Tuesday's show, but my absolutely baseless unreported conspiracy
Speaker 8:  theory is that the AirPods Max are going to be AI products. And
Speaker 8:  that's why it's been so long since they've been updated.
Speaker 7:  Oh no. It's gonna be the pros.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. No, the maxes are big. They can have a big battery.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But I like, I, I don't know, I I, I remember the first time I put in
Speaker 7:  AirPod Pros and I like just asked my phone to do something through the
Speaker 7:  headphones and I was like, oh, this is magic. And like If, you can do that
Speaker 7:  like consistently and regularly. But I think also
Speaker 7:  to the other, to If, you pull that out further, what we were all really seeking
Speaker 7:  is a, a voice assistant.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And like, like AI is the buzzword, but actually we're just all
Speaker 7:  revisiting the voice assistant. And, and the R one does it
Speaker 7:  horribly, like sassy, the R one is so
Speaker 7:  sassy. Every time I asked it something it was like, hold on, let me think
Speaker 7:  about it. And I'm like, well, I paid for you. I mean, I didn't Parker did,
Speaker 7:  but still
Speaker 5:  Wow. Wow. I paid Chop chopped, I paid
Speaker 5:  get Nightmare restaurant customer chop. I
Speaker 7:  Am absolutely
Speaker 8:  Paid for this. One of my favorites is when you ask it to do something it
Speaker 8:  can't do normally it'll say like, I'm unable to do that. And then every once
Speaker 8:  in a while it will just say, I cannot set a timer.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 7:  Oh i's like, all right.
Speaker 8:  Excuse me. That's,
Speaker 5:  I look, I like the idea that Apple's gonna subsume this entire market. WWC
Speaker 5:  is coming up. We, I've heard now
Speaker 5:  drumbeat of ai, ai ai. I've heard someone actually
Speaker 5:  say to me, Tim Cook is putting a lot of pressure on himself to deliver AI
Speaker 5:  at this wwc. It's a real sentence I heard from someone who knows,
Speaker 5:  you gotta make Siri good.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, let's not kid ourselves. And
Speaker 7:  I think that's gonna be hard because the problem is
Speaker 7:  yes, large language models are very good at making these assistants
Speaker 7:  loquacious, but they don't make them smart. Yeah. Like, like
Speaker 7:  there's still the core problem of we don't know how to regularly interact
Speaker 7:  with a voice assistant in like a comfortable and normal way. Because you're
Speaker 7:  still gonna be like, Hey, can you say it? And you do the, you know, you do
Speaker 7:  the voice. Your Siri voice. What's your Siri voice? Neely.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I don't, I don't You don't have one. I've, I've remapped the action button
Speaker 5:  on my phone at chat GBT. Oh. Which is equally frustrating.
Speaker 5:  But do you,
Speaker 7:  Do you have to do like a special voice, like an intonation to get it to respond
Speaker 7:  to you properly?
Speaker 5:  No, I, we do it to the Google assistant in our house.
Speaker 7:  What's what's your Google assistant voice?
Speaker 5:  Loud.
Speaker 5:  Just loud. Just shouting across the Yeah. Just like,
Speaker 5:  I'm not gonna do it. 'cause they're gonna let off everyone's,
Speaker 7:  David, what's yours?
Speaker 8:  Mine's very sort of monotone. Yeah. And,
Speaker 8:  and
Speaker 5:  Careful. Yeah. You're talking to the robot like a robot.
Speaker 8:  I'm always just like, Siri, please remind me tomorrow at
Speaker 8:  9:00 AM to take out the trash before the trash
Speaker 8:  arrives. And then it says, and then it always is like, got it
Speaker 8:  added reminder. And I say thanks and it goes, I can't help you with that.
Speaker 5:  Cool. That's
Speaker 8:  Pretty good. I just wanna put a point on the Siri thing because I've spent
Speaker 8:  a lot of time getting like emails and posts from people being like, Apple's
Speaker 8:  gonna do this. Do you, you all know how long Apple has spent trying to make
Speaker 8:  Siri good. And do you know how bad Siri is? It's real bad. And and not
Speaker 8:  only would Apple have to take the state of the art in AI and put it inside
Speaker 8:  of Siri, it would have to make the state of the art in AI much, much, much,
Speaker 8:  much better in order to do the things that we are asking for. Like
Speaker 8:  there, there is no ex extent proof in the universe
Speaker 8:  right now that it is possible to build the kind of high quality
Speaker 8:  assistant we're looking for. Like I Siri will get better
Speaker 8:  when they plug in a large language model that just seems to be true. It will,
Speaker 8:  it won't be good just because Apple does that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The thing that I've been knocking around in my head
Speaker 5:  as I read these reviews of these devices, as I think about what's coming
Speaker 5:  at this next set of developer conferences, Google IO is happening around
Speaker 5:  the corner, confident we're gonna see a bunch of AI stuff from Google at
Speaker 5:  Google io, right? Yeah. Microsoft Build is coming out. It's all, we're gonna
Speaker 5:  see another round of AI stuff. There's a rumor out in the world that we're
Speaker 5:  gonna see GPT five soon, who knows? We're gonna see another
Speaker 5:  version of this. What all of them have to show us
Speaker 5:  is whether these things are getting intelligent.
Speaker 5:  'cause right now all they've shown us is they can fire out a bunch of language.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Loquacious not intelligent.
Speaker 5:  Right? And like I know people who talk a lot. It's like,
Speaker 7:  It's like I'm really good at being loquacious and not intelligent. Like
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I, I think that turn remain it just, we'll see. Well, it's just
Speaker 5:  not there yet.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 5:  And I, you know, you can, Sam Altman today was like, I'll spend as much money
Speaker 5:  as it takes to build a GI and it'll be worth it. It's like, dude, you,
Speaker 5:  it's like I can get on a horse and be like, fly and like throw money at the
Speaker 5:  horse. Like there's no proof that this thing can do that
Speaker 5:  thing. Right? Like, you haven't gotten there yet and you haven't even like
Speaker 5:  demonstrated that you're on the right,
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry. Pathway still seeing you riding a horse, throwing money on your
Speaker 7:  head. Why?
Speaker 5:  Why? God damn you.
Speaker 5:  I hate horses. I, in fact, I had a girlfriend in high school with
Speaker 5:  a horse and I realized I was very allergic to the horse. Oh.
Speaker 8:  Didn't you ride into your wedding on a horse?
Speaker 5:  I did.
Speaker 8:  Did you, did you just sort of make it ran money off of the horse while you
Speaker 8:  rode into the
Speaker 5:  Wedding? I was, I was just screaming flying. God,
Speaker 5:  that's funny. If you're a horse person, you're listening to Bird Cha, first
Speaker 5:  of all, how, what Venn Diagram led you to us. Please let us know. You
Speaker 5:  can email us at Alex Cranz at the berg com,
Speaker 8:  But also we love you,
Speaker 5:  But also you're great. I'm so, I'm sorry that personally it's the
Speaker 5:  horse thing for me is a real problem. Anyway, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 5:  That's a good, as good a place to end it as any.
Speaker 5:  We'll be right back with the money ground. We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 5:  We're back with the money Round
Speaker 5:  Fly. It was when I was in college, there was a parking garage by my house
Speaker 5:  and it had a big sign that said Cash Lane
Speaker 5:  and my friends and I, we were like, we gotta make that cool. Somehow we're
Speaker 5:  in the cash lane like and we If. you can figure it out. Let me know. I don't
Speaker 5:  know if that parking garage is still there but all might have been torn down.
Speaker 5:  It was 20 years
Speaker 8:  Ago. Also If, you would like to generate an AI image of Neli in the cash
Speaker 8:  lane and send it my way. I would very much appreciate that. Please do
Speaker 5:  It if and If, you run a bank and you'd like to sponsor this, the cash lane
Speaker 5:  round.
Speaker 5:  That's cool. I feel like the banks aren't really promoting the
Speaker 5:  idea of cash anymore.
Speaker 7:  They're not fans.
Speaker 5:  They don't use Cash If, you run Cash App
Speaker 5:  and you or Jack Dorsey, you should just come on the show. We have a number
Speaker 5:  of questions for you sir.
Speaker 5:  All right. Money round. There's kind of a lot of money floating around.
Speaker 5:  Let's, let's stay in the AI for one second. A bunch of sort of like
Speaker 5:  search AI money move in the one Google's
Speaker 5:  antitrust trial, which we have not talked a lot about because it has been
Speaker 5:  very shrouded in secrecy. We have talked about that Google has done a good
Speaker 5:  job sort of shrouding its trial in secrecy. It is now barreling towards
Speaker 5:  closing arguments in the search antitrust trial like
Speaker 7:  Today, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we're covering that and a bunch of documents have been released
Speaker 5:  'cause various news organizations have basically been like filing motions
Speaker 5:  with the court being like, this is crazy. You've gotta release the evidence
Speaker 5:  in this case. So the New York Times and others have been filing motions to
Speaker 5:  get evidence unsealed in this case a bunch of other motions gone through
Speaker 5:  a bunch of documents sort of flooding out here at the end before closing
Speaker 5:  arguments. The thing that I think is most important,
Speaker 5:  we talk about some other stuff, is that we now have the number for how much
Speaker 5:  Google has paid Apple to be the default search placement on
Speaker 5:  the iPhone. It is $20 billion in 2022.
Speaker 7:  I'll be the default search on the iPhone,
Speaker 5:  Which is crazy. So much money that is a crazy amount of money.
Speaker 7:  Like so much money. Yeah, like more money than either of the two
Speaker 7:  companies we just talked about in the first round. Like have
Speaker 5:  Dream or will ever
Speaker 7:  Make
Speaker 5:  Probably. So the, you know, the argument here is if
Speaker 5:  you're running a search engine If, you have AI ideas, you
Speaker 5:  just need a lot of data and Google has gets a lot of data from
Speaker 5:  iPhone searchers or are clicking on things or picking results that helps
Speaker 5:  'em pick better results, obviously helps 'em serve a lot of ads. It's worth
Speaker 5:  a lot of money. Do we think that Google is making money
Speaker 5:  on the $20 billion it pays Apple?
Speaker 8:  Yes. It's a rev share. This, this is the thing that a lot of people miss
Speaker 8:  about all of this. This, this is not just like a flat fee that Google
Speaker 8:  pays to Apple. I don't know the exact details of it, but from a
Speaker 8:  lot of what we got in the trial, Google is sharing
Speaker 8:  revenue with iPhone,
Speaker 8:  using people with Apple. So if, if I'm
Speaker 8:  searching on my iPhone, apple is getting a percentage of that revenue from
Speaker 8:  me every time I use Google. Google wouldn't do this if it
Speaker 8:  wasn't profitable at this point. Sure. Google Google's market share is so
Speaker 8:  large and so substantial and a big part of the case that Google
Speaker 8:  is making is Apple saying we picked it because it is the best search
Speaker 8:  engine and not because there is some financial agreement
Speaker 8:  separately. Also there is a very lucrative financial agreement. But
Speaker 8:  this is a giant victory for both Apple and Google. And I
Speaker 8:  think the, the, the idea that's out there that Apple kind of has Google over
Speaker 8:  a barrel is just not true.
Speaker 5:  So two things there. One, if it's a rev
Speaker 5:  share, that means Apple's making a bunch of money on
Speaker 5:  Google's ad tracking,
Speaker 5:  which seems challenging for Apple to defend.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. At the same time that Apple is running around talking about how
Speaker 8:  insecure Android is for precisely that same reason.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So Apple's just collecting a bunch of money on the revenue Google makes through
Speaker 5:  Google search, which is entirely advertising based. Weird, just weird.
Speaker 5:  Fully, fully weird to consider. Second,
Speaker 5:  it is beneficial for Google to keep any
Speaker 5:  competitors away. I mean that's the heart of this trial, right? Yeah. Is
Speaker 5:  if Apple picked Bing,
Speaker 5:  whatever, there would instantly be another search engine at scale.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Google cannot afford that. So Yeah, sure. It's, it's making a deal
Speaker 5:  that works for everybody and it's probably making some money, but I suspect
Speaker 5:  even if it was losing some money, it would be worth it to keep another
Speaker 5:  search engine from emerging.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. Satya Nadella remembered last, whatever that was last fall. It feels
Speaker 8:  like ancient history now got on the stand and said he would've done it for
Speaker 8:  free just to get the queries coming from iPhone
Speaker 8:  users. Because better queries would've meant better results. Would've meant
Speaker 8:  better Ad placements would've meant more expensive ads. Would've meant more
Speaker 8:  queries. And like on and on and on and on it goes and
Speaker 8:  basically offered this whole thing, you can,
Speaker 8:  you can keep all the money Apple, we just want the searches.
Speaker 8:  And Apple said no. And that was a total non-starter for them. And
Speaker 8:  you're totally right. Like obviously it's a huge victory for Google to get
Speaker 8:  this and it's why, at least according to testimony, we've heard
Speaker 8:  Apple's share of that revenue has gone up over time.
Speaker 8:  But still, like Google, Google is not in the habit of
Speaker 8:  losing $20 billion to maintain its
Speaker 8:  place as the dominant search engine that everybody uses.
Speaker 8:  That's just, it just hasn't had to make that choice yet. And I don't think
Speaker 8:  this is that choice.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Google just likes losing money in other weird ways. Right?
Speaker 8:  Google likes to throw money at, at like roller skating executives trying
Speaker 8:  to build self-driving cars. Yeah. Not search ads.
Speaker 7:  I I was really surprised though by the part where they said that Apple's
Speaker 7:  like, or the 2020 payments that Google paid was
Speaker 7:  17.5% of Apple's operating income. That seems like
Speaker 7:  an awful lot. It's nuts. Am I like misunderstanding the numbers there?
Speaker 7:  Do I not understand business?
Speaker 8:  I mean that essentially means a a a and a fifth of
Speaker 8:  Apple's profit is coming from this deal because Apple
Speaker 8:  is pure profit. And Apple would tell you it's not that all the money that
Speaker 8:  they put into making the iPhone terrific is what makes that comfort. But
Speaker 8:  that's like a bunch of me mouth nonsense. It's it is pure profit to Apple
Speaker 8:  and it accounts for a huge amount of the money that that company makes.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that's just wild to me.
Speaker 8:  It's so much money
Speaker 7:  Like that Apple is that dependent on Google?
Speaker 5:  I don't know if it's dependency.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I I think that's where like, I'm like, do I understand business correctly?
Speaker 7:  'cause well
Speaker 5:  It is it in that if it went away, it would be a dependency
Speaker 5:  and maybe this trial will lead to some outcome in which it changes and the
Speaker 5:  money changes in different ways. But I think what
Speaker 5:  it actually speaks to is the, the phone market slowing down.
Speaker 5:  Apple itself is looking for whatever next thing will exist, right?
Speaker 5:  They just spent $10 billion on the car and shut it down.
Speaker 5:  They spent half of that Google money trying to build a car
Speaker 7:  One year of Google money.
Speaker 5:  Like literally the equivalent of Apple getting on a horse and screaming fly.
Speaker 5:  It just didn't work. Didn't work. You can't get in a midsize crossover and
Speaker 5:  be like, don't have a steering wheel. Like you can't do it. What Apple is
Speaker 5:  addicted to is monetizing every interaction you have on the phone. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. And this is, I has just led the company into
Speaker 5:  more and more perilous waters because that means a
Speaker 5:  bunch of people are now mad at Apple all the time, including a bunch of European
Speaker 5:  regulators, including our Department of Justice, what, whatever it is. But
Speaker 5:  the fact that Apple makes as much money as it does when
Speaker 5:  people merely search for things in the web browser,
Speaker 5:  it's
Speaker 7:  Insane. It's brutal. Yeah. Yeah. I think that was the like really
Speaker 7:  surprising part. You're just, anytime you type in, you're, you're helping
Speaker 7:  Apple make a shit ton of money. Right.
Speaker 5:  And I, you know, maybe that's fine and Apple's free to run its business
Speaker 5:  how it wants. Yep. But you can see that the, the chain
Speaker 5:  reaction of Apple saying it's our phone and every single thing you do
Speaker 5:  on our phone should generate revenue for us as the backstop
Speaker 5:  to the upgrade cycles are slowing. The phone market overall
Speaker 5:  is contracting, da da da, all that stuff. They hedged it by saying, okay,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna, we're gonna, everything on your phone is not being monetized.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna be aggressive with app developers. We're gonna have this deal
Speaker 5:  with Google everything. We're gonna shut down
Speaker 5:  ads with app tracking transparency, which is maybe a good thing. But then
Speaker 5:  we're gonna move the entire market of app install ads to the
Speaker 5:  app store and the app store gets, it's getting really weird. All of those
Speaker 5:  things are just them monetizing the software on the phone or the experiences
Speaker 5:  you have on the phone. Yeah. I think this trial is like shown us this is
Speaker 5:  real, you know, like it's, this is a real pressure Apple feels and
Speaker 5:  they're collecting a bunch of money from Google for the thing most people
Speaker 5:  do on the phone most of the time. Which is just like search for things in
Speaker 5:  the web browser. And then on the flip side, more
Speaker 5:  documents in the trial reveal. Microsoft is like terrified of this. And
Speaker 5:  they're looking at Google's investments in AI and what they can accomplish
Speaker 5:  there. They freak out and that's why they go invest in open
Speaker 5:  ai. Yep. Which you just see like Google's at the center of
Speaker 5:  a lot of things happening in tech right now. 'cause they're just throwing
Speaker 5:  money around. Google did have a good quarter this last quarter
Speaker 5:  like they did. Well it turns out people are still using Google search, but
Speaker 5:  you can see the threat it's under and you can see Google turning the
Speaker 5:  revenue lever on Google search to have
Speaker 5:  it make money instead of be good. Yep. More documents from the trial.
Speaker 5:  We should, ed Tron wrote Thiss, the title was the Man Who Killed
Speaker 5:  Google Search. And basically the thesis that story, which we'll link to is
Speaker 5:  the revenue teams at Google came to search and said we need to make more
Speaker 5:  revenue on search. The search team was like, no search is pure. And the
Speaker 5:  search team lost.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And we've all felt it
Speaker 5:  And we've all felt it
Speaker 7:  Like very keenly.
Speaker 8:  Well I think one of the things that has come up a bunch in this trial that
Speaker 8:  Ed also pointed out in his piece is that the question of
Speaker 8:  what does good search look like is
Speaker 8:  so mealy and hard to put your finger on that
Speaker 8:  literally what you are like goaling your team against
Speaker 8:  changes the way that you do business. Right? So If you, if you're Google
Speaker 8:  and you say, okay, the thing that we are going to measure is
Speaker 8:  number of search queries, the main thing we are going to do is make search
Speaker 8:  queries go up. Like s Phai always talks about this when he was running Chrome,
Speaker 8:  right? That the, the goal was the fastest web browser and they, they built
Speaker 8:  a bunch of things around that. But that was the goal. And so If, you run
Speaker 8:  towards the fastest web browser, you build a certain kind of web browser,
Speaker 8:  If, you run towards do the most searches. You're actually not
Speaker 8:  incentivized to make the search engine great because it means people
Speaker 8:  will actually search less because they found what they needed faster. But
Speaker 8:  in a certain way you also say, okay, if we get people to do more searches,
Speaker 8:  it must mean people like Google because they're doing more searches. And
Speaker 8:  both of those things are true. And yet they're completely mutually exclusive.
Speaker 8:  And, and I think this is what in, in a lot of ways seems to have happened
Speaker 8:  to Google as they got to the point where they were like, okay, we make money
Speaker 8:  when people do searches, we need people to do more searches. And so they
Speaker 8:  started spending money on deals like with Apple
Speaker 8:  and Mozilla and others they started changing the way that the
Speaker 8:  pages work and the results were delivered in order to get people to do more
Speaker 8:  searches. And that just sends you down a really ugly road.
Speaker 8:  You make people do more searches, but it actually, you don't care about
Speaker 8:  the experience as long as people are doing more searches. And that's just
Speaker 8:  that, that's what the thing that I think feels bad to people.
Speaker 7:  It's the what? What's Corey Dr. O call it in Ification? Yeah. I hate that
Speaker 7:  word, but it's a really good word. It's a
Speaker 8:  Good word. I wish he'd come up with a better term. Yeah. It's a, it's a very
Speaker 8:  useful like construct, but it's an awful word.
Speaker 5:  I love it.
Speaker 8:  Have you ever tried to type it? I can't. I have never once typed it successfully
Speaker 8:  on the first
Speaker 5:  Try. No. But by the time I get to around to being like, I should type this,
Speaker 5:  like 15 people have said it or typed it before I do. That's true. That's
Speaker 5:  'cause it's the default response to anything getting worse. Whether it counts
Speaker 5:  or not. 'cause specifically what Corey means is that most
Speaker 5:  web platforms products start by delivering a surplus of value
Speaker 5:  to you. 'cause they're all losing money at the beginning. Then they take
Speaker 5:  away that value from their advertisers. Right? They squeeze advertisers for
Speaker 5:  dollars, then that levers full, fully pulled and then they'd look at
Speaker 5:  you and they turn the knob away from you. Right. And like that's just the
Speaker 5:  cycle of the subsidized web platform.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that's what's Google's stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And you can, you can just see it with Google search. Like first they squeeze
Speaker 5:  the advertisers and then that is not great. So
Speaker 5:  now they're like, now it's you. You know the Google product
Speaker 5:  recommendations, the house fresh people. Yeah. They're,
Speaker 5:  they're starting to get more expensive. So you search for a product on Google
Speaker 5:  and they're starting to recommend you slightly more expensive products.
Speaker 7:  That part like shocked me. Yeah. Because they did a really good bar graph
Speaker 7:  there. Yeah. It was just really impressed with the bar graph and everything
Speaker 7:  was like red and and orange and showing it was really expensive. And then
Speaker 7:  the house fresh, which is at the very bottom, bright green, smallest bar.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We're always the cheapest. And I was respect it.
Speaker 5:  It turns out a fan blowing air through a filter is not necessarily an expensive
Speaker 5:  product.
Speaker 5:  Well to all of this stuff. But the point of this is like Google's
Speaker 5:  dominance of the ecosystem actually extends in every direction. Right?
Speaker 5:  It's pushing Microsoft to invest in open ai. One
Speaker 5:  of the documents here is Satya Nadela forwarding an email
Speaker 5:  from Kevin Scott, the head of AI explaining that Google's getting better
Speaker 5:  at stuff to the CFO of Microsoft. I mean like this is why I want to
Speaker 5:  invest in open ai. Like this is the reason. Here's, here's my, here's
Speaker 5:  my as the CEO justification to you as the CFO
Speaker 5:  of spending $13 billion over the next few years
Speaker 5:  to compete with Google. 'cause we see the opening and we're behind. And on
Speaker 5:  the other side, you see Apple just again,
Speaker 5:  a huge percentage of their incoming revenue. Right. Which is pure
Speaker 5:  profit basically. 'cause they're not doing anything
Speaker 5:  like that's a danger zone for them if this trial ends in some different thing
Speaker 5:  happening, like Apple starts to go off course. Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  is crazy to think about. Well
Speaker 7:  I think the thing that strikes me there is like
Speaker 7:  we've always talked, everybody talks a lot about how clever Apple is and
Speaker 7:  how good it is at making money and, and how good its products are and how
Speaker 7:  its products have really driven it to this place where it's really good at
Speaker 7:  making money. Does this kind of
Speaker 7:  like prove that wrong? The fact that they were making so much money off
Speaker 7:  essentially doing nothing.
Speaker 5:  I, it's like hard to begrudge Apple for being
Speaker 7:  Like, yeah, free money's free money. Like, you know, free money's nice. But
Speaker 5:  Like it just feels to me like no one eats for free in Tim Cook's house.
Speaker 8:  It does seem a little bit like the vibe of
Speaker 8:  Apple has shifted from like a bunch of geniuses around those
Speaker 8:  blonde wood tables. Desi designing stuff to like a handful of
Speaker 8:  unbelievably good negotiators. Yeah. Yeah. Winning deals. And like
Speaker 8:  that is the sort of mental picture that I have of Apple now is just
Speaker 8:  like Eddie Q and Craig Federighi just like rolling into
Speaker 8:  rooms being like, what's up losers?
Speaker 8:  I win
Speaker 7:  On a segue. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Out. I would point out that this is the other antitrust trial. Yes. Right.
Speaker 5:  That specific thing. How much power does Apple have? That's the DOJ
Speaker 5:  case against Apple.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, I don't know how that one's gonna go, but that thing, the vibe
Speaker 5:  you are describing, Eddie Q shows up to Hollywood, passes out in your boardroom
Speaker 5:  and you still have to give him a deal. Like there's reporting that
Speaker 5:  happened. I'm not just making that up. I dunno if that's true or not. There's
Speaker 5:  reporting that that's happened before and you still have to make the deal.
Speaker 5:  That's just Apple's power being expressed. Okay. So that's Apple. That's
Speaker 5:  the money stuff. That's money stuff. Apple, Google, Microsoft Money stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Other money stuff.
Speaker 7:  Less fun,
Speaker 5:  Less exciting. Peloton, which V just wrote a big
Speaker 5:  profile of, which was very prescient. Now she's like, what's up
Speaker 5:  with Peloton? The answer is nothing good. The CEO is quitting
Speaker 5:  and they're flying off more hundreds more people.
Speaker 5:  Which is weird. So the, the CEO Barry McCarthy joined Peloton, his
Speaker 5:  whole thing was that he was like a Netflix guy. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  Pelotons a subscription service. So he is gonna do a good job at the subscription
Speaker 5:  service.
Speaker 5:  He did not do that. Nope. He is
Speaker 5:  laying off 15% of the staff, which is about 400 people around the world.
Speaker 5:  That's the fifth round of layoffs.
Speaker 7:  Well, he's leaving
Speaker 5:  And by the way, last quarter he set on the earnings call, we're
Speaker 5:  done with layoffs and the ship is turning. He was
Speaker 5:  wrong.
Speaker 7:  Very wrong. Extremely wrong.
Speaker 5:  And then he's, he's leaving.
Speaker 5:  He took over from the founder who was a little more chaotic. He was supposed
Speaker 5:  to be the adult and now
Speaker 7:  It's two board members are now in charge, which is like, that's
Speaker 7:  never a good sign when it's like, yeah. Two board members are gonna be in
Speaker 7:  charge until we find a new CEO. Yeah. Ooh,
Speaker 7:  that's rough.
Speaker 5:  Peloton. Yeah. That who just got clipped.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yikes.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see what happens in Ton. It's obviously very sticky. People love
Speaker 5:  it that instructors are famous. You should go read v's. Piece and kinda
Speaker 5:  lays out what's happening here. Well re link it. It was from a few weeks
Speaker 5:  ago. Again, she saw this future coming. Yeah. by the
Speaker 5:  way, Barry McCarthy has never responded to request to be on decoder and I
Speaker 5:  suspect No, he never will. No,
Speaker 8:  I know why. I will say just two thoughts on that one. I think reading
Speaker 8:  the comments of that Peloton story was really interesting because the
Speaker 8:  number of people who drew a direct line from the
Speaker 8:  existence of Apple Fitness plus to the demise of Peloton is really
Speaker 8:  fascinating. I have no data on how successful Apple Fitness Plus is, but
Speaker 8:  just purely anecdotally speaking, like in my life and the people I know,
Speaker 8:  it's gone very well and I, and I think Fitness Plus, yeah, it's like it's
Speaker 8:  out there. It's like a thing people know about. It's not that expensive.
Speaker 8:  It's on your device. People who are like buying Apple watches are prone
Speaker 8:  to like that kind of thing. Anyway, it gives you the classes. It just seems
Speaker 8:  like Peloton maybe thought it had a moat
Speaker 8:  that it didn't, I think.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And add that to the, they got very excited because
Speaker 8:  everybody bought one during the pandemic and they said, oh, maybe this will
Speaker 8:  be our demand forever. Which was just an insane thing to
Speaker 8:  decide at that particular moment in time. But it, it's just interesting that
Speaker 8:  I think the question about Peloton has always been how do you take a thing
Speaker 8:  that is by all accounts very good and people really like and botch it so
Speaker 8:  spectacularly. And I think maybe I have underrated the extent to which
Speaker 8:  it has been kind of eaten alive by some of the other
Speaker 8:  products out there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean I think connected fitness is a thing v has
Speaker 5:  written about it. Yeah. Like people want these products. Peloton is a gold
Speaker 5:  standard brand though, right? It is. It is. People
Speaker 8:  Love Peloton.
Speaker 7:  I feel like the people who are using Apple Fitness are not necessarily the
Speaker 7:  same people who use Peloton. Like the people who use Apple Fitness are like
Speaker 7:  me, where every three months I'm like, this is the time
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna start working out all the time and become a total gym rat in my
Speaker 7:  house. That's who's using Apple Fitness. Right? It's people who are like,
Speaker 7:  this is easy. I can just hop into this. Peloton is like, I'm going to spend
Speaker 7:  thousands of dollars on this equipment. I'm going to have it in my home and
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna use it
Speaker 5:  And pay a subscription
Speaker 7:  Fee. Yeah. And pay a subscription fee. And it's, I think those are very kind
Speaker 7:  of different audiences
Speaker 8:  That could be Peloton is also stupidly expensive and has remained stupidly
Speaker 8:  expensive for way too long.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like $45 a month for our subscription. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's ridiculous. Like
Speaker 5:  I could pay for 10 HPO max
Speaker 8:  And
Speaker 5:  I will, it's not even true at this point. It's like one and a half HPO
Speaker 8:  Max
Speaker 5:  Speaking of boards, that should take a hard look at the CEO
Speaker 5:  EI
Speaker 7:  Already know who you're talking about.
Speaker 5:  Elon has gone quote absolutely hard core with Tesla layoffs.
Speaker 5:  He fired the entire supercharger team, including the people who are in
Speaker 5:  charge of refurbishing and installing new superchargers, which
Speaker 5:  seems very bad because everyone just signed up to use their connector.
Speaker 7:  Well, you heard the
Speaker 5:  Rumor, the a CS connector
Speaker 7:  For you did this. Why
Speaker 5:  Did you do this? So
Speaker 7:  The rumor is that the, the head of the supercharger unit
Speaker 7:  said, no, I, I like pushed back on the number of layoffs that she was asked
Speaker 7:  to do. And he was like, no, you're fired too.
Speaker 7:  Everybody on your team to prove a point to the rest of the team. That was
Speaker 7:  some of the reporting we saw this week.
Speaker 5:  And the point is, no one can do a good as job as
Speaker 5:  someone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I like, I I think it was, it sounds like the, the, the piece
Speaker 7:  was mainly about how he was really just pushing himself
Speaker 7:  out there and he's like, he's in charge and just reasserting his authority
Speaker 7:  after being at Twitter all this time and coming back in and being like, do
Speaker 7:  what I say and If. you don't wanna do what I say, you're gone and so is your
Speaker 7:  team.
Speaker 8:  Well that's a long running Elon Musk trend of of Right.
Speaker 8:  Wanting to be the shiny face on everything and demanding
Speaker 8:  to sort of disappear for a long time and then come back and exert total control
Speaker 8:  and then disappear for a long time. Again. That, that tracks with a lot of
Speaker 8:  what we've heard about his management style over the years. Yeah. Is there
Speaker 8:  something I'm missing in the why Tesla would slow down
Speaker 8:  its investment in Superchargers? Because everything I've understood about
Speaker 8:  this company, and I do not proclaim to be an expert in Tesla, would suggest
Speaker 8:  that actually the supercharger network is one of the things it should be
Speaker 8:  investing in the most.
Speaker 5:  Right. Especially because now there's expanding demand for it. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. Like If, you get Rivian and Ford and all
Speaker 5:  these other companies like using it BMW. Like you can't
Speaker 5:  name a company in North America that's not about to use NACS and sign a supercharge
Speaker 5:  deal. Right. If they're all coming online, like demand for supercharging
Speaker 5:  is gonna go up and they're gonna pay you money to
Speaker 8:  Use it. Does Deon Musk just like not want to be a gas station mogul?
Speaker 8:  Like, is that, is that just where we're landing?
Speaker 7:  I think that's why, why this, this theory that he did it to exert
Speaker 7:  his, his dominance essentially is, is so popular because like
Speaker 7:  it doesn't make sense. But then you'll hear the rumor about how Elon
Speaker 7:  always wants to be in charge. And it starts to, that theory makes a little
Speaker 7:  sense.
Speaker 5:  Andy and I did an entire episode on Tesla on decoder this week. So just go
Speaker 5:  listen to that. We can move off it. But we didn't talk about superchargers
Speaker 5:  enough on that episode, I think. And this to me is like, you take your
Speaker 5:  greatest advantage and you're like, stop.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That it's, it's just bonkers. Yeah. It makes no
Speaker 7:  logical sense.
Speaker 5:  Like If, you ask people like people Yes. People love the fact that the cars
Speaker 5:  get over their updates and have fart mode and all this stuff. What is the
Speaker 5:  real reason people buy a Tesla when they're in the ev market charging network?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And like you just literally no one's working
Speaker 5:  out. Like if one breaks right now, it's unclear who will come and fix it.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Weird. Just a
Speaker 7:  Weird And they canceled a bunch as well too, right? Yeah. So
Speaker 8:  I saw a tweet this morning, I think that was like, I wonder how many
Speaker 8:  charging startups will trace their founding day to whatever it was
Speaker 8:  April 30th, 2024. And like,
Speaker 8:  feels, kind of, feels kind of right. Somebody, somebody has to show up and
Speaker 8:  solve this problem in order to make electric vehicles work. And it is increasingly
Speaker 8:  unclear who that's gonna be.
Speaker 5:  I think I so my so that way too, and I was like zero.
Speaker 5:  Like this is an incredibly enormously expensive business to
Speaker 5:  be in. You gotta go buy real estate, you gotta buy a shitload of electricity.
Speaker 5:  You gotta work with every like software problems. The stuff does break. Just
Speaker 5:  like the capital expenditure to do this is so high. Like there's a reason
Speaker 5:  Electrify America is the big one. It's 'cause Volkswagen had Dieselgate
Speaker 5:  and that was their make good. That's why Electrify America exists.
Speaker 5:  Surprised.
Speaker 7:  Like Shell and Exxon aren't just being like, yeah, all right,
Speaker 7:  we'll do this. Like just diversifying into it
Speaker 8:  Somewhere. The CEO of Wawa is like drawing up a pitch right now. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like I got this like Bucky Well Bucky's already has buck's. Superchargers
Speaker 7:  actually
Speaker 8:  Bucky's should win. Yeah. I'm good with Bucky's just like owning electric
Speaker 8:  charging infrastructure in the United States.
Speaker 5:  I feel like I super know why Shell and Exxon aren't kidding into the charging
Speaker 7:  Game. Yeah. Yeah. They, they, they don't want anyone to use.
Speaker 5:  They're at my house right now keeping me from selling the Raptor. They're
Speaker 5:  like, this gets eight miles to the gallon and you're gonna have it forever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. See I hope the C of Exxon's at my house right now. I have a number
Speaker 5:  of questions for you too, sir.
Speaker 5:  Alright, let's take a break. We're gonna wrap this whole thing up in the
Speaker 5:  lightning around. We'll
Speaker 5:  adding mobile games to LinkedIn. Did
Speaker 8:  You see the guy, by the way,
Speaker 5:  Well, as a person who introduced David to his wife, I can tell you what I
Speaker 5:  know on B2B sales, which is be hammered on a boat and just
Speaker 5:  shove David into a girl.
Speaker 5:  Be like, you're gonna have a baby since it's a perfect trash. It worked.
Speaker 5:  That's a hundred percent what happened. It's
Speaker 8:  Literally the, that is the story.
Speaker 5:  Here's what I learned about B2B sales. You need a lot of tequila
Speaker 7:  That tracks that track
Speaker 5:  Also, LAR, the bigger the boat the better. Yeah. That's what I know about
Speaker 5:  B2B sales.
Speaker 8:  Absolutely. I mean, honestly, both of those are probably good sales tactics.
Speaker 7:  That's right. I was like, yeah. Yeah. Just in general. Those are good sales
Speaker 7:  tactics
Speaker 5:  Anyway. LinkedIn is a mobile games fits platform in an effort to make it
Speaker 5:  stickier. Because the only idea people have on how to
Speaker 5:  make things sticky and have you come back to them is casual
Speaker 5:  mobile games.
Speaker 7:  Consider this. LinkedIn doesn't need to be sticky.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's what I'm trying to get at.
Speaker 7:  Like LinkedIn buddies, you're doing fine. Yeah. People need a job. They go
Speaker 7:  on LinkedIn, they don't need a job, they don't use LinkedIn. It works
Speaker 5:  If, you find yourself in life being like, ah, I gotta get back on pinpoint
Speaker 5:  and like open, you know, like, reevaluate, throw your phone into the
Speaker 5:  ocean. What
Speaker 7:  If it's actually really good? What if it's like wordle?
Speaker 5:  You can only, you can only play each game once per day and after your daily
Speaker 5:  session you'll get access to your metrics. So it is wordle. It's wordle.
Speaker 5:  They made a wordle.
Speaker 8:  Can you imagine like, there's all these people now who are like, you know,
Speaker 8:  I wake up in the morning, I do connections, I do wordle. It's like a huge
Speaker 8:  success story for the Times. Great job by them. I think if I ever
Speaker 8:  found myself at a coffee shop and somebody was like, oh, hold on, I gotta
Speaker 8:  do cross climb for the day. I'd be like, I'm gonna go. Yeah. Like, I'm gonna,
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna leave.
Speaker 5:  I Oh, you're, you know too much about B2B. So we're
Speaker 8:  Not going on four dates.
Speaker 5:  It's like the ultimate red flag. Did we find out if the woman
Speaker 5:  he proposed to said yes? I'm assuming she said yes.
Speaker 8:  I don't know because
Speaker 5:  If like the last thing he learned about B2B sales was like, don't take no
Speaker 5:  for an answer. That's not great.
Speaker 7:  Ooh. Rough.
Speaker 5:  It's rough. All right. So I promise you we talked about LinkedIn gaming
Speaker 5:  and I we have in a matter of speaking.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you can do it If you want.
Speaker 5:  All right. I was really stalling in the hopes that Jim Farley, CEO of Ford
Speaker 5:  would call in to sponsor the lightning round. He did not.
Speaker 5:  Mostly because we published the show after we recorded, so he didn't know
Speaker 5:  I was waiting for that.
Speaker 8:  There's that
Speaker 5:  And I, I didn't text him. Yeah. Jim, quick question. This
Speaker 8:  Lightning round needs to be sponsored by horse girls because of the incredible
Speaker 8:  slander that we brought to them earlier in the show. I think we need to give
Speaker 8:  them this one. They
Speaker 15:  Got it. It's all you girl girls.
Speaker 5:  There was a second one in law school. I think it really cemented the
Speaker 5:  situation for me.
Speaker 5:  I wasn't a great person for many years. Then
Speaker 5:  after mastering B2B sales, I got married. There you go.
Speaker 5:  Alright. Lightning round. We gotta, we, this is important. This one's important.
Speaker 5:  There is an Apple event next week. Yes. By all accounts, this
Speaker 5:  is new iPads. David, you wrote a spicy headline this week. The last thing
Speaker 5:  the iPad needs is a spec bump.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  I'd say this is more than a spec bump. We're gonna get ole iPads spec bump.
Speaker 5:  This is like my dream spec bump.
Speaker 8:  Sure. Yeah. You and Liam are both gonna be psyched and everyone else on earth
Speaker 8:  is gonna say, what is Ole? I don't care. Leave
Speaker 5:  Me alone. Aww.
Speaker 8:  No, I, I think, I mean we, we've been asking this, what is the
Speaker 8:  iPad for and what, what is Apple trying to do with it? Question for a while.
Speaker 8:  And I was on the, they just need to make the iPad a touchscreen laptop train
Speaker 8:  for a long time. I'm, I'm now off that train because
Speaker 8:  the MacBook Air is that, is that thing like, it's not a touchscreen, but
Speaker 8:  it is. It is a damn good laptop. It is the laptop. People who want laptops
Speaker 8:  should buy problem solved. The iPad needs to figure out the
Speaker 8:  other thing that it wants to be. Yeah. And what's interesting is it
Speaker 8:  seems like, and again, I'm, I'm like a little bit kind of making a mountain
Speaker 8:  out of a molehill here, but the If, you just look at the invite
Speaker 8:  to the Apple event, it's called Let Loose. And it is just, it's just an Apple
Speaker 8:  pencil. It's not like hiding that it's an Apple pencil. It just is an Apple
Speaker 8:  pencil. And to me it's like, okay, if Apple wants this
Speaker 8:  to work, the thing that it needs to focus on is accessories. Like
Speaker 8:  sell, take the idea of the iPad as just, it's a screen and you
Speaker 8:  can attach every other piece of the device that you want to it and
Speaker 8:  take it off as you need it or don't. And
Speaker 8:  Apple has gone like an inch down this road. They have two different keyboards
Speaker 8:  for different kinds of people who want different kinds of keyboards. There's
Speaker 8:  the pencil. Do you remember when they had the smart connector that no one
Speaker 8:  ever used? Because Apple never opened it up to anybody. That was a thing.
Speaker 8:  Apple is like, it was cool. Is like this close to being a really
Speaker 8:  interesting modular accessory system around this really
Speaker 8:  great tablet and it just, it needs to stop worrying
Speaker 8:  about having more processing power because it already, it has had
Speaker 8:  too much processing power for like six years. Yeah. Like no one
Speaker 8:  is using all of the power of their iPad in part because they can't, because
Speaker 8:  there's not enough powerful software to do it. But also because you're not
Speaker 8:  giving people the literal physical tools they need to make the most out
Speaker 8:  of this device. So I think as we go into this event, I'm like,
Speaker 8:  whatever, I'm sure I'll end up buying an ole iPad because that is like a
Speaker 8:  sickness I have in my life.
Speaker 5:  Because you love black levels. I, I, yeah. Do, I mean, infinite contrast
Speaker 7:  Story
Speaker 5:  Shows we
Speaker 8:  Do that. But like, I just, I don't know. I feel like I I'm, we, we've all
Speaker 8:  sort of gone blue in the face yelling like, what is an iPad actually for
Speaker 8:  somewhere. Dieter Bone is like shaking his fist at our podcast
Speaker 8:  right now. But I just like, Apple's like right there and
Speaker 8:  it's like, just go, go finish the thing. Make me some accessories.
Speaker 8:  Build the iPad out. So
Speaker 5:  Two things. Rumor is they're gonna put
Speaker 5:  an M four chip in these iPads, massive
Speaker 5:  increase in processing power that the thing does not need. Second,
Speaker 5:  they need to change the software. That's actually what it needs.
Speaker 5:  The, the hardware ecosystem around it, whatever. Except make
Speaker 5:  accessory manufacturers make more stuff to make any of that worthwhile. You
Speaker 5:  need more software capabilities and they can't do that. 'cause
Speaker 5:  WWC isn't until June. Right. Right. You needed the next version of iOS. What
Speaker 5:  can they show us besides an OLED screen? An
Speaker 7:  Infor processor
Speaker 5:  And Right. And a a d like a chip dye diagram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Of the M four being like, look at this neural engine. Well
Speaker 5:  read it and weep.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. There's gonna be a lot of unlabeled graphs. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  There's gonna be, oh we're, there's a, there's a pencil and it's gonna have
Speaker 7:  replaceable nubs, but like Sure. Cooler
Speaker 7:  replaceable nubs in the current pencil has and there's a, there's
Speaker 7:  an aluminum magic keyboard that's also
Speaker 7:  not software.
Speaker 5:  The, the rumor from Markman, the rumor from Mark Urman at
Speaker 5:  Bloomberg is that it will be, it will lean into being a laptop or the pro
Speaker 5:  will lean into being a laptop. I mean, I expect a full model refresh, like
Speaker 5:  the iPad model range right now is outta control. It's, yes. So they should
Speaker 5:  end with an iPad that is cheap that makes sense for students. An
Speaker 5:  iPad, air that is like the mainstream one. An iPad Pro that is
Speaker 5:  expensive and has all the stuff Yeah, sure. That, that's theoretically what
Speaker 5:  they have now, but it's all very blurry. Yeah. And then a pencil that works
Speaker 5:  with everything one assumes and maybe some of these keyboard cases
Speaker 5:  and whatever else that work with
Speaker 7:  Everybody. I hope it still has a lightning port in the eraser.
Speaker 5:  The the base one. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I, I like, I I just hope that they, that they just whiff it
Speaker 7:  on a port.
Speaker 5:  There's like one last lightning port. Yeah. You're
Speaker 7:  Just, wha
Speaker 5:  I just think the future of the iPad Pro should
Speaker 5:  be, this is a modular Mac and you should just let the iPad,
Speaker 5:  the base model iPad be like, this runs Disney plus.
Speaker 8:  I just wanna point out that you, you're, you sort of like, you just hand
Speaker 8:  literally hand waved away the iPad that everyone buys and uses.
Speaker 5:  I think people buy the cheap one.
Speaker 8:  That's what I'm saying. The iPad Pro is, is not the most
Speaker 8:  important iPad by a million miles.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I but again, I think the cheap one runs Disney plus. Sure.
Speaker 5:  I think, I think that's what it's for. I like, here's the cheapest TV in
Speaker 5:  your house.
Speaker 5:  Fine. The iPad.
Speaker 7:  No, there's a Westing house you for
Speaker 5:  Like 90 bucks. That's exactly, you signed up for a bank account at Chase
Speaker 5:  and they gave you a tv. Like Sure, sure. But like, that's what I mean. Portable,
Speaker 7:  Portable tv. But
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah, this is like, here's this content consumption device
Speaker 5:  that occasionally lets you tap out an email. It's like, that's the base model
Speaker 5:  iPad. I don't fine. Like let that thing be
Speaker 5:  this weird appliance. I'm just saying for everything else to solve that
Speaker 5:  problem of like, what is this for? Actually should just be a
Speaker 5:  Mac. Like they should just let you run Mac apps on it at this point. Like
Speaker 5:  why not?
Speaker 8:  I do agree with that. I don't think it should be exclusively that, but I
Speaker 8:  think that is one thing it ought to do. Right. In the way that
Speaker 8:  you can now run some iOS and iPad apps on your
Speaker 8:  Mac. It should, it should pull in both directions at this point.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I don't think Apple will ever let it go. 'cause then they will have
Speaker 5:  made a touchscreen Mac by accident and that really implicates a lot of things
Speaker 5:  about everything they've ever said. But I just, I just dunno why you wouldn't
Speaker 5:  converge the iPad Pro and like the
Speaker 5:  cheapest MacBook
Speaker 7:  Pro because one time years ago they said they will never do that.
Speaker 7:  And now like, we'll really like ruthlessly mock them when they do it.
Speaker 5:  I mean, apple says they're not gonna do things until they do it all the
Speaker 7:  Time. That's
Speaker 8:  True. I do think If, you If you look at your Mac and you think about
Speaker 8:  what it would be like to use Mac os as a touchscreen.
Speaker 8:  It's a nightmare. Like just think about the amount of time you spend
Speaker 8:  in a menu bar and how it would feel on a 9.7 inch screen
Speaker 8:  to try to poke at those little icons in the corner. Like bad times.
Speaker 7:  Oh, no, no, no. It's, it's a great time. I'm, I'm, I'm checking out this,
Speaker 7:  this product right now from IN ao, I think that's how you say it. IN
Speaker 7:  ao they do like game little handheld game consoles and they have
Speaker 7:  one called the Flip Ds and it's got Micro, it's got
Speaker 7:  Microsoft built in. Yeah. It's just a tiny DS shaped Windows
Speaker 7:  machine. Oh no. And the only way I can like turn it on because
Speaker 7:  hardware wise gorgeous. Don't worry. Reviews are coming software
Speaker 7:  wise. It's just Windows and they didn't really do anything. So,
Speaker 7:  and there's no keyboard. So you have to like, you have to like fi I have
Speaker 7:  to use my pinky. I can't use my regular finger. I have to use my pinky to
Speaker 7:  like hit a button to turn on a a, a keyboard. And then
Speaker 7:  it's beautiful. It works every time. It takes 20 minutes.
Speaker 7:  I love it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean that's, that's the Apple experience I'm looking for.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's what I want from Apple too. Everyone should let me have like
Speaker 7:  a tiny, tiny screens that I've used my pinky to, to work on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And every time you push that button, apple makes $20. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  We all win. All
Speaker 5:  Right. Lightning around Crans. What you got?
Speaker 7:  Okay. Do you guys remember, do you remember when Razor Made made their mask?
Speaker 5:  They, they made like three masks.
Speaker 7:  Oh, sorry. Do you remember when they made the Zephyr? Yes. And, and and
Speaker 7:  it was kind of, see Yeah. And, and it had the RGB, they actually, they
Speaker 7:  appeared at our,
Speaker 5:  Our tenure. They did. And they refused to answer any questions about the
Speaker 5:  medical backing of this this device.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And, and shocker, they
Speaker 7:  didn't have backing this, this,
Speaker 7:  this mask. They, they said had like N95 grade filters and stuff. That
Speaker 7:  was just a lie. Or it was not the
Speaker 7:  truth. Maybe, maybe a lie is too hard.
Speaker 8:  N95 grade is an amazing phrase. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's like, it's not N95. It's like N95 ish.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And, and that's not anything like, that's
Speaker 7:  just, that's just not a thing. You know, it's,
Speaker 7:  and so they are now being required to fork over
Speaker 7:  $1.1 million in refunds to customers.
Speaker 7:  And I think the real question here is who are the people who
Speaker 7:  bought the Zephyr mask and are now getting their one point their their refund?
Speaker 7:  Because you did that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That means like thousands of people bought that thing. Wasn't it only
Speaker 8:  like a hundred bucks?
Speaker 7:  It it was, it was more expensive than that. Oh, okay. Oh no. It started at
Speaker 7:  a hundred dollars. Yeah. So,
Speaker 7:  but still you bought it and I should, I haven't seen you wear
Speaker 7:  it. I feel like I would've, if that many people bought it, I would've seen
Speaker 7:  at least one on the street. The only one I ever saw was at the, our, our
Speaker 7:  10 year party. And it was the razor guy wearing it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Cameron and our health reporter at the time, Nicole
Speaker 5:  Wetsman, who by the way, joined The Verge before the pandemic and then was
Speaker 5:  our health reporter during a global pandemic. Like
Speaker 7:  Right before the pandemic.
Speaker 5:  It was not, I feel like every time I see Nicole for the rest of my life,
Speaker 5:  I, I'm so sorry. Yeah. But anyway, but Nicole was there
Speaker 5:  and she was like, so is this certified? Is it actually in like over and over
Speaker 5:  again? And they're like, we'll get to it. It was a very weird moment at our
Speaker 5:  party, I must say. It was super weird when you think about The Verge party,
Speaker 5:  you think about our health reporters being like, are you lying?
Speaker 5:  That's, that's what, and then there's tequila. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean that was exactly the party. It was
Speaker 5:  Great weird product. Weird product, weird moment in his,
Speaker 5:  the global history to be like this. RGB
Speaker 5:  N95 is a fake,
Speaker 7:  It had like speakers in it.
Speaker 5:  It was a very product.
Speaker 7:  God, it was, it was see-through that was the part that was,
Speaker 8:  It really is a very specific artifact of a very specific time. That thing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. You will look at that thing and you will always know exactly when it
Speaker 8:  came out and exactly who made it and exactly
Speaker 5:  What happened to it.
Speaker 8:  Like it, it tells a whole story.
Speaker 5:  All right. I have a lightning round item here. Yeah. It's about Instagram
Speaker 5:  algorithm updates and what it means in the TikTok ban. Yeah. Da da da. But
Speaker 5:  then I'm just looking at this headline that says, Google is building a fart
Speaker 5:  button into Android.
Speaker 5:  And it is, they're putting a soundboard into the phone
Speaker 5:  app of Android.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  So you get what are called audio emoji so
Speaker 5:  that you can just play them during phone calls.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I shouldn't have that power.
Speaker 5:  You get clapping, laughing, crying, which is a literal sad,
Speaker 5:  trombone partying, a drum sting, which is
Speaker 5:  and then fart sound.
Speaker 8:  This is, and I, I I want to, I wanna not
Speaker 8:  be hyperbolic here. This is the worst idea I've ever heard from
Speaker 8:  a technology company maybe
Speaker 7:  Ever in history.
Speaker 5:  It's like, do you remember when Google's last idea about the phone was like,
Speaker 5:  we'll, have the robot make reservations for you? They're like, no, no, no.
Speaker 5:  Dude. They like, you should be able to wmp wmp your friends in the middle
Speaker 5:  of a phone
Speaker 7:  Call. I I love that you can just be on a phone, phone call and be like,
Speaker 7:  like that's great. This is also,
Speaker 8:  It's very good. What this reminds me of is like, you know, when the apple
Speaker 8:  rolled out the reactions thing in FaceTime and so everybody was,
Speaker 8:  do you would like do the an accidental a thumbs up on camera? Yes. And it
Speaker 8:  would in some horrifically inappropriate moment, do like
Speaker 8:  fireworks explosions behind you or like a really happy thumbs up or whatever.
Speaker 8:  This is going to be that. Because I guarantee you Google's gonna put this
Speaker 8:  button in a place that is too easy to find and people are going to be having
Speaker 8:  like, you know, hard conversations with their boss or their family or
Speaker 8:  whatever. And all of a sudden they're going to, their face is gonna tap a
Speaker 8:  button of their phone and it's gonna go, w
Speaker 5:  Wa
Speaker 7:  Like,
Speaker 8:  This is not a good idea.
Speaker 5:  I love it. Like the fact that we haven't had soundboards built into the
Speaker 5:  default dialers.
Speaker 7:  It's just why weren't we doing that
Speaker 5:  Audio emojis just
Speaker 8:  In case you wanted to make sure no one ever makes phone calls ever again.
Speaker 8:  Here's this. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's very good. I'm hoping they demo this on stage at io. I like if they
Speaker 5:  take a huge chunk of time at IO to be like, we've invented audio emojis.
Speaker 5:  You can make fart sounds during phone calls,
Speaker 7:  Hyper realistic
Speaker 5:  Fart sounds. This is what it's for. Surprise and delight your customer. This
Speaker 5:  is why we make the technology. Billions of dollars have gone into the,
Speaker 5:  the mobile phone supply chain. The, so the software,
Speaker 5:  the open source development of Android itself. Billions of dollars,
Speaker 5:  thousands of years of human effort. You know, cumulatively we built these
Speaker 5:  networks. 5G is a pH phenomenon
Speaker 5:  and now you can just make fart sounds.
Speaker 7:  You don't even have to use your mouth like innovation. Yeah. I love
Speaker 5:  It. Can I tell you yet one more story for my youth?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Is it a fart story?
Speaker 5:  No. Well it's sort of, it is in
Speaker 7:  Its way adjacent. Okay.
Speaker 5:  I had a remote controlled speaker that made swear words and fart sounds.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And i's super hid. One in that like the
Speaker 5:  balcony of the room that we had our high school morning meeting from.
Speaker 5:  And we just ruined that meeting for weeks.
Speaker 8:  It's
Speaker 7:  Good work. I mean, that's what you're supposed to
Speaker 5:  Do. I got suspended from high school, like a lot,
Speaker 5:  like all time records, but like
Speaker 7:  For good. Cause
Speaker 5:  My dad was like, are you gonna go to school? And I was like, well I'm getting
Speaker 5:  good grades. He was like, fine. You just like, That was the, that was the
Speaker 5:  trade in my household. You got good grades. My dad was like, I'll
Speaker 5:  don't talk to your principal again. Yeah. It was a small town. It was a private
Speaker 5:  school. There was nowhere for me to go. Alright. I think that's the first
Speaker 5:  cast.
Speaker 5:  Stay in school. Kids
Speaker 5:  just like, yeah. Love a fart button. Try hard.
Speaker 5:  No, that's it. That's the first test. Next week is gonna be a huge week.
Speaker 5:  We got an Apple event. We got this. We're gonna find out what's gonna happen
Speaker 5:  with the iPad. This Google trial closing arguments are today,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna hear a lot about what's happening very soon. 'cause that's a
Speaker 5:  bench trial. A lot of tech news is coming and then soon after
Speaker 5:  that IO starts and developer season is off the races. So take a breath,
Speaker 5:  pull over in your car. Just think about what it means to be a large
Speaker 5:  action model.
Speaker 5:  It means nothing. It actually doesn't mean anything at this point in time.
Speaker 5:  The the, it's a three. I had to work so hard not to make a fart noise of
Speaker 5:  that silence. See, that would've been perfect. Just, oh my god. All right.
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's our chest bucket.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The. Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.