# Transcript
ID: baee3496-f76d-4184-aaed-08df16a5e68a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4379357020584145223/4773425072271524126/s93290-US-5965s-1718581356.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss takeaways from WWDC, this week's gadget news, and Elon Musk dropping his lawsuit against OpenAI.
Speaker 5:  Verge cast for you.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't want to go too far down this road. I'm saying this is why
Speaker 4:  you should do bangs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. David would rock some bangs. I
Speaker 5:  Would say there are several things preventing me from growing good bangs
Speaker 5:  and I'm happy to talk about them anytime you want. That's a whole,
Speaker 4:  Except for right now, David gets bangs. That's what AI is for. If
Speaker 4:  someone can make an AI generated image of David with bangs like that, I have
Speaker 4:  very like bouncy curly hair. There's a lot of stuff in my hair to make it
Speaker 4:  not do that. Yeah. But we watched the fall guy and I came out of the bathroom
Speaker 4:  the other day with just like full floppy bangs. Yeah. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  back, should I do this? And she was like, no. She was like, just
Speaker 4:  don't just
Speaker 2:  Sit you right back into the bathroom. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I appreciate that. You like me And most men watch Ryan Gosling for an
Speaker 5:  hour and a half and then it's like, what if I changed everything about myself?
Speaker 2:  Could I, could
Speaker 5:  I be more like him if everything about me was different? I've had a lot of
Speaker 5:  those moments recently.
Speaker 4:  Becky met me when I had blonde highlights in my hair.
Speaker 4:  So I think there was, that's an immediate, she's like, I can't go back there.
Speaker 4:  I, I've, I suffered through this already. No thank you. Alright. A lot to
Speaker 4:  talk about. We promised an entire episode of the show,
Speaker 4:  not about the AI stuff. Apple announced at wwc. There has also
Speaker 4:  been a ton of gadget news. We're going through that and then lightning round
Speaker 4:  unsponsored. And I've seen the tweets from people who are like, I'm trying
Speaker 4:  to sponsor the lightning round. Quite frankly, you've gotta just
Speaker 4:  bring a suitcase of money to our office directly. Yeah. You're not trying
Speaker 4:  hard enough. That's all I'll say. You can't just be tweeting at me or posting
Speaker 4:  on threads. Yeah. Physical money in a suitcase. A good
Speaker 4:  suitcase. Yeah. I don't want Amazon. Alphabet soup
Speaker 4:  suitcases.
Speaker 2:  We wanna see you in the lobby. Just make
Speaker 4:  Icons Samsonite to me. You know, like good suitcase.
Speaker 4:  That's actually, it's not the money in the suitcase.
Speaker 2:  You just want the suitcase. Do do you need a new suitcase? This
Speaker 4:  Here not sponsored by a suitcase company. I don't know any other luggage.
Speaker 4:  France American tourist or topo. Do they make topo? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I, I would say away, but we wrote that story about away one time and they
Speaker 4:  threatened to sue us.
Speaker 4:  She doesn't work there anymore. She's not the CEO Anyway, that's deep VERGE
Speaker 4:  lore. We can set that aside. Okay. So we should talk about all the other
Speaker 4:  stuff from WWC that isn't ai. But first we should mention two quick things
Speaker 4:  about Apple ai. Apple intelligence, if you will. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  One we talked last week about the confusion over who was paying who
Speaker 4:  and the way Apple was treating open ai, which was just a plugin to their
Speaker 4:  system to basically do all the risky stuff. Apple will do a
Speaker 4:  very small set of things and then if you're like, this might create
Speaker 4:  horrible brand risk for us by telling you lies. So like, would you like to
Speaker 4:  use chat GPT? Yep. And then they had said, well
Speaker 4:  eventually we'll plug Gemini into this and maybe some other models. So it,
Speaker 4:  it seemed like they were just extending the capability of their system and
Speaker 4:  we couldn't tell who was paying who. Mark Erman has reported no one's paying
Speaker 4:  anyone. Apple is paying open eye and exposure.
Speaker 4:  And the, the idea here sort of makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like everyone in media starts there. Yeah. You get paid in
Speaker 2:  exposure. This is just like,
Speaker 4:  I haven't paid crayons in a year. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I I I just live off of like McDonald's that I steal from
Speaker 2:  dumpsters.
Speaker 4:  It's great. No, but the, the idea right, is
Speaker 4:  people will see the chat GBT logo, they'll see the capabilities,
Speaker 4:  they'll want to go and log in. This is where it gets real fuzzy. And then
Speaker 4:  they will pay for chat GPT the
Speaker 4:  20 bucks a month or whatever and then Apple will take
Speaker 4:  30%. It's always, it's always in the background.
Speaker 4:  What's Apple's plan? 30%. Yeah, that's that. You
Speaker 4:  walk into an Apple store, 30% show up with a Samsonite. You know, like
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's Tim Cook's vibe. Yeah. And I don't
Speaker 4:  know if that's going to work for a few reasons. One, I asked very
Speaker 4:  specifically while we were at wwc, is there gonna be an interface for people
Speaker 4:  to sign up for the chat GBT subscription?
Speaker 4:  And the answer very clearly was no. Yeah. Can confirm
Speaker 4:  you the the Safari is available to you. You, you may go and sign
Speaker 4:  up over there. Okay. So they need to build the flow,
Speaker 4:  which means Apple has to upsell you to someone else's product inside of its
Speaker 4:  own interfaces and then take 30%.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. Lots of question marks there.
Speaker 5:  Does that exist anywhere? I'm trying to think of a version of that
Speaker 5:  that exists currently on iOS and I can't think of one where you're
Speaker 5:  buying someone else's product inside of an Apple product and how that
Speaker 5:  flow would work. I don't think that exists. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Streaming the, for like some of the streaming
Speaker 5:  Channels. That's fair. That's probably the closest analog. Yeah. That kind
Speaker 5:  of, that kind of for that's all I got. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I don't know. It's, it's new. Right. But so, but the economics as
Speaker 4:  reported by Mark Urman would look like, you use this stuff,
Speaker 4:  you like it so much, you say to yourself, I wish this robot would re
Speaker 4:  remember me.
Speaker 4:  And then you go pay the money. So it has a, it has faithfulness, which is
Speaker 4:  the thing you would basically pay for at this point. Aren't
Speaker 2:  People kind of like getting fed up with paying the robot for money?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I don't know. I think the, the question here, how this works out is
Speaker 4:  if you're getting the basic version for free, which you
Speaker 4:  are the full GPT-4 oh all of its features somehow for
Speaker 4:  free, what you are not getting is, does
Speaker 4:  it remember you, can you use the chat GPT app on
Speaker 4:  your phone for free? I think not. I think you get to use it inside of Apple's
Speaker 4:  experiences for free. Okay. That's
Speaker 5:  Right. All of the custom instructions stuff doesn't work. It seems like the
Speaker 5:  custom GPTs wouldn't work. So there is a lot of stuff like
Speaker 5:  the, the access you would get as far as we know through
Speaker 5:  the OS level thing is very limited. And so the,
Speaker 5:  the upsell for chat GPT seems plausible. What seems
Speaker 5:  wild to me is how expensive the customer acquisition cost
Speaker 5:  there is gonna be. If I'm OpenAI, I, I can see two things going
Speaker 5:  on here. One is that OpenAI is
Speaker 5:  going to launch a search product, which I think everybody believes to be
Speaker 5:  true and seems to be true.
Speaker 5:  And it's possible that that is going to be part of this, right? That like
Speaker 5:  maybe one thing Apple will be happy to do is kick you to the web
Speaker 5:  through open AI's search product. And one very good thing you can do
Speaker 5:  there is have ads. So it's, there's like, there is maybe a version of that
Speaker 5:  that is like a direct correlation to Apple's Google deal where when you
Speaker 5:  search, you look at ads and Apple gets some of that revenue.
Speaker 5:  That's very straightforward. That product doesn't exist. We have no idea
Speaker 5:  what it's gonna look like. So who knows? We'll see the other one is
Speaker 5:  this is just like OpenAI spending a tremendous amount of money
Speaker 5:  giving you free stuff in the hopes that it can find some way to get you
Speaker 5:  to pay. And I think it's gonna be so fascinating to see
Speaker 5:  how Apple implements that because you'll be able to tell everything you've
Speaker 5:  ever wanted to know about Apple's priorities by when it tries to upsell you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know what I mean? Like if the first time you do it Apple's like
Speaker 5:  wouldn't it be better if you had then it's like, oh, this is a 30% company
Speaker 5:  like this is, this is what you're after. You are immediately trying to get
Speaker 5:  me to pay more money to do a thing that you have promised me is baked into
Speaker 5:  the operating system. Or if Apple is like happy to push this all the way
Speaker 5:  out and just make it a teeny tiny box you can find in Safari if you want
Speaker 5:  to. That's very different. And I think that that tension
Speaker 5:  between these two companies and that product is going to be so weird and
Speaker 5:  so interesting. If this is the actual business dynamic here
Speaker 4:  And it ramps up even higher if you can just switch it to Google, Gemini or
Speaker 4:  whatever next model right, in China they have to use or whatever models come
Speaker 4:  out of Europe or whatever. Like the idea that there's this other architecture
Speaker 4:  beyond Apple intelligence that these companies can plug into and that will
Speaker 4:  drive them customers sort of also implies that Apple believes
Speaker 4:  the economics of all these problems are subscriptions. Yep. You plug Google
Speaker 4:  Gemini into this, how is Google gonna make money? Well, it's not Apple paying
Speaker 4:  Google. It's hopefully they, you sign up for
Speaker 4:  Gemini at $20 a month. Right? I don't know if that's the way it will
Speaker 4:  actually play out. I think there
Speaker 2:  Well there's not, I mean I think there's not a lot of
Speaker 2:  risk for Apple in, in this right now. Like if they're paying for
Speaker 2:  exposure, then if chat GPT is just sucks and nobody uses it,
Speaker 2:  right. Which probably won't happen but could then it's
Speaker 2:  fine. Apple's like, okay, yeah, there's something that will we'll close down
Speaker 2:  in a couple of years when everybody stops talking about it. But if it like
Speaker 2:  actually takes off, okay, they make money and it's just like, okay, we get
Speaker 2:  free money now. Like it doesn't feel like there's a huge risk for Apple in
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 5:  You know who you sound like Alex. Cranz is everyone who argues that Apple
Speaker 5:  is a monopoly that needs to be broken up by antitrust law. Like
Speaker 2:  That's true. I do. I
Speaker 5:  Totally agree. Like this is all, it's, it's Apple is an incredible leverage
Speaker 5:  point where it has the distribution and nobody else does. And if you're
Speaker 5:  open AI and you wanna get in front of a lot of people who are not otherwise
Speaker 5:  likely to go to your website or your app, this
Speaker 5:  is your move. And that gives Apple all the power in the world.
Speaker 2:  This is huge for open ai, right? Like, like they, they have that first mover
Speaker 2:  advantage and that's it scale everything else. Everybody,
Speaker 2:  all the other, their competitors just have it all. So, so like they
Speaker 2:  need this
Speaker 4:  Well except that their, their big competitor is Google and Apple
Speaker 4:  has been very clear that Google is coming to the same plugin system. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  But not yet.
Speaker 4:  But, but now that it chips, so this is my second point. So that was 0.1 on
Speaker 4:  Apple intelligence is it appears we understand the
Speaker 4:  economics based on Mark's reporting. No one's really repeated it.
Speaker 4:  Apple's not saying it doesn't seem like anyone
Speaker 4:  at OpenAI is running around growing about a windfall of profits.
Speaker 4:  That's what we know so far. So it's,
Speaker 5:  I will say though, everyone at OpenAI is running around pretty aggressively
Speaker 5:  overstating the extent to which they're involved in all of this. There have
Speaker 5:  been a bunch of people tweeting, like we're so excited to be working with
Speaker 5:  Apple to help power all of the AI experiences on the iPhone. And it's like
Speaker 5:  Easy Buddies like Yeah. Is that accurate? A like last resort
Speaker 5:  checkbox kind of situation here. Like let's, let's pump the brakes on what's
Speaker 5:  happening here.
Speaker 4:  We're so excited to bring Voice of Scarlet Johansen Siri,
Speaker 5:  But only if you get past three popups, it's gonna be great. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  love it.
Speaker 4:  So that's one is right, we, we seemingly understand the economics
Speaker 4:  two actually directly. Right. So what you just said, Alex, it is
Speaker 4:  important I think to note that no one has seen
Speaker 4:  this work yet. Yeah. There have been some briefings.
Speaker 4:  I we've talked a bunch of reporters. Apple had briefings that showed a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stuff on Rails. Great.
Speaker 4:  Very cool. Love a controlled demo. Yeah. But having
Speaker 4:  just gone through this with the Vision Pro and
Speaker 4:  the Rabbit and the Humane Pen and everything else,
Speaker 4:  I would just caution everyone that there are only
Speaker 4:  two kinds of news where the truth just comes out.
Speaker 4:  One is sports and one is tech products.
Speaker 4:  One team wins or loses in you just that you get an answer
Speaker 4:  or the gambling economy forces the wrong answer. But that's actually,
Speaker 4:  that's whatever, that's another thing happens over there. But like at the
Speaker 4:  end you get a result, right? It's like there's not a lot of dispute about
Speaker 4:  what happened at the end of the Super Bowl intact. The products work or
Speaker 4:  they don't. And then real people get them and then all bets are
Speaker 4:  off. And I've said this a million times now in the show this year, all bets
Speaker 4:  are off. Once you start shipping the thing to thousands or millions of people,
Speaker 4:  they're just gonna do stuff you never expected. They're gonna break it in
Speaker 4:  extremely esoteric ways. They're definitely not gonna read the instruction
Speaker 4:  manual. Nope. All of your great ideas just
Speaker 4:  fall apart once like millions of regular people get this stuff. Apple is
Speaker 4:  gonna ship this to a billion people. The Oprah line.
Speaker 4:  They're in a billion pockets. Y'all. That's what Oprah said when they announced
Speaker 4:  Apple TV Plus, why'd you make this deal with a, with with Tim Cook and Apple,
Speaker 4:  Oprah. They're in a billion pockets. That's a real quote. You can go look
Speaker 4:  it up. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Remember you put this in a billion pockets. Some
Speaker 4:  weird stuff is gonna start. I guarantee you some weird stuff is gonna start
Speaker 4:  happening. Tim Cook said to the Washington Post opinion
Speaker 4:  section, they're not a hundred percent sure they can stop AI hallucinations
Speaker 4:  and he would never make a claim. 'cause why? 'cause why you can't,
Speaker 4:  don't, don't worry about hallucinations, it's fine. Just, it's just gonna
Speaker 4:  lie to you. Sometimes that's what you expect from your iPhone. It's just
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Some creative lies. Kevin Rus was at the event just waiting to see
Speaker 4:  if everyone intelligence would make love to him, by the way. I saw him at
Speaker 4:  the event. I, I apologize directly to Kevin for getting so much mileage
Speaker 4:  outta that joke. And he is like, no, everyone is. So I I love, I love you
Speaker 4:  Kevin,
Speaker 5:  Including his family. He said, so that's, it's good for everybody.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Rest, rest is assure he knows I continue to make the joke. We haven't
Speaker 4:  concretely seen the phone handoff from local
Speaker 4:  inference to the private cloud inference that Apple wants.
Speaker 4:  Like we just haven't seen any of this work
Speaker 4:  outside of a very controlled context. And I'm just,
Speaker 4:  just, just reminding everyone gently,
Speaker 4:  the AI economy so far has largely run on
Speaker 4:  hype and then they ship it and it's like you should put some
Speaker 4:  glue on your pizza. Yeah. And I'm not saying
Speaker 4:  Apple doesn't have a better track record than everyone else. I'm not saying
Speaker 4:  that people, it's wrong to, to believe that
Speaker 4:  they can out execute most of their competitors. Apple can definitely out
Speaker 4:  execute most of its competitors. The last time the company out
Speaker 4:  executed most of its competitors, it shipped the Vision Pro, which is easily
Speaker 4:  the most technologically advanced VR headset ever made. Yep. It's still
Speaker 4:  a VR headset, right? Like it has all of the problems of the category.
Speaker 4:  It does not have a bunch of really novel solutions to them. Right. And it's
Speaker 4:  just the best engineered, most complete version of the thing that it is.
Speaker 4:  We have yet to see it. So I'm just, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Didn't Apple also have like the disclaimer of like, sometimes it lies Oops.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. It's, it's right in the interface. Chatt sometimes check this info
Speaker 4:  just
Speaker 2:  Built right in.
Speaker 4:  So I'm not saying it's not gonna work. I I just want to call that out gently.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 2:  Gently
Speaker 4:  It, we, we have months to go like maybe even a year or more
Speaker 4:  to go before all of the features we saw demoed at WWC
Speaker 4:  ship shipped to thousands if not millions or billions of
Speaker 4:  people. And then a bunch of stuff that
Speaker 4:  no one anticipated happening is gonna happen at massive scale. I'll give
Speaker 4:  you an example. Casey and Platformer wrote, apple is now in the business
Speaker 4:  of content moderation at scale. And I wrote back, I was like, they have the
Speaker 4:  app store. He was like, no, no, no, no. Someone's gonna ask this thing to
Speaker 4:  draw a gun and Apple won't do it. And then Tim Cook is gonna end up in front
Speaker 4:  of Congress. Like, that is the level of chaos that is
Speaker 4:  coming for these systems and they have to bear the pressure.
Speaker 4:  And so it doesn't mean they've won, it doesn't mean they're ahead or behind.
Speaker 4:  It just means like, we came off a very good show
Speaker 4:  and now we have to get the thing. And I keep saying
Speaker 4:  like, there's only two categories where you definitively know at the end
Speaker 4:  if it worked or not. It's sports and tech. Like
Speaker 4:  I would even say like a lot of people when I bring up this comparison, say
Speaker 4:  politics 'cause there's elections look around man. Like
Speaker 4:  a lot of people don't think that's one of the categories anymore.
Speaker 2:  I I think this will probably be the same thing too. Yeah. I think, I think
Speaker 2:  a lot of people are gonna debate it because, you know, well I I've heard
Speaker 2:  this a lot. I I'm very vocal about thinking hallucinations are an enormous
Speaker 2:  problem and everybody is glossing over them and should stop. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And I get a lot of comments being like, don't worry about it.
Speaker 4:  The goalposts on hallucinations have fully moved. Yeah. I've noticed this
Speaker 4:  recently. We just had the CEO of cohere on decoder. He's one of the
Speaker 4:  people who wrote Attention is all you need at Google. The paper that
Speaker 4:  famously described Transformers, which Google loves reminding everyone up.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, can you, can you fix it? Like can you, if if you program
Speaker 4:  a computer and it delivers some answer to you and sometimes it's wrong,
Speaker 4:  like that seems like a bad computer. And he was like, well you get stuff
Speaker 4:  wrong too.
Speaker 4:  Sure. And he's not that's a totally correct answer. That's, but
Speaker 4:  it's like that's why I have a computer Yeah. Is to be far
Speaker 4:  more reliable than Yeah. My
Speaker 5:  Computer does the math correctly. Like that's, I feel pretty good about that
Speaker 4:  Every single time. Yeah. The example I gave him was
Speaker 4:  like, I would not let an LLM like an F 22 cannot be flown without a computer.
Speaker 4:  Like it just can't, like a human being cannot operate an F 22 fast enough
Speaker 4:  to keep it stable in flight. And it's like he would just not give it to an
Speaker 4:  L
Speaker 4:  He did make the point that the, the rate of hallucinations is coming down
Speaker 4:  and importantly in, in the context of Apple, apple intelligence is doing
Speaker 4:  such little stuff that they've scoped down what they
Speaker 4:  want it to do, what they wanna be responsible so far. And then
Speaker 4:  anything else is chat GBT, which can lie to you. Which
Speaker 2:  Just, I think that's a smart way to do it. So like I think chatt
Speaker 2:  PT is being hugely irresponsible by being like, yeah, use this for everything.
Speaker 2:  Sure. But Apple, that is a much more responsible like approach,
Speaker 2:  right. Saying, you know what, it's bad at that. So we're just not gonna let
Speaker 4:  It, that we've, we've let some of series, we've improved some of series pro
Speaker 4:  natural language process. Well
Speaker 2:  What if it like hallucinates meetings for you?
Speaker 4:  Oh, that'd be great. Because if we, if we, if I could, if I could
Speaker 4:  incorporate a lying robot into my meeting scheduling, I
Speaker 4:  take it. But, and speaking of scoped all the way down, this is another really
Speaker 4:  important piece that I, I didn't even think about while we were there, but
Speaker 4:  Gen two E has a piece coming up on the site, but it'll be up by the time
Speaker 4:  you read this.
Speaker 4:  The new Apple Intelligence, the new Siri won't work on the
Speaker 4:  HomePod, it won't work on the Apple tv and it appears it will not work with
Speaker 4:  HomeKit.
Speaker 5:  Wait, it won't work with HomeKit at all. Like the devices thing makes sense.
Speaker 5:  But to not even be part of HomeKit is really fascinating and seems bad.
Speaker 4:  It'll like fall back to the old Siri. So you'll be like, turn
Speaker 4:  on the lights and I'm like, dude, it's not gonna not work. But the whole
Speaker 4:  complicated orchestration piece, right? Well where you're like, I'm just
Speaker 4:  talking to my phone and stuff is happening. I don't, it's of fuzzy. We
Speaker 4:  don't know yet. Is
Speaker 2:  All of this AI ification of Siri gonna
Speaker 2:  improve the fact that Siri doesn't understand me half the time?
Speaker 4:  Yes. Hey, so I think this is like the thing that they're gonna fix. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That that like this, my impression is that they're gonna fix that. But like
Speaker 5:  That is the thing I'm most confident about with New Siri is that like
Speaker 5:  text to speech and speech to text have gotten very, very, very good, very
Speaker 5:  fast. And I think if Apple can't do
Speaker 5:  that better with Siri, it would, it's just a gigantic failure. Like
Speaker 5:  I have a lot of faith in Siri recognition being very good
Speaker 5:  and the transcription stuff being very good. Yeah. Like there's no excuse
Speaker 5:  for that stuff not to be very good anyway. But is it the state of the art
Speaker 5:  on that is really good. Does
Speaker 2:  This mean that it would work or not work with HomeKit? I guess we'll just
Speaker 2:  have to see.
Speaker 4:  Right? So I, the, I think that you pick up your phone, you open Siri and
Speaker 4:  you say turn open the garage door that appears like it will not get
Speaker 4:  routed through the Apple intelligence version. The command will get recognized
Speaker 4:  and it'll go to like, okay, whatever was happening. And
Speaker 2:  Hopefully they've kind of like made all of Siri smarter
Speaker 5:  In that respect. And then old Siri will say, here's what I found on the web
Speaker 5:  for turn on garage lights. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So we, again, we don't know 'cause it hasn't shipped, but the idea
Speaker 4:  that home kit is not yet part of this appears to be
Speaker 4:  like what Jen has. Like that's what she's writing about. And I think that's
Speaker 4:  really fascinating because so much of what you want Siri
Speaker 4:  to orchestrate all the examples they gave. Right. The the canonical example
Speaker 4:  is tell me what time to leave for the airport to go to my daughter's dance
Speaker 4:  recital. Right. And it's always this like made up very
Speaker 4:  transactional thing you want to do. Yeah. Right. Like, I'm gonna go to
Speaker 4:  a place 'cause I'm cool. I I have a family and a means of
Speaker 4:  transportation. I leave the house. My daughter's in dance class.
Speaker 4:  It's, this is all very normal. You
Speaker 2:  Sleep in a race car bed.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. I've got a phone,
Speaker 4:  but like one thing you would want to do is like, tell me when to leave the
Speaker 4:  office to catch the train. Also turn on my thermostat. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. It is like you would just add that in or like a very common thing
Speaker 4:  people script in the home kit is like, turn on the lights by the time I get
Speaker 4:  home. Like you can see how you would want to have this more
Speaker 4:  complicated conversation about stuff in your house. And it,
Speaker 4:  I that all feels like not yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well and that's also one of the big things they're talking about with
Speaker 5:  Apple intelligence is context awareness and the, the
Speaker 5:  deep rabbit hole of context awareness is like inside of your smart home,
Speaker 5:  right? Like knowing where you are and what you're doing and how you're feeling.
Speaker 5:  Like that's the, that's how we get all this stuff going down the road.
Speaker 5:  So I I'm actually surprised that that wouldn't be like a
Speaker 5:  flagship feature of this, but they really didn't come up at all during the
Speaker 5:  keynote. So I guess I'm not tracked. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that is more or less what Jen's entire piece is about. But by the way,
Speaker 4:  there's also another piece in Business Insider that came out today just before
Speaker 4:  we started recording about the Alexa unit at Amazon that
Speaker 4:  is like ringing the bell about how bad Alexa is at this
Speaker 4:  stuff and how Amazon is underinvested in it. And the, the pivot is just not
Speaker 4:  easy to do. Yeah. Like you can't have had this thing and
Speaker 4:  be like, we're gonna turn it off and here's a somewhat unreliable,
Speaker 4:  extremely horny robot. Like you're just gonna like brick a bunch of Alexa
Speaker 4:  devices that people depend on. So it, it is a very hard pivot
Speaker 4:  and I, you know, because Apple is Apple, they can just do it. Especially
Speaker 4:  because
Speaker 4:  Siri, like, I feel like most people are like, oh, Siri is bad. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Here's a newer horny or fine, let's try that out for a while. Whereas I
Speaker 4:  think Alexa exists in your house in nowhere, in no
Speaker 4:  other context and you cannot break people's houses in that way. Right.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That's enough on the AI stuff. There's a bunch of other stuff that
Speaker 4:  we promised people we would talk about from dub dub.
Speaker 4:  You wanna do the small updates? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  There's, there's a bunch of stuff that we found like that people have found.
Speaker 2:  Some of it we, we already talked about like the, the, the buttons, the volume
Speaker 2:  buttons. When you press 'em, there's like a cool little animation and now
Speaker 2:  that I've seen it, it looks sick, but it it
Speaker 4:  Does. But they're, they're definitely gonna take the buttons off the phone.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 2:  I I don't wanna talk about it.
Speaker 2:  I'm fine. It's okay. But also
Speaker 2:  bilingual typing is gonna be a thing that's very cool now, which I'm
Speaker 2:  super, super excited about because like some of us speak a little
Speaker 2:  Spanglish and it, it sucks when it tries to auto correct you
Speaker 2:  and you're like, no, I, I know I'm bad at Spanish, but like, come on, I knew
Speaker 2:  this one. So, and it won't just work in Spanish, it'll work with a lot of
Speaker 2:  other languages. And so that's gonna be like really, really cool. Also, the,
Speaker 2:  the, the light is like the flashlight only on the iPhone
Speaker 2:  15 pro. You'll be able to like control the, the
Speaker 2:  beam of it and like the brightness of it, the
Speaker 5:  Interface for it looks awful. Yeah. Cool feature. But it looks
Speaker 5:  insane to try and manage.
Speaker 2:  I am excited to watch people use that in the movie theater when
Speaker 2:  they're trying to find their seats. That's gonna be a really fun time. If
Speaker 2:  somebody, if they can make like a shortcut to just do like a movie theater
Speaker 2:  mode that would rule the widgets are gonna be a little easier to customize.
Speaker 2:  Which I think we kind of, we saw a little bit of that during the, the event,
Speaker 2:  but it'll be nice. Wes, our, our
Speaker 2:  like Vision pro lover on staff is
Speaker 2:  super excited that he will, can see his keyboard now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. When he like, if he puts the headset on, he'll be able to see his keyboard.
Speaker 2:  Whereas before I guess he just like typed an oblivion and hoped he was right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's very much the Vision Pro experience until recently.
Speaker 2:  So less
Speaker 4:  Oblivious. Also you can use any Bluetooth mouse you want. Yes. Which
Speaker 4:  incredible future update for a 3,500 computer
Speaker 2:  Now you can use your own inputs on your computer.
Speaker 5:  I mean, as we heard Tim Cook say to Marquez this week, he loves the Magic
Speaker 5:  Mouse and it's perfect. And nothing has ever been wrong with it. So it's
Speaker 5:  surprising that they would allow this at all. Frankly,
Speaker 4:  That he didn't. I'm sorry he didn't, I I don't want to be hetic about this.
Speaker 4:  That was more information about the Magic Mouse than existed in Tim Cook's
Speaker 4:  brain at that time. I encourage everyone to go watch that clip. It's on.
Speaker 4:  We posted Marquez's tweet of that clip. He was like, rank
Speaker 4:  product launches and you did a bunch of easy ones and you see
Speaker 4:  like the devil on Marquez's shoulder like Magic Mouse.
Speaker 4:  And he and you just the grin on his face. It's very good. And then Tim Cook.
Speaker 4:  Very good. I interview a lot of CEOs. I watched them scramble and
Speaker 4:  you just, the dust in that man's brain
Speaker 4:  where he was like, what's in this file cabinet? Is it anything? He was like,
Speaker 4:  magic mouse. And then yeah, I, he came up with ergonomics.
Speaker 4:  He's like, what's a word I can say about mouse? Yeah. It wasn't, we love
Speaker 4:  the magic mouse.
Speaker 5:  That's true. It was ergonomics.
Speaker 4:  Definitely.
Speaker 5:  Good. Are they bad?
Speaker 4:  The ergonomics? He's like, it doesn't stab you when you hold it. That's the
Speaker 4:  apple design,
Speaker 2:  Low bar, low bar that I sat there. There's also gonna be some new
Speaker 2:  wallpapers that are like very retro looking and, and look kind of cool. I
Speaker 2:  personally love the one that's the, the green and and gray. Of course you
Speaker 2:  do. Yeah. I like bring me back to that eighties monitor experience. Right.
Speaker 2:  We
Speaker 4:  Know,
Speaker 2:  You know, you
Speaker 4:  Know, after last week everyone else knows too.
Speaker 2:  I just, sometimes there's like listeners who might have skipped an episode.
Speaker 2:  Why, but I want, I want them to know as well. So, but they, they're like
Speaker 2:  animated, they look really sick. So you gotta we, we did a whole story
Speaker 2:  kind of chronicling a lot of these things and and there's a video in there
Speaker 2:  and it just looks, it looks dope. Yeah. Like it, it,
Speaker 4:  The Susan Care wallpaper, she was original Mac designer. They have a lot
Speaker 4:  of her iconography. It's very cool.
Speaker 2:  It's very, very cool. And then now when somebody leaves you a
Speaker 2:  voicemail, it'll like just transcribe it so
Speaker 2:  it looks almost like a text in your phone. So that'll be
Speaker 2:  really cool if the transcription actually works because if it's
Speaker 2:  anything like the Google transcription, it does not understand my mom.
Speaker 4:  Interesting.
Speaker 2:  It also, my, my my best friend who says mayor,
Speaker 2:  mayor, the same way that the horse
Speaker 2:  and the, the, the office. Those came up the same way as
Speaker 2:  Siri. She was telling me yesterday cannot comprehend that.
Speaker 4:  Wait. She often talks about mayors and horses. She
Speaker 2:  Often talks about
Speaker 4:  Mares and the problem is that they're
Speaker 2:  Confused. Yeah. And so it's always like, yeah, there's a lot of mares in
Speaker 2:  your area. And she's like, cool.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So just to confirm, you have a friend who calls you and
Speaker 4:  leaves you voicemails about the number of horses in your area.
Speaker 2:  In her area.
Speaker 4:  And the problem that we have identified is that Siri
Speaker 4:  thinks that she's talking about local elected officials. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 4:  Just checking that. I understand. I, like I said, Tim, if you're listening
Speaker 4:  that's right up there with magic master ergonomics,
Speaker 2:  It's up there a problem to solve. Like let's fix it. Well it just, it struggles
Speaker 2:  with like, she was telling me she's got a really strong Texas accent and
Speaker 2:  it like, like Siri does not comprehend her. Yeah, that makes sense. But then
Speaker 2:  she's got, she speaks Spanish and she has like a, a lovely Mexican accent
Speaker 2:  in Spanish and it, it understands it perfectly. So a lot of times she's just
Speaker 2:  like, I'm just gonna talk to Siri in Spanish. Wow. Because otherwise it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be like, let's talk about elected officials.
Speaker 4:  I don't know how to say female horse in Spanish, but if I did rest short,
Speaker 4:  I'd be doing it right now.
Speaker 2:  Same. I don't know either. And I'm gonna try to keep it that way. Put it
Speaker 2:  in post it's fine for as long as possible. Don't don't tell me. My friend
Speaker 2:  will tell me and I don't care. So,
Speaker 2:  but, but there's also, there there're gonna be, there's more
Speaker 2:  options for charging too. So I guess you're gonna be able to like change
Speaker 2:  how you want your phone to charge. Oh
Speaker 4:  Right. Like limits, like to save the battery,
Speaker 2:  Which is nice because we've been able to do that on
Speaker 4:  Computers. Yeah. A lot. A lot of Android features here. I wouldn't just,
Speaker 2:  Yes. Or and yeah. Like everybody, thanks Apple. I
Speaker 2:  appreciate you bringing parody. So there's still a lot more.
Speaker 2:  I know people are really looking into it and if you see something who will
Speaker 2:  like tag one of us? Mainly David.
Speaker 4:  There's just a lot of like
Speaker 5:  This cool stuff you full quality of life stuff. Like
Speaker 5:  the, now if you, if you paste a link into messages, it'll show you the link
Speaker 5:  preview before it sends the message. That's good. Which is like, it's one
Speaker 5:  of those things that's like, am I gonna send a link that is 90,000 letters
Speaker 5:  long or is it gonna do the nice preview thing and now, you know, before you
Speaker 5:  send it, there's just, there's just a million of those and I think that's
Speaker 5:  great. I will say the one I'm most excited about is that you can make the
Speaker 5:  app icons bigger and get rid of the label underneath it. Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  instead of saying like having the Safari logo and then saying Safari under
Speaker 5:  it, you can have a bigger Safari logo in it doesn't say safari under it.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 2:  Looks nice.
Speaker 5:  Unbelievable. This is the stuff like I really, I cannot shake the
Speaker 5:  idea that Apple had a whole two hour long ww
Speaker 5:  DC planned. That would've just been all this stuff. And they would've told
Speaker 5:  us about all of it and it would've been a very normal WW DC And then at the
Speaker 5:  very end they were like, we have to do a chat GPT thing and just like blew
Speaker 5:  it all up. I'm sure that's not what happened, but like we're finding out
Speaker 5:  about much more of what's going on on these platforms than we typically do
Speaker 5:  after the keynotes.
Speaker 2:  And Apple is, the last few years they were doing kind of a thing, right?
Speaker 2:  Where one year it'd be like small updates, like they're nice but
Speaker 2:  smaller. And then the next year it'd be like, oh, there's some really sick
Speaker 2:  stuff in here. And this year was kind of gonna be one of those years
Speaker 2:  where it's like, okay, we had a kind of smaller year last year. Really six
Speaker 2:  stuff this year. And then now also Apple intelligence.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I, I I think I'm, I'm totally in this like
Speaker 2:  theory with you, this conspiracy, David,
Speaker 5:  All of my productivity nerd friends are so excited that you can now see
Speaker 5:  reminders inside of calendar. Ugh. Ugh.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna get's so much done. You guys
Speaker 4:  Don't even know the installer audience is freaking out. They, you,
Speaker 5:  They literally are. It's very exciting.
Speaker 4:  Well, what's interesting, j Peters, j Peterson, The Verge, who's back from
Speaker 4:  parental leave. Congratulations Jay. He wrote that The AI
Speaker 4:  upgrade cycle is here for Apple. So a lot of this stuff would've never driven
Speaker 4:  an incremental upgrade. Yep. You've got an iPhone 13, you can see reminders
Speaker 4:  and calendar. You're not buying an iPhone 16 except
Speaker 4:  now maybe Apple Intelligence is gonna make you excited to buy a new phone.
Speaker 4:  And Apple's kind of banking on this.
Speaker 2:  I mean they, they they need to that like, that that cycle has gone
Speaker 2:  down. Right. Like people just don't upgrade as often anymore. Yeah. Unless
Speaker 2:  they're VERGE listeners, in which case they're like, who,
Speaker 4:  Who is doing, doing that? Yeah. We have eight gigs of ram. Yeah. Disgusting.
Speaker 2:  Gross.
Speaker 4:  I have more mares than that at home. Which ones?
Speaker 2:  Eric Adams is
Speaker 4:  Like, who's there? Eric Adams does not have a gigs of ram.
Speaker 4:  I don't know exactly what kind of insult that is, but I know it to be true.
Speaker 4:  No, but the, the idea that these features that are
Speaker 4:  cool that we're excited about, again, I think regular people
Speaker 4:  are gonna experience and be happy about the theming. Yeah. Get ready for
Speaker 4:  just a wave of just bananas themes and all the phones
Speaker 4:  around you. 'cause people are excited about those things. They're not gonna,
Speaker 4:  if Apple gated theming to the next generation of phones, one that would be
Speaker 4:  outrageous. Two, it would not inspire one person to buy a new phone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But if they gate, you can talk to Siri naturally to the next generation of
Speaker 4:  phones and it can do all this stuff for you and we can make ads about it
Speaker 4:  and market these new capabilities that might drive the cycle.
Speaker 4:  So you can see why they sort of like put all this stuff aside. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like, because they did it for that, they did it for the watch. The watch
Speaker 2:  is like the new update is not gonna work with the series four and the series
Speaker 2:  five. So it's just like, I think iPads two
Speaker 2:  are affected if the iPad doesn't have an M1 in, it's not gonna get a lot
Speaker 2:  of the, the AI features. Oh
Speaker 4:  They finally got me.
Speaker 2:  They got you. Or
Speaker 4:  Did they You
Speaker 2:  Go get it. It's so good. We'll find
Speaker 4:  Out.
Speaker 2:  Zero regrets. Spend all of your money irresponsibly on
Speaker 2:  iPads.
Speaker 4:  Just, I've, I've bought so many speakers this year. I can't be buying iPads
Speaker 4:  too. Are you kidding me? Your wife's
Speaker 2:  Like, no,
Speaker 4:  It's no more stuff. Please.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I like it. It's very interesting that they're pushing it this way.
Speaker 2:  But they also got me, 'cause I'm on an iPhone 14 pro and I'm like, okay,
Speaker 2:  you're gonna do it. Yeah. And I was gonna, I was gonna hold out for the folding
Speaker 2:  one. I just, in my heart of hearts, I fully believe it's any day now.
Speaker 2:  And I mean any year now, not day. But
Speaker 2:  instead I'll get it.
Speaker 5:  Do we think Apple is running out of things to take 30% of, and
Speaker 5:  that's, that's why we're back
Speaker 4:  Here. I think the European Union is taking away things that
Speaker 4:  can take 30% from
Speaker 5:  Fair, which is, which is then its spins back to now we have to keep selling
Speaker 5:  you an iPhone every year because Apple has been on this run
Speaker 5:  for good or for bad of saying, you know, hold onto your hardware
Speaker 5:  longer. Like, you know, you know the thing Amazon has always said, like,
Speaker 5:  we don't make money when you buy your hardware. We make money when you use
Speaker 5:  it. Apple has always been a hardware company but has increasingly made money
Speaker 5:  when you use it. And so I think they've always pushed you to make new stuff,
Speaker 5:  but, or to buy new stuff rather. But I don't think it has been as
Speaker 5:  existentially important for you to upgrade your iPhone every year. As long
Speaker 5:  as Apple keeps getting 30% of everything you do. But I mean
Speaker 2:  They were still feeling the pressure on this. This was like something we'd
Speaker 2:  see earnings after earnings after big iPhones. They'd be like, okay, they
Speaker 2:  did it, but not as many people bought it this year. But it's fine because,
Speaker 2:  you know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But I don't know that I, I think we, everybody kind of got used to
Speaker 5:  that and it was, it was the services revenue was coming up to
Speaker 2:  Supplant it. I think we got used to that. I think Tim Cook was always probably
Speaker 2:  looking for, okay, what's that thing that can drive the next upgrade? Well
Speaker 5:  Sure he invested $10 billion in a car and is now trying to build like home
Speaker 5:  robots.
Speaker 5:  Tim's got a lot of plans. They
Speaker 4:  Don't have, they got a lot of plans. Yeah. They don't have like post phone
Speaker 4:  hardware plans. Right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. But yeah, so that's kinda my point is like, I think it, it does seem
Speaker 5:  like Apple in a very real way is back to we have to sell you an iPhone as
Speaker 5:  often as possible and it feels like the move for a bunch of years has been
Speaker 5:  away from that and now it is like back to that in a real way. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  As someone who loves gadgets. I love that. Maybe there'll be like cool stuff.
Speaker 2:  Do
Speaker 5:  You think that's why Apple made the iPhone 15 Pro scratch so easily, which
Speaker 5:  is why mine is scratched to bits and now I desperately need a new one in
Speaker 5:  September.
Speaker 4:  If they would just make a phone whose battery consistently landed, lasted
Speaker 4:  for a whole day, six months into its, I'd be very happy. Yeah. But my 15
Speaker 4:  pro is like, I'm done, I'm out. You want screen time controls.
Speaker 4:  What if I don't turn on? That's, I think about that. Okay, well we
Speaker 4:  should take a break. One more thing I wanna call out something I noticed
Speaker 4:  and we were talking about customizing control center. See all this? They
Speaker 4:  added one control from one app that I thought was very interesting, which
Speaker 4:  was the FordPass app. And you can lock your
Speaker 4:  doors and start your car, turn on the AC right from
Speaker 4:  control center 'cause FordPass has a thing. And then Jim Farley, see you
Speaker 4:  Ford tweeted, we're excited to partner with Apple and blah blah, blah.
Speaker 4:  I I think there, I think there's, there's there's GM walked away from
Speaker 4:  CarPlay towards getting tighter.
Speaker 2:  Are you, are you saying that they're gonna make an Apple
Speaker 2:  like Ford's making the Apple car?
Speaker 4:  GMs
Speaker 5:  Not making, you just did the, the Brian Windhorst on ES espn. Like, hey,
Speaker 5:  let's, let's see,
Speaker 4:  Here's what's happening. Don't I don't have it. Do you understand? Would
Speaker 4:  I don't have it all the way. I'm just, I'm, I'm, I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm suggesting that if somebody does know this information, they should tell
Speaker 4:  me this information in a way that I can report it. So
Speaker 5:  There's a Skunk Works team inside of Ford that is building good cars
Speaker 5:  instead of stupid ones. Is this
Speaker 2:  Ford Red? What if
Speaker 5:  That's just
Speaker 4:  Apple? Hold on. There actually is the skunkworks team inside of Ford. I know.
Speaker 5:  This is what I'm saying. What if all of
Speaker 4:  Those people run by Doug Field
Speaker 5:  Are just apple moles?
Speaker 4:  No, I, I am saying GM walked away from CarPlay
Speaker 4:  and the other giant American automaker is like, what if we
Speaker 4:  integrate more tightly with Apple software and that is suggestive
Speaker 4:  that they might do something else. And if you are a person who might know
Speaker 4:  what that something else is,
Speaker 2:  They're gonna bundle a phone with a car.
Speaker 4:  It's, they're gonna, they're gonna buy Verizon, whatever.
Speaker 4:  Look, you know.
Speaker 5:  Right. Buy an iPad, get a Mustang. Look at, here
Speaker 4:  We go. I would do that
Speaker 4:  as a person with a used iPad and a used Mustang
Speaker 4:  if I That's there's your Supercycle. Yeah. And you know, if you know what
Speaker 4:  I'm, we gotta take a break. We're right back.
Speaker 4:  The Vergecast. In case you missed,
Speaker 2:  just
Speaker 5:  Give, gimme it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Cool.
Speaker 5:  It's so weird. Anyway, but I think the way more interesting
Speaker 5:  thing is Phil Spencer, who runs Xbox at Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has been, I would say like aggressively and loudly
Speaker 5:  hinting that Microsoft is going to build a handheld gaming device for a long
Speaker 5:  time. And then just said out loud in an interview, I believe with IGN
Speaker 5:  quote I think we should have a handheld too. So like, there it
Speaker 5:  is. He was basically like, this is, this is a a time we're doing
Speaker 5:  software, we're talking about games. They also talked about bringing more
Speaker 5:  games to other platforms, which made a lot of Xbox people mad in the way
Speaker 5:  that it did before. But he's just, they're just making a handheld
Speaker 5:  like it's just coming. I
Speaker 2:  Think the, the big difference here is we've heard these rumors about a handheld
Speaker 2:  from them for ages, right? Like when they were really pushing cloud
Speaker 2:  gaming right after the, the Xbox series X was launched,
Speaker 2:  everybody was like, okay, yeah, they're gonna do like a cool cloud console.
Speaker 2:  And then that didn't happen because of the cloud gaming stuff just didn't
Speaker 2:  kind of take off as they wanted. Right? There was that there was also the
Speaker 2:  streaming box and it got killed. And so all this stuff got killed a couple
Speaker 2:  of years ago and then it's like, okay, you're, you're gonna make a handheld
Speaker 2:  now. Cool. You've been saying that for like half a decade at this point,
Speaker 2:  but the difference now is it sounds like it's gonna run Windows and
Speaker 2:  that rules the dream. And as someone who uses these little consoles,
Speaker 2:  that's awesome because the current version of like windows on one of these
Speaker 2:  little game consoles sucks. Now
Speaker 4:  What makes us confident that Microsoft can overcome the nature of running
Speaker 4:  Windows on a handheld,
Speaker 2:  Nothing. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Have you heard about our,
Speaker 5:  Our Lord and Savior arm processors?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean it is like, like it is the arm
Speaker 4:  Processor and we think the games, well, I guess you can res 'em down, right?
Speaker 4:  You you don't have to, you're not trying to run 'em at full quality anything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  The, the steam deck automatically res this stuff down. Right? And, and
Speaker 2:  so the the idea here is that it would do this, we've also, we were hearing
Speaker 2:  rumors about like Nvidia getting back into the arm stuff. They used to do
Speaker 2:  the, the te grow, which notably powers the Switch. There's
Speaker 2:  also Media tech, you know, everybody knows Media Tech. There's,
Speaker 4:  There's a media tech processor within 50 yards of you right now. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Probably within like five 50 inches
Speaker 4:  That a threat. I'm just saying like, there's everywhere you are, there's
Speaker 4:  a Media Protect processor. They're gonna, if you're that TV right there guarantee
Speaker 4:  you there's behavior
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent. You guys can't see it, but there's a TV there and it definitely
Speaker 2:  has media tech in it. Yeah. But, but media tech is also like gonna be doing
Speaker 2:  the processor stuff and, and doing arm processors and there's even rumors
Speaker 2:  that
Speaker 4:  Be No, just to be clear, they already are. They already do because they're
Speaker 4:  everywhere. They're Yeah. But they wanna make good ones. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Thank you. Thank you. That is an important clarification. They already make
Speaker 2:  arm processors now they wanna make the ones that don't suck and,
Speaker 2:  and there's rumors that they might be partnering with Nvidia. There's something
Speaker 2:  happening there. So like the potential for
Speaker 4:  That is the media tech Nvidia combo is like,
Speaker 4:  oh boy, that dude probably has a lot of money, right? Like that's not a
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That, that is Nvidia being like the
Speaker 5:  Rock and Kevin Hart, is that what you're saying?
Speaker 4:  Right. Yeah. There's a movie called She's Out of my league.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, this is accurate. This is accurate. But, but I think that's kind of
Speaker 2:  all is is what's driving some of this
Speaker 2:  like hype for a new Xbox handheld console is there's a lot of
Speaker 2:  potential that could change, but they also have to make windows
Speaker 2:  not suck visually. Yeah. Like I don't, I don't care about how it runs.
Speaker 2:  It needs to not suck
Speaker 5:  Visually. Like they just run, run the Xbox app, like done.
Speaker 5:  That's, it's just sitting there like all that software is just sitting there.
Speaker 5:  That's true. Microsoft could do it and it just hasn't for some reason.
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean theoretically the Xbox itself is running a
Speaker 4:  version of Windows, right? Remember, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah it does. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And they just cut it down to run one app. Well,
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They could do that again and then all of these other consoles which
Speaker 2:  suck so much with full windows on them could suck less
Speaker 2:  that. That's what I really want. If you can tell there's stuff already out
Speaker 2:  there that's really sick and the software is garbage.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So that's the thing, right? And I think to me the reason this is very exciting
Speaker 5:  is that
Speaker 5:  we really haven't had Sony or Microsoft
Speaker 5:  make a really truly like first class
Speaker 5:  competitive handheld lately.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm sorry. In a long time. P was a and
Speaker 2:  The Vida, I mean come
Speaker 4:  On. The PSP was incredible.
Speaker 5:  It was, I I don't doubt it.
Speaker 4:  Know that vi
Speaker 5:  Six 50 years ago,
Speaker 5:  that was fair.
Speaker 2:  Did you watch a lot of movies on your PSP?
Speaker 4:  No. No, no, no. But it had a Sony disc format, like a custom UMVI
Speaker 2:  Believe. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Those are the days Good. It was right up there
Speaker 4:  With the mega base.
Speaker 4:  By the way, shout out to all the people wandering through best wise sending
Speaker 4:  me photos of UL T speakers. There's a Sony marketing person
Speaker 4:  who's like, this is off the charts and that's because of us. The chart
Speaker 4:  was flatline below. Just to be clear, the chart has gone to five boop,
Speaker 4:  but we're doing it, we're making a difference.
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 5:  They're like, it's so weird. Nobody ever presses the button yesterday. Six
Speaker 5:  people pressed the button. What's happening there?
Speaker 5:  But yeah, that was, that was all the Xbox stuff. My guess would be
Speaker 5:  it's, there's, there's, I just feel like if you're Phil Spencer, you don't
Speaker 5:  say that if there's not something happening. Yeah. He is relatively near
Speaker 5:  future consider Yeah. Yeah. And he's been, he's been sort of sneaky about
Speaker 5:  this. Like he's liked tweets and, and has sort of intimated
Speaker 5:  that this is a thing that he thinks is interesting. But I think you look
Speaker 5:  at the continued success of the steam deck, the fact that
Speaker 5:  Nintendo has a switch to coming that everybody's very excited about like
Speaker 5:  this, this idea is not going away. Like I think
Speaker 5:  handheld gaming is going to be the next big thing for a very long time.
Speaker 5:  And it seems very clear that Microsoft also believes that. But they will
Speaker 5:  also happily ship you a white version of the same thing they already have
Speaker 5:  seven months from now. If that's what you'd rather have. Congratulations
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, Phil has been very direct being like, we did not do
Speaker 4:  well in this generation of the console wars. This is why we had to go buy
Speaker 4:  Activision. Right. And like figure out a way to compete.
Speaker 4:  We just did an episode of Dakota with Ash Parish about the gay market and
Speaker 4:  she was like, desktop PC gaming is going down. And then a million
Speaker 4:  people wrote us an email to point out that it's going up if you
Speaker 4:  count the steam deck,
Speaker 4:  right? Like that's where the growth is. Yeah. At part of the market. So if
Speaker 4:  you're Phil and you're like, okay, we're not gonna magically
Speaker 4:  start a new console generation tomorrow and win against Sony and its various
Speaker 4:  advantages. We are looking at Nintendo
Speaker 4:  gonna launch a switch to, I really hope they call it the Super Nintendo Switch
Speaker 4:  by the way. That'd be great. That will be a dominant moment. Where are we
Speaker 4:  growing? Where's the action? The Action is immobile good? We bought Candy
Speaker 4:  Crush. Settled. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Well,
Speaker 4:  And, and then the action is in these handhelds where we're getting growth
Speaker 4:  against PCs, gaming PCs are a thing. Like we can maybe get some action
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 2:  And also a lot of, like the switches success has been on the backs of indie
Speaker 2:  developers. Right. And, and Microsoft actually has a pretty good relationship
Speaker 2:  with indie developers. They, they put a lot of these games out on, on their,
Speaker 2:  the Xbox in general. And people are like, I would like to play that on a
Speaker 2:  handheld and maybe not the Switch. Right. And that would be like, oh,
Speaker 2:  I can play big triple A Xbox games that aren't
Speaker 2:  exclusive because Xbox apparently doesn't make exclusive games anymore. And
Speaker 2:  you can play like Hades two. That would, that'd be sick.
Speaker 4:  Well, I think ex the exclusive game strategy didn't sell off Xboxes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like the other way around. Yeah. They're like, oh fine, just play our
Speaker 4:  games in your PS five.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They, they
Speaker 4:  Didn't didn't buy, buy some stuff in this game. We'll be happy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Because all the ones that they wanna make exclusive, the FTC will be
Speaker 2:  like, I'm sorry, what?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Now, now they got other problems. Yeah. Anyway. I I And the idea that
Speaker 4:  they made a white one and they just won't sell it is like, this is your big
Speaker 4:  holiday marketing push. You are gonna build demand for the white one.
Speaker 5:  Kills me. Kills me. Anyway, the the next one
Speaker 5:  I wanna talk about while we're just rolling through gadgets here is Jabra,
Speaker 5:  which put me on a real like, emotional rollercoaster this week. It launched
Speaker 5:  a pair of headphones, two pairs of headphones, the Elite 10 and Elite eight
Speaker 5:  active new versions of it with a very cool feature that I was very excited
Speaker 5:  to talk about on this show. And then promptly announced that they're not
Speaker 5:  making headphones anymore. Like within a couple of hours they were like,
Speaker 5:  here's this dope new thing that we made. Nevermind. We're out. Goodbye.
Speaker 2:  Well, they're still making it. It's still, it's still gonna come, but that's
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 2:  They're they're closing the door behind
Speaker 5:  Them. Yeah. They're like, they'll support these for the next few years. And
Speaker 5:  on the one hand I'm like, okay, do I need like, ongoing software support
Speaker 5:  from my Bluetooth headphone manufacturer? Like, not really. But on the other
Speaker 5:  hand, like the, the last death nails of
Speaker 5:  a company's headphone lineup seem like a silly thing to recommend to people.
Speaker 5:  Wait, what's
Speaker 4:  The cool feature?
Speaker 5:  So the cool feature is they, these are wireless earbuds and they
Speaker 5:  come in a case and you can plug in the case to an audio source.
Speaker 5:  You can, with a, a head, you can plug it into a headphone jacker.
Speaker 4:  They're a Bluetooth transmitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They, they're a Bluetooth transmitter. And so they'll, they'll turn
Speaker 5:  any wired thing into a Bluetooth thing that then streams directly to
Speaker 5:  your earbuds.
Speaker 2:  This would've been great. Unbelievable. Like years ago when planes still
Speaker 2:  had
Speaker 4:  No, they do
Speaker 2:  Not an Well, you're fancy.
Speaker 5:  You fly Dude, Alaska, I was on a united flight yesterday and
Speaker 5:  not only did they have a screen, the screens had Bluetooth and you could
Speaker 5:  pair your AirPods to the screen. But if you had ever done
Speaker 5:  it before on a united flight, the first thing you had to do was go in and
Speaker 5:  forget it in order to then go repair it. So the,
Speaker 5:  this poor flight attendant had to give us like a four minute speech about
Speaker 5:  how to connect your AirPods to the screen in front of you. But it's a thing
Speaker 5:  you could do it, it was the first time I'd ever encountered that and it was
Speaker 5:  very exciting.
Speaker 2:  Well, and now I'm just disappointed in Alaska and American. Then
Speaker 5:  I guess United is a, is a trash airline with one good plane was,
Speaker 5:  I would say my experience so far.
Speaker 2:  You were just on the one plane.
Speaker 5:  It was on the one good plane.
Speaker 4:  Wait, can I issue a very, very small complaint about Delta? Yes,
Speaker 4:  please. And actually in general, a thing that I think should be legal. 'cause
Speaker 4:  I flew home on Delta. Yeah. They had Infinity War, but not end
Speaker 4:  game. Hmm. And I, 'cause you get on the plane, you're like, I gotta kill
Speaker 4:  five hours. And that's sitting right there for you. You nod in and out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I was telling Alex I had one too many drinks in the plane home.
Speaker 4:  You know, it was one of those fights that started in the afternoon, but ended
Speaker 4:  late in the evening. Oh yeah. And you're just like, I'm just gonna ride this
Speaker 4:  way. You just
Speaker 2:  Go,
Speaker 4:  You, you have to have both. I think Lena Khan should get involved. You have
Speaker 4:  to have both. Yeah. That is consumer protection right there.
Speaker 4:  Even though I've seen both of these movies five,
Speaker 2:  I was like, do you know what happens?
Speaker 4:  I, I believe you know, the Avengers do a good
Speaker 4:  job.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's largely crap.
Speaker 2:  Eli recaps movies, new second of the podcast.
Speaker 4:  In the first one, they don't do a good job. And in the second
Speaker 4:  one they do a good job. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That, that was a really good spoiler free
Speaker 2:  recap. I appreciate
Speaker 4:  It. Well, I did spoil the first one, but if you haven't seen the first one
Speaker 4:  here, what you do get on Delta. 'cause that's all they got that
Speaker 4:  I'm actually, well, I was talking to Chris Welch about this story yesterday
Speaker 4:  and Liz Lipato was there and she was like, I believe that taking the headphone
Speaker 4:  jack away from phones led to the
Speaker 4:  proliferation of people just listening to stuff out loud on their phones.
Speaker 4:  Mm.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  True. That's such a Liz Lipato take. Yes
Speaker 4:  It is. It's
Speaker 2:  No, but she's, she's correct because the Path train people are like, no
Speaker 4:  Gonna, yes. Like whatever. My headphones are dead. I don't wanna dink around
Speaker 4:  with these. I'm just listening.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you're you're gonna enjoy whatever I'm enjoying and suck it if you
Speaker 2:  don't.
Speaker 4:  All right. New idea for a phone. No speakers, just headphone
Speaker 4:  jacks. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Thinking that. Yeah. There's your courage. Apple. Don't get rid of the
Speaker 5:  headphone Jack. Get rid of the speakers. Yeah. Give me a power button
Speaker 5:  and no speakers on my phone. Done. Let's do this. I'm ready.
Speaker 4:  It's the opposite. It's like the Schiller nightmare. He is like, wakes up
Speaker 4:  in a cold sweat. He is like, what's happening?
Speaker 4:  Speaking of weird phones, the The Light Phone. People
Speaker 4:  love talking about this phone. They do not love buying it.
Speaker 4:  From what I can understand. They love looking at it and talking about it.
Speaker 4:  David, you saw it. The Light Phone three.
Speaker 5:  I haven't seen it. I've seen it over Zoom, but I, I talked
Speaker 5:  to Kait, the co-founder of the company, and I've talked to him a bunch
Speaker 5:  over the years. The weird thing about The Light Phone two
Speaker 5:  was that it was never a huge hit, but also according
Speaker 5:  to him, it has sold more units every year. It has been around. This
Speaker 5:  thing is five years old and it's sold more this past year than it
Speaker 5:  did in its first year, which I think is fascinating and is not something
Speaker 5:  you normally see from a phone. And they're in this position now
Speaker 5:  of the, the sort of intellectual idea that
Speaker 5:  I would like to change my relationship with my smartphone, I think is bigger
Speaker 5:  than ever. We are also more invested in our
Speaker 5:  smartphones than ever. And so what they tried to do was basically figure
Speaker 5:  out, okay, how do we get away from the idea that like
Speaker 5:  what you need is a phone that doesn't do anything at all and give you a phone
Speaker 5:  that just does the right things and not the wrong things. And actually that
Speaker 5:  is like the dream of the sort of minimalist smartphone and has been forever.
Speaker 5:  And there are a lot of people who say, oh, why do you need any
Speaker 5:  of this stuff? Just like, have more discipline and be more responsible on
Speaker 5:  your phone. To which I say that's a stupid argument.
Speaker 5:  It's true. But it's also like, if, if, if just discipline was the
Speaker 5:  answer to all of our problems, like the world would be a really different
Speaker 5:  place. And what it actually is is like the one
Speaker 5:  good thing about the social dilemma, which is an otherwise
Speaker 5:  I think disaster of a documentary was that it
Speaker 5:  framed the idea as like you against thousands of engineers trying to destroy
Speaker 5:  you. And I think that is like a pretty correct way to think about your smartphone.
Speaker 5:  And so light phone's idea is like, how do we just reset that balance? Right?
Speaker 5:  So they've, they added a camera but gave that camera much less to
Speaker 5:  do. They added NFC, but they're only gonna do payments with it. They
Speaker 5:  have a better screen. But because apparently people were having
Speaker 5:  trouble with E Inc. Like one of the things Kai said to me was that the single
Speaker 5:  biggest issue people had with the phone that like
Speaker 5:  50% of the reason people returned it or stopped using it was because of the
Speaker 5:  refresh rate of E Inc. Yeah. Which I thought was really interesting. There's
Speaker 5:  just something about it that just didn't work for people. So instead they
Speaker 5:  switched to a Matt Ed, which should refresh much faster, should be much easier
Speaker 5:  to type on, should look a lot better, but should have some of those same
Speaker 5:  kind of monochrome, not quite so blaring
Speaker 5:  properties and
Speaker 2:  Battery like support. Right. Because
Speaker 5:  It's all we'll see about battery The Light Phone two, two lasted forever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This thing is, it's substantially bigger, so it definitely has
Speaker 5:  more battery, but it does run that screen, but it's not doing
Speaker 5:  all that much with it most of the time. Well, yeah. And it's, and since it's
Speaker 5:  ol lead, it should only have to power some of the pixels and not the others.
Speaker 5:  So I, I reasonably high hopes for this thing, but
Speaker 5:  at least according to the traffic to our website, people are very interested
Speaker 5:  in this thing. It
Speaker 2:  Looks like I don't need it and I want it. I will never use
Speaker 2:  it. I know that, but I'm still like, oh,
Speaker 4:  This is, so I would love to get to a place where I could just take
Speaker 4:  a phone outta the house depending on my mood.
Speaker 4:  Like sunglasses. Yeah. And it would just like have my phone number and take
Speaker 4:  my messages and like, I don't think any of the carriers or
Speaker 4:  smartphone operating system vendors or smartphone makers want that to happen.
Speaker 4:  And it, it's funny 'cause if it did happen, I would buy like six phones.
Speaker 4:  So the,
Speaker 5:  The reason, it's, it's the carriers. I, I have been like meaning to write
Speaker 5:  a piece and I need to just sit down and write it that the reason dumb phones
Speaker 5:  won't work is because Verizon won't let them. I've had this moment
Speaker 5:  recently actually where I, I got the new iPad Pro and
Speaker 5:  just turned it on, logged into my iCloud account and all of a sudden I had
Speaker 5:  LTE on it and it was like the most magical
Speaker 5:  experience. And it was, it was my data, it's connected to my account that
Speaker 5:  it was just like, it was like, oh, because all this EIM stuff works,
Speaker 5:  I just have all of my stuff on this new device and it is
Speaker 5:  connected through my account. And it's like, oh, that's how all of this should
Speaker 5:  work. And it just super doesn't, and even you go to a place like Europe where
Speaker 5:  like physical sim cards are much more important and you can just pop your
Speaker 5:  sim out and pop it into another thing and that kind of works. It's just not
Speaker 5:  how it works in the US and it sucks. And, and so as a result,
Speaker 5:  I think what light is trying to do is buy a phone that
Speaker 5:  actually becomes your primary device. Yeah. Like I think The,
Speaker 5:  Light, Phone plus laptop or light phone plus iPad
Speaker 5:  is very much the thing that they're going for. They want you to have this
Speaker 5:  sort of simple minimal thing that goes in your pocket that has like
Speaker 5:  music and podcasts and directions and that's about it. And then if you wanna
Speaker 5:  do more stuff, you sit down at something else. And I think in a certain way
Speaker 5:  that's actually like a much healthier way to use technology and to think
Speaker 5:  about all of that. But it's probably, I mean, it's not probably,
Speaker 5:  it is definitely still not realistic for most people.
Speaker 2:  Did they show you like the photo app? That's, I I just wanna know,
Speaker 2:  is it showing photos in color or monochrome?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. That's a really good question. I would assume it's showing
Speaker 5:  them in monochrome. Yeah, because what, and he said
Speaker 5:  this very pointedly that they don't want you spending a lot
Speaker 5:  of time on your device looking at your photos. Apparently the thing that
Speaker 5:  they heard, one of the biggest reasons they put the camera on was to have
Speaker 5:  a QR code scanner that makes sense. And these people like to take pictures
Speaker 5:  of receipts and it's just like the little sort of toolsy things you need
Speaker 5:  to do with a camera rather than, I want a thing to take lots of beautiful
Speaker 5:  photos. They're like, their ideas again. Like you should not be looking at
Speaker 5:  your screen very often. Often. And even when you're looking at something
Speaker 5:  through it, you're still looking at it. Right. And so, yeah, the
Speaker 5:  way he described it is like, it's about documenting, not about like
Speaker 5:  fiddling. And so my, I, again, I haven't seen it, this thing's not shipping
Speaker 5:  till next year, which is a real bummer, but Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 5:  But I think the, the idea definitely seems to be like, get
Speaker 5:  in and get out as quickly as possible.
Speaker 4:  I'm utterly fascinated by this, but it the, I just am laughing at the idea
Speaker 4:  that a good computing outcome is you have a pretty useless phone and then
Speaker 4:  an iPad and at some point you're just like, none of this shit can do anything.
Speaker 4:  I mean, iPad is probably the wrong idea. I'm gonna sit down with this iPad
Speaker 4:  and not do a whole lot,
Speaker 2:  Not looking at Instagram on it.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. I but but the idea that you would like pick up a phone and
Speaker 4:  be like, push a button that's like, this is my phone right now. Take my calls,
Speaker 4:  send my messages. Yeah. You should be able to get there. Yes.
Speaker 4:  But you, you can switch between laptops more easily than you can switch between
Speaker 4:  phones and some of it's carriers 'cause of phone numbers and where you gonna
Speaker 4:  route calls and some of it is RCS and iMessages and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like,
Speaker 5:  I mean, even switching WhatsApp devices is a pan. It's gotten better
Speaker 5:  but it's still tough.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But that is like ultimately the dream. And
Speaker 4:  I dunno, maybe Apple needs to make the cut down phone or just make it easier
Speaker 4:  to put an iPhone into a mode like this. Apple
Speaker 2:  Will never do that unless they can figure out the app. 30%. Yeah, just
Speaker 4:  30%. Just like Tim for
Speaker 5:  $20 a month, we'll give you a chill phone inside of your
Speaker 5:  phone.
Speaker 4:  You know, am GI given the interest in The, Light, Phone. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's real. It might worth, it's worth a shot. So. Alright. Yeah, we should
Speaker 5:  keep going. Alex, the next thing on my list is literally, I should have just
Speaker 5:  put these two links as just ask Crans. Is
Speaker 5:  any of this anything, two different chip stories?
Speaker 5:  One is basically media tech. Our, the, the
Speaker 5:  flower of The Verge, our favorite chip company
Speaker 5:  is claiming it's out here doing Qualcomm level things and
Speaker 5:  everybody is out here basically being like, we now have fast chips too.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then there was this company Flow Computing that just published
Speaker 5:  a white paper being like, we haven't made any of these chips, but we know
Speaker 5:  how to make chips that are a hundred times faster. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The the, the flow thing is interesting in that they're basically
Speaker 2:  saying, we wanna compete with Arm and you, you
Speaker 2:  buy our
Speaker 2:  engineering that we have never actually proven. Oh. And then you go and you
Speaker 2:  engineer and do cool stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's my idea too. So
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 4:  Look, if you want to make a chip that's a hundred times faster, you just
Speaker 4:  come talk to me and then you do the work. Yep.
Speaker 2:  But, but, but Neely's gonna be like, yeah, that looks good. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Good job. Good
Speaker 4:  Job. But you have an idea for a building. Thank you for building, if you
Speaker 4:  bring your architect to me, I will describe that building to them an extraordinary
Speaker 4:  deep step. Well it's
Speaker 2:  Kinda like they are the architects and now they're looking for someone to
Speaker 2:  go build the building.
Speaker 4:  No, that's, that's normal. That's much more normal than I think what this
Speaker 4:  is.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. I guess it is in a weird spot, huh? Yeah. And I don't know what
Speaker 2:  the comparison is.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's one level away from like we've done it. Yeah. and more like we
Speaker 4:  have an idea we we for how to do it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We, we know the architect firm we wanna hire
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 2:  And it's you and it's you. And then also can you find someone to build this.
Speaker 2:  Yes. So yeah, that one is very interesting. Their, their claims are really,
Speaker 2:  really big. I know a lot of people are talking about it right now and trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out if it is an anything and I think it's a little bit of the
Speaker 2:  verdict is still out there.
Speaker 4:  So, but the idea here is that they have a new thing Yeah. Parallel
Speaker 4:  processing unit that it can be inside or outside the
Speaker 4:  chip and you can run parallel
Speaker 4:  workloads through that much faster Right. Than any other chip that exists
Speaker 4:  today. Right. This is the core of the claim.
Speaker 2:  Yes. But, and it's also weird 'cause parallel processing is having
Speaker 2:  kind of a moment right now or like people are re rethinking it.
Speaker 2:  So there's just, I I wanna say verdict is still a little
Speaker 2:  out on this
Speaker 2:  just because most of like, I I know enough to be like, Hmm,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'm gonna stay in that head space until proven otherwise. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  I think the, the media tech thing potentially
Speaker 5:  exciting. Like there's no reason everyone couldn't start making good arm
Speaker 5:  chips. Like if this is the thing that's out there, more power to
Speaker 2:  'em. Look, anytime somebody is saying, Hey let's compete, that's always good.
Speaker 2:  Right? Even though it's media tech and they are not known for their super
Speaker 2:  powerful processors. This is, it's it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  kind of cool because they're saying that that they'll be as fast, they'll
Speaker 2:  be capable of doing copilot PCs and that means that they have to do at
Speaker 2:  their NPU has to do at least 40 tops. And while we
Speaker 2:  still don't fully understand what Tops means in this context,
Speaker 2:  that is still like 40 is the number Microsoft gave everybody.
Speaker 2:  Sure. And so if, if media tech can get there when, like even Apple, the M
Speaker 2:  four, they were claiming 38. So
Speaker 2:  if Media Tech can do that, cool. Great.
Speaker 2:  Will companies put this in? We'll see. What
Speaker 5:  Are your thoughts on tops in this context? Neli.
Speaker 4:  Wow you guys,
Speaker 4:  I know what you can do with 13 Tops. Yeah. I've been given
Speaker 4:  an answer. You
Speaker 2:  Go to Fire Island.
Speaker 5:  Well there's the title of the episode today.
Speaker 4:  No, no I do, I actually have a real non Yeah.
Speaker 2:  What what is
Speaker 4:  13 family friendly answer.
Speaker 2:  What is 13 trillions operations per second.
Speaker 4:  So we had, we had, someone wrote to us
Speaker 4:  not about the other interpretation of what you can do with an incremental
Speaker 5:  Talk. Well we should say lots of people wrote to us about the other interpretation.
Speaker 5:  Thank
Speaker 4:  You guys. Yeah. Lots of people made jokes about one thing.
Speaker 4:  Although I will say that no, regardless of context, no one has said what
Speaker 4:  you can do going from 35 to 38, just saying that's fair. Hasn't been proven
Speaker 4:  out yet. But hey, the Raspberry Pi has
Speaker 4:  13 trillion operations for set. We were like, why? And so we got a
Speaker 4:  an email from Scott and he's like, look, there are lots of
Speaker 4:  iot applications where you have a sensor and then you have like something
Speaker 4:  like a camera and you want to know what happened. So the sensor
Speaker 4:  detects motion in a parking lot and you're like, is that the right car? And
Speaker 4:  you can take a picture of the camera so the sensor fires the camera and then
Speaker 4:  you gotta send a bunch of data somewhere to do image recognition. And
Speaker 4:  if you can bring it down to the edge, you're only sending bytes of data instead
Speaker 4:  of megabytes of data. Hmm.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's
Speaker 5:  Cool. That's a good one. That's
Speaker 4:  A good one. That's
Speaker 2:  Extremely good. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Good. I'll take it. Here we
Speaker 5:  Go. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I think the idea that there is some sort of like race
Speaker 4:  to put all of like that's great. That's a great workload.
Speaker 4:  I like, I like it. Yeah. You can see how people can do all this stuff in
Speaker 4:  all kinds of places, but Microsoft is like,
Speaker 4:  this is how many you need. Yeah. My Microsoft and they haven't de they have
Speaker 4:  not done even that example, we can detect a car.
Speaker 4:  Like that's the, that's fundamentally the example. We, this computer
Speaker 4:  can now recognize a car in a parking lot. Microsoft has not come up with
Speaker 4:  one of those things on a Windows PC for consumers that matters yet.
Speaker 2:  I can recognize a car in a parking lot too.
Speaker 4:  So many people can recognize a car in a parking lot. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  A lot of them.
Speaker 4:  It's true. But Microsoft is just out there being like,
Speaker 4:  you need this many 'cause it's gonna unlock what exactly
Speaker 2:  The future down the line. Don't, not right now. Just
Speaker 2:  the future. Just look over
Speaker 4:  That
Speaker 5:  Last thing we should talk about before we take a break is this bit of Google
Speaker 5:  news that is either
Speaker 5:  a small piece of news that ultimately doesn't matter that much or
Speaker 5:  the like little tiny butterfly flap of something sort
Speaker 5:  of enormous. And basically the news is Google
Speaker 5:  announced that it's going to be putting a lot more of the underlying
Speaker 5:  Android stack inside of Chrome os. So essentially
Speaker 5:  slowly but surely they're going to build Chrome OS to
Speaker 5:  resemble Android in such a way that they can build stuff faster that will
Speaker 5:  work on both platforms. I find this fascinating because there are
Speaker 5:  lots of rumors that say essentially, well I mean there have been rumors for
Speaker 5:  Jesus like a decade saying that Google is going to merge
Speaker 5:  Chrome OS and Android. Isn't that, was that fuchsia? I can never remember
Speaker 5:  all the code names. Okay. So there was fuchsia, which was I think even showed
Speaker 5:  up on like a random Nest device or something and then that got killed. But
Speaker 5:  these things have been separate projects that should never have been separate
Speaker 5:  projects. And then there have been rumors that there's going to be some
Speaker 5:  combination of them that gives you like a desktop mode on your Android phone
Speaker 5:  that essentially looks like Chrome os. And it's just all these little pieces
Speaker 5:  are coming together that is like, maybe we're actually gonna get this
Speaker 5:  cross device single thing combination that we should have had a really long
Speaker 5:  time ago.
Speaker 4:  Boy, do I disagree with you? Really tell me. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Fight.
Speaker 4:  Well I mean it, it all just comes down to like how complicated you want a
Speaker 4:  Chromebook to be in the end, right? So like an Android phone
Speaker 4:  is a lot, right? It has like a full app model. It has a bunch of capabilities.
Speaker 4:  It is just a, it has interface. Metaphors a
Speaker 4:  right, it's, it's more of a computer arguably than a Chromebook. Yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  initially was Linux running Chrome. Yep. And the whole
Speaker 4:  model was like, all you need is a browser. Then I think
Speaker 4:  they realized, and I, and I think that's great. I think for a lot of people
Speaker 4:  that is actually what you need. Yep. But then you gotta add things like windowing
Speaker 4:  and background apps and blah, blah, blah blah, blah. And you end up being
Speaker 4:  like, ah, shit, we made a computer. Like now this thing is just windows with
Speaker 4:  the app model. Instead of win 32 is Chrome. And then you're
Speaker 4:  like, ah, but we have this other thing. We should let it run Android apps.
Speaker 4:  Oh we need to put Google now in here because that's what we decided to announce
Speaker 4:  it. I you're like whatever. And you just like end up junking up Chrome os.
Speaker 4:  And so then you come to this like final place where you're like, it's just
Speaker 4:  an Android laptop.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Like fine. But you're just, I think you're just so
Speaker 4:  far afield of the initial vision for that product.
Speaker 2:  But the initial vision for that product
Speaker 2:  was kind of bad in that. Not, not, not like the, the just
Speaker 2:  this is a browser go forth. I think that was a great vision.
Speaker 2:  Execution was bad because it was always like,
Speaker 2:  oh, the idea was that it's only the browser, therefore it's super cheap.
Speaker 2:  But that cheapness also meant your monitor was garbage. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Your keyboard was garbage. Everything was garbage. And so people kept saying,
Speaker 2:  well I want a more power. Like I don't want it to be garbage. I would like
Speaker 2:  a pretty display. And they're like, okay, well that's gonna cost you more
Speaker 2:  money. And so it just kind of creeped up.
Speaker 5:  Right. And then you go, oh, what? But it's only a browser. Why would I pay
Speaker 5:  all that money? And then back it
Speaker 2:  Was, it was always this, this fight back and forth. And so it was, I think
Speaker 2:  for a long time it's been like, well just, just make it Android guys. Come
Speaker 2:  on. Like stop, stop messing around. You're not, you're not doing this other
Speaker 2:  thing. That was a really cool idea. That doesn't
Speaker 2:  actually exist in a world where you have different partners who want money
Speaker 2:  for the things they provide you to put into that computer.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, look, I is one of the few people in the world who's ever bought
Speaker 4:  a thousand dollars Chromebook Pixel. It worked really well when
Speaker 4:  you threw Windows, like high-end windows horsepower at it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like that Chromebook Pixel I believe an I five. Yeah. Like 16
Speaker 4:  gigs of ramp. That
Speaker 2:  Thing was
Speaker 4:  So good. It was beast. It was, it was great for its time. It's still going.
Speaker 4:  My mom still uses it, but no one's gonna spend that much money. 'cause then
Speaker 4:  you think you need a, a whole computer. But I would challenge you, I'm looking
Speaker 4:  at my Mac right now, it's running Chrome and then like mostly electronics.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 2:  My God. The files, you gotta, you're
Speaker 4:  Just, that's just screenshots. You can make 'em go away.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God. That was, it's really upsetting. Oh, that's be okay. I'm
Speaker 4:  Better now. It was just, it was just an open stack of screenshots. But like
Speaker 4:  the only native app really in my doc is Lightroom. And like most people
Speaker 4:  are not running Lightroom. Yeah. And you just look at that, you're like,
Speaker 4:  oh, this is just a bunch of electron apps. Fine.
Speaker 4:  But I don't think Google, I mean Google like, what else do I have to say?
Speaker 4:  Like, is there, they never ran the idea to completion and used the ecosystem.
Speaker 4:  So now they're shuffling up all those teams. Right. Dave Burke, who ran
Speaker 4:  Android for a long time is gone as that's today that news broke
Speaker 4:  today. Hiroshi, who was in charge of the whole thing left.
Speaker 4:  Right. He's, he's off finding himself on some other projects at Google
Speaker 4:  and like they're, they're just shuffling up those teams and this seems like
Speaker 4:  a natural outcome of that. Yeah. You'll recall like they, a
Speaker 4:  year ago or two years ago, they were like, Android tablets are gonna make
Speaker 4:  a comeback 'cause of folding devices. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Hey, the Pixel tablet is cooler than people think. That's, that's my hot
Speaker 5:  take for the day. But I will say, I mean on this front, I think go the Google
Speaker 5:  sort of stated reason for doing this is it lets them roll out AI stuff across
Speaker 5:  these two platforms faster. And I think that's fair,
Speaker 5:  right? Like you, you look at some of the stuff Google's already doing with
Speaker 5:  Chromebook plus devices like the, it has the generative AI
Speaker 5:  wallpaper and the magic editor in Google photos. Like that's stuff you
Speaker 5:  want to do on device as much as you can. And so building that
Speaker 5:  into the stack for both of those platforms makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 5:  Nila, to your point, I'm, I'm very bullish about this combination for
Speaker 5:  Android phones and I'm very skeptical about it for Chromebooks. Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm kind of with you in that, like, the idea of being able to
Speaker 5:  blow up my Android phone, whether it's for Android tablets or
Speaker 5:  foldable devices or whatever, like a thing that gets more chromeo se the
Speaker 5:  bigger it gets, I find very compelling. But a, a Chromebook that looks
Speaker 5:  more like Android is an experiment that Google has tried many times and it
Speaker 5:  has typically gone very badly.
Speaker 4:  Right. 'cause Android developers do not want to put their apps on a laptop
Speaker 4:  in that way. Right.
Speaker 5:  And, and it's, and it requires a huge amount of work to do it well. And when
Speaker 5:  you don't do it well, it kind of sucks and it mostly doesn't get done well.
Speaker 5:  And I, I yeah. So I agree. I think this is a, a thing that for
Speaker 5:  Chromebooks is gonna be complicated
Speaker 5:  if we are in fact getting this sort of big combined
Speaker 5:  user interface thing that might happen here or Google
Speaker 5:  is telling the truth and this is just like the bottom of the tech stack so
Speaker 5:  that they can get Gmails help me write to run
Speaker 5:  4% faster on your Chrome. Yeah. I just, which is fine.
Speaker 2:  Love the idea that they're gonna put like full Android on a, on a Chromebook
Speaker 2:  and then just completely dumb it down. Just like No, you only open the
Speaker 2:  Chrome app. That would be hysterical.
Speaker 4:  They've they've been there before. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know what's funny about that is the Chrome app for Android is so,
Speaker 5:  so, so much worse than Chrome on Chromebooks that
Speaker 5:  like that what an unbelievable Chromebook down downgrade that would be if
Speaker 5:  they did
Speaker 4:  That. Yeah. Because they had to make Chrome on Chromebook a real browser.
Speaker 4:  Right. 'cause that is the application model.
Speaker 5:  It's the best version of Chrome that exists in the world.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I know a lot of designers who run Figma in expensive Chromebooks. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  Oh interesting. And expensive is like a but they, but
Speaker 4:  they just like don't have MacBooks anymore. They're just like, we just run,
Speaker 4:  we live in Figma. We might as well have a Chromebook or some of 'em have
Speaker 4:  Chrome boxes that Chrome desktop fancy monitors and that's just the end of
Speaker 4:  that. And it's like, that's the application model. And if you bring a browser
Speaker 4:  of that capability to a phone or a tablet, you
Speaker 4:  can't take your 30% anymore. Yep. And that, and that's why the iPad
Speaker 4:  browser sucks everybody. Yep. All the way around.
Speaker 4:  And that's also why Android tablets have the not great version of
Speaker 4:  Chrome. Instead of the Chromebook version of Chrome. There's no reason a
Speaker 4:  powerful Samsung tablet shouldn't run full on Chrome. Same
Speaker 4:  business pressure exists. Yeah. Anyway, that's totally separate. It's
Speaker 11:  Fine.
Speaker 4:  30% Bring me a suitcase
Speaker 4:  actually. Apple and Google. I would pay a subscription fee for a full
Speaker 4:  desktop class browser on my mobile devices. That'd be one thing
Speaker 4:  You want to get me to pay a subscription fee for Apple One or Google One.
Speaker 2:  But what if it's the same garbage?
Speaker 4:  No, it has to be the good. It has to be the good browser.
Speaker 11:  Alright. Arc.
Speaker 5:  What if instead of a browser, it's just a chat bot that lies to you?
Speaker 5:  Can I interest you in that
Speaker 4:  horniness in the history of The
Speaker 4:  I'll sell out. You just tell me what to say. You show up. No one's
Speaker 4:  fired the gun. It's a problem. All right, David, what's your lightning round
Speaker 4:  item?
Speaker 5:  I think I wanna talk about this survey that Pew did about how
Speaker 5:  people get news on social media platforms. We've talked
Speaker 5:  obviously a lot about this. This is like, the only thing anyone on
Speaker 5:  Threads ever talks about is news on threads. Because Adam, Ari like keeps
Speaker 5:  saying how much he hates news, but loves news but hates it, but doesn't want
Speaker 5:  it, but loves it. And so Pew did a study
Speaker 5:  basically looking at four platforms. So it was X,
Speaker 5:  TikTok, Facebook and Instagram and essentially asked people,
Speaker 5:  do you get news on this platform? And is it like a primary reason
Speaker 5:  you come here? And the numbers are sort
Speaker 5:  of fascinating. Like in almost every case, like I'm looking at this now,
Speaker 5:  over 80% of people on all platforms see news content
Speaker 5:  on all four of those platforms. So like on on X
Speaker 5:  they call it news related content. And it's, it's sort of like news and news
Speaker 5:  adjacent things. And 92% of people on X reported seeing
Speaker 5:  it. It was 90 and 91 for TikTok and Facebook, Instagram the lowest at 82%.
Speaker 5:  All huge numbers. But in almost every
Speaker 5:  case, most people said it's not the primary reason they
Speaker 5:  go to the platform. X was the exception. Two thirds of people said it was
Speaker 5:  either a, I think it was a major or minor reason to go. But
Speaker 5:  TikTok, Facebook and Instagram all somewhere between like 30 and 40% of people
Speaker 5:  said that's even a reason they think about going to those platforms,
Speaker 5:  which I just think is very telling. Right. We talk a lot about news and these
Speaker 5:  companies keep telling us news is a tiny percentage of what people do and
Speaker 5:  people don't actually care and they're not here for news. And the only people
Speaker 5:  who care about news are the people who report on the news. And everybody
Speaker 5:  should just shut up about the news for once. And this was, I just thought
Speaker 5:  this was a really interesting way of looking at that. And Pew
Speaker 5:  has also come out and said over and over and over again that for young people
Speaker 5:  in particular, TikTok is where they're seeing a lot of their news. Even if
Speaker 5:  they're not seeking it out, that's how news finds them. So there's like a,
Speaker 5:  there's just the amount of like accidental news consumption that is happening
Speaker 5:  on social media right now, just fascinates me. Especially in an election
Speaker 5:  year. All of this is gonna get very weird. I just thought it was really interesting.
Speaker 2:  Well, particularly because the news isn't always
Speaker 2:  packaged well.
Speaker 4:  No. Right?
Speaker 2:  Like, like it's always, it's it's frequently packaged in to, to get you
Speaker 2:  as upset as possible.
Speaker 4:  Can I, can I just like roll this into my lightning red item?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, go for it.
Speaker 4:  So mine is a bunch of Elon stuff. So one is just a victory
Speaker 4:  lap for me. Elon drops his lawsuit against opening. I shocking. 'cause he
Speaker 4:  didn't have a contract and I super told you so. And you can't
Speaker 5:  Reach a contract. You don't have would, would you say that's a fair legal
Speaker 4:  Reason and that literally, I, when back looks at that post hundreds of comments
Speaker 4:  being like, you can assemble a contract on it. And it's like, no, you can't.
Speaker 4:  You just can't. You have, and if you could, you you would
Speaker 5:  If he wanted to he would. He. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. I'm just saying he he did, he didn't.
Speaker 4:  So whatever, if you wanna sue someone, come up with
Speaker 4:  a good idea. One, but two bunch of
Speaker 4:  stuff about SpaceX this week, the culture at SpaceX, that actions
Speaker 4:  towards women at SpaceX, the, the sexist culture at SpaceX
Speaker 4:  in two stories. Yeah. One, the Wall Street Journal big expose,
Speaker 4:  talked to a number of people and then the, the second one,
Speaker 4:  a lawsuit from former SpaceX employees saying it's a culture of harassment.
Speaker 4:  We wrote them both up. Right. What you do. And the headline
Speaker 4:  we wrote on the Wall Street Journal one was not as just
Speaker 4:  aggressive as people wanted. And I got tweets about it and I was like,
Speaker 4:  we have to be really careful when we write these headlines, especially
Speaker 4:  when it's not our reporting. Right. We're we're talking about a Wall Street
Speaker 4:  Journal story. And if you look at the Wall Street Journal story, the journal
Speaker 4:  story is very carefully reported and it's mostly about
Speaker 4:  one woman, an intern who lawyered up with
Speaker 4:  the same lawyer as Elon and SpaceX to
Speaker 4:  refute the story. And she sent a bunch of affidavits in
Speaker 4:  which confirms some of the reporting of the story. But she's like, none of
Speaker 4:  this is true. Which is weird. Like the construction of that story is weird.
Speaker 4:  And the thing you're saying, David, is like people encounter their news and
Speaker 4:  then the thing Alex is saying is that news is not, that news is not packaged
Speaker 4:  well. Right. What everyone wanted us to say was
Speaker 4:  like,
Speaker 2:  Elon did look.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Look at, look at how bad this is. And indeed there's a lot of bad stuff
Speaker 4:  in there if you rolling around your own company being like, will you have
Speaker 4:  my babies? Don't do that. And then you retaliate against the women who say
Speaker 4:  no. Like that is very bad when the president of your company who's a woman,
Speaker 4:  retaliates against a woman who was helping to plan your birthday party
Speaker 4:  because she suspected that the phone call from the husband to the woman
Speaker 4:  was evidence of an affair as opposed to the planning of a birthday
Speaker 4:  party. That's bananas. Yeah. Maybe that should have been our
Speaker 4:  headline like birthday party affair situation at SpaceX
Speaker 4:  Bananas.
Speaker 4:  But this tendency to overread the news for maximum
Speaker 4:  emotional value or to assign some emotional value
Speaker 4:  to something, even if that's not what the evidence of the news, like that
Speaker 4:  is the thing social media does. It is in particular the thing that
Speaker 4:  Threads does because that is how you get engagement in that algorithm. So
Speaker 4:  there's no news there. Adam Ary is like,
Speaker 2:  We refuse.
Speaker 4:  He's like, we, we just want, you know, people to talk about politics or he's
Speaker 4:  like, we don't want people to talk about politics. We just want 'em to talk
Speaker 4:  about, you know, things that are not politics, like sports and fashion. And
Speaker 4:  it's like,
Speaker 4:  I don't, okay. There's no politics in sports famously. Yeah. No one, no
Speaker 4:  politics
Speaker 2:  There and, and either of those ever,
Speaker 4:  Nothing about the fashion industry has anything to do with the way the world
Speaker 4:  works. No. Anyhow, all I'm saying is that then you look at the Threads algorithm
Speaker 4:  and it's like just rage bait like that is
Speaker 4:  algorithmically what it will show you. Yep.
Speaker 2:  And like old rage bait lately. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I just like that little bit where it's like our, the
Speaker 4:  people that are being serviced here, being careful
Speaker 4:  and maybe we were too careful and we'll accept that criticism when it's,
Speaker 4:  I don't think you can, that our story is written by Liz, by the way, like
Speaker 4:  The Virgin and Liz Lipato are too easy on Elon Musk is a very hard case
Speaker 4:  to make. Yeah. Based on our work, we are careful
Speaker 4:  because we want our shots to land and we're especially careful when it's
Speaker 4:  other people's reporting. Right. That's just the way it goes. But I would
Speaker 4:  just say like, what social media has done is allowed a lot of people
Speaker 4:  who don't have to practice that care to participate in the media ecosystem,
Speaker 4:  which is great.
Speaker 4:  But it is also like
Speaker 4:  weird. Like people, I think people are confused. So you accidentally encounter
Speaker 4:  a lot of news, but you, you, there's not the part of the other
Speaker 4:  end where it's like, I know how this was made or I
Speaker 4:  am being careful. It's like if you optimize for engagement, you will get
Speaker 4:  engagement.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And oftentimes that engagement is done to like, it, it, it's just really
Speaker 2:  explosive. Right. Like it is, it's just, I I see it on, on TikTok a lot
Speaker 2:  'cause I went through and was like, we were hearing a bunch of different
Speaker 2:  news was popping up on TikTok. So I went and like searched that news. So
Speaker 2:  now my feed is just all of that news and the stuff, the
Speaker 2:  rhetoric is really heated. The rhetoric is very different than how you would
Speaker 2:  normally report on a story where you would be really cautious and careful
Speaker 2:  without every single part of it. Instead it's just like, yeah, these people
Speaker 2:  suck. This is evidence, right. Let's just get into it. And I'm like,
Speaker 2:  well no, you can't. That's not how you cover this
Speaker 2:  stuff. And there's a lot of reasons we cover it that way. Both because we
Speaker 2:  wanna be accurate and and honest and because we wanna like Yeah. Yeah. There's
Speaker 2:  just a bunch of reasons to do it and, and these people don't seem to have
Speaker 2:  the same concerns.
Speaker 5:  Well, and there's also, I think one of the things that really jumped out
Speaker 5:  to me in this Pew study was that I think across
Speaker 5:  platforms, somewhere between like half and three quarters
Speaker 5:  of people said they pretty frequently
Speaker 5:  see inaccurate news on those platforms. And at some point the
Speaker 5:  only response to that is just total nihilism. Yeah. Right. Like,
Speaker 5:  you just assume nothing is real, everything is chaos. You, you
Speaker 5:  can't trust anything. You can't believe anything. This all came to you by
Speaker 5:  accident. Right? Like it's, it's killing the idea of sit, like sitting down
Speaker 5:  and reading the news like that as a behavior that people do on purpose
Speaker 5:  is dying because this stuff is just bombarding at you all the time. And so,
Speaker 5:  like, it's hard to be a news consumer now. And so I think all these people,
Speaker 5:  especially when these things are coming up, they're used to that inflamed
Speaker 5:  rhetoric. They're used to have this stuff being wrong anyway. And so you,
Speaker 5:  you don't know the provenance, you don't know how this stuff works. You don't
Speaker 5:  know the story. It's just all sort of happening around you. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  how on earth are you supposed to make heads or tails of anything? Yeah. In
Speaker 5:  that ecosystem.
Speaker 4:  Wait, what is the, what is the source of truth? Right? Like, and all these
Speaker 4:  platforms wanna say they don't wanna be arbiters of truth. Mark Zucker famously,
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna be the arbiter of the truth, but then you need a place to go.
Speaker 4:  Right? And that's what media institutions are supposed to be. I'm not saying
Speaker 4:  any of us do a good job of this. Like that is the thing that we have
Speaker 4:  allowed to wither away in the, in the platform era. But it's stories like
Speaker 4:  this. Like if you go look at the comments of the Wall Street Journal article,
Speaker 4:  the comments are full of people being like, this is just a hit piece. Right.
Speaker 4:  Like their own comments section is a disaster of people being like, I don't
Speaker 4:  even, I don't even read this. I think it's bullshit because we have now conditioned
Speaker 4:  a bunch of people 'cause of social media to believe that everything is overdone
Speaker 4:  or sensationalized or just done for outrage or just done for
Speaker 4:  clicks. And in this case, what you're looking at is,
Speaker 4:  boy, the culture at SpaceX appears to be a disaster. Like from
Speaker 4:  top to bottom there are a whole bunch of very
Speaker 4:  unhappy women. There are women who have been retaliated against
Speaker 4:  by the most senior women at the company.
Speaker 2:  Which none of this is like, when I first saw this story, I was like, oh,
Speaker 2:  didn't we cover this already? Yeah. Because, because we've seen this story
Speaker 2:  from SpaceX before. Lauren Gresh used to cover it a lot for
Speaker 2:  us. And, and to just see it crop up again, it's like, oh,
Speaker 4:  And now there's all this additional reporting Yeah. In the journal where
Speaker 4:  it's like, I just like, again, I, if you're listening to this and
Speaker 4:  you're thinking about starting a company, one thing you should not do is
Speaker 4:  walk around your company asking employees if they will have your children
Speaker 2:  Just don't do it.
Speaker 4:  It feels like a very basic rule that we have to lay out at this time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's not a rule that appears to apply to Elon
Speaker 4:  against whom there are credible allegations that a woman who
Speaker 4:  accused him of sexual harassment he responded to by offering her a horse.
Speaker 4:  It does come back to horses a lot. It always does. On this episode first.
Speaker 5:  Oh, on that note, Alex, I actually have a question for you. What's your lightning
Speaker 5:  round thing?
Speaker 2:  My lightning round thing is also related to horses.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. 'cause did you guys ever, did you guys go to Alamo Draft House? Either
Speaker 2:  one of you Draft house fans?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, all the time. They're, they just opened one like a mile from me
Speaker 5:  maybe a year ago. And it's now my go-to movie theater.
Speaker 2:  So I'm, I'm gonna be be real old right now in, in
Speaker 2:  my twenties. I spent a lot of time in Austin, Texas, which is
Speaker 2:  where Alamo Drafthouse started. I went to a lot of screenings, went to a
Speaker 2:  lot of parties, went to a lot of things, sort of knew Tim League, the,
Speaker 5:  Is that the one that's also like a movie museum? And they have like the most
Speaker 5:  incredible collection of old stuff from movies.
Speaker 2:  The, the Alamo Drafthouse there. I think
Speaker 5:  It is.
Speaker 2:  I don't, I could be wrong. One of them might be there. There's a bunch of
Speaker 2:  different ones. Say they've, some have come, they've gone. It is
Speaker 2:  great. Every time I go to Austin now I'm like, oh, that draft house is closed.
Speaker 2:  And I once saw people run for their lives because they didn't want to talk
Speaker 2:  to the audience because we were so mad at them about the movie. It was super
Speaker 2:  cool. Poughkeepsie tapes. But, but so Alamo
Speaker 2:  draft drafthouse famous, famous institution, one of like, kind of the core
Speaker 2:  movie theater franchises and very terminally
Speaker 2:  online. It ran its own blog for years. Badass Digest. It
Speaker 2:  really, it was famously huge friends with Harry Knowles who is like the
Speaker 2:  original movie blogger. We don't talk about him anymore. You can go
Speaker 2:  Wikipedia y and and they have been in
Speaker 2:  a lot of trouble the last few years. There was allegations of
Speaker 2:  labor issues there and sexual harassment and, and lots of
Speaker 2:  sorts of things. And then COVID hit and they, like every movie
Speaker 2:  theater friend company got bodied
Speaker 2:  really, really badly. They filed for bankruptcy in 2020. One whole new
Speaker 2:  like reorg happened, got in a bunch of investors. Tim League was still
Speaker 2:  in charge. Then last week I believe
Speaker 2:  they suddenly closed a whole bunch of their theaters in Dallas.
Speaker 2:  And that was a real bummer because I was planning to go to them and
Speaker 2:  it was, it's fine. I'm through it. And then this week they announced that
Speaker 2:  Sony has purchased them. So, so yeah. Alamo is now
Speaker 2:  gonna be completely owned by Sony. I assume you're gonna see some Sony movies
Speaker 2:  there, but you should probably still see all the other ones. 'cause like
Speaker 2:  Disney still has the, the biggest market share of, of
Speaker 2:  films. And I don't think Disney like, excuse me. I don't think Alamo is gonna
Speaker 2:  be like, no, we're not gonna screen a Star War.
Speaker 4:  Well, I think the, you know, Netflix owns a bunch of theaters and they do
Speaker 4:  limited theatrical runs. 'cause they gotta keep the stars happy and get them
Speaker 4:  star awards
Speaker 2:  Also. Yeah. That's, it's all for awards.
Speaker 4:  I think Sony actually wants to like, have a chain of movie theaters. I think
Speaker 4:  it's very different.
Speaker 2:  It it is very different. Like Sony is just like, no, we want this to be a
Speaker 2:  business again. And there was a reason it
Speaker 2:  wasn't allowed to be a business. And, and the, the ramifications of the paramount
Speaker 2:  decree were huge. Right? Like we got independent film, we got, we got
Speaker 2:  more queer film, we got more women in films, more people of color in films.
Speaker 2:  There was just like miscegenation was illegal to, to show on film. And
Speaker 2:  then the Paramount Decree came out and they started to soften those rules
Speaker 2:  a little. It took a long time. But there's just, the paramount decree was
Speaker 2:  very, very important for competition in the filmmaking industry.
Speaker 2:  And the fact that it has gone now has always been kind of a bummer. Even
Speaker 2:  though streaming has really taken a lot of that audience and Sony's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, we're just gonna follow back and it's 19 30 80.
Speaker 4:  Well, yeah, but just to make the argument times have radically changed. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There is not a booming theatrical business anymore. It's true. True. It seems
Speaker 4:  to be declining. Does Almo Drafthouse even exist unless the
Speaker 4:  studio like Sony shows up? Like Sony doesn't have a streamer. Yeah, they
Speaker 4:  have crunchy roll. They got Sony picture core. Oh, it's like
Speaker 4:  Bravia core.
Speaker 2:  Wow. Just like rise up, just really hurting yourself there.
Speaker 2:  But
Speaker 4:  They were like, do you wanna watch Madame Webb at 80 megabits per second?
Speaker 4:  Did you? And I said, no, sir, I do watch
Speaker 5:  The only way to do that's gonna be at an Alamo draft house from on. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna like at 2:00 AM a little drunk.
Speaker 5:  No, I think the answer to your question, Eli, is no, it doesn't. And and
Speaker 5:  I think the, like, the idea that we have to, you know,
Speaker 5:  protect the movie industry from the big bad studios and
Speaker 5:  theaters is like such a long gone phenomenon at this point.
Speaker 2:  No, I disagree.
Speaker 5:  What we desperately need is someone with real money
Speaker 5:  trying to get everyone back into movie theaters.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But I don't think it should be the movie theater. I don't think it
Speaker 2:  should be the people making the movies,
Speaker 5:  But no one else is incentivized to do
Speaker 2:  It. But like Alamo's issues were
Speaker 2:  not necessarily, like some of the Alamo's issues were declining viewership.
Speaker 2:  That's totally true. A lot of Alamo's issues were overextending
Speaker 2:  themselves. They've got a theater in Fi Dye and I can always get a ticket
Speaker 2:  to see a movie there because no one goes to the see the movies in fi d
Speaker 2:  Why? That's
Speaker 5:  All the financial industry movie theaters now. That's everywhere. That's
Speaker 2:  Not true. That's,
Speaker 4:  It's like a handful of blockbusters that get sold out. And then no other
Speaker 4:  movies like
Speaker 2:  Alamo has famously been very good at programming big events around their
Speaker 2:  other movies and, and they were really, really good at it. But they've overextended
Speaker 2:  themselves. They never recover from 2021. And I don't
Speaker 2:  think it necessarily needed to be Sony that went and did this. Right.
Speaker 2:  I don't think it should be these movie theaters because they are already
Speaker 2:  control, they're already so vertically integrated. We shouldn't just add
Speaker 2:  more on and give up. We should in fact say, Hey, you shouldn't be
Speaker 2:  able to own everything all the way down because it does
Speaker 2:  actually measurably make the entire industry worse and
Speaker 2:  less creative.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I just, they they didn't buy a MC, they bought Elmo Drafthouse. I
Speaker 4:  know. And
Speaker 2:  They're, I went there so
Speaker 4:  Much. Right. Like, I, I, I'm, I'm with you and I'm usually the one who's
Speaker 4:  like the most pro diversified competition on the show. Is
Speaker 2:  This just me being super film nerd? We
Speaker 4:  Are. No, I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't so diversified though. Like, the idea that the movie theaters is
Speaker 5:  this like, gigantic business that we can't possibly let the studios back
Speaker 5:  into is just not how it works anymore. Like, it, it,
Speaker 5:  if anything, we should be saying Sony can't own a streaming service.
Speaker 5:  Like that's the, that's the scarier way to take too much control of the
Speaker 2:  Industry right now. Right. What's already happening in the industry, I think.
Speaker 5:  Right. So be mad about that. I
Speaker 2:  Just, again, why, I mean, I'm mad about that. I,
Speaker 4:  I just, again, I just want to remind everyone that the streaming companies
Speaker 4:  that Sony owns are Crunchy Roll and Sony Pictures core, which
Speaker 4:  I use because it
Speaker 5:  That is crackle erasure and I will not stand for it.
Speaker 4:  It streams at 80 megabits per second. Does Crackle still
Speaker 4:  exist? Only leads to so many televisions? No, it does not. Sir. Crackle has
Speaker 4:  long since gone 90.
Speaker 5:  No. How dare you. I can still make a free account on crackle.com sir,
Speaker 4:  To do what?
Speaker 2:  I don't know. You can watch. There's, there's the, the Alfred from Batman
Speaker 2:  prequel where like Alfred, I never watched it, but
Speaker 2:  apparently he, he solves crimes. I
Speaker 4:  Swear to God. Crackle.
Speaker 5:  No Crackle still exists. I had to, what? I'm, I'm literally on their website
Speaker 5:  and I'm not positive it still exists, which is tele,
Speaker 2:  Are any of those things real? But
Speaker 5:  It's here. I can watch, I can watch
Speaker 2:  You have to name a movie that actually exists.
Speaker 5:  Dominion, can I interest you in season one episode one of Dominion Creek?
Speaker 2:  That's not true. That's, that's ai. Okay. You have to give me something that
Speaker 2:  doesn't sound like AI
Speaker 5:  Made it. Abandoned Colon Angelique's Isle. How about that?
Speaker 5:  What about ICU? But it's spelled EYE and it appears to
Speaker 5:  have Yl Stallone in it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's a real person.
Speaker 5:  All of this is fake. I don't believe this website is real.
Speaker 5:  Sorry, I have to stop looking@crackle.com. This is too much. I'm enjoying
Speaker 5:  this too much.
Speaker 2:  Oh man.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Everybody gets on there. I see what happened here. I just want to point
Speaker 4:  out Sony exited Crackle and sold it to
Speaker 4:  a company called Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment.
Speaker 5:  Ooh. Which also owned Red Box and I think is also in the middle of going
Speaker 5:  out of business.
Speaker 4:  I'm just going to, just gonna say that counts as going 90. All
Speaker 4:  right.
Speaker 4:  It's not, it is. SEO honeypot now for
Speaker 4:  Self-help content fully gone. 90,
Speaker 4:  although it's now David's preferred streaming service. From what I understand
Speaker 2:  You, you watch Ghost Squad, it's something called Crossbo Angel.
Speaker 4:  Click on
Speaker 5:  Is my favorite movie.
Speaker 4:  When you click on the crackle FAQ, this is a real thing that I did. I clicked
Speaker 4:  on the FAQ assuming that it would tell me who owned Crackle, but instead
Speaker 4:  it showed me a list of trending support topics. And one of them.
Speaker 4:  Number two, on the list of trending support topics in the crackle
Speaker 4:  FAQ. How many Vizio devices can I add to my crack? What?
Speaker 4:  This is real, I'm not, I'm not kidding at all. Well, the other one is, how
Speaker 4:  do I troubleshoot issues my Xbox Series S? So I think we know a lot about
Speaker 4:  this. Yep. Version of Crackle.
Speaker 2:  Mm.
Speaker 4:  You, yeah. All right. Crackle has gone 90, that's one thing we've
Speaker 4:  learned about this. I'm with you that consolidation is bad. I just,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, yeah. I think I mainly just bummed to see Amazon or I'm mainly
Speaker 2:  just bummed to see Alamo go this way. I spent a lot of time there in my twenties
Speaker 2:  seeing some of the worst movies. And like two, I got to see
Speaker 2:  Otto's Mur Mero. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Metropolis there at a 24 hour movie festival.
Speaker 2:  Colorized absolutely spectacular. But I also saw Poughkeepsie
Speaker 2:  tapes and again, we, we chased the filmmakers out of the theater
Speaker 2:  because
Speaker 4:  We don't so much. I'm saying when I was in law school, I got absolutely hammered
Speaker 4:  with my friends and went and saw a broken li, broken Lizards Club dread at
Speaker 4:  an animal drop pass. You can have experiences at movie theaters. Oh my
Speaker 2:  God, it's
Speaker 4:  Great. All right, that's it. We gotta, we gotta re wrap this up. We are like
Speaker 4:  500 years over time. There's still so much to say about Crackle.
Speaker 2:  I was like, that's, we're just in a whole episode about it.
Speaker 4:  We'll do that next week. By the way, one thing we didn't get to the is
Speaker 4:  as we speak, the Tesla vote to give Elon is money or
Speaker 4:  not is money is still ongoing. It looks like he might win.
Speaker 4:  We'll cover that on