# Transcript
ID: 027c2a36-f171-47fe-a0fb-f8d3f4aea039
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1166966254434435363/-7168964917377188742/s93290-US-2153s-1716162642.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of refillable scent cartridges:
Producer Andru Marino tries out a gadget called the Gamescent, an AI-powered scent machine that syncs with your gaming and movie watching experience. He walks David Pierce through the experience and whether integrating olfaction could be the future of gaming.
We also hear from Nimesha Ranasinghe, an assistant professor at the University of Maine working on taste sensations and taste simulation in virtual reality experiences, which can lead to adding another sense into the world of gaming.
Speaker 3:  joystick crisis, both super fun episodes. If, you haven't listened to them,
Speaker 3:  go do so. But I would be lying to you if I said this is not the episode I
Speaker 3:  was the most excited about. We gave our producer Andrew Marino, I would say
Speaker 3:  the roughly impossible task of taking the two senses
Speaker 3:  that make the least sense in the context of this series and trying to
Speaker 3:  figure them both out. Those two senses are taste and Smell.
Speaker 3:  How do you do that in games? Let's find out. Andrew Marino. Welcome.
Speaker 4:  Hi. Hi David.
Speaker 3:  You knew I was gonna give you this episode, didn't you? I
Speaker 4:  Would've fought for it.
Speaker 3:  I'm glad. So where do you wanna start? I, I feel like we, we just sort of
Speaker 3:  sense you on a, like God only knows where this is gonna go adventure. Let's
Speaker 3:  see, let's see what you can come up with. Yeah, where do you wanna start?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so let's just bring up the idea of where Smell would even go
Speaker 4:  in in this stuff. Right. Okay. So you may remember the
Speaker 4:  term Smellovision. Oh yeah. Yes.
Speaker 3:  I honestly could not tell you if that's a real thing that ever existed or
Speaker 3:  not, but I have heard, I have heard of Smellovision before.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. People just use it as a term for like broadcasting smells,
Speaker 4:  you know, but it was actually a product at one point, there was a movie
Speaker 4:  in 1960 called The Scent of Mystery.
Speaker 5:  Scent of Mystery.
Speaker 4:  And it was a movie that used this technology called Spion.
Speaker 4:  They had like this whole machine built where there was like
Speaker 4:  kind of like how a soundtrack in a film strip would be like
Speaker 4:  there's just triggers for when scents would come Throughout the film
Speaker 4:  there was like 15 scents that were deployed into the audience.
Speaker 4:  So there was a villain in the movie who smoked a pipe. So whenever that villain
Speaker 4:  was on screen you could Smell the tobacco from his pipe
Speaker 4:  and it was supposed to be like the future of cinema. They were just like,
Speaker 4:  we got sound, we got visuals. Now we gotta add another thing.
Speaker 4:  And that's Smell. The other
Speaker 3:  Important part of movies
Speaker 4:  Now, like you still kind of see that. I don't know if you've ever been to
Speaker 4:  one of those four DX theater experiences.
Speaker 3:  Those are the ones with like the, the seats that rumble when there's action
Speaker 3:  sequences and stuff. Right. To that extent, I think four DX is super fun,
Speaker 3:  but every time there's one of these, I remember this thing from, it
Speaker 3:  was the Honey I Shrunk the Kids Yes Thing at Disney World, which to me is
Speaker 3:  like the canonical version of all of this to me. And there's a moment in
Speaker 3:  it where a bunch of rats are scurrying around and they actually had
Speaker 3:  the rats scurry underneath you and it freaked me out. Like genuinely
Speaker 3:  earnestly scared me. I
Speaker 4:  Am still s scarred from that. That's so funny you brought that up. I remember
Speaker 4:  the tails. There's tails at the bottom of the chair. It's
Speaker 3:  Awful. I don't like it at all. And so that forever has
Speaker 3:  ruined the idea of 40 x for me, even though I think the like rumble when
Speaker 3:  you're in the car thing is actually pretty cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, a lot of them don't do this since apparently there's a theater in
Speaker 4:  Japan that has like a thousand different scents you can load into a movie.
Speaker 4:  But we're talking about video games here, so how do we do this in
Speaker 4:  video games? Yeah, that
Speaker 3:  Seems like a really different problem to me. Yeah, you can't just like load
Speaker 3:  the track with the smells I guess.
Speaker 4:  Right? 'cause it's so interactive. Once we got into like the desktop
Speaker 4:  era of computers, there was this company called Eye Smell
Speaker 3:  Amazing. Which
Speaker 4:  Is just an amazing name for Verizon Company
Speaker 3:  And this is in the nineties. So they were, they were ahead of their time
Speaker 3:  on Eye Smell. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  In 1999 there was like a USB device you'd plug into your computer.
Speaker 4:  It would work with like websites and programmers to
Speaker 4:  install these like Smell activation files where
Speaker 4:  it would release a scent when you click on something in a, in a game or
Speaker 4:  a website. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You can imagine Tomb Raider you're going through different spots and you
Speaker 6:  know, smelling mold and mildew and animals and
Speaker 6:  tapestries and then shoot 'em up game. Of course that can get pretty gross
Speaker 6:  when you say this game stinks. It might be a compliment
Speaker 4:  That never took off in 2006. PC World Magazine listed
Speaker 4:  I Smell as one of the worst tech products of all time. Oof.
Speaker 3:  That's tough.
Speaker 4:  So there's a, you know, there's a lot of challenges there. I don't know if
Speaker 4:  people were ready for scent in video games. We are still, you know,
Speaker 4:  we're still getting the visuals and sound right at that point. But now
Speaker 4:  technology has progressed. David,
Speaker 7:  Guys, guys, guys, guys. Okay. Smell of vision.
Speaker 7:  It's real.
Speaker 4:  There's been lots of prototypes. I've seen Linus, Tech Tips did a
Speaker 4:  video with something called the Celia, which worked with a game called
Speaker 4:  Adventure Climb vr.
Speaker 7:  Oh my god. I can to,
Speaker 7:  I can totally Smell the water.
Speaker 4:  This fan will blow scents on you if you're in like the wooded area or
Speaker 4:  like near water.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  There's some innovative stuff there. But I actually found
Speaker 4:  one product that is shipping does add scent
Speaker 4:  to your game and they promise to work with any video game
Speaker 4:  console and any streaming platform. It's called Game Scent.
Speaker 4:  Have you heard of this?
Speaker 3:  I'm guessing this is the sort of thing that we would've seen and been like,
Speaker 3:  well that'll never amount to anything and then just all sort of forgot about
Speaker 3:  in this long history of Smell products. Yeah, but you're telling me it's
Speaker 3:  real.
Speaker 4:  It's real. We're here. Smell of vision is back in
Speaker 4:  games. It's made by a company called Elevated Perceptions. You can
Speaker 4:  buy it right now on Amazon. You can hook it up to your Xbox, you can hook
Speaker 4:  it up to your switch or whatever. It's like this hexagon
Speaker 4:  box that you hook up to your console. It has six spray
Speaker 4:  nozzles each with a different fragrance. So when you're playing a game
Speaker 4:  it will just eject some, it's like an oil diffuser.
Speaker 4:  Okay, sure. And it's powered by
Speaker 4:  ai.
Speaker 3:  Oh God Andrew. Well that's the end of the episode. No
Speaker 4:  David hear me out. AI is going to solve
Speaker 4:  Smell of Vision. Okay. We're finally at a point where this
Speaker 4:  is actually gonna work because you know previously in all these examples
Speaker 4:  I talked about, you have to map it to the game, to the movie
Speaker 4:  before you play it. You know,
Speaker 3:  Like the track you're talking about, it actually doesn't work If, you don't
Speaker 3:  have the like cue points for the sense
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  So you'd have to work with the video game developer, you'd have to work with
Speaker 4:  the movie distributor to sync everything. But what Game Sent is doing
Speaker 4:  instead is you're actually just running an audio signal to
Speaker 4:  the game scent from your game console through this little adapter
Speaker 4:  which syncs to that hexagon box called the
Speaker 4:  Atomizer. And so the adapter is listening to the sound
Speaker 4:  in the game, sending it to a cloud server and then some AI
Speaker 4:  software is figuring out what those sounds are and then it tells the
Speaker 4:  atomizer to deploy those sense. So it's related to what you're hearing
Speaker 4:  in the game. I
Speaker 3:  Can't tell If you just described something really clever or that is like
Speaker 3:  the most hacky hack in the history of hacks
Speaker 3:  and I think it, it's actually probably both as I'm thinking about this now.
Speaker 4:  I think so. Yeah it's super clever because yeah you don't have to map
Speaker 4:  it to any game. You can use literally any game. You can watch literally any
Speaker 4:  movie with it. It's
Speaker 3:  A lot of smells though. Andrew, what what? What are the scents in this
Speaker 3:  thing?
Speaker 4:  It's a lot of smells. The starter pack that comes with it
Speaker 4:  is gunfire racing cars, explosions
Speaker 4:  forest storm and then a neutralizing scent
Speaker 4:  or called clean air scent. So those are the six that come
Speaker 4:  in the box
Speaker 3:  I love you can just tell what kind of game and movie they're designing this
Speaker 3:  for. That three of them are just action movie things.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like the game sent hears gunshot noises, it will
Speaker 4:  deploy the gunfire, Smell If you hear leaves
Speaker 4:  rustling and birds chirping. You might Smell the forest
Speaker 4:  scent from the device like If. you played this podcast
Speaker 4:  through the game scent. I'll just play some thunder and rain sounds right
Speaker 4:  now.
Speaker 4:  The game scent should hear that and then it will deploy the storm
Speaker 4:  scent. So they want people to use this for movies and and whatever too.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so you mentioned a few minutes ago that this thing is available to
Speaker 3:  buy on Amazon. I'm begging you to tell me that was foreshadowing and that
Speaker 3:  you have one of these things and you can tell me how it works.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, I got, I got the game scent. So after this little break
Speaker 4:  we'll have, I'll get into my experience with using the game scent and see
Speaker 4:  how it actually does with Smell of Vision in 2024.
Speaker 3:  Oh my god,
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. Andrew Marino, you have a game cent in your life
Speaker 3:  right now and you have not told me about it. I am desperate to know about
Speaker 3:  your experience with the Game Cent. How'd it go?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I was so excited to play with this. I reached out to game set and the
Speaker 4:  company sent me a unit to try out for The. Vergecast. When I
Speaker 4:  got the package immediately it had a very strong
Speaker 4:  set.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think some oil leaked or something 'cause it's very strong
Speaker 4:  And so as I was opening the glass vials of fragrance,
Speaker 4:  I noticed that one of them was actually shattered.
Speaker 9:  Oh no.
Speaker 9:  The clean air sent,
Speaker 9:  it's broken. I wonder if that's why it was all oily
Speaker 9:  when I was spelling was clean air. Apparently
Speaker 3:  Better that than like gunfire or explosions though I guess.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So all these little vials of oil, they probably should have
Speaker 4:  used different canisters. Like they're just generic glass containers. You
Speaker 4:  can screw the nozzle spray thing on it. But yeah, it,
Speaker 4:  so I didn't have the neutralizer scent anymore but I felt that was okay
Speaker 4:  because my entire apartment smelled like clean air for a
Speaker 4:  few days. So you just said
Speaker 3:  Infinite neutralizer Smell for a while. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. But it was actually pretty easy to set up in my living room.
Speaker 4:  Usually as you know, devices that are connected to the internet and Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  can be a pain in the butt. So I was actually surprised how easy it was to
Speaker 4:  set up. I hooked it up to my Nintendo Switch, plug it into the audio
Speaker 4:  adapter, I put the atomizer on my coffee table and I
Speaker 4:  was sitting on the couch, plugged it in the wall and the first game I wanted
Speaker 4:  to try it out with was Mario Kart
Speaker 10:  For
Speaker 4:  The first lap or two, it wasn't really doing anything. I couldn't Smell anything.
Speaker 4:  But then suddenly something came through outside of
Speaker 4:  that clean air
Speaker 10:  Scent. Oh
Speaker 10:  I'm getting a new Smell.
Speaker 10:  Oh
Speaker 10:  I don't know, I don't know what it is.
Speaker 10:  So
Speaker 4:  It was working but some of the scents were just like too hard to
Speaker 4:  figure out like storm scent versus forest scent.
Speaker 3:  Can you see the scents coming out by the way? Like is there a steam thing
Speaker 3:  coming out?
Speaker 4:  You can see it working. There's like a cloud of puff Okay. Coming out
Speaker 4:  and you will Smell it for sure. Even
Speaker 3:  If you can't tell exactly what it is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, eventually it started to make sense.
Speaker 10:  Oh I'm getting
Speaker 10:  very like burnt kind of Smell. I think that's the racing car
Speaker 10:  Smell. I'm on the third lap and it just triggered that
Speaker 10:  so it kind of smells like burning tire.
Speaker 4:  I got the racing car Smell from playing Mario Kart. As you can
Speaker 4:  expect, that just kept going off for a bit, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's, it's just racing cars the whole time.
Speaker 4:  Right, because you're always hearing turbo boosts and
Speaker 4:  engines revving and all that. Some other things I would activate the game
Speaker 4:  cent during Mario Kart was grumble volcano. That course
Speaker 4:  there's like an erupting volcano in the beginning and that deployed
Speaker 4:  the explosion scent bullet bill, that big bullet that
Speaker 4:  whizzes past you or hits you depending where you are in the race that
Speaker 4:  got the gunfire scent.
Speaker 10:  Oh this is a new Smell.
Speaker 10:  It's very smoky Smell.
Speaker 4:  So overall it does work. I also played this with Animal Crossing.
Speaker 4:  I know these are probably not the best case scenarios, but they said you
Speaker 4:  could use it with anything. Yeah, I got the forest sent immediately
Speaker 4:  when I was in animal crossing on my island. I have a lot of trees. So
Speaker 4:  overall it does kind work. Does
Speaker 3:  It add anything though? Like does it, do you feel like it made Mario
Speaker 3:  Kart more exciting or immersive to have this working?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I don't think so. I think maybe if I'm
Speaker 4:  using it longer over time and I'm not noticing it, like
Speaker 4:  if I crashed horribly in Mario Kart, I Smell
Speaker 4:  that burning tire scent, it might be a little bit more powerful. Also,
Speaker 4:  you kind of have to have the atomized fairly close to you to like
Speaker 4:  immediately Smell it when it happens. If you put it a little
Speaker 4:  too far away from you, it might take a bit for the scent to come up,
Speaker 4:  but if it's more experiential environment thing, you may
Speaker 4:  not change scents very often. Like if you're in a forest
Speaker 4:  in in Zelda or something, you're probably there for a long time.
Speaker 4:  But I, I'm not sure if it's all there yet. Like I'm not
Speaker 4:  more immersed in Mario Carr.
Speaker 3:  Well I, I kind of, I have sort of two theories about that. One is that maybe
Speaker 3:  the problem is just that Smell doesn't work like sound does. Like it sort
Speaker 3:  of sounds like you're saying like what if the soundtrack of the movie
Speaker 3:  just played constantly for an hour and I was like well it wouldn't do anything.
Speaker 3:  Right. The fact that you can play music at specific points that does
Speaker 3:  specific things is actually really powerful in a way that just diffusing
Speaker 3:  oil into the air. You just don't have that kind of control. Right. But also
Speaker 3:  then I'm like, what if there were just way more smells? What if instead of
Speaker 3:  six it was like 6,000 and it could be like small explosion,
Speaker 3:  big explosion, you're dying in the explosion. Like maybe,
Speaker 3:  maybe we just, instead of doing less of this, we need to do much, much, much
Speaker 3:  more of it.
Speaker 4:  That's what I think. I think 6 cents are not enough and
Speaker 4:  technically it's five because there's like the neutralizing odor, right.
Speaker 4:  So I don't think it's there's enough yet for a full immersive
Speaker 4:  experience. But I talked to the people at games sent, they
Speaker 4:  were experimenting with Daisy chaing a bunch of these. Oh. So
Speaker 4:  you can buy a bunch and maybe put, you know, multiples of
Speaker 4:  6 cents in your gaming setup. So
Speaker 3:  Like forest plus gunshot equals
Speaker 3:  war, I dunno. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh totally. Yeah. And they do plan on adding more scents to swap
Speaker 4:  out Right now on the website it says there will be a
Speaker 4:  ocean scent. Okay. A sports arena scent, fresh cut
Speaker 4:  grass. There's a zombie Smell that's gonna be coming. That's
Speaker 4:  what they told me.
Speaker 3:  This is my new favorite job in the tech industry that I am
Speaker 3:  desperate to know much more about is the, the Smell designers for video
Speaker 3:  games. Yeah, that's a, that's a life goal right there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They work with a third party company to like design these custom scents
Speaker 4:  for the game scent. So it's not just these stock ones that they just buy,
Speaker 4:  you know, but I would love for them to make like a bundle for certain
Speaker 4:  games. Mm. If there was like a Mario Kart bundle, I could have a
Speaker 4:  racing car scent and like a banana scent for the banana peel
Speaker 4:  in the game. Yeah. And then an ink Smell for when you get blooper. That would
Speaker 4:  be cool. And you could, you know, have different packs for different games.
Speaker 3:  That's a really fun idea. You, you buy the $70 game and for
Speaker 3:  15 more dollars you get all the game smells. Yeah. I like weirdly
Speaker 3:  feel like that would work.
Speaker 4:  I think so too. And I talked to the president of the company and the VP of
Speaker 4:  marketing at the company about this and they like want to work
Speaker 4:  with companies in movie production houses to make
Speaker 4:  customs sense for games and movies. They said they would love to partner
Speaker 4:  with like Dune and figure out what the spice smells like in
Speaker 4:  Dune. You know, know.
Speaker 3:  Oh that's, that's very compelling.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So David, would you use something like this
Speaker 4:  for movies or games? I
Speaker 3:  Think games I actually find more interesting than movies and
Speaker 3:  I think actually your spice example is sort of the perfect one where to me
Speaker 3:  the idea of having like lots of different smells
Speaker 3:  kind of coming and going as you play a game or watch a movie is probably
Speaker 3:  just too hard to pull off. Like just because of what you're talking about.
Speaker 3:  Like it has to diffuse oil into the air at a particular time.
Speaker 3:  But if I could sit down to play Dune and it just kind of smelled a little
Speaker 3:  like spice, it's like, you know how when the room smells like popcorn,
Speaker 3:  like every movie's a little more enjoyable. Like it's just that little thing
Speaker 3:  that if I could just kind of, or the thing people do where they like sync
Speaker 3:  up the lights to the movie. Yeah. Just having that one little
Speaker 3:  additional thing where instead of having everything
Speaker 3:  on screen have a Smell, you can just sort of have the game, have a Smell
Speaker 3:  or like the world like the, you mentioned the fresh cut grass thing
Speaker 3:  and like I play a lot of FIFA and the idea of having that where I can
Speaker 3:  sort of feel like I'm on a pitch even though I can't Smell the sweaty dude
Speaker 3:  next to me, it just kind of smells like I'm on a soccer field. Yeah. That
Speaker 3:  kind of does something for me and feels maybe slightly more achievable. I'm
Speaker 3:  just not convinced that the like soundtrack a game with smells thing is
Speaker 3:  even technically possible. Mm. But I hope I'm wrong. Like I, I,
Speaker 3:  I love the idea. I think it's great that people have been working on this
Speaker 3:  for like what, 50 years now. I think it'd be awesome if it worked. I'm just
Speaker 3:  not convinced it will.
Speaker 4:  Like even in that movie I mentioned the Scent of Mystery, there was like
Speaker 4:  a point where it will deploy a perfume scent of
Speaker 4:  one of the characters that was off screen and so you knew this character
Speaker 4:  was about to come in Oh kind of thing. So there's like a storytelling aspect
Speaker 4:  to it Yeah. That you could totally take advantage of. I
Speaker 3:  Love that you can, you can Smell the bad guy before the bad guy appears on
Speaker 3:  screen. Oh
Speaker 4:  Totally. Yeah. This is great for shadowing. It really is.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I, I want one, I'm, I'm like this thing is on Amazon, which is a real
Speaker 3:  problem because I'm now tempted to buy it just because of the sheer sort
Speaker 3:  of delightful silliness of the whole thing. Are you gonna keep using yours
Speaker 3:  now that you don't have to for The Vergecast anymore? Do you think it'll
Speaker 3:  still stay hooked up to the switch?
Speaker 4:  Probably not until they get new Cent. I think it's
Speaker 4:  pretty strong overall and after a while it's like eh, I actually don't
Speaker 4:  wanna Smell this forest Smell. A lot of it's very perfumey
Speaker 4:  so far
Speaker 3:  Have it, has it lingered in your apartment? Like do you come home and you're
Speaker 3:  like hmm, smells like burnt tires?
Speaker 4:  Well the box does the box with all the oils still
Speaker 4:  inside it.
Speaker 3:  so excited. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  It's time for maybe the weirdest sense in the five senses of video games.
Speaker 3:  Taste Andrew. It turns out Smell has a decades long
Speaker 3:  history in movies and video games. Does taste,
Speaker 3:  have there been people trying to make you taste video games since the seventies?
Speaker 4:  Well so the first time we started talking about this, I
Speaker 4:  remembered this 2017 podcast we did. Our colleague
Speaker 4:  Addie Robertson interviewed Jaron Lanier who you know is
Speaker 4:  a pioneer in that first phase of VR from the eighties and nineties.
Speaker 4:  At the time he was promoting a book and in the book he mentioned this VR
Speaker 4:  taste simulator he tried from a Japanese company and then he
Speaker 4:  talked about it on the podcast
Speaker 11:  The next time was Japan. I tried this crazy thing and it was really
Speaker 11:  hard to sterilize between users and really hard to initialize and really
Speaker 11:  crazy. But it was like this weird little morphing robot with little
Speaker 11:  chemical squirters and you would stick it in your mouth and start chewing
Speaker 11:  on it.
Speaker 12:  Wait, did it just look like a blob, like a little blob robot?
Speaker 11:  It was like this rubber thing with all these little robotic effectors inside
Speaker 11:  it that could collapse or move and then it had like these little nozzles
Speaker 11:  that would squirt flavors out of little holes in it. Yeah, I
Speaker 12:  Know that sounds really disgusting.
Speaker 11:  It it absolutely the most repulsive user interface item I have ever seen
Speaker 3:  A heck of a sales pitch BI agree. That does sound sort
Speaker 3:  of disgusting.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That is bizarre. I, I would love to have seen what that looks like or I
Speaker 4:  would love to try it honestly. But you can imagine like something like that
Speaker 4:  is very hard to emulate taste putting something in your
Speaker 4:  mouth. I haven't seen anything remotely close to what he was talking
Speaker 4:  about there, but I did find someone who is working on
Speaker 4:  something in the world of taste simulation.
Speaker 13:  I'm Nisha Inger, I'm an assistant professor at
Speaker 13:  University of Maine in the School of Computing and information science.
Speaker 4:  So I talked to Naisha, he was previously in this
Speaker 4:  research group at the University of Singapore focusing on human
Speaker 4:  interaction and virtual reality and he specifically was
Speaker 4:  interested in incorporating taste sensation and simulation
Speaker 4:  into this. So the best way that he was figuring it out
Speaker 4:  was through controlling electrical currents and electrical
Speaker 4:  pulses onto your tongue to give different taste
Speaker 4:  sensations. So like, you know, If, you lick a battery If,
Speaker 4:  you've ever done that? Sure. It's like kind of like a so kind of
Speaker 4:  sharp taste. So he built on that idea.
Speaker 13:  So I thought like maybe we can focus on that and we can fine
Speaker 13:  tune the electrical stimuli, like reduce it to very, very, very low
Speaker 13:  electric current around like a hundred micro amia and then
Speaker 13:  start studying like when we change the electric current
Speaker 13:  and the frequency as well as the different areas of the
Speaker 13:  tongue when we stimulate how we can sort of
Speaker 13:  relate those electric stimuli like perception into
Speaker 13:  like actual basic taste perceptions like salty, sour,
Speaker 13:  sweet and bitter sensations. Mainly,
Speaker 4:  You know, different currents attacking your tongue, maybe
Speaker 4:  changing the temperature to make it hot or cold for like a spic or minty
Speaker 4:  feeling. You know, I had
Speaker 3:  No idea this was like understood science that you could
Speaker 3:  essentially push a taste onto someone's tongue
Speaker 3:  with electrical currents. I guess I'm, I shouldn't be surprised by this,
Speaker 3:  but that's very cool to have just learned about just now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's pretty wild. Apparently it works. There was an early
Speaker 4:  prototype they worked on that was like a 3D printed spoon with
Speaker 4:  electronics inside it and it little electrodes underneath the spoon
Speaker 4:  so when you put it on your tongue it would like zap these
Speaker 4:  sensations. Whoa.
Speaker 3:  So you, you bite the spoon and it, it's like cinnamon toast crunch
Speaker 3:  and then you bite the spoon again and it's like spaghetti.
Speaker 4:  I don't know if it was that advanced. Okay. But it was like, oh maybe this
Speaker 4:  tastes salty now this fair enough is super sweet. You know they also
Speaker 4:  had like metal chopsticks they worked on that was like a plus and minus kind
Speaker 4:  of a circuit. Whoa. They tried a soup bowl, all these
Speaker 4:  things. They wanted to make sure it all represented stuff that people were
Speaker 4:  already used to putting in their mouth. Sure.
Speaker 13:  We wanted to see like a, a range of different food items and
Speaker 13:  like a semi-liquid kind of food items like porridge and soaps
Speaker 13:  and how we can sort of augment the flavors based on the
Speaker 13:  electrical stimulation.
Speaker 4:  So that kind of thing. Only manipulates primary tastes. Sensations like you
Speaker 4:  mentioned salty sour. They also realized that individual
Speaker 4:  senses influence each other so that can be a powerful tool. They
Speaker 4:  started adding like Smell to give a more immersive experience in this
Speaker 4:  drinking machine. Much like the game scent, you could engage
Speaker 4:  food and drink smells in, which totally influences the way you
Speaker 4:  taste. And then also they want to incorporate sight. So they're
Speaker 4:  experimenting with color
Speaker 13:  If, you go to a bar, they have these like beautiful like range of colors,
Speaker 13:  cocktails and yeah, each and every color sort of gives us like some kind
Speaker 13:  of like a pre sort of conceive or like an idea like
Speaker 13:  this is going to be sweeter, this is going to be sour, this is going to
Speaker 13:  be sweet and sour and bitter. Kind of like a some idea, right? Based on
Speaker 13:  the look and feel or based on our previous experiences. So we
Speaker 13:  wanted to expand on that idea and then see like
Speaker 13:  how we can create the same beverage but add the colors
Speaker 13:  and taste and Smell using the digital controls to see whether
Speaker 13:  we can change the people's perception.
Speaker 4:  So all that idea was made into this invention called the
Speaker 4:  virtual cocktail.
Speaker 13:  So we got like a traditional martini glass and then 3D print like a structure,
Speaker 13:  attach the glass and then we, we also had a electronic control
Speaker 13:  system and then like a tree Smell chambers and then three like
Speaker 13:  air pumps, like the air pumps we use in like fish tanks, like the tiny
Speaker 13:  micro air pumps. We put them inside and then we can release like
Speaker 13:  three different smells on top of the beverage surface. And then
Speaker 13:  on the rim, instead of putting like like a margarita, like a salt
Speaker 13:  or sugar, we put those electrodes and then now we can simulate the
Speaker 13:  ness of saltiness using the electrodes. And then we also put like
Speaker 13:  A-R-G-B-L-E-D to change the colorful beverage.
Speaker 4:  So adding all that stuff together like actually changed the way
Speaker 4:  you would taste this drink that was ba you know, it would just be water,
Speaker 4:  you know? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That also sounds like an incredible gaming accessory. I
Speaker 3:  feel like he just describes something that I now want every time I do anything.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I can imagine like in Fortnite you're going to a bar in Fortnite and
Speaker 4:  you're having like this in real life electronic Tumblr of water
Speaker 4:  and then you sip it and it sinks with the game. Like whatever you're tasting,
Speaker 4:  I don't know. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  The mead you drink in like a medieval game actually tastes like meat is you're
Speaker 3:  drinking it. I want this so bad Andrew. That sounds awesome.
Speaker 3:  Is this a real thing? Did they actually, like they made one of these, it
Speaker 3:  sounds like, is this a real thing?
Speaker 4:  They demoed it at a virtual reality showcase a few years ago in London.
Speaker 4:  It was really popular. A lot of people wrote about it. The Mesha said that
Speaker 4:  they spun off the research into another company that is actively working
Speaker 4:  on this thing with the spoon version as well.
Speaker 3:  That's very exciting.
Speaker 4:  There's also like another aspect of this that is outside of games.
Speaker 4:  So like If, you wanna watch the sodium or the sugar
Speaker 4:  intake in your diet. You can kinda like, you know, have a spoon with
Speaker 4:  oatmeal and like artificially add salt with the
Speaker 4:  spoon electronics. So it's like, oh now this is a little saltier even though
Speaker 4:  I'm not adding any salt. And then also just communicating another
Speaker 4:  form of sense to someone.
Speaker 13:  How can we think of like these devices as communication devices?
Speaker 13:  So communication media for example. Like how many times we go to like
Speaker 13:  some other place or some other like the restaurant and wondering like how
Speaker 13:  can we send this sort of flavor or like the dish to my
Speaker 13:  girlfriend or my wife or like my parents or my sister or
Speaker 13:  brother just for them to try. One of the sort of vision I have
Speaker 13:  is also like create kind of like a flavor social media, how
Speaker 13:  can we share flavors? And I mean we do these kind of things
Speaker 13:  every day. Like we take photos and try to upload them into social media
Speaker 13:  and explain things verbally. One of the questions I asked is,
Speaker 13:  can we do this in virtual reality environment with these kind of tools
Speaker 13:  integrated so that you will get like a much more believable sort
Speaker 13:  of being there sensation plus these taste and
Speaker 13:  Smell sensations to sort of complete experience.
Speaker 3:  That sounds very cool. You know what it makes me think of is I had a conversation
Speaker 3:  with Eric Yuan, the CEO of Zoom maybe six
Speaker 3:  months into the pandemic. So this is like four years ago now. And I was talking
Speaker 3:  to Eric like, okay, what's next? We're all doing this now but we're all rectangles.
Speaker 3:  And he had a bunch of ideas but then he was like, what I want to have happen
Speaker 3:  is I want be able to have a cup of coffee and share it with you
Speaker 3:  on Zoom. And I remember having this idea of being like, that is the most
Speaker 3:  bananas thing I have ever heard in my entire life. But also very
Speaker 3:  cool and I feel like this is, this is how you do it, right? Like this is
Speaker 3:  that same kind of thing. We've gone way past gaming here. Yeah. But I think
Speaker 3:  that's a, that's a really cool, interesting
Speaker 3:  scientific way of approaching that idea of like, how do you and I actually
Speaker 3:  share virtual experiences. Maybe he's not wrong. That between Smell
Speaker 3:  and Taste, you actually get a pretty long way doing that.
Speaker 4:  I know. I would love to just email you a lemonade to,
Speaker 4:  I could sell up a lemonade stand and I could email you the
Speaker 4:  the drink open
Speaker 3:  The email bite the spoon Lemonade.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I don't know if that's Utopia or dystopia, but I'm gonna be thinking about
Speaker 3:  that for a really long time.
Speaker 4:  All this stuff seems kind of silly, but when you think about the future of
Speaker 4:  all this, when gaming becomes more immersive, there might be
Speaker 4:  a point where the only thing that really pulls you out of that immersion
Speaker 4:  is like, oh, why doesn't this bar Smell like stale beer?
Speaker 4:  Or why don't I feel any sensation when I'm
Speaker 4:  restoring my hunger points and Minecraft? Do you think maybe this
Speaker 4:  stuff is just inevitable in video games once we get more immersive?
Speaker 3:  I I sort of buy the argument honestly. I think to me the first
Speaker 3:  thing we have to solve, and it's gonna take a really long time, is the haptic
Speaker 3:  stuff, right? Where I feel like where we are now is the thing that takes
Speaker 3:  you out of it almost is no longer the graphics. Like I feel like with the
Speaker 3:  Vision Pro and even sort of the Quest three, your brain is in the place that
Speaker 3:  you are pretty successfully, but then you reach out and touch something
Speaker 3:  and there's no sensation of actually touching the thing. Or when you move
Speaker 3:  it's obvious that you're not in the game moving. So I really do sort of
Speaker 3:  sincerely believe that someday when we wanna play video games, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  have to put on like full body haptic suits and I'm actually fine with that
Speaker 3:  future. I think it's gonna be awesome. Like put on your wetsuit, put on your
Speaker 3:  headset and like go play Call of Duty. That's a world I'm very excited to
Speaker 3:  live in. But I think you're probably right that if and when we solve that
Speaker 3:  problem, the next thing will be, well this still doesn't feel like
Speaker 3:  I'm grabbing anything because all of my other sensations are not there.
Speaker 3:  Right. We will have solved sight, we will have solved hearing and we will
Speaker 3:  have solved touch. And then there's two left and like as you know, you've
Speaker 3:  been talking about kind of through this whole segment, like it's the way
Speaker 3:  that those senses work together that makes them powerful.
Speaker 3:  And also like I'm, as I'm thinking about this now, the idea that
Speaker 3:  Smell could work in my headset actually seems like maybe it solves a bunch
Speaker 3:  of problems that having to work in my living room doesn't Yeah.
Speaker 4:  When you got this thing right up to your face anyway.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So I think like, I don't know, I'm, I, this all feels like maybe
Speaker 3:  it's like a 50 year problem and will have much bigger things to deal with
Speaker 3:  than, than Smell. But I can sort of see why people
Speaker 3:  continue to care about this.
Speaker 4:  I'm imagining like a whole helmet that has like a straw you sipping and
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A thing that goes on your nose and the GOs
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's the combination of like the two beers on the side of your, on
Speaker 3:  the side of your head in the hat and a camelback that goes to your mouth
Speaker 3:  and like a, a motorcycle helmet that you're essentially just hotboxing with
Speaker 3:  different smells all the time. Yeah. And that's just, that's how you play
Speaker 3:  Animal Crossing.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. It's a future I would love to live in.
Speaker 3:  This sounds great. Apple, if you're listening, this is how you make the vision
Speaker 3:  Pro a success. We, Andrew and I just figured it out. We did it.
Speaker 4:  Make it stink.
Speaker 3:  All right Andrew, you did better on this project than I expected anyone
Speaker 3:  possibly could. This is very fun. Oh thanks. Thank you for going on these
Speaker 3:  bizarre adventures for us. Oh
Speaker 4:  It was so fun. Good.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we should get outta here. That is it for The. Vergecast thank you
Speaker 3:  to Andrew and everybody else who helped us with this show. And thank you
Speaker 3:  as always for listening lots more on everything we talked about, including
Speaker 3:  we'll link to Smellovision in the show notes. If, you buy it. Tell us how
Speaker 3:  you like it and what sense you would like to see If you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 3:  feelings. Email us VERGE cast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline. Eight six six
Speaker 3:  Vge one one. The show is produced by Andrew Moreno, Liam James and Will Poor
Speaker 3:  Vergecast is VERGE production part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll
Speaker 3:  be back on Tuesday to talk about surface stuff and open AI stuff.
Speaker 3:  There's a whole lot of news happening, so there's a lot to do on The Vergecast
Speaker 3:  in the next few weeks. We'll see you then. Rock and roll