# Transcript
ID: 6905ed84-46af-42f0-a2dc-c6e5d6390284
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8074754098002129413/6422615253353380991/s93290-US-4772s-1724581609.mp3
Description: You can learn a lot about somebody just by learning about how they get things done. Are they the sort of person who might have a perfectly color-coded email inbox, a flawlessly organized to-do list, and what’s that, they just sent you a calendar invite for happy hour next week? Or are they more likely to have a giant pile of sticky notes they never look at, a computer desktop with so many files you can’t even see the wallpaper, and today’s main tasks written on their arm? Neither is wrong, but they’re very different.
On this episode of The Vergecast, the second in our three-part miniseries about work and productivity and how to get more done in a digital world, we decide to get to know our colleagues in a new way: by asking them to share their own productivity systems. We didn’t give them much specific instruction or homework, other than to come ready to answer a question: how do you get stuff done? Eight Verge staffers showed up, with eight very different ideas about what being productive means and how best to pull it off. Along the way, we found some ideas to steal, a few new apps and tools to try, and a lot of new thoughts about our co-workers.
If you want to know more about the things we discuss in this episode, here are a few links to get you started:
A Googler’s guide to getting things done
TickTick
Upnote
Notion
Google Keep
Google Calendar
The Rhodia #16 spiral notepad
Papier’s productivity planners
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (18 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Never Ending
Speaker 2:  to-Do Lists. I'm a friend David Pierce and this is the second
Speaker 2:  episode in our three part mini series, all about productivity
Speaker 2:  defined as loosely as possible. If you missed last week's episode, I
Speaker 2:  talked to Laura May Martin, who is like Google's internal
Speaker 2:  productivity guru. We talked all about tools and
Speaker 2:  hustle bros and process and what it means to be productive
Speaker 2:  without totally losing your mind this week, I wanna do something
Speaker 2:  completely different. I have this theory that You can tell a lot about a
Speaker 2:  person just by understanding how they manage their life.
Speaker 2:  Are they super duper organized with a beautiful, perfect
Speaker 2:  foolproof system for making sure everything gets done? Do they
Speaker 2:  just totally fly by the seat of their pants, trust their memory, and hope
Speaker 2:  for the best? Do they like digital tools or pen and paper? Ai? No
Speaker 2:  ai. It's all very revealing honestly. And it's
Speaker 2:  really fun to talk to people about. So today we're going to use this
Speaker 2:  episode as an excuse to get to know a few of my coworkers. We reached
Speaker 2:  out to a bunch of folks on the Verges staff and asked them to come on the
Speaker 2:  show and tell us about their productivity systems, however they want to define.
Speaker 2:  That phrase was fine by me. My goal is to learn a bunch
Speaker 2:  of new ideas, steal a few for myself, and also maybe
Speaker 2:  psychoanalyze my coworkers. At the end of it, I'll share mine too,
Speaker 2:  but I'm gonna go last, so we're gonna get into all of it. But before we do,
Speaker 2:  I have to go find my notes on who exactly we're talking to. And spoiler
Speaker 2:  alert for my system. That's not that easy right now. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  productivity systems, one for work and one for at home.
Speaker 4:  Which would you prefer to hear about or both?
Speaker 2:  Well, first I have a question, which is why think of those as separate things?
Speaker 2:  What does it help you to differentiate those so completely?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, totally. Because then like I can do things
Speaker 4:  on the weekend without thinking about them as work stuff and
Speaker 4:  my personal productivity system links in pretty closely to how my
Speaker 4:  wife does it as well. So we can kind of share tasks and
Speaker 4:  language and communications that way. So that's like
Speaker 4:  personal stuff. And then my work stuff is purely work stuff and
Speaker 4:  you know, I can add specific reminders for work. Things that
Speaker 4:  don't muck up my personal reminders. It's kind of a way for me to, to keep
Speaker 4:  it separate.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So let's start with the personal one. How does that work?
Speaker 4:  So we've are both fully in the Apple ecosystem
Speaker 4:  and So I rely a lot on Apple reminders and Apple
Speaker 4:  Notes and Apple Calendar for reminders.
Speaker 4:  I have my own personal set of reminders and we do a set of shared reminders,
Speaker 4:  which is super useful for like weekend tasks or
Speaker 4:  you know, remembering to reach out to X, Y, or Z person for their birthday.
Speaker 4:  Stuff like that. We have a calendar system
Speaker 4:  that allows us to, like if one of us has a call, we put
Speaker 4:  it on our shared calendar so the other person knows like, oh, maybe
Speaker 4:  I'll not be in the office at that time. Or Oh, I need to remember to be there
Speaker 4:  at this time for this thing. And we use Apple Notes
Speaker 4:  to, we keep a, this is one of my favorite things that we do. We keep a
Speaker 4:  running list of stuff throughout the day that we wanna tell each other about.
Speaker 4:  And then at like the dinner table or over lunch, we just go over our
Speaker 4:  bullets of like, oh, I saw this funny thing on the internet, or Oh we need
Speaker 4:  to talk to our family about X, Y, Z thing. It's
Speaker 4:  been super clutch.
Speaker 2:  That is the most adorable thing I've ever heard in my entire life, Jay.
Speaker 4:  We've been doing it for years. It is so awesome.
Speaker 4:  It's like so, so, so useful. And I think even if we didn't
Speaker 4:  have, like let's say we stopped using iPhones, which I don't anticipate
Speaker 4:  we'll be doing anytime soon, we'd probably just build like a shared Google
Speaker 4:  doc or something like that because like
Speaker 2:  Why share it though? Doesn't it remove all of the surprise and fun of bringing
Speaker 2:  your topics to each other when You can see the list? Well
Speaker 4:  We sometimes write like, you know, a single note or like a single word or
Speaker 4:  like maybe just include the link but the link is so giant and
Speaker 4:  gross that you can't tell what it is right immediately. And
Speaker 2:  So she'll just put in like pants and you get to spend the whole day being
Speaker 2:  like what is pants about and
Speaker 4:  What is pants? Yeah, sometimes. Okay, I love this. My wife, my wife's very
Speaker 4:  good at using acronyms for names and so usually I
Speaker 4:  know what they are but sometimes it's a surprise when like I didn't get the
Speaker 4:  right person.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And all of this is like shared, just shared between the
Speaker 2:  two of you. So you have this like whole collaborative system?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean for like notes what's kind of useful about
Speaker 4:  it is we delete things off the note and they just go away
Speaker 4:  'cause it's just like a series of bullets that we're like deleting it, adding
Speaker 4:  to over and over and over and over for reminders. We have a bunch of like
Speaker 4:  shared reminders that like are scheduled on a weekly or monthly basis
Speaker 4:  or whatever. Like every Sunday we have a reminder to vacuum. Whether or
Speaker 4:  not that happens is a choice that we make because like we decide we do have
Speaker 4:  time to vacuum this weekend or we skip it and we push it another weekend.
Speaker 4:  And then the calendar is just a, a shared calendar of reminders and dates
Speaker 4:  and and all the stuff you need a calendar for.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So what about the work system? That's a surprisingly
Speaker 2:  like tight, simple personal system. Is is work as
Speaker 2:  as clean and perfect?
Speaker 4:  Mm. I keep it pretty simple at work too. So my work
Speaker 4:  reminder system is tick tick. Like I just use an entirely separate reminders
Speaker 4:  app. I love Tick Tick primarily because You can type like
Speaker 4:  get draft to David by 4:00 PM and it will know
Speaker 4:  everything I need to do there in terms of like making a 4:00 PM reminder
Speaker 4:  or making it happen today. If I needed to get you a draft every
Speaker 4:  week, I would add every week and it does it every week and like all that
Speaker 4:  stuff is just super fast and super easy and allows me to jot
Speaker 4:  things down like the moment I think of them, So I don't lose track of them.
Speaker 4:  We use Google Calendar here at The Verge and So I use
Speaker 4:  that for scheduling things on my calendar. And then I also kind
Speaker 4:  of live and die by my email and I try really hard to keep
Speaker 4:  inbox zero. I've, it's sometimes I'll end the day with like three,
Speaker 4:  I don't know if you've seen Andrew Bosworth at Meta, he talks about Inbox
Speaker 4:  10, which is actually kind of a useful system where there's not the pressure
Speaker 4:  of like always getting to exactly zero at the end of the day.
Speaker 4:  But thinking that as a to do list keeping, maybe just a couple things
Speaker 4:  you need to do in there, but otherwise like replying to something right away
Speaker 4:  or archiving it right away. It's pretty much what I always try and do.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So again, the system makes a lot of sense to me. The only thing
Speaker 2:  I'm tripped up on is it feels like you've given yourself so many things
Speaker 2:  to check and like I spend all of my time obsessively looking for one to do
Speaker 2:  list that does everything because I'm like, dear God, I can barely remember
Speaker 2:  to open this one app and look at it often enough. You've given yourself like
Speaker 2:  six. Are you, are you just good about opening and checking
Speaker 2:  these things?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean I think of them all as like they're my separate spaces where
Speaker 4:  I do certain tasks in certain places and
Speaker 4:  sometimes every once in a while it gets a little mixed up. But it's a
Speaker 4:  system I've used for a few years at this point. And so like maybe if
Speaker 4:  it's messy I'm just used to it at this point.
Speaker 2:  All right, well you have way too healthy a relationship with your productivity
Speaker 2:  tools. I find this is, this is very annoying and frustrating and making me
Speaker 2:  feel better about myself. So go away Jay. Thank you. That was great.
Speaker 2:  This was great. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Great to be here. I'm sorry I made you feel bad.
Speaker 2:  All right, next up on The Verge productivity docket Senior Reviewer Victoria
Speaker 2:  Song V Song, welcome back. Hello. Tell me about your
Speaker 2:  productivity system.
Speaker 5:  So it used to be digital and then I remembered that
Speaker 5:  my memory is going to shit and it actually is a lot better if you
Speaker 5:  write things down. So it is now more than half analog
Speaker 5:  with one app. Okay. So, I got so sick of all the to-do
Speaker 5:  apps, like even the good ones even I was trying super list, I was, you know,
Speaker 5:  I continually miss Wonder List. Yes. And then
Speaker 5:  I, you know, I'd been using Todoist for years. No,
Speaker 5:  I'm forced to use the Airtable here because we have to like
Speaker 5:  collaborate and whatever. So I do use that
Speaker 5:  not as well as I should, but I do use it. But I have like
Speaker 5:  a, I have like four journals that I, I keep all my product
Speaker 5:  productivity in. But the main one, and this one was actually recommended
Speaker 5:  to me by our, our former colleague McKenna Kelly. It is
Speaker 5:  the Papier productivity journal and it's great because
Speaker 5:  it is a actual journal where I write things
Speaker 5:  down and like the best part of the spread is that You can
Speaker 5:  see a little undated schedule thing. Like I didn't fill this day out but
Speaker 5:  an undated schedule thing of your hours, your three most important
Speaker 5:  things that you need to do in the day and then a to do list and a little
Speaker 5:  space for you to write notes.
Speaker 2:  So it gives you like the kind of daily template and you just fill it out
Speaker 2:  each day. That is kind of nice.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so it's, it's really nice. And then I've used this as a, as a
Speaker 5:  giant excuse to buy pens. So many pens in
Speaker 5:  multiple different colors. This is the pentel Matt hop, it dries,
Speaker 5:  it's Matt.
Speaker 2:  So you're one of those people who is like deep into like bullet journal TikTok
Speaker 5:  Unfortunately
Speaker 2:  And you're like studying calligraphy just to be able to write your calendar
Speaker 2:  events more beautifully.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I've actually been like hobbyist calligrapher
Speaker 5:  for like several years. I don't ever get better. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  This all tracks v, this all fully tracks.
Speaker 5:  I unfortunately don't get better but like you can't see it. But I have this
Speaker 5:  entire drawer of washy tapes. I just went to New York
Speaker 5:  City stationary Fest a couple of weeks ago to buy more
Speaker 5:  washy tape. Oh my god. And so many stickers of
Speaker 5:  cats. So this is like a whole
Speaker 5:  thing. I have this whole bag full of of of of like
Speaker 5:  glue and different kinds of markers and all of these things. Do I need all
Speaker 5:  of these things to write out what a bullet journal should be?
Speaker 5:  No, absolutely not. But the physical act of writing things
Speaker 5:  actually is quite, it helps me remember what
Speaker 5:  it is that I'm supposed to do and it helps me be very
Speaker 5:  intentional with my day. And then what I'll do is like once I figure out
Speaker 5:  a game plan, it never goes according to plan. Sure. Ever. Not once
Speaker 5:  has my plan for the day ever gone according to plan. The point is, is in
Speaker 5:  writing it. And so that if we get 75% of the way there,
Speaker 5:  we've done a very good job. But generally what I'll do
Speaker 5:  is I'll put in like some of my like most important tasks
Speaker 5:  that I know I absolutely do not want to do into my
Speaker 5:  Pomodoro app, which is focus to do and I've written
Speaker 5:  about it for the site. It just forces you to do something
Speaker 5:  for a very digestible amount of time. So like
Speaker 5:  I, I stick to the usual 25, 5 minute breakdown with the
Speaker 5:  Pomodoro timer and I find if there's just like a draft, I am
Speaker 5:  absolutely like I, I don't wanna write this draft like theoretically
Speaker 5:  I wanna write it but the actual physical act of writing is giving me
Speaker 5:  palpitations. I I'll just hit hit Go and
Speaker 5:  You can do anything if it's only for 25 minutes. Totally. Like it's amazing
Speaker 5:  So I will use that. and what I like about this particular
Speaker 5:  Pomodoro Timer app is that it lets you do things as to-dos. So you
Speaker 5:  get the really nice little like, ooh, I checked it off. Mm this is a great
Speaker 5:  and if I've like really got a stacked day and I'm just like,
Speaker 5:  I mean we all feel the days where we go to work and you're like, I don't
Speaker 5:  wanna do this today. Absolutely not. Capitalism has a choke hold on my
Speaker 5:  existential dread today. This is how I like basically force myself
Speaker 5:  to get through it. And it's nice because I look for those like five minute
Speaker 5:  breaks and I'm like, and then I'm gonna clean like
Speaker 5:  furiously for five minutes and then get back to it's
Speaker 2:  Also, it's amazing how much You can do in five minutes when
Speaker 5:  You're like
Speaker 2:  Yeah it's, I only have five minutes.
Speaker 5:  It's amazing. Yeah, it is amazing. Like I can't tell you I've gotten down
Speaker 5:  to like emptying the dishwasher down to like a four minute
Speaker 5:  55 second art. It's really great. So yeah, like
Speaker 5:  that's like what I do now. I used to do so many other different things
Speaker 5:  and like I do use Notion Calendar because I like that
Speaker 5:  it will block off on my personal calendar
Speaker 5:  stuff on my work calendar. Yes. And vice versa. That's honestly
Speaker 5:  the main reason why I still use it because once they changed over from
Speaker 5:  Cron to the Notion calendar thing, I got very mad at the icon
Speaker 5:  change 'cause it now disrupts the harmony, my aesthetic harmony
Speaker 5:  of my task bar, which is like
Speaker 5:  small potatoes. But as we've established, I am a very aesthetic
Speaker 5:  bullet driller. It takes more time to make my
Speaker 5:  spread.
Speaker 2:  I have heard by the way that you and I specifically have caused a ruckus
Speaker 2:  inside of Notion with our loud public hate of that icon. So
Speaker 2:  we are going to continue to fight the good fight and we're gonna win someday
Speaker 2:  some way We will, we will win.
Speaker 5:  It's an ugly icon. It's an ugly icon. It's an, it's an ugly icon.
Speaker 5:  I am sorry. It used to be just like all my productivity
Speaker 5:  apps were red and I was so happy and now this just sticks
Speaker 5:  out. Unfortunately it's like the best one for my
Speaker 5:  use. So like yeah I don't, I have a choice. Yeah. I'm stuck with it
Speaker 5:  for now. That's fair.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I have two quick questions about the journal. Yes. One,
Speaker 2:  is it just the act of physically writing it that you feel like helps you
Speaker 2:  remember it enough that you don't have to like check it every 10 minutes?
Speaker 2:  Or is it still like you have it open next to you all day and you're like
Speaker 2:  constantly looking at it?
Speaker 5:  I will periodically open it just to like be like what's the game plan again?
Speaker 5:  What am my to-dos again? Okay, cool. But actually like physically writing
Speaker 5:  things down, it does help me remember things better.
Speaker 5:  And like I think there's studies showing that when you physically write stuff
Speaker 5:  you do retain the information a lot better than you would with the digital
Speaker 5:  clutter. Oh yeah. That's the main reason why I do it. It keeps me on track
Speaker 5:  of things. So bullet journaling, they have like this whole iconography of
Speaker 5:  like symbols. Oh yeah. I I I hate it. Can't, can't retain that stuff
Speaker 5:  for the life of me. The only thing I do retain is like they use like a little
Speaker 5:  sharp arrow to kind of indicate you didn't get it done.
Speaker 5:  You have to migrate it to the next day. So I do hate it but it
Speaker 5:  does kind of give me insight into the things that I really
Speaker 5:  kind of put off. That would really only take me 10 minutes to do
Speaker 5:  so I'll try. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's something too, the third day in a row you're writing the
Speaker 2:  same task that you've been moving where you're like, fine, I'll just do it.
Speaker 2:  Like leave me alone journal, I'll just do the thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah it, I actually find it works a lot better that annoyance than actually
Speaker 5:  just like resetting the due date digitally 'cause you
Speaker 5:  just erase the due. Like there's something about like the digitalness of
Speaker 5:  it that really doesn't work for my brain. Which is odd 'cause
Speaker 5:  I also wrote a story for The Verge that was like all I want is one
Speaker 5:  productivity app that does everything. It's never gonna happen. But that's
Speaker 5:  all I wanted for the long time. And I actually do think that like being
Speaker 5:  obsessive and writing out every single
Speaker 5:  workout that I've done for August helps me like
Speaker 5:  visually like it's also insane 'cause I've done like 38 workouts so
Speaker 5:  far in August. But I don't know something about it and
Speaker 5:  just like, oh let me just write down every single book I read and my four
Speaker 5:  like four word review of them or just,
Speaker 5:  it just helps me be intentional. It's like a five minute break at the end
Speaker 5:  of my day. It lets me not look at the
Speaker 5:  horribleness of Airtable and getting mad at how everyone else is
Speaker 5:  using it wrong compared to me. 'cause I am the only one using it
Speaker 5:  correctly. It's not true but that's just
Speaker 2:  How, by not using it very much I think is that, is that what you're saying?
Speaker 2:  That feels
Speaker 5:  Right. I used to use it so much and I got so frustrated with how
Speaker 5:  everyone else at The Verge uses it that I was just like, screw this. Like
Speaker 5:  I can't, I can't handle it anymore.
Speaker 2:  Does the journal go everywhere with you by the way? Or does it like live
Speaker 2:  on your desk? Can you come back to it at the beginning and end of the day?
Speaker 5:  It lives on my desk and I come back to it at the end of the day. Like
Speaker 5:  I do notice that on days that I go to the office, I tend to like fall off
Speaker 5:  for that one day. So if you look at my journal the Thursdays, which are the
Speaker 5:  days I most often going to the office completely blank most of the time.
Speaker 5:  But that's okay. It's like not intended to be perfect.
Speaker 5:  That's why I use undated journals. I used to use the dated ones and
Speaker 5:  then the pressure of filling every single day would just like
Speaker 5:  make me not use it. So it's all undated, it's all loosey
Speaker 5:  goosey. Were were, it's, I stopped being too
Speaker 5:  precious and pretty with all of my spreads because then that was too much
Speaker 5:  pressure to be like, oh my God it's the 30th or the first of the month I
Speaker 5:  have to spend four hours calligraphy a
Speaker 5:  spread with stickers and transfer papers and all that sort of stuff. So
Speaker 5:  yeah, no, no. Like now we're, I, I'm a normal person now and
Speaker 5:  I just mostly write stuff and I make things pretty for my
Speaker 5:  brain and that's about it. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I love that for you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Also pens,
Speaker 2:  You're, I know more pens. I just can't get over this convention you went
Speaker 2:  to but we'll, we'll talk about that another time. Thank you as always be
Speaker 2:  no problem. Next on my productive person list is Kara
Speaker 2:  Verney, the s managing editor unprompted. Three of the five
Speaker 2:  people were like I just don't, I don't, I don't know how I'm gonna compare
Speaker 2:  to Kara. So
Speaker 6:  What's funny is like there's a rumor that's been started about me
Speaker 6:  and I did not start this rumor that I am like this hyper
Speaker 6:  organized person and I am not actually,
Speaker 6:  I am very rudimentary in my product
Speaker 6:  productivity software that I use to keep myself organized.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So let's just dive in. Tell me about your productivity system.
Speaker 6:  I take a lot of notes. Is basically the long and the short of it.
Speaker 6:  I take notes all the time. My tip
Speaker 6:  for myself that I learned long ago is that if I don't write it down, I don't
Speaker 6:  know it. So if I'm in a meeting I take notes. I went to the doctor last week,
Speaker 6:  she was saying a bunch of stuff. I wasn't gonna remember that So I took notes.
Speaker 6:  I usually default reach for just the notes app on my
Speaker 6:  phone 'cause I don't need a bunch of AI
Speaker 6:  summaries and prompts and ways to streamline and all of that stuff.
Speaker 6:  'cause I actually think all of that is distracting. Distracting and makes
Speaker 6:  you less productive. So I like the stuff that's pretty basic.
Speaker 2:  So is your notes app like just an
Speaker 2:  unbelievably long series of individual notes or do you have like
Speaker 2:  a, do you have a notes system?
Speaker 6:  It's an unbelievably long series of individual notes. Okay. but they
Speaker 6:  do all have titles so that I can find them very quickly because
Speaker 6:  it often comes up where someone's like, oh what did I say? Or, and
Speaker 6:  I'm like, I'm a Scorpio, I need receipts. Like So I always am able to
Speaker 6:  find what I'm searching for, which is very handy. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, I don't, I don't interact with technology perhaps
Speaker 6:  as much as some folks think I do a lot of handwritten
Speaker 6:  post-Its
Speaker 2:  Do you have a to-do list?
Speaker 6:  I do have a to-do list. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Tell me about it.
Speaker 6:  It moves, it shifts based on where I am. I
Speaker 6:  sit in multiple places during the day so that I can be closest to the sun.
Speaker 6:  And so if I'm cat
Speaker 2:  Basically Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'm, I'm a plant, I just angle. So if I'm at my desk,
Speaker 6:  my to do list is like a big wall calendar that I keep. I
Speaker 6:  obviously keep things on my phone. My phone and my work computer do not talk
Speaker 6:  to each other 'cause I think that that's important. So I
Speaker 6:  often have two things. I have like work Cara and then I have life Cara.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And they don't interact with each other. But my Google Calendar interacts
Speaker 2:  But that's the only that, that's the only system that's allowed to overlap.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I try not to keep, like if I, I was outta town the past two days and I
Speaker 6:  took Slack off my phone. So I try to be very
Speaker 6:  separate when I can be.
Speaker 2:  Is that a like life work balance thing or why
Speaker 2:  keep them so far apart?
Speaker 6:  I just think it's like, it's kind of a scam.
Speaker 6:  Productivity is kind of a scam because you feel like the more time that
Speaker 6:  you spend plugged into the thing is like making you better. But actually
Speaker 6:  it's just wasting your time from doing the thing that needs to get done.
Speaker 6:  And this is not to say that I don't procrastinate because I do, I mean until
Speaker 6:  the last minute to do literally everything. But there's something about
Speaker 6:  like having to plug it into a thing so that I can cross it. Like
Speaker 6:  that just doesn't make sense to me. So I'll often just,
Speaker 2:  Ah, so the idea of like it feels good to check something off of your,
Speaker 2:  to-do list does nothing for you.
Speaker 6:  It like does sometimes if I'm like starting at like the top of a day and
Speaker 6:  I know that I'll get something done in five minutes, sometimes I get that
Speaker 6:  little like buzz. But oftentimes I'm like I'm just gonna get the thing done.
Speaker 6:  So I don't really like do a ton of task tracking through my
Speaker 6:  various moments of every day. It's kind of just like taking
Speaker 6:  notes and just remembering what was said and what I need to get done from
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. Do you spend a lot of time like going back and reviewing your
Speaker 2:  notes? Yes. Afterwards.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I pour over them constantly. Okay. 'cause that from my notes is
Speaker 6:  what I know my next steps are. If I need to add something to my calendar,
Speaker 6:  if I need to follow up with someone, if I need to schedule a meeting, like
Speaker 6:  everything comes out of my notes. So it's kind of like a brain dump and then
Speaker 6:  I take from that.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I think that is actually less chaotic
Speaker 2:  than you're making it sound like. What, what's interesting though is
Speaker 2:  I think the, the thing I hear from a lot of like, you know, quote unquote
Speaker 2:  productivity experts is like the first step is like write everything down.
Speaker 2:  Right? I think you're actually like way ahead of the game on that one. And
Speaker 2:  then step two is like take all the stuff
Speaker 2:  that's in there and make like a beautiful task
Speaker 2:  system out of it. And then step free is just get everything done and you
Speaker 2:  just skip step two. Which I find fascinating. You just go through the notes
Speaker 2:  and you're like, okay here's the stuff. I'm just gonna go do the stuff. Instead
Speaker 2:  of like plugging it all into some incredibly organized
Speaker 2:  middleware to do list system.
Speaker 6:  Correct. Because that's the stuff that I think is sucking your brain outta
Speaker 6:  your body is just like making things color coded and beautiful. 'cause like
Speaker 6:  who, unless you're sharing it with someone that like really needs to know
Speaker 6:  exactly what you're doing every minute of the day. But I operate very independently
Speaker 6:  in my work life and my personal life. And So I don't have like a ton of people
Speaker 6:  that need to know every detail of how I'm spending my, my moments.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Are you, I know for sure that you're a like
Speaker 2:  calendar person at work because you have to be. Yeah. Are you a calendar
Speaker 2:  person? Not at work. A hundred
Speaker 6:  Percent. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Are you like sending friends calendar invites when you're hanging out
Speaker 2:  on Saturday?
Speaker 6:  So I only do that with people that know me really well. I don't like if I
Speaker 6:  make a new friend, I'm not like, we're gonna get drinks on Saturday. Like
Speaker 6:  I don't do that 'cause that would be like next level. But if people know
Speaker 6:  me really well, I also have a, a dear friend of mine who does that with me.
Speaker 6:  Like, we're going to a wedding at the end of September and she already sent
Speaker 6:  me the calendar invite for like what we need to be where, which I appreciate,
Speaker 6:  I like
Speaker 2:  It. There's something honestly like truly wonderful about that. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  my, my immediate reaction is to be horrified by that. But the longer I think
Speaker 2:  about it, I'm like, I love this. Yeah. Like this is great. It's, we are doing
Speaker 2:  this together. Put it on my calendar's.
Speaker 6:  Go. I think yeah, it's flattering when someone takes the time to like think
Speaker 6:  of you and they're like, hey, they would probably appreciate like knowing
Speaker 6:  that I'm telling them where to be, but I'm bossing them around. That's
Speaker 6:  flattering. I think there's like a, there's like an element too of if
Speaker 6:  I don't, again, if I don't write it down I won't remember it. But if I write
Speaker 6:  something down, it's in my head. So there'll be some like vague
Speaker 6:  recollection that someone quoted me, you know, something to come fix my car.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, actually I know that you said it was $737 because I know I
Speaker 6:  wrote that down. So like it's kind of like a weird photographic thing that
Speaker 6:  happens to me. So even if I have like a workout class or like
Speaker 6:  something like that, I put it on my calendar 'cause then I won't forget that
Speaker 6:  that's what's happening that night. So, okay,
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. This works for me. So the the remembering it because you
Speaker 2:  wrote it down thing is really interesting 'cause I've talked to a couple
Speaker 2:  of people on our staff for this episode who have said the reason they switched
Speaker 2:  to like analog notebooks is because
Speaker 2:  the act of writing long hand helped them remember. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 2:  true, right? Like there's tons of science that says if you hand write, you
Speaker 2:  remember better than if you type. Have you and I half expected you
Speaker 2:  to be a person who like lifted up your giant trapper keeper of a notebook
Speaker 2:  and you're like, look at this organizational system. Have you ever been that
Speaker 2:  kind of person?
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent yes. Okay. I have, like I said, it just depends on where
Speaker 6:  I'm seated, what kind of thing I use to keep track of things. So if I'm at
Speaker 6:  my desk, which I'm not right now I have like folders and
Speaker 6:  post-its and calendars and a thing of my, like that's how I kind of organize
Speaker 6:  myself. But when I'm not, I'm kind of left to
Speaker 6:  more minimalist devices. So, I think it just kind of depends on
Speaker 6:  where, but for me, I think maybe this is what you're asking. It doesn't matter
Speaker 6:  if I'm typing it or if I'm writing it like same result as long as it's going
Speaker 6:  somewhere. Interesting. Okay. I think this was also just like a, our age
Speaker 6:  group thing was told like maybe in college that like writing things down
Speaker 6:  is how you remember. Like I just think like that's just, people
Speaker 6:  think that way. And maybe it's true. I don't know. It is for me,
Speaker 2:  I think the thing that I've found that works is I do it much more slowly.
Speaker 2:  Like I type really fast and I don't write by hand that fast. So there is
Speaker 2:  something to the, like you have to, I think the, the,
Speaker 2:  I had a professor once who described it as like, You can transcribe when
Speaker 2:  you're typing, but because you can't write as fast as someone can talk, you
Speaker 2:  have to kind of synthesize as you go. Right. And it's actually making your
Speaker 2:  brain work. And that's really useful. Yeah. And I totally get that. I also
Speaker 2:  just hate writing by hand. I just, I just, I'm done writing by hand. It's
Speaker 2:  2024. Handwriting is over. I don't,
Speaker 6:  Do you have good penmanship? No. So that's probably why,
Speaker 2:  That's my real problem because people complain. I I, my wife makes fun of
Speaker 2:  me because I have like, like literally there will be like a a, you
Speaker 2:  know, postcard written by a kindergartner on someone's fridge and Anna will
Speaker 2:  point at it and be like, that looks like your handwriting. Yeah. And she's
Speaker 2:  right. That's nice. It's terrible.
Speaker 6:  That's nice. Yeah. I feel very proud of my penmanship. So that's
Speaker 6:  probably part of it is like that helps, you know, when you're like in a group
Speaker 6:  setting and someone's like, who has good handwriting? I'm always like, gimme
Speaker 6:  an
Speaker 2:  Ah, yeah, I, I run from those rooms. Like that is not
Speaker 2:  under no circumstances should I be allowed to write on the whiteboard for
Speaker 2:  everybody.
Speaker 6:  But I do think there's something to that. There's like a slightly performative
Speaker 6:  nature if you're doing something with someone else and you're handwriting
Speaker 6:  it 'cause you're like, they have to be able to understand what I'm saying
Speaker 6:  here versus for sure typing it. You're like they'll get it. They don't have
Speaker 6:  to worry about that element. So Totally. You know, part of it is just like,
Speaker 6:  is this for me to remember that I need to like go pick up my dog from doggy
Speaker 6:  daycare or is this for like somebody else to know what I'm doing? You know,
Speaker 2:  It is amazing how far write everything down
Speaker 2:  gets you like that. That is one of the big takeaways I've gotten from talking
Speaker 2:  to people about this. Like kind of at all levels of it that like if you just
Speaker 2:  write everything down, most other things kind of start to solve
Speaker 2:  themselves.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna be really interested to see if there's any
Speaker 6:  communication increase after this podcast because I'm curious to see how
Speaker 6:  many people say they write everything down and then I'm gonna be like, Bob,
Speaker 6:  where? What's the deadline? You know? Yeah. We'll
Speaker 2:  See a bunch of liars. It turns out. All right. Thank you Kara.
Speaker 6:  No problem.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna keep going. I'm having
Speaker 2:  so much fun with this. I'm already learning so much. We got more to do. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right back.
Speaker 2:  So are you like a, you have one doc called like my to do list that everything
Speaker 2:  lives in? Or are you like every time you get a new thing to do, you make
Speaker 2:  a new beautiful Google Doc and start from there?
Speaker 7:  I I, there it's both right. So, I have my to do list in life and at work
Speaker 7:  that I just run, like run through and add things and take things away from.
Speaker 7:  And then I project base have lists that,
Speaker 7:  you know, a lot of the memos that I write or project trackers that I put
Speaker 7:  together are just glorified Google docs with checklists that I just,
Speaker 7:  you know, assign different people to different things like, but it's just,
Speaker 7:  it gets checked as it gets done. So that's like my number one way in
Speaker 7:  which I organize my life and my work and get everything done.
Speaker 2:  Why Google Docs? So, I love Google Docs, but I loathe using
Speaker 2:  Google Docs on my phone, which is the reason I don't do what you're describing.
Speaker 2:  So I'm curious why Google Docs?
Speaker 7:  I love Google Docs because it's the closest thing to a piece of paper and
Speaker 7:  so that's why I use it again, old, old school here. I don't really use my
Speaker 7:  phone for productivity. I guess that's a good thing to mention here. I feel
Speaker 7:  like when I'm in getting things done mode, it's gonna be me and my computer
Speaker 7:  typing away and looking at things and having my 87 tabs open.
Speaker 7:  My phone is more for fun and to hear from my kids and my husbands.
Speaker 7:  Besides for that like So I, guess that that doesn't really answer your question
Speaker 7:  about how it's bad on the phone 'cause I don't use it on my phone.
Speaker 2:  Right. That's a totally fair answer. Yeah, I'm the opposite where like for
Speaker 2:  me I am constantly like the only reason I ever remember to do
Speaker 2:  anything is because I write stuff down on my phone all the time and if I
Speaker 2:  had to wait until I was back at my computer, I would forget everything. And
Speaker 2:  so Google Docs becomes a total non-starter for me. Oh
Speaker 7:  Wow. I do that also, but here's what I do. I
Speaker 7:  text myself remind, like things that I wanna remember. So that is my
Speaker 7:  own chaotic personal system is I will text myself whether it's like a
Speaker 7:  link to something that I wanna buy, whether it's a reminder to do something
Speaker 7:  like anything. And then that gets transferred to my to-do list when I'm sitting
Speaker 7:  in front of my computer. So if I'm sitting down to write a grocery list,
Speaker 7:  let's say I can't do that on my phone. That has to be on my, and like I
Speaker 7:  said Google Docs is for my work life, for my personal life, I use the notes
Speaker 7:  app on the Apple, apple Notes solely, but
Speaker 7:  that's, it has a really, really good check feature. So,
Speaker 7:  but again, if I'm trying to get things done, whether it's like to plan a
Speaker 7:  menu or figure out school supplies for the kids or whatever,
Speaker 7:  I'm sitting down and typing on my computer, I'm not doing that on my phone.
Speaker 2:  Does it help like
Speaker 2:  organize your life a little bit? Where like when I'm sitting on my computer
Speaker 2:  I can, I can do you know like capital P productive things. Yeah. And then
Speaker 2:  I close the computer and I don't have to do those things anymore.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think it's helpful because I just, I feel like when I'm
Speaker 7:  on the computer I'm fo it's more, I'm more focused. Whereas
Speaker 7:  my phone is like the opposite of focus for me it's just like jumping from
Speaker 7:  like social media apps to streaming apps to the news to notifications
Speaker 7:  to So-and-so's calling me and texts and WhatsApp,
Speaker 7:  So I just like being from my computer. Sometimes I mute text if I need to
Speaker 7:  focus really more and that's like my work time, that's
Speaker 7:  my getting things done time. And I think also like, again, this is, I'm showing
Speaker 7:  my age, but like bigger screen, easier to just like
Speaker 7:  picture the thing you need to picture, look at the full thing you need to
Speaker 7:  do. I'm much more comfortable browsing the internet on my laptop
Speaker 7:  browser than I am on my phone. Like I feel like it's, the phone is too small
Speaker 7:  and too confined and so if I need to look something up or
Speaker 7:  anything like that, I just, I'm much more comfortable on the computer than
Speaker 7:  I am on my phone. So.
Speaker 2:  Okay. What about calendar? I like you're, you're a person who has a lot of
Speaker 2:  meetings at work, So, I assume your calendar is very important, but are you
Speaker 2:  like a, are you a calendar person in general? Like are you the one who's
Speaker 2:  throwing like take out the trash in your calendar with a reminder
Speaker 2:  every week kind of vibes?
Speaker 7:  So if it's a spectrum, I'm definitely not all the way on that side, but
Speaker 7:  I'm also not on the like ignore the calendar side.
Speaker 7:  I would say I am really into calendar.
Speaker 7:  I rely on my Google Calendar so much, but
Speaker 7:  I'm not at the point where like I wanna have a shared gal with my husband.
Speaker 7:  Like we're not like, that's not like, I'm not like, and I know a lot of people
Speaker 7:  do that and they love it. Like I don't need to do that. Like, no thanks.
Speaker 2:  Are you the holdup there or is your husband the holdup there?
Speaker 7:  I think we are both very happy not to, not to be okay not to be that efficient
Speaker 7:  as a family together. You know, like that's too much pressure.
Speaker 2:  So when you have a thing that you all have to do together, how do you
Speaker 2:  who, how, how does it happen?
Speaker 7:  I put it in my calendar. He puts it in his calendar. We remind each other,
Speaker 7:  we just remember
Speaker 2:  Would you send him a calendar invite? No,
Speaker 7:  No, no, no,
Speaker 2:  No. Okay. That's too much too. No,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's too much. I, I would not take it While if he did that to me,
Speaker 7:  I feel like that's very aggressive. Thank you very much.
Speaker 2:  He's like, date night sends you an invite to your work email.
Speaker 7:  No, no, no thanks. But, but I would say at work especially I
Speaker 7:  do like to be really strict with my calendar and
Speaker 7:  more because I think it's like it gives you permission to focus on that task
Speaker 7:  when you, when you're doing it. So like I try to even
Speaker 7:  sometimes if my meetings get canceled I won't take them off my calendar 'cause
Speaker 7:  I'll wanna spend that 30 minutes or that hour working on the things I would've
Speaker 7:  done in that meeting anyways. So like I'm really good at getting things on
Speaker 7:  the calendar, not super uptight about like canceling things
Speaker 7:  in advance or whatever. Like it's more about just setting those times up
Speaker 7:  as I'm setting up my week and setting up my month or whatever it is.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. That makes sense. So anything else that, when you think about
Speaker 2:  the, like how Esther lives her life system, does
Speaker 2:  anything else belong in that system? Yes.
Speaker 7:  I would say, let me think how to phrase this. I would say
Speaker 7:  there's a step before making a to-do list I think sometimes,
Speaker 7:  which is like what are the things I care about when I'm, when I'm
Speaker 7:  embarking on this project, right? So, I do a lot of like, you could call
Speaker 7:  it journaling, you call it brain brainstorming or just kind of like vibing.
Speaker 7:  But I like to have a written down vibe session with myself
Speaker 7:  of just like what are the things that I need to, that are, what are
Speaker 7:  like the pillars of this project or what are the things I need to solve for
Speaker 7:  when I'm doing this project before I sit down and then break down the
Speaker 7:  actual to do list. It's really helpful because that kind of defines the buckets
Speaker 7:  of work as you're gonna start doing them. and it also serves as like your
Speaker 7:  guide to like making sure you're always staying on track and hitting those
Speaker 7:  original goals. The other thing which is much that was like the
Speaker 7:  macro answer, this is the micro answer, is I like to, especially
Speaker 7:  when I'm doing, you know, I work in a lot of group projects and I work with
Speaker 7:  a lot of different departments. A lot of the time I
Speaker 7:  assign stakeholders to everything. Like even if it's like,
Speaker 7:  you know, blink your eyes, like I will literally put a, put a assign a stakeholder
Speaker 7:  because I think it's really important to just always have the person who's
Speaker 7:  accountable to do the thing written down in everything you do. Otherwise
Speaker 7:  that's when things don't get done. If people are like, oh I thought you were
Speaker 7:  doing it. No I thought you were doing it. And sometimes that's funny, right?
Speaker 7:  Like I'll be in meetings with like VPs or executives and I'll be like, okay,
Speaker 7:  so just pause everyone. Like so who's gonna do the thing you all said we
Speaker 7:  should be doing? And it's awkward and funny but I find that it helps me
Speaker 7:  get things done when I know like who is in charge of doing everything.
Speaker 2:  I love that. All right Esther, this is, you came in saying I have
Speaker 2:  no system. This is actually like a surprisingly thoughtful system. I'm kind
Speaker 2:  of impressed. Is it,
Speaker 7:  Is it though? We'll see,
Speaker 2:  I listen, I, I would get you out of Google Docs but otherwise I feel like
Speaker 2:  you're doing fairly well.
Speaker 7:  I think my, my church and state with phone in my computer is a good thing.
Speaker 7:  So. I. I can stay in Google Docs for now. I
Speaker 2:  Agree with that. Yes. Awesome Esther, thank you. Thanks
Speaker 7:  For having me.
Speaker 2:  I'm starting to sense a theme here with a lot of these, but I'll come back
Speaker 2:  to that. Let's keep going up next. Senior producer Victoria,
Speaker 2:  Barrios Victoria. Describe to me your productivity system.
Speaker 8:  So for my own life I have a like three
Speaker 8:  block system. Basically So, I have a wide like
Speaker 8:  Eagle eye view. I have like a weekly view and then I have
Speaker 8:  like thoughts and notes and the way those are broken up is
Speaker 8:  above me. If you're ever in a meeting with me, I might be looking up 'cause
Speaker 8:  I have a three month calendar breakdown full of sticky notes
Speaker 8:  of like main events for my personal life or work life.
Speaker 8:  And that's the best way for me to like see both work and personal.
Speaker 8:  And then I
Speaker 2:  Have like a big paper calendar with sticky
Speaker 8:  Notes. So full sticky notes, easy to reference. And then
Speaker 8:  for like my everyday, like weekly tasks, I have a Google sheet
Speaker 8:  that is broken up by the different team functions. So because of
Speaker 8:  my role, I am like integrating in a lot of different aspects of
Speaker 8:  production but also like editorial management, special projects,
Speaker 8:  So, I, have it like literally broken down Monday, Wednesday, Friday.
Speaker 8:  And then sponsorships, operations production.
Speaker 8:  And then I spend about 20 minutes a day before my day
Speaker 8:  begins filling out my tasks. And usually So
Speaker 2:  You're just like, these are the buckets of my job and then you kind of fill
Speaker 2:  out each bucket each day?
Speaker 8:  Exactly. Okay. And then I have this like loose
Speaker 8:  notebook at me next to me at all times. Taking notes
Speaker 8:  during meetings, whether they're like the actual direct tasks or
Speaker 8:  thoughts that I have while someone else is speaking, especially depending
Speaker 8:  on what kind of meeting it is. Like I just had an operations meeting with
Speaker 8:  Kara and Sarah who are also two of the most organized people at The. Verge.
Speaker 8:  Yep. And for that one, it's like I usually have tasks
Speaker 8:  to do. Like I go in with the list of things I wanna discuss written in this
Speaker 8:  notebook. And then I have the tasks that I go away from. I take
Speaker 8:  everything written in this and then I'll put it onto that weekly calendar
Speaker 8:  and then I'll make sure that weekly calendar is working back from the big
Speaker 8:  three month calendars. I feel crazy like I'm describing this to you
Speaker 8:  look crazy.
Speaker 2:  No, I actually, I think you've actually described like a surprisingly
Speaker 2:  like catchall system that kind of collects everything. But what I'm, what
Speaker 2:  is tripping me up is, is the mix of digital and analog because
Speaker 2:  you're like, you're taking all your notes physically, but
Speaker 2:  then you like live inside of a spreadsheet. But then mo your most
Speaker 2:  important stuff is on a physical like wall calendar. So
Speaker 2:  particularly with the like sitting there at your computer during a meeting
Speaker 2:  taking notes, why do that on paper instead of like
Speaker 2:  in a Google Doc or whatever notes app you feel like using?
Speaker 8:  I feel like that's more of like a, a social
Speaker 8:  courtesy. So I don't, oh interesting. Okay. So I don't wanna look at another
Speaker 8:  screen while I'm speaking to someone, taking notes. I also
Speaker 8:  don't want to like break my 'cause like visually,
Speaker 8:  unless I have a huge monitor, which I don't, so maybe this will change in
Speaker 8:  the future, but if I wanna be looking at the computer and looking
Speaker 8:  at the person, I'd have to like split my windows to then be taking notes.
Speaker 8:  See it really comes down to like one like social
Speaker 8:  courtesy and another being like the amount of space I have on my windows
Speaker 8:  and how cluttered I want that to feel. So the Excel,
Speaker 8:  like weekly stuff, I'm not looking at that constantly. I'm not referencing
Speaker 8:  that constantly unless I finish a task. So, I have a task you break around
Speaker 8:  for like an hour, 20 minutes, whatever it is, X amount of time
Speaker 8:  throughout the day. I don't need it. And I don't want a window that I constantly
Speaker 8:  need. I've tried like the Google for like Google Notes or Google
Speaker 8:  Keep or Google Check. Yeah, I tried that
Speaker 8:  and I found that I kept having to go to like a certain tab to keep that open.
Speaker 8:  It's not like flush across all screens and all tabs and
Speaker 8:  all programs. So the two paper things
Speaker 8:  helped me keep that, like keeping it flush across it no
Speaker 8:  matter what I'm working into or what program I'm looking into. And I reference
Speaker 8:  'em constantly. Like I'm constantly looking at these calendars because I'm
Speaker 8:  constantly talking about when things should be published and who's doing
Speaker 8:  what and where.
Speaker 2:  I'm realizing now that I've never really thought about this, but just having
Speaker 2:  like an at a glance thing that is just like, here are the one or two
Speaker 2:  most important things on days is so
Speaker 2:  helpful. Like this happens to me all the time where it's just like, oh, somebody
Speaker 2:  is like, can we do this thing two weeks from Thursday?
Speaker 2:  And being able to just look up and be like, oh, what's two weeks from Thursday?
Speaker 2:  And just have like the one or two main things from that day seems so
Speaker 2:  useful. I think I'm gonna end up stealing that idea from you. It's
Speaker 8:  Very good. Yeah, please do. It's probably my proudest like moment of
Speaker 8:  realization working at my guess for four years.
Speaker 2:  So why a spreadsheet, by the way, for all the weekly stuff? Is that because
Speaker 2:  you're like working with other people and sharing that stuff? Or you're just
Speaker 2:  like a spreadsheet person? I know from experience you are a bit of a spreadsheet
Speaker 2:  person, but I'm curious why it works for you.
Speaker 8:  I am a a thousand percent proud spreadsheet girl.
Speaker 8:  And I, I think it's, it's super versatile. So
Speaker 8:  I keep my spreadsheet super easy and I think it's a matter of
Speaker 8:  it's adaptable. So something like Airtable, which I love also,
Speaker 8:  it's two, I think sharing focused and like
Speaker 8:  you need to follow the rules that Airtable brings up. and it is very adaptable
Speaker 8:  and versatile in its own ways. Whereas in an Excel sheet, or sorry in a,
Speaker 8:  in a Google sheet or Excel sheet, like I could build that no matter what.
Speaker 8:  I've not, I haven't always had it broken down into the three
Speaker 8:  buckets of my position. Like way back when in the day I used to
Speaker 8:  just be, you know, five columns, six rows and like
Speaker 8:  I'd call that, you know, a working day. But now I could like, I have a
Speaker 8:  note section like throughout the week if I need to like remind myself of
Speaker 8:  like, oh, you know, this is this coming up catchall again. 'cause I never
Speaker 8:  want anything to slip through the cracks, even though it will maybe eventually,
Speaker 8:  but it's just very versatile.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that makes sense. I I have become like a
Speaker 2:  reluctant spreadsheet person and I'm, I sort of hate that I've become a spreadsheet
Speaker 2:  person, but I'm slowly becoming a spreadsheet person for that exact reason.
Speaker 2:  And it's like the more I learn about how to make spreadsheets, the more fun
Speaker 2:  it is to make spreadsheets. Like I just learned how to do the thing where
Speaker 2:  you take a bunch of cells and just turn it into one big white box that You
Speaker 2:  can just write in. Ah, ah, feel so good Now I'm just
Speaker 2:  like taking notes and spreadsheets. It's bad times. What about all the stuff
Speaker 2:  out of work? Like when you're not at work, are you as sort of ruthlessly
Speaker 2:  organized in like personal tasks and, and personal
Speaker 2:  life and all that stuff?
Speaker 8:  No, I've admitted myself to being a digital
Speaker 8:  hoarder. So like I have, I'm one of those people that has like
Speaker 8:  way too many photos on my phone, too many unread
Speaker 8:  messages and I've tried, I think what it comes down to is like,
Speaker 8:  I also like the luxury of just letting life happen. And so
Speaker 8:  just, you know, whatever email comes through, whatever notifications come
Speaker 8:  through, I'll read them when I can. And it's kind of like a snapshot
Speaker 8:  of just what I can get through in a day. Whereas if I keep trying to focus
Speaker 8:  of organizing every moment, then I don't enjoy
Speaker 8:  like what's actually happening. 'cause if that also happens at work, right?
Speaker 8:  That's why I also have these notes. Like what's so important for me to be
Speaker 8:  looking at someone while taking notes is because I don't wanna like take
Speaker 8:  myself away from the creativity of it all. I know that sounds
Speaker 8:  way more like prophetic or philosophical than I
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say that's a pretty profound insight about digital life right
Speaker 2:  there.
Speaker 8:  That's really good. So no I would say like, the biggest buckets I have
Speaker 8:  is like the, these big calendars for my personal,
Speaker 8:  like how I'm organizing, but how I organize when I'm like in a team setting
Speaker 8:  is very different because how I understand how other
Speaker 8:  people are taking information is gonna be very different. So
Speaker 2:  This is why you're a good producer because there's like you, you're like
Speaker 2:  left to my own devices, just let chaos, rain. But I
Speaker 2:  understand that other people are less chaotic and so I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  have to, this is like you just described why you're good at your job and
Speaker 2:  that's, that's very good.
Speaker 8:  That's good at least.
Speaker 2:  All right, awesome. Victoria, thank you very much. This is super fun. Next
Speaker 2:  on my list we have Jake Kakis, the VIRs executive editor.
Speaker 4:  I, for the longest time just wrote down
Speaker 4:  a manual to do list in text edit every day. I wanted it to
Speaker 4:  be as ugly and simple as possible. Okay. Very quickly realized
Speaker 4:  that doesn't work. You need a a real system of to-dos that
Speaker 4:  can alert you at certain times on certain days. So eventually
Speaker 4:  I found Tick Tick, which has been a game changer for me and I've
Speaker 4:  relied on it for years now. So I, 99% of my organization
Speaker 4:  is in Tick. Tick. Okay. Professional, but also like personal too.
Speaker 2:  So just everything you have to do whenever, wherever, whatever ends
Speaker 2:  up in tick tick in some way.
Speaker 4:  I literally, I have reminders to talk to my friends
Speaker 4:  in Tick tick. I, yeah, I
Speaker 2:  Mean I do too. I'm laughing, I'm laughing out of like, it feels good to
Speaker 2:  know that it's not just me not at you. Don't worry.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. No, Kara has like mocked me for being like, oh, I see. I was
Speaker 4:  a a to-do for you today to, to, to say hi.
Speaker 2:  On a normal day of work, how many to-do's would you say
Speaker 2:  are in your tick Tick.
Speaker 4:  Oh God. It's okay. So it's probably like 10. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 4:  Not so bad. But the reason is that I don't rely on a, on a
Speaker 4:  calendar and So I have all my entire calendar duplicated
Speaker 4:  into Tick tick. So tick tick isn't just my to-dos, it's also my
Speaker 4:  meetings.
Speaker 2:  Wait, so you write a to-do with a time for every meeting that
Speaker 2:  you have to go to. Yeah. Listen Jake, I'm not judging, I'm just asking, but
Speaker 2:  I'm also, I'm on this one to be honest. I'm slightly judging because Tic
Speaker 2:  Tick has like a whole calendar thing where You can sync your calendar to
Speaker 2:  tic tick. I
Speaker 4:  Okay. They do, I tried paying for it. It's like their only paid premium
Speaker 4:  feature. And I was like, you know what, I should pay these guys some money.
Speaker 4:  And So I paid for it and it was total chaos. It was terrible. And
Speaker 4:  then as it turned out, and like maybe edit this out, turns
Speaker 4:  out if you stop paying them, they don't turn it off.
Speaker 2:  So,
Speaker 2:  okay. So
Speaker 4:  Cool. I'm not recommending anybody do that, but I, I
Speaker 4:  may still have access to some of their calendar features. Yeah. But basically
Speaker 4:  that is what I do. I, if somebody sends me a Google Calendar invite,
Speaker 4:  I accept it in Google and then I go over to Tic Tick and I type it in
Speaker 4:  because I don't know how to get the alert from Google Calendar. I don't have
Speaker 4:  a Google Calendar app that's real, pretty and nice and simple.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I just want, I just want a nice little list.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so you, you like, your days are basically, you like wake up and just
Speaker 2:  sort of follow your tick tick list down through the day. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. It's like a mix of untimed, just like
Speaker 4:  general to-dos at the top. And then I've got my list of
Speaker 4:  like basically meetings after that and then, you know, very
Speaker 4:  pleasantly check them off and You can set things to repeat the next day,
Speaker 4:  the next week, next month.
Speaker 2:  So do you check your calendar essentially? Never.
Speaker 4:  No, I still check my calendar all the time. Okay. But just in
Speaker 2:  Case,
Speaker 4:  I guess the visual element of checking the calendar is still helpful. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And I don't get that from the to do list, which is weird. 'cause otherwise
Speaker 4:  I don't find the calendar. I find it overwhelming.
Speaker 2:  There is something So I I've, as, as you well know, as the person who edits
Speaker 2:  most of my stories, I have been writing about calendar apps for forever.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. And one of the things I have found fascinating about calendar apps
Speaker 2:  is that they're mostly terrible, but the like time grid
Speaker 2:  might be perfect. Like we might have just solved it when it comes to
Speaker 2:  like quickly looking at a thing and getting a sense of what's going on and
Speaker 2:  when lots of people have tried to do a new job and the time grid might just
Speaker 2:  be perfect. And I, I have gone through the same thing where like a a list
Speaker 2:  of stuff I have to do doesn't like communicate
Speaker 2:  the same level of understanding that just like quickly opening my calendar
Speaker 2:  and looking at it does.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A list is perfect for me personally, if I'm just planning out my
Speaker 4:  own day. But as soon as somebody says, when are you free? Or as soon as I
Speaker 4:  have to figure out when I mix in with somebody else's
Speaker 4:  schedule, just gotta go to the calendar app.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Are you a person, like do you every morning or every night,
Speaker 2:  like sit down and make a plan? Or do you just like show up and see what
Speaker 2:  Tick tick has for you?
Speaker 4:  Oh God no. Yeah, I just like, if it, it is either in there or it's not. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. If it's, if it's not, then I'm forgetting
Speaker 4:  somebody's birthday.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's, listen, I buy it. So do you have things like
Speaker 2:  you see a, you see a link that you wanna come back to? Where does that go?
Speaker 2:  A
Speaker 4:  Link that I wanna come back to. Oh,
Speaker 2:  It just stays as an open tab until it destroys your computer, doesn't it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. No, that's a hundred percent. That's all,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's most people's answer. Yeah. and it, it makes me so sad. Its,
Speaker 2:  it is the answer. Yeah. I just leave it as an open Chrome tab until
Speaker 2:  my computer beach balls and then many of them are gone. And that's just what
Speaker 2:  it is. That's
Speaker 4:  The cycle of life.
Speaker 2:  Where, what's your stance on email these days
Speaker 4:  Where that's a, an existential question?
Speaker 4:  Email is sort of like my, like B tier to do list.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Email is like, I leave a lot of things to be like, I
Speaker 4:  gotta get back to that. Now. The problem is when I have to respond to somebody
Speaker 4:  and then I'm like, Hmm, it's been a month.
Speaker 4:  Feel bad about this. I, my inbox is a total, total. I, I,
Speaker 4:  I do clear it out. I aim for inbox zero, but like that requires
Speaker 4:  archiving like a hundred emails a day. 'cause I get so much
Speaker 4:  nonsense. But it is like, I don't know, I guess email is mostly
Speaker 4:  like a secondary to do list for me. So I, check tic tick. And then I go over
Speaker 4:  to my email and I'm like, oh, okay. What do I actually have to do?
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah. I feel like we are a weird example because
Speaker 2:  like more than any company I've ever worked at Vox Media, just like does
Speaker 2:  not use email. Like we, we are so Slack
Speaker 2:  run as a company that I think we, we have a different relationship with
Speaker 2:  our inboxes than most where like if I got an email from Neli, I would
Speaker 2:  literally, it was, assume it was spam, I'd be like, why on earth would Neli
Speaker 2:  email me? But that's not how it works most places. Yeah. Yeah. So I think
Speaker 2:  we, we've all like, but then because we're like, we we're
Speaker 2:  people in a newsroom whose email addresses are mostly public, we get more
Speaker 2:  email than most people and we get more crap email than most people. So I
Speaker 2:  feel like I have reached a point where I've realized like my own email habits
Speaker 2:  have nothing in common with most normal people's email habits.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I always see journalists complaining about email and I'm like, right.
Speaker 4:  I don't think most people get like 200 spam
Speaker 4:  pitches every day. Right. Like I, and if they are, like, I,
Speaker 4:  I don't know. I have a lot of questions, but Yeah. I, I think that we are,
Speaker 4:  are unique there and like probably email is fine if you are
Speaker 4:  getting a more manageable amount of it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That, that seems right. So, okay. One more tick, tick question and
Speaker 2:  then I'll let you go. Yeah. Tick, tick on your computer versus
Speaker 2:  tick tick on your phone. Do you spend more time with one or the other? Do
Speaker 2:  you think about them differently?
Speaker 4:  It's, it's 95% on my computer. Okay. But
Speaker 4:  the fact that it is cross platform, I'm pretty sure it's Windows,
Speaker 4:  Mac, Android, iOS web as well. Yeah. It's everywhere. That was
Speaker 4:  big for me because I use a Mac and I use an Android phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you're like a unicorn in the tech universe.
Speaker 4:  I, I don't know what's wrong with me, but most of the beautiful to-do
Speaker 4:  apps are, are Apple ecosystem only and would like to be
Speaker 4:  able to change platforms whenever I'd like. And it's important to be able
Speaker 4:  to get, this is other things that's really nice about Tic Tick, it'll send
Speaker 4:  me reminders on my phone as well. So if I'm running late, late for a meeting,
Speaker 4:  I'll look down my phone and it'll tell me that I'm running late. So it's
Speaker 4:  90% on the Mac, but having the ability to quickly add things
Speaker 4:  and quickly check things on the phone key.
Speaker 2:  Any, any feature requests. What, what would you change about your system
Speaker 2:  if you could change something?
Speaker 4:  I mean, look, it's a mostly free app that's like slightly buggy and
Speaker 4:  broken but does absolutely everything you could dream of. I wouldn't change
Speaker 4:  a thing that
Speaker 2:  Sounds like every to-do list app. I love it. Mostly buggy wouldn't change
Speaker 2:  anything. Yeah. Awesome. All right Jake, thank you.
Speaker 4:  Got speed.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we have to take one more break and then I have two more people to
Speaker 2:  talk to and then I'll share my own system at the end. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  couch from my desk where I'll just take my notepad notebook with me, kinda
Speaker 9:  keeps me on task for the most part. And when I, you know,
Speaker 9:  get it done, I have the joy of checking it off the list with a little pen
Speaker 9:  and sometimes I use a different pen with a different style nib and different
Speaker 9:  color ink to check it off versus to, you know, to write
Speaker 9:  it. So it's a, each each time's a little treat, you know, because I
Speaker 9:  love this, frankly, every time I've tried like some kind of digital
Speaker 9:  solution, I feel like I spend more time working on that and
Speaker 9:  setting up what it is than I do actually just putting it in and getting a
Speaker 9:  task done. Awesome. Like, I tried, I tried like notion years, like
Speaker 9:  David, I I, I know every time there's a, there's a chat about this stuff
Speaker 9:  in, in work Slack, I, I I snicker to myself and I don't weigh in because
Speaker 9:  I, I'm all I think is like notion is a scam. Like I just can't get
Speaker 9:  behind it.
Speaker 2:  I mean, you're, you're right and you're wrong. I, I fully
Speaker 2:  understand that. What kind of notebook do you have?
Speaker 9:  So. I have alternated. Oh yeah. And this is an important thing. Yeah. Have
Speaker 9:  notebooks are pretty cheap and I think it's fun to get like ones of different
Speaker 9:  styles. Like I've used like this like basic black one that my wife got
Speaker 9:  me I think off Amazon like years ago. and it looks like a whole lot like
Speaker 9:  moskin or that kind of style. But you know, You can
Speaker 9:  pick ones that have like different like rulings, like different like line
Speaker 9:  spacing or dots instead of like a dock grid instead of lines. Or
Speaker 9:  I've used one that had, it was really a sketchbook. I think my wife wasn't
Speaker 9:  happy with me, but I kind of stole her sketch pad 'cause it was kind of
Speaker 9:  fancy. But I liked having for a period of time, no lines at
Speaker 9:  all. It was kind of like, oh, I can write big, I can write small. And some
Speaker 9:  pens that have like a broad nib for example, force you to write bigger and
Speaker 9:  that that can be kind of, kind of fun or adventurous. But I've kind of settled
Speaker 9:  on like The Rhodia notepad that's spiral bound and the
Speaker 9:  spirals on the top, which is kind of nice because You can like tear these
Speaker 9:  sheets out, throw 'em away when you're done with them or you know, kind of
Speaker 9:  make it, keep it nice and tidy if you really muck, muck up a, a sheet
Speaker 9:  and then it's a, it's a good quality paper, but you don't have to like, spend
Speaker 9:  a lot on a notebook. I mean, only if you really want to.
Speaker 2:  I do, I'm a big believer in the, the top spiral bound ones.
Speaker 2:  'cause You can, like, you don't run into the crease when you're trying to
Speaker 2:  write on the left side. It lays flat. It's, that is the way if if it's
Speaker 2:  just gonna live on your desk. Exactly.
Speaker 9:  And if I'm, I'm a righty. But if anyone's a lefty, that's also good. Totally
Speaker 2:  Good. Does your notebook go everywhere with you? Or does it like live on
Speaker 2:  your desk and, and you go to it when you need it?
Speaker 9:  It usually lives on my desk. I don't go to many places sadly,
Speaker 9:  but know
Speaker 2:  That feeling.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean I'm, I'm, I'm a, I'm remote but I have gone to our
Speaker 9:  New York office like a bunch of handful of times and
Speaker 9:  yeah, every time I've gone I've, I've brought my notebook with me. Sometimes
Speaker 9:  doesn't leave the bag, but, you know, hey, it's all well intentioned, right?
Speaker 9:  Like we're, we're we're just, we're just trying here.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely. I'm I'm with you. So what about like what calendary
Speaker 2:  stuff when you're like, I have to do something next Thursday,
Speaker 2:  where does that go?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean that's where like I always lean on Yeah. Digital stuff and that's
Speaker 9:  really gonna be like Google, Calendar, you know, for work. I've, I've got,
Speaker 9:  I've got my work and personal calendars of course separated personal calendars.
Speaker 9:  My wife and I have a bunch of shared ones that are like, here's our events,
Speaker 9:  here's our like, you know, works related stuff or hustles
Speaker 9:  or whatever that maybe come up from time to time. So they're all color
Speaker 9:  coded and like family functions, stuff like that, you know. So when
Speaker 9:  it comes to like scheduling in advance, there's that. And then what I do
Speaker 9:  for my personal, like errands, I I I just use like a
Speaker 9:  Google Keep to do list sometimes. Like if I'm just, 'cause I, I
Speaker 9:  think I started using GoogleKeep like years ago when I had a pixel just 'cause
Speaker 9:  it was there and it's clean and simple enough to make a little checklist
Speaker 9:  and it
Speaker 2:  Is the perfect, if you just want like a notes app you use every once in a
Speaker 2:  while, Google Keep is perfect.
Speaker 9:  Exactly. And it's like the perfect kind of thing to not care about because
Speaker 9:  it's just like, pull it up, make some check boxes. It's
Speaker 9:  like, this is the kind of thing I'm like, it's a Saturday and I've got a
Speaker 9:  bunch of chores to get done and I want some kind of like, I, I just wanna
Speaker 9:  write this stuff down fast. Like without like, again going to my desk and
Speaker 9:  like writing stuff down by hand. Like that'd be nice, but I don't, I just
Speaker 9:  don't need to on like a, a busy Saturday. So it's like, all right, it's all
Speaker 9:  there and then check it off, check it off, check it off, I'm done. You know,
Speaker 9:  like maybe I can put it depending on, I used to like change the color of
Speaker 9:  it and I think I stopped caring about that too.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So for the, that sounds very much like you think about it the same
Speaker 2:  way you think about the physical notebook, just kind of a digital
Speaker 2:  version of like, it has pages, You can tear off as you need to,
Speaker 2:  every, everything is kind of transitory that way. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Basically. And, and, and I try not to get too attached to it. I mean like,
Speaker 9:  the amount of times like I go to write and, and like on, on my
Speaker 9:  actual notebook and like a pen doesn't wanna start because I, oh I haven't
Speaker 9:  used that one in a while. It's like, ah, screw it. Just move on to the next
Speaker 9:  one. Or like, I, I'm just like, so they each, each page sometimes is like
Speaker 9:  filled with like scribbles of me getting a pen to start and you know,
Speaker 9:  sometimes it's like, alright, whatever, it's ugly. Who, who cares? It's fleeting.
Speaker 9:  Like it's just, just kind of be in the moment, get your stuff done for the
Speaker 9:  day and, and move on. Because like the greater tasks are gonna be
Speaker 9:  like probably in like your calendar appointments or for us with
Speaker 9:  work, if it's Airtable, you know, it's kind of like, you know, you, you're,
Speaker 9:  you're, it's what you're getting assigned and it's like, well it's, it's
Speaker 9:  there for like me to, but I need to dive into like the micro
Speaker 9:  tasks for, for just today. Like what do I start on right
Speaker 9:  now? What do I need to do? How do I make this mechanical? So many times like
Speaker 9:  we, we jump, I jump into like a, a post and I think, like I tell myself,
Speaker 9:  make it mechanical. If I don't know where to start writing, lemme start filling
Speaker 9:  in like the, the less exciting, less cre not
Speaker 9:  creatively demanding things that just make it, I'm just going through the
Speaker 9:  motions to get those gears moving. And when those gears are moving it's
Speaker 9:  like, okay, now I can kind of take off and, and and run So I start walking
Speaker 9:  basically with every little step.
Speaker 2:  That's great. Make it Mechanical is a pretty good like sticky note to put
Speaker 2:  on your computer monitor every day. I like that a lot. Thanks. Anything you
Speaker 2:  would add to your system? If you, if you could, what do you feel like is
Speaker 2:  missing? Or do you feel like it works?
Speaker 9:  I would add more pens. I will always be buying more pens. Love it.
Speaker 9:  Better handwriting. But no, like I, I don't really know, but
Speaker 9:  maybe like if for some other like personal projects that
Speaker 9:  really are kind of more multi-layered, like a photo project that I'm,
Speaker 9:  that I kind of am, am ideating on or whatever. Like, I don't know, maybe,
Speaker 9:  maybe I could see myself trying again with something that's like a little
Speaker 9:  bit more involved. Again, not notion, sorry,
Speaker 9:  been there, tried it. Nope. But no I don't, I don't know. I just, I guess
Speaker 9:  I just, I just try to keep things really simple.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. I like it. All right Antonio, thank you for doing this. Appreciate
Speaker 2:  it. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  No problem. Thanks David.
Speaker 2:  Up next and last but certainly not least, reviews Editor
Speaker 2:  Barbara Krasnoff. Barbara, welcome to the show. Thank
Speaker 10:  You.
Speaker 2:  So tell me about your productivity system.
Speaker 10:  Oh, it all depends on what I'm doing that week or what I'm using that week
Speaker 10:  because I've used a whole lot of things. Right now my main
Speaker 10:  productivity app is Notion, I use it to track most
Speaker 10:  of the things I do. I basically take a page, I say
Speaker 10:  it's my tasks for this day or this week
Speaker 10:  and it, there's a list of everything that needs follow up. Sometimes
Speaker 10:  I use a checkbox to do list. Sometimes I just type things out. Sometimes
Speaker 10:  there are links to the Slack messages that inspired them.
Speaker 10:  Sometimes I've got due dates, sometimes I don't, if anyone else looked at
Speaker 10:  it, they wouldn't see it as an organizational system. They see it as a
Speaker 10:  mass of, of of stuff. But it works for me.
Speaker 10:  I did try to be more organized with Notion. I tried building a Notion
Speaker 10:  database because if you do that then You can right click
Speaker 10:  on a Slack entry and share directly with Notion without having to
Speaker 10:  do the cut and paste thing. And I tried that for about two weeks
Speaker 10:  and it did not work for me. A, it was much too formal. In
Speaker 10:  fact that's it. It was much too formal. I just couldn't deal with that.
Speaker 2:  I had the exact same experience. It ends up being, it, it felt so fiddly
Speaker 2:  to me to be inside of this database thing that I
Speaker 2:  ended up, I went back to the same thing you did of just like, I'm just gonna
Speaker 2:  write down a bunch of stuff and figure it out from there.
Speaker 10:  Absolutely. Now if there's something that I'm really afraid I'll miss like
Speaker 10:  a task that's due at a certain date, then I'll use
Speaker 10:  Google tasks. And the reason I use that is because I'm always checking my
Speaker 10:  calendar because I'm always missing meetings. So I'm always checking the
Speaker 10:  calendar and that the tasks come right up on the calendar. I mostly
Speaker 10:  don't give them dates. I mean times I just give them a date
Speaker 10:  because then you have this big
Speaker 10:  colored bar across the top of each date and I can use that
Speaker 10:  to, to give myself a a sort of poke in the ass.
Speaker 2:  So Notion is kind of the like scratch pad for your life
Speaker 2:  but then if it's like this thing has to get done or else the world falls
Speaker 2:  apart, it goes into your calendar in some
Speaker 10:  Way? It goes into my calendar, yeah. Okay. And then of course there's Airtable
Speaker 10:  because we've got to use Airtable.
Speaker 2:  Do you like Airtable? We've heard some mixed things about Airtable from folks
Speaker 2:  so far.
Speaker 10:  You know, the funny thing is I first I liked it because it was fun to play
Speaker 10:  with then I didn't like it because it's one more thing to check.
Speaker 10:  But now that I'm starting to pay more attention
Speaker 10:  to when something that I edit has to appear and So, I
Speaker 10:  have to look at the calendars that Alex Kranz and
Speaker 10:  some other people have created, now I'm finding it useful again, So I keep
Speaker 10:  going back and forth. So on the whole, I like Airtable. I do have some
Speaker 10:  problems with it. I think if I spent about another two
Speaker 10:  weeks really, really learning it, I'd like it even better.
Speaker 2:  I think that's probably right. Which is the thing that drives me crazy about
Speaker 2:  Airtable, which is it like so many of these tools including Notion actually
Speaker 2:  it is so incredibly powerful and I
Speaker 2:  don't care about most of it and as a result it ends up
Speaker 2:  being kind of fussy and slow in some ways. Every
Speaker 2:  time I go back to Notion, I end up like running away towards some other simpler
Speaker 2:  app. But then it can't do all the things that notion does So I go back to
Speaker 2:  Notion and I feel like Airtable is the same way where it's like you, if you
Speaker 2:  leave you can't do stuff, but if you come back it's too much stuff. And
Speaker 2:  this is like the productivity app nightmare that you and I have signed ourselves
Speaker 2:  up for somehow.
Speaker 10:  Yes, it really is. And the funny thing is with Notion, I'm actually starting
Speaker 10:  to like it more. I left it for a little while 'cause I felt it was a little
Speaker 10:  bit too fussy too. There was too much you could do with it and it was
Speaker 10:  get getting Evernote syndrome, you know, where there was just too much
Speaker 10:  stuff there. But then I started using it back and now I'm actually trying
Speaker 10:  to write, use it to write a novel. So it's,
Speaker 2:  Is it working well for that? Yes
Speaker 10:  It is because I have, I have trouble, I'm a short story writer mostly and
Speaker 10:  I'm trying to write a novel and I need separate chapters. I was able to
Speaker 10:  separate them in Notion where I wasn't able to really do it in in a couple
Speaker 10:  of other things I tried. So we'll see what happens with that.
Speaker 2:  That's cool. What about outside of work? Do you have the same kind of organizational
Speaker 2:  system for your non-work life that you do for your work life or,
Speaker 2:  or do you have a totally separate way of thinking about
Speaker 10:  It? I've totally s well except for the fact that I'm now using Notion, trying
Speaker 10:  Notion Sure. With writing. But for personal to-dos, I use Tic Tic.
Speaker 10:  I've been using that for a long time. Unfortunately. I'm also,
Speaker 10:  I also tend to ignore it sometimes. So I'm, I, I'm
Speaker 10:  starting to actually go back, use the same Google tasks
Speaker 10:  format that I used with my
Speaker 10:  work stuff because I have a different calendar for personal
Speaker 10:  but you know, it sort of waves at me and says Hi, you got to do this by
Speaker 10:  this time. Right? Which tick tick really doesn't. And then I used
Speaker 10:  to use Evernote but it got too
Speaker 10:  large and then it got too expensive.
Speaker 10:  Way too expensive.
Speaker 2:  Agreed and agreed
Speaker 10:  Or what I used it for, which was fairly simple stuff. So
Speaker 10:  I recently left Evernote in favor of
Speaker 10:  Up Note, which is one of the lesser known ones. And
Speaker 10:  I'm keeping my fingers crossed because it's also very small. So who knows,
Speaker 10:  it'll be around in five years. But it
Speaker 10:  pulled in my Evernote stuff without much trouble. and
Speaker 10:  it looks a little bit like a simpler version of Evernote. I like it.
Speaker 10:  It's just a day by day. You can make to do notes or You can
Speaker 10:  write whole essays and it's, it's looks, it looks a little bit like Evernote
Speaker 10:  if I was gonna say
Speaker 2:  It's like if, if Evernote were much better designed and didn't
Speaker 2:  have 15 years of like cruft attached to it, I feel like that's what Up Note
Speaker 2:  looks like. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Exactly. Yeah, exactly. And they,
Speaker 10:  they're responsive. I had a little trouble with my getting my Evernote
Speaker 10:  stuff over and I sent them a note and figured I'd hear from them in about
Speaker 10:  two weeks and I heard from them in a few hours. Nice. So it was great.
Speaker 2:  That is really great. Any other apps you've tried recently that you really
Speaker 2:  like? You're the, you're probably the person on staff who tests as many of
Speaker 2:  these as I do. I just do it 'cause I'm a lunatic. You do it because you like
Speaker 2:  to help people on the internet. Anything else you've tried recently that
Speaker 2:  you like?
Speaker 10:  Not recently, no. I mean there are, there are several, I should have
Speaker 10:  brought up my article because I can never remember the names of these things.
Speaker 10:  There are several that are sort of on the up note level that
Speaker 10:  are okay and that I was trying and so
Speaker 10:  let's see. I used Keep occasionally,
Speaker 10:  but that's only for the, the odd note here and there.
Speaker 10:  Joplin was not bad. Mm, okay. That that,
Speaker 10:  that's really interesting because it uses markdown
Speaker 10:  and my problem with it was it depends on markdown a little bit too much
Speaker 10:  and if that doesn't bother you, it's really nice and
Speaker 10:  simple and you know, there is a, a very decent
Speaker 10:  free version available.
Speaker 2:  That's a good one. I have not tried that one but I I have heard a few people
Speaker 2:  who swear by Joplin Yeah as a, as a tool for collecting all your stuff
Speaker 10:  And a lot of of people swear by obsidian as well. Yes. And
Speaker 10:  that was what I almost went to Obsidian. It was between
Speaker 10:  that and up note and I ended up with
Speaker 10:  Up note. I also use a notebook. I mean I actually write
Speaker 2:  What a concept
Speaker 10:  You know in a real notebook so there's that as well. I always
Speaker 10:  carry something like that around with me because you know, sometimes
Speaker 10:  you just have to grab something and write down a very quick note. I have
Speaker 10:  not found it as easy to, you know, grab
Speaker 10:  my phone and talk into it. Sometimes I do, but not all the time.
Speaker 10:  This
Speaker 2:  All makes a lot of sense to me. It just sounds like a lot of things. That's
Speaker 2:  my, my only, my only immediate reaction is like, this strikes me
Speaker 2:  as a lot of places just to check for stuff
Speaker 2:  and especially like, you know, you the the to-do lists. I, as soon as you
Speaker 2:  said, I also use Tic Tick, I was like, do you remember to check Tick tick?
Speaker 2:  And you said you don't but, so do you ever feel like you, you want to
Speaker 2:  consolidate everything into fewer places or does the system you have work
Speaker 2:  for you?
Speaker 10:  I, I should probably consolidate a little bit. My biggest problem was with
Speaker 10:  the to-do list with the Tick Tick versus Google tasks.
Speaker 10:  And I sometimes think I need to go to tick tick, look at all the
Speaker 10:  stuff that's like months old that I haven't done.
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 10:  You know, and go through that and get rid of it. I'm so used to
Speaker 10:  using it then sometimes I think I should be using Google tests. I should
Speaker 10:  be just using Tick Tick better. But those are the only two.
Speaker 10:  'cause everything else like Notion I use for almost everything else
Speaker 10:  fairly, I like playing with the other stuff but
Speaker 10:  I always, I usually tend to come back to that. And
Speaker 10:  the only other thing I really use is writing in a notebook and that's
Speaker 10:  just something I carry around with me. And then if any, if there's anything
Speaker 10:  in there that I need permanently, then I move it over.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Yeah, again, I, I keep trying to quit Notion and I
Speaker 2:  keep coming back to Notion So I
Speaker 10:  I feel I know. And by the way, if you find anything that you think I should
Speaker 10:  be trying or playing with or adding to my list of note taking apps,
Speaker 10:  please, please tell me because I'm always playing with new ones.
Speaker 2:  I will, I'll keep you posted for sure. All right Barbara, thank you so much.
Speaker 10:  Thank you. This was a lot of fun.
Speaker 2:  Well that was fascinating. There are some things in there I'm definitely
Speaker 2:  gonna steal immediately. Like Jay's shared doc of stuff to talk about with
Speaker 2:  his partner and Victoria's Wall calendar. I also think the
Speaker 2:  idea of just like writing all your stuff down no matter what as a to-do list
Speaker 2:  is great. Also Kara is definitely right. Everyone should just
Speaker 2:  take more notes on everything all the time. But before I
Speaker 2:  make anything work better in the spirit of sharing and openness, here's
Speaker 2:  how my system currently works. I've tried
Speaker 2:  everything. Like I, I actually feel fair
Speaker 2:  saying that I've tried every app that there is to try. I've
Speaker 2:  tried a lot of systems and I've settled on this thing that you hear a lot
Speaker 2:  called time blocking. And basically the idea is at the beginning of every
Speaker 2:  day or the night before or whenever you wanna do it, you sit down and you
Speaker 2:  go through your calendar and you give every minute a job, right?
Speaker 2:  So things like projects you have to get done. You don't just put them on
Speaker 2:  a list, you put them on your calendar at a time because the theory is if
Speaker 2:  you don't give things the time to get done they won't get done. And So
Speaker 2:  I for a long time would have things like take a shower and
Speaker 2:  eat breakfast as calendar events and then that started to seem
Speaker 2:  bananas. So now it's just an hour of like get ready in the morning
Speaker 2:  on my calendar every day. But I put sit and watch
Speaker 2:  movies on my calendar like downtime is a thing I schedule now
Speaker 2:  because the idea is if you put everything in your calendar in a way that
Speaker 2:  works and makes sense, You can trust that when you say
Speaker 2:  downtime, You can do downtime and that has actually been really meaningful
Speaker 2:  for me. And the app I use most is an app called Note Plan. It's
Speaker 2:  mostly on Apple devices but there's a web app now that works pretty well
Speaker 2:  too. And its thing is it's basically a combination of
Speaker 2:  calendar notes and to-Do List app. And I wouldn't say it's
Speaker 2:  amazing at any of those things, but it does all of them
Speaker 2:  serviceably well and I love that So I can open the app and
Speaker 2:  it shows me all my calendar events in the right sidebar for the day and all
Speaker 2:  of my reminders. I mostly use Apple Reminders now because I use an
Speaker 2:  iPhone and it's just easy to use Siri to dump stuff into reminders and
Speaker 2:  then it shows up in that sidebar in note plan. And so every morning I'll
Speaker 2:  sit down, I'll look at my calendar events, I'll look at my to-do list and
Speaker 2:  I will basically write a bulleted list of everything in order that I
Speaker 2:  plan to do that day. And then the goal if all goes right is just to
Speaker 2:  plow through that every single day. Something about writing it all down and
Speaker 2:  sort of seeing it in one place and also knowing like what do I need to do
Speaker 2:  next is a question I can answer just by opening an app is very
Speaker 2:  handy. I would say I switch away from Note Plan like once every
Speaker 2:  three weeks. I've tried Notion, I've tried Obsidian,
Speaker 2:  I used Obsidian for a long time actually I think that app is very good. I
Speaker 2:  go to Evernote periodically. I tried Rome, I really like WorkFlowy
Speaker 2:  because my brain just kind of thinks in bullets and outlines and
Speaker 2:  that worked for me really well. I've tried all of the apps
Speaker 2:  that there are for doing this kind of thing and note plan because
Speaker 2:  it's that combo of calendar reminders and notes all in one place
Speaker 2:  has just worked for me. I do live out of my calendar. I'm very much the kind
Speaker 2:  of person that if I don't put something on the calendar, it's not going to
Speaker 2:  happen. I just don't trust my brain and I trust my calendar.
Speaker 2:  So. I don't even think, right? Like I that lingering sense of like, oh,
Speaker 2:  did I schedule that thing? What was I supposed to be doing today? I don't
Speaker 2:  have that because I just assume it's all on my calendar. I
Speaker 2:  miss things occasionally because I forgot to schedule them. But I trust
Speaker 2:  my calendar a lot. I use an app called Fantastical, which
Speaker 2:  I think is wonderful and again has reminders. Integration, So. I can see
Speaker 2:  my tasks in there too. I can schedule stuff. Google, Calendar
Speaker 2:  works fine. I think the Outlook calendar is kind of hideous, but
Speaker 2:  Google Calendar is solid. It all works fine. I don't have particular
Speaker 2:  religion when it comes to calendar apps, but I like fantastical a lot.
Speaker 2:  Like I said, I use Apple Reminders, I've switched between all the to-Do lists.
Speaker 2:  I think to do list is great. I think Tick Tick, which a bunch of my colleagues
Speaker 2:  have mentioned is also great. But for me, just being able to
Speaker 2:  like fire up Siri, say remind me to
Speaker 2:  take out the trash at 9:00 PM tomorrow. But just being able to
Speaker 2:  fire up Siri, say Remind me to take out the trash at 9:00 PM
Speaker 2:  tomorrow and have it appear in the rest of my system is amazing.
Speaker 2:  The other part of my system, I would say is what I use for bigger
Speaker 2:  projects, like stories I'm working on or vergecast
Speaker 2:  episodes or bigger things, especially things with due dates and
Speaker 2:  deadlines. I have used literally
Speaker 2:  every app that exists to do this kind of thing. I've used Notion where I
Speaker 2:  built a really beautiful database and Kanban board that has everything just
Speaker 2:  right. I've used what basically you could just call like a big
Speaker 2:  long list of stuff. There's a productivity blog that I read a long time
Speaker 2:  ago that says, one thing a lot of CEOs do is just have a
Speaker 2:  long ass list. So I've tried the long ass list. Right now I'm using an app
Speaker 2:  called Capacities that I think is pretty clever. It has some neat
Speaker 2:  organizational tools, but it might be too complicated. I might end up back
Speaker 2:  at Notion before I get frustrated with it and switch to something else. Again,
Speaker 2:  the note plan thing is pretty settled for me, but this idea of like how do
Speaker 2:  I manage all of the different sorts of things that I need to get
Speaker 2:  done in one way, shape, or form that's bigger than just like a task I can
Speaker 2:  write on one line I have not solved and I spend a lot of time thinking about
Speaker 2:  it because I think when I get it right somehow everything will become
Speaker 2:  more pleasant and doable in my life. Probably not, but
Speaker 2:  it's worth a try. All of this is to say, I think the big thing I've learned
Speaker 2:  from this is that I switched too much and this anarchy is
Speaker 2:  bad. All of my information is in lots of places. I don't
Speaker 2:  necessarily know how to use each of these apps to their
Speaker 2:  fullest extent, which is a thing I talked about a lot with Laura Ma Martin.
Speaker 2:  The idea of like really understanding the settings and being able to make
Speaker 2:  the most of the app. I don't have any of that and I gotta work on that. And
Speaker 2:  to that point, one thing that I'm learning both from talking to Laura last
Speaker 2:  week and talking to all my colleagues here is that simplicity and
Speaker 2:  consolidation actually go a really long way. Or digital lives
Speaker 2:  by nature kind of tend to spiral, right? We're on so many platforms,
Speaker 2:  we're in so many apps, we do so many different kinds of things all day and
Speaker 2:  we're interacting with these endless feeds full of stuff that it just
Speaker 2:  feels like the entropy of it all feels inevitable. So, I,
Speaker 2:  think picking a place or a couple of places that are your places
Speaker 2:  feels really important. And I think that actually might be more important
Speaker 2:  than what those places are. Just knowing that there are a
Speaker 2:  couple of them, whether it's telling people that email and text is better
Speaker 2:  than Slack for you, or throwing your entire life no matter
Speaker 2:  what it is into a to do list or just being like, I am a person who
Speaker 2:  uses Google Docs for everything. I think less is more,
Speaker 2:  even if the tools aren't perfect and actually require a little more busy
Speaker 2:  work. You know that phrase a single source of truth. I think having
Speaker 2:  that for your digital life might actually be more important and
Speaker 2:  more useful than building these perfect beautiful
Speaker 2:  interlocking systems that I've been trying to build myself for way too many
Speaker 2:  years at this point. Anyway, lots to think about. Lots of good
Speaker 2:  ideas. I am probably gonna go blow up my entire
Speaker 2:  productivity system because that is what I tend to do when things like this
Speaker 2:  happen. And we have one more episode actually coming up in this series,
Speaker 2:  which I suspect will have some insight into this as well. We're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about one of the OG all time, most popular
Speaker 2:  productivity apps and kind of how the world changed around it.
Speaker 2:  But for now, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  came on the show and did this with me. And thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or awesome productivity
Speaker 2:  systems you want to ruin my life by introducing me to You can always email
Speaker 2:  us vergecast at The Verge dot com. Keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  VERGE one, one. we love hearing from you. The feedback to this
Speaker 2:  series so far has been really fun. I worry sometimes that I'm like the only
Speaker 2:  person who thinks too much about productivity and how to manage your life
Speaker 2:  digitally, so it's been really nice to hear from all the people who have
Speaker 2:  enjoyed this as much as I have. Thank you to everybody who's reached out.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Angel Marino, Liam James, and Will Poor, and this
Speaker 2:  episode was edited by Xandr Adams. The Vergecast is The Verge production,
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday and Friday
Speaker 2:  with our regularly scheduled programming. Everybody's back. We're going to
Speaker 2:  have tons of fun stuff and we actually have a couple of really great things
Speaker 2:  coming up this week. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.