# Transcript
ID: f15de005-b9d4-4d6a-b519-b15c984b8683
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5192883973129364899/-8839081164137772598/s93290-US-3527s-1724141678.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of hydrogen futures:
The Verge’s William Poor, Andrew Marino, and Alex Parkin head to California to figure out why hydrogen fuel cell technology, once a super-promising successor to gasoline, lost out to battery electric cars. They also put the embattled tech to the test with a road trip across California’s “hydrogen highway.”
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Hydrogen Futures. I'm your
Speaker 2:  friend David Pierce and I am trying to
Speaker 2:  redecorate a bit. So if you watch The Vergecast on YouTube,
Speaker 2:  you've noticed that we just recently got a really awesome new studio in our
Speaker 2:  New York office. You may have also noticed that Neli got a really awesome
Speaker 2:  new studio in his house. So I'm very jealous of all of this, which has really
Speaker 2:  led me to spend, I would say, an inappropriate and unnecessary amount of
Speaker 2:  time trying to figure out my own background. I feel like everyone went through
Speaker 2:  this like in 2020 when we all started being home more often. You started
Speaker 2:  to be aware of kind of how your space looks on
Speaker 2:  camera. I make a podcast on camera now, and so
Speaker 2:  I notice it more than is probably healthy or reasonable and
Speaker 2:  I've just been trying to figure out how do I make this look a little nicer,
Speaker 2:  a little more studio ish and less like the basement
Speaker 2:  slash home office slash guest room slash child
Speaker 2:  PlayPlace that it actually is. So I suggested this to Liam,
Speaker 2:  our producer, that maybe I want to do some stuff. He sent me a long list
Speaker 2:  of things to do. He wants me to put blinds on the window. He wants me
Speaker 2:  to move the guitar that's over here, but I think I actually just need to
Speaker 2:  get rid of it because I don't play it enough or well enough for it to feel
Speaker 2:  honest to have a guitar in the shot. I already put some books up that I think
Speaker 2:  look nicer than the mugs that were there. The mugs are now up there. There's
Speaker 2:  just a lot going on. Will I eventually put some like cool purple lights
Speaker 2:  and go full YouTuber? Probably it's gonna happen. I'm excited about it. If
Speaker 2:  you have ideas for my home studio, please hit me up, ideally if they don't
Speaker 2:  cost a million dollars and won't make my wife very angry.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today. We're doing something
Speaker 2:  a little different on the show today, will Pour. Our producer
Speaker 2:  got very interested in what I would call an alternate future
Speaker 2:  for transportation. Right now we're in the middle of this incredible
Speaker 2:  revolution in EVs. We're rethinking the way that charging networks work.
Speaker 2:  They're being built out all over the place. There's huge money being put
Speaker 2:  into it. Lots of companies, every car company is suddenly in on what
Speaker 2:  if the future of cars is batteries? But that's not the only future that we
Speaker 2:  could have had. And in fact, there was a minute where it looked like that
Speaker 2:  wasn't gonna be the future that we did have. So Will
Speaker 2:  and a couple of other folks on our team went out to California and went on
Speaker 2:  a road trip to see what that future might have looked like and what we
Speaker 2:  missed. All that is coming up in just a sec, but first, I have to
Speaker 2:  move this stuff behind me because now I notice all the clutter and I hate
Speaker 2:  it and I gotta fix it. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 4:  was 2004 years before Tesla got everyone
Speaker 4:  jazzed about battery powered electric cars. Batteries were
Speaker 4:  promising, but another technology was farther
Speaker 4:  along. Hydrogen fuel cells could power an
Speaker 4:  electric motor using only hydrogen gas. The cars
Speaker 4:  produced no emissions or byproducts except pure
Speaker 4:  water. Governor Schwarzenegger got very excited about
Speaker 4:  fuel cells and he proposed an elaborate hydrogen highway
Speaker 4:  to support them. The government would help fund a network of fuel
Speaker 4:  stations which would encourage automakers to build cars.
Speaker 4:  More cars would lead to more stations and by 2010 the
Speaker 4:  plan went every Californian would have access to hydrogen
Speaker 4:  fuel. From there, advocates predicted a nationwide
Speaker 4:  expansion. It could spell the end of the petroleum era
Speaker 4:  in America.
Speaker 4:  That is not what happened.
Speaker 6:  San Jose Snell Avenue under maintenance.
Speaker 4:  Oh, offline.
Speaker 6:  Since this morning at 10 50. Oh geez. Okay. The station is
Speaker 6:  offline for repair.
Speaker 4:  20 years later, I found myself driving across California
Speaker 4:  in a fuel cell car. A Toyota Marai. Rolling
Speaker 4:  again. I was there to find out what became of that
Speaker 4:  grand green vision of the future. We are 23 minutes away
Speaker 4:  from the closest station. Today there are hydrogen
Speaker 4:  powered cars You can buy in California and some stations to fill
Speaker 4:  them up at. But the statewide network never
Speaker 4:  materialized, let alone a national one. And those
Speaker 4:  stations are failing.
Speaker 7:  Maybe one pump worked for months at a time. Sometimes none of 'em
Speaker 7:  worked.
Speaker 4:  The cost of fuel is skyrocketing. $36
Speaker 8:  A kilos and it's
Speaker 4:  Insane. And car sales are plummeting.
Speaker 9:  I'm trying to take it back to Toyota.
Speaker 4:  The hydrogen experiment is teetering on the
Speaker 4:  brink Right now. The auto industry is making this
Speaker 4:  huge seismic shift to battery powered
Speaker 4:  cars. Why not hydrogen? Why didn't that version of
Speaker 4:  history win out? Who's still fighting for hydrogen today
Speaker 4:  and what's happening to the thousands of drivers still sticking it out with
Speaker 4:  their cars? This all felt like a lot of questions that
Speaker 4:  only a road trip could answer. So in June I roped in
Speaker 4:  fellow producer Andrew and our video director Alex. The three of us
Speaker 4:  flew to San Francisco, rented a marai on Touro and
Speaker 4:  charted a course from the Bay Area to Los Angeles
Speaker 4:  along whatever was left of the hydrogen
Speaker 4:  highway here to here.
Speaker 4:  We are going there.
Speaker 1:  Yep.
Speaker 4:  We picked up our marai in the parking lot of a mini golf course outside
Speaker 4:  San Jose, just south of San Francisco.
Speaker 4:  It's a very ordinary looking sedan. If it weren't for the little
Speaker 4:  fuel cell badge on the back, you wouldn't know there was anything unusual
Speaker 4:  about it.
Speaker 1:  Whoa.
Speaker 4:  Under the hood, a marai and a Tesla are surprisingly
Speaker 4:  similar. They're both powered by electric motors and a fuel
Speaker 4:  cell is basically a battery just instead of pumping
Speaker 4:  in electricity to store and use later you're pumping in
Speaker 4:  hydrogen to react with oxygen and generate electricity on the
Speaker 4:  fly. In other words, a Mariah's hydrogen tank and a
Speaker 4:  Tesla's battery are just two different ways of storing energy until
Speaker 4:  it's needed to power the car. Oh, there's one other difference. The fuel
Speaker 4:  cell creates a decent amount of water as a byproduct. In the
Speaker 4:  Mariah, it's almost a cup per mile traveled. So the car does need
Speaker 4:  to
Speaker 4:  pee.
Speaker 4:  As the Mariah drives it occasionally shoots water out a little hole
Speaker 4:  underneath the car. You can also make it pee on command by
Speaker 4:  hitting a button on the dashboard.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Go ahead and start the car. The remote is in the middle.
Speaker 11:  You side the
Speaker 4:  Remote. The guy we rented from Salman gave us a quick tour of the
Speaker 4:  car
Speaker 11:  And it's a luxury car. It drives beautiful actually, once you drive this
Speaker 11:  you'll feel it.
Speaker 4:  The Mariah has a classy interior and a flashy nav system with a
Speaker 4:  gazillion cameras. The only oddity is this hump in the back row
Speaker 4:  of seats. The main hydrogen tank sits underneath it. It makes sitting
Speaker 4:  in the middle kind of awkward. Alman told us we'd love the
Speaker 4:  car, but he wasn't sure about our travel plans.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. When I came to know you were in LA I was like, wait a second. I was
Speaker 11:  a little uncomfortable.
Speaker 4:  The problem is most of the fuel stations in California are
Speaker 4:  clustered around the Bay Area and Los Angeles. There's just one
Speaker 4:  pump on Interstate five in between. It's at a place called Harris
Speaker 4:  Ranch. We kind of need to refuel there. The drive
Speaker 4:  to LA is about 325 miles, which is
Speaker 4:  right at the max range of this car. But we also
Speaker 4:  need luck because apparently hydrogen stations
Speaker 4:  just don't work. Sometimes there's
Speaker 11:  Always a credit card issue. Sometimes the card system is down, sometimes
Speaker 11:  the pump itself is down. Sometimes there is not enough hydrogen,
Speaker 4:  Which makes our stop at Harris Ranch. Very high stakes.
Speaker 11:  If that pump is down Yeah. Then you know you're stuck.
Speaker 4:  You've never driven down to No, not
Speaker 11:  Yet. Yeah, I didn't wanna take a chance yet.
Speaker 4:  Not exactly a pep talk. Pep. Oh and there was one other
Speaker 4:  FYI, the price of hydrogen two
Speaker 11:  Years ago. It used to cost like 50 or $60 to fill the whole whole tank.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Right now it's like 180, 190 to fill the tanks. Yeah. So
Speaker 11:  that is killing everybody right now.
Speaker 4:  $180 to fill up a sedan. Yeah. I don't think we
Speaker 4:  budgeted enough money for the fuel for
Speaker 11:  This trip. Yeah, so, so that's what I got disappointed. I said, you know
Speaker 11:  what, I'll just put on Turo. Yeah. And live with it like that.
Speaker 4:  And with that there was nothing left to do but hit the road
Speaker 4:  excited and suddenly very nervous. Turn
Speaker 12:  Right then your destination will be on the left.
Speaker 4:  Thank you Siri. Our first goal was to visit as many fuel
Speaker 4:  stations as we could find in the Bay Area. On paper there are
Speaker 4:  about 17, but according to the station finder apps we
Speaker 4:  downloaded, lots of them were offline or under some kind of
Speaker 4:  maintenance. Alright, we're coming up on it. I never know. You never know
Speaker 4:  what kind of gas station it's gonna be. Almost all the stations here
Speaker 4:  are operated by a startup called First Element Fuel, but they're
Speaker 4:  co-located at Chevron or Shell or other gas stations.
Speaker 4:  First element leases the space from station owners, the Shell station,
Speaker 4:  the pumps themselves are bright blue with these eye catching awnings.
Speaker 4:  Some of them are slotted right in between gas pumps. Others are set
Speaker 4:  apart in their own little pads and parking
Speaker 4:  lots. Well let's try to figure this
Speaker 4:  out. The mechanics of filling up a hydrogen
Speaker 4:  tank are familiar enough. Insert a credit card, select
Speaker 4:  fuel connect pump to car, hang out for five
Speaker 4:  minutes. But unlike gasoline, these pumps are moving
Speaker 4:  around a compressed freezing cold gas. So there are
Speaker 4:  locks and sensors to keep everything safe and reliable. The
Speaker 4:  nozzle is a heavy metal cylinder with a collar that keeps the
Speaker 4:  hose in place. It's all a bit of a learning curve. It
Speaker 4:  says hide the yellow mark. I don't see a
Speaker 4:  yellow mark, but I think pulling this sleeve down locks
Speaker 4:  it. So we just push it in and
Speaker 4:  then lock it. Oh,
Speaker 13:  There we go.
Speaker 4:  Just a yellow. Okay, we're filling up. We tried
Speaker 4:  fueling at most of the stations we visited and we always got
Speaker 4:  fuel, but we hit a glit or two in just about every part of the
Speaker 4:  process. The screens are both wigging out a little bit, but it
Speaker 4:  seems like it's fine. I
Speaker 4:  don't know what door sensor means, but, oh I think it
Speaker 4:  timed out or something. I gotta run my cart again.
Speaker 4:  One constant struggle. The nozzle kept sticking to the car after we were
Speaker 4:  done filling. I hate that.
Speaker 4:  I hate yanking that hard on
Speaker 4:  anything. But that was just our
Speaker 4:  experience. We also talked with every Mirage driver. We ran
Speaker 4:  into, Hey, excuse me. Do you have time while you feel to
Speaker 4:  to chat with us for our, for our story and their stories
Speaker 4:  Were more extreme.
Speaker 14:  These are third stage station we are right now. We came
Speaker 4:  Oh, you you tried to go to two others.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, there's one station in Sunnyvale, one in San Jose. This is one in
Speaker 14:  Cupertino. Half of the time these don't work here. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 13:  So they're either out of gas or That's the problem with
Speaker 14:  The machine. And even sometimes it shows you to insert card. When you insert
Speaker 14:  the card it's says transaction canceled and it doesn't give you anything
Speaker 14:  out.
Speaker 4:  It just doesn't work and then you
Speaker 14:  Just, it just doesn't work.
Speaker 4:  Mead and Rupesh have been driving their Mirai for about four months,
Speaker 4:  which for them has been a nonstop hunt for working
Speaker 4:  stations. I had no idea just how frequently they run out
Speaker 4:  of fuel or glitch or lose pressure and can't fill
Speaker 4:  tanks completely. And
Speaker 13:  It's always a pressure on you mentally because you never know which
Speaker 13:  one's gonna work, which one's not gonna work.
Speaker 4:  Fuel has been so hard to find that these guys have been stretching
Speaker 4:  every kilogram. That's how hydrogen is measured. When they drive,
Speaker 4:  they accelerate and break carefully. They avoid air
Speaker 4:  conditioning because it uses more fuel and when the car says it still
Speaker 4:  has a hundred miles left in the tank, they look for a station. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Boy. So you have to really think about how you're driving the car.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. You have to focus on the road and also on the, on your mileage here.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Manatee bought the car because of a huge incentive from Toyota.
Speaker 4:  Every new or certified used Mariah comes with a
Speaker 4:  $15,000 preloaded fuel card. Toyota
Speaker 4:  told us it's there to absorb any volatility in fuel prices
Speaker 4:  and that's not the only big promotion out there.
Speaker 15:  So this car I got for 15,000 hard to
Speaker 15:  beat, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Rebecca said she went shopping for a battery electric car but she couldn't
Speaker 4:  find anything for less than $40,000. But then a Toyota
Speaker 4:  dealership offered her that killer deal on a 2022
Speaker 4:  marai with only 23,000 miles on it. Toyota's also been
Speaker 4:  offering big discounts on Nu Maiz earlier this year. You
Speaker 4:  could get $40,000 off some models. That's a
Speaker 4:  60% discount. That's
Speaker 15:  It. I'm paying a fortune in hydrogen but it'll take something
Speaker 15:  like 13 years. I did my math. Okay. It'll
Speaker 15:  take 13 years before this vehicle will
Speaker 15:  cost me more than if I were to buy a 40,000
Speaker 15:  something electric vehicle. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Rebecca loves her. Mariah, so she's content for now.
Speaker 15:  I'm gonna stick with my marai as long as I'm in
Speaker 15:  California.
Speaker 4:  Mandeep and Rupesh, not so much
Speaker 14:  I don't think. To be very honest with you. After the gas cutt is finished,
Speaker 14:  it's not worth maintaining This car.
Speaker 4:  Manad left us with some words of caution about our trip, which
Speaker 4:  believe me, we took to heart when we said goodbye to the bay
Speaker 4:  and headed south for Los Angeles. No ac go easy on the
Speaker 4:  pedal. Yeah. Always know where the next station is. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Call the
Speaker 14:  Stations close to the speed limit.
Speaker 4:  Stick to the speed limit
Speaker 14:  If possible, go below the speed limit. Try to be in the right most
Speaker 14:  lane.
Speaker 4:  This is not the the road trip that we were looking forward to
Speaker 4:  having. You know,
Speaker 14:  Road trip. I'm really sorry for a spoiling year. Road
Speaker 14:  trip.
Speaker 4:  We can start with the windows down. Windows down also, how fast do you
Speaker 4:  think I should drive? We should play with the settings on the car to see.
Speaker 4:  It tells you how efficiently you're
Speaker 4:  driving on the road to
Speaker 4:  la I had a lot of downtime to think about everything I'd seen
Speaker 4:  and most of my questions boiled down to how did we get
Speaker 4:  here, which You can think about in two ways. There's the big broad
Speaker 4:  version. How did hydrogen cars start out so promising
Speaker 4:  but stumble so badly. And then there's the more
Speaker 4:  specific, why is it so hard to get fuel for your
Speaker 4:  car? So as we cruise down I
Speaker 4:  five, let's start with the big, how did we get here for that? I
Speaker 4:  called up Keith Wike. He's an industry veteran from the National Renewable
Speaker 4:  Energy Lab.
Speaker 16:  You did come to the right person. I've been involved in hydrogen technologies
Speaker 16:  for over 20 years.
Speaker 4:  Keith took me all the way back to 2004. Again, back then
Speaker 4:  fewer people were talking about climate change the way we all are today.
Speaker 4:  But California had a smog problem.
Speaker 16:  They had the the worst air quality, especially in the Los Angeles
Speaker 16:  basin. And so they had a, a strong driver to clean up local air
Speaker 16:  quality
Speaker 4:  Battery electric cars existed but they were not the obvious
Speaker 4:  air apparent to gasoline. In fact, as a storage medium
Speaker 4:  to power a car, batteries kind of sucked.
Speaker 16:  Batteries were not good at the time. It was lead acid batteries and
Speaker 16:  nickel metal hydride was the up and coming thing, which of course is what
Speaker 16:  Toyota launched their Prius hybrid with, with nickel metal hydride batteries.
Speaker 16:  That was a challenge for batteries at the time. 80, 90 mile
Speaker 16:  range. A very heavy, a lot of compromises on the vehicle itself
Speaker 16:  to get reasonable performance. So hydrogen kind of
Speaker 16:  was being born into that era.
Speaker 4:  Meanwhile, hydrogen was showing a lot of promise. You could get
Speaker 4:  all the emissions benefits of a battery electric car without the
Speaker 4:  battery. Plus fueling was a faster and more familiar
Speaker 4:  process for drivers. It looked like a great successor to
Speaker 4:  gasoline and California got on board.
Speaker 5:  I'm going to encourage the building of a hydrogen highway to take us to the
Speaker 5:  environmental future.
Speaker 4:  The original plan called for at least 150 stations by
Speaker 4:  2010, but that never happened. Around 10 demo
Speaker 4:  stations came and went, which were co-funded by a federal
Speaker 4:  program. Everyone learned a lot, but it was an r and d
Speaker 4:  exercise by the end of the decade. Lots of people were
Speaker 4:  asking, where is this hydrogen highway?
Speaker 4:  But in 2013 California reset and
Speaker 4:  recommitted, it put up $20 million a year for stations
Speaker 4:  and between 2015 and 2020, at least 37 new
Speaker 4:  stations came online.
Speaker 16:  I do think that I and a lot of other people thought it was just
Speaker 16:  gonna be a bunch of dominoes falling, that the hydrogen stations were gonna
Speaker 16:  go 50, a hundred, 200 stations in California. The
Speaker 16:  northeast market would launch and take off there and then people like
Speaker 16:  me in Colorado would maybe get a backbone across
Speaker 16:  interstates and we would be able to drive a hydrogen car
Speaker 16:  as part of our daily commute.
Speaker 4:  The car companies played their part too. In 2008, Honda
Speaker 4:  began leasing a fuel cell sedan called the Clarity. Toyota
Speaker 4:  made a big splash with the Mariah in 2015. This
Speaker 17:  Isn't just another car, this is an
Speaker 17:  opportunity to really make a difference.
Speaker 17:  The name we've given to our new car is midlife, which
Speaker 17:  in Japanese means future.
Speaker 4:  The other fuel cell car You can buy today. The Hyundai NEXO hit the
Speaker 4:  US in 2018.
Speaker 16:  So I've seen and witnessed various launches and and for me each
Speaker 16:  one of them felt like, okay this is it now we just need
Speaker 16:  more of that car, we need more fueling stations. And then we see the
Speaker 16:  other companies launch. Okay, that's further validation that this is going
Speaker 16:  in the right
Speaker 16:  direction.
Speaker 4:  The fuel cell market has come a long way in 20
Speaker 4:  years, but along the way something else
Speaker 4:  happened too. Batteries got good, good enough to power
Speaker 4:  cars and in the race to replace gasoline,
Speaker 4:  batteries had some big advantages over hydrogen. I called up the
Speaker 4:  verges transportation editor Andy Hawkins to explain. And he started
Speaker 4:  with the fact that we already have a power grid
Speaker 18:  With EV charging, it's pretty simple. You install the charging
Speaker 18:  station, you plug it into the grid and barring any software
Speaker 18:  problems or anything else like that, it's good to go. It should work.
Speaker 4:  That was a huge advantage in the early days of battery EVs. Drivers
Speaker 4:  could just plug in at home.
Speaker 18:  It's a different story with hydrogen. There needs to be a supply chain.
Speaker 18:  You need to truck the hydrogen in for where it's being produced to the filling
Speaker 18:  stations fill up those tanks at the filling stations and then once
Speaker 18:  the hydrogen has been depleted, the whole process starts all over
Speaker 18:  again.
Speaker 4:  Now granted it's taken years for a public EV charging network
Speaker 4:  to mature. In fact, it's been a mess of competing standards
Speaker 4:  and flaky charging ports, but it's getting
Speaker 4:  better. And the reason reveals another huge
Speaker 4:  difference between hydrogen and batteries.
Speaker 18:  The hydrogen car industry as it were, didn't have a
Speaker 18:  Tesla. Ladies and
Speaker 19:  Gentlemen, Mr. Elon
Speaker 19:  Musk
Speaker 4:  Tesla hit the scene in 2008 with the a hundred thousand dollars
Speaker 4:  Roadster and it has utterly defined the battery
Speaker 4:  electric business ever since. Over the past 15 years its cars
Speaker 4:  have steadily gotten cheaper and more ubiquitous and along the
Speaker 4:  way it also built a huge charging network, which
Speaker 4:  is so good that pretty much every other automaker in the US is
Speaker 4:  now signing on to Tesla's standard.
Speaker 18:  We're getting the entire industry realizing that Tesla has the best charging
Speaker 18:  network, they have the best chargers, the most reliable. We're all gonna
Speaker 18:  just end up using Tesla's as we probably could have realized a lot
Speaker 18:  sooner.
Speaker 4:  In other words, say what you will about Elon Musk and on
Speaker 4:  this podcast we surely do, but Tesla gets a lot of
Speaker 4:  credit for dragging the battery electric market into existence,
Speaker 4:  which is something that hydrogen just never had.
Speaker 18:  There was no Tesla startup company that was out
Speaker 18:  there innovating, taking its lumps, losing
Speaker 18:  millions and millions of dollars in the process, but also
Speaker 18:  generating lots of buzz, generating lots of hype and
Speaker 18:  speculation amongst investors and on Wall Street in the
Speaker 18:  government as well. And sort of proving eventually, ultimately that there
Speaker 18:  was gonna be this huge untapped market for battery electric
Speaker 18:  vehicles.
Speaker 4:  In the end, the numbers tell the story. Battery electric
Speaker 4:  cars and charging stations exploded across the country.
Speaker 4:  Today there are roughly 43,000 public charging ports in
Speaker 4:  California alone. Whereas hydrogen seems to be
Speaker 4:  backsliding.
Speaker 18:  There still is this plan that exists like state grants to
Speaker 18:  companies to build out stations. The only problem is the companies that
Speaker 18:  have agreed to do so are now backtracking on those plans.
Speaker 18:  Like for example, shell said that it was going to create a huge network
Speaker 18:  of hydrogen stations in the state, but then they saw sort of like the writing
Speaker 18:  on the wall and decided to start backing outta that
Speaker 18:  plan. They declined a $40 million state grant to build like an extra
Speaker 18:  50 stations and then they went ahead and just closed practically all
Speaker 18:  of their stations in California.
Speaker 4:  Gotcha. So basically there's money out there and there just aren't takers
Speaker 4:  for it right now
Speaker 18:  There's a pretty strong belief right now in sort
Speaker 18:  of in, in California and elsewhere that battery electric vehicles, they
Speaker 18:  won hydrogen could have, you know, surpassed EVs at some
Speaker 18:  point. But over the last like 15 or 20 years, it's very clear
Speaker 18:  that battery electric vehicles are, are the preferred alternate
Speaker 18:  technology for private vehicles. And hydrogen is kind of
Speaker 18:  becoming a bit of a
Speaker 18:  footnote.
Speaker 4:  So there's the big picture, how do we get here? But
Speaker 4:  that doesn't fully explain what we saw. Glitchy
Speaker 4:  stations, the price of fuel, the shortages. To understand those
Speaker 4:  problems, I needed to talk to first element, the company that runs
Speaker 4:  almost three quarters of the stations in California. So I called up one of
Speaker 4:  the co-founders, Shane Stevens, who was pretty candid with
Speaker 4:  me.
Speaker 21:  We've been doing some, I would say field testing on customers to
Speaker 21:  get this equipment kind of commercial ready to where it needs to be. Right.
Speaker 21:  And it's, you know, we didn't mean to do that right? But we've sort of we're
Speaker 21:  forced into that situation because as we started operating these stations,
Speaker 21:  we just uncorked all sorts of issues that needed to be addressed.
Speaker 4:  Here's what happened back in 2013, the year California
Speaker 4:  announced new funding for hydrogen stations. Shane was working at
Speaker 4:  the National Fuel Cell Research Center at uc, Irvine. He watched the
Speaker 4:  wave of interest and hydrogen build again and he saw an opportunity on the
Speaker 4:  fueling side of things. So that same year he and two
Speaker 4:  partners founded First element.
Speaker 21:  From there we actually got some initial financing from Toyota
Speaker 21:  and Honda and we were able to leverage that private financing and go get
Speaker 21:  California state grants. We won 19 stations and we were able to
Speaker 21:  develop the initial network of hydrogen stations.
Speaker 4:  First element made a big push right out of the gates and it got around
Speaker 4:  15 stations up and running. By the end of 2016, that
Speaker 4:  speed was a calculated risk. They built more smaller,
Speaker 4:  cheaper stations to prove out the network and encourage automakers
Speaker 4:  to start selling cars. And the plan worked a
Speaker 4:  little too well.
Speaker 21:  The cars came more quickly, the stations were overwhelmed more quickly and
Speaker 21:  the customers drove the cars more than we anticipated Early on.
Speaker 21:  What became obvious to us is that this technology for hydrogen stations
Speaker 21:  was actually not really ready for prime time commercially. The
Speaker 21:  equipment that we're using in the field today, it hasn't gone
Speaker 21:  through sort of hours of testing to make sure the robustness is there to
Speaker 21:  make sure that you know, little design kinks or design flaws have been worked
Speaker 21:  out. And then when it's used, you know, regularly every day
Speaker 21:  on hundreds of customers, all of a sudden you start to see that it, it maybe
Speaker 21:  doesn't hold up as well because it's never been tested under those conditions.
Speaker 4:  Which lines up with our experience at the pumps, lots of little quirks and
Speaker 4:  rough edges.
Speaker 21:  We had a lot of hiccups on uptime, we had performance
Speaker 21:  issues, we had logistics issues on supplying the fuel and we actually had
Speaker 21:  a lot of fuel run outs to the station.
Speaker 4:  First element has spent years trying to fix that first big
Speaker 4:  mistake. It's newer stations are bigger, more expensive and more
Speaker 4:  robust. They can store more fuel and dispense more at a
Speaker 4:  time. They actually store hydrogen as a liquid now rather than a
Speaker 4:  gas, which has been a lot easier.
Speaker 21:  And you know, the reliability is getting much better than what it was as
Speaker 21:  well. I don't think we're all the way where, where we we could
Speaker 21:  be, but we're now at a point where we see a a commercially viable
Speaker 21:  product
Speaker 4:  That also attracts with what we saw. We just had fewer hiccups using the
Speaker 4:  newer stations and drivers told us they were more reliable.
Speaker 4:  But those older flimsier stations are still
Speaker 4:  there. They account for nearly half the overall network and
Speaker 4:  they're not going anywhere.
Speaker 21:  We've invested quite a bit of money into permanent infrastructure
Speaker 21:  that's in the ground to upgrade the station is not really an
Speaker 21:  option. And the other thing is we don't wanna leave customers hanging
Speaker 21:  that may be depending on that station, even if it's an older generation.
Speaker 4:  So drivers are stuck with temperamental hardware and first element
Speaker 4:  is stuck maintaining it.
Speaker 21:  So right now we're charging, you know, considerably more for hydrogen than
Speaker 21:  what we'd like to be and what we think we should be.
Speaker 4:  And that's not the only cause of expensive fuel first element. And
Speaker 4:  others have had a hard time competing for hydrogen against much bigger
Speaker 4:  industries like oil refining and agriculture. There just isn't enough
Speaker 4:  to go around. There have also been supply chain problems and
Speaker 4:  other market issues. The war in Ukraine is even playing a
Speaker 4:  role. So prices have been spiking and not
Speaker 4:  enough. Hydrogen is making it to drivers.
Speaker 21:  But unfortunately that's the, the reality of the landscape today.
Speaker 4:  First element is now staring down the barrel of a vicious
Speaker 4:  cycle. The more the fuel network struggles, the less viable the
Speaker 4:  cars look. It's the exact opposite of what they were trying to do
Speaker 4:  by opening all those stations in the first place. Our transportation
Speaker 4:  editor, Andy said it best.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, I mean it's kind of like enmeshed in like the worst chicken and egg
Speaker 18:  scenario that you could possibly imagine. You know, like people aren't going
Speaker 18:  to buy hydrogen cars 'cause there's just, there's no way to fuel them,
Speaker 18:  right? And then you're not gonna have anyone building any fueling
Speaker 18:  stations because so few people own the hydrogen cars. So
Speaker 6:  warning until eight o'clock tonight.
Speaker 4:  A few more miles of nothing and then an exit sign.
Speaker 6:  There it is.
Speaker 4:  You see it? Oh, Harris Ranch. All
Speaker 4:  right. Harris Ranch is perfectly spaced
Speaker 4:  between San Francisco and la so it's a way point for all
Speaker 4:  kinds of drivers. There's a Shell gas station and what
Speaker 4:  is currently the largest bank of Tesla superchargers in the
Speaker 4:  world. Over the years though the owners of Harris Ranch
Speaker 4:  have made it a destination unto itself. They've built a massive
Speaker 4:  Spanish hacienda style hotel, multiple
Speaker 4:  restaurants, and the only gift shop I've ever seen with a butcher
Speaker 4:  counter. All right, there's the shell station. We drive past
Speaker 4:  all of this past palm trees, past a barbecue pit
Speaker 4:  slash convenience store, past an under construction RV
Speaker 4:  park. And there off on a lonely plot of
Speaker 4:  concrete is one first element hydrogen pump. This
Speaker 4:  is a very weird place. There's
Speaker 6:  A couple flies in the car.
Speaker 4:  Well, should we gas up? Let's do
Speaker 4:  it. We pull up to the pump, get
Speaker 4:  out and my god, the heat.
Speaker 4:  Ugh, it just hits you. I better not
Speaker 4:  take seven
Speaker 4:  tries to get
Speaker 4:  Hydrow. The buttons are hot.
Speaker 4:  Unfortunately the pump doesn't care how hot we are.
Speaker 4:  All right, it's done. That doesn't feel like a a full
Speaker 4:  tank's worth, but we'll see when we turn the car back
Speaker 4:  on,
Speaker 26:  Please
Speaker 4:  Seek attendant. We got fuel. I don't think
Speaker 4:  there's an attendant here. I hope I didn't just break it for everybody
Speaker 4:  else
Speaker 26:  I can. Did you get a full tank?
Speaker 4:  Well, let's
Speaker 4:  see,
Speaker 4:  236 miles. No, we didn't get a
Speaker 4:  full tank. We start the process all over again. This time the
Speaker 4:  pin pad freezes, then gives us an input error, but then
Speaker 4:  it resets and fuel starts flowing. Dispenser is okay,
Speaker 4:  we're getting, we we're getting more hydrogen. We finally get our
Speaker 4:  full tank, but then the nozzle gets stuck to the car.
Speaker 4:  Again. 101 degrees, no shade.
Speaker 4:  Dwindling patients. I don't know what I'm doing
Speaker 4:  wrong.
Speaker 4:  Look, I know I'm harping a lot on these finicky pumps and I know
Speaker 4:  normal gas stations don't work perfectly either, but it's
Speaker 4:  shocking how much trouble we've had in just a couple days of
Speaker 4:  driving and it's not hard to imagine frustrations like
Speaker 4:  these dragging down the whole idea of
Speaker 4:  hydrogen. Anyway, the nozzle finally comes
Speaker 4:  free. We retreat to a picnic table under a tree and
Speaker 4:  wait for other fuel cell drivers to show
Speaker 4:  up.
Speaker 4:  We wait for an hour, two hours,
Speaker 4:  as dusk
Speaker 4:  LA and he is gone up to San Francisco
Speaker 4:  la.
Speaker 4:  tool to fight climate change.
Speaker 4:  steam methane reforming, which produces carbon dioxide
Speaker 4:  emissions. It also depends on a supply chain that tends to leak
Speaker 4:  methane. Those are two gases we're desperately trying to keep out
Speaker 4:  of the atmosphere right now.
Speaker 30:  Methane is a greenhouse gas pollutant that is
Speaker 30:  even more potent in the short term than carbon
Speaker 30:  dioxide. And so a majority of hydrogen today is,
Speaker 30:  is what you call gray hydrogen
Speaker 4:  Meaning basically dirty. Now there is such a thing
Speaker 4:  as green hydrogen fuel that's clean and climate
Speaker 4:  friendly.
Speaker 30:  So the way that green hydrogen is made is typically
Speaker 30:  using renewable energy to power electrolysis,
Speaker 30:  which is splitting water into hydrogen and
Speaker 30:  oxygen. Right now, electrolyzers are pretty
Speaker 30:  expensive and green hydrogen is, is something like four times the cost of
Speaker 30:  gray hydrogen right now. So costs have to come way
Speaker 30:  down.
Speaker 4:  To be fair, lots of power that's used to charge batteries isn't
Speaker 4:  green either. About 60% of the electricity in the
Speaker 4:  US comes from gas and coal. And to pull off a clean
Speaker 4:  battery electric future, we're gonna need a lot more green
Speaker 4:  energy and big upgrades to the grid. None of that is going to be
Speaker 4:  easy or cheap. But even in an ideal
Speaker 4:  future that's flush with green electricity, hydrogen is
Speaker 4:  still less efficient.
Speaker 30:  A passenger vehicle can much more easily plug into the
Speaker 30:  grid and run on a battery that you juice up with
Speaker 30:  renewable energy. So with hydrogen, you're, you're adding another step to
Speaker 30:  that, right? You're basically using renewable
Speaker 30:  electricity to create the hydrogen to then run the
Speaker 30:  vehicle. Versus you could also
Speaker 30:  just run the vehicle on renewable electricity in the first
Speaker 30:  place.
Speaker 4:  So if the question is where do we spend the hydrogen we're making, the
Speaker 4:  answer might be things that are harder to plug into the power grid.
Speaker 30:  There's more hype around it for industrial
Speaker 30:  uses, for aviation, for shipping,
Speaker 30:  because it's much harder to get a
Speaker 30:  plane off the ground or to have a ship that is
Speaker 30:  battery powered. Passenger vehicles are just so low down on the
Speaker 30:  list.
Speaker 10:  What did it say? Turn right.
Speaker 4:  Turn
Speaker 4:  right
Speaker 4:  after another long stretch of highway five we pulled into
Speaker 4:  la
Speaker 6:  All right, here's the palm trees
Speaker 12:  1000 feet turn right onto San Fernando Mission Boulevard.
Speaker 4:  We were excited to check out the scene. There are more fuel cell cars and
Speaker 4:  stations here than anywhere else in the state. But we'd also
Speaker 4:  read about a months long hydrogen shortage. And our fuel map
Speaker 4:  showed a lot of offline stations. I see it. It's glowing
Speaker 4:  Those blue audiences. Oh,
Speaker 6:  It's nice looking.
Speaker 4:  I are those
Speaker 6:  A little futuristic looking?
Speaker 4:  They're a little snazzier. We found lots of fuel cell
Speaker 4:  drivers really quickly and well,
Speaker 4:  here's your vibe. Check.
Speaker 7:  Hey, it's been awful. To be completely honest. I'm trying
Speaker 9:  To trade it in for a regular car, like a gasoline car.
Speaker 31:  We bought this with the idea of saving the earth or whatever and of
Speaker 31:  course saving for the gas, but never happened. Have
Speaker 4:  You ever run out? Oh, of course. Yeah. Oh yeah. You get towed or I get
Speaker 4:  towed. We heard lots of familiar things. Love for the
Speaker 4:  cars, frustration around fueling flaky stations,
Speaker 4:  brutal prices, range anxiety, regrets. We
Speaker 4:  also saw one Hyundai nexo, the owner tick. Ron
Speaker 4:  actually solved a mystery for us. He told us why fuel nozzles
Speaker 4:  kept sticking to our car.
Speaker 7:  So I've been standing here for five minutes trying to yank it off. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And sometimes it just, okay, like right now is a
Speaker 7:  good example. Okay. This has happened to me. So it gets like really cold.
Speaker 7:  Like you could tell there's like ice. Oh,
Speaker 4:  Okay. So that's, it is just like, yeah, freezing. It
Speaker 4:  turns out that the more the pumps get used, the colder the hardware gets
Speaker 4:  from all the cooled hydrogen moving through so the nozzle can freeze
Speaker 4:  to the car. Oh wow. It's, yeah, my finger.
Speaker 7:  So that was actually stuck to it. Actually not bad. It took about 10 seconds,
Speaker 7:  but other times I've literally sat waited five minutes. Yeah. For it
Speaker 7:  to loosen up. But oh,
Speaker 4:  We thought we, we were pulling on that handle wrong or something. Yeah. We
Speaker 4:  thought there was some trick that we didn't know and it's, it's the freezing.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 7:  Just the freezing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I later realized that Shane from first Element had warned me about
Speaker 4:  this. I even found a video from Toyota about it.
Speaker 32:  At times, the nozzle may become temporarily frozen and unable to
Speaker 32:  disconnect from the vehicle for several minutes. Do not
Speaker 32:  try to remove it forcibly or you could cause damage to the nozzle
Speaker 32:  vehicle or dispenser.
Speaker 4:  Shane had told me the problem was largely resolved, which doesn't
Speaker 4:  seem to be the case.
Speaker 7:  I met people here. They're like, oh, I carry a bottle of water with me and
Speaker 7:  I just kind of pour a little bit just to loosen it up a bit.
Speaker 32:  Do not pour water or spray chemicals on the nozzle.
Speaker 4:  All in all tigran is at the end of his rope. Does it feel like you're just
Speaker 4:  in this kind of pilot program? Yes. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  But it wasn't sold like that when I got it. Okay. It was like, oh, you just
Speaker 7:  go to, it's like filling up a gas, your gas at a regular station. Right.
Speaker 7:  You just go put it in and you're done. Yeah. And when it's working it, it's
Speaker 7:  fine. That that's generally true. But yeah, most days it doesn't just
Speaker 7:  work.
Speaker 4:  So what do you think you're gonna do with the car long term?
Speaker 7:  The resale value's? Very bad.
Speaker 4:  Oh God. You're just really stuck. Yep.
Speaker 7:  I looked to trade it in for a Tesla and Tesla's like, we'll give you 10,000.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I owe 30 on it.
Speaker 4:  That feeling of a bait and switch, we've heard that a lot. One
Speaker 4:  Mirai driver, Denise says the dealer misled him about the value of
Speaker 4:  the car
Speaker 9:  At the time of closing. They told me the actual value, this
Speaker 9:  car was 20, about 23,000. Okay. After I closed, they
Speaker 9:  told me it's actual value is $7,000.
Speaker 4:  What happened?
Speaker 9:  So I think what they do, they try to factor in the fact that
Speaker 9:  they give you a fuel card for $15,000. Oh,
Speaker 4:  They C, they consider that part of
Speaker 9:  The value of the car. They consider that part of the deal. Gotcha.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. So now the resell value of the car is not what you thought it
Speaker 4:  was.
Speaker 9:  No, it's not. It's not what I thought it was.
Speaker 4:  I asked Toyota about this and they declined to comment on it, but they did
Speaker 4:  confirm that the fuel cards are not transferable altogether.
Speaker 4:  These stories started to paint a picture about how these cars were
Speaker 4:  sold to lots of people over and over. Drivers told us that they
Speaker 4:  were shopping for a battery electric car. But
Speaker 4:  someone, a friend, a salesman, the internet talked them
Speaker 4:  into a Mariah. It was a new zero emission luxury
Speaker 4:  car. Yeah. It's
Speaker 31:  Like driving a Lexus or BMW.
Speaker 4:  And it was priced like a Toyota Camry. It was a win-win.
Speaker 4:  Except it wasn't. Here's one more. Mariah driver. Jonathan,
Speaker 4:  what do you think you're gonna do with it long term?
Speaker 33:  Get rid of it. Yeah, yeah, for sure. Yeah. Yeah, I will. But I do like
Speaker 33:  the newer models, don't get me wrong. They're very beautiful, but it doesn't
Speaker 33:  matter what model of the car comes out, it's just if,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, if you can't drive it.
Speaker 33:  If you can't drive it.
Speaker 4:  Talking to these drivers made me think back to a very clarifying
Speaker 4:  moment at Harris Ranch. During our stakeout, we got
Speaker 4:  bored and wandered over to the Tesla area and after
Speaker 4:  hours spent listening to fuel cell drivers, talk about hanging in
Speaker 4:  there, meeting Tesla owners was a shock. Where you
Speaker 4:  coming from? Where are you going to? We
Speaker 28:  Live in Metca and we're headed to Anaheim to go to Disneyland.
Speaker 34:  Super reliable and super easy to get charging
Speaker 34:  everywhere. Yeah. So I'm excited. Yeah.
Speaker 35:  Road trips are amazing. When you have a Tesla and you have the whole
Speaker 35:  thing,
Speaker 4:  They were all just so unburdened. That's the best end
Speaker 4:  state for any new technology. You forget about it and just use
Speaker 4:  it. And right now hydrogen just isn't
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 4:  After everything we saw on this trip. There's one player I
Speaker 4:  can't quite figure out. Toyota. Why is
Speaker 4:  Toyota still so committed to the Marai? In the first half
Speaker 4:  of this year, about 322 fuel cell cars
Speaker 4:  were sold in California total for reference.
Speaker 4:  During that same period, maybe 200,000
Speaker 4:  battery EVs were sold in California alone.
Speaker 4:  And yet Toyota is still marketing Mariahs and pushing them
Speaker 4:  at huge discounts. During the Paris Olympics this summer,
Speaker 4:  Toyota provided 500 Marais to shuttle around
Speaker 4:  athletes and bolster the green credentials of the Olympics,
Speaker 4:  which actually upset a lot of environmentalists. So what's
Speaker 4:  Toyota's angle here? I spoke with Craig Scott, the general manager
Speaker 4:  of fuel cell solutions. Craig said that hydrogen has
Speaker 4:  been a big hedge.
Speaker 36:  It's back to the foundational things of what are we trying to accomplish.
Speaker 36:  We're trying to remove carbon to the tailpipe. And the only way to do that
Speaker 36:  really, in a complete way, in a zero emission way, is, you know,
Speaker 36:  there there are two competing technologies. Batteries and, and, and fuel
Speaker 36:  cells. And so, you know, we wanted to make sure we had a good foothold in
Speaker 36:  both.
Speaker 4:  Toyota continues to hedge more than most major
Speaker 4:  automakers. It made hybrids a huge success with the
Speaker 4:  Prius, but it's dragged its feet on full battery
Speaker 4:  EVs. Today. The company sells just one battery powered Toyota
Speaker 4:  and one model Lexus compared to more than a dozen
Speaker 4:  hybrids. And the Marai critics have spent years dinging
Speaker 4:  Toyota for this. And the company does have a lot more battery models in the
Speaker 4:  works, but it hasn't abandoned the Marai. I put
Speaker 4:  this question to our transportation editor, Andy, why is Toyota sticking
Speaker 4:  with the marai? He's mystified too. But he argued that
Speaker 4:  it's not just about the Marai.
Speaker 18:  These companies have this technology, they want to use it in some way.
Speaker 18:  They spent a lot of money, they've invested in it and they want to get something
Speaker 18:  out of it. So they're all sort of casting about and looking for ways in
Speaker 18:  which this, this fuel source can be useful for future
Speaker 18:  applications.
Speaker 4:  Toyota is working on powering buses, trucks, and trains
Speaker 4:  with its fuel cells. It's developing stationary
Speaker 4:  generators and Honda Hyundai and other companies are doing
Speaker 4:  similar work. First element is investing in truck
Speaker 4:  refueling. This is what our environment reporter Justine was talking
Speaker 4:  about. There are other places that fuel cells might make
Speaker 4:  more sense. It's the next step in that hedge. If any of
Speaker 4:  those industries go all in on hydrogen, Toyota and others
Speaker 4:  will be there. And the marai its success or
Speaker 4:  failure might not matter so
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 4:  This is the big, this is the big one. We gotta see what the final price
Speaker 4:  tag is. It's the end of our road trip and we're at a gas
Speaker 4:  station back in the Bay Area. Our rental was
Speaker 4:  not point to point, so after we were done in LA we had to turn around
Speaker 4:  and drive back across California. We ended up taking the
Speaker 4:  more scenic, high risk, high reward route along the 1 0 1.
Speaker 4:  The route Billy from Harris Ranch told us about it. Gave us one last hit
Speaker 4:  of range anxiety. If the the first station is
Speaker 4:  out of order for any reason, then it's another 10 miles to the next
Speaker 4:  station, which we have budgeted in.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And if that's outta order, it's another 10 miles. So it
Speaker 4:  like, I could see this getting a little hairy, but so
Speaker 4:  far we're okay. We pulled into San Jose
Speaker 4:  with 40 miles left in the tank, all in. We put about
Speaker 4:  875 miles on the car and a little more than three
Speaker 4:  days. We also had to return the Mariah with a full tank. So we
Speaker 4:  were treated to one last shock. 120
Speaker 4:  bucks, 130. What do we think? It's gotta
Speaker 4:  be more than the most. Okay.
Speaker 4:  4.605 kilograms,
Speaker 4:  $165 and 78 cents. That's a big finish
Speaker 4:  for the road trip. If we'd been driving, say a Toyota Camry,
Speaker 4:  we'd have spent about 30 bucks on gas road trip
Speaker 4:  complete. It's a good doable souvenir. The
Speaker 4:  most expensive tank I've ever
Speaker 4:  purchased
Speaker 4:  In the back of my head. Throughout this story, I've thought a lot about
Speaker 4:  laser discs of all things the failed competitor to
Speaker 4:  DVDs. I've wondered, is that what this is? Is this
Speaker 4:  just an alternate history story of why the world went this
Speaker 4:  way instead of that way kind of thing? After taking this
Speaker 4:  trip? I don't think that's quite right. Batteries
Speaker 4:  won, but I think that there's still some part of the future that's up for
Speaker 4:  grabs. Hydrogen is still more portable than batteries
Speaker 4:  and it's a much faster way to move energy around. And
Speaker 4:  there are still lots of hydrogen believers out
Speaker 4:  everything, it was weirdly fun to be part of the fuel cell
Speaker 4:  club. Most of the drivers I talked to were so open and
Speaker 4:  honest and helpful. It was great to swap tips and stories with
Speaker 4:  everybody. I got the sense there was a community here,
Speaker 4:  even if it was based on shared grievance, that's probably not the
Speaker 4:  way that Toyota or First Element wants drivers bonding. But I
Speaker 4:  got a kick out of it. Case in point. After we filled
Speaker 4:  up at the final gas station, I happened to see another Mirage
Speaker 4:  driver wandering from pump to pump, looking at all the little
Speaker 4:  screens. I asked him what was up and he said he couldn't get his
Speaker 4:  pump to work. The screen was frozen. I told him the pump we
Speaker 4:  used was fine and he pulled over to that one. And
Speaker 4:  just like that, I was a fuel cell driver
Speaker 4:  too.
Speaker 2:  Verges YouTube channel. We also have a fun story