# Transcript
ID: 0c0008ca-5c80-4b40-ac9b-3ebc3d93eb42
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4657877533801445570/-3486492732501118611/s93290-US-3955s-1720516519.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of corporate infighting:
The Verge's David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Alex Cranz roleplay as CEOs of Vergecast Inc., tasked with creating a tech company by acquiring product lines from various industry giants. They select established products ranging from smartphones and PCs to messaging and audio solutions, sourced from companies such as Apple, Google, Amazon, Samsung, Meta, and others.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (26 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Corporate in Fighting.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting on my back patio getting the
Speaker 2:  grill ready because it is July 4th weekend and that's just what you do.
Speaker 2:  This is America. It's July 4th. It's also my birthday on
Speaker 2:  July 4th. And so we sit outside and we grill even though it's
Speaker 2:  very hot and there's mosquitoes everywhere. And would I rather be inside
Speaker 2:  in the air conditioning looking at my television? Yes, but it's July 4th,
Speaker 2:  so we're grilling stuff. Anyway, we have an awesome episode coming up for
Speaker 2:  you today. We are gonna basically start a tech company together. Neil
Speaker 2:  Appel, Alex Kranz and I are going to, as a group of
Speaker 2:  CEOs, which couldn't possibly go poorly, figure out how we
Speaker 2:  would build a tech company out of the tech industry as it exists. Now, it
Speaker 2:  sounds a little complicated, but I'll explain the rules when we get into
Speaker 2:  it. It'll all make sense. But basically I wanted to see if you were to start
Speaker 2:  from scratch and say, okay, what are the best products in tech? What can
Speaker 2:  I take? What can I put together? What could we build that would be cool and
Speaker 2:  different and that we could make? Awesome. How would we do that? We had a
Speaker 2:  lot of fun putting this together and figured this would be a fun time to
Speaker 2:  do it. It's July. The news is a little bit slow. We're about to get
Speaker 2:  into Crazy Gadget season again. But it felt like a fun way to take
Speaker 2:  a different kinda look at the tech industry. I should also say some
Speaker 2:  credit for this whole concept goes to a podcast I really like called The
Speaker 2:  Big Picture, really good show about movies. And they did one recently where
Speaker 2:  the two of them started their own studios together and they
Speaker 2:  kind of did a draft and picked actors and writers and it was a very fun episode.
Speaker 2:  And so I just kind of stole that concept and we're going to take it
Speaker 2:  and turn it and do something similar on the show today. So we're gonna start
Speaker 2:  a tech company. I'm very curious what you think as you listen to it. If you
Speaker 2:  think we made bad decisions, if you think we made good decisions. If you
Speaker 2:  think we're monsters, I wanna hear everything. Call the hotline. Eight six six
Speaker 2:  VERGE one one. Email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Tell us how you'd
Speaker 2:  start a tech company and maybe between us we're gonna take over the tech
Speaker 2:  industry. It's gonna be awesome. Anyway, all of that is coming up in just
Speaker 2:  a second. But first I just noticed that I turned the grill on without
Speaker 2:  actually turning the propane on. So this is how good I am at grilling. I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna go fix that problem. This is The Verge Cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right,
Speaker 2:  of other companies is essentially how this is gonna work. So I have, I think
Speaker 2:  it's either 10 or 11 categories here that we as a, as a tech company
Speaker 2:  are going to enter by taking that product from another company.
Speaker 2:  There are several rules. Again, this is very convoluted. Yeah. But it's
Speaker 2:  gonna work. It's gonna be fine once we get into it. Everything we take from
Speaker 2:  a tech company, we get, as it exists right now, whatever it's selling,
Speaker 2:  whoever it is that makes it all the factory deals, all the marketing stuff,
Speaker 2:  everything we can, we can change it as we like, but we get, we don't get
Speaker 2:  the idea of it. We get the thing as it is right now. We only care
Speaker 2:  about things up to 2030 after that. Who knows We're all gonna live on Mars.
Speaker 2:  So we're, we're playing like a six year long game here. And frankly, if we
Speaker 2:  as the triumvirate of CEOs last until 2030, we will have been wildly
Speaker 2:  successful.
Speaker 5:  I'm banking out really fast. Yeah. As soon as we IPO I'm gone. I'm
Speaker 2:  Sorry. Alex is resting investing from like day one here. It's, it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be great. We can spend as much money as we want, but making money
Speaker 2:  is not the point. We're actually not gonna talk about money at all on this
Speaker 2:  show. Okay? We don't wanna go out of business. But our main goal
Speaker 2:  is just to build the greatest tech company in the history of the universe.
Speaker 2:  Like that. That is what we're after here. Because this is like, if we start
Speaker 2:  talking about the money side of things, it just gets weird and complicated
Speaker 2:  in ways that we don't have time for. That's what
Speaker 6:  We're gonna tell our investors. We're just gonna be like, look guys, if we
Speaker 6:  talk about money, this is gonna get weird and complicated. Yeah. So just,
Speaker 6:  you just relax, we're
Speaker 5:  Just out to make an a GI don't worry about it. I guess.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, like for 20 years Jeff Bezos was like, I can make money whenever I
Speaker 2:  feel like it for now I'm just gonna like make cool stuff. Like that's the
Speaker 2:  vibe at our tech company. And I would say the two most important
Speaker 2:  things as we pick here are we can only take one product
Speaker 2:  from each company. So once, once we have used something from
Speaker 2:  Apple, we cannot use anything else from Apple or Samsung or Google or whoever
Speaker 2:  else. One product per company, which I think is gonna be very complicated.
Speaker 2:  That product also cannot be the whole company. So if, if there is a
Speaker 2:  company that makes a single product with its name, like I originally had
Speaker 2:  Figma in one of our categories as like a thing we might want to take. But
Speaker 2:  if you take Figma from Figma, there is no Figma anymore. So that doesn't
Speaker 2:  count. Well
Speaker 6:  What about, what about Fig Jam?
Speaker 6:  Sure. Moving right along. Yes,
Speaker 2:  Sure. That's actually, I'll give you that. Another one I had is like,
Speaker 2:  oh here's a good example. Like we can't take Salesforce from Salesforce,
Speaker 2:  but we could take Slack from Salesforce.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I see. So if Apple had a product called Apple, you would just be like,
Speaker 6:  no. That
Speaker 2:  Accounted for, you know, 98% of its revenue. Yeah. So, sure. I guess under
Speaker 2:  that rule we can take fig jam, I'll add fig Jam back to the
Speaker 2:  list. And most importantly, this is not competitive. We are
Speaker 2:  three CEOs. We are doing this together. And so we have to agree on everything
Speaker 2:  that we're going to take. Which I assume means this is going to take 12 hours.
Speaker 5:  Is there such thing as a hung jury in this situation?
Speaker 2:  No, because there are three of us and if it comes to it, we will vote and
Speaker 2:  two to one will win. Yeah. This is why we have three CEOs. This is, it's
Speaker 2:  a perfect, I can't believe no one has thought of this before.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Why? Why are people doing one and two
Speaker 2:  Odd number? CEOs solves all your problems. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Here are the
Speaker 2:  categories. We're gonna do smartphones, tablets, and PCs. Then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  take a break. We're gonna do wearables, headphones, app platforms,
Speaker 2:  which is not specific apps, but think of like app businesses, like
Speaker 2:  Microsoft Office is one of the options in that category. And then we're going
Speaker 2:  to do what I have called boring B2B money faucets, which is the thing that
Speaker 2:  makes you all the money that nobody ever wants to talk about. Then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna take another break and then we're gonna do messaging, streaming service,
Speaker 2:  wild card gadgets, and wild card everything else. And then we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  outta here and we're gonna go be filthy rich. Sound good?
Speaker 5:  I'm so excited to be rich.
Speaker 2:  Alright. Category number one is smartphones. This to me is maybe the
Speaker 2:  easiest but also maybe the most difficult one to do first, which is why I
Speaker 2:  wanted it to do it first.
Speaker 5:  See, I, I also agree with you 'cause I think we're probably along the same
Speaker 5:  lines for what the phone should be.
Speaker 6:  Well it, the only thing that makes it different is David told us not to worry
Speaker 6:  about money.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. We
Speaker 5:  Don't worry about money. Well
Speaker 6:  If you give one wit about money, you take the iPhone. Yes. Right? Because
Speaker 6:  then you then now you funded whatever other boondoggles you want to get on.
Speaker 6:  Like Yeah. Then we can pick the Cobo for tablets and it's fine.
Speaker 5:  That's what we should do. Exactly. You're you're right on the same wave
Speaker 6:  Link. But if you don't care about money, then you might have a substantive
Speaker 6:  discussion about what phone you want. Well,
Speaker 2:  So, okay, let me, let me frame this slightly differently. We don't care,
Speaker 2:  we are not spending our time thinking about quarterly earnings and shareholder
Speaker 2:  value, but we do wanna win Right In like big picture win
Speaker 6:  Then we're taking the iPhone. Yeah, I've already, I've crushed you.
Speaker 5:  We're taking the iPhone. We win.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. I think the only reason for me that the iPhone is challenging
Speaker 2:  is that there are a lot of categories here in which Apple is also very good
Speaker 2:  and some in which it has a lot less competition. Oh
Speaker 6:  No, no. I can, every other category I can, I can defeat everyone
Speaker 6:  else with the power of the iPhones lockin.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  Do you trust me? You just wait God And I'm allowed to change stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we're good. We nailed it. It's fine.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God. I just realized we're gonna speed run building an app
Speaker 2:  tax out of Yeah, it's,
Speaker 6:  It's gonna go so fast. You think I don't care about money David.
Speaker 6:  45%. Let's
Speaker 2:  Go. Yeah, somewhere. Le Conn just started listening to this and she's like,
Speaker 2:  this is,
Speaker 6:  She's like, this isn't the tech company I would've built.
Speaker 2:  We
Speaker 5:  Were not even gonna be allowed to make a company. Lena Conn's. Like, Nope,
Speaker 5:  no, not
Speaker 6:  This person. Your fake company is illegal, sir.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But just for this, for the sake of argument, the other nominees
Speaker 2:  that I had here were Samsung, which I think is probably the only other
Speaker 2:  reasonable competitor here. The Google Pixel. If you're, you know, feeling
Speaker 2:  good about yourself, the nothing phone, which is a fun, like dark horse if
Speaker 2:  you wanna like bet on doing something weird and cool in the next six years
Speaker 2:  until 2030. Interesting bet. Huawei one plus Asus
Speaker 2:  Motorola, like, it gets bleak pretty fast.
Speaker 6:  Real fast. Were you hoping that one of us would be like Motorola?
Speaker 2:  I was hoping one of you would fight for Samsung to be honest, just because
Speaker 2:  I think it's possible to maybe want to pick an Apple product in another one.
Speaker 2:  'cause we've now ruled out every other Apple product. No, 'cause
Speaker 5:  I'm looking it through the rest and I'm like, I'm like, there's other really
Speaker 5:  good competitors in these other places. Okay. But like the iPhone, if you're,
Speaker 5:  if if the phone is like the engine of the business,
Speaker 5:  which it feels like probably is true, then we want the iPhone.
Speaker 6:  I mean alternatively the, the one that I would've argued for would've been
Speaker 6:  the pixel because then the one thing you would change about it would be caring
Speaker 6:  and then, and then it would be good. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But
Speaker 5:  The iPhone we've got like the people who are making the good processors on
Speaker 5:  the iPhone. Whereas the Pixel we've got not that,
Speaker 6:  But sure. But you know, a little, a little caring goes a long way. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  that's true. That's true. Like also trying to market the phone would be useful.
Speaker 2:  I mean, yeah, like in, in terms of raw upside, the
Speaker 2:  ROII think for the Pixel would be huge. Whereas the iPhone, I have a hard
Speaker 2:  time imagining making the iPhone more successful. But it's also very successful.
Speaker 2:  I think the answer is just the iPhone. I don't know that we need to talk
Speaker 2:  about this much longer.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna solve every other problem on this list.
Speaker 2:  So again, I would, I would remind you that one of the things we are not trying
Speaker 2:  to do here is build a services business or a monopoly.
Speaker 6:  Wait, we, we are not trying to build a monopoly. We wanna win. Hmm. So you're
Speaker 6:  saying this collection of three CEOs has to have some values? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  We wanna like be cool. Our main value is like be cool.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I want to have a monopoly in a cool way. Yeah. Yeah. All right. Fair.
Speaker 6:  Okay, we, we can move
Speaker 2:  On. All right. So the iPhone next up tablets, which is
Speaker 2:  ironically a very similar set of companies, but I would say that we, we can't
Speaker 2:  pick the iPad. So the iPad is out, which leaves us with the four
Speaker 2:  nominees I picked so far. Were the Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 2:  tabs, the Google Pixel tablet such as it is Amazon's
Speaker 2:  whole Kindle lineup, which I think counts as a tablet. Cobo, you could do
Speaker 2:  one plus there's a lot of tablets out there. We could argue about the Microsoft
Speaker 2:  Surface as a tablet line, but I think, I won't count that. We'll get to that
Speaker 2:  in a minute. What do you guys think? Who's the favorite here?
Speaker 5:  I think we go with the books and then we have the Apple, the iPhone
Speaker 5:  team make the operating system good.
Speaker 6:  Wait, is that, can You, can you make that choice? Can I pick the Galaxy?
Speaker 6:  But it runs iPad os.
Speaker 2:  No, but it, but if we don't take the iPad, we don't get iPad os we're
Speaker 5:  Gonna use iOS to put on, put that on the books.
Speaker 6:  Oh and then I didn't, we didn't take Mac Os which would've been the real
Speaker 6:  move. We can't, huh?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. See
Speaker 6:  So wait, so wait, hold on to wind this. Put a red
Speaker 2:  On all of this To get an iPad running Mac os
Speaker 6:  I have to like take the pixel so I can take the MacBook so
Speaker 6:  I can take the Samsung Galaxy and make it run Mac os
Speaker 6:  to get to a Galaxy pad running Mac os I have to take the Pixel and then a
Speaker 6:  MacBook. That would be
Speaker 2:  The way. I'm gonna be honest, I don't hate that strategy.
Speaker 6:  I feel like the board of directors meeting will be very confusing.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm with, I'm with Krantz. I think you take the Kindle lineup, you jazz
Speaker 6:  up the software a little bit. People are happy. I
Speaker 5:  Wanted to go books to get Escape the lock-in. 'cause I feel like we save
Speaker 5:  some money with that acquisition. But
Speaker 2:  We can solve the lock-in, remember Android is open source. So Android is
Speaker 2:  fair game. no matter what we do, we can just have Android,
Speaker 6:  We can un DRM the books is what you're saying.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think, so then the real question is like, who, who is better
Speaker 2:  at making the hardware that we can take and have a pretty solid lead
Speaker 2:  on? And I feel like, I feel like it's Amazon. Like books does cool stuff,
Speaker 2:  but I feel like if we, we just steal the Amazon team and we're like, what
Speaker 2:  if we did a good job again? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause we get, we get Panos. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we get Panos.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we're doing the Kindle. That's right.
Speaker 2:  I feel good about that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're doing the Kindle and we're gonna make it good now
Speaker 6:  It's a real culture hire right there. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do we immediately kill the whole Kindle fire line? Yes. And we just focus
Speaker 2:  on E Inc. No, no,
Speaker 6:  No. That's good for kids. Okay, so actually I would say we take the, the
Speaker 6:  tablet thing we're taking is like the extended Kindle. The
Speaker 2:  Kindle universe we get Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All this class of ca tablets is accomplishing for anyone is
Speaker 6:  playing Disney Plus for your children. So we're just like, the Kindle Fire
Speaker 6:  kids is the centerpiece of our tablet strategy.
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 5:  Then we also just make a nice e-reader on the side that runs iOS.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then I can go to various state capitals and be like, you want,
Speaker 6:  you wanna make laws protecting kids make a law saying you have to buy a Kindle
Speaker 6:  fire for kids.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There we go. I mean, I love how we're like making a really good
Speaker 5:  culturally important company that also doesn't break laws.
Speaker 6:  I'm not trying to break the laws. I'm trying to make the laws. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm trying to be the laws.
Speaker 6:  Do you understand if you don't buy a Kindle fire, you will be arrested.
Speaker 2:  Here is my question is, do we reboot the fire phone with our
Speaker 2:  iPhone team?
Speaker 6:  Which part are we like the
Speaker 5:  3D display. We've
Speaker 6:  Already added 50 cameras to the phone. What if we had four more to make
Speaker 6:  it 3D? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it's one of them is just for barcodes. Yeah. Amazon Kindle easy choice.
Speaker 2:  Next up is PCs. And I think the list of folks is fairly
Speaker 2:  familiar here. Alex, what do you got?
Speaker 5:  Okay, so the list is, it's, it's, we can't do Apple, but we got Microsoft,
Speaker 5:  Lenovo, Seus, aer, hp, razor Dell. I think
Speaker 5:  we should go Lenovo because if you, you get rid of all of the spam wear
Speaker 5:  that they like automatically install. You have some really nice laptops.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 6:  Got really nice hardware. Yeah, you
Speaker 5:  Got really nice hardware. And then we make the iOS team,
Speaker 5:  they're gonna be working nights, but they're gonna have to basically like
Speaker 5:  reinvent Mac os like they, they can figure it out.
Speaker 6:  You can back into it. You start iOS started with Mac Os and you're like,
Speaker 6:  go the other way. Go
Speaker 5:  The other way. I I I fully believe in them. If we can make PC
Speaker 5:  clones, we can do this too.
Speaker 6:  But we don't have the chips. I guess we do. 'cause we have the iPhone. So
Speaker 6:  now we're just, now we just put a, a hinge and a lid on an iPhone. We're
Speaker 6:  like, that's a laptop. Yeah. Which is more or less the iPad. I just
Speaker 6:  wanna be very clear about what we're discussing. We're like, we make iPads
Speaker 6:  now, but it's
Speaker 5:  Also got the little, it's got the little the dot
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, the little, the Trackpad guy. Yeah. I see. I was gonna say Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  'cause you I want control of the operating system. That's
Speaker 2:  Where I go to. Right.
Speaker 6:  And I want the surface line. I don't, now I've pulled the tablet
Speaker 6:  ecosystem bigger, right? Yeah. I've got my, my Kindles and my Kindle fires
Speaker 6:  and I've got the Surface Pro and I've got a whole range of products.
Speaker 5:  Tell us about all of the really good laptops and all-in-ones
Speaker 5:  that, that we're gonna get with our Microsoft acquisition.
Speaker 6:  So here again, a lot of my strategy is just try hard. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Right. Just to be clear. So yeah. The Surface Studio, but like what if you
Speaker 6:  put a real chip in it? Mm huh And that's just me and meetings
Speaker 6:  like what if circle this on the whiteboard and then write, try hard and
Speaker 6:  then like three exclamation points. And that's my whole surface strategy.
Speaker 5:  We can make it all run risk v
Speaker 6:  With like the power of one Raspberry Pi four. Yeah, my
Speaker 6:  vote. We, David, you're the tiebreaker here. It's between Microsoft and Lenovo.
Speaker 6:  I agree. Lenovo makes some of the, the better hardware here.
Speaker 5:  You make a compelling point about being able to have Windows and make it
Speaker 5:  good.
Speaker 2:  The one wrench I would like to throw in is that if we get Dell, we just instantly
Speaker 2:  have the best lineup of Windows PCs that exists.
Speaker 6:  But we don't have Windows. We don't have
Speaker 2:  Windows. Do we want windows?
Speaker 6:  You know, like for example, like, I would like to walk up to the box that
Speaker 6:  says like security and Right. Try hard.
Speaker 2:  I will say though, under the rules of this game though, I don't, we, I think
Speaker 2:  what we're getting is like a perpetual license to Windows. I don't think
Speaker 2:  we're getting
Speaker 6:  Even inside my, that's probably how the service team, yeah. I
Speaker 2:  Don't think we get to run Windows,
Speaker 6:  But so when we took the iPhone, we don't get to run iOS. No,
Speaker 5:  We do. That one counts. It
Speaker 2:  Does, it feels different. I can't describe to you why. No, it's because it's,
Speaker 2:  it's one device to one operating system. This is not one device to one operating
Speaker 2:  system. We are a partner to the operating system, not the only venue for
Speaker 2:  the operating system. Even
Speaker 6:  If we're Microsoft, we're
Speaker 2:  Not. But we're the Surface team. We aren't Microsoft, we're Vergecast incorporated.
Speaker 2:  We're not taking Windows from Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  Ah.
Speaker 2:  I still think it's Microsoft just because I think we're, we're clearly building
Speaker 2:  a luxury thing here. And I think getting there with Lenovo
Speaker 2:  is gonna be challenging. Like, I don't, I don't know how we're gonna convince
Speaker 2:  everybody that Lenovo is like, kick ass cool again. I think we can get there
Speaker 2:  with Surface. Well,
Speaker 6:  No, but we are not. We're we're not Lenovo. We're just, we're just taking
Speaker 6:  the product. We're doing a little rebrand. You
Speaker 5:  Got the think pad. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You're right. We wearing a little coat of paint on there.
Speaker 2:  Get the yogas. So you guys want some yogas? Yeah, they do the flippy
Speaker 2:  things. I'm gonna make tent mode happen for America. Okay. I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  going Lenovo, because I think we're gonna want Microsoft later. I think there
Speaker 2:  are other things in this list that are going to be more useful to have for
Speaker 2:  Microsoft. So I think we should pick Lenovo.
Speaker 5:  You're right. That's true.
Speaker 2:  I'm dying to know what you think those things are, but we'll come back to
Speaker 2:  it. Think of all the boring things that make you the most valuable company
Speaker 2:  on planet Earth. And that's, that's what Microsoft does so
Speaker 2:  well.
Speaker 5:  It's not the surface team.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think. All right, so we're, we're picking, we're picking Lenovo.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the team. The little nub. It's very, what's that thing called?
Speaker 2:  The track point? Is that what that's called? Track
Speaker 5:  Point. Track point. Love that thing. We just call it a nub. That's it's a
Speaker 5:  nub. We're rebranding it immediately. Just immediate. That's the first thing
Speaker 5:  we do. Day one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I love this. Alright, so just to recap so far, we're gonna take
Speaker 2:  a quick break. We have, as Vergecast incorporated, we now make the
Speaker 2:  Apple iPhone, the Amazon, Kindle, and Lenovo's set of
Speaker 2:  PCs. I feel
Speaker 2:  company I thought of when I said wearable out loud to myself. What do you
Speaker 2:  guys think? Any, any jump out to you that we should definitely get into?
Speaker 2:  I have a clear favorite here
Speaker 6:  Out the gate. I'm going bold and taking Meta for the Ray bands. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Okay. Ooh, that's a good plan. I wasn't even, I was thinking of the, the,
Speaker 5:  the headset. I forgot about the glasses.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. On that front, do we get one or the other or do we get both?
Speaker 2:  Like if we, if we say Quest, we get all the quests in one
Speaker 2:  product, but I feel like the smart glasses are a different thing.
Speaker 6:  Get your face computers away from me. Okay. You know what I mean? Just that.
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. Although what are three band?
Speaker 2:  You just want the smart glasses.
Speaker 6:  I just want the glasses.
Speaker 2:  Even if we get the whole team, we're immediately killing the Quest line and
Speaker 2:  we're just going Smart glasses. That's
Speaker 6:  What they just did. I just want That's what Meta just did. Yeah. Smart Fish
Speaker 6:  reorganize that team. So I am saying the glasses are the
Speaker 6:  future. Okay. And we're, we're putting, we're putting our excess iPhone profits
Speaker 6:  into the glasses.
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Oh, I mean, if the glasses like ran a really good
Speaker 5:  ai, well no, we don't have one of those. We have Siri.
Speaker 6:  Although on a six year time horizon, it's like, hmm, hmm. Maybe I just wanna
Speaker 6:  take Samsung's watches and do login.
Speaker 2:  I mean, that is, that is actually an interesting question, right? Like, is,
Speaker 2:  are we betting that smart glasses are going to be
Speaker 2:  sufficiently huge by 2030? That this is like worth it for us? Or are we
Speaker 2:  just taking like a nerd gadget for the next six years?
Speaker 5:  No, this makes sense for us because we are, we're like, we're, we're cool.
Speaker 5:  We're luxury. What's this luxury? Like a pair of Ray bands
Speaker 2:  Fair. Okay. I have two others I'd like to throw at you. An
Speaker 5:  Aura ring.
Speaker 2:  That is one of the things I was gonna throw at you. I think Aura is like
Speaker 2:  a sneakily fascinating company. They're, and they are, they're way ahead
Speaker 2:  in Smart Rings. Smart rings are a lot of people think including our own
Speaker 2:  v song about to be a real thing. I think especially if you're betting that
Speaker 2:  this like health and fitness thing is gonna keep growing really fast, that's
Speaker 2:  a place to go. I also think Garmin for kind of the same reasons. Like what
Speaker 2:  if we can redesign Garmin's watches so that they don't look dumb,
Speaker 2:  but they have all the cool stuff that Garmin already has that people really
Speaker 2:  like. I feel like you could make something out of Garmin. I also, my
Speaker 2:  immediate reaction when we did this was Snap because I want the spectacles
Speaker 2:  line, but I think we go, we go RayBan Meta Smart Glasses and that gets us
Speaker 2:  everywhere. We're going probably significantly faster.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's basically, do we wanna go watch Ring or Glasses?
Speaker 5:  Totally.
Speaker 2:  But
Speaker 5:  If we go Samsung, we do watch and ring. Right?
Speaker 6:  Well, so the the thing that this I think makes very clear
Speaker 6:  is You can take any of the watches and You can do iPhone lock in.
Speaker 6:  And now you have a realistic competitor to the Apple Watch, right? Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's the thing that actually holds a bunch of these companies back
Speaker 6:  is they cannot communicate with the iPhone. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But that be cool Neli. It's written, it's written
Speaker 2:  at the top of the building of our headquarters. It just says, be cool. What's
Speaker 2:  cooler
Speaker 5:  Than lock in? What's cooler
Speaker 2:  Than lock?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The change I'm making is being like, all right, whoop, you're in like,
Speaker 6:  let's go. You know? Yeah. Like You can, You can now more directly
Speaker 6:  figure out Apple integrations.
Speaker 2:  Buy a ThinkPad, get a whoop, let's go.
Speaker 6:  But I'm just saying like, if that on a six year time horizon, maybe that
Speaker 6:  is a better move than take the Meta
Speaker 6:  ray bands and figure out how glasses work. Which by the way, glasses
Speaker 6:  also held back because they cannot properly integrate with your phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is like a, a real problem for all these products, but
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's why like the glasses, we get them properly integrating
Speaker 5:  with the phone. Then we also have like an additional
Speaker 5:  audio solution. When
Speaker 6:  You say an additional audio solution, I mean, some headphones. Well,
Speaker 5:  You know, we headphones is headphones coming up next. So you,
Speaker 6:  You've been a CEO for 20 minutes. You are already super corporate.
Speaker 5:  It's an additional Yeah. We need, we need more than one audio solution for
Speaker 5:  our company guys,
Speaker 2:  I've prepared a deck to talk about this. We even
Speaker 5:  Need to be diversified in our audio.
Speaker 6:  This is good. Good. It happens to everybody know,
Speaker 5:  It's, it be just immediate. Yeah. But the Garmin, like the Garmin has
Speaker 5:  so much cool stuff in it. They just look so ugly and we've got the
Speaker 5:  Apple team now. Right. They can like make it look good. We're that team,
Speaker 5:  that poor team in Panos pane just chained to their desk.
Speaker 2:  We need that team to keep making iPhones though. I don't know.
Speaker 6:  But but they, it's not like they're doing a lot. They're like, take the buttons
Speaker 6:  off it. You know?
Speaker 2:  That's true. It's, it's thinner next time. Like we did
Speaker 6:  It. I think you're the tiebreaker. I think it's between Garmin and Meta once
Speaker 6:  again. David, you have to, you have to pull apart this corporate battle.
Speaker 2:  I think we should pick Meta. Ooh. Yeah. Because I think, I think the
Speaker 2:  RayBan Meta partnership is
Speaker 2:  cool. I think the glasses are awesome and people really like them and I think
Speaker 2:  our ability to like integrate them a little and make them way better
Speaker 2:  for people. Instant victory. Like I think with the other
Speaker 2:  picks that we have here, we have a chance to like immediately make these
Speaker 2:  things much cooler in a way that I feel like we're gonna have to basically
Speaker 2:  like tear down the Garmin hardware team and build it back up. And I feel
Speaker 2:  like that's gonna take us a while. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's gonna be more than six years.
Speaker 2:  Garmin, please know that I love you and you make cool things. Just like make
Speaker 2:  them cooler.
Speaker 6:  Garmin. If you'd like to integrate with Vergecast Incorporated's, iPhone
Speaker 6:  You can pass 55%.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We'd love to have you. We've
Speaker 5:  Got some really good audio solutions for you.
Speaker 6:  The, the developer program is open and it will only be slightly more than
Speaker 6:  half of your revenue.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Also, the smart glasses are just like cool. And I love using them and
Speaker 2:  I want to have them. So we're, we're going with that. I feel good about it.
Speaker 2:  I don't love that we just hired a hardware team out of Meta, which
Speaker 2:  makes me feel a lot of feelings in general, but it's okay. We're we're doing
Speaker 2:  it. We
Speaker 6:  Now know everything about you.
Speaker 2:  Our privacy policy by the way, is dope. Like, let's just take that for granted
Speaker 6:  Because
Speaker 2:  You're wondering about our privacy policy. It is sick.
Speaker 5:  The EU never gets mad at us.
Speaker 2:  No. It's like not a problem at all. I should have said at the beginning,
Speaker 2:  by the way, by picking the iPhone, we did just bring ourselves a delightful
Speaker 2:  antitrust case that I'm not super psyched about, but I feel like it's
Speaker 2:  it's one of those is coming anyway, right? Yeah. Like you might as well,
Speaker 2:  Lena
Speaker 5:  Call us.
Speaker 2:  Neli has been begging to fight an antitrust case. So like it's
Speaker 6:  Time from this side. That's really what I've been after this whole time is
Speaker 6:  let me be the monopolist.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's perfect.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying we're raising rent. If we're going down, we're going down
Speaker 6:  Rich.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And by the time any of this comes out, it'll be past 2030. We'll be
Speaker 2:  out anyway. It's, it's fine. Yeah. I'm not worried about it. Alright, next
Speaker 2:  category is headphones. And here again, we're pretty wide
Speaker 2:  open. Apple is off the board, but I'm gonna allow Beats to stay on the board
Speaker 2:  because it is different enough that I think will allow it because
Speaker 6:  They don't care about it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, pretty much. Like, I don't know if Apple knows that it owns Beats,
Speaker 2:  so we're just gonna let it ride. But there's also obvious players here. Bose
Speaker 2:  and Sony and Sonos is a new one.
Speaker 5:  Just headphones though. We'll,
Speaker 2:  No, we'll make this headphones slash speakers. We'll go audio solutions.
Speaker 2:  Oh my gosh. In, in Alex Grand. I
Speaker 5:  Think you know exactly where we're going with this.
Speaker 2:  Neli is gonna advocate for the party speaker.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm taking Sony now that it's audio solutions.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we've got a lot Ara. Wider range.
Speaker 6:  It's the ult. I mean, you want luxury. What
Speaker 6:  screams luxury more than the words? Mega base.
Speaker 2:  A seven foot tall speaker
Speaker 6:  By the way. Shout out to the Vergecast listeners who just send me pictures
Speaker 6:  of it in the wild. Amazing. It's like they're birding, you know,
Speaker 6:  but like the only one person cares about birds and it's me.
Speaker 2:  How does it feel to be known for the cyber truck wiper and Sony party speakers?
Speaker 2:  Like, is this a good legacy that you're happy
Speaker 6:  About? Is that on the list? Cyber truck wiper on the wild card gadgets. Cyber
Speaker 6:  truck wiper.
Speaker 2:  We have two wild card options, so don't, don't worry. I, for me
Speaker 2:  it's Sonos on this one. Interesting. I want Sonos real bad because again,
Speaker 2:  we're in this like, we want to build cool stuff that's integrated. Sonos
Speaker 2:  makes good products. They know how to make good audio products. I feel like
Speaker 2:  we could take Sonos and be like, just learn how to make software. Everything's
Speaker 2:  gonna be fine.
Speaker 6:  Just learn this easy part. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 2:  Have you heard of apps? What if we did that? This could be
Speaker 6:  Fine. So again, I I I would actually take Sony here, not just because of
Speaker 6:  the party speaker situation. I think our headphones are really good. They're
Speaker 6:  my Sony noise cancels are really good, right? I think they compete with Bose
Speaker 6:  to be the top of the market. Then they've got an actual audio solutions catalog,
Speaker 6:  like an actual array of speakers and like, what is one product I want desperately
Speaker 6:  from Sonos so they won't sell is like a receiver, right? Like fair. There's
Speaker 6:  a huge array of those audio products that You can
Speaker 6:  ruthlessly integrate with a phone in a way that even Sonos can't right now.
Speaker 6:  That's why they have the software problems. Like their app platform has to
Speaker 6:  support a bunch of stuff because they can't just put it on your phone directly.
Speaker 6:  And also Mega Megabase. I would just get it. Okay. I would
Speaker 2:  Have it. Alex, what do you think? I just
Speaker 5:  Really like the Sony headphones. Okay. They just have such a nice, wider,
Speaker 5:  wider range. Like Sonos just got into headphones. They don't have any in-ear
Speaker 5:  monitors. Sure. They don't have any buds.
Speaker 2:  Also tough time to be taking over Sonos. Like real, real kind of reputation
Speaker 2:  hit
Speaker 6:  Oh, you know what you don't have on here. What's that? And again, I'm, I'm
Speaker 6:  just gonna point this out for everyone. I think the age of televisions is
Speaker 6:  coming to an end because David made a list of gadgets and didn't put TVs
Speaker 6:  on them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't care. I, no part of me wants to build televisions.
Speaker 6:  Well, I'll just remind everyone that I asked the CEO EO of Netflix about
Speaker 6:  the Samsung frame tv and he was like, why are you stop talking to me. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I was like, do you think this is a harbinger of doom? And he was like, I
Speaker 6:  don't know what you're saying. I have,
Speaker 2:  I own
Speaker 6:  One, but I'm just saying you made an entire list of gadgets and you didn't
Speaker 6:  put TVs on here. It's a, it's a prophecy because
Speaker 5:  He knew you were gonna say the Sam we're gonna acquire the Samsung frame
Speaker 5:  and fix it.
Speaker 2:  To be clear. Not an oversight. We are not getting in the television business.
Speaker 2:  What if we made no money and everything was impossible and we had to spy
Speaker 2:  on our users.
Speaker 6:  All I'm saying is if TVs were on here anywhere, then I would
Speaker 6:  change my headphones pick to see if you're giving me audio solutions, but
Speaker 6:  not TVs, then it's Sony. Okay. If you're, if TVs
Speaker 6:  are back on the list, then I, I have to, I'm required by
Speaker 6:  like blood and heritage to take Sony televisions. Okay. And then I would
Speaker 6:  change my headphones pick. So
Speaker 2:  We do have a wild card round coming later. And, if you, if you think You
Speaker 2:  can win the fight for us to get Sony TVs, You can, You can hold your fire
Speaker 2:  for them.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna fight for TCL so hard.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I don't think you're gonna win the Sony TVs fight. I just don't think,
Speaker 2:  think we wanna be in the TV business.
Speaker 6:  Well, if I take him off the board here, it's a big, it's a big decision.
Speaker 6:  Yes. How do I get Ma West in the tablet is kind of the, you know, I gotta
Speaker 6:  play three moves ahead.
Speaker 2:  I will be down with Sony here, by the way. Tough beat for Bose that none
Speaker 2:  of us are even attempting to take Bose. They're
Speaker 5:  Fine. Well, well
Speaker 6:  You made it audio solutions, right? If it was just headphones,
Speaker 6:  I would immediately go Bose so I could win the Sony fight later.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay. Yeah. And I don't, it's just like a bunch of weird scientists
Speaker 2:  in Massachusetts. Like, we don't, we don't need that. I'll go Sony under
Speaker 2:  one stipulation, which is that we immediately rename every single product
Speaker 2:  they make to something. Yes. Not stupid.
Speaker 6:  No. With more letters. Twice as many letters
Speaker 2:  And another dash in the middle for no
Speaker 6:  Reason.
Speaker 6:  Just get in there.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I think it's Sony. Okay. Yeah. I, I feel good about this. I think we're,
Speaker 2:  I think we're aligned.
Speaker 6:  I can figure something out for TVs. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I feel now obligated to take something from Samsung just so that you can't
Speaker 2:  argue for the Frame tv because I don't need this in my life.
Speaker 6:  That's not what I was gonna take again. I believe it's a harbinger of doom.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So the next two things on here are, I would say
Speaker 2:  the sneaky places. We're gonna make a lot of money. This is what pays for
Speaker 2:  everything else that the shareholders are gonna love and we're probably never
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about again. The first one is app platforms, which I suppose
Speaker 2:  could be a single app if we wanted a single app. But I'm thinking more along
Speaker 2:  the lines of like big groups of things. So like, I had Adobe Creative Cloud
Speaker 2:  as an option here and Microsoft Office and Google Workspace. This is like
Speaker 2:  probably B2B software that is going to make us just a tremendous amount of
Speaker 2:  money. What do we think?
Speaker 6:  So I have to go with office. Okay. Only for one
Speaker 6:  small reason, and I can't believe you didn't think of it first, David. We
Speaker 6:  cannot run this company without Microsoft Excel.
Speaker 2:  Oh, that's interesting.
Speaker 6:  No company can be run without Microsoft Excel. Like just for our own survival.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know,
Speaker 5:  You can just like pay for a license. We'll have so much money
Speaker 5:  we can just pay for a license for Excel.
Speaker 2:  But what if other people paid us for licenses?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm just saying you want, you want a, you want a dog food, you know,
Speaker 6:  your your own your own work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But we can have Adobe Creative Cloud and just have a
Speaker 5:  stranglehold on the entire industry.
Speaker 6:  You want people to hate us.
Speaker 5:  We can just like, I love a monopoly. I'm, I'm on this side of
Speaker 5:  things now,
Speaker 2:  Another antitrust fight that I'm really excited about. Yeah. We're
Speaker 5:  Only gonna be there six years By the time that stuff all hits, we'll be long
Speaker 5:  gone.
Speaker 2:  So I think the upside of Creative Cloud is we take Creative Cloud,
Speaker 2:  we make the pricing better and we're legends. Right? Like instantly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Best possible PR win is we just like give away
Speaker 2:  Premier. We're just like here You can have it.
Speaker 5:  No, we, we sell like, rather than the cloud license, we're like, okay, You
Speaker 5:  can just buy Premier, but it'll cost a thousand dollars. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Then we make a lot of money and people are happy because they can just own
Speaker 5:  it for
Speaker 2:  Six years. Yeah. For
Speaker 5:  Six years. And then it's gone and then, and then, you know, whoever
Speaker 5:  follows us. Panos, I'm sorry you're taking over the company from us.
Speaker 5:  Good luck.
Speaker 6:  A lot of our ideas are like, what if we made slightly less money? But that's
Speaker 6:  fine. Whereas my ideas are what if we made a lot more money?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This, this says a lot about the, the distinct vibes of The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  Incorporated team. I would say it's either office or it's Creative
Speaker 2:  Cloud. Right? I feel like there's nothing else you, like, we could go try
Speaker 2:  to get like Oracle's weird business or like IBM's consulting arm or
Speaker 2:  whatever, but we haven't picked a Google thing. Mm. Do we not want Google
Speaker 2:  Workspace? Do we just take Google Workspace and go kill office?
Speaker 6:  So my, my idea here again, you know, the, our our company's mission
Speaker 6:  is try hard. Yeah. And workspace is a ripe target for trying hard. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is also where you could do messaging. You could, you know, you could
Speaker 6:  walk in the room, be like, make a list of all the messaging products and
Speaker 6:  then walk out and six months later you come back in and look at the list
Speaker 6:  and you like circle one and you're like this one we're just doing this one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And we're gonna name it Gchat. That's a real, that's a thing you could
Speaker 6:  do here.
Speaker 2:  It is. It is. Messaging I would point out is a separate category. So we're,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna get to messaging, but if we, whatever company we pick here, we
Speaker 2:  can't pick there. Okay. Which is a case for and against some folks
Speaker 2:  here. And
Speaker 5:  If we pick Microsoft Office, we can't pick Azure. If we
Speaker 5:  pick Google Workspace, we can't pick Google Cloud. That's
Speaker 6:  Right. No one was picking Google Cloud. Come on. I, okay, I'll, I'll I will
Speaker 6:  nce and say we should pick Creative Cloud. And our mission here is to make
Speaker 6:  people not not hate us. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think, I think this is where we win over all the people to use
Speaker 2:  our hardware because they're gonna love, this is how we sell Lenovo ThinkPads
Speaker 6:  Because of 55% lock-in Yeah. You can run Creative Cloud
Speaker 6:  on someone else's laptop. It'll just cost four times as much money.
Speaker 6:  I I don't make the rules. Yeah. Except for that one.
Speaker 5:  Well just like, like the more your company makes, we charge you more like
Speaker 5:  just a, a scale, a sliding scale.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I like that. You pay per YouTube subscriber instead of per
Speaker 6:  So evil.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Oh, you're just getting out in this industry. You basically get
Speaker 5:  it for free. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I love this. The minute
Speaker 5:  You start making success that we, we come for our
Speaker 6:  Cut and if you're wearing our wearable, we can track your general
Speaker 6:  burnout level as a creator and we start bringing the price back down. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I love that. See, oh my god. Synergy.
Speaker 2:  We actually turn the app off when you need a rest day and then, and then
Speaker 2:  we'll get it
Speaker 6:  Back. Calm down Jimmy.
Speaker 2:  All right. So we're, we're good on Creative cloud. Alright.
Speaker 6:  I mean Sure.
Speaker 2:  I think it's the right answer.
Speaker 6:  That's okay. I, I know I'm the one who has to deal with like whatever terms
Speaker 6:  of service conflagration. It's like I'm fine. I'll I'll do it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  David and I work four days a year. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Kran and I are the ones who like go to canned lions and like meet with
Speaker 2:  advertisers. You have to actually like do the things. I
Speaker 6:  Have to write the blog post. It's like, all right, we changed our terms of
Speaker 6:  service. Exactly. It's true that we're gonna take your firstborn child,
Speaker 6:  but we're doing this for the good of all humanity.
Speaker 2:  This is beautiful. I love this for you. Alright, next category is the
Speaker 2:  boring B2B on a faucets. This is where we get to, we get to
Speaker 2:  pick our cloud provider. We can make B2B chips
Speaker 2:  that we sell. I was gonna put arm in here, but we can't have arm because
Speaker 2:  arm only thing is arm. So that doesn't really work. We can, this is, this
Speaker 2:  is where we make all of our money, but we try to never talk about in public
Speaker 2:  because no one cares.
Speaker 6:  Can we take TSMC?
Speaker 2:  What would you want to take from TSMC
Speaker 6:  Making the chips for everybody?
Speaker 2:  No, that's their whole thing.
Speaker 6:  But they don't make a product called TSMC. No, we don't ship T
Speaker 6:  SMCs around the world.
Speaker 2:  Right. That would be then just buying the company, which is not what we're
Speaker 2:  doing. We're taking products.
Speaker 5:  You get like one TSMC factory.
Speaker 2:  This is like an expansion draft in sports. Right. We get to like pick from
Speaker 2:  your roster, but we can't have your team.
Speaker 6:  What about that one company in Europe that actually makes the lithography
Speaker 6:  machine? Ooh, that TSMC relies on
Speaker 2:  That like $23 million machine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's only, what's the name of that company? A SML. I think we should
Speaker 6:  take a s ml. I think we should take the machine that makes the fabs.
Speaker 2:  The machine. That makes the fabs. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Not like Azure. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But like, you know, I'm already defending Creative Cloud. Like, I'm not trying
Speaker 6:  to be outta
Speaker 5:  Here. I just wanna print all the money. Like this. This is, this is our money
Speaker 5:  printer. Who, who gets mad at Azure? Right? Lately
Speaker 6:  No one. But it's also in second place. Right? You have to, you have to go
Speaker 6:  make the AI case, you gotta do the AI CRM thing to
Speaker 6:  make, to grow Azure. Right. I guess we're just milking it for profits and
Speaker 6:  walking away. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. Yeah. We're only here for six years
Speaker 6:  And we are, we can't take AWS 'cause we took the Kindle. Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which is a very funny trade to have made. If, if
Speaker 2:  you're trying to build a business,
Speaker 5:  I mean, Ooh, we could take whisper from OpenAI
Speaker 2:  Whisper's open source. We're good there. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Good. Also OpenAI, it's on this list as a money faucet, but it is not,
Speaker 6:  it's like a reverse, it's a drain. Oh, I
Speaker 2:  True. I meant to write this as basically like if we want, we can take
Speaker 2:  like GPT-4 oh from OpenAI, which,
Speaker 6:  Which still, which they are now in a one, a stunning business.
Speaker 6:  Judo move or giving away for free to Apple.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. No, I, I'm not, I don't think that's the winner, but I just, I wanted
Speaker 2:  to have an AI I option here.
Speaker 5:  Let's take Nvidia GForce now. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So this is the thing. How do we get something from Nvidia? This is, this
Speaker 2:  is my question. What do we take from Nvidia? Is it just the H 100 business?
Speaker 2:  Do we just, we just take NVIDIA's whole AI
Speaker 2:  chip situation.
Speaker 6:  I'm telling you. Do you, do you buy a SML and then you're like, if you
Speaker 6:  use these machines to make H one hundreds, 55%.
Speaker 2:  Huh?
Speaker 5:  That is a pretty good funny faucet. I feel like we'll be ripe for
Speaker 5:  disruption there.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think taking the, the Nvidia AI chip
Speaker 6:  business is like a strong move. 'cause now you're selling to Google Cloud
Speaker 6:  and Azure. Yeah. And on a six year horizon, they all wanna disrupt you, but
Speaker 6:  they won't be able
Speaker 2:  To. That's what I was about to say. Do we worry that every other chip maker
Speaker 2:  on earth is going to start making these and this becomes a bad bet pretty
Speaker 2:  soon?
Speaker 5:  That's Panos problem in six years.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Not in six years, baby. Okay. In six years I'm on a boat. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean the other, the other problem here is that if we, if we take that
Speaker 2:  the bubble bursts and we become the poster child of the AI bubble
Speaker 2:  that just burst and that's gonna happen in less than six years.
Speaker 6:  That's true. This is why I'm saying we should take, take a s ml, the chip
Speaker 6:  company
Speaker 2:  That is like the least sexy business you could possibly imagine in that
Speaker 2:  I doubt there's as much money in it because I don't think they can make all
Speaker 2:  that many of those. They really
Speaker 5:  Cannot. It's like Samsung in their battery business. Actually, maybe this
Speaker 5:  is a good idea. We're Samsung just makes a bunch of random stuff that makes
Speaker 5:  'em a ton of money. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We could take LG display right here.
Speaker 2:  Right? Oh, that's good. Ooh.
Speaker 6:  Right. Like you want, you wanna put an in your phone, come talk to Lucky
Speaker 6:  Gold Star. You know. Wait, I
Speaker 2:  Like that a
Speaker 5:  Lot. I was like, LG display that, that feels like it the way we all were
Speaker 5:  just like, yeah.
Speaker 2:  See, and it, that feels, that feels sticky. They're gonna make screens for
Speaker 2:  a long time. I feel like we're in and that's like, that's easy. It runs itself.
Speaker 2:  We're good. All right. I love this. And,
Speaker 6:  And we love talking about it. We do. You know. Yeah. You, you want to talk
Speaker 6:  about dual layer OLEDs? Let's go.
Speaker 2:  Do you feel like this gets you close enough to the TV business that you're
Speaker 2:  happy now, Eli?
Speaker 5:  They make the panels that go in your So
Speaker 6:  It's true. They do make the panels.
Speaker 2:  That's, we're like, we're, we're
Speaker 6:  Fine. I got my, I got myself a monitor in TV business. Yeah. We're gonna
Speaker 6:  take l LG display and we're going to, we're we're gonna make TVs
Speaker 5:  And then we're just gonna bolt two Sony party speakers to it. Boom.
Speaker 6:  You think we won? Sell these tomorrow. Come on.
Speaker 5:  Come on. Some little pulsing lights at the bottom. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. Nailed it. That's good. LG display. This is great. I'm in.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're gonna take one more break and then we're gonna come back.
Speaker 2:  We got four more to do. We're gonna build VERGE casting. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Next up for the triumvirate
Speaker 2:  at Vergecast Incorporated is messaging. We can,
Speaker 2:  we can take, again, not a company, so we can't take signal from Signal
Speaker 2:  or Telegram From Telegram, but we can, we can take and reinvent any
Speaker 2:  messaging app or platform or ecosystem that we want. We can't take
Speaker 2:  from Meta, which I just realized because we took the RayBan Smart Glasses,
Speaker 2:  which I now slightly regret because I would like to have taken WhatsApp so
Speaker 5:  We can take all of the different Google chats that have existed and finally
Speaker 5:  make one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This is our opportunity. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We can make Gchat
Speaker 6:  Done. Done. I, I can solve, I canfin
Speaker 6:  I can solve this.
Speaker 2:  I mean, again, on the list of like do it and be legends. Finally making
Speaker 2:  Gchat is is way up there.
Speaker 6:  Just making Gchat and then I, you know, I got the phone. So, or
Speaker 6:  your blue bubble problems are solved. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. We don't have to worry about Messenger. We
Speaker 2:  Just put blue bubbles on the iPhone. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's super done. Whoa. This isn't even, why are we in Gchat, baby? I
Speaker 6:  met my wife on that. That's a real story, by the way. That's not just a case
Speaker 6:  in your
Speaker 2:  Picture. That is a real thing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Becky and I spent years of our, our early relationship in Gchat and nowhere
Speaker 6:  else.
Speaker 2:  Do you ever randomly find like the transcripts of those chats when you're
Speaker 2:  searching for something in your Gmail? This is a thing that happens to me
Speaker 2:  occasionally. I'll search for like, pizza in my Gmail and it'll be like,
Speaker 2:  did you mean this conversation you had with your ex 11 years ago that we
Speaker 2:  saved in Gmail?
Speaker 6:  Ooh, I haven't thought about that. And now I'm worried about looking.
Speaker 5:  Don't look. Don't
Speaker 6:  Look. So we're, we're gonna set that aside.
Speaker 5:  Don't look.
Speaker 2:  It's good. It's probably for the best. All
Speaker 6:  Of those Gchat conversations were before we were dating. So they were just
Speaker 6:  conversations about the things we had gotten up to at night,
Speaker 6:  which is a lot of things.
Speaker 2:  I. love it. Yeah. That's very good. Yeah. All right. The only other one I
Speaker 2:  would throw in is Slack, which I think is like a forever
Speaker 2:  unrealized potential that
Speaker 5:  Or Discord.
Speaker 2:  So, but we can't take Discord. 'cause Discord is Discord, right? Like, oh,
Speaker 2:  that's right. That's, that's It's off the, just I
Speaker 5:  Thought somebody else on Discord now.
Speaker 2:  No, they almost sold, but it's still just Discord. Microsoft was gonna, but
Speaker 2:  then they were like, this seems like a disaster. Which probably reasonable
Speaker 2:  call
Speaker 5:  Gchat being good, like, we're gonna kind of win people
Speaker 5:  over with, with Adobe, but eventually we will jack
Speaker 5:  up the prices on them and have it like, without question. Yeah. Yeah. Just
Speaker 5:  having Gchat there as like instant win. Okay. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Oh, yeah. All right. I feel good about this. It's Gchat and we're, we're
Speaker 2:  agreed that we're scrapping all the other nonsense. And we're calling it
Speaker 2:  Gchat, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. Without, okay. Easily
Speaker 2:  We are building the Gchat that always should have existed. Next one is streaming
Speaker 2:  service, which is actually fun because again, we can't steal a company. So
Speaker 2:  like, Netflix is out. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Shit. We just traded Gchat for YouTube,
Speaker 2:  Dude. Oh, no,
Speaker 6:  No, no. Can we go back? We should take Slack.
Speaker 5:  No, we can take TikTok.
Speaker 6:  Oh, we can take TikTok. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  You're right. We can take TikTok
Speaker 6:  For now. It's on by, by chance.
Speaker 2:  So.
Speaker 6:  Oh, we can buy. We are it We are gonna save America. Yeah, we,
Speaker 5:  We buy it. Oh yeah. There we, oh my God.
Speaker 6:  My dude. The wild card round here is amazing. We're gonna, we're gonna be
Speaker 6:  heroes with Gchat and we're gonna save America's youth. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Wow. We just did it. This is, this is, we did it. We're now the coolest company
Speaker 2:  on earth. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. And the good news is this one isn't even gonna
Speaker 2:  be very expensive because they're desperately trying to get rid of it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Eat your heart out Oracle.
Speaker 6:  We do have to fight the Chinese government and Larry Ellison, it'll be fine.
Speaker 6:  Do you think at the end to buy TikTok you have to win a boat race against
Speaker 6:  Larry Ellison? He's like, I'll do this. If You can beat me in the
Speaker 6:  America's
Speaker 2:  Cup, let's yacht about it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So I will just say there's a bunch of Disney streaming services that
Speaker 2:  are interesting. ESPN would make us an awful lot of money for a pretty long
Speaker 2:  time. Hulu exists, Disney Plus exists.
Speaker 2:  We could have Apple TV Plus and have all the good shows. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But those are also dependent on external licenses that we might not
Speaker 5:  acquire.
Speaker 2:  True.
Speaker 5:  With our streaming service acquisition. Right. We're not getting the star
Speaker 5:  rights to Star Wars. We
Speaker 2:  Get, we get all the existing contracts. Yeah. But I think you're right. If
Speaker 2:  we get Disney plus we get, we don't get to own Star Wars. You're right.
Speaker 6:  The economics of streaming are very simple. There's a handful of companies
Speaker 6:  who think the Samsung Frame TV will continue to exist. Their business model
Speaker 6:  is they pay a lot of money for content and then try to pay, make people
Speaker 6:  pay money for it. The other model is TikTok
Speaker 6:  gets free content from America's teenagers and then sells ads against it.
Speaker 6:  And not for nothing. An infinite array of pirated movies from the idiots
Speaker 6:  who are paying for content. Yeah. It's, it's gotta be TikTok you just for
Speaker 6:  the, the economics of the business. Like, do you want to have costs or not
Speaker 6:  costs.
Speaker 2:  But again, TikTok not famously making a ton of money right now.
Speaker 6:  Well, 'cause they're, they're, you know, we're, we'll fix that 55%.
Speaker 5:  No, no. It's, it's, we, we do something like deal with Adobe Creative Cloud
Speaker 5:  where we somehow charge our own creators.
Speaker 2:  Well, we're gonna have to, because if we get TikTok, we don't get cap cut.
Speaker 2:  So we're gonna have to immediately put the Creative Cloud team on building
Speaker 2:  cap cut. Yeah. So that people would,
Speaker 6:  But the TikTok video editor is cap cut. So we just spin it out.
Speaker 2:  It's good enough. Yeah. Like it'll work
Speaker 6:  And we call it cut cap.
Speaker 2:  You can probably cut Cap. There we go. All right. TikTok and cut Cap. We've
Speaker 2:  done it. All right. I, I think that's right. I feel good about it. I like
Speaker 2:  briefly wanted to fight for Prime video just because it is like, it's another
Speaker 2:  one that is like, try harder. Oh no. We took Kindle.
Speaker 2:  God. Yeah, we took Kindle. Yeah. The amount of money that cost that taking
Speaker 2:  Kindle has cost us. Good Lord.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it is very funny that we took Kindle and Google Check.
Speaker 5:  That's what we took from those companies. I
Speaker 2:  Will say if, if we want to go back and take Slack and YouTube, we have a
Speaker 2:  chance.
Speaker 5:  No, we're committed.
Speaker 2:  Is there anything cooler than fixing Gchat? Like, that might be the single
Speaker 2:  most important thing we do at this company. I feel really good about it.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  Mean, the teens will prefer us for TikTok.
Speaker 2:  That's true. Okay. So we have, we have two more categories, one of which
Speaker 2:  I just changed two minutes ago and I'm very excited about it. So far. We
Speaker 2:  have the iPhone business from Apple. We have the Kindle
Speaker 2:  business from Amazon, the PC business from Lenovo. We're doing
Speaker 2:  all of Meta's wearables. We haven't decided yet if we're killing the Quest,
Speaker 2:  but we're probably killing the quest. We're all in on the smart glasses.
Speaker 2:  We're taking Sony's audio solutions. We're taking Adobe Creative
Speaker 2:  Cloud. We're taking LG Display and we're taking Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Gchat. Well, we're taking the mess of Google's messaging systems, which I
Speaker 2:  think actually probably means we hire most of Google because everybody's
Speaker 2:  working on messaging in one way or another. And we're, we're, we're making
Speaker 2:  Gchat and then we are saving America and taking over TikTok.
Speaker 2:  How do we feel so far? Feel good? Just
Speaker 6:  How many rules? I'm feeling great.
Speaker 2:  I really feel like it does. Lenovo is still very much the like, weird
Speaker 2:  one out, but we're gonna make Lenovo cool again. It's gonna be great. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We'll fix it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So we have, we have two left. Which one is wild card
Speaker 2:  gadgets, which is, I think the rules still apply. So we can't
Speaker 2:  take from a company we've already taken from, but we can take from any category,
Speaker 2:  including categories we have not talked about. So it's some other product
Speaker 2:  that Vergecast Inc is going to make that is not off limits because we've
Speaker 2:  already taken from another company. We can, we can do TVs. This is where
Speaker 2:  we take the cyber truck. If we wanna take the cyber truck. Anything you guys
Speaker 2:  want? Any initial thoughts? Anything you're excited about?
Speaker 6:  Well, so this is where I was kinda back into taking LGS TVs.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Too
Speaker 6:  Late. But then we already have LG display.
Speaker 2:  I think this is better. We have the part of the business that's like good
Speaker 2:  and not the part of the business that is Web os. I feel really good about
Speaker 2:  LG Display and not lgp.
Speaker 5:  Have you guys heard of a company called Stores and Bickle?
Speaker 2:  Is this how we get into like, I bespoke whiskey?
Speaker 5:  No, this is how we get in. We just get the volcano. They make a whole bunch
Speaker 5:  of different vapes. We just get the volcano business. Okay. And then we,
Speaker 5:  like, we make one that looks really, really cool. We put
Speaker 5:  a big screen on it, put some big speakers on the side. Just a whole
Speaker 5:  one-stop party business.
Speaker 2:  It's just for Alex Krantz.
Speaker 5:  It was just, you know, legalization is coming for this country. True. We
Speaker 5:  gotta, we gotta be there at the st at the start.
Speaker 2:  I'm not feeling that. I gotta tell you. No, I just feel like by, if, if we
Speaker 2:  were in this till 2040, yeah,
Speaker 5:  That makes sense.
Speaker 2:  I'd be down 20, 30. Feels iffy. And that's just like a lot of
Speaker 2:  legislation stuff. All right.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm just, I'm throwing this out there. The Nvidia Shield, we,
Speaker 5:  We, oh yeah. We didn't, didn't do
Speaker 2:  Nvidia
Speaker 6:  Did, we didn't do we we didn't take, we took LG display over NVIDIA's GP
Speaker 6:  business.
Speaker 2:  We're doing really well.
Speaker 5:  This gets us the Tegra. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Why this? Because
Speaker 6:  I, I think between Crans and I, we can communicate with an audience of
Speaker 6:  tv. We can, we can bring the shield back to problem.
Speaker 2:  This is a try harder move. Look,
Speaker 6:  If you look, if you look on the forms right now, people are like the shield,
Speaker 6:  isn't it anymore?
Speaker 2:  It's true. and it was for a long time.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of people who are like, what you wanna do is run infuse on
Speaker 6:  Apple tv. And I think that's, that's a shame.
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Yeah. We're not getting infused.
Speaker 2:  Do we wanna get into the car business is my big question here.
Speaker 6:  No. 'cause I, we, to be a successful car maker, you gotta, you gotta make
Speaker 6:  a shoe, you gotta make a mid-size crossover. And I, that's just not for us.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  But again, we, we, we would take all the infrastructure required to do it.
Speaker 2:  So we'd, we'd be up and running, making Kia Forte's tomorrow.
Speaker 5:  We're not buying Kia. We're
Speaker 2:  Not, we're we're just taking the Forte.
Speaker 5:  I was like, I don't want any part of the Kia Hyundai business. They keep
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 2:  Neli. You don't want the Mustang Mach. This is your moment. Take the Mach
Speaker 2:  e man.
Speaker 6:  It's a shoe. I I'm just telling you, I'm just not, I'm not making a mid-size
Speaker 6:  crossover. Alright. No, thank you. Like, if you're gonna let me be like
Speaker 6:  crazy about it, you know, let's get nuts. But I don't,
Speaker 6:  that business is too, too wackadoo. I, I, I talk to a lot of car CEOs.
Speaker 6:  They're all same. Like, that's what will tear
Speaker 2:  Us apart. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Wait, I thought of it. Okay. Samsung's barely a
Speaker 5:  live digital camera business.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I like getting into the camera business.
Speaker 6:  Ooh. And then we can actually make them smartphones, right? Yeah. We actually
Speaker 6:  take, you do the thing where you make the smartphone mirrorless camera. Exactly.
Speaker 6:  Interesting.
Speaker 5:  Does Samsung still make cameras?
Speaker 2:  Do we want Samsung's though? Or do we want like Fuji's X 100
Speaker 2:  business?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then we, and then the solution is you just make them.
Speaker 2:  Right? Make more of them. Let people buy them. Who would like them? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I like that. I I like taking the camera. That's actually a great idea. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then we fix the software so that it like, doesn't take you 12
Speaker 5:  hours just to change the setting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Sony cameras, but with menus that humans beings can
Speaker 6:  navigate. Yeah. But I, I do think Fuji is like a good, in terms of wild card
Speaker 6:  gadget for our brand especially. And
Speaker 5:  Then we do like a limited release of the iPhone and the Fuji and they have
Speaker 5:  like the same look to 'em. We'd sell a lot of money.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty good. All right. That's good. So we're, we're taking, we're
Speaker 2:  taking Fuji's X 100. All right. Yeah. Yeah. I like it. And
Speaker 2:  then last category, the one I just added a minute ago, I had
Speaker 2:  another non gadget wild card, but I think that's boring. So what we're gonna
Speaker 2:  do instead is we're gonna buy a startup. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I, I know my answer right away. Really?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Really hope it's the same one.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's rivian.
Speaker 2:  Oh, so you want to get into the car business
Speaker 6:  The whole time? Yeah. It was because they don't make a shoe.
Speaker 2:  They also famously lose all the money in the world.
Speaker 6:  Sure. But 55% I can fix it. If you
Speaker 2:  Want a Rivian, you have to buy an iPhone. Rivian
Speaker 2:  are now in app purchases on iPhones.
Speaker 6:  55%.
Speaker 5:  What about like, we could get SSI we could have like just the AI guy.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Just one guy. We're
Speaker 2:  You're,
Speaker 5:  We're already, I
Speaker 6:  Mean in that case, is OpenAI still a startup? 'cause that would be another
Speaker 2:  I was just about to say, I think open AI counts, but
Speaker 6:  You want something, you want like a startup, you want like an earthy.
Speaker 2:  So my vote, if we're buying an AI company, I wanna buy Anthropic. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which is, I would say less valued but also way
Speaker 2:  less problematic. And they're
Speaker 5:  Actually making products, right?
Speaker 2:  Their product is, is moving along fast. They're like kind of right in the
Speaker 2:  mix with Google and Open ai. I don't know that I want to deal with the, like
Speaker 2:  Sam Altman of it all, if I'm being honest.
Speaker 6:  And a CEO is notoriously difficult here. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. So if, if we're going ai and
Speaker 2:  that was one of my instincts, my vote would be anthropic. I also think like
Speaker 2:  a company like Notion would be an interesting one for us to buy potentially
Speaker 2:  a lot of money. There is
Speaker 6:  Notion, a startup. They've been around for a long time. This gets us into
Speaker 6:  like, what is a startup zone? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like, is Stripe still a startup? They're doing pretty well. I like
Speaker 5:  The idea of Anthropic though. Like that is firmly a startup.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And Anthropic counts. I think like
Speaker 5:  Rivian has factories. Is that a startup when it has factories.
Speaker 6:  Fair.
Speaker 2:  It is just a fair point. Pretty much a car company. Yeah. But Neli, the problem
Speaker 2:  is if we buy Rivian, they're gonna, we have six years to convince you to
Speaker 2:  make a shoe. We will convince you to make a shoe.
Speaker 6:  Look, the R three X is very close to a shoe, but it's a, it's
Speaker 6:  a cool shoe. That's all I got for
Speaker 2:  You. So, okay. The, the other anthropic question is, do we wanna be in the
Speaker 2:  AI game? Like, are we, no, we don't need a move.
Speaker 5:  Not really. 'cause then we have to deal with copyright stuff. Neil's got
Speaker 5:  a lot of blogs he's gonna have to write already, like apology blogs. I don't,
Speaker 5:  we don't need more.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Neli is definitely the one testifying in Congress. Right. We're all,
Speaker 2:  we're all on the same page about that. Yeah. I have, I have several other
Speaker 2:  options for You. can I throw some options at you? I love an option. We could
Speaker 2:  buy DJ I another company that might need some saving in America that
Speaker 2:  does some interesting stuff, but not a startup.
Speaker 6:  So you, you, this is now just companies we could buy. Mm.
Speaker 2:  Is it not a startup? It's
Speaker 6:  Super not a startup.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You're probably right. Okay. Fine. That doesn't count. There's the
Speaker 2:  like Canva's and Figma of the world that also are kind of iffy on whether
Speaker 2:  they're startups. But like if we're in the creator world with Creative Cloud,
Speaker 2:  we fold that in the FTC won't allow it. Yeah. But these aren't the rules.
Speaker 6:  Canva is 10 years old and has a $26 billion value. Like, it's just like not
Speaker 6:  a startup. They
Speaker 6:  like, you wanna go? You do. You need some installer shit. Like what's some
Speaker 6:  like weird two person app?
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. Okay. Let's get
Speaker 5:  Carrot.
Speaker 2:  Does Discord count? No. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Not a startup. Like the, if Rivian isn't a startup, none of these other things
Speaker 6:  are startups that you're mentioning.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair enough. I think Anthropic is the best idea I have. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Anthropic is
Speaker 2:  Good. I think I'm buying Anthropic. Yeah. It's like we're gonna like run
Speaker 2:  them off to the side though. They're, we're gonna sort of Instagram anthropic
Speaker 2:  where it's like you do your thing And. if you become really successful, we'll
Speaker 2:  ruin it for you eventually. Yeah. But until then, like you're kind of, this
Speaker 2:  is like your, your problem. And like if you get in trouble, that's your
Speaker 2:  problem and not ours. We're gonna call them like the moonshot factory
Speaker 2:  or whatever.
Speaker 5:  Well I think just having them collab on making Siri not suck would be like
Speaker 5:  huge. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. 'cause we do need Siri to not suck. Yeah. That's pretty important.
Speaker 5:  Big, big change for us.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Alright. and it is welcome to the team Anthropic
Speaker 2:  people.
Speaker 5:  How do you feel about party speakers? Anthropic? How can you make AI
Speaker 5:  accelerated,
Speaker 6:  Make these LEDs blink smarter than ever?
Speaker 2:  We have a lot of audio solutions that are ready for you. Okay. I
Speaker 2:  feel like we've done this. Can I, can I recap for you? Yes. Yes. At Vergecast
Speaker 2:  Incorporated, here are the things that we make now we
Speaker 2:  have the iPhone business. We have the Kindle business and all that that entails.
Speaker 2:  Lenovo PCs are now Vergecast PCs, Meta's whole
Speaker 2:  wearables thing. The Quest and the RayBan Smart Glasses.
Speaker 2:  That's us now. Sony's audio solutions, headphones, party speakers. The whole
Speaker 2:  jam. That's ours now. Yes. Adobe Creative Cloud is our big software
Speaker 2:  app platform Play. LG Display is now ours.
Speaker 2:  We are, we are. Just fing it up for everybody. If you want a TV hit
Speaker 2:  up. The Vergecast. I love this. Yes. That feels right. We are taking over
Speaker 2:  all of Google's messaging shenanigans and turning 'em into Gchat, which might
Speaker 2:  be the single hardest thing we signed ourselves up for
Speaker 6:  Here. This is what kills us. I want to be clear. That's right. It's like
Speaker 6:  the guitarists in the singer start arguing a little bit and then Oasis breaks
Speaker 6:  up. That's messaging. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Joe Biden just gave us TikTok. Yeah. Congrats to us. Big day. We
Speaker 2:  now have Fuji Film's X 100 business and Anthropic is
Speaker 2:  now part of The Vergecast Incorporated. How do we feel? This feels
Speaker 6:  Good. This feels great. This is the right combo of things.
Speaker 6:  We're doing a little bit of good. We're doing a little bit more evil. We're
Speaker 6:  making some money and then we're gonna fix messages.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We are incredibly deep into hardware. Like my only worry
Speaker 2:  is like, should we not have done LG display and pick something that is more
Speaker 2:  like cloud software? ai e No.
Speaker 5:  No, no. Because if we own the hardware, then they all have to do We done
Speaker 5:  ai, we got Anthropic. Yeah, we got anthropic in the iPhone. We,
Speaker 5:  we have all the power.
Speaker 2:  And Anthropic is like, their whole thing is they want to be like a B2B thing.
Speaker 2:  So that's, that could eventually pay dividends for us. And we have
Speaker 5:  Most of Google because we acquired all of Google messaging. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And we're, we're just printing money on increasing creative cloud fees. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Just to be clear,
Speaker 5:  Right. Microsoft is gonna be paying us so much money for their creative cloud.
Speaker 6:  I I think there's money to be had. And again, tiktoks business model is they,
Speaker 6:  they pirate content.
Speaker 2:  What are we gonna do with the TikTok shop? What's our first move with the
Speaker 2:  TikTok shop?
Speaker 6:  Oh, we are 55%. Yeah. Straight up.
Speaker 6:  You wanna transact in the TikTok shop? We're taking the fees.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We just charge outrageous fees there. Except for our own products,
Speaker 5:  in which case we give them. We don't charge a fee at all.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. The self preferencing is going to be out of control. Yeah. On all
Speaker 2:  of these. Like, do you want good Photoshop? You have to use RX
Speaker 2:  100 camera. Otherwise you get bad Photoshop. Really? Sorry.
Speaker 6:  This is actually great. It's like why do these companies act like this? And
Speaker 6:  it's like we're pretending we run the company and we're like, we are gonna
Speaker 6:  be so evil.
Speaker 2:  We started out trying to do a good job and now we're doing this. We're just
Speaker 2:  the most
Speaker 5:  Evil. Lena Khan just waiting behind us All right
Speaker 5:  now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. Well I think we've solved it. I feel like there's, we're,
Speaker 2:  we're easily a trillion dollar company right off the bat here.
Speaker 5:  Immediately.
Speaker 2:  Our website is gonna be sick, by the way. Yeah. That, that's very important
Speaker 2:  to me. We're gonna give all our products cool names and our website is gonna
Speaker 2:  be so tight with like a good, understandable URL scheme.
Speaker 2:  These, these are the things I care about. I'm gonna run the
Speaker 6:  Megabase
Speaker 5:  Every time you type just a,
Speaker 2:  weird thing with me. And thank you as always for listening. As You can tell,
Speaker 2:  we have a lot of thoughts on all this, but I wanna hear yours too. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna put some links in the show notes to coverage we've done of these companies.
Speaker 2:  But