# Transcript
ID: a8262ea3-550b-426f-95e5-1d7ad65cc529
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8412223903097765585/-498330309098942234/s93290-US-4819s-1719911607.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of spatial computing:
The Verge’s David Pierce chats with Victoria Song and Wes Davis about using the Vision Pro for the five months that it's been available to the public. The group details what works, what doesn’t, and what’s next for the device.
Apple Vision Pro review: magic, until it’s not
Apple announces visionOS 2 with 3D photo transformations and an ultrawide Mac display
The Vision Pro isn’t destroying your eyes, but maybe get eye drops
The Vision Pro is a computer for the age of walled gardens
Apple’s Vision Pro team is reportedly focused on building a cheaper headset
The Vision Pro will get Apple Intelligence and ‘Go Deeper’ in-store demos
David chats with the folks at Sandwich Vision, who create Vision Pro apps called Television and Theater, about why they made 3D-rendered versions of CRT TVs in virtual reality.
Sandwich Vision
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (14 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Spatial Computing. I'm
Speaker 2:  your friend, David Pierce, and I am in Bora Bora. I mean, no, I'm not. I'm
Speaker 2:  in my basement where I always am, but I'm in the Apple Vision Pro in
Speaker 2:  one of the immersive environments. and what I've discovered about this thing
Speaker 2:  is that obviously You can turn the Vision Pro all the way down and
Speaker 2:  see your actual surroundings through pass through, or You can turn it all
Speaker 2:  the way up with the digital crown and be in sort of a pure VR
Speaker 2:  environment. But I like to turn on one of the environments, but only to like
Speaker 2:  60%. and what that means now is as I'm looking forward
Speaker 2:  here, I'm seeing my Mac Monitor because I think that's how most people
Speaker 2:  use their Vision Pro is as a monitor for their Mac plus a couple of Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro apps that I've aligned around. And it looks like I'm on
Speaker 2:  the beach, right? I'm in a lounge chair on the beach in Bora Bora. It's delightful.
Speaker 2:  But then if I look off to the side or I look behind me, or
Speaker 2:  I even look kind of down at my desk, I can see my actual
Speaker 2:  surroundings. And that's usually what I need to be able to see in a glance
Speaker 2:  anyway. Like the dog comes charging down the hallway. I need to be able to
Speaker 2:  look and see the dog charging down the hallway. But normally if I'm just
Speaker 2:  looking forward, I get this lovely serene beach environment. It's
Speaker 2:  delightful and I can do it from my basement. It actually like, it feels so
Speaker 2:  silly to talk about this, but it's kind of great. Anyway, the Vision Pro
Speaker 2:  is what I wanna talk about on the show today. So five months ago today,
Speaker 2:  as you're listening to this, on Tuesday, July 2nd, was
Speaker 2:  the launch of The Vision Pro. February 2nd, 2024. That was when it shipped.
Speaker 2:  And regular people started getting to use it. And I thought this might be
Speaker 2:  a good time to just do a check-in. It's been five months. We've heard a lot
Speaker 2:  about new software, we've heard a lot about new hardware developers have
Speaker 2:  gotten a chance to do it. People have gotten to spend real time messing around
Speaker 2:  in this thing. I think the novelty is worn off in a way that's actually really
Speaker 2:  useful. We can just talk about this thing. So that's what we're gonna do.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about what we've been up to in this headset for the last
Speaker 2:  few months. We're gonna talk to some developers about what they've been up
Speaker 2:  to. We're gonna talk about where all of this is headed. Lots to do. I think
Speaker 2:  The Vision Pro has sort of been through the hype cycle and really
Speaker 2:  we've all, in a certain way, kind of forgotten about it. Honestly, it was
Speaker 2:  not a huge hit. It didn't change the world, but I feel like there's
Speaker 2:  still a lot to talk about here. So that's what we're gonna do. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about it. All of that is coming up in just a second. But first,
Speaker 2:  I have to go and fix my hair because dear Lord, you use this thing for 10
Speaker 2:  minutes and your hair looks ridiculous and we just can't have that. Lots
Speaker 2:  of Vision, Pro, isn stuff to do. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  heard a lot about other headsets and glasses, sorts of devices.
Speaker 2:  The RayBan Meta Smart Glasses have been a huge hit, which I think is a really
Speaker 2:  interesting part of the Vision Pro story. There's just a lot going on. This
Speaker 2:  gadget is five months old, which is brand new and also in a certain way,
Speaker 2:  kind of old in the way the tech news world works. But there's still
Speaker 2:  a lot happening. and it feels like whatever is gonna happen here is very
Speaker 2:  early. But I wanted to get some perspective from people who frankly have
Speaker 2:  used this thing more than I have. So I grabbed two of the folks at The
Speaker 2:  Verge who have the most Vision Pro experience, and that is Wes Davis
Speaker 2:  and Vs. Song. They have spent many more hours goofing around at this
Speaker 2:  thing, testing it, using it in their own lives than I have. And so I thought
Speaker 2:  I'd grab them to talk about what they've seen so far, how they've used it,
Speaker 2:  whether they would continue to use it over time, and
Speaker 2:  where it seems like all of this might go next. So let's just get into it.
Speaker 2:  Wes Davis. Welcome To. The Vergecast. Yes. Hello. Good to be here. Vong,
Speaker 2:  welcome back. Thank
Speaker 3:  You for having me.
Speaker 2:  So I wanted to talk to you because you're, you're two of the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro isn people at The Verge, which is, I would say is kind of a dubious
Speaker 2:  distinction at this moment in time. Agreed. But let's just, let's just talk
Speaker 2:  about how you're both using the Vision Pro. And Wes, I wanna start with you
Speaker 2:  because unlike V and Me, you paid the hard earned
Speaker 2:  actual human dollars for your Vision Pro. I'm still
Speaker 2:  paying money for it. I did the bought it with installment
Speaker 2:  payments through my Apple card, so I'll be paying for it
Speaker 2:  for some time. Oh no. So when you bought one, what did you buy it for?
Speaker 2:  What did you think you were getting? I knew that I was getting a product
Speaker 2:  that isn't fully fletched. I knew it was going to
Speaker 2:  be basically a, you know, like a tech demo product. I
Speaker 2:  had read the review, I knew the shortcomings, I knew what I was
Speaker 2:  getting into. I think to be completely transparent, like the reason
Speaker 2:  I wanted to get it is because I hadn't really used a
Speaker 2:  VR thing since the virtual boy, like n Nintendo's,
Speaker 2:  you know, it's been a minute drastic failure. Like I had played
Speaker 2:  with other people's stuff, but I hadn't owned one. You know what I mean?
Speaker 2:  So I kind of wanted to see where, I guess
Speaker 2:  not just where things are, but kind of where they're going, right? Because
Speaker 2:  this is like, it's a little bit ahead of, its, time is not the right word,
Speaker 2:  right? But like, but it's, you know, it's ambitious. The, the
Speaker 2:  tech is pretty ahead as far as like visual clarity
Speaker 2:  and, and all that stuff. The screen's a really high resolution. And
Speaker 2:  did you have a thing that you were like, okay, even if it's
Speaker 2:  terrible at everything, at least it'll do this one thing for me and that'll
Speaker 2:  make it worth it. Did you have one of those in your mind that you're like,
Speaker 2:  if only it's X, yeah, I can live with this purchase? Not
Speaker 2:  really. I was intrigued by the whole, like, let's
Speaker 2:  put a big virtual screen in front of me thing. I have since found out that,
Speaker 2:  that it's nice for certain things, but
Speaker 2:  it does also do things like when you have a gigantic display in front of
Speaker 2:  you, I've never used on a regular basis
Speaker 2:  more than like a 27 inch screen. But when you have a gigantic
Speaker 2:  screen, like blow it up to, you know, the size of a huge HD TV V
Speaker 2:  or projector or whatever, you will miss notifications because
Speaker 2:  like really on Mac Os, they're all just in the top right. And when,
Speaker 2:  when the top right is five miles away from you, you don't see them.
Speaker 2:  You mean like literally in your eyesight? Like, yeah, yeah. The screen is
Speaker 2:  so large. Yeah. Okay. So I don't do that.
Speaker 4:  I feel like I have the exact opposite, really. Experience with that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just feel like I see everything all at once. I just become
Speaker 4:  Michelle, yo everything everywhere, all
Speaker 2:  At once.
Speaker 4:  And I have the power.
Speaker 2:  You have fingers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, with hot dog fingers, or it feels like hotdog finger.
Speaker 4:  It might as well be hotdog fingers. Just 'cause like, I have a lot of problem
Speaker 4:  with it, recognizing my finger gestures. I don't, I have feel like I, every
Speaker 4:  single time, every so often, I have to recalibrate using it. So yes, truly,
Speaker 4:  I just become Michelle, Leo.
Speaker 2:  I mean, there are worse things to become, right? Yeah. It's, it's in certain
Speaker 2:  ways that's the dream. And in other ways, less so. But v
Speaker 2:  what about you? You, you, you acquired this thing basically from Neli. You
Speaker 2:  stole it from him like eight minutes after we published our review in January.
Speaker 2:  Why did you, why did you want to have this thing around?
Speaker 4:  Basically one, you wear it the wearables lady. So
Speaker 4:  that is, it is like, it is a category of wearables and one that
Speaker 4:  I, you know, I like emerging tech a lot, so I'm just curious about it because
Speaker 4:  it also, I wanted to see how it stacks up to the
Speaker 4:  idea of smart glasses and just kind of, I feel like it's part
Speaker 4:  way on the evolution to that. So I just really wanted to kind of
Speaker 4:  dig into it. and it wasn't what I expected in many ways.
Speaker 4:  Like, I, I don't, I think I was expecting something different than a VR headset,
Speaker 4:  even though everyone had said it's, it's just essentially a VR headset and
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. and it, it is a VR headset. It's slightly different though. It's
Speaker 4:  very, it's very Apple is what I'll say when I'm in it. I also have
Speaker 4:  the me Quest three. Yeah. The, the most recent one I have
Speaker 4:  that. So I kind of go back and forth, forth in between them sometimes, and
Speaker 4:  it's just, they're the same, but it's like the same thing written in different
Speaker 4:  fonts. But one of those fonts is comic sands, and the other is like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know what the hypno font is
Speaker 2:  Anymore. It's
Speaker 4:  Comic sands, but what is that? Oh, okay. Yeah. So it's comic sands. So it's
Speaker 4:  just very, I'll let people wonder which one I think is comic sense
Speaker 4:  and which one I think is the hyp new font.
Speaker 2:  I feel like it's very obvious, but that's, yeah. Well, it's good. We'll,
Speaker 2:  we'll leave it mysterious for you. So, okay, so fast forward to now, and
Speaker 2:  Wes, I'm, I'm curious for you two, what do you do when you put on the headset?
Speaker 2:  Like, I feel like we've, it's been long enough. Part of the reason I wanted
Speaker 2:  to do this now is it's been long enough that the, like, I wonder what this
Speaker 2:  is and how it'll work. Is this anything? I would assume that's
Speaker 2:  worn off by now. And now it's like, you don't quite have the like, oh my
Speaker 2:  God, every time you put it on, or the like, ugh, this sucks every time
Speaker 2:  the battery dies. So you're like, you're in a space where You can actually
Speaker 2:  kind of use it as a person. How do you use the Vision Pro now
Speaker 2:  just for cooking? No, I, I use it.
Speaker 2:  I was about to be like, that is the most
Speaker 4:  Exciting answer. I believed you for a
Speaker 2:  Second. I tried it once after reading those Joanna Sterns review, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. Joanna Stern's story. But it's horrible for that. Don't
Speaker 2:  use it for cooking. Not a good cook.
Speaker 4:  We were FaceTiming while you were cooking that one time. Were did
Speaker 2:  We? Okay. I forgot that I,
Speaker 4:  We were FaceTiming in the Vision Pro while you were cooking. That was an
Speaker 4:  experience watching you,
Speaker 2:  It was a bad idea. That was something, yeah, don't, not safe.
Speaker 2:  No, mostly. So I will use it
Speaker 2:  one or two times a week while I'm working.
Speaker 2:  Usually it's like, if I really want to focus on a,
Speaker 2:  something specific, if I'm working on, on, you know, a bigger piece or
Speaker 2:  every now and then, I just, just to try it just to see. But I, I,
Speaker 2:  I'm a three monitor guy, which is stupid, but I am,
Speaker 2:  I've gotten used to it. And so when I have just the one monitor, I'm like,
Speaker 2:  now all my stuff's on top of each other. I can't just look over, I can't
Speaker 2:  put all my apps on all the screens. So there's that. I use it a
Speaker 2:  fair amount actually, to watch stuff I've been catching up on for
Speaker 2:  all mankind, which I never watched before this year. So
Speaker 2:  I've been watching that a bunch. Every now and then I'll think like, hey,
Speaker 2:  like this is basically a movie theater on my face.
Speaker 2:  So like, are there old movies that I never got to see in theater?
Speaker 2:  Things that I missed? So I'll, I'll do that sometimes. So you use it as
Speaker 2:  like a single tasking device. Yeah. And as a, I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  fascinated by this idea that you're like, I have too many screens and when
Speaker 2:  I need to focus I put on a headset. Yeah. Which on one hand sounds
Speaker 2:  so counterintuitive, but it's also a thing I've actually heard a few times
Speaker 2:  from folks that it is like, it is a surprisingly useful
Speaker 2:  focus device. Like why does it work for you? That's harder to
Speaker 2:  explain. I think it's, it's sort of that it zeroes me
Speaker 2:  in. So it's like when I put it on, it's like I get to go into
Speaker 2:  like mentally into a mode where I'm like, like, this is the thing that I'm
Speaker 2:  doing right now, is working on whatever this task is. I,
Speaker 2:  I don't know. It's, it's helpful. I like it for that. Is it worth
Speaker 2:  $3,500 to do that when I could also just get
Speaker 2:  my laptop and like, go do that exact same
Speaker 2:  thing? I, I'm not sure. Although, you know, my laptop is like a tiny
Speaker 2:  little rectangle and this lets me, as I said earlier,
Speaker 2:  have a, you know, 500 mile wide screen. So yeah,
Speaker 2:  it is a very funny thing that like years ago I had a coworker who had a
Speaker 2:  Chromebook that he had rigged up to not run anything other than
Speaker 2:  Google Docs. And he was just like, this is my, this is my typewriter, right?
Speaker 2:  Like, I sit here when I just need to write things and, and like, do you have
Speaker 2:  a hundred other devices that will also run Google Docs? Yes, of course. Absolutely.
Speaker 2:  But there was something about that space that just felt sort of better and
Speaker 2:  saner and more focused to him. But you hear about writers, right? Like
Speaker 2:  yeah, who keep around like Old Max or whatever. Like
Speaker 2:  for the same reason
Speaker 4:  George R. Martin still mad at him.
Speaker 2:  That's funny. Like, I'm sure part of that is just like, this is the comfortable
Speaker 2:  thing that I've been writing my novels on for, you know, decades. I'm not
Speaker 2:  gonna give it up until, you know, it completely dies or whatever.
Speaker 2:  But v what about you? What has been sticky for you over time?
Speaker 4:  Actually, kind of very similar to Wes, when I really need to focus on a draft,
Speaker 4:  like really just, I have a lot of little focus tools on my regular
Speaker 4:  thing because breaking out the Vision Pro, it has to be really
Speaker 4:  intentional for me just because I have really bad eyes. So if I'm
Speaker 4:  wearing glasses, I don't have the zes inserts, so I have to be like, okay,
Speaker 4:  it's time for me to go upstairs and put my contacts in.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow. Yeah. It's like a several step process for you just to be like, it's
Speaker 2:  i's several step. I'm, I'm gonna open up Google Docs in the headset now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I actually think that the most useful thing for me has
Speaker 4:  been actually having a 500 foot Google Docs
Speaker 4:  in front of me just to like really zero in on the words.
Speaker 4:  And actually I write mostly in the CMS. So sometimes it's just
Speaker 4:  the CMS just in front of me with the chaos. Like, just, just
Speaker 4:  really impressing upon me the importance of finishing this draft.
Speaker 2:  Literally the stuff of nightmares.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's a giant nightmare screen and or you know,
Speaker 4:  you know, sometimes I'll watch stuff on there. 'cause I really do think it's
Speaker 4:  like best when you're using it as a screen. It kind of isn't as good
Speaker 4:  in my opinion, when you're using it for the way that I think Apple wants
Speaker 4:  you to use it. It's really just like having an
Speaker 4:  amazingly large screen in front of you. And my problem
Speaker 4:  though, with watching content is the platform of content.
Speaker 4:  Like I think if you have something that you wanna watch on Disney Plus,
Speaker 4:  or the stuff that's, or Apple TV plus that's integrated, oh yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  super easy. But I wanna watch my KDRs because my husband
Speaker 4:  won't watch KDRs with me. And this is a solitary experience.
Speaker 4:  So, you know, going to my crappy streaming Kdr
Speaker 4:  websites where everything is like a one second away from getting
Speaker 4:  malware, it ECTs it into my Vision pro. That's kind of not quite
Speaker 4:  so easy. And then when you do watch it sometimes, like I did watch a little
Speaker 4:  bit of bridgeton through going to Netflix in
Speaker 4:  Safari and in the thing, I was just like, wow, this is
Speaker 4:  too overwhelming. There's just so much happening.
Speaker 4:  You'll like, I don't, I don't know that I feel quite
Speaker 4:  as enamored with it, like a few months on as like a watching
Speaker 4:  medium because I do wanna, I do wanna like text crayons who's the one
Speaker 4:  use the sole reason why I watch Bridgeton and be like, oh my God, the men
Speaker 4:  on this show are stupid. They just need to talk about their feelings. And
Speaker 4:  like, you know, it's so easy when you're just on a TV and You can just pull
Speaker 4:  out your phone and be like, oh, Simon is stupid in Bridgeton. I can't really
Speaker 4:  do that. I have to hold my thoughts and then, then like, tell people afterwards.
Speaker 4:  'cause I could type in Yeah, you just in in the, the actual,
Speaker 4:  yeah, but it's stupid 'cause you have like one finger and typing. Unless
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna, what am I gonna do? Get up from my very comfy daybed and then
Speaker 4:  type into my computer so that Yeah, no, with
Speaker 4:  the, my keyboard just to, to message someone more clearly. Eh, it's, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's not quite as intuitive. You
Speaker 2:  Guys are talking about this sort of singletasking thing. Do you do this in
Speaker 2:  the like immersive environments, VR headset style? Or do you just sit in
Speaker 2:  your own living room with a gigantic screen?
Speaker 4:  I, I sit on the moon. I love this. I sit on the moon just because I'm just
Speaker 4:  like, it's, it's goodbye everybody. Every once in a while, my, every once
Speaker 4:  in a while my cat will just like start touching me while I'm on the
Speaker 4:  moon and that kind of takes me out of the
Speaker 2:  Moon. That is a real thing. Like, cat jumping
Speaker 2:  on you while you're immersed. I'm sorry, I just used that
Speaker 2:  term, but while you have that turned on Yeah. Cat jumping on
Speaker 2:  you. Although I will say that my cat,
Speaker 2:  one of his favorite things to do and it feels very intentional, is to jump
Speaker 2:  in my lap while I'm, you know, holding my phone or my tablet or
Speaker 2:  whatever and be in the way of that. Like, it, it's, oh, absolutely
Speaker 2:  not. Yeah. And he can't do that when I'm using
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro. He has to wedge himself between your thumb and your, your
Speaker 2:  index finger and that's, that's the hook. Yeah. And sometimes he'll kind
Speaker 2:  of like flash, like I'll see little ears flashing into the screen.
Speaker 2:  But as far as like using the immersive stuff, if
Speaker 2:  I'm trying to type it's, I don't know, like trying to find the
Speaker 2:  keyboard is really annoying now. They fixed that in Vision OS two. So if
Speaker 2:  you have the beta You can You can do that and it will recognize a magic
Speaker 2:  keyboard. They say that it's just for magic keyboards. I've gotten
Speaker 2:  it to recognize this NES controller that I have as a keyboard
Speaker 2:  for, for just a few minutes and it would kind of show it when I look down
Speaker 2:  at it again and then it stopped, it figured out I was lying. So I love that
Speaker 2:  the pro tip is just fooling the vision pro. Yeah, that's a good strategy.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely. But no, you're, you're getting ahead of me on some of the software
Speaker 2:  stuff, but one of the things I've heard a bunch of people talking about is
Speaker 2:  that the phone mirroring thing inside of Mac
Speaker 2:  Os inside of the Vision Pro could be a big deal
Speaker 2:  for solving kind of both the problems you're talking about, right? Like the,
Speaker 2:  the Yeah. How do I input while I'm in this space and
Speaker 2:  v like the thing you're describing, which I call like light multitasking
Speaker 2:  is a thing I have thought so much about with the Vision Pro because like,
Speaker 2:  I love going to movie theaters. I go to movie theaters alone all the time
Speaker 2:  to see movies just because I'm not allowed to use my phone. It is the best.
Speaker 2:  And it's just like, I'm gonna sit here, I'm gonna watch this whole movie
Speaker 2:  like a maniac, right? Like I'm gonna just look at the movie the
Speaker 2:  whole time. And, and there is something about the Vision Pro that is really
Speaker 2:  compelling in that way. I found, especially in like the good
Speaker 2:  streaming apps and really it's basically like Disney and like
Speaker 2:  Max a little and that's kind of it. Apple TV's good, but there aren't many.
Speaker 2:  But the ones that are good I have found, I actually like really enjoy watching
Speaker 2:  stuff in. But v I'm with you. Like, if it's a matter of loading up a browser,
Speaker 2:  it just, that doesn't, at that point I'm like, this is worse than watching
Speaker 2:  on my television. What am I doing here?
Speaker 4:  I wish all the stuff that I wanted to watch on my own was in the good apps,
Speaker 4:  but they're not. Yeah. Which is kind of, you know, the whole thing about
Speaker 4:  the loneliness in the Vision Pro. It's, it's a real, I think that's like
Speaker 4:  my biggest problem with it is that I would enjoy it so much more
Speaker 4:  if I had more people to hang out with in there.
Speaker 4:  Otherwise, yeah. Otherwise I'm just kind of like, eh,
Speaker 4:  everyone's out here. Who am I gonna,
Speaker 2:  That tension sort of both sides of that. I I was one of the things I wanted
Speaker 2:  to ask you both about, because you both live in households with other people
Speaker 2:  and also are like big nerds who are online talking to people all
Speaker 2:  the time. For me as a person in a, in a household with other people, I cannot
Speaker 2:  bring myself to wear this around other people. Like, and it, that's probably
Speaker 2:  just a me thing. Maybe I'll get over it. But I'm curious what your experience
Speaker 2:  has been like. Like do you sit on the couch around your, your partner,
Speaker 2:  family, friends, whoever and what?
Speaker 4:  I have been roasted within an inch of my life
Speaker 4:  wearing that thing. I actually wore it in a car one time just
Speaker 4:  to test the truffle mode. I was not driving, oh. Just to be clear, I was
Speaker 4:  not driving. I was the passenger and that was just, that was
Speaker 4:  not fun. The the, the windows were, it was,
Speaker 4:  it was trying to fight me the entire time. 'cause I think it knew that I
Speaker 4:  wasn't supposed to be in a car with that thing. But when I was testing it
Speaker 4:  more frequently, my spouse would walk by, would just look at me and go, oh,
Speaker 4:  I'll talk to you when you're a human again. Oh.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. Bye. Like n no. Or
Speaker 4:  he would go, that is just so cursed because you have the eyesight
Speaker 4:  on the other side and he's just like, that's not, that's not your eyes. That's
Speaker 4:  just, Hmm.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Eyesight's not the solution. It's just not,
Speaker 4:  I get why they did it. I get why they did it. I think it's actually like
Speaker 4:  very oddly human and thoughtful why they did that. Right?
Speaker 4:  'cause eye contact is so, they're actually like talking about the social
Speaker 4:  cues with, by creating that particular feature. But
Speaker 4:  I have not, I have never had a single person go, wow, that's so cool.
Speaker 4:  Can I try it? I've been like, delighted. 'cause most of the people in my
Speaker 4:  life are not huge tech nerd. Like my husband's just,
Speaker 4:  they, he gets so mad seeing it and he's like, why do you have this thing?
Speaker 4:  What is the purpose of this? What is the pur? Meanwhile
Speaker 4:  they love, they love the Meadow RayBan glasses. Like they, they
Speaker 4:  can't stop using them, but they look at me and the Vision pro and they're
Speaker 4:  like, why? Humanity is like, yeah.
Speaker 2:  The one thing that I do kind of in like the common space in
Speaker 2:  the, in the living room is I will go in there because it's the one room
Speaker 2:  that's bright enough and big enough in my house where I can
Speaker 2:  play games on it. Which like, I don't do a lot of,
Speaker 2:  but there, there is one rhythm game, which called synth writers
Speaker 2:  and it's basically beat saber, right? Kind of. It's like you have
Speaker 2:  balls flying at you and you have to catch them in time with the music or
Speaker 2:  whatever. It's stupid. But it's also, I enjoy
Speaker 2:  it. Those games are very fun and, and the good news is you look so cool doing
Speaker 2:  it. You look very cool. Cool. Yeah. And so like every now and
Speaker 2:  then, like my, my wife will come downstairs and
Speaker 2:  walk in and I'm just standing there like doing like all these
Speaker 2:  weird movements, waving my arms around and stuff. But
Speaker 2:  she also has played it and has fun with it. She never asks to play,
Speaker 2:  but if I'm playing and I'm like, do you want to do the thing? And, and then
Speaker 2:  she, you know, often will take me up on it because she
Speaker 2:  also secretly thinks it's fun. But her reaction, she's
Speaker 2:  not as angry I think as or or upset
Speaker 2:  by it. She's not offended by it. She's just like, she'll come in and and
Speaker 2:  just be like, oh look, it's my robot husband. Yeah. I think the, I'll talk
Speaker 2:  to you when you're done in there. Yeah. Reaction is so
Speaker 2:  common and so fascinating because that is like 100% the, the precise
Speaker 2:  thing that Apple was trying to solve. Right? This thing where like, I,
Speaker 2:  and they did so many interesting technical things to make it work. Like the,
Speaker 2:  the thing where a person sort of fades into your view as you come in, like
Speaker 2:  technically incredible. It works shockingly well.
Speaker 2:  It's only alarming, at least for me the first couple of times like, it, it
Speaker 2:  freaked me out pretty legitimately the first couple of times and then I got
Speaker 2:  used to it. But it doesn't, it it fixes the problem for you
Speaker 2:  as the wearer a little bit. But I've had the exact same reaction every time
Speaker 2:  I've been ringing around somebody else that like, as soon as they see me
Speaker 2:  in the headset, it's like, oh, we're not interacting. Like we can't, you're
Speaker 2:  somewhere else. I can't, You can, even if You can see me, even if You can
Speaker 2:  see the space you are somewhere else. We are not going to talk. I wonder
Speaker 2:  if that's because eyesight itself is the problem
Speaker 2:  or if it's because it's just not bright and high fidelity enough. Because
Speaker 2:  you know, when you look at it, it looks like a, like a, like you're looking
Speaker 2:  at one of those hologram cards of, of somebody's like,
Speaker 2:  you know, eyeballs. I think that's
Speaker 4:  Part of it. And just like the uncannyness of it. Sure. At the same time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, just like that really. 'cause you know, like it, it kind of, you see
Speaker 4:  the eyes but it's like, there's like tinge, there's a tinge with blue
Speaker 4:  I think. Yeah. If you're in an app so they know that your full focus isn't
Speaker 4:  there. But unless you sit down with someone and explain to them what that
Speaker 4:  means and they're aware of what those cues are, I think just people
Speaker 4:  are gonna look at that and just go like, Uhuh. Yeah, there's gonna do a big
Speaker 4:  Brendan Frazier and the Mummy just going Uhuh.
Speaker 2:  So let's, let's talk about like where we go next, right? Because I think
Speaker 2:  it is, it is, we're five months in. This thing is brand new. Like every time
Speaker 2:  I talk to people who love the Vision Pro, they're like, what about the iPhone
Speaker 2:  after five months? And like that's true. It's none of it. None of it was
Speaker 2:  any good after five months. So like it's fine. Sure. But Wes, you've
Speaker 2:  been writing a bunch about Vision OS two, which I think my read on Vision
Speaker 2:  OS two is basically like, this is now fixing
Speaker 2:  all the sort of table stakes stuff. It's basically Vision OS
Speaker 2:  one. Now what in there are you excited about? Gimme the rundown. So the thing
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm most excited about is the big curve display thing
Speaker 2:  for the reasons I mentioned earlier. Just not having all the space that I'm
Speaker 2:  used to. And it's weirdly like a lot of the
Speaker 2:  things that they brought in for this version are things
Speaker 2:  that I like, had thought specifically that I
Speaker 2:  wanted. And a curved display was like, I had thought like,
Speaker 2:  you know, we all, well not we all, but a lot of people were saying in forums
Speaker 2:  and stuff, like we want multiple displays and the Vision Pro, why aren't
Speaker 2:  there multiple displays? And one day I was thinking like, why, why do we
Speaker 2:  need multiple displays? It's a virtual environment. Why can't you just have
Speaker 2:  a big, you know, a big long display or whatever. And then they
Speaker 2:  announced that and I didn't expect that. Like I, I thought it was gonna be
Speaker 2:  a multiple display thing, but like why not? Why not have a big curve
Speaker 2:  display thing? Another thing that that I had
Speaker 2:  really wanted was some better ways to get to things
Speaker 2:  in, in the Vision Pro. So like launching the,
Speaker 2:  launching your apps for instance, like the home screen before
Speaker 2:  your two options were to reach up and push the little button on the top,
Speaker 2:  the digital ground. Or you could go into the control center by
Speaker 2:  looking up, hoping you get the little dot, tapping the dot. I hate that
Speaker 2:  so much. Yeah. That whole process, it's like a three step process now.
Speaker 2:  You just like do this funky like little flourish with your
Speaker 2:  hand and I love it. It is like a little, it's it's the very end of a magic
Speaker 2:  trick kind of vibe. Yeah, it is. You're just like, you, you flourish your
Speaker 2:  hand. Yeah. And there's a little dot that shows up right here. It's
Speaker 2:  shows up pretty reliably and then you tap your fingers together and you've
Speaker 2:  got your home screen. It's easy. And then while you're doing that, if you
Speaker 2:  want to quickly check the time or the battery, which is
Speaker 2:  like not a thing You can do normally. I mean You can by
Speaker 2:  again looking up and finding the dot. But it's not, I don't know, it's not
Speaker 2:  as, somehow it's different than this motion, which is just like
Speaker 2:  turning your hand over. And I kind of likened it when I
Speaker 2:  wrote about it before to, to being like turning your hand to look at your
Speaker 2:  wrist to see what time it is. I don't know if that's what they were going
Speaker 2:  for, but it's what I immediately thought and they, you know, that,
Speaker 2:  that seems aply right? To kind of think about it that way.
Speaker 2:  And that will show you the time, the battery level and You can tap there
Speaker 2:  to get to the control center or You can tap and hold to like change the volume,
Speaker 2:  stuff like that. Just bringing in easy quick gestures
Speaker 2:  to do stuff inside of the
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro, get to menus and and all that stuff instead of having to go through
Speaker 2:  all this rigamarole. I would love it if there was like a way to get to settings
Speaker 2:  for instance, that way too. Because this being a new product,
Speaker 2:  I'm still, you know, months later constantly going and and
Speaker 2:  changing settings. Right? Just tweaking little things. And I do
Speaker 2:  that anyway on all of my devices. But you know, it's just, it's more
Speaker 2:  pronounced on the Vision Pro. How often do you guys use Siri on the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro? Because I feel like my answer to all of the weird UI stuff is I just
Speaker 2:  yell at Siri. I use Siri three times as much on the Vision Pro is on any
Speaker 2:  other Apple device. I am surrounded by home pots. Oh, fair enough.
Speaker 2:  And phones and all kinds of things. I do use it and it does
Speaker 2:  seem to prioritize the Vision Pro, but my
Speaker 2:  experience over the last several years of using like the
Speaker 2:  Apple Home stuff has been that like, while it has
Speaker 2:  improved, it's still frequently enough
Speaker 2:  misunderstands Siri still sucks is what you're saying. Siri. Like
Speaker 2:  I, my phone is not like, still doesn't have Siri turned on
Speaker 2:  because of that. Like, if I want Siri on my phone, same, I will press the
Speaker 2:  button.
Speaker 4:  I use Siri most while driving. And even then half the time when I'm driving
Speaker 4:  it's like, no, that's not what I asked. Oh my God, stop. And some of that
Speaker 4:  is just me. Like I have to, I have to like know what I wanna ask and how
Speaker 4:  I wanna ask it in a way that the voice assistant is gonna understand.
Speaker 4:  And I'm not too good at that because I just word vomit half the time
Speaker 4:  what I want. So it's not like a coherent sentence. I feel like you have to
Speaker 4:  say, you know, Siri. See, I don't even know what to
Speaker 4:  say in a fake Siri prompt besides like setting
Speaker 4:  timers before that. I'm just like, it's like Siri and then my brain like
Speaker 4:  buffers. I'm like, what do I want her to do? How should I say that? That
Speaker 2:  Brain Buffer thing is real. Oh yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like, that's my main issue with it and it's why I don't, but it's
Speaker 4:  frustrating 'cause when I'm in there and I am on Safari and I'm, you know,
Speaker 4:  trying to type, I go like, oh, it would be so much easier if I could just
Speaker 4:  talk to, to Siri and do it and then I'll look at the microphone and
Speaker 4:  try and tap. Yeah. and it just not working. And so then I just give up and
Speaker 4:  then I, and yeah, so that's, that's my
Speaker 2:  Issue. I will say though, like, yeah to your point David, like opening
Speaker 2:  apps that way is actually like, I, I do do that somewhat frequently.
Speaker 2:  The part of the reason that I don't is because I'm always
Speaker 2:  forgetting the name of Vision Pro apps. Mm. 'cause they have weird names
Speaker 2:  sometimes. And then other times it's like until recently until Vision
Speaker 2:  OS two you couldn't rearrange the home apps and now You can. That's another
Speaker 2:  thing I'm excited about. I guess like, I don't know, like it feels
Speaker 2:  weird to say I'm excited about that so much of Vision OS two is like,
Speaker 2:  now You can copy and paste on the iPhone, right? It's like, yeah, okay great.
Speaker 2:  That is good and useful and hooray and also Absolutely. How on earth did
Speaker 2:  this not exist until now? Yeah. And you still can't, like, as far as I
Speaker 2:  know and v if you've figured out how to do this, but I don't think You can
Speaker 2:  make folders in inside the home. There is a folder
Speaker 2:  for iPad apps that's already there. Right. And you have to use it like
Speaker 2:  it came with Vision Os but you can't make more. And that drives me
Speaker 2:  nuts because like, I don't like, like on my iPhone, I have it
Speaker 2:  very intentionally set up where most of my apps live in
Speaker 2:  the library and only a few are actually on my home screen
Speaker 2:  in any way. And it's organized so that I only
Speaker 2:  have the things that like, that I use regularly.
Speaker 2:  So like my podcast app is there and my books app,
Speaker 2:  stuff like that. Otherwise it's like everything else is shoved over in the
Speaker 2:  app library. I will search for it when I want it. I don't want it there.
Speaker 2:  Like I don't want TikTok on my home screen being like, do you wanna watch
Speaker 2:  some videos?
Speaker 4:  How responsible of you.
Speaker 2:  But like with the Vision Pro, you can't do that. There's no app library.
Speaker 2:  It is the app library. It, it's very old school
Speaker 2:  iPhone in that way. It's just pages and pages of apps and
Speaker 2:  thankfully You can re rearrange them, but that's annoying too. This
Speaker 4:  The whole app experience in the Vision Pro has been annoying. How so? Like
Speaker 4:  downloading them, it takes forever to download something. Like, it just,
Speaker 4:  you're just waiting and then by the time it's downloaded, I forget that
Speaker 4:  it's there. So it takes me a while to go back and find the new app
Speaker 4:  or something. And like with Wes said, it's just like having to find stuff
Speaker 4:  like I'm, I'm, I don't know. It's, it's, it's just easier to
Speaker 4:  do it on my phone sometimes. And then sometimes the apps that are
Speaker 4:  in there, I I am just like that this, this is, this was not
Speaker 4:  what I was promised. I was in the Zillow app in there and it's not, that's
Speaker 4:  not what I wanted from a Zillow app on the Vision Pro.
Speaker 2:  I wanna talk about the Zillow app in a minute, but I'm curious. V can you
Speaker 2:  actually read your phone? Because I'm want, like I can't.
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. Like, I mean, I could, if I s like I have really bad eyes. Like
Speaker 4:  I don't know if this is useful because my eyesight is garbage, but like I
Speaker 4:  have tried looking at my phone and it's just kind of, I have to squint and
Speaker 4:  I'm already like, so my eyes are already dry in the Vision pro
Speaker 4:  because my eyes are so wide on the inside and like I'm wearing contacts,
Speaker 4:  which is extra drying and so then I have to squint really hard to look at
Speaker 4:  my phone. So it's just not worth it really. Yeah. And I still can't wear
Speaker 4:  it for very long at a time. Like I, I I think Wes you said
Speaker 4:  you figured out how to wear it for like two plus hours. Like I, I have to
Speaker 4:  tap out after an hour. Like, it doesn't matter how I
Speaker 4:  arrange it on my head, it doesn't matter what strap I'm using, just after
Speaker 4:  a while I really feel it. So I kind of have to take it off.
Speaker 2:  And it's not that way for me every time. Most of the time I can
Speaker 2:  legitimately get away with wearing it for an hour or two hours. I've,
Speaker 2:  I've gone even longer than that. Not all day, or at least I haven't tried
Speaker 2:  it all day. It took a while to get to that. Like it took a lot of fiddling
Speaker 2:  with the strap. Like I still, I still use
Speaker 2:  the solo thing. I tried the other, the one that's supposed to be the
Speaker 2:  comfortable one for a while and it made the top of my head numb and
Speaker 2:  that bothered me. So, so I switched back and I figured out a way to make
Speaker 2:  it work. But I think you've written about this the
Speaker 2:  just about like how personal wearables are, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And now like, like especially with like, with like smart
Speaker 2:  rings and stuff like that, just every, every single
Speaker 2:  person's body is different and you know, I might be able to
Speaker 2:  wear the vision pro all day, maybe who knows why. Maybe, maybe
Speaker 2:  I have like an extra fat forehead or something and it's just got a lot of
Speaker 2:  padding there. I don't know. We had Parker, who's our, our product person,
Speaker 2:  like went through hell to get that thing, to like to fit his
Speaker 2:  face. Yeah. Whereas me, I got lucky, but it, it took a while. Like
Speaker 2:  at first it was like, you know, it would press too hard here or press too
Speaker 2:  hard here or it felt heavy. My neck hurt from wearing
Speaker 2:  the thing. I don't know if I just have an extra strong, like back of
Speaker 2:  my neck now or, or what, but like most of those issues are gone.
Speaker 4:  I actually will lie down wearing it. Yeah. If I try to, if I
Speaker 4:  have to wear it for a longer period of time because it just like relieves
Speaker 4:  the pressure from the top of my head and like the tightness around it, I,
Speaker 4:  it's, I have flat cheekbones so you know, there's
Speaker 4:  no actual bone support to lift this thing, so I
Speaker 4:  have to like tighten it around my face. And so I think that's part of the
Speaker 4:  reason why I have no, like, I have no bone structure with which
Speaker 4:  to hold this thing up. And that is like a thing with wearables, like your
Speaker 4:  face, everybody's face is gonna be structured differently. And like with
Speaker 4:  the glasses, it's, it's the nose bridge again. I have a flat face, I have
Speaker 4:  a flat nose bridge. I have nothing to hold these things up. So if there's
Speaker 4:  no supportive structure in there, I, it just slides down my face all the
Speaker 4:  time. So I don't have a face made to wear it comfortably, but I
Speaker 4:  do so for the blog. So
Speaker 2:  It's important to sacrifice sacrifices. Yeah. As, as somebody with very good
Speaker 2:  vision and ample nose. I suppose the
Speaker 2:  thing that always gets me is just like my, my eyes
Speaker 2:  get tired at the end of it. And wes like, that's the thing that is most
Speaker 2:  surprising to me. Like I can fight through the, you know, my head
Speaker 2:  hurts thing. Like do you guys ever see the tiktoks of the people who have
Speaker 2:  the, the dent in their, he from wearing headphones all the time? Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  I'm convinced the Vision Pro isn gonna end up doing that to me. But I can
Speaker 2:  soldier through all of that, but I get like physically exhausted
Speaker 2:  just from looking at this stuff all the time. And I think to some extent
Speaker 2:  that's just like, it's just the light in your eyes all the time. Like if
Speaker 2:  I sat close to my tv, watched it for hours at a time, it
Speaker 4:  No, no, no. I actually talked to ophthalmologist, it's on The Verge dot com
Speaker 4:  about is it dangerous to have a screen that close to your face? And the answer
Speaker 4:  is not really the, like that's a myth about having the screen so
Speaker 4:  close to your eyes. It's actually that your eyes are just open for too long.
Speaker 4:  You're not blinking as much. Oh, interesting. So your eyes become less hydrated
Speaker 4:  and that's can, that can cause like burst blood vessels in your eyes.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's benign generally.
Speaker 2:  I had a friend in high school who used to play doom so
Speaker 2:  much that he would come to school with burst blood vessels in his eyes because
Speaker 2:  he would forget to blink for hours at a time. Shout out to him.
Speaker 4:  So you do, you do need to be putting the eyedrops in your eyes if you're
Speaker 4:  prone to, prone to dry eye. And it's like also again, with me, with
Speaker 4:  my contacts, contacts are drying. So because the the,
Speaker 4:  the display is so stimulating, you're just gonna blink less. You're not gonna
Speaker 4:  be blinking normally as you would in there. So that, I do think that the
Speaker 4:  eye fatigue is a thing that we haven't necessarily talked about because you
Speaker 4:  know, you're in an immersive environment every so often. Are you gonna hit
Speaker 4:  pause to like just open, oh like take off the
Speaker 4:  thing, squirt in some eyedrops and then put it,
Speaker 2:  You should build that into the vision pro. It's like the opposite of the
Speaker 2:  thing in the watch that expels the water. It just flushes water into your
Speaker 2:  eyes every 20 minutes. So just
Speaker 4:  Flush water and choose the saline solution because I, you know, that is eye
Speaker 4:  hygiene. There there is like, like good health and good practices
Speaker 4:  that you have to use with these devices that we don't always do. So like
Speaker 4:  the screen distance, like talk to actual ophthalmologists. The screen distance
Speaker 4:  is not the problem. It is the fact that you are not blinking that can cause
Speaker 4:  actual eye strain and that's not great for you. So it's,
Speaker 4:  there's, they said 20 20, 20 every 20 seconds. Look 20 feet away
Speaker 4:  for
Speaker 4:  I think 20 seconds. Every 20 minutes. Look 20 feet away for 20 seconds. That's
Speaker 4:  what it is. But you can't do that in a vision pro,
Speaker 2:  Right? 'cause it's all an inch and a half away. It's fair.
Speaker 2:  I do have to say one thing that I thought of earlier. I, right
Speaker 2:  now I'm, I I I'm building a bicycle from a frame,
Speaker 2:  that old frame that I had and I realized I didn't have
Speaker 2:  the measurement of something and I don't own calipers. There's an app in
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro called Hand calipers. There you go. Did you put,
Speaker 4:  Did you put calipers on in virtual reality?
Speaker 2:  The, you don't put them on, you hold your fingers up and two little dots
Speaker 2:  show up and it shows the measurement between your fingers and it's
Speaker 2:  delightful. And I used it and it gave me an accurate measurement.
Speaker 2:  And that's all I want to say. They are going to make a Vision Pro commercial
Speaker 2:  about you tomorrow. Yeah. I hope they do.
Speaker 4:  Somewhere, somewhere the vision of Vision Pro team, someone's screaming with
Speaker 4:  Joy saying yes, they used it the way I want.
Speaker 2:  Oh, it's nobody on the Vision Pro team. It's just some guy who made me up
Speaker 2:  as far as I could tell. But, but that's, that's the stuff, right? Like you
Speaker 2:  talk about spatial computing, like that is, that is the stuff and there need
Speaker 2:  to be a million more things like that. But that is if if this stuff is ever
Speaker 2:  going to be the thing, it's things like that. But David's like when
Speaker 2:  you were talking about like not ever wanting to wear the Vision Pro around
Speaker 2:  people. Like I had to walk out to my garage, which is a separate building
Speaker 2:  holding the Vision Pro and I was like holding it on the side of my body
Speaker 2:  so that like my neighbors wouldn't see me.
Speaker 2:  I have to go to Home Depot this afternoon and I'm gonna bring the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro and just wander the aisles holding stuff up to the Vision Pro just to
Speaker 2:  see what happens. See how quickly they can get kicked outta the store. It's
Speaker 2:  gonna be great. But, okay. Other than calipers, so there are two great uses
Speaker 2:  for the Vision Pro. There's calipers, big screens and hand calipers.
Speaker 2:  The big screen thing is really interesting to me 'cause I think that's where
Speaker 2:  most people have landed, right? Whether you use it as a, as a big giant display
Speaker 2:  for your Mac or as kind of a, a personal television, it's a
Speaker 2:  big screen. What, what goes on it? Who knows? It's a big screen but then
Speaker 2:  there's all these rumors about like, okay the thing Apple is doing and
Speaker 2:  Mark Kerman at Bloomberg has been reporting this over and over is trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out how to make these things cheaper. And the way that Apple seems
Speaker 2:  to be making it cheaper is by making the screens worse. That
Speaker 2:  that apparently the pixel density of the next vision device
Speaker 2:  might be half of what the current one is. And on the one hand
Speaker 2:  that makes absolute perfect sense. These screens are ridiculous. This is
Speaker 2:  how you get it to be this good. It's also why it's this expensive. Like it's
Speaker 2:  why it takes so much power on and on and on. Does that work, like if you
Speaker 2:  take away the fact that this is such a good screen on your face, does the
Speaker 2:  cheaper version of this become more compelling or does it become less compelling
Speaker 2:  because you've just made the only really great feature half as good?
Speaker 2:  I don't know, I'm so torn. What do you guys think? I think it depends, right?
Speaker 2:  I'm torn If it's lighter, if it's more comfortable,
Speaker 2:  if the interaction still works as well.
Speaker 2:  You know that thing where, you know, if you go back and you watch
Speaker 2:  like a, you know A DVD even on the right screen, like maybe
Speaker 2:  a 10 80 P TV or whatever, you kind of forget that it's
Speaker 2:  lower resolution for the most part until like some text shows up and You
Speaker 2:  can see all the like aliasing around it or whatever. I wonder if
Speaker 2:  that could be the case with the Vision Pro two, not
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro two, but the Vision Pro Cheap whatever, whatever they call
Speaker 2:  it. Oh
Speaker 4:  Like Light se Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro isn se Yeah, you Vision Pro, isn se they
Speaker 4:  Should, I just kind of wonder, doesn't that just make it a Metas three?
Speaker 4:  Right. And if that's the case, yeah,
Speaker 2:  So they'd have to be really good at
Speaker 2:  all. The other stuff.
Speaker 4:  I was using them kind of concurrently for a while and I would go
Speaker 4:  into the, to the, you know, the Meta Quest three and I'd be like, oh my God,
Speaker 4:  it's so much lighter, it's so much easier to use. There's so many more things
Speaker 4:  to do. And then I'd be in the app and I'm like, dang, this is pixelated.
Speaker 4:  You know, so that would kind of just be like a, you know,
Speaker 4:  I can get around it. It's not the end of the world, but it is a thing that
Speaker 4:  it's just like, okay then what does, what is setting it apart?
Speaker 4:  Because like right now what's setting it apart is the screen, the pass through
Speaker 4:  is just like, oh wow, this is a noticeable noticeably better. And those
Speaker 4:  experiences, like I, I don't know, I don't know. It would have to set
Speaker 4:  itself apart besides being chief.
Speaker 2:  Part of the problem I think is like, I think, I think it was the Germond
Speaker 2:  report from this weekend. I wanna say that
Speaker 2:  he, he said that it might actually be an even like
Speaker 2:  less field of view. It might not have been goman, but like if, if that's
Speaker 2:  the case, if it's lower resolution and it's like s you know,
Speaker 2:  suddenly you, you don't have that impressive thing to look at. Then
Speaker 2:  abruptly, the $500 me Quest
Speaker 2:  three versus the maybe
Speaker 2:  $2,000 Vision Pro, like the calculus is suddenly
Speaker 2:  like really wonky. 'cause like the experience inside
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro would have to be significantly better than a MedQuest
Speaker 2:  three or four or whatever.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I don't know that compromising on the screen is the right move
Speaker 4:  so much as making the materials lighter. Yeah. And cheaper because like
Speaker 4:  isn't it made out of some, like, I forget what exactly it's made of, but
Speaker 4:  you have actual glass on the, on the front of the, I
Speaker 2:  Mean it's metal and glass. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's, that is, that's heavy.
Speaker 2:  Well and the Quest three is not that much lighter right. Than the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro. Like really
Speaker 4:  It's li it's significantly lighter. It's so much easier for me to wear
Speaker 4:  and it's because the weight distribution, it's not so front heavy. The Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro is very front heavy and it's all that glass and I
Speaker 4:  kind of think that is sort of it, it has a very premium
Speaker 4:  feel when you touch it because Apple, right, everything, apple makes premium
Speaker 4:  feel super lux or whatever. You could just make it less lux
Speaker 4:  and keep the thing that makes it really special. Which I think is the screen.
Speaker 4:  Or try to keep that as, as close to possible. I don't know if that's possible,
Speaker 4:  but if I were gonna make this thing cheaper, which you should make it cheaper
Speaker 4:  because it's more fun when more people you know are in there. I, I don't
Speaker 4:  know if that's the right move. I think the right move would be make it lighter
Speaker 4:  and feel cheaper.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean take the glass off like it can still feel good
Speaker 2:  without having a big, just get
Speaker 4:  Rid of eyesight. Nobody needs that really. I
Speaker 2:  Actually agree with that. Yeah. Put googly eyes on the front of it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Honestly I think people would have more fun if you just put giant googly
Speaker 4:  eyes. You know what we, we really will make it like everything everywhere
Speaker 4:  all at once. Just put giant googly eyes on the front. Absolutely. I can pretend
Speaker 4:  I'm a rock
Speaker 2:  Perfectly in keeping with Apple's entire design ethos and branding
Speaker 2:  too. It makes sense. I really like, I never thought I would sit on this podcast
Speaker 2:  and try to convince Apple to make a plastic gadget, but like here we are.
Speaker 2:  It's it, it would probably be better if it were a plastic gadget.
Speaker 4:  It probably would be just because the wearability, I like I I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna say this until I'm blue in the face with a wearable device, it
Speaker 4:  has to be wearable. If you're not going to wear it, it's
Speaker 4:  not successful. So if making it plastic means
Speaker 4:  that more people will wear it, not only because it's more comfortable but
Speaker 4:  because it's cheaper. Make it plastic. Just do it or
Speaker 2:  Titanium. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  Is that gonna lower the price Wes? Because we also have to lower the price.
Speaker 2:  No, it's okay. Wes is paying for this thing every month. Just make it $5,000.
Speaker 2:  Wes won't even notice. It'll be fine. Oh God.
Speaker 2:  Well that is a good note to end on. We're gonna get via cheaper one. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna get we and more expensive one and everybody's gonna be happy. It all
Speaker 2:  works out. $10,000. Love it. Let's take it to the moon. Thank you both.
Speaker 2:  Thanks.
Speaker 4:  Alright, thanks for having us.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and get a bit
Speaker 2:  of a different perspective on what it's like to make
Speaker 2:  stuff for and live inside Vision Pro. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Have a question or need how to advice. Just ask meta
Speaker 3:  AI whether you want to design a marathon training program that will get you
Speaker 3:  race ready for the fall. Or you're curious what planets are visible in
Speaker 3:  tonight's sky. Meta AI has the answers.
Speaker 3:  Perhaps you want to learn how to plant basil when your garden only gets
Speaker 3:  indirect sunlight. Meta AI is your intelligent assistant.
Speaker 3:  It can even answer your follow-up questions like what You can make with your
Speaker 3:  basil and other ingredients you have in your fridge. Meta AI
Speaker 3:  can also summarize your class notes, visualize your ideas and so
Speaker 3:  much more. The best part is You can find meta AI right in the apps
Speaker 3:  you already have Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook,
Speaker 3:  and Messenger.
Speaker 2:  the 1950s. It can be this tall teal thing right out of
Speaker 2:  the Jetsons. It can be one of those big flat screen TVs with those huge
Speaker 2:  speakers on the sides. Lots of things. Whatever set you pick, you then
Speaker 2:  plop the set down in your physical space and then then You can put
Speaker 2:  whatever kind of video you want on it. You can stream stuff that you've
Speaker 2:  shot. You can play stuff from YouTube, all kinds of stuff. It's just a
Speaker 2:  television. I like the app because it's charming, but also because it's the
Speaker 2:  kind of thing that could only work on a device like the Vision Pro. It
Speaker 2:  would seem like ridiculous kind of kitschy skew, morphic design
Speaker 2:  on an iPad or a TV screen. We've actually seen things like this on those
Speaker 2:  devices and it always seems like kitschy and dysmorphic, but when it's a
Speaker 2:  physical seeming object that You can actually walk around and place in space,
Speaker 2:  it's just more fun. And since the TV stays right where you left it,
Speaker 2:  I kind of use it like a background tv like you might find in a waiting
Speaker 2:  by a company called Sandwich, which you might know from the super deadpan
Speaker 2:  and fun commercials it's been making for a long time.
Speaker 2:  I talked to three of the folks at Sandwich, all of whom worked on the app.
Speaker 7:  I'm Adam Lis Gore. I'm the founder of Sandwich in the context of Sandwich
Speaker 7:  Vision, the Vision OS App Studio. I would say I'm the creative director.
Speaker 2:  My
Speaker 8:  Name's Dan Stear. I am the visual effects supervisor at Sandwich.
Speaker 9:  I'm Andy Roth and I'm the engineer on both television and theater.
Speaker 2:  Oh, right. To Andy's point, they also just made an app called theater, which
Speaker 2:  is similar to television except instead of putting a funky old TV in your
Speaker 2:  living room, it sends you to a big immersive movie theater style place.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, I asked the Sanders team to go back to the beginning a bit, to even
Speaker 2:  before the app existed, even before the Vision Pro was really a thing people
Speaker 2:  could buy and tell me about what it takes to dream up, build,
Speaker 2:  ship, and sell a Vision Pro app. Adam said the idea came to him
Speaker 2:  kind of out of nowhere.
Speaker 7:  Personally speaking, six months ago I did not assume I
Speaker 7:  was gonna be building for the platform. I was just not in software development
Speaker 7:  Headspace at all. I didn't become activated until I was sitting
Speaker 7:  down. I'm working on another startup sort of more in the SaaS space and
Speaker 7:  my co-founder had not really had experience with VR that much and I have
Speaker 7:  a MedQuest at home. I've been a, I was a DK one user, an Oculus DK one
Speaker 7:  user early on, so I've been paying attention and tracking the space but never
Speaker 7:  thought it was worth developing for. The Vision Pro had been announced, my
Speaker 7:  co-founders WA was curious and he said, you have a MedQuest, let see how
Speaker 7:  it's changed since the one time I used it. So we spent kind of
Speaker 7:  half a day just exploring different things in the MedQuest platform
Speaker 7:  and it was fun to see him get activated again. And then we started talking
Speaker 7:  about Vision Pro that was coming and just wondering what are things, what
Speaker 7:  things are gonna happen in this space? And then that night I kind of was
Speaker 7:  laying in bed and I just kind of like my imagination started
Speaker 7:  popping off and I started writing down app ideas in terms of just thinking
Speaker 7:  what does this device make possible that the other devices don't make possible?
Speaker 7:  How can we take advantage of our space? Like what? At that point spatial
Speaker 7:  computing as the nomenclature was kind of a laugh, right? It felt like
Speaker 7:  a branded Apple thing that they were making up just to differentiate and
Speaker 7:  not say VR 'cause they're contrarians, which I, and I love that about them
Speaker 7:  of course. So what is spatial computing? What does that
Speaker 7:  mean? It means using the space of the world
Speaker 7:  around you as your display, as your you, your interaction
Speaker 7:  model with the software and then suddenly starting to think about,
Speaker 7:  okay, what can happen when computer stuff happens in your space
Speaker 7:  that can't happen when it's on the black rectangle. That's where
Speaker 7:  my imagination started really going into overdrive because
Speaker 7:  we're filmmakers at Sandwich and we think in terms of that 2D
Speaker 7:  rectangle and then obviously in non spatial
Speaker 7:  computing we think in terms of the 2D rectangle, even the people who have,
Speaker 7:  you know, their whole desk is filled with displays that in vertical and
Speaker 7:  horizontal orientations. So like what does it
Speaker 7:  mean when you see past the black rectangle and the world is your display?
Speaker 7:  And then that's when we started, I started dreaming up the television app
Speaker 7:  and that's when I got in touch with Andy and you know, sort of just lucked
Speaker 7:  into meeting Andy and explained the idea to him.
Speaker 2:  Andy, do you remember what the explanation was? I'm trying to imagine how
Speaker 2:  like the four sentence pitch of what television is.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think it was basically, let's throw some old school
Speaker 9:  3D TVs in your space and You can watch anything. And I was like, all right,
Speaker 9:  I'm sold pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Were you into all the headset vr,
Speaker 2:  ar stuff at the time?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I've been into VR for a few years. I had been doing development for
Speaker 9:  the Quest for a while in both Unity and Unreal and I've just been
Speaker 9:  anticipating Apple's headset for a few years now, just waiting to
Speaker 9:  see what they could bring to the table and do differently than
Speaker 9:  the other headsets.
Speaker 2:  Like even before it launched. And before you started building, like had you
Speaker 2:  seen what the Vision Pro was? Were you like convinced this was the one like
Speaker 2:  this They're they've done the thing.
Speaker 9:  I'm still not convinced it's the one. Okay.
Speaker 2:  But fair enough. I'm with you on that.
Speaker 9:  But it's, it's definitely an interesting approach to
Speaker 9:  spatial computing and it's something that I've just been interested in since,
Speaker 9:  since they announced it.
Speaker 2:  And then Dan, where did you come into the picture?
Speaker 8:  I think in, in those early conversations with Adam, the, the filmmaker
Speaker 8:  storytelling side of the device, like, it, it, it's kind of our
Speaker 8:  responsibility to understand the technology that we're
Speaker 8:  telling stories about and to a certain point getting ahead of it because
Speaker 8:  we're kind of assuming that there's gonna be more vision os developers who
Speaker 8:  are gonna come to us to help tell that spatial computing story. And we don't
Speaker 8:  wanna be guessing at what that's like. We, we wanna know what it's like intimately
Speaker 8:  to, to use the device and what, what are the, what are the amazing parts
Speaker 8:  of it? What does it feel like to use, what's the stuff that's going to really
Speaker 8:  attract people to a product? And that really
Speaker 8:  starts with us using it. You know, we saw all the, the videos that Apple
Speaker 8:  released and that's great and it shows what it can do, but there's no way
Speaker 8:  to prepare you for what it feels like when you first put it on. I mean
Speaker 8:  even in our very early tests with 3D models that didn't have video on
Speaker 8:  them, 'cause I'm not a VR guy, I've never really been a VR guy, but when
Speaker 8:  I put this thing on and I started manipulating a 3D TV in my space,
Speaker 8:  like it was incredible. Like I, I've never felt anything like that before.
Speaker 8:  It's just like I stood up and I walked in a circle around A 3D TV in my office
Speaker 8:  and it's like what is this? Like this is incredible. So you know, getting
Speaker 8:  our feet on the ground like which is Vision os in general was where we started
Speaker 8:  and then what does that enable? What are the, what are the parts of this
Speaker 8:  that we want it to look like? Like what, what is our ideal version of this
Speaker 8:  app? You know, what are the things that we wish it could do? That sort of
Speaker 8:  stuff. That's where we started. I think Adam you just reminded me. We were
Speaker 8:  texting, I think it was a Saturday about this idea and you had one of the
Speaker 8:  models, I think it was the streamline media stand or whatever and you texted
Speaker 8:  it to me and I was sitting in a chair watching my kid play and I put my iPhone
Speaker 8:  up in AR mode and I put the TV over there and I just kind of turned and saw
Speaker 8:  a TV and then turned back to my kid and I was like, yeah that's awesome.
Speaker 8:  I want that. I just wanna have a TV over there to the side of my room and
Speaker 8:  there'll be stuff on it.
Speaker 2:  At this point, again, I should mention the Vision Pro wasn't for sale. All
Speaker 2:  the Sandwich guys had, all anyone had was a simulator that they could
Speaker 2:  use to get a rough idea of how it might work. So the
Speaker 2:  team here started with an off the shelf 3D model of a retro tv
Speaker 2:  just kind of spinning it around and seeing how it picked up light and if
Speaker 2:  it felt sort of realistic in this virtual space inside a simulator
Speaker 2:  on a computer screen. That worked pretty well Adam said. So then
Speaker 2:  they were off to the races, they found more TV types, sent them to
Speaker 2:  Dan to turn into 3D models and basically tried to figure out how
Speaker 2:  you're actually supposed to interact with all of this stuff. This thing is
Speaker 2:  so new, this whole category of devices is so new that
Speaker 2:  nothing about how we use them is settled. How do you select stuff,
Speaker 2:  where do buttons go? Which should those buttons look like? Nobody knows,
Speaker 2:  which is fun and kind of daunting.
Speaker 7:  We made the classic dev mistake of like making one
Speaker 7:  control panel that had like 18 different buttons on it. Oh
Speaker 7:  sure. That feels like a cockpit of a, of a Cessna And then
Speaker 7:  figuring out okay, what are the use things the user always needs access to
Speaker 7:  and what are the things we can hide behind settings? And Andy came up with
Speaker 7:  some ingenious stuff like the drawer gallery that that slides out you know,
Speaker 7:  of the control panel stuff that nobody else was doing. This is the evergreen
Speaker 7:  time like right now for developing all the, designing all this new language
Speaker 7:  that nobody else is doing. This is when the next put pull to refresh comes
Speaker 7:  out. You know that now like a year from now everybody's using has a pattern.
Speaker 2:  Their first real experience with television in a headset came at one of
Speaker 2:  Apple's developer labs in Cupertino. Apple did a lot of these before the
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro came out just to give developers a way to see what their app
Speaker 2:  would look like and how it would feel when real users put on real headsets
Speaker 2:  and had real experiences with their apps. It's a big moment
Speaker 2:  honestly for a lot of these developers. It's a thing I've heard a bunch of
Speaker 2:  is you either put it on and it either feels magical and great
Speaker 2:  or it feels totally broken. For the television crew
Speaker 2:  it was pretty good.
Speaker 7:  I looked over at Andy 'cause he got the app up and running before I did.
Speaker 7:  I look over at him, he is got a big smile and he goes, it works, you
Speaker 9:  Know?
Speaker 7:  And then as soon as I got the app up and running it was like, oh this TV
Speaker 7:  that we only have seen flat on the simulator,
Speaker 7:  it now feels like a substantial 3D object in front of me and
Speaker 7:  I can look around it and view it from different angles. It picks up the light
Speaker 7:  that was boom. That was like everything.
Speaker 2:  How true was the simulator in retrospect? Like was it when you loaded up
Speaker 2:  for the first time in the headset, is it, was it what you expected and hoped
Speaker 2:  it would feel like? Or did you all of a sudden understand it in a new way?
Speaker 7:  There's just no substitute for your actual space. You know, you could take
Speaker 7:  a photo of your actual space and put it at, you know, use it as your environment.
Speaker 7:  You can model your own room and put it into the simulator and it doesn't
Speaker 7:  even come close to 1% of the experience of of what VR
Speaker 7:  is supposed to be or ar. That's the most frustrating thing as storytellers
Speaker 7:  or 'cause if you, I mean if we're designing products we know that the
Speaker 7:  end user is going to experience the same product as we're experiencing in
Speaker 7:  their own space. If you're telling the story in 2D like we had to do,
Speaker 7:  like we often have to do a software like Dan alluded to. It's so
Speaker 7:  frustrating 'cause you can't even come close to the feeling of it until these
Speaker 7:  technologies are pervasive where everybody's using it. So you know, there's
Speaker 7:  no disparity between the superficial simulation of it and the real thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Andy you were smiling as he was saying that. What was that experience
Speaker 2:  like for you?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that experience in the dev lab was a little more nerve
Speaker 9:  wracking for me I think than Adam with other VR
Speaker 9:  headsets. I have some experience where, you know, you build something on
Speaker 9:  a PC and it is running great on this Nvidia graphics
Speaker 9:  card and then you go to build it on the quest and everything just falls apart,
Speaker 9:  right? And so I was, I was really, really nervous about
Speaker 9:  that happening 'cause we'd been using the simulator for a few months but
Speaker 9:  luckily the simulator is pretty representative of how the device works, the
Speaker 9:  software at least you don't get, you know, the full experience of wearing
Speaker 9:  it. And we went to that dev lab and it just worked like I
Speaker 9:  expected. I was just, I was so excited.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's pretty cool
Speaker 7:  To Apple's credit 'cause they really have built a supercomputer device in
Speaker 7:  that thing. It's this, it's not hobbled. Even the version 1.0 of it,
Speaker 7:  the processor is not hobbled. It can do what they want you to do with it.
Speaker 2:  Dan what about you like building all this stuff, making it work like you,
Speaker 2:  you're, you're sort of deep in the details of it. What is that experience
Speaker 2:  like the first time you're actually sort of inside of the space getting to
Speaker 2:  look at the space?
Speaker 8:  I mean to Apple's credit, I mean they, they had sort of laid the groundwork
Speaker 8:  for this stuff with AR kit on the phones and fair. Yeah. Playing around with
Speaker 8:  these models on an iPhone, you, you get a decent sense of like what level
Speaker 8:  of quality you're gonna get out of it. You know, all of the USDZ format stuff,
Speaker 8:  which is all very boring, but it's great that it worked outta the box basically.
Speaker 8:  So you kind of understood that they're gonna wrap it in this sort of like
Speaker 8:  soft world sphere of lighting so it, it accepts some of the light around
Speaker 8:  you. But in the filmmaking world from visual effects, if a 3D model
Speaker 8:  doesn't look good, you just like give it a million more polygons and render
Speaker 8:  it and it's gonna take a day to render a frame but it look, it'll look great
Speaker 8:  and you can't do that kind of stuff in VR or in any of these systems.
Speaker 8:  So finding ways to not destroy all of
Speaker 8:  Andy's work with a model that's, you know, three gigabytes or something is,
Speaker 8:  is very complicated work. It's, it's a, it's a delicate balancing act between
Speaker 8:  detail and performance at all times. I mean there are a few tests we did
Speaker 8:  that just, they were just dead on arrival where it's just like, yeah just
Speaker 8:  throw all the detail in the world at it 'cause it'll look great and it's
Speaker 8:  like, oh my computer is dying. The Vision Pro doesn't like this. Like let's
Speaker 8:  take a step back for a minute and figure out like what we actually need to
Speaker 8:  do to optimize it. Which is very interesting 'cause there's not a lot of
Speaker 8:  people a a, there's not a lot of people trying this sort of stuff within
Speaker 8:  their apps and b there's definitely not a lot of people talking about how
Speaker 8:  to do it. I think only recently we've gotten some guidance from Apple in
Speaker 8:  terms of like how to optimize your app for Vision Os and it's like, oh
Speaker 8:  we missed those targets by a long shot but you know, we're doing our own
Speaker 8:  version of that so, you know, trying to align with what they want us to do
Speaker 8:  is, it's interesting. It's, it's fun work too.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And this level of detail is even more apparent
Speaker 7:  and frustrating and challenging in our theater app that we're, you know,
Speaker 7:  that we're sort of building out right now because it's not just a 3D object
Speaker 7:  in front of you, it's an immersive space that really does require detail
Speaker 7:  in, in order to render believably at a massive scale. So
Speaker 7:  like it's, it's almost like 10 x the challenge in the room as
Speaker 7:  it is to just have the polygonal object in front of you. Right?
Speaker 8:  And we made it harder by saying like we want people to be able to move around
Speaker 8:  the space to to to like actually experience the theater. If we just sat in
Speaker 8:  one place and everything 20 yards away was, you know, fewer
Speaker 8:  polygons and cheapens detail like that would be great for performance but
Speaker 8:  we don't want that out of our experience so we gotta figure out how to make
Speaker 8:  that work.
Speaker 2:  This is the thing I'm so stuck on when it comes to Vision Pro and the thing
Speaker 2:  that I keep feeling as I use it. There's so much cool tech in here
Speaker 2:  and to a large extent it is remarkable that it works as well as it does forget
Speaker 2:  about the fact that it's $3,500, which I think is ridiculous. Forget about
Speaker 2:  the fact that it's so big. Forget about the battery life, it's impressive
Speaker 2:  that this thing exists at all. But like are we sure this is
Speaker 2:  how it should be? Should I really have to laser focus my eyes on a
Speaker 2:  button for the entire time it takes to click it? Do I want to do some things
Speaker 2:  with my hands and other things with buttons? Is a virtual keyboard
Speaker 2:  floating in the air a good idea? What is the best way to move windows around
Speaker 2:  or send something to someone or open an app or anything else? These
Speaker 2:  things get decided and then we treat them as if they were inevitable. But
Speaker 2:  it just isn't that way and it doesn't have to be that way. And there's something
Speaker 2:  exciting about the fact that on the Vision Pro, all of this feels new and
Speaker 2:  unknown and also there's something deeply annoying about the fact that
Speaker 2:  so much of it right now just feels weird to use. But from a
Speaker 2:  big picture perspective, I really like the way Adam described how he thinks
Speaker 2:  about the user experience and how the vision pro ought to feel.
Speaker 7:  We're in an interesting space with its own opportunity 'cause we're trying
Speaker 7:  to build experiences that feel like the real world but better,
Speaker 7:  right? So just imagine you go outside and suddenly you want the
Speaker 7:  information of the world at your fingertips. So what is the interaction that
Speaker 7:  your mind would design in that moment? Hmm? How do you wanna reach up and
Speaker 7:  access the information and then have it go away? That's essentially what
Speaker 7:  we're doing. We're sitting our users down in a movie theater. If you were
Speaker 7:  in a movie theater that you could just chill out in all the time and be by
Speaker 7:  yourself and You can summon any content to that big
Speaker 7:  screen, how would you do that? What would be an interaction model
Speaker 7:  or you know, a lot of it just translated to the outside space. I think that's
Speaker 7:  how designer UI designers have to think about this stuff is knowing
Speaker 7:  that eventually 50 years in the future there will be no hardware and
Speaker 7:  the world in front of us will always be sort of like have a digital layer
Speaker 7:  to it that feels organic and real. What is that interaction model?
Speaker 7:  You know? So if You can summon things, you know, really we are,
Speaker 7:  especially at this early phase of the O os as a, as a platform,
Speaker 7:  we're at the mercy of Apple 'cause Apple, you know, they'll let you do new
Speaker 7:  cool things that they've deemed worthy of the SDK
Speaker 7:  and then we will be able to do new cool futures. And I think
Speaker 7:  that at some point there's an inflection point where
Speaker 7:  developers kind of invent new stuff and then Apple follows. But right now
Speaker 7:  I think we're in the apple leading time of the of the process.
Speaker 2:  Do you feel like that's the right way for things to be right now? I think
Speaker 2:  that's probably pretty normal for a new platform like this, but are you,
Speaker 2:  are you like chafing at the edges of what Apple will let you do or does it
Speaker 2:  feel like we're in the a good zone?
Speaker 7:  Yeah but a perfect example is like playing with light to
Speaker 7:  reflect what the real world feels like. We know that we want, when you use
Speaker 7:  a real tv, especially a vintage one with a a bezel,
Speaker 7:  the light that casts from the screen is reflected on the edges of the tv,
Speaker 7:  right? Well that is not easy to do with, especially in
Speaker 7:  os one of reality kit. We know that in apple's own
Speaker 7:  immersive cinema, when something is playing on that big screen,
Speaker 7:  the light bounces off the screen to the ceiling and the floor and
Speaker 7:  in real time it makes it feel very material, it makes
Speaker 7:  it feel like the light is real and the surfaces are real. Hmm. And Apple
Speaker 7:  doesn't make that easy because working with light as a source
Speaker 7:  in reality kit version one was really not possible. And
Speaker 7:  version two Apple's decided let's make these tools available to
Speaker 7:  developers and that means that we can start to build in this new
Speaker 7:  replication of reality that wasn't possible before. And in in our app
Speaker 7:  in theater Andy came up with an ingenious way to fake it of reflections from
Speaker 7:  the screen bouncing off the walls in the ceiling and floor. But now
Speaker 7:  we get to do it for real, which is very exciting.
Speaker 2:  Obviously a lot of this stuff is changing really fast. Apple just announced
Speaker 2:  Vision OS two which has a bunch of big changes including some of what Adam
Speaker 2:  is talking about with reflections and light. I mean these are the things,
Speaker 2:  right? You have to change the way that light works in
Speaker 2:  an API in order for apps to be able to build things that feel real like this
Speaker 2:  is how long the pipeline is. Television has been out since February
Speaker 2:  and it has already changed a lot. You can now browse and watch YouTube inside
Speaker 2:  of television. You can use share play to watch stuff with friends. There
Speaker 2:  are a few new ways to fast forward and rewind and control playback speed
Speaker 2:  and You can now play spatial video on any of the screens too. That's
Speaker 2:  kind of the Vision Pro thing, right? Ultra retro TV playing the file format
Speaker 2:  of the future supposedly. Anyway, the last thing I asked the
Speaker 2:  sandwich crew was how it's going. Being someone who sells Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro apps.
Speaker 7:  It's funny 'cause you know in the early days of iPhone I think everybody
Speaker 7:  assumed app millionaires. You know, you're just, the business model for
Speaker 7:  app development is you make the app and then you sell a
Speaker 7:  billion copies of it and you get rich. But I think it's what's more
Speaker 7:  interesting from a business perspective is what is, what are the models that
Speaker 7:  it opens up that weren't possible before? And in our case it's like for
Speaker 7:  delivering content, if our app is a content delivery
Speaker 7:  system, then where are the business opportunities in that?
Speaker 7:  It's pretty fascinating stuff. The mind reels with possibilities
Speaker 7:  but I don't know like what in terms of app sales? Oh it's definitely been
Speaker 7:  a loss. I mean like this business runs at a cost at
Speaker 7:  a net loss and I expected that to be the case. I mean I held out hope.
Speaker 7:  You know, we didn't, none of us knew. We didn't know if like we were gonna
Speaker 7:  get a hundred thousand downloads on the first day. We did not.
Speaker 7:  But it turns out like that's not the exciting part of this. The exciting
Speaker 7:  part is like building a new, it's a whole new infrastructure for creating
Speaker 7:  software and running a business and that's where it really gets interesting.
Speaker 2:  Like a lot of developers I've talked to, they're really optimistic about
Speaker 2:  where all this could go and I sort of hope that they're right. It'd be
Speaker 2:  fun to have the Vision Pro become a huge new platform with lots of new
Speaker 2:  kinds of things to do. And the more there is to do, the better the headset
Speaker 2:  is and the better the headset is, the more people will buy it and the more
Speaker 2:  people who buy it, the more developers will get on board and the more developers
Speaker 2:  get on board, the more there is to do and then the flywheel is off and
Speaker 2:  running. This is the thing you need if you want a platform like this to work.
Speaker 2:  I've got a Vision pro sitting right here next to me. Luckily I didn't buy
Speaker 2:  it. I think The Verge did and I just stole it for a while. And as impressive
Speaker 2:  as it is, I just don't use it very much. The only way that is going to change
Speaker 2:  is if more developers find more of these silly, fun, weird
Speaker 2:  things to make for it. I really hope they do.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  take a question from The Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 10:  actual computer aspect of that product is already
Speaker 10:  pretty compact. If you take off the light seal and
Speaker 10:  the headband and even like the stems where like the speaker
Speaker 10:  is and just look at the sort of like eye mask ish
Speaker 10:  part of it, it's pretty slim and most
Speaker 10:  of the bulk that you get from the headset is actually the distance
Speaker 10:  needed or like presumably needed to not fry your
Speaker 10:  eyeballs off of just looking at really small screens in
Speaker 10:  really bright light. So how do you expect Vision Pro
Speaker 10:  to progress to something more wearable or more socially
Speaker 10:  acceptable if the size of it is not
Speaker 10:  actually the tech and is actually just like natural
Speaker 10:  human physiology of not being able to strap LCDs to
Speaker 10:  your eyeballs really closely. I'm curious what you guys see the
Speaker 10:  Vision Pro series two or three or four or five
Speaker 10:  where the thing should get smaller, but just given the way
Speaker 10:  they've built this around pass through and LCD displays, I
Speaker 10:  don't expect it to follow the same path as some of their other products
Speaker 10:  that you, bye.
Speaker 2:  So I think this is the question, right? I think if you're Apple,
Speaker 2:  you have to do one of two things here. You either have to figure out how
Speaker 2:  to take what the Vision Pro is basically in in its
Speaker 2:  relatively current hardware form and make it more palatable to people.
Speaker 2:  And I think what that looks like is just making it cheaper,
Speaker 2:  right? Like take this exact Vision Pro and make it half the price and I think
Speaker 2:  it would be more than twice as compelling to more than twice as many people.
Speaker 2:  That's a hard thing to do. That is the kind of thing that happens over time
Speaker 2:  just as you get better technology. But it doesn't happen quickly and it
Speaker 2:  doesn't happen easily. And so a lot of the stuff that we've seen for
Speaker 2:  Apple's new, cheaper, simpler push that we've heard about has to
Speaker 2:  do with the screens in particular. These screens are ridiculously expensive,
Speaker 2:  they're hard to produce, they are as good as you will find in a headset.
Speaker 2:  And I think what we're gonna see is Apple try to just pull all of that down
Speaker 2:  a little bit to make it cheaper. And in theory, lower
Speaker 2:  resolution would mean lower power, it would mean less need for things like
Speaker 2:  cooling. It would solve some other problems just by not
Speaker 2:  having to drive so many pixels all the time. And so you might get a little
Speaker 2:  bit smaller and more wearable there, but I don't think so the question
Speaker 2:  is right that this thing is already pretty small, like as a pure
Speaker 2:  piece of hardware, it's pretty remarkable. It's made of metal so you could
Speaker 2:  get some weight back on that front. It's definitely
Speaker 2:  rigid in a way that I think over time these things will wanna be a little
Speaker 2:  more flexible, which will make them wearable. But I don't know how you make
Speaker 2:  this thing that much smaller and that much lighter without
Speaker 2:  fundamentally changing what it's, which brings me to the other point. I just
Speaker 2:  can't stop thinking about the difference between what the Vision Pro is and
Speaker 2:  is trying to be and what the RayBan meta smart glasses are
Speaker 2:  and are trying to be. And it's so obvious to me at
Speaker 2:  this point that the RayBan meta strategy is the right one.
Speaker 2:  I think especially if you believe that AI is gonna change how we talk to
Speaker 2:  computers. Having something on your face that is essentially a very good
Speaker 2:  microphone, a good set of speakers and a camera actually gets you
Speaker 2:  a shocking amount of power out of your device. You can do so
Speaker 2:  much with a simple wearable thing that can see the world and talk
Speaker 2:  to you. That is massively powerful, especially if you believe AI is really
Speaker 2:  the future. What Apple has built here is that
Speaker 2:  plus a screen and an entertainment device. And I think that's
Speaker 2:  interesting and that's where we will go in the future. But the road
Speaker 2:  from here to there I think looks a lot more like smart
Speaker 2:  glasses than it does like headsets, if that makes sense.
Speaker 2:  The steps between something like the RayBan Meta Smart Glasses and
Speaker 2:  something like the Quest, even if you wanna take the other meta product out
Speaker 2:  there are super unknown too. It's a lot of really hard
Speaker 2:  problems to solve in displays and in processor
Speaker 2:  efficiency and in how to get a GPU on your face that is good enough to work
Speaker 2:  all day, how to solve battery life. Like people talk about
Speaker 2:  making a lot of huge progress in tech as like solving
Speaker 2:  multiple physics miracles all at once. And that's kind of what Apple and
Speaker 2:  meta need if you believe that these all encompassing
Speaker 2:  headsets are the thing. But if you don't and I'm not sure that I do,
Speaker 2:  then smart glasses is the answer. And I think
Speaker 2:  if you're Apple, you had the iPod before the iPhone, you could
Speaker 2:  look at smart glasses as the iPod, they don't do as much but they do it very
Speaker 2:  well. They are the right form factor, they feel good people like them, they
Speaker 2:  solve a couple of very specific problems. And
Speaker 2:  then years later, once the tech gets better, once people get more
Speaker 2:  comfortable with the idea of the form factor, once you've found a couple
Speaker 2:  of new things to do and new ways to interact, then you do
Speaker 2:  the iPhone. We weren't ready for the iPhone in 2001
Speaker 2:  when they started shipping iPods. The technology wasn't there, the world
Speaker 2:  wasn't ready. We didn't have the sort of cultural understanding of how all
Speaker 2:  this stuff would work. It just wouldn't have worked as well as it did six
Speaker 2:  years later. And I think headsets might be the same thing. And Apple
Speaker 2:  just tried to skip all the way to like the iPhone 10
Speaker 2:  instead of shipping the iPod. And I'm totally brutalizing this
Speaker 2:  metaphor, but I think I have no evidence for this, but I think that if
Speaker 2:  you're on Apple's hardware team, you're looking at the RayBan Meta Smartt
Speaker 2:  glasses and saying, oh, what we should have done is built something that
Speaker 2:  does less stuff and is wearable instead of trying to
Speaker 2:  build the thing that does all the things, including some things that people
Speaker 2:  don't really want and isn't all that wearable. So the idea of what
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro is now, it's gonna be hard to make this thing more wearable.
Speaker 2:  There's some things Apple can do with the straps, like just having the overhead
Speaker 2:  strap built in instead of having just the one around
Speaker 2:  goes a long way towards making it wearable. Actually Adam Lior from Sando
Speaker 2:  said in our interview that he has actually taken out the light
Speaker 2:  seal, he uses the overhead strap and uses it essentially like an AR device
Speaker 2:  so he can see around it and uses it much less
Speaker 2:  sort of immersively, but it's still very comfortable for him. And I think
Speaker 2:  that's really clever and there are more ways that Apple can start to press
Speaker 2:  on that. Solving some of the battery stuff will go a long way, like just
Speaker 2:  having that cord on your face is a real wearability problem. I think putting
Speaker 2:  the battery on the headset is also a bad idea. Again, physics miracles, but
Speaker 2:  that's one thing you'll start to see. I wouldn't be surprised to see Apple
Speaker 2:  use a less heavy material even if it's slightly less impressive. Again, if
Speaker 2:  you wanna get the price down, that's another way to do it and it'll also
Speaker 2:  have the delightful side effect of pulling some weight off of the device.
Speaker 2:  So again, there are little things Apple can do around the edges here, but
Speaker 2:  I think if you wanna see Apple do something more
Speaker 2:  wearable, it's gonna have to look like a different device. And I would
Speaker 2:  bet I wouldn't bet a lot, but I would bet a little that what Apple
Speaker 2:  is going to do next with the Vision Pro is going to look less like a
Speaker 2:  worse Vision Pro and more like something else entirely. I could be wrong,
Speaker 2:  maybe this is just wishful thinking because I would love for Apple to make
Speaker 2:  something like the Meta RayBan Smart glasses, but that connects to
Speaker 2:  Siri and all of my other devices as seamlessly as like a pair of AirPods
Speaker 2:  does. I want that. So maybe I'm just hoping for that. But You can see it,
Speaker 2:  right? Like all the things that AirPods are on your face plus
Speaker 2:  a camera that feels powerful, it feels like Apple. And you could see that
Speaker 2:  being the vision and then this being the Vision Pro. That's how you get to
Speaker 2:  wearability as far as I'm concerned because I don't think we're anywhere
Speaker 2:  close to a world in which You can build something that is as
Speaker 2:  powerful and capable as the Vision Pro and feels as good on my face as a
Speaker 2:  pair of glasses or even close. And some of the reporting, particularly from
Speaker 2:  Mark Kerman at Bloomberg has said that Apple is working on something more
Speaker 2:  like AR glasses, but that's still a couple of years away. That wouldn't totally
Speaker 2:  shock me, but again, from what I've seen from these meta
Speaker 2:  glasses, they don't have to do that much to be really useful to people.
Speaker 2:  Camera, speaker, microphone, incredibly powerful
Speaker 2:  and I think there's a lot more to do there and I think we might see Apple
Speaker 2:  do it sooner rather than later. Anyway, that's all outta conjecture. I'd
Speaker 2:  love to hear what you think. If you have had a Vision Pro for any of
Speaker 2:  the last five months, I wanna know what you think. We got a lot of feedback
Speaker 2:  from folks when we published our review and in those early days, but now
Speaker 2:  that things have settled, has the Vision Pro found a way into your routine?
Speaker 2:  Are you still using it all the time? Did you return it because it's $3,500?
Speaker 2:  Are you finding new ways all the time to use it? Do you use it for something
Speaker 2:  totally unusual that no one talks about? Tell us. I wanna hear everything.
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one. One is the hotline, the email is vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. Reach out. I wanna hear everything.
Speaker 2:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  in the next couple of versions of this thing. I think the Vision Pro isn
Speaker 2:  gonna change a lot. It's gonna be really interesting. Also, read the version.com.
Speaker 2:  Surprising amount of news going on this summer. This is usually like the
Speaker 2:  dead period of the tech news cycle that ain't happening and it's about to
Speaker 2:  be phone season again, so it's gonna get crazy. As always, if you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  questions, feelings or Vision Pro apps you think I should try, You can always
Speaker 2:  email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline eight six six
Speaker 2:  VERGE one one. we love hearing from you. This show is produced by Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino, Liam James, and will pour VERGE cast's, VERGE production, and part
Speaker 2:  of the Vox Media Podcast Network. As I mentioned, we'll be back next week
Speaker 2:  after the break. Everybody have a great holiday. We'll see you then. Rock
Speaker 2:  and roll.