# Transcript
ID: 969b12cd-7163-4628-87a7-108374280d89
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2700198998721048203/9169285102658635801/s93290-US-7053s-1718581354.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Allison Johnson, and David Pierce discuss all the announcements from Apple's WWDC event.
Speaker 3:  I picked
Speaker 3:  announcements, Apple Intelligence, which is the company's approach to
Speaker 3:  ai, which has many, many, many components including all the way
Speaker 3:  at the end. A little, little chat. GPT-4. Oh yeah, just a little.
Speaker 3:  There it is. Just shut up. Wall Street. That's pretty much what
Speaker 3:  it was. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You want us to have a chat GPT strategy. Here it is. It's
Speaker 3:  Just chat GPT. So David and I were walking around the event, we're walking
Speaker 3:  to Apple Park. The vibe was very much like, what is GPT doing
Speaker 3:  here? Like they were excited about it. They were talking about it,
Speaker 3:  but they were kept on talking about all the stuff they had built. Yeah. In
Speaker 3:  the keynote, their principles for how to build it, how they're gonna protect
Speaker 3:  user privacy. There was a second on the record
Speaker 3:  event where I, Justine interviewed John Jean Andrea,
Speaker 3:  who's their head of ai and Craig Federighi, they re recapitulated the keynote
Speaker 3:  and said the principles and values again. And then they kept being, and then
Speaker 3:  some people are gonna want to use chat bt. Right. And it was just like,
Speaker 3:  I think all the lead up was about are they gonna pick Google? Are they gonna
Speaker 3:  pick open ai? They're behind, they gotta catch up. These
Speaker 3:  models will power this stuff. And David, I it just felt like
Speaker 3:  they could have done without it.
Speaker 4:  Well there was the assumption going in that if they were gonna sign a deal
Speaker 4:  like this, it was gonna be to sort of underpin all of this stuff.
Speaker 4:  Right. That like in the sense that when you go to Safari and you do a search,
Speaker 4:  you get Google, right? You don't get like a mishmash of Apple and Google
Speaker 4:  when it's useful. Like it's just Google because that's the one that Apple
Speaker 4:  picked. And also billions of dollars is fun. But the assumption
Speaker 4:  then was like, okay, this will be a Siri based on Gemini.
Speaker 4:  Apple doesn't have the technology yet. Apple hasn't been able to compete
Speaker 4:  with OpenAI and others. So they're gonna build on top of this infrastructure,
Speaker 4:  which as we've talked about, has all kinds of like weird privacy implications,
Speaker 4:  but in a certain way kinda makes sense.
Speaker 4:  Instead it's just like a weird thing off to the side where
Speaker 4:  Apple made a huge deal out of all the stuff that it has built. It says it
Speaker 4:  can do a ton. It's built this incredibly vertically integrated system that
Speaker 4:  it says preserve your privacy and knows what's on the screen. And then like
Speaker 4:  you said, oh, and also chat GPT. Yeah. And so it's, it feels like
Speaker 4:  just a, an afterthought because it's a really good brand
Speaker 4:  that people know. Well
Speaker 5:  It it, it does actually feel like the Google thing because it
Speaker 5:  in that it's only being used for search, right. Like that that was, that
Speaker 5:  was my understanding.
Speaker 3:  It's not even used for search in that way. It's, it it would
Speaker 4:  Be like if you only took Google images. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Everything else was Apple except Google images and you it. And
Speaker 4:  so if you do a search for a picture, you get Google and everything else is
Speaker 4:  Apple. And you'd be like, what? This doesn't make any sense because the
Speaker 5:  Integration is like you just, you ask and then if it
Speaker 5:  decides that it doesn't want to do it and it wants chat GPT to do it.
Speaker 3:  Well no, sorry. We should step through it. Yeah. Like walk, the big headline
Speaker 3:  feature we should talk about is Apple. Intelligence. Yep. The way the keynote
Speaker 3:  was structured was to put all of that stuff at the end. It was the grand
Speaker 3:  finale of
Speaker 4:  It was the one more thing
Speaker 3:  Almost WWDC
Speaker 4:  Me. I turned to me at one point during the live blog as they, they hit like
Speaker 4:  a wrap up moment. Yeah. Before they did the Apple Intelligence stuff. And
Speaker 4:  Neil, I just turned to me and goes, is that it? Yeah. Like are
Speaker 3:  We, because they ran through all the oss. Yeah. Which, which we'll get to
Speaker 3:  later. But they ran through all the oss and like here's the new grid of icons
Speaker 3:  on the home screen. Look, you could put the icons everywhere. Here's TV os
Speaker 3:  we didn't do anything. And then they, they came to like a
Speaker 3:  natural wrap point. Yeah. And then Tim Cook came back and he is like, power
Speaker 3:  of generative intelligence, blah blah, blah. Here's all the stuff we're doing.
Speaker 3:  And they laid out a bunch of principles. It has to be powerful, it has to
Speaker 3:  be useful, it has to be private. They've built this extraordinarily
Speaker 3:  complicated system where your device decides
Speaker 3:  whether it can do some of the things that you might want it to do or
Speaker 3:  it has to go to Apple's private cloud compute nodes, which we should definitely
Speaker 3:  talk about. Lots of privacy claims there. And then it's not,
Speaker 3:  and then it goes to chat. GPT. Okay. It's,
Speaker 3:  that's Apple. Intelligence. And the heart of almost all these announcements
Speaker 3:  are like, here's some stuff you can do on your phone or your Mac. Here's
Speaker 3:  some stuff that we built this very complicated system to do in
Speaker 3:  the cloud securely. And then also there's a button
Speaker 3:  here where if you want to take a picture of your fridge and ask it to make
Speaker 3:  up a recipe, you can send a photo to chat GPT if you'd like. Also,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna ask you if you ever wanna do that and every time you do it, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna say, do you want to send this photo to chat GBT? You know what?
Speaker 3:  So there's no, there's almost no integration. Oh
Speaker 5:  That is like, yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  The opposite. I had, I had not thought about this until just now. I think
Speaker 4:  that's on purpose. I think that's like extremely on purpose. Yeah. Because
Speaker 4:  what Apple is trying to do is like abstract all of the AI ness away.
Speaker 4:  Right. That like you as a user shouldn't have to care or notice what's
Speaker 4:  going to the cloud and what's happening on device. They want it to all be
Speaker 4:  secure. It should all work the same. Like fine Apple wants it to
Speaker 4:  be damn clear when you are using chat GPT. Yep. Because chat
Speaker 4:  GPT is going to make mistakes. It's going to do a lot of weird stuff and
Speaker 4:  Apple would very much like to be like, Hey, remember when you hit a button
Speaker 4:  that said chat GPT, like this is no longer our problem.
Speaker 5:  Even the prompt is like, sometimes we'll make errors.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. At the bottom of every result it says check important info. Brutal.
Speaker 3:  Which is just chat G's reputation now. Yeah. This thing lies to you. It's
Speaker 3:  even
Speaker 4:  That's even crueler than like Chad GT's typical,
Speaker 4:  which is just like, sometimes it makes mistakes. Apple
Speaker 3:  Is like straight up check this. Right? Yeah. So, but there's a real line
Speaker 3:  there. And that's what I'm saying. It felt like the vibe was we did all this
Speaker 3:  stuff also this is here so don't ask us about it. Right. Like yeah. They
Speaker 3:  said Craig Federighi at the,
Speaker 3:  I don't even know what you would call this, it was an interview, but it was
Speaker 3:  like interview, it was very stage little
Speaker 5:  Coffee side.
Speaker 3:  He said that Gemini would be an example of another
Speaker 3:  LLM they could bring into this. And he said there will be others. We heard
Speaker 3:  people talk about like, what if you're a doctor and there's a medical
Speaker 3:  AI system that you want to plug into your Mac in this way the
Speaker 3:  hooks are being built so that you'll have multiple models you can pick from.
Speaker 3:  So chat GBT is just the one they're starting with today because they kept
Speaker 3:  saying it's the market leader. They think it's the best one of these things
Speaker 3:  they can integrate in all these places. Over time it's obvious
Speaker 3:  that Apple Intelligence this much more private system is gonna get better
Speaker 3:  and maybe push one out or there's gonna be like competition
Speaker 3:  and you get to pick whatever model you want.
Speaker 5:  So is it effectively just advertisement for the API then
Speaker 3:  I think, I suspect I do not know that
Speaker 3:  Apple is paying open AI to have this built into
Speaker 3:  their operating systems. I don't know how they're getting paid. I dunno if
Speaker 3:  it's per use. I dunno if it's a bulk rate, whatever.
Speaker 3:  I know that OpenAI doesn't make any money.
Speaker 3:  Famously they have not yet made any money. Microsoft owns
Speaker 3:  49% of OpenAI. It would be very funny if
Speaker 3:  Microsoft was putting money into OpenAI and OpenAI was paying Apple
Speaker 3:  for the privilege of being an Apple's operating, like that would be almost
Speaker 3:  backwards. So the, you know, the, the logical
Speaker 3:  assumption is that Apple is paying to have this be part
Speaker 3:  of their operating system and maybe they'll pay other companies over time.
Speaker 3:  What's weird about that or there will be some other kind of arrangement you
Speaker 3:  can have. You can log in. If you have a subscriber to chat GPT, you can log
Speaker 3:  into your account, you get more features. Yeah. It will remember you for
Speaker 3:  example. Whereas if you don't have a chat GPT account or you're not paying
Speaker 3:  for premium,
Speaker 3:  it doesn't remember anything about you, it's free.
Speaker 3:  It's free to use on your iPhone. It has no memory and it's, it throws everything
Speaker 3:  out about you. So they have built this like very firewalled version of chat
Speaker 3:  GBT that's just around. Yeah. But all of the action is Apple
Speaker 3:  Intelligence, which is totally controlled by Apple.
Speaker 5:  That makes a hundred. Like that just makes sense. Apple was never gonna
Speaker 5:  let anybody that tightly integrate
Speaker 3:  Into this. But this, these are not the rumors, right?
Speaker 4:  No. Well and it also makes the chat GPT piece of it make less sense to me,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. 'cause if, if OpenAI is paying Apple, that I understand, right?
Speaker 4:  Like I get that for OpenAI. They say, okay, this is going to make people
Speaker 4:  use our product more, which is gonna make more people subscribe. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's the path we get. User data, whatever. But
Speaker 4:  OpenAI in the way that it's set up now seems to
Speaker 4:  be getting most of the upside. And all Apple gets is just like a weird way
Speaker 4:  to offload you to another system for some questions that you have. It's
Speaker 3:  Very much like to do the good fun stuff. It has to be not private. And that's
Speaker 3:  Sam Alton's problem. We're gonna, we're gonna have this. So the
Speaker 3:  the architecture.
Speaker 4:  So you think the risk then is that if, if it's, if you don't have that, all
Speaker 4:  you get is kind of a like not fully baked AI system that people don't use
Speaker 4:  and so you're sort of lost at from the beginning. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I think one of the really interesting pieces of the puzzle here is
Speaker 3:  we don't know how much of these features will arrive with iOS
Speaker 3:  18 at the beginning. Right. We don't know how many are coming towards the
Speaker 3:  end. Every time they talked about Siri,
Speaker 3:  I kept noticing that they, they insisted, they used like often
Speaker 3:  the distance verb tenses. Yeah. Siri is going to be able to do
Speaker 3:  this. And it's like, when is Siri going to be able to do this? The
Speaker 3:  answer appears to be within the window of iOS 18.
Speaker 3:  So Siri will be able to do a bunch of the stuff they demoed before iOS 19
Speaker 3:  comes out,
Speaker 5:  But not necessarily
Speaker 3:  A long time from now. Yeah, yeah. Like that's, that's September, 2025 is
Speaker 3:  the release date of iOS 19. So there's a long way to go
Speaker 3:  before they have to ship all these features. But the fundamental architecture
Speaker 3:  of Apple Intelligence is really interesting because they have,
Speaker 3:  they are claiming very much that the on-device
Speaker 3:  intelligence that they've built, they said there are already 200 models running
Speaker 3:  air phone before we ever do any of this generative stuff for things like
Speaker 3:  car crash detection and photo editing and all photos in general on an
Speaker 3:  iPhone. Tons of ai. And then now they're adding some of these other models.
Speaker 3:  It's only gonna run on The iPhone 15 Pro and
Speaker 3:  presumably the next one and then Max with an M1 chip or
Speaker 3:  above. So that's interesting. 'cause the M1
Speaker 3:  I think is more similar to some of the previous I iPhone ships. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But they are gating it. So it's the 15 pro and above and M1 and above
Speaker 3:  obviously running the new versions of the operating system and it's gonna
Speaker 3:  add more models that let you do more stuff on the phone. So you will be
Speaker 3:  able to generate horrifying images on the phone
Speaker 3:  based on I'm So what's happening, your photos that you'll be able to
Speaker 3:  ask Siri for certain things using App intent, which we talked about a bunch
Speaker 3:  last week, but
Speaker 5:  It's only using the data on your device. Right.
Speaker 3:  Only using the data on your device. Which
Speaker 5:  Is why all of the images from the image playground that we saw
Speaker 5:  in the keynote were horrible.
Speaker 4:  They were so bad.
Speaker 5:  They were like, it was like, do you remember how when you're, when you're
Speaker 5:  downloading app and it's like, do you wanna download any of these other games
Speaker 5:  that you've never heard of and are probably gonna steal your data? They it
Speaker 5:  like all the art looked like those apps.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So it's Image Playground, which is all local
Speaker 3:  and yeah, it looks bad. It looks real bad. But Image playground is a, a thing
Speaker 3:  you can just integrate into apps now. So you can draw sketch and notes and
Speaker 3:  circle it and then it'll make the AI bubble and then it'll turn your sketch
Speaker 3:  into a thing.
Speaker 4:  Is that anything
Speaker 3:  Like,
Speaker 4:  I'm sort of serious, like I think
Speaker 3:  I have been,
Speaker 4:  I have been thinking about this so much the last few weeks about like how
Speaker 4:  what in AI is a real thing that people will do and what is going to be a
Speaker 4:  tech demo that no one in the world ever actually does. And I've been thinking
Speaker 4:  about this actually ever since Rabbit did the demo where he drew a spreadsheet
Speaker 4:  on a piece of paper and then pointed his rabbit to it and was
Speaker 4:  like, transposed the rows and columns and send this to my email and it did
Speaker 4:  it. And it was like, oh neat unusable feature for anyone who exists
Speaker 4:  in the world. Like why on earth would you do this? And I wonder with this
Speaker 4:  thing where he's like, there was a moment in the keynote where he was in
Speaker 4:  notes and he just did a circle in a note
Speaker 4:  in an open part of the note and it made a picture of the stuff that was
Speaker 4:  in his note. And it's like a technically neat thing.
Speaker 4:  It made a thing. Why? What is this for?
Speaker 5:  No, I figured it out. It's when, you know how when you have to send a deck
Speaker 5:  and you don't wanna go look for art to send that deck to like all your other
Speaker 5:  coworkers to be like, this is why we're gonna do this new policy or whatever.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That's actually, that's actually
Speaker 3:  It. You really tell that Alex used to be the managing editor. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right? Oh
Speaker 3:  Yeah. She had to explain a lot of policy.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I think I don't make enough decks to like be Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Steward of the world. I need to make more texts.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We, you make me an installer deck using an entire,
Speaker 3:  But there's other stuff that you, that will happen locally on the phone,
Speaker 3:  like the new iOS that you get AI powered summaries of
Speaker 3:  your notifications and they previewed this with a very like,
Speaker 3:  like the stock thing that everyone previews everything with, which is like
Speaker 3:  your friends are planning a trip in a group text and it's like, so and so
Speaker 3:  booked a house, so the first date is this and so and so is gonna be late.
Speaker 3:  I'm like, none of my friends are this transactional, they do not communicate
Speaker 3:  this way. It's gonna be like your law school friends are shit posting. Again,
Speaker 3:  some of these images are not safe for work. Right. And it's like, what will
Speaker 3:  we have do this? So like there's a real,
Speaker 3:  I think just gap between sort of these demos, like these ideas of what you
Speaker 3:  can do on the phone, the reality of how powerful your phone might have to
Speaker 3:  be and then like what actually is happening on people's phones. And
Speaker 3:  then at some point, and we don't really know when the phone's gonna say,
Speaker 3:  I don't have the horsepower to do this, or my battery life will be too compromised,
Speaker 3:  or the thermals are outta whack and it will create a secure connection
Speaker 3:  to Apple's secure private compute cloud
Speaker 3:  service that is running apple silicon somewhere.
Speaker 3:  And that whole mechanism is Apple's innovation.
Speaker 3:  Like at the end of the day, apple running a bunch of tiny models on device
Speaker 3:  and a bunch of bigger models in the cloud is what everyone is doing. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Some of the user experiences they are delivering are exactly
Speaker 3:  the same ones as we've seen demoed by other companies.
Speaker 3:  Apple's much better at telling you a compelling story about those user
Speaker 3:  interface ideas, but it's the same stuff. We're gonna read all your email
Speaker 3:  and make you a list of flights like Yeah, we saw that at io, right? That's
Speaker 3:  Microsoft is demoing, but the the big innovation is they're saying
Speaker 3:  we're doing this all on your device as much as we can. And when we have to
Speaker 3:  go up to the cloud, we've built this whole system
Speaker 3:  to keep that secure and then importantly throw your data away on the cloud
Speaker 3:  when we're done. So there's no chance of being compromised. Right. That
Speaker 4:  Whole chain is supposed to be exactly as secure as just doing it on your
Speaker 4:  device. Yeah. Which just instinctively I don't believe. Yeah. Because that's
Speaker 4:  not a thing. You've just, you've taken a thing that was on my device and
Speaker 4:  you've put it somewhere else. And so now by definition it's less secure,
Speaker 4:  but at least to apple's credit, it does seem like it has done just about
Speaker 4:  everything you can do to mitigate that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's gone to like, it seems to be just as secure
Speaker 5:  as possible with still acknow but refusing to acknowledge
Speaker 5:  that it is still way less secure than everything just being on your device.
Speaker 5:  Right. Because it's like, yeah, this is probably one of the most secure ways
Speaker 5:  you can transfer this information. You are still transferring this information
Speaker 5:  and that means you open yourself up to other people
Speaker 5:  inserting themselves in.
Speaker 4:  Right. And there's all kinds of potential for weirdness if you have network
Speaker 4:  problems or again, like it turns out sending a bunch of data to the web
Speaker 4:  and the cloud is also taxing on your battery life. Yeah. And thermal, it's
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, this stuff is hard. And I think doing all of this super
Speaker 4:  seamlessly, if Apple can pull it off, is going to be like the true magic
Speaker 4:  trick of this whole system.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So the the basics are complicated. They just released a white paper
Speaker 3:  about how it all works. It is very dry.
Speaker 3:  Oh my god. Alex, I believe your read on it was they don't want people to
Speaker 3:  read this. No,
Speaker 5:  You sure don't.
Speaker 3:  But some interesting pieces of it. Right. Craig
Speaker 3:  Federer described one part of the system as blockchain ish. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 3:  actually a great description. So your phone
Speaker 3:  when it goes to talk to one of these servers, if they have not published
Speaker 3:  the code for researchers to verify the security of the
Speaker 3:  code to an append only cryptographically signed database
Speaker 3:  blockchain ish that your phone can check, it just won't
Speaker 3:  talk to that server. Right. So like your, your man in the middle attack
Speaker 3:  there, like they're trying to cut that down. There's a line in the white
Speaker 3:  paper that says we do not want there to be targetability. So
Speaker 3:  it's not like you have a Mac in the cloud. Yeah. There's a huge
Speaker 3:  array of devices in the cloud and they don't want any one of those to be
Speaker 3:  associated with you. So your device, when it asks for a server to run
Speaker 3:  some these workloads on, it actually will only ever get a group and it won't
Speaker 3:  know which one is in the end. And then that load balancer is also like hardened.
Speaker 3:  So you like you can't attack it. Right. So No, no. Like attacker
Speaker 3:  can be like, okay, they always get that one and it's not sending all the
Speaker 3:  data in plain text, but it's not storing a database of everything you've
Speaker 3:  ever done on your computer in plain text. Yeah. Good. Like windows those
Speaker 3:  recall. It's good. Yeah. Although Microsoft did say they were gonna fix it.
Speaker 3:  This is like, there's just a bunch of stuff like that. One of the more interesting
Speaker 3:  pieces the servers run a custom operating system that
Speaker 3:  Apple says in the white paper is a combination of Mac OS and iOS
Speaker 3:  that is designed just for inference loads. They've cut down all the other
Speaker 3:  attack surfaces and then they, the hardware itself, in
Speaker 3:  addition to all their usual like security measures, they
Speaker 3:  have additional layers of security when they make the hardware
Speaker 3:  ship it to the data center and validate it for installation.
Speaker 4:  And also there's a large man with a gun just standing next to each one
Speaker 3:  Just in case. Well I think, I think some of that stuff is in this white paper.
Speaker 3:  They talk about it, it's in this blog post because if you are recall, there
Speaker 3:  was a huge Bloomberg story about Apple's data centers
Speaker 3:  being attacked at the supply chain level. And I think they're like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  we're not, that's not even a possibility here. Yeah. So they're, they're
Speaker 3:  saying all of these things about how the system will work. I think the most
Speaker 3:  important thing they're saying is we want researchers to come in and validate
Speaker 3:  this stuff over and over and over again. Yeah. The firmware for these devices,
Speaker 3:  they're gonna publish it in plain text and like look at it.
Speaker 3:  So I think there's this level of we want, we want to take the pressure
Speaker 3:  on the system. At the same time, the pressure is not
Speaker 3:  necessarily technical. The pressure is legal and
Speaker 3:  political. Like the Chinese government doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 3:  They're just gonna say, if you want to keep selling iPhones in China, you're
Speaker 3:  gonna have to let us see everything. Right. What are gonna do about that?
Speaker 3:  The Indian government is probably not gonna give a shit. Like they just
Speaker 3:  want to see things. They just had some elections. It's a little softener
Speaker 3:  over there, but like, who knows? Right? Like that's the pressure on the world.
Speaker 3:  Our FBI here in the United States has repeatedly tried to pressure Apple
Speaker 3:  into turning over encryption keys to iMessage and iCloud. This is a
Speaker 3:  new vector of attack to say, okay, you're moving personal device off of
Speaker 3:  people's phones into the cloud. There is something called the third
Speaker 3:  party doctrine in this country that says if you anything touches your telecom
Speaker 3:  provider or a cloud service, you had no longer have a reason why expectation
Speaker 3:  of privacy. 'cause a third party has seen it and now the government can see
Speaker 3:  it too. Apple's answer to this is we're gonna throw it all away as soon as
Speaker 3:  we're done processing in the cloud and we send you a result back. And so
Speaker 3:  we don't even have it to turn it over, but the pressure is gonna keep coming.
Speaker 3:  So it's interesting that the, the technical side, they've tried to button
Speaker 3:  it up as much as they can. The legal and political side.
Speaker 3:  They, they want to keep selling phones in China. Yeah. They're,
Speaker 5:  It's just a big We'll see. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's like we're, we're just gonna see how Well also
Speaker 4:  That problem, that problem doesn't cease to exist even if you don't have
Speaker 4:  this system for Apple. Right. Like this is just, this is just the price of
Speaker 4:  doing business in Apples or in China. Yeah. So fundamentally like Apple
Speaker 4:  made that decision a very long time ago. Yeah. And this is just another version
Speaker 4:  of that same decision. What it seems like here is Apple is trying to
Speaker 4:  give itself an out for the rest of the world's versions of
Speaker 4:  those legal and political problems where it can just be like, sorry, we don't,
Speaker 4:  we don't have it to give you like, I don't know what you want. Right. They,
Speaker 3:  They've sort of engineered a technical solution to a legal problem. Right.
Speaker 4:  Right. Well this is the thing you hear a lot now from people who are building
Speaker 4:  web services is like the main thing you should do is make sure you don't
Speaker 4:  have one shred of data that you don't absolutely need. Because if you
Speaker 4:  accidentally store a bunch of people's credit card numbers, somebody's gonna
Speaker 4:  hack it and they're gonna get it. And that's gonna suck real bad for you.
Speaker 4:  Yep. If you have a bunch of people's email addresses and passwords for accounts
Speaker 4:  that don't really matter to you, same thing's gonna happen. Like all this
Speaker 4:  stuff. And so these data minimization practices are not just like good
Speaker 4:  for the world, even though I think they are, but it's just good business
Speaker 4:  practice. And so it's like for Apple, if they're sincerely not
Speaker 4:  turning around and training more models on that data or selling that data,
Speaker 4:  both of which they say they're not. And I think, I believe them keeping that
Speaker 4:  data is just a liability. Yeah. And so it's actually, it's smart for so many
Speaker 4:  reasons to be like, the minute you're done with it, it's just shredded and
Speaker 4:  gone. We can get back if you want it. I mean, I
Speaker 5:  Think Apple's ideal is that everything will eventually be on the phone. The
Speaker 5:  processors will be fast enough that they don't have to send anything to the
Speaker 5:  cloud. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I I think very clearly Apple's goal is to do more and more on
Speaker 4:  device over time.
Speaker 3:  I disagree. Really? Yeah. But not in like a meaningful way.
Speaker 3:  I shouldn't, I I think when you say Apple's goal is to get it all on your
Speaker 3:  phone, I think, I think it, it's gone. The horses
Speaker 3:  left the station. It's been a long day. Horses, you keep horses in the station,
Speaker 3:  right? And Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. The horses left the barn. The train is
Speaker 5:  Has left station, the train has the
Speaker 3:  Station, station train has left. The The iPhone workload has left your phone.
Speaker 3:  And I think what's gonna happen is the phone will get more and more powerful.
Speaker 3:  It'll take more workloads onto the phone. Sure. Mm. But then you're gonna
Speaker 3:  invent more stuff you wanna do, and now you've built this incredibly powerful
Speaker 3:  secure cloud, blah, blah, blah, and you're gonna do all the stuff you,
Speaker 3:  there will always be some level of stuff you can't do on the phone that now
Speaker 3:  you can do up there.
Speaker 4:  I think both of those things can be simultaneously true. Right. Like the,
Speaker 4:  the private cloud compute is how you get rid of chat
Speaker 4:  GPT and like ultimately at some point, if we go far enough down this
Speaker 4:  road open AI and Apple will be naked competitors in this space. Like that's
Speaker 4:  just where we're headed and that's how you get rid of chat
Speaker 4:  GPT needing to do all this stuff. Right. I think every time
Speaker 4:  Apple sends something out of Apple Intelligence and into chat GPTT,
Speaker 4:  that is going to look like failure to Apple. Yeah. For a whole variety of
Speaker 4:  reasons.
Speaker 4:  But it's still true. I think that as the set of workloads gets
Speaker 4:  larger, apple is going to want to do more and more of them on your device
Speaker 4:  because it's gonna save them computing. Apple talked a bunch about the environmental
Speaker 4:  impact of all of this stuff and they make a big deal about the fact that
Speaker 4:  the more you can do on your device, the less they have to send anywhere,
Speaker 4:  which is computationally expensive costs electricity. Like it's just
Speaker 4:  more efficient to do it on the device. So I think the push to do that's of
Speaker 4:  locally is going to be real. It probably won't ever be the whole answer though.
Speaker 4:  I think you're like, and the bleeding edge stuff can happen in the compute
Speaker 4:  cloud so that it doesn't have to happen in Azure. Yeah. Which is a
Speaker 4:  bummer if you're Apple.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean I, that's what, that's kinda what I'm getting at. It's, I I
Speaker 3:  disagree with you, but not in like some huge sense. I just think there will
Speaker 3:  always be some set of ideas that is too big for the phone. Yeah. And once
Speaker 3:  you've opened the door to Apple saying we've
Speaker 3:  built a system that allows us to take some stuff away
Speaker 3:  from your phone and up into the cloud, which they're very proud of that all
Speaker 3:  of their data centers run on a hundred percent renewable energy and Apple
Speaker 3:  silicon is already high performance per watt. And like
Speaker 3:  they can do all this stuff where maybe they can solve some of those efficiency
Speaker 3:  problems, right? Like Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Fair. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  There's just gonna be some set of stuff that they can do in the cloud. So
Speaker 3:  like I, this is like, this is today's the change
Speaker 3:  and like a year from now or two years from now, it'll just be part of the
Speaker 3:  way The iPhone works is you have access to private compute cloud
Speaker 3:  that no dumb Android phone comes. Right.
Speaker 4:  Whereas
Speaker 3:  Like with Android, you gotta send everything to Google, which is like training
Speaker 3:  on your emails, like whatever thing Apple's gonna say. So I just think this
Speaker 3:  is the beginning of a change and that's really how they framed it all day
Speaker 3:  long. Yeah. Was this is the beginning of a change. Like this is the next
Speaker 3:  generation of these devices. This is the next generation of how we use these
Speaker 3:  apps. David, at one point he said, you can, you can
Speaker 3:  squint and you can see the end of the app era here. And the way that they're
Speaker 3:  talking about Siri, there's just excitement in a way that I would, for example,
Speaker 3:  contrast with the Vision Pro. Yeah. Which received 45 seconds
Speaker 3:  of like, now you can look at your keyboard in immersive mode,
Speaker 5:  Ultra wide displays. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  But you know, the way, the way they talked about that product four months
Speaker 3:  ago was like, we have to pretend this is the thing and the way they
Speaker 3:  talked about Apple Intelligence today, but was like, this is the thing that
Speaker 3:  changes your experience with this phone forever.
Speaker 5:  What is the cool stuff here? Because I, I mean I obviously see there
Speaker 5:  or wasn't there, I watched it here at this beautiful house, the image
Speaker 5:  playground I was really excited about, but I can just like do that right
Speaker 5:  now with most online image generators. What are the other like
Speaker 3:  At high, at higher quality?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Right. They will look better. Yeah. My, my shit post will be
Speaker 5:  infinitely better with something else. What, what is cool? Like we
Speaker 5:  got chat GPT integration, we got image playground, we got emojis,
Speaker 5:  which is like make your own emojis. That's cool. That rules.
Speaker 5:  What's the other AI stuff? Like what is this for? Oh, we, the the math notes
Speaker 5:  where we'll like calculate the math.
Speaker 3:  I think that's from everything. I don't think I, that's like ai but it's
Speaker 3:  the old kinda, it's
Speaker 5:  The old AI
Speaker 4:  That's, this is, I mean this is the weirdest thing about all of the Apple
Speaker 4:  Intelligence stuff is like, you and I kept accidentally disagreeing with
Speaker 4:  each other on the live blog, which I really enjoyed. You kept saying so weird.
Speaker 4:  We're 45 minutes in and there's been no ai. And I kept saying, all they're
Speaker 4:  talking about is AI because like every single one of these features, it's
Speaker 4:  just AI underneath. Yeah. It's not the AI they're talking about. And there
Speaker 4:  is this like long spectrum of what is just software
Speaker 4:  and what is AI and what is like new and it's, it's all
Speaker 4:  sort of compressing together.
Speaker 5:  Fuzzy as AI's definition is right now
Speaker 4:  For sure. But like the, the everything on the iPad pure ai
Speaker 4:  and they didn't talk about it as AI at all. They in fact pulled it out of
Speaker 4:  the thing where they talked about AI and talked about it separately. But
Speaker 4:  I think all the intelligence stuff to me felt like
Speaker 4:  a sort of developer demo in a very real way. Right? Yeah. Like this is a
Speaker 4:  developer conference and I think it, it, it made me think of the Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro thing actually because to some extent, like what Apple is doing with
Speaker 4:  all of this is saying, look, we built a bunch of really cool technology,
Speaker 4:  here it is. Please go do something interesting with it. And
Speaker 4:  so far, the Vision Pro, not so much we'll get to that later, but I
Speaker 4:  I was kind of struck by the same thing of like, this is a lot of talk about
Speaker 4:  the logistics of a compute cloud and not a lot of talk about
Speaker 4:  features that people can use. Yeah. And there's a bunch of Siri stuff and
Speaker 4:  I think we, we can talk about what's coming to Siri, but this idea,
Speaker 4:  I think especially of the sort of Siri app intense thing where you
Speaker 4:  can talk to your phone and it can do stuff on your device for you. That's
Speaker 4:  the whole thing. Yeah. And, and I feel like Apple didn't weirdly sort of
Speaker 4:  connect those dots today because they have this big idea of what Apple Intelligence
Speaker 4:  can be. They have to convince everybody that this is going to be humongous
Speaker 4:  and like the size of, you know, The iPhone as an industry. That's how you
Speaker 4:  keep growing. If you're Apple, this whole thing I just could not stop thinking
Speaker 4:  was like Apple executives talking to investors like in a very real way. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yes. With them being like, please we, we have a growth plan. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  be so successful. Don't let us be the third most valuable company
Speaker 4:  anymore. Like give it back to us.
Speaker 3:  Well, I'll just give you the, the clearest, the clearest evidence of this
Speaker 3:  that I can offer you. The keynote ended and we did not go to look at any
Speaker 3:  demos. Yeah. We went to we we had lunch. Yeah. How was it? It was
Speaker 3:  fine. I I I eat the, I ate the corporate food with an immense amount of guilt.
Speaker 3:  So it was, it was fine. It was, you know, apple, they have a good chef at
Speaker 3:  Cafe Maxx or whatever, but, but there were no, there was not like a thing
Speaker 3:  where we like ran around playing with a bunch of AI stuff afterwards. Right.
Speaker 3:  And I even think to some extent that OpenAI partnership is so that no one
Speaker 3:  is comparing Apple to OpenAI. Oh.
Speaker 5:  A hundred. I like, I think the AI OpenAI partnership is almost
Speaker 5:  exclusively for investors rather than actual people.
Speaker 3:  Well see, we, we have to get the stuff and like Ba Craig said,
Speaker 3:  any place you see a blinking text cursor is a place where you can use this
Speaker 3:  integration Yeah. In the system. That's pretty interesting. Yeah. Well
Speaker 5:  A lot of it also felt like very windowy.
Speaker 5:  Like a lot of the big, the biggest tools, the coolest stuff was like, oh,
Speaker 5:  that's also stuff Microsoft announced. Oh yeah. Like, like, oh are
Speaker 5:  we can convince an email.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Cool. Yeah, it's really, it's, it's like
Speaker 4:  genuinely insane to me how similar
Speaker 4:  everybody is doing ai. Like, God help me if
Speaker 4:  one more company is like, we have an idea for how to summarize your emails
Speaker 4:  so that you can read them faster. Like, I'm good. Yeah. We have solved that
Speaker 4:  problem. That I don't think was a real problem.
Speaker 3:  Did you, did you see the fake email that they made? Nicer? It was actually
Speaker 3:  very good.
Speaker 4:  Was it? You
Speaker 3:  Should get the screen cap of this from the keynote, but they're like, you
Speaker 3:  know, sometimes you're write an email at work and it's a little too spicy.
Speaker 3:  You need to make it nicer. And then there was like, they flashed up a mean
Speaker 3:  email and it was like, guys, we have to stop doing this bullshit.
Speaker 3:  And you're like, oh that's, that's how Craig emails.
Speaker 3:  I must insist that you like blah blah blah. And they made it nicer and it
Speaker 3:  was like, gentlemen, I must once again ask that you stop
Speaker 3:  fucking it up.
Speaker 4:  Is it Jeff Bezos who was famous for forwarding customer emails to people
Speaker 4:  with just a question mark. It's very good. I'm imagining now you take that
Speaker 4:  you can really and high the question mark and you're like, make this nice
Speaker 4:  and it's just like, hello everyone. Yeah. I received this email from a customer.
Speaker 4:  Can you,
Speaker 3:  There's a real part of this to you point about features in the only the six
Speaker 3:  ideas they are playing a little bit of catch, right? Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  Microsoft's been out there making Google dance this whole time. Like it's
Speaker 3:  hard to demo features and say like, we made it more personal until
Speaker 3:  you get to Siri and all the stuff they think Siri can do.
Speaker 3:  Which is you just ask Siri, what time do I have to leave? So you get to my
Speaker 3:  daughter's to answer settle, this is the example they used 50 times. And
Speaker 3:  then Siri has to know that you have a daughter and where she is and where
Speaker 3:  that dance recital is and what your schedule is. I think
Speaker 3:  Federer you pointed out like it has to know if you like using Uber or Lyft.
Speaker 3:  Like you just, you go down the list of things you do on your phone and you
Speaker 3:  need all what they call personal context to make it work. And right now
Speaker 3:  none of the other compute models we've seen pull this off. Yeah. Maybe
Speaker 3:  Google will get there on Android. They're less good
Speaker 3:  at making the people who work at Google talk to each other than Apple.
Speaker 4:  But those are the only two companies that even can't, they're
Speaker 3:  Only two companies that come close. Yeah. And like Google to some extent
Speaker 3:  was trying to show these ideas right. In a less sort of like focused way.
Speaker 3:  Apple was straight up like, here's what you're gonna do. You're gonna pick
Speaker 3:  up Siri, you're gonna say I gotta get to this dance recital, make it happen.
Speaker 3:  And then Siri is gonna run off and tie into all the app intents on your phone.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna book a thing, it's gonna move a meeting, it's gonna call it today.
Speaker 3:  And you're gonna get in the car, you're gonna look at the dance recital.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna say edit me a video. It was a fishing trip. That was the demo.
Speaker 3:  I think that's like, I went fishing, make me a video of this fishing trip
Speaker 3:  of my son learning to fish and Siri is just gonna talk to whatever
Speaker 3:  video editing app is on your phone that you've chosen. It's gonna like read
Speaker 3:  all the videos for you. It's gonna make a thing. It's gonna pick a song about
Speaker 3:  fishing from Apple Music. Here you go. Bob's your uncle, you're all done.
Speaker 3:  Right. And like this thing, those are the features. They
Speaker 3:  need a bunch of developers to expose all the hooks. Right. So
Speaker 3:  that Siri can actually do it. I, I think it is very interesting that they're
Speaker 3:  going to app intense. They're not doing the the stuff that we thought they
Speaker 3:  might do, which is like screen reading your phone and clicking
Speaker 3:  around for you. I think everyone has realized like that idea sounds great
Speaker 3:  but is ultimately not trustworthy. I think it would also break Apple's
Speaker 3:  relationships with its developers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's also unnecessary if you have a gigantic developer ecosystem
Speaker 4:  of people who are very happy to build stuff for your platform.
Speaker 5:  But that means they have to be happy to build stuff
Speaker 4:  For this platform. Right. Which is super debatable right now I feel
Speaker 5:  Like. Right? Yeah. Because this would also your, your example that means
Speaker 5:  okay I'm not checking Outlook to, to find the email for when the recital
Speaker 5:  is, I'm not checking Outlook to move this. You can tell I use Outlook to
Speaker 5:  use to, to move my calendar around. I'm not going to Uber into the Uber app
Speaker 5:  myself or the Lyft app. It's gonna auto choose all of that. Like
Speaker 5:  that suddenly that's lost revenue for a lot of different people. Right. Just
Speaker 5:  to make my experience. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Uber CEO is like, all right, when do I upsell you to Uber Plus or whatever,
Speaker 3:  right.
Speaker 4:  Nonsense. Right. What this means is the subscription
Speaker 4:  economy in apps goes through the roof because all of a sudden I just
Speaker 4:  need you to sign up for my thing. Right. Like if I'm Uber, I don't actually
Speaker 4:  care if you're in the Uber app for the most part, as long as you're using
Speaker 4:  Uber because I make money when you use Uber. So actually making it easy for
Speaker 4:  you to use Uber
Speaker 4:  benefits me to some extent. Right. Whereas if I run Yelp and
Speaker 4:  I'm an ad-based system, I have exactly zero
Speaker 4:  incentive to be part of this because all I'm doing is giving you the information
Speaker 4:  that you want without you having to come look at my ads. So like the end
Speaker 4:  of this is, and I think this is true with a lot of AI, is you look at a lot
Speaker 4:  fewer things but you pay a lot more subscriptions. Yeah. And that,
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 4:  Hate that. Dunno how I feel about that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I, I can say I hate that. I don't wanna spend more money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But they did say they have something called onscreen awareness, which is
Speaker 3:  they will know the state of your phone as you're using it. They'll able like
Speaker 3:  help you. Again, this is Google apps
Speaker 4:  Google maybe
Speaker 3:  A million years ago. We have an entire feature about Google Nile from like
Speaker 3:  10 years ago.
Speaker 3:  Like these ideas have been floating around for a while and I think it's been
Speaker 3:  very hard for Apple to make them see do in this context. 'cause we just
Speaker 3:  came, we're in developer conference season, this is the end of it. And the
Speaker 3:  same ideas have been demoed over and over again. The one that struck me as
Speaker 3:  particularly interesting is type to Siri.
Speaker 3:  'cause they kept saying it's, you know, chatbots are not this, we actually
Speaker 3:  keep people safe by not letting them just do chat bot stuff. That's how you
Speaker 3:  break this stuff and find its weaknesses and make it do evil stuff. Also
Speaker 3:  you can now type to Siri. Yeah. And it's like first of all, they should
Speaker 3:  have had type to Siri from the very beginning of Siri. I think Paul Miller
Speaker 3:  on this show is like, it is a crime that you can't just like type
Speaker 3:  Siri a command that you have to talk to it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like an accessibility nightmare.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But this
Speaker 4:  Is, well it does exist but you have to pick, which is ridiculous. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like I'll just remind everybody that Siri launched, like the year The Verge
Speaker 3:  launched. Like that's how old this thing is. Like
Speaker 4:  Who do you think has done better?
Speaker 3:  We are told that it's like a billion and a half request of Syria Day. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Just slightly behind the vch. Yeah. People command us to do set timers
Speaker 3:  all day long. The Vergecast hotline is just like five minutes.
Speaker 3:  But they should have had it from all long and now they do. So you can type
Speaker 3:  to Siri whether that feels like a chat bot to people or just commands
Speaker 3:  who, who knows. Yeah. One of the coolest features by the way they added to
Speaker 3:  AirPods for Siri is now when it asks you if you wanna do something, you can
Speaker 3:  just nod Yes. Or shake. No,
Speaker 5:  I'm very excited about
Speaker 3:  That. Very cool. So they're just kinda making Siri more natural and more
Speaker 3:  like available to you and then increasing it set of capabilities. None
Speaker 3:  of that is coming in the betas of iOS they're gonna be at Nope. That is just
Speaker 3:  gonna slowly increase over the course of now until
Speaker 3:  the end of iOS 18 and then we'll see what makes it, what gets pushed to iOS
Speaker 3:  19, whatever. But they're basically saying like, we're starting now.
Speaker 3:  We're, we're going, yeah. Siri's gonna become this thing. That's what we
Speaker 3:  want it to be. And
Speaker 5:  It and they're severely limiting what phones it will work on. Right,
Speaker 3:  Right. And it's, you know, it's unclear whether that's because they want
Speaker 3:  everybody to buy a new phone. They probably want everybody to buy a new phone.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 4:  Was gonna say, you don't think that's clear? I think
Speaker 3:  That's fair. Clear. Well it, it's, I, I think I need to like spend more time
Speaker 3:  thinking about the, the differences between the M1 and sort of like
Speaker 3:  whatever the A series The, iPhone, The, iPhone 15 Pro. Like
Speaker 3:  there's some stuff there that's different but yeah, they probably just want
Speaker 3:  everybody to buy a new phone and you're not gonna get some like M1 MacBook
Speaker 3:  error on two. Like I'm doing this. What
Speaker 4:  We get in theory, if this cloud computing thing works as well as Apple
Speaker 4:  says, you should actually be able to fail it pretty gracefully down and just
Speaker 4:  do more and more in the cloud as you get to older and older phones. Well
Speaker 4:  you
Speaker 3:  Want, yeah, you want the older phones With the older cell radios pushing
Speaker 3:  more and more of
Speaker 4:  Hell yeah dude, let's go.
Speaker 5:  Maybe the cell radios is it? Huh? Like maybe the cell radio is why
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Who doess Or they just wanna sell a bunch of phones. I dunno if you
Speaker 3:  looked at their last of earnings. Probably they're desperate for an upgrade
Speaker 3:  cycle. Probably a mix.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But I do think this is an unusually developer dependent feature. Not only
Speaker 4:  to plug into the intents, but like one of the things Apple did a lot of
Speaker 4:  today, and we should get into it, like we have a lot of oss to get to,
Speaker 4:  but they opened up a lot of new APIs
Speaker 4:  and things people can tap into and gave them access to new stuff that's going
Speaker 4:  on in the system. And like they're both giving users
Speaker 4:  more stuff they can noodle around with. But also developers feel like they're
Speaker 4:  getting way more access to like the underlying stuff
Speaker 4:  happening on the device than they have in the past. And I feel like if you're
Speaker 4:  Apple and you wanna like make things work across the device, you have to
Speaker 4:  do that. But it also feels like this is Apple being like, okay, we are sort
Speaker 4:  of throwing open The iPhone in a new way. Please come
Speaker 4:  do cool things with it. Please. We need it so bad, please
Speaker 5:  Come. Yeah. Which is like wild for them to be doing right now
Speaker 5:  when probably their relationship with the developers has never been more
Speaker 5:  fraught.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. I spend a lot of time trying to decide how big a deal I think
Speaker 4:  that is because on the one hand, where the hell are you gonna go? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like what other moves do you have at this point? A hundred percent. And for
Speaker 4:  Apple, this is another chance to shore that up because if this increases
Speaker 4:  Apple's market share, it starts to fight against some of these other AI systems.
Speaker 4:  Everybody who's like, oh, open AI is gonna break the paradigm of the smartphone.
Speaker 4:  Apple can just sit here and be like, gotcha. We win and come make apps
Speaker 4:  for us again. Yeah. But at the same
Speaker 3:  Your rabbit.
Speaker 4:  Right? Right. But at the same time it is, it is true that there are a lot
Speaker 4:  of developers who do not believe Apple has their best interest at heart right
Speaker 4:  now.
Speaker 3:  And especially at the point of the all this stuff is to obviate the app.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like
Speaker 3:  I think, I think like fundamentally it's very interesting to look at
Speaker 3:  Apple under a little bit of competitive pressure. Like, where are you gonna
Speaker 3:  go? Is like, that's the monopoly. Where are you gonna go? Like we, they have
Speaker 3:  all the customers. No one right now is like running
Speaker 3:  off by an AI powered Surface Book. Feder again today
Speaker 3:  said, technically we've been shipping AI PC since 2020.
Speaker 3:  Alright. And some people wanna call that a category now. And it's like they
Speaker 3:  are feeling pressure. It's good. Yeah. Like I, it's good for all of
Speaker 3:  technology when these companies are ferociously competitive and this stuff
Speaker 3:  has made them ferociously competitive. They all have the same idea.
Speaker 3:  It's all the same stuff. We make this email 10% nicer. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Email summarization wars, baby, let's go.
Speaker 3:  There's just a part of, but there's a part of this where at the end of it,
Speaker 3:  it's just like, I'm sending David a robot email. It's his robot's
Speaker 3:  summarizing it. He's sending me some weird mutant Jen
Speaker 3:  Moshe response. It's like, what have we accomplished
Speaker 5:  Here? I I love how it's just abstracting all communication. Like
Speaker 5:  that's all AI does now. Is it just abstracts everything we say. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You'll send the first email and then it'll just be AI forever. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then something will end up in your calendar. Yeah. And that'll
Speaker 4:  be great.
Speaker 3:  Some stuff that they did not announce, which I was curious if
Speaker 3:  they would, they announced AI image removal in the background of photos,
Speaker 3:  but not anything beyond that. Right. So basically Smart Eraser,
Speaker 3:  which like Google Photos has had forever and Lightroom now has,
Speaker 3:  that's really interesting. They're gonna add this to more with our products.
Speaker 3:  But you could go even farther and be like, you can just take people out of
Speaker 3:  these photos and like, they didn't demo that. Right? Yeah. So Apple is clearly
Speaker 3:  operating within some set of constraints. They did a lot of safety
Speaker 3:  checking around the gen, their generative AI tool, which again produces just
Speaker 3:  like horrific cartoons. I'm, I'm so excited. It's not nearly as photo realistic
Speaker 3:  as the other stuff that we see on the market. Like Meta's AI tool is just
Speaker 3:  like, just a weird spaghetti Jesus day and night. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Apple can't make anything of that quality. 'cause it's running everything
Speaker 3:  locally.
Speaker 5:  Well it's using all of like your images to train on it,
Speaker 3:  Right? No, it's not. It's no, there's no training. There's, so
Speaker 5:  Where is it training? How's it
Speaker 3:  Training? It just has a model. It's pre-trained model. It's running on your
Speaker 3:  phone.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So a pre-trained garbage model.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And they were very clear, actually David brought this up, the apple,
Speaker 3:  just like everybody else. Like Yeah. We, we trained on the public web for
Speaker 3:  its text models. Yep. Yeah. Just like Yeah, like you do. Like Yeah. And they're
Speaker 3:  like, publishers could have opted out and it's like what publisher is like,
Speaker 3:  get to make sure Apple Bot isn't scraping us. Maybe they were, I mean
Speaker 3:  everyone freaked out about chat v Weren.
Speaker 5:  There's one person was like,
Speaker 3:  I don't even know if we block it disclosure, we have a robot's file.
Speaker 4:  Someone
Speaker 3:  Else is in charge of it.
Speaker 3:  But like they said, they trained their image model on a bunch of Apple
Speaker 3:  owned images in order to maintain safety.
Speaker 3:  They selected the data they were training with, they licensed a bunch of
Speaker 3:  books and news archives and stuff. So all that stuff is sitting on the, on
Speaker 3:  the phone, which is why it's as limited as it is. It's not trained
Speaker 3:  on your data.
Speaker 5:  I was really
Speaker 3:  Training, training a model on even just the amount of photos in like a normal
Speaker 3:  phone. Like your phone would explode. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Also just horrible.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I don't wanna, I
Speaker 5:  Don't wanna, I don't wanna see anything. No, you, it, it does there.
Speaker 3:  That that's why, that's why you need to go from 35 to 38 tops.
Speaker 3:  Good comments on YouTube last week.
Speaker 3:  But like that last piece where like, how will we keep it safe? How will we
Speaker 3:  keep it from doing the weird stuff the other models have done. The weirdest
Speaker 3:  part about this is on your own phone code, running locally
Speaker 3:  on the phone you purchased with the operating system you're on, there's stuff
Speaker 3:  Apple will not let you do in a way that right now Apple doesn't sit between
Speaker 3:  you and what you type into pages. It doesn't sit between you and what you
Speaker 3:  can record with the camera. It doesn't sit with between you and what you
Speaker 3:  can edit and iMovie, but you open image playground and you're like, make
Speaker 3:  me some horrific stuff. And Apple's just gonna say no because
Speaker 5:  Apple doesn't want to run into what every single other company runs
Speaker 5:  into where it's like, oh no, you did a racism.
Speaker 3:  But that, so the difference is all that stuff is happening on a website controlled
Speaker 3:  by a company, on someone else's server. There's a lot of precedent
Speaker 3:  for, you know, once you're using cloud service, other people get to say what
Speaker 3:  you do with it. There's not a lot of precedent for, you are running code
Speaker 3:  locally on your computer company. If you can do,
Speaker 4:  Do it in airplane mode, should there be any
Speaker 3:  Rules. Right. And the one that I think of all the time, I've asked a bunch
Speaker 3:  of people about this, the one that comes to mind right now is Adobe Photoshop
Speaker 3:  will not let you print out a dollar bill. You really
Speaker 3:  scan a dollar into Photoshop and try to print it. I'll be like, no, it's
Speaker 3:  a dollar. We're not gonna let you do counterfeiting. The government has asked
Speaker 3:  us very politely to not enable counterfeiting and just like won't do it.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Like we've just, I I think everyone has sort of like accepted over
Speaker 3:  time. Yeah. You, you know, fine. Like don't do counterfeiting
Speaker 3:  in Photoshop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But that's very different than like, what, just reading the paper and,
Speaker 5:  and what kind of Apple tested on and what they're trying to get rid of. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like, it's just all the shit posting, it's, it's all the stuff like
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Sometimes you do wanna send something absolutely horrible to your phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like I bet Photoshop will let you print out like a bunch of butts.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. The Photoshop will absolutely,
Speaker 5:  In fact, and
Speaker 4:  I, the Apple will not let you,
Speaker 3:  I don't know if Fireies is ready for like, make a bunch of butts, but Firefly
Speaker 3:  runs in the cloud, right? Yeah. So we've accepted this thing where it's like
Speaker 3:  you're using someone else's computer, particularly for free and they
Speaker 3:  have to say, well, it's good or bad. Yeah. And we have some expectations
Speaker 3:  about what they will allow. You're using your own computer. There are no,
Speaker 3:  there we do not usually allow these things to have rules. Right. You
Speaker 4:  Can make all the butts you want. Right.
Speaker 3:  If you pick an open source,
Speaker 5:  I mean, that is the use
Speaker 3:  Case. Finally, finally, a way to sell Chromebooks at scale.
Speaker 3:  I PC is from Microsoft. All the butts you want.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, if you take an open source model and like run it on some PC today,
Speaker 3:  nothing's stopping you. Right. And there's not really a way to stop you unless
Speaker 3:  I know the chip makers prevented. Like that's just not gonna happen. Right.
Speaker 3:  Like I've asked Lisa Sue this question, I've asked Qualcomm this question,
Speaker 3:  they're like, yeah, if the government tells us not to allow stuff, we do
Speaker 3:  it anyhow. The point of this is I think people are gonna get this, they're
Speaker 3:  gonna assume it's their computer and the thing that it will not be is a hundred
Speaker 3:  percent their computer anymore.
Speaker 5:  No. It, and I, I kind find, kind of find that a little gross.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's, it's, I think if, if it was an just a straight up app, if it
Speaker 5:  wasn't like integrated into a whole bunch of other apps, I wouldn't feel
Speaker 5:  as gross about it. If it was just like, oh yeah, that's the app full image
Speaker 5:  generator app. It won't let you make butts. I'd be like, okay, that's fair.
Speaker 5:  But like, okay. If you wanna make butts in any of these other tools, I
Speaker 5:  should be allowed to,
Speaker 3:  Well, I think we're, have our first test.
Speaker 5:  I'm so excited. Apple,
Speaker 3:  Apple, apple. The, again, the vibe at WC is like, we know people are gonna
Speaker 3:  do weird stuff with our thing. We'll take it down when we need to. They,
Speaker 3:  they very much know that the systems will hallucinate and there's gonna be
Speaker 3:  some weird outcomes. They're just like, ready for it. Yeah. But it, I just
Speaker 3:  like, and then I think we should take a break and actually talk about all
Speaker 3:  the OSS after this. But like the one piece of this that like philosophically
Speaker 3:  I'm thinking about is like, this is the first time an operating system is
Speaker 3:  gonna be straight up. Like no, no,
Speaker 5:  I, yeah.
Speaker 3:  We're just not gonna let you do it. And Apple's approach to it is like, we
Speaker 3:  are the ones generating it, so we're gonna set the rules.
Speaker 5:  That's just, that feels weird to me. It's
Speaker 3:  Weird. It's gonna be weird.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't like that.
Speaker 3:  And all the other ones are on the cloud, so you can't like roll up to Google
Speaker 3:  and be like, here's what I wanna do with your data center today.
Speaker 5:  I think I just wanna say free the buts. Like, we gotta free, we gotta
Speaker 3:  Take a
Speaker 5:  Break. So we're taking a break. We'll take a break. We'll
Speaker 3:  Fine. Every, everybody think about what you, whatever you need to think about
Speaker 3:  what we run.
Speaker 5:  Free the buts. Free
Speaker 3:  The buts. Well, we're right back.
Speaker 4:  I feel like the first one we should start with is
Speaker 8:  customizable. You can like resize the tiles and you can move things around
Speaker 8:  and then that kind of feeds into the lock screen
Speaker 8:  where you can change the shortcuts. The like,
Speaker 8:  what is it? Flashlight in camera?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, flashlight. Bottom, left camera, bottom right. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 8:  Which for some reason I have trouble hitting those things, but you can change
Speaker 8:  'em and you can make them pretty much anything that's in the control center
Speaker 8:  options. I think
Speaker 3:  The Haylight folks are very excited because you can just put Hali in
Speaker 4:  Video keynote. True.
Speaker 3:  Right on watch watch screen. Yeah. Which is wild. Like do I
Speaker 3:  want to blame this on EU regulatory pressure? I would like to blame,
Speaker 5:  But it's rules. I think it's
Speaker 3:  Great. It's cool. It's just like what everybody wants is to be able to reprogram
Speaker 3:  a bunch of these buttons to different kinds apps. Yeah. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's, I mean it's something that Android's been doing what, since it
Speaker 5:  started
Speaker 8:  A long time. I would
Speaker 3:  Say
Speaker 4:  It is so funny watching Craig Rigi stand on stage and be like, look, I
Speaker 4:  have an app icon. I can put it anywhere I want. Yeah. And it's like, oh my
Speaker 4:  God, Craig
Speaker 3:  By the way, I just wanna put
Speaker 4:  You, you can't put No, you can't. No thank you.
Speaker 3:  No, it's still a grid.
Speaker 4:  I compared to the stage manager in the live blog and a bunch of people gave
Speaker 4:  me shit for it. And I'm Right. It's stage manager. It's
Speaker 3:  Not like a preform, you can't get to like desktop levels of
Speaker 3:  crazy. Yeah, it's a grid. Yeah. And you can put some stuff on
Speaker 3:  one side or the bottom, honestly,
Speaker 5:  Moving out of the grid and making you be like, allowing you to put wherever
Speaker 5:  you want would be good security for them. 'cause if you get somebody's phone,
Speaker 5:  you're like, ah, I don't fucking know where any of these apps are.
Speaker 8:  It's
Speaker 3:  Just a pile. It's just a pile.
Speaker 5:  Oh God. Like done.
Speaker 3:  They also announced what I, I think should just be known as the Grinder feature.
Speaker 3:  Oh, the Ashley Madison if you will. Yeah. Where you can have a folder
Speaker 3:  full of hidden apps that are locked.
Speaker 5:  I was like, oh, what are those hidden apps? Oh, well if you're married, I
Speaker 5:  know what those hidden apps are. So
Speaker 8:  Sensitive information.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna be suspicious of all of y'all's phones.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's where I put the, the notes for things. I'm gonna buy my wife because
Speaker 4:  I just don't want her to know ahead
Speaker 3:  Of time. You're real sweet.
Speaker 5:  A whole app just for that.
Speaker 4:  No, but so I'm very excited about the, the apps on the home screen thing.
Speaker 4:  Like that rules. Just the thing where you can put a row of them on the side
Speaker 4:  and nowhere else. Wonderful. Yeah. Like that's where icons
Speaker 4:  should go. Like if you've ever tried to use your phone in one hand, it's
Speaker 4:  stupid that there are icons everywhere. Anyway. The thing that I think
Speaker 4:  is bad is the, the color themeing that Apple is trying to do. No,
Speaker 4:  I've seen a bunch of screenshots of this. So in theory you can, like apps
Speaker 4:  will be able to theme their own apps, so you'll be, or their own icons. So
Speaker 4:  you'll be able to do lots of different things with it. But you can also,
Speaker 4:  it seems like just brute force a color across the whole home screen.
Speaker 4:  Every single screenshot I've seen of it from Dev so far looks like
Speaker 4:  trash.
Speaker 5:  That's because they haven't done it. Right. It's gotta be that really horrible
Speaker 5:  green and you've gotta have like the matrix background on your phone
Speaker 5:  and then it's gonna be sick. I
Speaker 8:  Don't believe that.
Speaker 3:  I don't think so. I dunno if anyone has ever seen Kranz Slack theme
Speaker 3:  Unusable. Yeah. An unusable.
Speaker 5:  I it's, it's a beautiful security measure. No one's gonna be like looking
Speaker 5:  over my shoulder at Slack because they're gonna be like, Nope. Mm.
Speaker 4:  It screws, you know, you have to look at it. Right? Like, that's, that's
Speaker 4:  the, the
Speaker 5:  Challenge there. Yeah. But you like, you just harden yourself.
Speaker 4:  This explains a lot of why sometimes I'll Slack you and like eight days later
Speaker 4:  you're like, oh hey.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't like it. But no, I, I thought, I thought that was like both
Speaker 5:  the dumbest thing and also my favorite thing. 'cause like if
Speaker 5:  there's the potential to make it look really pretty, you could
Speaker 5:  theoretically, but every example they had on there was like
Speaker 5:  horrible. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  What Google has done with Material UI think is is great. And they've done
Speaker 4:  a good job of making it match with backgrounds. And that's some of what Apple
Speaker 4:  is trying to do here, it seems like. But I don't know, it's just like a weird
Speaker 4:  brute force thing that I'm, I'm not into
Speaker 5:  Even the sample he did where he is like, it's like the dog and then there's
Speaker 5:  bunch of tennis balls and he was like, yeah, I can choose a color from here
Speaker 5:  and immediately chose the tennis ball color. So like that was like, that
Speaker 5:  was in the demo. Yeah. He made it look like garbage in the demo.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. I You got, you choose all of, you underestimate the power of
Speaker 3:  teens to theme their phones. Like this is for
Speaker 3:  some huge percentage of people. This is the reason they have been jailbreaking
Speaker 3:  their phones. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Totally. No, no. There's gonna be so many purple and pink
Speaker 5:  very, very soon with like the comic sands font. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's gonna be amazing. I'm very excited for the, the teenagers to ruin
Speaker 3:  their phones. Yeah. But this is like table stakes stuff. Yeah. Apple
Speaker 3:  has not had forever and now they're like, okay, you can like customize your
Speaker 3:  on screen even more. And the reason they never had it before was because
Speaker 3:  Steve Jobs and maybe only Steve Jobs had the, the,
Speaker 3:  the conviction to say, most of you have bad taste and I don't want you to
Speaker 3:  make my phone ugly. And now they're outta those guys. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Jo Joni left.
Speaker 3:  He's gone. Yeah. What's he gonna do?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He was like, they like, and with him all good taste went too.
Speaker 3:  All the rest of the designers left. They're gonna throw up some other designers.
Speaker 3:  Like here's this guy. He made the fabric band on the Vision Pro.
Speaker 3:  He thinks we have horrible taste.
Speaker 8:  I feel like every year for the past few years we've been allowed to make
Speaker 8:  our phones a little bit uglier. Yeah, yeah. Like, we're just given a little
Speaker 8:  bit more
Speaker 5:  And, and we should be allowed to make them as ugly as possible. If I want
Speaker 5:  in MySpace. Let me,
Speaker 3:  It's, it's fair. It's so obviously coming. Just give it,
Speaker 5:  I'm so excited.
Speaker 3:  Even though even the control center stuff is really fascinating that there,
Speaker 3:  it now has pages.
Speaker 3:  I think Ford, CEO, Jim Farley was out there posting on threads about
Speaker 3:  how excited he is for the Ford Pass integration with
Speaker 3:  control center.
Speaker 5:  The Mach e got like a little cameo Yeah.
Speaker 3:  On the phone. You can, you can super unlock your doors from control center
Speaker 3:  now. Great.
Speaker 5:  I think they even unlocked the doors. I think they just turned on the air
Speaker 5:  conditioning in the car.
Speaker 3:  That was the demo during the keynote. But the, the integration has, you can
Speaker 3:  unlock the doors from your luxury. Awesome. It's just what everybody wanted
Speaker 3:  was to not have to use the FordPass app, but it's like, even that
Speaker 3:  is just, it's a little bit more, just let anything happen here. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like control center I think is a successful product
Speaker 3:  for Apple. I think. So it does the thing that everybody wants it to do. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And now it's just another surface to muddy up.
Speaker 5:  I did like, well 'cause Jim and I have talked about this a lot where we talk
Speaker 5:  about the smart home stuff. And the smart home controls in the control center
Speaker 5:  were pretty terrible.
Speaker 3:  They weren't great. Yeah. Because they kept on, they moved them around,
Speaker 3:  which is exactly what you don't want to Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're like, I wanna turn off my light. Oh cool. You decided I never need
Speaker 5:  to turn off my light.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's
Speaker 3:  The button. Because the, the four that they do, they auto-populate based
Speaker 3:  on what you've used last. Horrible. So if you're like, I wanna turn off this
Speaker 3:  light, you gotta, you end up all the way in the home app. Yeah. Whereas the
Speaker 3:  light you turned on yesterday is like, here I am ready to turn me on again.
Speaker 5:  No, I never go in that room. Leave me alone. Yeah. So, so I think the
Speaker 5:  fact that you can customize the home stuff more, that that was like, I was
Speaker 5:  like, okay. 'cause that gives me, that's like I think about how many swipes
Speaker 5:  it takes me to like turn off a light in my house. Right? Yeah. And right
Speaker 5:  now it's like, okay, I gotta go into the home app. I gotta find the look
Speaker 5:  for it. If it's not on that front page, I gotta go to the thing and now be
Speaker 5:  like swipe, swipe to the home section
Speaker 3:  And soon you're able to just be like, Siri dark. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Was just gonna to say, there's now like a lot of ways to do everything on
Speaker 4:  your phone. Yes. Because to some extent your home screen now has
Speaker 4:  widgets, your lock screen now has widgets. There's still the weird old like
Speaker 4:  today screen to the left of your home screen. Oh yeah. The, you can put stuff
Speaker 4:  in apps, you can long press on an app icon to do stuff. You can now, one
Speaker 4:  cool thing that I saw, you can long press on an app icon to turn it into
Speaker 4:  a widget in place on the home screen, which looks very cool. It's neat.
Speaker 4:  They like breezed through this stuff to get to the ai and there's actually
Speaker 4:  a lot of like little design details in I 18 that look really great.
Speaker 3:  The new settings for flashlight in the flashlight widget are awesome. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You can set the width of the beam of the flashlight. It's awesome. Beautiful.
Speaker 3:  They should have spent an hour on this. That's, I've like, yo,
Speaker 4:  I honestly believe like in any other year where Apple didn't feel like
Speaker 4:  it either had to or had an AI story to tell,
Speaker 4:  we would've spent like an hour talking about little tiny design details and
Speaker 4:  there would've been long videos about, like, I just saw one thing on Twitter
Speaker 4:  that now when you press the volume button, the bezel
Speaker 4:  indents slightly on the screen so you can see the button being pressed. Just
Speaker 4:  this like tiny little affordance that it looks like it's being pressed from
Speaker 4:  the side. Oh, that's beautiful. Love it. But also,
Speaker 3:  No, no, I know, I know what they're doing with that. You know what they're
Speaker 3:  doing with that. We all know what they're doing with that. They're getting
Speaker 3:  ready, ready to take the buttons away.
Speaker 4:  No, that was my next thought. Oh, that's interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I hate both of you for ushering that into existence.
Speaker 3:  Oh no. I mean the second I saw them be like, the screen will dink, I'm like,
Speaker 3:  oh, I know what you're doing.
Speaker 4:  It's true. You don't make my screen dink. But we, we have paired the lead
Speaker 4:  long enough. We got our RCS. It's RCS time. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  If you I screened loud.
Speaker 3:  IIII did a welp
Speaker 3:  I wish I had thought about it sooner. So at
Speaker 3:  io when they mention RCS, like the crowd goes wild. Like
Speaker 3:  Dieter rips the shirt
Speaker 3:  at the Apple event when their RCS shows up and he says it for one second.
Speaker 3:  And I don't remember RCS thing dead silence except for me.
Speaker 3:  And I believe Alison also cheered. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  When I realized you were Yeah. I was like, oh, I can do a cheer.
Speaker 3:  I should have just screamed Tee. Yeah. Just like that would've gotten the
Speaker 3:  laugh. I think other than that there was no, there were no sounds it no sound,
Speaker 3:  no other sounds
Speaker 4:  Were made. I bet you could hear you somewhere in the livestream if you, if
Speaker 4:  you do send it to us, vergecast The Verge dot com send us Neli screaming
Speaker 4:  about RCS.
Speaker 3:  There's a very famous bootleg of Jeff Tweedy from Loco playing in Madison
Speaker 3:  and I'm, it forced him to play the song Gun by Uncle Tupelo. And like it
Speaker 3:  goes out there and it's just me going gun. And he's like, really?
Speaker 3:  It's out there. You can find it. It's, it's not a legal recording. You know,
Speaker 3:  I,
Speaker 4:  The RCS, so we talked last week and we were debating like our,
Speaker 4:  how big a deal are they gonna make out of RCS? And I think where we landed,
Speaker 4:  if I'm not mistaken, was it'll be in the, the Bento box at the end that shows
Speaker 4:  all the features but they won't name it. And I would say we almost got that
Speaker 4:  he did say the letters Yeah. RCS out loud on stage as
Speaker 5:  The Bento box appeared.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. Right. It was like a brief, I was kind of like, oh, there's RCS
Speaker 4:  and then he said, and now we have RCS and then just breezed past it. Dead
Speaker 4:  silence.
Speaker 3:  They spent more, they did not like this.
Speaker 8:  They spent more time on the satellite messaging. Like you are
Speaker 8:  in the woods, you can now thumbs up emoji. Yeah. You know your friend.
Speaker 8:  And then we have RCS. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And the fact that you can now do text formatting, you can do like a Oh that
Speaker 4:  rules breakthrough in your messages now. Yeah. Which is definitely not gonna
Speaker 4:  work over rrc SI can tell you that with great
Speaker 3:  Content. Yeah. They asked a bunch of features on are Im message only so that
Speaker 3:  they could be like, now we have RCS by the way, SMS works over a satellite.
Speaker 3:  It's but not RCS. Yeah. I did that s message work the
Speaker 3:  satellites but not Rrc SI did think it was incredible
Speaker 3:  that in 2024 we went to a keynote
Speaker 3:  by the third richest company in the world
Speaker 3:  state-of-the-art computing company. And they're like, you can underline this
Speaker 3:  text. And then they're like, and you can also bold it and italicize it. And
Speaker 3:  people were like,
Speaker 4:  Well, and there was a moment in Sir one where he was like, now you can find
Speaker 4:  documents. And they're like, oh my god. Documents
Speaker 3:  Amazing. In the iPad where it was like, we've made file browsing easier.
Speaker 3:  It's like, dude, this problem is super solved. Like you just
Speaker 3:  refuse to solve it. Yeah. A lot of those moments where you just
Speaker 3:  re-contextualize old solutions into new places. Like you can't italicize
Speaker 3:  text and messages. Yeah. Yeah. I, I understand why it was just like
Speaker 3:  really it's the, it's the eye button that's been in every word
Speaker 3:  processor I've ever used a little slanty eye. You could just push it,
Speaker 5:  You could just anywhere. You can do it on Twitter or you
Speaker 3:  Could you ize. Nah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But you had to like, it was like weird. You had to like think about
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well now I can do it in messages. It's very exciting message. Also
Speaker 3:  got any emojis now a tap back in, in messages
Speaker 4:  That actually think is very
Speaker 3:  Exciting. People are super stoked about that. You can make your words
Speaker 3:  jitter and shake and explode. Right. Things the other, do
Speaker 4:  You guys use that stuff? Like do you I find I use the tap backs all the time
Speaker 4:  and that's about the only kind of wacky iMessage feature I
Speaker 4:  use consistently. I'm very excited. Except the birthday balloons. I love
Speaker 4:  the birthday. I rock the birthday balloons every time
Speaker 8:  I forget about them and I see 'em. They're very good. Oh that was nice.
Speaker 5:  I always forget about them until I'm like, oh congratulations. Oh I get fired
Speaker 5:  up.
Speaker 3:  Right. I am very excited about the ability to use any emoji as a tap pack.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think that's gonna
Speaker 3:  Effectively it just now you just have emoji responses which
Speaker 3:  every other platform supports. Whereas being like, haha, just like
Speaker 3:  this is too sarcastic.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. Right. It's like the, I use the thumbs up and the the bang bang
Speaker 4:  for way too many things.
Speaker 5:  I mean I use the haha when like I'm not truly engaged Yeah. In
Speaker 5:  conversation. That's what I mean. But I'm like, oh but that was funny point.
Speaker 3:  It's it's, it's the, you tried of emoji reactions. It's
Speaker 5:  Like I don't have any more energy for this. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I got nothing. It it makes you a dick whether or not you want be one. Like
Speaker 3:  it's not. So I'm very excited to expand the range. Blood tears
Speaker 3:  is my favorite. Yeah. Oh you're not gonna be able to get custom emojis. I
Speaker 3:  think blood tears might be a custom emoji just in our Slack instance. If
Speaker 3:  you wanna know what it's like working at The Verge often I reply with a picture
Speaker 3:  of a smiley face crying blood.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  True. It's super useful.
Speaker 3:  Externalism, it expresses so much about what we do here.
Speaker 5:  More than haha.
Speaker 3:  More than
Speaker 5:  Ha. Just way more than
Speaker 3:  Haha. What if, okay. Starting today. Haha means blood tears.
Speaker 4:  Tell everybody, just make it happen.
Speaker 3:  Tell
Speaker 5:  Your friends, tell
Speaker 3:  Your, tell your
Speaker 5:  We're just gonna make this a thing now. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You see these words? It means I'm crying blood.
Speaker 5:  I mean sometimes the jokes. Yeah, that's, that is a feeling. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Alright, let's keep moving. We got more platforms to do here.
Speaker 3:  Oh, you're talking about game mode. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What's some game mode
Speaker 4:  There? You just did. That's welcome to game mode. You can now play
Speaker 4:  5-year-old video games poorly on your computer and there's a
Speaker 4:  new assassin. It's
Speaker 3:  On the
Speaker 4:  Whatever
Speaker 5:  The new assassin screens coming today.
Speaker 3:  Your phone on computer now about, we're gonna talk about Apple announces
Speaker 3:  and games from 2017. We're gonna get to the Mac. Sorry. Game mode prioritizes
Speaker 3:  wireless performance of controllers on your iPhone. Okay.
Speaker 4:  There. Done. Great. Congratulations to all of your wireless controllers.
Speaker 4:  Let's move on.
Speaker 4:  The next platform, and this is not technically a platform by Apple's definition
Speaker 4:  but I think we should talk about it, is photos. Because photos is like
Speaker 4:  a hugely used app and they announced a bunch of stuff including a giant
Speaker 4:  redesign that I would argue is not a particularly giant redesign.
Speaker 4:  It's just that they put a bunch of new
Speaker 4:  albums in your photos app that I am suspicious of their usefulness.
Speaker 4:  But now they exist. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's very like memories forward. Like it seems like
Speaker 8:  the actual photos you're going to look for are just right up there with
Speaker 8:  like, remember this time and here was this thing that happened.
Speaker 5:  Look at all your dead pets. Yeah. Yeah. Really, really enjoy
Speaker 5:  'em.
Speaker 4:  I just remember them. There was years ago at an iPad event, I think it was
Speaker 4:  the iPad event they did in New York. They put up this marketing image that
Speaker 4:  was a guy sitting like in a, in the crook
Speaker 4:  of one of the supports on the Brooklyn Bridge doodling on
Speaker 4:  his iPad. Sure. And it's like, sure. This is like a normal thing a person
Speaker 4:  does on their device. And every time Apple shows new photos features, I think
Speaker 4:  of that guy sitting on the Brooklyn Bridge because it's like this thing where
Speaker 4:  there is a whole album of just all your awesome pictures from
Speaker 4:  yesterday. It's like, no, I don't have any awesome pictures from yesterday.
Speaker 4:  Like I have a bunch of accidental screenshots, I have receipts
Speaker 4:  from the plane and I have a picture of my toddler that is the same
Speaker 4:  picture that I take of my toddler that's blurry and weird every single day.
Speaker 4:  Like I don't need this apple. And all of these things are made for like
Speaker 4:  extremely interesting worldly beautiful people who take
Speaker 4:  thousands of photos of themselves every day. Yeah. And I think none of those
Speaker 4:  people exist in the actual world. It makes me crazy. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They exist on Instagram. All my friends friends on Instagram
Speaker 3:  But they tap, they try. Yeah. Right. Like most people just using their
Speaker 3:  phones to take photos. But I do think the idea that that the app is not
Speaker 3:  memory forward is fascinating.
Speaker 3:  'cause it does imply you're taking more photos and videos than ever and it's
Speaker 3:  hard to find them. And the device should like sort them for you.
Speaker 4:  Which I buy in theory. Like it's good logic. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I mean I don't use Google Photos as my camera roll. Do you? I mean like on
Speaker 3:  The iPhone?
Speaker 5:  No I use the the photos app.
Speaker 3:  Right. And I think the sort of conflation of the photos app with the camera
Speaker 3:  roll is like fighting against Apple's goals here, which is to compete with
Speaker 3:  Google photos and other apps like Google Photos. And so it's just like at
Speaker 3:  some point it's, I just need to see all the photos I took I in a list
Speaker 3:  Google Photos right now actually it's the most infuriating feature is it
Speaker 3:  insists on stacking your photos for you.
Speaker 5:  Oh I hate that.
Speaker 3:  And it's like you took five of these frames and it's like, yeah, I, I know.
Speaker 4:  I would like to see all photos.
Speaker 3:  I would like to see them. Yeah. I don't want you to pick one. And I think
Speaker 3:  it gets weird when you think of the photos app is actually your camera roll
Speaker 3:  and not this like memory playground.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well I wonder also how much of this is the fact that we all review
Speaker 5:  devices?
Speaker 4:  What do you mean?
Speaker 5:  Like do most people take screenshots?
Speaker 3:  Yes. Okay. All the time.
Speaker 5:  On purpose. All the time. I take a lot
Speaker 4:  Of accidental screenshots. Yeah. That's real. Yeah. But I also take a lot
Speaker 4:  of purpose.
Speaker 3:  I know people have 10,000 screenshots and they're just like things,
Speaker 3:  conversations disappearing, messages,
Speaker 3:  Snapchats like all the stuff, like anything that happens on your phone. The
Speaker 3:  way the easiest, fastest way to capture is screenshot. Yeah. So you can actually
Speaker 3:  do some segmenting and making that stuff searchable and filterable from the
Speaker 3:  rest. Like there's a lot of good intent in this app and I think the
Speaker 3:  way it looks is like ever, it's
Speaker 3:  even more complicated than it's ever been before.
Speaker 5:  But I also think it is prettier than it's ever been. Like if you
Speaker 5:  think of where we started with eye photos to now
Speaker 5:  gorgeous app compared to eye photos. Right?
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's, I care about that. No,
Speaker 4:  I agree. It has gotten a lot better and I think as a like management
Speaker 4:  system, it makes sense that this is kind of what they're trying to do. It
Speaker 4:  just seems like this idea of we are going to constantly repackage your photos
Speaker 4:  and shove them at you. Feels like the wrong answer to me.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I do think some of the stuff they're doing, like they, I think
Speaker 4:  said the exact same. You can find your driver's license or your license
Speaker 4:  plate in your photos. The like the identical demo to Google,
Speaker 4:  which is just like, this is everybody's
Speaker 3:  I idea your driver's license
Speaker 4:  Was your driver's license. Okay. Google's was your license plate. Right.
Speaker 3:  Right. So you're Yeah it was what, what is my license? Slightly different.
Speaker 4:  Totally features
Speaker 9:  Two phones in order to
Speaker 4:  Get all your information. Right. And then I'll know everything about my particular
Speaker 3:  Well the demo of the, they're slightly different. They were, were so
Speaker 3:  slightly different. Google was, you just asked it, you just like asked
Speaker 3:  Google photos what my license plate number was. Right. And like told you
Speaker 3:  the answer. This one was you were in a web form and said enter your driver's
Speaker 3:  license number and like the Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  would go and get it. Oh. And like enter it for you.
Speaker 4:  That's cool.
Speaker 3:  Slightly different demo. Sure. Same exact result. Correct. You filled out
Speaker 3:  a meaningless number of form. Fine.
Speaker 4:  Welcome to the AI future. It's just a bunch of weird UI affords.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna row robots at the DMV until the DMV submits. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  My tax is paid for the shit.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's perfect. So that's photos iPad, which
Speaker 4:  I think was a weird one in that it was both incredibly disappointing and
Speaker 4:  also the single coolest demo of the day by a pretty wide margin.
Speaker 3:  I ended the iPad session with all Lifelog by saying I'm sorry.
Speaker 3:  That was overwhelmingly what I felt at the end of that. It was Why did you
Speaker 3:  think that was cool? The math.
Speaker 4:  The math thing was awesome.
Speaker 3:  Just the calculator. Right?
Speaker 4:  Just the single Just in terms of like Holy god this is cool technology.
Speaker 4:  Just the thing where he's writing down an equation and notes and he writes
Speaker 4:  the equal sign and it just does it. Yep. In his handwriting that ripped.
Speaker 4:  And then another one that I'm like, does it, does this help anyone with anything
Speaker 4:  in reality that exists? Yeah. I don't know where
Speaker 3:  Where they did the table tennis algebra and then he was like make a graph
Speaker 3:  of velocities. Yeah. No distance over velocity
Speaker 4:  Rules. They're just doing stuff on Chromebooks now. Like it's fine. But it
Speaker 4:  was awesome technology and yet I think, and I'm curious if this was your
Speaker 3:  It just the calculator app.
Speaker 4:  Listen, it was awesome.
Speaker 9:  Look, they spent 14 years to
Speaker 4:  Make the best
Speaker 3:  Him. People walked into this thinking iPads were gonna come outta wwc running
Speaker 3:  Mac os a thing. And you're like the calculator app
Speaker 4:  Did a thing that is important to say is that the
Speaker 4:  biggest cheer by a wide margin at this year's.
Speaker 4:  Www C was for the calculator app for iPad do with that. Which you will.
Speaker 4:  But it was not close. People
Speaker 3:  Saw algebra being done by a computer and they're like finally.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But
Speaker 4:  I found this one so fascinating because it was like we got the new iPad Pro
Speaker 4:  and the new iPads. What like a month ago, two months ago. Time is
Speaker 4:  whatever. Everybody was like, okay, this is a device
Speaker 4:  waiting for amazing software and like WWDC
Speaker 4:  is coming, this is gonna be the one. And we just super duper didn't get it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. Like just not even a little bit at all. And I don't
Speaker 4:  know if you guys felt this way being in there, but the energy
Speaker 4:  in the room was the lowest as he was describing like
Speaker 4:  share play improvements on the iPad.
Speaker 3:  Right. When he got to, we've added some UI improvements to the iPad and everyone
Speaker 3:  thought it would be like a window in system. Right. And he is like floating
Speaker 3:  tab bar. And then he said the word morph five times in row
Speaker 3:  just seamlessly morphs into the sidebar.
Speaker 3:  I don't know if you've seen anything morph. Famously the robot and
Speaker 3:  Terminator two morphs the video for Michael Jackson's black and white.
Speaker 3:  So the first morphing, good morphing ever done, he turns into a tiger.
Speaker 3:  Nothing about this hit on the level of Michael Jackson
Speaker 3:  turning into a tiger in the video for black and white. This
Speaker 5:  Was no two one
Speaker 3:  Houses like absolute zero zero response to this morphing.
Speaker 5:  It was, it
Speaker 3:  Was the mighty more from Power Rangers. I think emotional reactions from
Speaker 3:  everybody in that room, nothing on this hit the level of the
Speaker 3:  white ranger coming back. You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 4:  It's an impossible bar. Yeah. Impossible bar.
Speaker 5:  It's nobody else. I'm just surprised you know that much about the white ranger.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  I have morphing.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 4:  A lot. I
Speaker 3:  Grew up in a time of morphing.
Speaker 5:  These
Speaker 3:  Are core childhood memories.
Speaker 5:  Morphing was very popular in
Speaker 3:  The nineties. It was a big deal. Like a lot of late nineties, early two thousands.
Speaker 3:  Culture really revolved around morphing if you ever, I'm just saying the
Speaker 3:  guy, he said, we watch the tab or seamlessly morph into the sidebar. I was
Speaker 3:  like,
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it is baby morphing.
Speaker 4:  We should move on. But I just wanna say, if you ever write like a Soufan
Speaker 4:  Steven style album, I grew up in a time of morphing. Is this title of your
Speaker 4:  single?
Speaker 3:  It's just, it was oddly prevalent. Alison's with me. She knows
Speaker 5:  There there wa Yeah. There was a lot of morphing. There was morphing.
Speaker 3:  They were, they were mighty and they were power.
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 3:  Were only, only one verb in there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right, let's move on. That's enough for the iPad. The iPad
Speaker 4:  still disappointing now with the calculator.
Speaker 4:  I put watchOS next but it's really a tie between,
Speaker 3:  Wait, can we say two things on the iPad? Sure. There are two things. One,
Speaker 3:  they announced the most important feature of all for anyone who has a parent
Speaker 3:  with an iPad. You can now take over their screen. Oh I missed that. So
Speaker 3:  when you're FaceTiming with them, you can share play and they're like, what
Speaker 3:  am I doing? You can draw on their screen to call their attention to something
Speaker 3:  you want them to do or you can just do
Speaker 4:  It. That's cool. Killer feature. Yeah. That's a good feature.
Speaker 3:  Absolutely. Killer feature. And then the weird dynamic
Speaker 3:  handwriting font thing, they're doing smart script. Oh. Or you draw it and
Speaker 3:  it smooths out your handwriting but then also sort of creates handwriting
Speaker 3:  for you. It's unclear whether there's like a system wide
Speaker 3:  typeface or it just has a model of your handwriting that you can now copy
Speaker 3:  and paste. You can paste, you can copy text from somewhere else. Paste it
Speaker 3:  into a document. Your handwriting. In
Speaker 4:  Your handwriting. That's pretty awesome. Couldn't
Speaker 5:  You do that on like a surface device five years ago? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But now it's on the
Speaker 3:  IPad. Yeah. Look, they didn't head windows. They added a
Speaker 3:  morphing tab bar, task bar. And you get smart. They
Speaker 5:  Were like, we're gonna set the bar real
Speaker 3:  Low. It's very low. And
Speaker 5:  Then we're gonna go
Speaker 3:  Slightly. People thought they were gonna run Mac os on their iPads coming
Speaker 3:  outta this event. Smart script people
Speaker 4:  Were not.
Speaker 3:  Correct. And David got a calculator. You know what's ironic? All the algebra
Speaker 3:  you do at work. This
Speaker 4:  Is actually, this is a good segue into the next one. Let's do Mac os next
Speaker 4:  because what we actually got is much closer to the exact opposite
Speaker 4:  of getting Mac Os on your iPad. We got iPhones on your Mac.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Mac os Sequoia. How do you feel about Sequoia?
Speaker 5:  It's like a, A name.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. It's a name. I, I've
Speaker 3:  Lo, I've lo live logged a W for like 10 years, 15 years now.
Speaker 3:  And when Craig does the bit about the name, I literally just like take a
Speaker 3:  break and like Yeah. Crack my knuckles. I'm like, you're gonna, it's a name.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be a mountain. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We're good. They did or didn't get high. It's fine. Yeah. But yeah, the big
Speaker 4:  things we should talk about iPhone mirroring because this is one of those
Speaker 4:  things that I think this is the big thing. Apple probably didn't expect to
Speaker 4:  be as exciting to people as it was, but is very exciting. And I think is
Speaker 4:  is like gonna be a huge deal.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean they're, they're missing a key
Speaker 3:  interface element.
Speaker 4:  You mean a digital crown?
Speaker 3:  It took the World bunch too. It's right up there. It's the click
Speaker 3:  wheel, it's Digital Crown, it's the track path. Three most important devices.
Speaker 3:  No, they don't have a touchscreen. It's like bananas. I can mirror a phone
Speaker 3:  onto your Mac without a touchscreen. But I think that the basic
Speaker 3:  idea that people wanna use their phone. There's a bunch of apps in your phone
Speaker 3:  that did not sign up for the Mac app store. When the Mac went to Apple Silicon,
Speaker 3:  which they really thought would happen. It did not happen. Yep. How are you
Speaker 3:  gonna get the Instagram app on your Mac? How are you gonna do it? It
Speaker 4:  Was a catalyst that was supposed to bring all that stuff
Speaker 3:  Across. Catalyst was iPad apps being remapped into Mac apps. Okay.
Speaker 3:  But now you can just run iOS apps on Apple, Silicon Mac
Speaker 3:  straight up, no porting. The Bluetooth lights in the
Speaker 3:  studio at my house have a horrible iPhone app. And it's the only, it's
Speaker 3:  the only app that has ever, I've been like, I wonder if that's here and it's
Speaker 3:  there. Sure. 'cause they don't care. Yeah. Instagram is like, no, we're not
Speaker 3:  letting you do this. Right. TikTok is like, we're not letting you do this.
Speaker 3:  We're not making you a Mac app.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You just mirror your iPhone and I, it's just the most
Speaker 3:  brute force. Like we're just horse powering your this screen
Speaker 3:  onto that screen. Solve the problem. The app's still running on the phone.
Speaker 3:  It's very cool. I think it will work. I think people are gonna use it all
Speaker 3:  the time. The coolest part, I dunno if you guys saw this. The notifications
Speaker 3:  get remapped that, so your notifications show up on your Mac and you click,
Speaker 3:  it has Mac notifications, it has Mac notifications and you click 'em and
Speaker 3:  it'll pop up in The iPhone mirroring and drop you into The iPhone. I
Speaker 8:  Mean I'm nervous about that. Yeah. But I already don't like how many
Speaker 8:  notifications I get on my iPhone. I'm like, are they gonna be on my computer
Speaker 8:  now too?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So you like AP News loves to push a breaking notification
Speaker 5:  for everything. Yeah. Is that gonna pop up on my, my Mac?
Speaker 4:  Well supposedly now thanks to the magic of ai,
Speaker 4:  all of your notifications are going to be sorted by priority. Which couldn't
Speaker 4:  possibly go wrong or be gamed by any systems because Apple has historically
Speaker 4:  done such a good job of managing notifications
Speaker 5:  Roll back. Like that's, that's all you gotta do.
Speaker 3:  No, they sherlocked the hell outta
Speaker 5:  Grs. I know they sherlocked it, but like they didn't make anything better.
Speaker 5:  No, that's,
Speaker 3:  They just made it worse. That's not what you do when you use your dominant
Speaker 3:  monopoly to kill your competition. Makes me so matter. It's not a choice
Speaker 3:  you're making.
Speaker 5:  But I am, I am excited about like the The iPhone thing just because I'll
Speaker 5:  be able to never have to get off my couch again when I need to like log
Speaker 5:  into something that needs two-factor authentication.
Speaker 3:  That's why you got an Apple watch.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's a good one.
Speaker 3:  You all think the Apple Watch is a health and fitness device. I think of
Speaker 3:  this as a two factor dongle. Does it have like, that shames me from, does
Speaker 3:  it
Speaker 5:  Have the authenticators on it?
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I use, I use Okta Verify and Authe on it. Well I'm
Speaker 5:  Thanks
Speaker 4:  To you actually because you have been proselytizing this for years.
Speaker 3:  We don't use any of those services. We use other ones. This was not a security
Speaker 3:  hole.
Speaker 5:  I don't have any of those on my watch.
Speaker 3:  We
Speaker 4:  Use the new Apple password that I'm
Speaker 3:  Downloading 'em right now. This is a, this is a two factor dongle that will
Speaker 3:  occasionally shame you for not standing up. And it's fine. It works. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's great. But I, but that thing where they added more iPhone to the Mac
Speaker 3:  Deeply, deeply funny. Oh yeah. They also, we talked
Speaker 3:  a lot about Siri in the AI section. They changed the way Siri looks and works
Speaker 3:  on the Mac to make it more powerful to give it more of these text inputs.
Speaker 3:  But like it's, they didn't change much. The big other feature they got a
Speaker 3:  lot of cheers in the Mac section was automatic window tiling, which Windows
Speaker 3:  has had for 100 years.
Speaker 5:  I have used it so much on Windows. And I have an app on my computer that
Speaker 5:  I like. When they announced it, I was like, but I thought we already had
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's it's one of those features that it is truly bonkers. It didn't
Speaker 4:  have already. Yeah. And there are a million apps out there that are free
Speaker 4:  and great for window tiling and will do it better than Sequoia I'm sure.
Speaker 4:  So go use those Magnet. I use one called Rectangle. It's very good. Highly.
Speaker 3:  That's a good name for an app. It
Speaker 4:  Is. It's very good. Very good. It's very good. And it's free and it's wonderful
Speaker 4:  and everybody should use it. But this, it's, yeah, there's so many
Speaker 4:  things in here that are just like Apple sort of slowly checking off boxes
Speaker 4:  of like features. It's insane that have not been here for a decade. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that's fine. I'll take
Speaker 3:  It. A lot of people have asked me
Speaker 3:  how to feel. I guess I, I don't know about Sari, how to describe this about
Speaker 3:  Safari. Yeah. Yeah. And the fact that it has AI summaries built into it now,
Speaker 3:  which is, I know you two love Arc, but a lot of people have feelings about
Speaker 3:  Arc doing that in different ways. Feelings about perplexity doing that in
Speaker 3:  different ways. This one feels much more innocuous.
Speaker 3:  'cause you're browsing the web and it is loading the webpages.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I have it turned off in Arc. I always forget that it's, it's there
Speaker 3:  Though. You just like Arc.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I just love Arc.
Speaker 4:  But that, that distinction you made I think is actually really important.
Speaker 4:  And as the whole thing, right? Like Apple's way of doing this is you go to
Speaker 4:  a webpage and then AI can do things to that webpage. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And like a bunch of it is really clever. Right? It's like there, if you're
Speaker 4:  looking for important information on a webpage, it will help you surface
Speaker 4:  it. Like Yep. If you ever go to like a restaurant website and you look for
Speaker 4:  the phone number, impossible. And this is like, it will just find you the
Speaker 4:  phone number. Like that's good. But you're already on the website, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And so now, now all you're doing is you're solving for awful web design,
Speaker 4:  which I'm fully in favor of. Like, hey, I should destroy bad web design.
Speaker 4:  But it, it flips the equation of the thing. Like it's not going to the webpage
Speaker 4:  and then returning information on my behalf. I am going to the webpage. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then asking it for information.
Speaker 3:  To be clear, we have not used this to any great extent. Like no, we've seen
Speaker 3:  some demos. We people have the private betas and they're publishing about
Speaker 3:  it. So like people are talking about it. But I think there's gonna be a lot
Speaker 3:  of back and forth between, hey, this web browser is now doing a lot of summary.
Speaker 3:  You have a big partner with OpenAI, which not everyone is so happy with.
Speaker 3:  I have a disclosure. Our company has a content deal with OpenAI.
Speaker 3:  Cool.
Speaker 3:  I dunno if we have one with anyone else,
Speaker 3:  but like, I, I think a lot of, a lot of the Safari work,
Speaker 3:  at one point the person who's presenting Safari was like, if you haven't
Speaker 3:  used it, you should try it. It got pretty good. Yeah. It's like, oh boy,
Speaker 3:  you need to get this back. Yeah. You gotta get this back on track. So they're
Speaker 3:  adding some features to it because as David has been covering an installer,
Speaker 3:  like Browser Wars are back, there's like a bunch of very interesting browsers
Speaker 3:  because of AI features. And so I think Apple needs to capture some of that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And the, like, the reader mode updates that it got
Speaker 4:  was cool reader's another one that it's like nobody's mad at reader mode
Speaker 4:  even though it strips everything out because you have to load the webpage,
Speaker 4:  you have to load the webpage. Like it's, that's just the whole thing. And
Speaker 4:  the, there's now the, what's it called? They call it the viewer mode where
Speaker 4:  it'll just pop up a video that's on the page if you wanna watch the video
Speaker 4:  and give you like native picture and picture and viewing controls. That's
Speaker 4:  very good. Awesome. Love it. Yeah. Incredible. It's making that websites
Speaker 4:  better. Unbelievable. Yeah. Huge fan. Make me go to the website.
Speaker 3:  Right. The the problem with all the other browser is like, you'll stop browsing
Speaker 3:  the web. Right. And then there's no more incentive to make web And I think
Speaker 3:  Apple's trying to walk the line here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. But I'm, I'm again, yeah, there's a lot of questions, but I'm
Speaker 4:  kind of in favor. Is does anyone sitting here use Safari with any
Speaker 4:  regularity? I, I do. Do you like on purpose?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. For, for until I'm switched to Arc, I would do like Edge is my work
Speaker 5:  browser and Safari was my personal browser.
Speaker 5:  I tried to keep the work separate.
Speaker 4:  So what I've learned about you in this podcast so far, you are a
Speaker 4:  devoted Mac user who loves Outlook and Edge,
Speaker 5:  Make better mail and web browser,
Speaker 4:  Use other devices. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Have you heard about these? IPCs? Yeah. You love being watched surface
Speaker 4:  By big corporations. Surface tight. Dude, you were also on this podcast not
Speaker 4:  long ago being like, oh, what Apple wants to do is build a surface. You can
Speaker 4:  just have one.
Speaker 5:  I know, but I don't want it. I I want, I want Apple to do what I want it
Speaker 5:  to. You
Speaker 4:  Just want U up your iPhone.
Speaker 3:  This is like, people in America are so confused about competition. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They're like, I'll just yell at Apple until it makes me the product I want.
Speaker 3:  I won't just buy the product that exists. Exactly. The party is the thing
Speaker 3:  I want.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's why I'm in the job I'm in. So I can, that's very yell everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Very.
Speaker 3:  Can we spend two seconds talking about gaming and then talk about passwords?
Speaker 4:  Literally two seconds. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Apple announced a bunch of,
Speaker 4:  That's it. Sorry.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna announce they they were like, you can now play Death Stranding
Speaker 3:  on the Mac that came, came out in 2019. That Assassin Creed
Speaker 3:  game. The one that is coming out. That's true. But another one came out in
Speaker 3:  2019 and then the big finale was Control Now with Ray Tracing
Speaker 3:  Control was the game of the year in like
Speaker 3:  2017.
Speaker 5:  It, yeah, it, the control is a game that everybody just uses to show off
Speaker 5:  Ray tracing. 'cause it has really good ray tracing. Like Yeah. That's kind
Speaker 5:  of why it exists in most people's computers now. I It's
Speaker 3:  Good game like Control is at the point where it's like, if you open the PlayStation
Speaker 3:  store on the right day, it's like, do you just want control? Yeah. Like you
Speaker 3:  should have it is like really good, you know, like you should try it out.
Speaker 5:  But the Ubisoft stuff was interesting. It did feel like Apple is trying to
Speaker 5:  kind of brute force its way back into the gaming conversation.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's been doing it for the last three or four years, but having the
Speaker 5:  Ubisoft like guy on stage, having the new
Speaker 5:  games come out on the iPad. On the Mac like day and date. That
Speaker 5:  that's, that's not nothing.
Speaker 3:  Wait, I got this wrong. Control is a Game of the Year contender
Speaker 3:  in 2019. The Assassin's Creed game came out in 2017. I'm sorry Zoe.
Speaker 3:  Apologies to
Speaker 5:  Everyone. Yeah, it's, they're all old. But
Speaker 4:  Also this, they're
Speaker 3:  Old game. This does, I was a different person. This was before the pandemic.
Speaker 3:  I was
Speaker 5:  Like, it's pre Covid. It's
Speaker 3:  Old. I used to, I was breathing on people every day.
Speaker 4:  This does continue Assassin's Creed's Perfect streak of being available on
Speaker 4:  every platform invented by
Speaker 3:  Anyone. If you add a computer and you're like, can I fucking stab someone
Speaker 3:  on this computer? Ubisoft is there.
Speaker 5:  They're like, yes. In a little French accent.
Speaker 3:  The new one is Infu Japan. All
Speaker 4:  Right. That's, that's too much Game mode talk. Let's talk about watchOS
Speaker 4:  briefly. This is the one I am perhaps least qualified to talk about because
Speaker 4:  I just went in and turned off all of the fitness notifications. Yeah. On
Speaker 4:  my Apple watch because they were making me sad. Now they like, do you wanna
Speaker 4:  stand up? And I was like, no, I'm on a call. Leave me alone Apple. But there's
Speaker 4:  like, if you're a fitness person and Allison, you're wearing a watch and
Speaker 4:  seem like a fitness person. There's a lot of new stuff here. This thing is
Speaker 4:  like a super intense health and fitness device. Now. It's getting serious.
Speaker 8:  I, I will say, and we'll give this shout out for Colleague V Song
Speaker 8:  that you can now finally tell Apple you're taking a rest day
Speaker 8:  and or like you're sick. You are not gonna go do your little jog or
Speaker 5:  Whatever. I think he's soft. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Probably. I like, I could feel it. I could feel her, you know,
Speaker 8:  energy.
Speaker 4:  He was typing in our Slack when this got launched and was typing in all caps
Speaker 4:  so fast. She was just making thousands of typos. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 4:  Happy your joy. Yeah. Yeah. But yeah, so there's, you can now take rest
Speaker 4:  days. You can also change your goals day to day throughout the week.
Speaker 4:  Which I think is very clever. There's a new vitals app that'll track new
Speaker 4:  stuff on your body. If I explain it more than that, I will immediately
Speaker 4:  sound as dumb as I am about all of this. You can rate like
Speaker 4:  the effort of a workout. It's basically like, this is all just health
Speaker 4:  inputs and outputs, right? Yeah. Like that is what this device is. Now
Speaker 5:  They, it felt like they added a bunch of stuff that other folks have been
Speaker 5:  doing. Like Aura Ring has been doing and Garment has been doing it. Especially
Speaker 5:  the health stuff. Like Aura has been all over that. Yeah. And it was like,
Speaker 5:  oh we, we, we've got all those sensors. We've in fact got better sensors.
Speaker 5:  We could probably do that. And Apple has just been really weird about it
Speaker 5:  before now and
Speaker 3:  Well they've been in a pretty healthy lawsuit. The company event. That's
Speaker 4:  Probably, yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  Probably why. But so, so it's, it's nice to see that. Yeah. You'll be able
Speaker 5:  I, the rest days is the big one though. I think. I think that was what the
Speaker 5:  one like I was seeing on threads even everybody was just like
Speaker 3:  Rest. Yeah that was the one the people ask that forever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah because it's, yeah, sometimes you feel like garbage and your watch is
Speaker 5:  like, you haven't moved at all today. You piece of shit. Yeah. And you're
Speaker 5:  like, because I feel like garbage. Thanks mom. Like leave me alone.
Speaker 4:  And it seems to get like meaner and meaner as time goes on. Like if you get
Speaker 4:  to like day three of not closing all your rings,
Speaker 4:  your watch is just so disappointed in you. Yeah. It's like, it's like you
Speaker 4:  get Yeah you get the message. It's like you didn't close any rings yesterday.
Speaker 4:  Like let's just try for one today. I'm like, I'm sorry, what's the bare minimum
Speaker 4:  you can get me? What you did anything today. I'm like I didn't even have
Speaker 4:  my watch on yesterday. Leave me alone.
Speaker 3:  Stand ring. We're gonna go for stand ring once
Speaker 4:  An hour. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Just stand.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna put my goal to three hours today. Let's go Apple.
Speaker 3:  That's good.
Speaker 4:  Alright, let's burn through the last ones then we can take a break. AirPods,
Speaker 4:  we talked a little bit about the AirPods. You not head shake. Oh yeah, nod.
Speaker 4:  Very good. That good. Unbelievably unconvinced that that
Speaker 4:  works. But if it does, I'm very excited. There are a lot of people out there
Speaker 4:  who are trying to make that stuff work. Turns out you move your
Speaker 4:  head a lot. I don't know if you've noticed, but like in just being a person
Speaker 4:  in the world, you move ahead your head a lot. And so figuring those
Speaker 4:  gestures out. I
Speaker 5:  Complic, I hope it's the same way. Like when you talk to your computer or
Speaker 5:  you use a voice, you have like your computer voice. I hope you have to like
Speaker 5:  have a computer head nod dramatically.
Speaker 4:  Head nod.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. So you're just like walking down the street doing these really dramatic
Speaker 5:  head nods. That would be ideal.
Speaker 4:  Which is definitely better than talking to yourself. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Not,
Speaker 4:  not weird to just constantly be walking those spaces. In both
Speaker 5:  Cases you'll probably get the car to yourself on the subway.
Speaker 3:  I was walking down the street in Philadelphia the other day and a woman rode
Speaker 3:  by on her bike and she just goes, Hey Siri, really loud, you have a
Speaker 3:  pods in. And I was like, literally like a lot of people stopped because that
Speaker 3:  was just a weird thing to happen. And I said out loud to the person I was
Speaker 3:  walking with, I've never seen anyone do that in the wild before. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  they're like, that was special. And that we had like, everyone's like the
Speaker 3:  whole street had a moment. 'cause she was like, I'm gonna talk to Siri while
Speaker 3:  I'm just biking. It's
Speaker 5:  Hard to do in public 'cause you're like, I'm always like, Hey Siri,
Speaker 3:  How are you? Yeah, no, she, I you gotta, no, she just Philly man with
Speaker 5:  Her whole chest. The whole, I love that point. Philly,
Speaker 3:  That's where, that's where you can just do it. Yeah. There are some towns
Speaker 3:  in America where you can just address Voice assistant. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The AirPods Pros, they're getting better like phone calls to
Speaker 3:  Microphone voice isolation. Yeah. Yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  Is a feature that has existed for a long time and is deeply buried
Speaker 4:  in settings on all of your devices. This is like a thing you can do on phone
Speaker 4:  calls now and it makes you sound so much better. Yeah. And it has always
Speaker 4:  driven me crazy that Apple doesn't just turn it on by default. But it's a
Speaker 4:  thing that exists on the Mac. It's a thing that exists on The iPhone, but
Speaker 4:  you have to turn it on for every single call like in the middle of the call.
Speaker 4:  And that's very stupid. And so the fact that it's just on now, there's also
Speaker 4:  the personalized spatial audio, which, you know, NE's favorite feature so
Speaker 4:  that everyone can sneak up on you during your phone calls. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's what you want.
Speaker 4:  But no, I'm, I'm into it. The AirPods,
Speaker 3:  They did it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're still AirPods. No more Air AirPods Maxes. I really thought
Speaker 4:  that we were gonna get AirPods today. Either it was gonna be a home pod or
Speaker 4:  a new AirPods maxes and they were gonna like make a whole series story out
Speaker 4:  of it. Nothing.
Speaker 3:  Whatever in thought was that they were gonna add Macs, the iPod and the AirPods
Speaker 3:  would be the focus of all the AI efforts. And all of you people were disappointed.
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 4:  We got a calculator app and it was sick.
Speaker 4:  TVOS we have covered several times. We'll just move on from there.
Speaker 4:  It'll now we're getting a new season.
Speaker 3:  The added 21 9 projector support to TVOS. Okay. This is the next hour
Speaker 3:  of the George Cast. I'm moving on excited
Speaker 4:  About this to speaking of the next hour of The Vergecast vision os
Speaker 3:  I will not name names, but a friend of ours, friend of
Speaker 3:  the show came up to us and they're like, so they're just giving up on the
Speaker 3:  Vision Pro and they, they, this person looked
Speaker 3:  bereft. Aw, bereft.
Speaker 5:  That's sad.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, no, I think they just, they announced four months ago. I
Speaker 3:  don't think they had anything left in the tank.
Speaker 3:  And like they're giving up on it. Well,
Speaker 5:  Wes Davis was going through all of the updates and he's like, oh, what
Speaker 5:  they didn't say on stage was that they're fixing a ton of bugs and
Speaker 5:  issues he's had with it. 'cause he's like the one PE person upset. He loves
Speaker 5:  it. He loves it. God bless him. He's always like, you wanna FaceTime? I'm
Speaker 5:  like, absolutely not.
Speaker 5:  Put that in the fire. But, but yeah. So he's apparently there's doing a bunch
Speaker 5:  of updates to it, but they just didn't talk about any of that.
Speaker 3:  They did not. Because I think you have to know what is broken about
Speaker 3:  the Vision Pro in order to appreciate the fixes. Yeah. And most people don't
Speaker 3:  know anything about the vision program
Speaker 5:  And they're like, we're not spending time on that. This
Speaker 3:  David is fond of reminding us it costs $3,500.
Speaker 4:  Seven outta 10 baby. Here we go.
Speaker 3:  I, I stand by my review now more than ever. Actually not the score, but the
Speaker 3:  review.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. No, I, I think it's right. And I think we, we have, we have continued
Speaker 4:  to find what is that? It's better out here than in there.
Speaker 3:  But they did add, they're adding more immersive videos. They're gonna release
Speaker 3:  more stuff. They're releasing it more countries, which actually got a huge
Speaker 3:  cheer that expands the market. Canons making a special
Speaker 3:  lens just for the R nine. Which Allison, I'm curious to you read on this.
Speaker 3:  Oh my
Speaker 8:  God, I totally like blanked that out. It looked like,
Speaker 8:  wasn't there a moment where some company was making a 3D lens for the camera?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like Fuji Film I think did the, like, you know, when
Speaker 8:  3D was gonna be the next thing, they're like, here's a camera lens that will
Speaker 8:  shoot 3D photos for you. And I was like, we're doing it
Speaker 8:  again. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Oh know, I can't tell if the, the EOS R nine, it was specifically the
Speaker 3:  camera they called out has a sensor or a
Speaker 3:  processing system that can take the split image. Right.
Speaker 3:  'cause what they're doing is they're making a right and left image and then
Speaker 3:  combining it somewhere. So I'm wondering if the camera has some setting but
Speaker 3:  it, it, the Canon's making a lens for one camera. It's not just
Speaker 3:  a canon lens like you would expect. It's for this one camera. So now you
Speaker 3:  can shoot Apple immersive with this one camera.
Speaker 5:  Is it the R nine or the R seven?
Speaker 3:  Was it the R seven
Speaker 3:  urine? Says it was the R seven urine's already bought the lens.
Speaker 8:  No. Oh my gosh. Live fact checking.
Speaker 3:  Maybe I just typed it wrong in the Lifelog.
Speaker 3:  Now I'm checking.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Again, I would say this is indicative of how important this actually
Speaker 4:  to the world.
Speaker 3:  It's zero seven actually. But I think this is really wild. 'cause there's
Speaker 3:  not enough content for this headset. Right. So that they spend a lot of time
Speaker 3:  talking about just like how they're building out the content pipelines for
Speaker 3:  the Canon EOS R seven. Thank
Speaker 8:  You.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no it's true. It's very clear that Apple thinks content is
Speaker 4:  the thing. Yep. And they, they announced like new environments, new
Speaker 4:  ways to look at the spatial photos, like new, new tools for showing this
Speaker 4:  stuff. It's very obvious to me that the two things they're seeing people
Speaker 4:  do in this are used it as a monitor, which is why they announced the new
Speaker 4:  ultra wide monitor, which looked awesome. I'm confident will not look like
Speaker 4:  that in actual use. But the idea of having one
Speaker 4:  wi giant like wall sized monitor in front of you kicks
Speaker 4:  ass. And I want it very badly.
Speaker 3:  I'm very excited to see if that means Mac OS will now support
Speaker 3:  ultra wides. Curved ultra wides more natively. Oh, that's interesting. So
Speaker 3:  right now if you get one of the crazy Samsungs, they just like don't work
Speaker 3:  very well. Right.
Speaker 5:  It would be hysterical if it only works with the Vision Pro.
Speaker 3:  It would be perfectly un brand. Yeah. If you could get a giant curve culture
Speaker 3:  wide in the $35 headset, but that same resolution could not be
Speaker 3:  displayed in an actual monitor. Just beautiful. Yeah. Notice, we'll see.
Speaker 3:  But I, people did cheer for that. It is the thing they're using it for.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, I, I I think that just means they're adding more display resolutions
Speaker 3:  to the Mac. Which would be good. 'cause there's a class of honors that
Speaker 3:  you really can't use very well with Mac right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and with that, that's the last we're gonna hear of the Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro for a pretty long time, I think.
Speaker 3:  But wait, can I, in my continuing quest to describe the, what is a photo
Speaker 3:  apocalypse? They added a feature right now you can shoot spatial audio
Speaker 3:  right now. You can shoot spatial video and photos with
Speaker 3:  your iPhone. I don't think you should do it. 'cause it actually really reduces
Speaker 3:  the quality of, especially in low light. So they and the
Speaker 4:  Files are monstrous.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And you can only look at them in headset. Yeah. Just like not
Speaker 3:  worth it right now. But they are adding a feature where it can
Speaker 3:  spatialize your regular photos, which means it is
Speaker 3:  creating a bunch of synthetic data for your eyes to look at out of one photo.
Speaker 3:  Yep. So you've got a left eye vision and it's gonna make a right eye or you've
Speaker 3:  got a right eye or whatever, whatever it's doing. It's just gonna create
Speaker 3:  a little bit of a depth map and it's gonna just
Speaker 3:  synthesize some information that super wasn't there in the photo.
Speaker 3:  That doesn't upset me. Is this the greatest? What is a photo crime? No, it
Speaker 3:  is not. Is it super weird that we're all just
Speaker 3:  racing ahead long into the future of synthetic imagery and being
Speaker 3:  like, oh that's fun.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But that's stuff they've been doing in like TVs for ages right?
Speaker 5:  When they do the auto upscaling and stuff. Isn't that the same thing where
Speaker 5:  they're just adding pixels where
Speaker 3:  Well no. So auto upscaling is, you know, you take like a a seven 20 image
Speaker 3:  and you just like make it bigger. Yeah. And, but I mean shows and you get
Speaker 3:  a bunch of AI stuff in there shows this is and like
Speaker 3:  that's still right. You're right that that's happening. But you're adding
Speaker 3:  pixels like in a 2D plane. Yeah, this is, they're gonna
Speaker 3:  add a 3D image. So you're gonna get another angle from like
Speaker 3:  if, assume the picture again as your left eye. You're gonna get another angle
Speaker 3:  on the same image and you're gonna see like a little bit of the side of someone's
Speaker 3:  head.
Speaker 5:  I cannot wait to look at a little bit of the side of Allison's head.
Speaker 3:  I but an AI Allison's head,
Speaker 5:  Right? Synthetic. Yeah. You're just gonna have like four ears. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It'll
Speaker 3:  Be great. I'm just saying it's just like one of those things where you're
Speaker 3:  like, oh, huh, they're just doing that. They're gonna totally synthesize
Speaker 3:  another image for you to look at to create a 3D effect.
Speaker 3:  That image never existed. Nope. It, it, it did not happen. You did not
Speaker 3:  capture it. This computer's just gonna confidently tell you this is what
Speaker 3:  your other eye would've seen and you're gonna be like, huh. That's weird.
Speaker 3:  It's a weird thing that's happening. I will say I know people, Liam is always
Speaker 3:  on me for endlessly going on about what is a photo. I ruthlessly use the
Speaker 3:  generative racer in my room the other day to take people outta the background
Speaker 3:  of a photo of my daughter. I'm as conflicted as you are. I am, but a man.
Speaker 3:  Okay. How
Speaker 4:  Did it make you feel? Huh? Do do you look at that photo differently now?
Speaker 4:  Awesome.
Speaker 3:  I do look at the photo differently 'cause I know what I did. But I don't
Speaker 3:  know that most people have a feeling of shame when they're done using Lightroom.
Speaker 4:  Generative shame is a whole thing we're not even
Speaker 3:  Ready for. They should mark it as shame.
Speaker 3:  We're about to, by the way, have a big story just weather about is working
Speaker 3:  on it. Regular photographers are now running into the reality that
Speaker 3:  any use of AI tools depends on watermark. Which then Instagram
Speaker 3:  will just like say made with AI and people have real feelings about that
Speaker 3:  label.
Speaker 3:  It's the vers for story that exists, but Justin working on it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Alright, well that's all the platforms. There's a lot we didn't
Speaker 4:  get to. I suspect we will talk a lot more about this both like on Friday
Speaker 4:  and for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 4:  But it was a lot like it was a big, it was a lot. This was a big day. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I think in it was a funny one 'cause in another world
Speaker 4:  just that run of platforms would've been a two hour.
Speaker 3:  That's why at the end of it I was like, are they done? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And as it was, they just blew through it. Like I think one of the things
Speaker 4:  we're gonna see over the next few days, because the developer Raiders are
Speaker 4:  out, we're gonna learn about so many things that didn't even come up or
Speaker 4:  get mentioned. They're not in blog posts, they weren't on the bentos. Like
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of stuff in these platforms. Talk bentos
Speaker 3:  Are getting surprisingly less
Speaker 4:  Dense. Yeah, they're very spar now.
Speaker 3:  I think Apple should repack those with information. They're
Speaker 4:  I think just like a plain text screen. Here's list.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Just full change log. That's, that's it. We should, we should
Speaker 4:  take a break.
Speaker 3:  You don't wanna talk about games some more? No,
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna play Assassin's Creed on any of my Apple devices. Please be
Speaker 4:  alone about it.
Speaker 3:  All right, we'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Alright,
Speaker 5:  am have no artistic ability and the ability to make a horse with 12
Speaker 5:  butts just sounds weird. I wanna see what happens.
Speaker 4:  It's a really interesting, no artistic ability and terrible person. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like a really fascinating combination.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's but somehow but also wildly creative. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like if you were like, I have no artistic ability, I'm a bad person,
Speaker 3:  but I couldn't imagine a horse with 12. But like it's fine. Go about your
Speaker 3:  right crazy's like I got ideas. Yeah. I go, I wanna see,
Speaker 5:  I wanna see what happens. So I am, I am super excited
Speaker 5:  about that. We'll see how long I'm allowed to be excited about it before
Speaker 5:  Apple just shuts me off.
Speaker 3:  Who shut you down at the server level? Like we got the kill switch in iOS
Speaker 3:  Fire.
Speaker 5:  Soon as I log in they're like, Nope, that's not for you. Execute, but
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be sick. And then my other one I've talked about already is the,
Speaker 5:  the ugly dark mode apps.
Speaker 4:  Crayons. Oh my God.
Speaker 3:  It's bad. You've
Speaker 5:  Seen that. My Slack now. You know, I just, I want
Speaker 5:  everything. I want all of my devices when I turn them on for you to go.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Again, why don't you use Windows and Android? Which
Speaker 3:  from the like the base levels of the operating system, it's too easy, are
Speaker 3:  designed to be this ugly. It's too easy. Oh, I see. You're
Speaker 5:  Not a hacker if you're not hacking
Speaker 3:  By using the system level being controls added
Speaker 3:  to the operating system.
Speaker 5:  It feels like hacking when it's on iOS.
Speaker 3:  Alright, Kranz, everybody.
Speaker 3:  David, what are you?
Speaker 4:  My two I, I changed it because I wanna talk about two things You changed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But who can remember what my last one was? Now it's, it's been too
Speaker 4:  long. There were rules. This I changed show not
Speaker 4:  during the break, so it was fine. I changed it while you were talking about
Speaker 4:  something or other theme mode. Yeah, probably.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You were like, oh, Assassin's Creed. And I just started typing, you
Speaker 3:  Know, I shot control in 2017. My first one,
Speaker 4:  My first one is weirdly just like a throw in at the end of
Speaker 4:  wwc, which I actually, that was very exciting. It's transcription and AI
Speaker 4:  summarization in the voice memos app
Speaker 3:  And also the phone app. And
Speaker 4:  Also the phone app. Yeah. So exciting. Which is like, this is the kind of
Speaker 4:  thing that like if you're a reporter is life changing and if you're a real
Speaker 4:  person is just like sort of whatever. But for me, like I spend a lot of time
Speaker 4:  talking into things and being talked at on those same things
Speaker 4:  and having a decent recorder is amazing. Like you use the pixel
Speaker 4:  recorder, Allison, I know I have a pixel because that is a magical little
Speaker 4:  piece of software Yeah. At all times. And this feels like it might do the
Speaker 4:  same thing. And I'm very excited about that fact. Yeah. So that's awesome.
Speaker 4:  Also, maybe the thing that AI is the most consistently good at is transcription
Speaker 4:  and summarization. So like sold. Love it. I'll take it.
Speaker 4:  The other one is all of the organization stuff in mail,
Speaker 4:  which I am more excited about as time goes on because
Speaker 4:  NE is making a face at me, which is fair.
Speaker 3:  He's just thinking mime screen is, I'm just, I'm like, this man has to run
Speaker 3:  installer and he has to pretend all software is
Speaker 4:  Interesting. So no, it's that all
Speaker 4:  email apps for iPhone are bad. Yeah. Which is just a
Speaker 4:  fact of the world solve problem on the Mac mime stream is excellent. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Everybody should use Mime Stream. Love it to death. There are no
Speaker 4:  good email apps for The. iPhone. And before you hear this or see this
Speaker 4:  and send me one, don't. I've tried it. It sucks. They're all bad.
Speaker 4:  But this thing that Apple did, which is basically just launched Gmail. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 3:  Were just like, they have an updates tab, like the whole thing. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They, they do the categorization. They're doing some AI summarization.
Speaker 4:  You can use the tools to rewrite your emails like we were talking about earlier.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna go back to using Apple Mail again because it is like
Speaker 4:  useful. The problem with Apple Mail has always been that search sucks, which
Speaker 4:  I assume is still the case. And it doesn't have the
Speaker 4:  split inboxes in Gmail, which I've actually now come to rely on. They're
Speaker 4:  not very good, but they're better than just dumping everything into your
Speaker 4:  one inbox. And at least when I go to promotions, it's like mostly
Speaker 4:  stuff I don't want. And when I go to updates, it's like mostly newsletters
Speaker 4:  and receipts. Again, not perfect, but pretty good. And if Apple can do that
Speaker 4:  stuff, even that well, it immediately becomes the best email app on The.
Speaker 4:  iPhone like by a mile. And so I'm cautiously
Speaker 4:  optimistic. I just, the Gmail app is so bad. I
Speaker 3:  Want to believe for you, it's so bad. It's not good. Yeah. That's why you
Speaker 3:  gotta use Outlook.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 4:  sucks about Outlook.
Speaker 3:  Every
Speaker 4:  Is, well, A, everything B it's very slow. But C, when you open an email,
Speaker 4:  the archive button, which is the only button that matters on an email app,
Speaker 4:  is all the way at the top right of the screen where it's completely unreachable
Speaker 4:  no matter how hold you hold your phone. Ridiculous. You
Speaker 3:  Archive them.
Speaker 4:  Do you just leave them? Oh, you're, oh crap. Oh no, I'm discovering
Speaker 4:  I hate you in this episode.
Speaker 3:  Oh no,
Speaker 8:  Don't, don't worry about my little numbers. You don't. Don't worry about
Speaker 8:  it. Thousand don't you? It's fine.
Speaker 4:  You just, you read it then mark it, it unread for the chaos and then go about
Speaker 4:  your business, don't you?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like sometimes I'll be like, oh, that's spam. I'll leave it unread.
Speaker 5:  So I for one day,
Speaker 4:  No
Speaker 3:  One, oh, that hurt my soul. Soul. That's way to do it. Say second. The Gmail
Speaker 3:  app has actually solved this by way of a, a, a bug that is still not fixed.
Speaker 3:  Which is sometimes when you open an email from the notification on the
Speaker 3:  Gmail app for iOS, it just deletes the email.
Speaker 5:  I've
Speaker 4:  Noticed that. And it's
Speaker 3:  Just like, how do you get here? How did, how
Speaker 3:  did you arrive at the state? Google, I mean all that ai. Like I
Speaker 3:  bet what you wanted to do was immediately delete this email that you actually
Speaker 3:  chose to take an action on. Then action was delete. And that's
Speaker 3:  how I hit inbox zero. Congratulations.
Speaker 8:  That's
Speaker 4:  Really exciting. Yeah. Reading it is not important to get into inbox Zero.
Speaker 4:  No longer
Speaker 3:  Steps the robots summarize the email. Yeah. I can't believe you picked fucking
Speaker 3:  mail out.
Speaker 4:  I honestly, the more I think about it, the more excited I, but also
Speaker 4:  the thing where you can now group by sender. So I'm like the one time you
Speaker 4:  go to a restaurant and then they send you an email every day for the rest
Speaker 4:  of your life. Going and clicking the unsubscribe button. Too much work Doing
Speaker 4:  it in Gmail. Yeah. Doesn't work. That's just a lie that they tell you.
Speaker 4:  But now you can group them and just delete them all at once. Yeah. I I like
Speaker 4:  that.
Speaker 3:  I'm excited. I'm excited for their, the same AI idea everyone else has, which
Speaker 3:  is like, you're planning a trip and all the emails from your trip are gonna
Speaker 3:  be a little diagnosed of trip emails. Love it. Great. I'm super excited
Speaker 3:  for you in Mail Act. Thank you.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be an awesome like six days. Yeah. And then somebody will
Speaker 4:  update their app again and I'll be like, maybe they fixed it and they
Speaker 4:  didn't. Yeah. But I'll try it again. You've
Speaker 3:  Got a problem and it's fine because it keeps you writing in
Speaker 4:  Star. I do it for work now Alison.
Speaker 3:  What it some saying? Yeah. All right. What are yours,
Speaker 3:  Allison?
Speaker 8:  Mine messaging related. Ooh, I am,
Speaker 8:  because I test a lot of Android phones. I'm usually the person on Android
Speaker 8:  in the group chat. So
Speaker 4:  Do you turn iMessage on when you test an iPhone and then off when you stop?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Does it ruin your life every time you do that?
Speaker 8:  Kind of like possibly. I have missed out on
Speaker 8:  friendships, you know, things happening. I
Speaker 8:  don't know. When
Speaker 4:  You deen enroll from, from iMessage, you miss messages. Like for days. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's insane.
Speaker 8:  I think there's people I just don't talk to anymore
Speaker 5:  Because
Speaker 8:  They probably try to Yeah. Message me. No, I do this, I do it with
Speaker 8:  RCS. So like, yeah. RCS and iMessage is
Speaker 8:  gonna Yeah. Fix everything for me. I feel really good
Speaker 3:  About my, oh man, that's even more optimistic than David picking nail out.
Speaker 8:  I love this.
Speaker 4:  Well, you can send high resolution it's photos. Now is
Speaker 8:  The photos. 'cause like right now when in the group chat we're
Speaker 8:  sharing photos of our kids doing cute things and I have to be
Speaker 8:  like, I'm sorry, I'm screwing up the, the
Speaker 8:  high, you know, the quality of the images here. Can you just send them to
Speaker 8:  my husband or can we put 'em in a Google? There's so many Google photos
Speaker 8:  albums. It's
Speaker 3:  Like, oh God. Yeah. How are you
Speaker 8:  On any group chats in
Speaker 4:  Text? It's so I
Speaker 8:  Really,
Speaker 4:  I love the idea of everybody sending photos back and forth and then you just
Speaker 4:  sending Google photos, links, it's
Speaker 8:  Oh my God. Yeah. Check out my cool photos. And
Speaker 8:  you have really good friends. I know. They are so patient with me.
Speaker 8:  Those are some like rock solid. But you know what, there was one Android
Speaker 8:  guy and he just switched to iPhone too. I was like, that's tough. Now it's
Speaker 8:  just me. Yeah. So that's it. RCS is gonna fix everything for me.
Speaker 8:  I feel good about it.
Speaker 4:  That is a good one.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And scheduling messages.
Speaker 3:  Yes. That's a clut one.
Speaker 8:  I message only.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna schedule so many messages for like seven minutes from now,
Speaker 3:  just so it's not like immediately thirsty, but like within 10 is too much.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. Yeah. Send seven minutes from That's
Speaker 8:  So that true. It fixes the like, oh, you just texted me and I'm gonna text
Speaker 8:  you right back. But that like, seems weird. Yep. And then I'm gonna forget
Speaker 8:  about it and then never text you back.
Speaker 3:  Yep. Those are the only two options that exist. Yes. Right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm honestly, I'm so glad you both just said that because this is my
Speaker 4:  main problem as a person because I'll read your message and if I
Speaker 4:  respond, if I am in the right head space to respond to it, I'm very responsive,
Speaker 4:  I'm ready. But if I do the thing where I put my phone down, we're done.
Speaker 4:  It's, I'm gone. Never, ever getting back to it. And I will just feel an increasing
Speaker 4:  sense of guilt. Like I could name you right now, off the top of my head,
Speaker 4:  15 people I owe text messages to who are never getting text messages from.
Speaker 4:  Do you, do you read
Speaker 3:  Them? Name them. Now I've, I've, this will be the greatest TikTok in
Speaker 3:  history. Name the 15 people you know that you are
Speaker 3:  supposed to text under no circumstances.
Speaker 4:  But all of them know who they are, which is the beauty of it.
Speaker 4:  And I'm just, it's seven
Speaker 3:  Minutes around. They should just add it as a default button. Send in seven
Speaker 3:  minutes. Yeah. Right. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Tell send. But be cool.
Speaker 3:  Be cool about it.
Speaker 8:  Chill. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's,
Speaker 3:  That's a really good one. This is like the swingers button. All right. It's,
Speaker 3:  I can't believe I picked this two. Hey.
Speaker 8:  Hey Neli. What, what are yours? What are
Speaker 3:  Your picks? I picked one that I, I I stand by, which is
Speaker 3:  phone mirror. Phone mirroring. Yep. Yes. And remote iOS
Speaker 3:  access for grandparent tech support. That's huge. Game changers.
Speaker 3:  Game changers all the way around. And that's it. Those are two.
Speaker 8:  Two. I picked it. Yeah. No, if you had one more. What was
Speaker 3:  It at the time? I did not know what we were picking.
Speaker 3:  I thought we were just picking some cool features. I did not know that
Speaker 3:  I would create false conflict with David in the iPad segment
Speaker 3:  and I picked the calculator app. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Eli, I would like you, I would like you to do the following. I would like
Speaker 4:  you to right now make the case that the calculator app is
Speaker 4:  the missing thing on the iPad. And the iPad is now perfect and complete.
Speaker 4:  I would like you to make that case right now.
Speaker 3:  The problem with the iPad for the past 13 years has been its
Speaker 3:  inability to do simple mathematics,
Speaker 3:  I think as we've all known.
Speaker 3:  And now you can,
Speaker 4:  That was it. I do wanna say quickly, just to pour one out
Speaker 4:  for the app called Solver. Yeah. Which is an awesome,
Speaker 4:  very cool, very clever app where you can just like type out the math
Speaker 4:  you're trying to do. You're just like, the bill is $65, there's four of us.
Speaker 4:  How much does everybody owe with a 20% tip? And it just answers your math
Speaker 4:  questions like that Apple just full Sherlock that app today.
Speaker 3:  No. 'cause you would have to get out your iPad and start writing with
Speaker 3:  a pencil at dinner. And I just don't, I don't think that's what's happening
Speaker 3:  here.
Speaker 4:  You're like, oh, do you wanna sign the check? And you're like, not yet. Hold
Speaker 4:  on.
Speaker 3:  I've got a draw dinner.
Speaker 3:  How much, how much of the apps did you have?
Speaker 3:  I agree that they took a lot of those ideas, but yeah, I don't, I think
Speaker 3:  solver's one. 'cause that's not kind of an app, right? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's very good on the iPad.
Speaker 3:  It's unbelievable. They're not adding any of these calculator features to
Speaker 3:  The iPhone. It's like The iPhone and the iPad will never have the same calculator
Speaker 3:  experience.
Speaker 4:  The the epiphany that I had during the live blog today was that everybody
Speaker 4:  desperately wants the iPad to become a Mac. And what it actually is,
Speaker 4:  is an iPhone with a stylist. Yes.
Speaker 4:  And to the extent that that changes what you can do on it, apple is like
Speaker 4:  pushing really hard on that idea that like, because there's a stylist, you
Speaker 4:  can do new things. That's, that's the whole bent of the iPad right now when
Speaker 8:  We get the folding fold. Yeah, exactly. It's gonna be sick when it folds.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It may well be all over, but it is, is further and further away
Speaker 4:  from being a Mac all the time.
Speaker 8:  And then you can use your folding iPad on your
Speaker 8:  computer because it will do iPhone mirroring.
Speaker 8:  Oh.
Speaker 4:  And then you plug in your vision pro and you get a giant ass monitor. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Bringing it all together. We fixed it.
Speaker 3:  I think I've never been more depressed about computers after that entire
Speaker 3:  sequence. What
Speaker 3:  I, I actually think we saw a lot from Apple today,
Speaker 3:  which indicates this company can actually like, have new ideas, which is
Speaker 3:  sort of not been the case for a minute. Right? Like they're like,
Speaker 3:  we had a themeing to iOS for Krantz. Great. Yeah. Thank you. Stuff that other
Speaker 3:  platforms had forever. Even at the, all these AI features are kind of the
Speaker 3:  same like as everybody else. They've integrated 'em into the operating system
Speaker 3:  in better ways. They have a better story to tell. Like here's why it's useful
Speaker 3:  as opposed to like, here's just the raw amount of compute that we can throw
Speaker 3:  at a problem. Which is basically how Google handles things. But
Speaker 3:  I come back to this thing about the iPad and it's like they still don't know
Speaker 3:  why they make this thing. They just don't know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It gets increasingly cool without ever getting
Speaker 4:  Yeah. More itself in any
Speaker 3:  Way. Yeah. I think they, they make it 'cause they sell 'em. Yeah. And that,
Speaker 3:  and that's kind of, and it's like they're, they need to kickstart that somehow
Speaker 8:  Or do
Speaker 4:  Today's
Speaker 4:  week. All
Speaker 3:  Right. That's it. Thank you for listening. Thank you Allison for joining
Speaker 3:  us. We'll be back on Friday with more of this,
Speaker 3:  which you love and all the platforms you love the most. Well that's it. That's
Speaker 3:  where