# Transcript
ID: 9ed0f453-5e9f-4d36-98dc-2c73f5682735
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8308979507248821182/863237606932370716/s93290-US-3071s-1730634129.mp3
Description: For the first episode in our three-part miniseries on the future of music, we tell the story of Track Star, a music game show that has become a viral hit on TikTok and Instagram. Jack Coyne, the show's friendly host, tells us how Track Star came to be, why the format works so well, and why A-list celebrities like Olivia Rodrigo, Ed Sheeran, and Kamala Harris are all clamoring to be on the show. Coyne also tells us where Track Star might go next — and why the future of music content might look a lot like the past.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Low Stakes Game
Speaker 1:  shows. I'm your friend David Pierce and I finally
Speaker 1:  have perfected my Nintendo Switch setup. So. I mentioned on this
Speaker 1:  show a while back that I needed a new game console mostly because
Speaker 1:  there's a bunch of new games coming out that didn't support my PS four. I
Speaker 1:  wanted something new. The team almost convinced me to
Speaker 1:  buy a steam deck, but then they were like, oh, it doesn't play the only game
Speaker 1:  that you care about, which is EAFC, which used to be called fifa. So that
Speaker 1:  didn't work. So I did a bunch of research and a bunch of trying stuff and
Speaker 1:  eventually landed on just buying EAFC at 25 and
Speaker 1:  trying to run it on my unbelievably old and kind of
Speaker 1:  busted Nintendo Switch. It's not great Game's a little
Speaker 1:  laggy jumps a lot every time you wanna like move down a menu. It takes
Speaker 1:  a full second to think about it, but it works. I have the game game's
Speaker 1:  downloaded, it's all going fine. So of course as I'm want to do, I then got
Speaker 1:  very obsessed with the setup. I bought a new controller from
Speaker 1:  this company called Power A, which looks cool but I hate it, so
Speaker 1:  I'm already in the market for another controller. I bought an adapter so
Speaker 1:  that I can connect the switch to my iPad and use it as
Speaker 1:  a bigger screen when I'm on the road. I bought a thing to connect it to my
Speaker 1:  tv. I bought a thing to connect it to my computer monitor. I've
Speaker 1:  done way too much work to make this all work, but now I have gotten to the
Speaker 1:  point where basically anywhere I am at any time with zero setup,
Speaker 1:  I can play EAFC 25 on my Nintendo
Speaker 1:  Switch. It's the dream. The game doesn't work very well, but
Speaker 1:  it works and I have it and at least for now that is enough. Also,
Speaker 1:  Nintendo, please release the switch too because my setup is now perfect.
Speaker 1:  All I need is a better console. Let's do this. Alright, we're
Speaker 1:  not here to talk about the Switch. We are here to do the first episode in
Speaker 1:  our new three part miniseries all about the future of music.
Speaker 1:  We've done episodes on this topic before and it's just something we really
Speaker 1:  like talking about and it turns out music actually hits a lot
Speaker 1:  of the stuff we care about most. On The Vergecast. It's about creators, it's
Speaker 1:  about policy, it's about ai, it's about infrastructure, it's about
Speaker 1:  what it means to be a person in the world. Music
Speaker 1:  just covers everything and so it's really fun to find new ways to talk about
Speaker 1:  music. Today on the show I'm talking to a guy named Jack Coyne who is
Speaker 1:  a creator. He's on TikTok. You've probably seen his show
Speaker 1:  and you may not even have realized it. Super fun conversation. I really enjoyed
Speaker 1:  talking to Jack. I learned a ton. We're gonna get into it. But
Speaker 1:  first. I'm almost done with this game. There's this new mode called Rush.
Speaker 1:  Every game is like seven minutes long. I'm just gonna finish that and then
Speaker 1:  we'll get into it. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. I'm so, so sorry to do this,
Speaker 1:  especially right at the beginning, but I have to tell you a
Speaker 1:  back in my day story just really quick. So back in
Speaker 1:  my day back when I was a kid, way back in the ancient history,
Speaker 1:  that was the 1990s and early two thousands, MTV was
Speaker 1:  the biggest thing in music. Turn
Speaker 4:  It on, leave it on America. See the, you wanna
Speaker 5:  See, I want my MTV. Alright,
Speaker 4:  I want my mtv.
Speaker 1:  I probably don't have to explain the idea of television to most of you,
Speaker 1:  but just in case MTV was a TV channel that for
Speaker 1:  hours and hours a day would just play shows about music.
Speaker 1:  Sometimes it would just play music videos back to back one after
Speaker 1:  another for hours at a time and you really cannot
Speaker 1:  overstate how big a deal culturally MTV was.
Speaker 1:  In particular, it felt at the time like Carson Daly and TRL
Speaker 1:  Total Request Live were the most important brands in the music
Speaker 1:  business. I'm sure there are people who will say otherwise, but that's how
Speaker 1:  it felt to me at the time. I just went back and found a bunch of old
Speaker 1:  TRL episodes, which you can find a surprising number of just by
Speaker 1:  searching around on YouTube and I kept noticing that what I
Speaker 1:  remembered about TRL and what TRL actually was are
Speaker 1:  two really different things. I remember TRL as the music video
Speaker 1:  countdown, they would do a top 10 usually over the course of an entire episode
Speaker 1:  and it was a big deal for artists to get in that top 10. They would come
Speaker 1:  on and be congratulated for moving up a spot, but most of
Speaker 1:  these episodes that I'm seeing is just artists like hanging out and
Speaker 1:  talking about music. They're sitting on couches or stools or
Speaker 1:  just standing in the crowd, just kind of hanging out. Some
Speaker 1:  artists would bring their favorite music videos to talk about. Sometimes
Speaker 1:  they would guest, host and talk about all the most popular videos. Sometimes
Speaker 1:  it had nothing to do with music at all and winds up
Speaker 1:  feeling like, why on earth is this a TRL episode?
Speaker 1:  Here's one good example. I found an episode from 2001 where
Speaker 1:  Jessica Simpson, who at that time was like at the peak of her powers, is
Speaker 1:  talking about her new music and she takes a quiz during
Speaker 1:  another music video about other music and TRL.
Speaker 6:  I'm here with Jessica Simpson. Jess, how are you on your your TRL trivia?
Speaker 6:  You've seen the show before.
Speaker 7:  I have seen the show before. I hope I'm good. I'm not really good at this
Speaker 7:  kind of thing, but all them
Speaker 6:  Are. Yeah, we've put you with your fans, Joel, be able to confer with their
Speaker 6:  fans. We'll give you five questions and here are your five questions. Question
Speaker 6:  number one is, what was the first NSYNC video to go to
Speaker 1:  Number one? Something about that clip just screams 2001
Speaker 1:  to me. I don't know why. Just everything about it. This is like a
Speaker 1:  crazy blast from the past. Anyway, I've been thinking a lot about
Speaker 1:  TRL and MTV recently and really the whole idea of how we
Speaker 1:  discover and get to know new music. Obviously the whole
Speaker 1:  music universe is different than it was 20 years ago and
Speaker 1:  in so many ways we're actually much closer to artists than we've ever been.
Speaker 1:  Every time an artist has an album coming out now you suddenly see them on
Speaker 1:  a million podcasts or they're doing some like hour long
Speaker 1:  interview with Za Lowe for Apple Music where they walk around London or they're
Speaker 1:  doing cover songs on an Australian radio station's YouTube channel, like
Speaker 1:  a version. By the way, one of the great things on the internet, there's more
Speaker 1:  music content than ever and we actually get more chances to
Speaker 1:  see and hear from our favorite musicians than ever. A lot of the most
Speaker 1:  followed people on Instagram are musicians. All of that
Speaker 1:  together is why it's so interesting and almost strange to me
Speaker 1:  that this little TikTok show has worked as well as it has. Welcome
Speaker 1:  to
Speaker 8:  The show. Hello. Hey. Hey If. you can name the artist. You win five bucks.
Speaker 8:  It's The Beatles. The Beatles.
Speaker 1:  The show is called Track Star and it's all over the place on TikTok and
Speaker 1:  Instagram in case you've never seen it. It goes more or less like this.
Speaker 1:  Jack Coyne, the host who's a voice you just heard meets somebody on the street.
Speaker 1:  Sometimes it's a totally random person just happening to walk by.
Speaker 1:  Sometimes it's an a plus list musician. Sometimes it's something kind of
Speaker 1:  right in between and he hands them a microphone and a pair of headphones.
Speaker 1:  Jack then plays a song through the headphones and if the person can guess
Speaker 1:  the artist of that song, they win five bucks. If they get it right, they
Speaker 1:  get to try again for 10 bucks or keep the five bucks and walk away.
Speaker 1:  The number keeps doubling until they get it wrong or walk away and then it
Speaker 1:  ends. It's a super simple premise and it really works.
Speaker 1:  TrackStar is only a couple of years old but it has 400,000 followers on
Speaker 1:  TikTok, another 340,000 on Instagram and is
Speaker 1:  continuing to grow really fast. But more than just the numbers, it's
Speaker 1:  the guests that Jack gets on this show that blow my mind. Just to scroll
Speaker 1:  through some of the most recent ones, Keith Urban is on here. Julia Louis
Speaker 1:  Dreyfuss is here. Joe Jonas, Kamala Harris. Sure.
Speaker 1:  Dan Reynolds, the lead singer of Imagine Dragons, Ed Sheeran, Olivia
Speaker 1:  Rodrigo, Nelly Ferdo is here. Okay, sorry. You get the idea. But these are
Speaker 1:  a-listers. These are big name people and they're just rolling up
Speaker 1:  to listen to Jack CO's playlists. I needed to know
Speaker 1:  why this show has worked. So I called up Jack at his office in Manhattan.
Speaker 9:  My name's full name's Jack Coyne and you can call me a content creator.
Speaker 1:  Quick Jack backstory, he got started as a creator way back in the day
Speaker 1:  when he started working for Casey NY Stat who is probably still your favorite
Speaker 1:  YouTuber's. Favorite YouTuber. He was an assistant, an office manager,
Speaker 1:  a producer eventually made videos for Casey's app Beam and
Speaker 1:  basically cut his teeth both as a content creator and more
Speaker 1:  specifically as a content creator on the streets of New York City.
Speaker 9:  I worked on his very first YouTube video ever with him and his thing was
Speaker 9:  just, there's a million stories out there, especially in New York City, If,
Speaker 9:  you look outside, you'll trip and fall into a story and So
Speaker 9:  I. That attitude was really ingrained in me from like the time I was 18 years
Speaker 9:  old.
Speaker 1:  Jack, by the way, calls himself a music guy, but only in the way that
Speaker 1:  everyone who likes music is a music guy. He liked classic rock and pop music
Speaker 1:  and just liked music. He definitely did not set out to be
Speaker 1:  known for making music related stuff, but a few years ago
Speaker 1:  he was working with brands on social media content and he started a
Speaker 1:  company with his brother and a friend who were both doing the same kind of
Speaker 1:  thing to see if they could all just do it more efficiently together.
Speaker 9:  We said if we put our our clients together and we all help
Speaker 9:  each other with our videos, we'll have extra time on the side to come up
Speaker 9:  with our own original shows and ideas. I had previously had
Speaker 9:  a YouTube channel, I'd worked with YouTube creators before
Speaker 9:  and I just sensed that there was this huge opportunity in the moment to do
Speaker 9:  something with short form video both on TikTok Instagram
Speaker 9:  and of course on YouTube and so we kind of carved out extra time for
Speaker 9:  ourselves and resources from doing the brand work to be able to create
Speaker 9:  Public Opinion.
Speaker 1:  What was the thing you wanted to do first when you were like, okay,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna have this spare time to make something we wanna make.
Speaker 1:  Did you have a like initial sense of what that thing was? Well,
Speaker 9:  So the reason we called the company Public Opinion was because it was about
Speaker 9:  talking to people. That was like a shorthand way of saying talking to
Speaker 9:  people and the reason that we wanted to talk to people is we
Speaker 9:  recognized that this man on the street type content was
Speaker 9:  increasing in popularity, but we felt like no one was doing it great. It
Speaker 9:  was a lot of like gotcha sort of making fun of people.
Speaker 9:  Let's catch someone in an awkward or funny moment and make them look stupid
Speaker 9:  and we were like, I've always
Speaker 1:  Felt like half the internet was just people doing Billy on the street impressions.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Exactly. Yeah, and we felt maybe there's a way to do this that's like nicer
Speaker 9:  and more positive and and maybe we can try and make people a little bit
Speaker 9:  smarter with the stuff we were doing. So we were asking trivia questions
Speaker 9:  about New York City and trying to educate people about New York City. That's
Speaker 9:  where we got started.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Was it, was that like a civic-minded thing
Speaker 1:  or was it just fun and you thought New York was cool and that was a good
Speaker 1:  way to do it?
Speaker 9:  It's, it's a personal interest thing. It's something that I've always been
Speaker 9:  interested in, curious about and I think it was like, okay guys, we gotta
Speaker 9:  go shoot. We looked out the window and we're like, what's that building?
Speaker 9:  Oh, maybe there's something interesting about that building and we can talk
Speaker 9:  to people about it. And that was the entry point. Okay. It was just like
Speaker 9:  the obvious thing because we were here in New York and I love it here.
Speaker 1:  The Public Opinion channel is very much alive and super fun too, by the
Speaker 1:  way. And it works just the way you think. Since it's obviously currently
Speaker 1:  election season, Jack has been mostly running around asking people trivia
Speaker 1:  questions about New York City and US presidents and how the two kind
Speaker 1:  of collide,
Speaker 8:  Which president has a parkway named after him? You're driving? Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 8:  yeah, yeah. Driving on the east side. Where are you driving? I think the
Speaker 8:  FDR man. Yes. Two more questions
Speaker 1:  But the problem they ran into early on was that most people in New York don't
Speaker 1:  actually know that much about New York, new York's whole thing. Its whole
Speaker 1:  appeal is that people come from everywhere. It's a super transient
Speaker 1:  town. That's what makes it so exciting. But I mean your trivia
Speaker 1:  game show isn't very fun if nobody knows any of the answers. Right.
Speaker 9:  I would say maybe our hit rate was two outta 10 people who actually knew
Speaker 9:  something about New York that besides just, oh, I don't really know the answer
Speaker 9:  to that question. That's not interesting content. And so it was like our
Speaker 9:  second show has to be something that's much more universal and something
Speaker 9:  that everybody can talk about because like I said, Public Opinion,
Speaker 9:  what's something that is gonna cast a wider net music was the obvious answer
Speaker 9:  and we found right away like the hit rate of just getting people to engage
Speaker 9:  with us with higher and their reactions and the stories that came out of
Speaker 9:  talking to songs was really exciting.
Speaker 1:  Why was music the obvious answer? I could imagine, especially as a New Yorker,
Speaker 1:  like a dozen things you might land on before music. You're like, let's do
Speaker 1:  Yankees trivia or like let's talk about you know, famous New
Speaker 1:  Yorkers or whatever. Like there's a lot of places you could go other than
Speaker 1:  music. Why? Why did you learn on music? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  We definitely thought about doing sports stuff and continue to think about
Speaker 9:  doing sports stuff because we have a little tangentially and it's super fun
Speaker 9:  and people are so passionate about that and a few other things. But I think
Speaker 9:  simultaneously we recognize that there was a lot of music
Speaker 9:  conversation happening on the platforms and TikTok
Speaker 9:  is a music driven platform, right? Like the reason videos,
Speaker 9:  a lot of videos take off is the sounds that are attached to 'em. So, so we
Speaker 9:  were like, let's just get into the sound and music business because
Speaker 9:  that's where the platform is driving people and we pretty quickly realized
Speaker 9:  that there's a lot of interest from record labels, from musicians, from
Speaker 9:  music management, PR to attach themselves to something that's making
Speaker 9:  waves in music on social media.
Speaker 1:  This makes perfect sense to me. TikTok is many things but it is mostly
Speaker 1:  a music platform. And remember, just to reset the timeline here,
Speaker 1:  this is like 2022, early 2023 as
Speaker 1:  everyone is going outside again post pandemic and as TikTok is still growing
Speaker 1:  at an absolutely outrageous, unprecedented rate,
Speaker 1:  TrackStar got a hundred thousand followers in its first month of existence,
Speaker 1:  which is wild. They basically started posting videos and it took off immediately
Speaker 1:  and he's right. It's definitely true that music is as universal as
Speaker 1:  anything out there, but what do you think the odds are just as a thought
Speaker 1:  experiment that If you just walked up to some random person and handed them
Speaker 1:  your headphones that they would know the song you were currently listening
Speaker 1:  to. I feel like pretty low, right? Just for fun.
Speaker 1:  Here's the top five songs in the United States right now as I'm recording
Speaker 1:  this. According to Billboard Love Somebody by Morgan Wallen brand new.
Speaker 1:  Don't think I've heard it but I think I could probably pick out Morgan Wallen
Speaker 1:  a bar song by Shazi. That one I've got that's been everywhere for months.
Speaker 1:  Birds of a Feather by Billie Eilish, maybe I think I could guess
Speaker 1:  a Billie Eilish song but I can't hear that one in my head right now. And
Speaker 1:  there's like a whole genre of people who kind of just sound like Billie Eilish,
Speaker 1:  So I, don't know about That one, die With a Smile by Lady Gaga and Bruno
Speaker 1:  Mars. I actually love both those artists and have literally never heard of
Speaker 1:  that song until right this second. And Espresso by Sabrina Carpenter,
Speaker 1:  obviously yes, everybody knows Espresso, even If, you don't think you know
Speaker 1:  Espresso, you know Espresso, but that's the top five songs in the country.
Speaker 1:  Do you know all Five? Do you think everyone knows All Five? Every
Speaker 1:  time I watch Track Star, that's all I can think about. How Hard must Jack
Speaker 1:  have to try to find songs that people know And how many throwaway
Speaker 1:  takes must there be of just total failure where people
Speaker 1:  don't know the music?
Speaker 9:  So more often than not, younger people
Speaker 9:  who grew up with the streaming platforms are much
Speaker 9:  more playlist oriented and and artist agnostic.
Speaker 9:  They're listening to songs and sounds and they know tons of songs but they're
Speaker 9:  like, I don't know who that is. So oh totally it is harder with
Speaker 9:  like young 20 somethings because they, they just go on Spotify
Speaker 9:  and they listen to a playlist and then that playlist through that playlist
Speaker 9:  they discover certain types of artists that they like.
Speaker 9:  So if I can figure that out, it's helpful. Okay, you like this one band?
Speaker 9:  Maybe there's like a thread here that I can pull on but, but now I think
Speaker 9:  there's a little bit of pushback with that generation where some people are
Speaker 9:  saying, you know what, I want to go back and discover what the eighties was
Speaker 9:  like. And you find these younger people who are like, I love classic rock
Speaker 9:  and some of those videos perform really well for us. Or we had a kid who's
Speaker 9:  in high school and he's like, I'm really into yacht rock man, I can't believe
Speaker 8:  We're doing yacht rock with a 17-year-old Here you are,
Speaker 10:  Great song, bless the reins, kind of wanna let it play through to be honest.
Speaker 10:  Let it
Speaker 8:  Play, let it Rock. It's Africa by Toto $5, let's
Speaker 10:  Go introduce yourself. My name's Jack,
Speaker 8:  Great name, great name
Speaker 9:  And and the internet loved this kid because he just
Speaker 9:  was talking about how great yacht rock is and he's like 16 years old
Speaker 9:  and he was just had an amazing run of songs and was so funny and
Speaker 9:  charismatic. So when we first started the very first episodes I had
Speaker 9:  created a playlist of like game show, I called it, I have a playlist on my
Speaker 9:  phone now. It's called like game show game songs or something. Okay. And
Speaker 9:  it's just like great classic songs like If, you go at the
Speaker 9:  500 greatest artists of all time Rolling Stone List and pick their best
Speaker 9:  songs. Like that's a good, like songs everybody kind of knows.
Speaker 9:  So we just, I had a playlist set and If you didn't know these songs,
Speaker 9:  sorry You're Outta Luck. And then there was like the realization of well
Speaker 9:  if someone gets out after two songs that's kind of boring, you want to encourage
Speaker 9:  them to go to five or six, it's more fun, interesting video.
Speaker 1:  So now when they're doing a random interview with a person on the street,
Speaker 1:  Jack will usually start by talking with them a little bit about music.
Speaker 1:  And when it's a celebrity it becomes a big research project to find songs
Speaker 1:  that both might be in their wheelhouse but also
Speaker 1:  meaningful to them. In both cases the goal very explicitly is
Speaker 1:  for people to do well at the game but not so well it's suspicious,
Speaker 1:  you know, you wanna make it easy enough to be fun without making it so
Speaker 1:  easy. It's boring and that's a really tricky balance.
Speaker 9:  So there's like a dialogue, what kind of stuff do you listen to? And I
Speaker 9:  think we did one early version where somebody was like, I only love jazz
Speaker 9:  music. And so it's like, okay, let's do a jazz theme. And that video performed
Speaker 9:  well and you realize like having a group of different jazz songs
Speaker 9:  gives the video a theme in addition to the person that you're talking to.
Speaker 9:  There's another sort of narrative playing out there. And so
Speaker 9:  shifted much more into, can I try and find like groupings of songs
Speaker 9:  that make sense together? Anytime we do eighties pop, it's
Speaker 9:  like it's clear what's where you're going and the audience wants to know
Speaker 9:  what are the eighties pop songs that ace gonna play here. So finding those
Speaker 9:  themes is helpful. And then when it comes to someone
Speaker 9:  who's a celebrity, it's trying to research them and and
Speaker 9:  understand or listening to their music and thinking to myself what do,
Speaker 9:  what do I think they were inspired by? And if I can figure that out,
Speaker 9:  they're gonna have a bigger reaction say, how do you know that I was into
Speaker 9:  this song? I just guessed it. Based on these other songs you've written,
Speaker 9:  they sound like alike or they, it seems like there's inspiration there
Speaker 1:  As with everything on the internet, the whole process isn't quite as random
Speaker 1:  and chaotic and man on the street as it might seem in the videos. But I think
Speaker 1:  that's fine and we're gonna talk more about how TrackStar works
Speaker 1:  and why it works. But first we gotta take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. So let's just go behind the music here for a minute
Speaker 1:  with TrackStar and talk about how the show actually gets made because I think
Speaker 1:  something about its structure and format is actually a big part of why it
Speaker 1:  works. So the whole thing just starts with Jack just wandering
Speaker 1:  out into the streets of New York.
Speaker 9:  So the way that we approach like man on the street content creation
Speaker 9:  is I, I have a sign that I hold up that I just in Sharpie
Speaker 9:  on cardboard write whatever the question is and the question might be name
Speaker 9:  the artist win $5 or it might be like New York City trivia win
Speaker 9:  a prize and people see that sign and they approach me and they say, what
Speaker 9:  is this about? I wanna win some money, I wanna be a part of this.
Speaker 1:  This is one way to do a man on the street stuff The other way, the one
Speaker 1:  I think you see probably more often online is just to ambush people with
Speaker 1:  a microphone and a camera. Catching people off guard in that case is part
Speaker 1:  of the appeal and frankly part of why it's fun to watch. But that
Speaker 1:  was never Jack's thing. I can't tell if he's too embarrassed to do it
Speaker 1:  or feels too bad or it just feels sort of gross. But whatever it is, he
Speaker 1:  didn't wanna do it. So instead he'd stand there with a sign, wait for someone
Speaker 1:  to come up to him, he would explain the show and then they were off and running.
Speaker 1:  Jack would hand them a pair of headphones, they would put them on and then
Speaker 1:  he'd hand them a microphone.
Speaker 9:  So the handheld microphone was going back to when we
Speaker 9:  run a whiteboard, deciding what we wanted to do. I wanted to
Speaker 9:  capture this like local news feel and give
Speaker 9:  like the idea of handing a microphone to someone on the street
Speaker 9:  of New York. Like we wrote down on the board voice of New York City. That's
Speaker 9:  what we wanted to be one of our intentions. So when I have a mic and I say,
Speaker 9:  you know what, we're gonna give you a chance to spotlight and say your piece
Speaker 9:  or put your thing. That was the in the sort of what we were trying to indicate
Speaker 9:  visually with with the stick mic and the flags. So that was
Speaker 9:  totally locked in the headphones were both practical so
Speaker 9:  like you're not, we could cut the music however we want to and people can
Speaker 9:  sort of be in the zone. And then it was also a visual signifier of when you
Speaker 9:  put the headphones on you're part of the game. And then there's the
Speaker 9:  branding aspect where we felt like at some point before we started the
Speaker 9:  show I'm like a headphone brand will wanna sponsor this show for sure because
Speaker 9:  this we're just making headphones look cool. So it was a lot of those things
Speaker 9:  I think.
Speaker 1:  Have you gotten the headphone sponsor yet?
Speaker 9:  We've had a few throughout the years. We've had a few different different
Speaker 9:  ones. Yeah, we've worked with Sennheiser, Bose and Beats.
Speaker 1:  I think this kind of stuff is so clever and it's the stuff I think about
Speaker 1:  all the time when I watch these really successful social shows. If, you create
Speaker 1:  a show that requires nothing other than a set of Bluetooth headphones, a
Speaker 1:  smartphone and two handheld local news microphones. You can do that
Speaker 1:  show basically anywhere and with almost no setup. Like
Speaker 1:  do you know why the Hot one set is all black the way it is or
Speaker 1:  why all of those like Vanity Fair videos or the Wired Auto Complete
Speaker 1:  series are just on white backgrounds. It's at least in part
Speaker 1:  so that they can set up that set basically anywhere.
Speaker 1:  Because one thing I've learned over the years is that If, you want to do
Speaker 1:  a show with famous people, your show has to be able to travel to those
Speaker 1:  famous people. And in this case it's a heck of a lot simpler than
Speaker 1:  showing up and eating hot wings and talking about your feelings. All you
Speaker 1:  have to do is show up, put on headphones and listen to some music. But there
Speaker 1:  is one other thing about Track Star that's really clever and I think kind
Speaker 1:  of unique in this space, it's also a game for the viewer.
Speaker 9:  There's like a couple different aspects of it. There's playing people's snippets
Speaker 9:  of songs like on when you're driving around on the car, on the radio is a
Speaker 9:  game that everyone's played. Like this is not a new idea. So it was
Speaker 9:  more taking this concept of guest the artist and putting it in a
Speaker 9:  framework that's gonna make sense for social media. And I think the biggest
Speaker 9:  lesson that we took away was people like watching the guest,
Speaker 9:  they like watching the interaction but they also like to be actively
Speaker 9:  participating in what's happening. So a lot of the comments are, oh you
Speaker 9:  shouldn't put the album cover 'cause I guessed it too soon. Like or I've,
Speaker 9:  I've watched people watching it on their phone looking over their shoulder
Speaker 9:  and they're saying the answers as they're watching it, ah, that that happened.
Speaker 9:  Like when I showed it to my mom for the first time, she's like, oh that's
Speaker 9:  Bruce Springsteen. And so then I realized we were onto something 'cause
Speaker 9:  there's this active participation instead of sitting back and
Speaker 9:  watching it.
Speaker 1:  Right, which is different from your average like even
Speaker 1:  celebrity interview or something where you're, you're just sort of in the
Speaker 1:  audience, like you're trying to invent something that you're both watching
Speaker 1:  and playing simultaneously.
Speaker 9:  And I think because of that, which I guess is
Speaker 1:  A game show like that, you just made a good game show basically. Yeah, well,
Speaker 9:  Well when you watch Jeopardy, right? Right, you're trying to answer the questions
Speaker 9:  as quick as Ken Jennings or whoever's on
Speaker 9:  and So I think what's cool is because of the celebrities and the regular
Speaker 9:  people mix, everyone who's watching feels like if I'm in New York,
Speaker 9:  maybe I could end up being on this show and maybe I could win a lot of money.
Speaker 9:  Which say that's why we watch Who Wants To Be a Millionaire? All these other
Speaker 9:  shows, like we could win a million dollars
Speaker 1:  At this point. I think I get why the show works, it's fun to play
Speaker 1:  this kind of trivia game. It's fun to watch strangers succeed and frankly
Speaker 1:  even more fun to watch them fail. And there's also something about
Speaker 1:  just all kinds of man on the street content that is compelling.
Speaker 1:  Like do you ever see those videos where a bunch of dudes set up a basketball
Speaker 1:  hoop or a soccer goal and then they throw the ball to a bunch of strangers
Speaker 1:  who either shoot it or kick it or get hit in the head or fall
Speaker 1:  on their heels trying to do it or whatever. That all works
Speaker 1:  for the same reason. I honestly, I swear to you, I think I could make that
Speaker 1:  shot. I hope that I get to try someday and I will watch every single one
Speaker 1:  of those videos when they cross my timeline, So I get Why the show works.
Speaker 1:  But I'm still wondering why all of these big name musicians keep
Speaker 1:  showing up on TrackStar. It's not the biggest show in the world. It's doing
Speaker 1:  well, but it's not, you know, earth shattering and frankly a lot of
Speaker 1:  these artists are vastly more famous than Jack or TrackStar.
Speaker 1:  It kind of seems like he has more to gain than they do. And plus
Speaker 1:  when they do come on, it's not like they do some nakedly
Speaker 1:  promotional version of the game where they talk about themselves the whole
Speaker 1:  time or they only listen to their own songs. There's tons of that kind of
Speaker 1:  thing on the internet and it's all fine. But on Track Star, they really are
Speaker 1:  just another contestant playing the game sometimes literally the only
Speaker 1:  promo they do is just saying their name. And obviously
Speaker 1:  even that is not a new idea at all. Of course every late night guests
Speaker 1:  who plays a game with Jimmy Fallon or does like the thing where they
Speaker 1:  test British snacks versus American snacks, they're all promoting
Speaker 1:  something without wanting to seem like they're promoting something. You know
Speaker 1:  what I mean? But like that's the Tonight Show. Jack Queen is great,
Speaker 1:  don't get me wrong, but I think Jimmy Fallon is probably just a smidge
Speaker 1:  more famous and yet apparently every single one of track
Speaker 1:  star's celebrity appearances have come from those people getting in touch
Speaker 1:  with him, not the other way around. That means a-list. Musicians are
Speaker 1:  going out of their way to be on his show. Who was the first artist
Speaker 1:  to reach out?
Speaker 9:  Olivia Rodrigo. Okay. It was Olivia Rodrigo or Ed
Speaker 9:  Sheeran, I can't remember the order. But those two were very early on and
Speaker 9:  close to each other. It was crazy. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Why did they reach out?
Speaker 9:  I guess they have savvy teams and then I, I think in
Speaker 9:  hindsight now I've realized more so that this is part
Speaker 9:  of the music business now is being on social
Speaker 9:  media and making sure that these social platforms are
Speaker 9:  aware of what you're doing in the music space. And so
Speaker 9:  doing stuff on your own TikTok account is important and then appearing
Speaker 9:  in the TikTok universe is important or or your
Speaker 9:  streams aren't gonna do well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think part of the reason I ask about that specifically with
Speaker 1:  TrackStar is your, you're not
Speaker 1:  doing the thing where it's like, let's do a podcast where we talk
Speaker 1:  about your album for an hour or you're not saying like let's
Speaker 1:  rank your 10 favorites of your own songs. Like the sort of standard things
Speaker 1:  people do to promote themselves in their work. People just come on and play
Speaker 1:  your game, right? Like and and the most they get to say
Speaker 1:  I watched the Keith Urban one again right before we did this. So this is
Speaker 1:  like fresh on my mind. All he says is my name is Keith Urban. Like he barely
Speaker 1:  promotes himself or his work or anything like at all. He's just like, what's
Speaker 1:  up, I'm Keith Urban and does the show with you. And on the one hand
Speaker 1:  it's slightly surprising that that's a thing artists are willing to do in
Speaker 1:  this day and age when everything is so transactional and promotional and
Speaker 1:  all that stuff. But also the fact that they started coming to you just
Speaker 1:  wanting to do that is like very cool and very unusual in this moment. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  in the industry.
Speaker 9:  I think that and that you can look at the comment section on that video.
Speaker 9:  I think it's the best thing that he could have done to promote himself is
Speaker 9:  to not talk about himself because people are are saying, damn, this guy
Speaker 9:  is really cool. Who knew Keith Urban was so cool? Yeah. And knew so much
Speaker 9:  about music And that's where they're commenting and then they're going to
Speaker 9:  his profile and they're looking at his music and they're like, is this guy
Speaker 9:  let me explore this myself. And you give the audience the tool of
Speaker 9:  feeling like they get to discover it on their own instead of shoving it down
Speaker 9:  their throats. And I think that's one of the great things about the
Speaker 9:  show is that we, it's not like heavy promotional.
Speaker 1:  There are two things in there that I find really interesting and frankly
Speaker 1:  very telling and very 2024. The first is the idea that you have to
Speaker 1:  keep signaling to the platforms themselves, TikTok and Instagram and the
Speaker 1:  rest that you're relevant and you're around. You have to keep making your
Speaker 1:  own stuff obviously, but also showing up in stuff with a similar
Speaker 1:  focus and a similar audience to be like, Hey algorithms, other people think
Speaker 1:  I matter. This has obviously been a thing forever, right? Creator
Speaker 1:  collabs have been around as long as there have been creators. But there's
Speaker 1:  something specific about signaling that to the platform that I find really
Speaker 1:  fascinating. The other thing is the thing that keeps making me think of TRL,
Speaker 1:  that maybe actually doing something that gets you out there but doesn't just
Speaker 1:  feel like pure promotion of your latest project is more important
Speaker 1:  than ever. This is the reason people post their personal lives
Speaker 1:  on Instagram. It's the reason authenticity is
Speaker 1:  everything, right? That stuff is what people care about now.
Speaker 1:  It's what they gravitate to and it feels more important to do
Speaker 1:  and maybe harder to pull off on social media than just about on any
Speaker 1:  other platform. And I think TrackStar and things like it give people
Speaker 1:  a way to show up in front of an audience that feels
Speaker 1:  candid and authentic and not nakedly promotional even
Speaker 1:  when it's not exactly any of those things.
Speaker 1:  On a lot of the videos that Jack does with well-known artists, there are
Speaker 1:  comments from people who love that the artist isn't promoting themselves
Speaker 1:  on the Keith Urban video, which I just re-watched, there's a ton of that.
Speaker 1:  People love that Keith is just a guy who wants to show up and talk about
Speaker 1:  music. And I think that works for Keith Urban. There are also, by the
Speaker 1:  way, comments from people on every single one of these videos who are just
Speaker 1:  like, oh my gosh, imagine running into so-and-So in New York or
Speaker 1:  OMG, I can't believe you just ran into them. I assume a bunch of
Speaker 1:  those people are in on the bit, but I bet they aren't all in on the
Speaker 1:  bit. And I think that vibe is really important both for the
Speaker 1:  show and for the guests coming onto it. Personally, I first
Speaker 1:  found TrackStar because of one of those better known artists. I think.
Speaker 1:  I think it was Olivia Rodrigo Go
Speaker 8:  Birthday, 50 cents. It was the number one song of the year, the year you
Speaker 8:  were born. I did know that. Can you introduce yourself? Hey, I'm Olivia Rodrigo,
Speaker 8:  thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  But I do also have a distinct memory of seeing the Track star video with
Speaker 1:  Malcolm Todd who is an up and coming artist who was in track stars all
Speaker 1:  time, most popular video with more than 15 million views.
Speaker 1:  Three
Speaker 11:  20 or you want to take the 1 63 20? I just have to beat Olivia. Rodrigo,
Speaker 11:  you're not going two, there's one goal at this point. She's
Speaker 8:  Unbeatable.
Speaker 11:  Oh, black Sabbath.
Speaker 1:  The fact that Malcolm Todd was more popular than Olivia Rodrigo or
Speaker 1:  Ed. Sheeran or any of the other names that I've mentioned so far. By the
Speaker 1:  way, did I mention Oprah yet? Because Oprah was on the show pretty recently.
Speaker 1:  Wild Times. This all continues to surprise me, but it
Speaker 1:  turns out that celebrities even really big ones aren't needle
Speaker 1:  movers the way that you might think.
Speaker 9:  It's interesting, I've thought about a lot like what would happen if Taylor
Speaker 9:  Swift came on the show. That would be a huge moment, right? Biggest artists
Speaker 9:  in the world. I think we would maybe gain
Speaker 9:  5,000 followers from having Taylor Swift done. I don't, I think the
Speaker 9:  video itself would do really well and then maybe some people would write
Speaker 9:  about it and say, Taylor Swift went on this social media show,
Speaker 9:  but, and that would be valuable for us from a brand equity standpoint, but
Speaker 9:  it would not boost the following in any meaningful
Speaker 9:  way. But then down the road, you know,
Speaker 9:  Oreo might say, wow, this guy had Taylor Swift Dom, we should pay him a million
Speaker 9:  dollars to do something else.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about the something else there. But first. We have to take a break.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. So TrackStar is working, it's popular, it's
Speaker 1:  growing. The format is endlessly repeatable and essentially works forever.
Speaker 1:  The team does want to have Taylor Swift on just in case that wasn't clear
Speaker 1:  before. And Jack also has a running list of other ideal guests.
Speaker 1:  He's talked a bunch in interviews before about Bruce Springsteen, but there
Speaker 1:  are lots of others too.
Speaker 9:  Barack Obama. Oh yeah. Because he does, he releases his
Speaker 9:  songs all the time and And
Speaker 1:  Nobody ever believes him, which I love. Everybody is like he, there's no
Speaker 1:  way he listens to these songs.
Speaker 9:  I would, I would actually play him the songs from his own playlist. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Be like, you really listen to Million Dollar Baby by Tommy Richmond, like
Speaker 9:  that's really your jam. Yeah. And then I'm imagining him anyway,
Speaker 9:  that would be a fun one to do just to like put him to the test. I think
Speaker 9:  as far as musicians go, there's Paul McCartney
Speaker 9:  so, or Ringo even might be more legendary than Paul McCartney. Sure.
Speaker 9:  So there's like those classic just people who've been around for a long
Speaker 9:  time who are legends and icons are great. And then
Speaker 9:  I think that there's a huge opportunity with like hip hop that we
Speaker 9:  haven't fully tapped into where like an extended conversation
Speaker 9:  with Nas would be really cool. And talking about stuff that he's
Speaker 9:  listening to and rappers that inspired him I think would be a little unexpected.
Speaker 9:  And then, yeah, more non-musicians, more just like
Speaker 9:  interesting people who care about music I think would be fun. And athletes.
Speaker 9:  That's like the real untapped one. Totally. Like I want to talk to LeBron
Speaker 9:  James, like I he loves music. What if what? What would it be like if he and
Speaker 9:  I were in a room together and I'm playing him songs and he's getting all
Speaker 9:  fired up this, I
Speaker 1:  Love listening
Speaker 9:  To this before
Speaker 1:  A game. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  It'd be amazing.
Speaker 1:  Beyond that though, it's pretty clear to me that the Public Opinion team
Speaker 1:  has tapped into something bigger than just the 92nd
Speaker 1:  setup with the headphones and the microphone on TikTok. So now they're trying
Speaker 1:  to expand outside of that.
Speaker 9:  I mean I think it's exciting for us to experiment and add on different layers
Speaker 9:  and try different things. So we recently started doing a head-to-head TrackStar
Speaker 9:  versus Competition,
Speaker 1:  Which I like. It's very good,
Speaker 9:  Which is fun where you get, especially when you have two artists who have
Speaker 9:  a song that they're collaborating on or maybe it's a band with where
Speaker 9:  you can create some of that band rivalry and banter.
Speaker 9:  So we're experimenting with that. And then we have another show that we do
Speaker 9:  called Track Star Presents, which is a performance show here in the studio
Speaker 9:  and we put out episodes like every week or two and it's kind of like
Speaker 9:  a tiny desk concert but with more conversation in between the songs.
Speaker 9:  And that's like a half 20 minute to a half hour episode on YouTube. So
Speaker 9:  it's very different.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Is that, how big a focus is that for you right now
Speaker 1:  trying to sort of build the like longer form YouTube
Speaker 1:  channel?
Speaker 9:  Well we just, for a long time we had both shows Public Opinion
Speaker 9:  and Track Star on one YouTube channel and we recently decided to
Speaker 9:  split them just because it felt like the two, there was two different audiences
Speaker 9:  and so putting two different videos up on the same channel didn't make sense.
Speaker 9:  So we finally split them and started a new track star YouTube
Speaker 9:  channel and our first video was five or so minute
Speaker 9:  conversation with Amelia de Malden Bird from Chicken Shop Date. She's great.
Speaker 9:  and we, we realized she's amazing. We realized doing she her
Speaker 9:  press people said, can she come on Track Star? She's gonna be in New York.
Speaker 9:  Yes, of course. That'd be amazing. We film for 20 to 30 minutes probably
Speaker 9:  each episode. And what you see on TikTok is 90 or less usually and we're
Speaker 9:  like, we're leaving so much great stuff on the floor, like
Speaker 9:  why don't we put out a five minute episode and show people what that's like
Speaker 9:  and then add some more layers to it. And so we just put out the first one
Speaker 9:  and then we're putting out these TrackStar presents sessions
Speaker 9:  on the same channel. So we're really excited about it. The hard part about
Speaker 9:  long form is you have to create the packaging. You're not just a
Speaker 9:  hundred percent relying on the algorithm to push it to people who want it.
Speaker 9:  Right? You have to get people to click in, which is a whole other game.
Speaker 1:  Do you think you're in a position now where you
Speaker 1:  and TrackStar are big enough that you can pull that audience
Speaker 1:  anyway? Or does it truly feel like starting from nothing trying to make it
Speaker 1:  happen on YouTube?
Speaker 9:  It feels like starting from from nothing because
Speaker 9:  the consumption pattern is so, so different.
Speaker 9:  Like when you're watching short form videos in your feed, it's like
Speaker 9:  you're on the toilet, you're making coffee, you're in line for something.
Speaker 9:  It's just like in the background throughout your day. Whereas YouTube is
Speaker 9:  like, you've gotta really dial in and pay attention to it. Even a podcast
Speaker 9:  can be like, you're in your car, it's in the background, you're walking to
Speaker 9:  work. Whereas YouTube, you really have to get people and and I think
Speaker 9:  it's almo, a huge percentage of it now is happening on connected TVs.
Speaker 9:  So you really gotta get people to say, instead of watching Netflix, I'm gonna
Speaker 9:  watch TrackStar for a half hour. And so it's a big jump and hopefully we
Speaker 9:  can get some people, but I think we have to find that people who are already
Speaker 9:  looking for great stuff on YouTube and get them to discover us,
Speaker 1:  A big part of making the existing channel work and the success of all these
Speaker 1:  new initiatives hangs on the person in these videos that we haven't talked
Speaker 1:  that much about yet. That's Jack. He's always
Speaker 1:  really involved in the track star videos. He's often wearing a backwards
Speaker 1:  hat or like a cool overcoat, but he is always laughing and having
Speaker 1:  fun with the guests and he's the one who really sets the vibe
Speaker 1:  for the whole thing in a way that I actually think is really important. He
Speaker 1:  like points to the camera and demands of the person that they introduce
Speaker 1:  themselves regardless of whether it's a person that you've never seen before
Speaker 1:  and we will never see again. Or if it is like one of the 50 most famous people
Speaker 1:  on planet Earth, I love that he's kind of
Speaker 1:  reluctant to give himself much credit, but I really do think he's a bigger
Speaker 1:  part of it than it might seem.
Speaker 9:  I think my job is to be very sort of
Speaker 9:  optimistic and kind and make people feel
Speaker 9:  comfortable and sort of try and bring out a positive like I'm
Speaker 9:  If you as you watch the show, you see 'em really smiley and I'm laughing
Speaker 9:  and I'm giggling all the time. That's true. That is who my personality is.
Speaker 9:  But I also think that that helps make the random person on the street comfortable.
Speaker 9:  Like I'm not trying to play. Gotcha. I'm trying to encourage you
Speaker 9:  to guess these songs correctly because when you get something right, you're
Speaker 9:  excited and you're happy and you're like, oh wow, I just won five bucks.
Speaker 9:  And then I can come in and say, so tell me about your life, like
Speaker 9:  how did you grow up? Or tell me about your mom or whatever. And So I, it's
Speaker 9:  sometimes I refer to it as like a, the game show as a Trojan horse to
Speaker 9:  get people to open up 'cause they're distracted by guessing songs
Speaker 9:  and then they're much more comfortable and willing to talk about everything
Speaker 9:  else, which is like eating the hot ones, eating the, the hotter they get,
Speaker 9:  the more you're distracted by how spicy it is. So you talk about your feelings,
Speaker 9:  right? So I think that's probably a large part of my
Speaker 9:  role and and where it comes from is my whole career of
Speaker 9:  making videos and doing YouTube content. I've always been told the best
Speaker 9:  part of what you do is when you're engaging and talking to regular people
Speaker 9:  and and having that off the cuff conversation, you should lean into that.
Speaker 1:  This is the sneakiest thing about TrackStar and it's the thing that makes
Speaker 1:  it different from so much music content out there.
Speaker 1:  It's actually really only a little tiny bit about the music.
Speaker 1:  Jack seems to have always understood this thing as a conversation show
Speaker 1:  with sort of a loose musicy structure rather than
Speaker 1:  a thing where the music is the point. And honestly even the music
Speaker 1:  he picks is meant to make that other dynamic work
Speaker 1:  better.
Speaker 9:  So before I go into it, or even at the beginning of the
Speaker 9:  conversation, I'm asking about what do you listen to or what are some, who
Speaker 9:  are some artists that have resonated with you or I research the celebrity
Speaker 9:  and I try and find things that they're, they're they're gonna have an emotional
Speaker 9:  response to and that helps open people up. Like, wait, you played
Speaker 9:  this song? Like how do you know that this was like the song that I danced
Speaker 9:  my first dance in my wedding? And so that's gonna trigger an emotional response.
Speaker 9:  So that's the intention of the songs is to try and find things that remind
Speaker 9:  people of, oh man, I used to listen to this with my dad when we were
Speaker 9:  on the way to baseball practice. Well tell me about that.
Speaker 9:  So I'm hoping that that's working. It's not easy to do like always on the
Speaker 9:  spot, but that's what I'm a hundred percent striving for all the time.
Speaker 1:  I feel like that has come up a bunch where you play a song for somebody and
Speaker 1:  they're like, oh this is, this song indirectly inspired some
Speaker 1:  other song that I wrote or was like meaningful to me as a teenager or whatever.
Speaker 1:  And I always assumed that was mostly research, but
Speaker 1:  it's, it's interesting that it's a mix of research and just sort of
Speaker 1:  educational guesses about what music people like.
Speaker 9:  You'd be surprised how often I stumble into something that I had no,
Speaker 9:  I didn't realize that there was all this meaning behind it. And that's like
Speaker 9:  my favorite moments in doing the show
Speaker 1:  If, you think about that, setup music as a way into other kinds
Speaker 1:  of content and especially into personal conversation. You can go all
Speaker 1:  sorts of ways and that in a nutshell appears to be the TrackStar plan.
Speaker 9:  There have been lots of conversations about starting a record label
Speaker 9:  really. So it's not like happening tomorrow, but it's definitely
Speaker 9:  something that's TrackStar Records could happen.
Speaker 1:  A that's a good name. Yeah, so that's good. What would that, why, why do
Speaker 1:  a record label? What would that look like?
Speaker 9:  Well there's, it's twofold. There's, because of the sessions that are happening
Speaker 9:  in here, we have artists come in and do covers. So there's a lot of,
Speaker 9:  I think a lot of covers are blowing up online and there's an
Speaker 9:  opportunity there. Triple J is like releasing stuff and a few of those
Speaker 9:  different online publishers have released songs in conjunction with
Speaker 9:  artists. So there's an opportunity there. And then like you, like you talked
Speaker 9:  about like discovering new artists, what if we, what if we got a pool of
Speaker 9:  money together and we said we're gonna invest a million dollars in 10 artists
Speaker 9:  and we're gonna tell the story of Track Star records through social media
Speaker 9:  over the course of a year. And it's almost like how making the band was on
Speaker 9:  MTV back in the day. Can we do that through social media?
Speaker 1:  Do you think? You could?
Speaker 9:  A hundred percent. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I watched making the band religiously back in the day when it was
Speaker 1:  about creating the Band o town. And I swear to you, that show would
Speaker 1:  100% work today. A super intense competition
Speaker 1:  show. That's also a behind the scenes look at, at what it means to be a pop
Speaker 1:  star is like social media gold. Actually there
Speaker 1:  was recently a Netflix show about a K-pop group called Cat's Eye that
Speaker 1:  was essentially that, but they also had this very public side of it where
Speaker 1:  people were seeing the performances throughout the audition process. It was
Speaker 1:  wild. the show is awesome. I would watch it a million more times, about a
Speaker 1:  million more kinds of groups. There are other moves for
Speaker 1:  TrackStar itself too, as it grows and becomes more of a business.
Speaker 1:  One thing I see in the comments of the videos all the time is people discovering
Speaker 1:  new songs thanks to TrackStar, the show does have an official Spotify
Speaker 1:  playlist with all the songs, but there's definitely more it could do there
Speaker 1:  because being a reliable source of new music or just a reliable
Speaker 1:  way to make old songs cool again, makes you very powerful
Speaker 1:  in the modern music world.
Speaker 9:  It's like, it goes back to being a teenager and saying
Speaker 9:  like, pass me the ox. Like I'm gonna play a song that's like,
Speaker 9:  you guys are gonna love that. I think everyone has that like little piece
Speaker 9:  of there where they wanna show their friends, like, check this song out.
Speaker 9:  This is a great song.
Speaker 9:  So yeah, huge part of why, why I do this and how I like to choose the song
Speaker 9:  So. I just wanna play good stuff in terms of becoming a taste maker. Like
Speaker 9:  if that's happening, that's great.
Speaker 9:  I just want people to know about good music, I guess. And maybe there's a
Speaker 9:  way to turn that into something that's a little bit more substantial or meaningful
Speaker 9:  or focused specifically on that. I mean we have playlists on on our
Speaker 9:  Spotify, like a bunch of different playlists, so there's some stuff there.
Speaker 1:  Have you gotten labels or anything calling you being like, Hey, can you play
Speaker 1:  this song during Track Star?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, all the time people ask us to play songs, but I can't just,
Speaker 9:  the, the thing is a lot of times it's new songs, can you play this brand
Speaker 9:  new song? I'm like, well how are people gonna know this song that like, no
Speaker 9:  one, this artist just came out. It doesn't make any sense. Like, like I,
Speaker 9:  I If, you wanna pay me to play The Beatles? I'll do that. And people are
Speaker 9:  like, we're not gonna pay you to play the Beatles.
Speaker 9:  Like, damn.
Speaker 9:  So yeah, it's, it doesn't it, it's hard. You have to find things that like
Speaker 9:  are universally recognized and tend, those tend to be things that people
Speaker 9:  aren't promoting.
Speaker 1:  Remember though, Jack is not a music guy that's important to all of this.
Speaker 1:  He's a creator. He likes telling stories. Music is just a vehicle to get
Speaker 1:  there. TrackStar was just an excuse to talk to people about something they
Speaker 1:  liked and cared about and knew everything else they're working on
Speaker 1:  is the same way. And you know, if that happens to also double
Speaker 1:  as a really fun game show to watch and a way for mega famous
Speaker 1:  celebrities to be out and about and into music all the better.
Speaker 1:  It really does feel to me like a throwback to the early two thousands when
Speaker 1:  shows like TRL were all about making music feel like a hang.
Speaker 1:  And they understood before social media, before the
Speaker 1:  internet made, everything about the individual people that getting to
Speaker 1:  know the artists and getting to know what they liked and what they cared
Speaker 1:  about and what inspired them was maybe even more important to
Speaker 1:  liking their music than the music. Another show that
Speaker 1:  I loved from around that time was popup video, which was adding trivia and
Speaker 1:  jokes to music videos way before anyone was posting memes on Instagram.
Speaker 1:  Popup video by the way, was apparently a big inspiration for TrackStar.
Speaker 13:  What was the cute Beatle doing in a Tokyo jail cell?
Speaker 13:  Should George Harrison get his own sit
Speaker 1:  TRL popup video making the band? The music industry has
Speaker 1:  changed in countless ways in 20 years, but maybe it hasn't
Speaker 1:  changed at all. And maybe if it has, we're going back
Speaker 1:  to some things about the way that it was that maybe we never should have
Speaker 1:  left in the first place. People are buying records again. They're listening
Speaker 1:  to full albums to get away from the infinite playlisting of
Speaker 1:  everything that thing Jack is talking about where you just hear music and
Speaker 1:  you sort of know the sounds, but you don't know the artists, you don't know
Speaker 1:  the lyrics. That just feels bad. I had a friend
Speaker 1:  who used to call it Spotify music, music that's designed to not
Speaker 1:  bother you when you're not paying attention. And to be just interesting enough
Speaker 1:  when you are to keep you hooked. That's not good music. That's
Speaker 1:  Spotify music and I think people are pushing back toward looking for good
Speaker 1:  music. They're also, you know, rocking wired headphones and
Speaker 1:  they're looking for new ways to hang out with their favorite music and
Speaker 1:  musicians and get to know them in new ways. It's new platforms,
Speaker 1:  new hosts, new musicians, but the more things change, the more
Speaker 1:  they say the same. I think that lines from a song actually.
Speaker 1:  It's a good one.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to Jack for being
Speaker 1:  on the show with me today. And thank you as always for listening. There's
Speaker 1:  lots more on everything we talked about at The Verge dot com. I'll put a
Speaker 1:  bunch of links in the show notes. You should go watch TrackStar videos. They're
Speaker 1:  super fun. I see a lot of people who will find one video and then
Speaker 1:  just go back to the very beginning of TrackStar and watch them all the way
Speaker 1:  through. Super fun. I actually highly recommend doing so.
Speaker 1:  As always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other
Speaker 1:  early two thousands era TV shows that you think I should watch again, you
Speaker 1:  can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the
Speaker 1:  hotline. we love hearing from you. Send us all of your thoughts and questions.
Speaker 1:  We have two more of these future of music episodes to do this month.
Speaker 1:  I would love to hear what you think about all of them and other things you
Speaker 1:  think we should do. This is one of our favorite series. We've done it before.
Speaker 1:  We'll probably do it again. I'd love to hear your ideas. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Will Pour and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is The Verge production,
Speaker 1:  and part of the Vox Media Podcast network. We'll be back with your regularly
Speaker 1:  scheduled programming on Tuesday and Friday because good Lord,
Speaker 1:  the news never stops. We've got Alexa stuff to talk about. We're gonna do
Speaker 1:  our best to avoid talking about the election. We've got a lot of Apple stuff
Speaker 1:  going on. Just a lot to do. Keep coming back. We'll see you then.
Speaker 1:  Rock and roll