# Transcript
ID: 1465cc53-b8d1-4ac8-8fa8-6178f41f2378
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-36340377397444266/-6423048657516472908/s93290-US-6032s-1725977000.mp3
Description: Apple launched the iPhone 16, Apple Watch Series 10, and AirPods 4 at its annual fall event in Cupertino. The devices come with some big upgrades — a new camera control on the iPhone, a new design on the Watch — but also a lot of promises about AI. Today on the show, we discuss everything that's new, everything that's missing, and all the reasons you might or might not want to upgrade your Apple gear this year.
Speaker 3:  Welcome To The Vergecast. The flagship podcast of the A
Speaker 3:  18 and a 18 Pro, which are different things.
Speaker 3:  This is our Apple event special. I'm your friend David Pierce. Alex
Speaker 3:  Kranz is here. I i Are they different? Honestly, I
Speaker 3:  couldn't tell you, but we'll get to that. Neela Patel is here. Hi Neela.
Speaker 2:  35 flops.
Speaker 2:  It's all you get from me. You want 36? You got 35.
Speaker 2:  That's the deal on the table. You can take
Speaker 3:  A leave it. I I love this for you. Okay. First of all, NELI, it's very important
Speaker 3:  to me that you describe your whole setup right now, both for people who can
Speaker 3:  watch, who would like to know what's happening, and also for people who can't
Speaker 3:  just paint us a word picture of your current setup. Right now
Speaker 2:  I am in my hotel room in Sunnyvale, California. I just came from Apple
Speaker 2:  Park. There's a David's running the show because I have no idea what's going
Speaker 2:  on. I I, I was in Apple's ambient experience.
Speaker 2:  Either you're gonna get a new phone or you're gonna be raptured. That's my
Speaker 2:  experience every time I go to Apple Park, I don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I was just at the Apple event with our whole crew, the Allison,
Speaker 2:  Chris Welch Veen. We had a great time. We ran around and played a few phones
Speaker 2:  and I'm in my hotel room, which I've attempted to turn into a podcast studio.
Speaker 2:  It went six.
Speaker 3:  Okay. What, what's, how's the lamp? Tell us about the lamp.
Speaker 2:  The, the lamp is glued to the table. I'm very late. You know, I'm on the
Speaker 2:  West Coast. Everyone else is on the East coast. 'cause they didn't, they
Speaker 2:  didn't come. They, they abandoned me to Apple. We
Speaker 3:  Did. That's
Speaker 2:  Correct. So they've been very patient while I tried to figure out how to
Speaker 2:  make this room work and the lamp being glued to the table really through
Speaker 2:  a, you know how you like leave a room. You're like, I know what I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  do when I get back to that room and you walk back into the room and the lamp
Speaker 2:  is glued to the table. Been there. I dunno, that's been metaphor been there.
Speaker 2:  I dunno if that's, that happens to other people. But anyway, I'm back in.
Speaker 2:  It's our room. I just, we, we just played with the phones. I met a bunch
Speaker 2:  of people. I talked to Phil Schiller for five minutes about camera
Speaker 2:  buttons, which is a fascinating conversation. I'm ready to rock.
Speaker 3:  I am very excited because it does feel like a solid two thirds of this episode
Speaker 3:  is gonna be about camera buttons. But let, let's go back to the beginning.
Speaker 3:  You were saying, like, before the event even started that
Speaker 3:  the vibe of this event at the Steve Jobs theater was
Speaker 3:  unusual and you've been to a million of these.
Speaker 3:  And so just to hear you be like, this is not how this room normally feels
Speaker 3:  is fascinating. So like what, what, what was the room?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't wanna do too much immediate criticism on our show.
Speaker 2:  It's not anything criticism, it's just media talking about itself.
Speaker 2:  Sure. But the mix of people in that space was different than before.
Speaker 2:  It was like tangibly different than before. There was a lot more foreign
Speaker 2:  press. There were more TikTok creators call
Speaker 2:  'em. It was just like a different younger, more
Speaker 2:  visual video crowd. and it, everyone's just like thrilled.
Speaker 2:  Like I think for a lot of people it was their first time at an Apple event.
Speaker 2:  So you just had this like, surge of enthusiasm and then
Speaker 2:  all the old heads in the corner just like grumbling about how the kids dunno
Speaker 2:  what they're doing with their selfie sticks. And I think that's a healthy,
Speaker 2:  it's like a healthy tension.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, If, you rewind a decade. It was just like
Speaker 3:  the old heads and Apple employees at those events, right?
Speaker 2:  Well, no, it was like, it was like the legendary print reviewers. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And me being like, here's what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna take a photo and upload
Speaker 2:  it to the internet right away. And they were like, what are these bloggers
Speaker 2:  doing? Get 'em out my face.
Speaker 3:  It was like, I don't go to print for three days. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like I appreciate that I'm in this circle of life. But the, the point I kept
Speaker 2:  making in the Lifelog was that the room was super enthusiastic,
Speaker 2:  which we just have not seen in a, in like quite a while. Right. The
Speaker 2:  the, obviously there was Covid and then a bunch of people came back and I
Speaker 2:  think Apple turned over its crowd. I asked a few people it, if it
Speaker 2:  feels like the big change was the dramatic increase in international
Speaker 2:  press, that that feels like the big change. I I don't have the numbers. And
Speaker 2:  on Apple's data, that just seems like they, they widen the aperture of who
Speaker 2:  was covering the event and they, they had a, a more lively atmosphere.
Speaker 3:  Interesting. I do miss the, the, like, I, I mostly don't miss
Speaker 3:  Apple event days when I'm not at Apple Event days. But there is something
Speaker 3:  kind of lovely about the Steve Jobs theater. Like it's a, it's a, it's a
Speaker 3:  nice place. They did a very good job with the Steve Jobs theater.
Speaker 2:  Good. They did a good job. And then they, they opened a new building for
Speaker 2:  this event called The Observatory, which is just sort of like over the hill
Speaker 2:  and, and, and around the corner. And that's the, their new like
Speaker 2:  briefing space. Oh. So they have the Steve Jobs theater was
Speaker 2:  too small the day it opened. They, they've been saying this since literally
Speaker 2:  the day it opened. Like this was too small because they, you know, they designed
Speaker 2:  it in a very different time. It took a long time to build and designed, improved.
Speaker 2:  So it's always been too small. And in particular the, the
Speaker 2:  sort of spaces within it where You can like, have conversations always too
Speaker 2:  small. So they built an entirely new thing called the Observatory where they
Speaker 2:  were having additional meetings and stuff because they have so many more
Speaker 2:  people there now. And the observatory is like this like glass window that
Speaker 2:  looks a Apple park. Apple sent some photos to magazine called D Zine Today.
Speaker 2:  We were not allowed to take photos, but You can look at it. It's very cool.
Speaker 2:  And that's sort of their, their their space for after the event. 'cause they
Speaker 2:  have so many more people to talk to.
Speaker 3:  That's cool. There is nothing more Apple E than, look we built, built this
Speaker 3:  very cool building. You are not allowed to photograph. Yeah. Like that's
Speaker 3:  it. That's Johnny Ive, the spirit of the man lives on.
Speaker 3:  Alright, let, let's, let's talk about the anthem So I. Think let's do it
Speaker 3:  in reverse order, kind of, of how Apple did it.
Speaker 3:  Just because we, we gotta start with the phones, right? Like the phones is
Speaker 3:  the thing. There were watches, there were AirPods and there were phones.
Speaker 3:  Those are the big three. Both of you I believe last week said
Speaker 3:  that we weren't gonna get Max congratulations on all of your accomplishments.
Speaker 3:  Yes. We
Speaker 2:  Also did not get a TV real. We did
Speaker 3:  Not get a television. No, I was devastated Ted Lasso no appearance. Very
Speaker 3:  upsetting. Jason Sudeikis wasn't even there as far as I know. He's just like,
Speaker 3:  when shooting lefty threes at WNBA games still, I, when
Speaker 2:  Tim Cook was like, this is some of our most breakthrough and meaningful innovations
Speaker 2:  yet, I was like, oh, they're doing a tv. It was not to be
Speaker 3:  No. I'll ask but the phones got bigger, which is we're we're on the way to
Speaker 3:  a television.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. The prize is gigantic. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But let's, let's do, let's start with the cheapest phones and then
Speaker 3:  go up to the most expensive phones. Alex, do you just wanna like
Speaker 3:  brief rundown of The iPhone 16 and 16 plus. Yeah. and
Speaker 5:  We can get into it. Yeah. The, iPhone 16 and 16 plus are like good. They're
Speaker 5:  exciting. It's, well, I think, I think the big difference is a lot of the
Speaker 5:  stuff is new on these as well. Specifically the
Speaker 5:  camera control all IE camera button,
Speaker 5:  shutter button. Although I think Neil, I probably has some feelings about
Speaker 5:  that. So maybe we don't call it the shutter button, but it, so it's got
Speaker 5:  camera control. It's got an, the action button, which was on the pro
Speaker 5:  last year. It's one to 2000 nets. It's got the
Speaker 5:  ceramic shields. So you should theoretically be able to drop it with minimal
Speaker 5:  scratches. The eight 18 and
Speaker 5:  visual intelligence, which is kind of like Google Ends, but,
Speaker 3:  But Apple did it. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  Apple did it. and it goes through like the camera control button. And most
Speaker 5:  of the stuff, they really spent most of their time talking about the action
Speaker 5:  button and the camera control, which like, as a button lover,
Speaker 5:  I was elated. But other people, I don't know. And it's, it's it,
Speaker 5:  the colors are different this time too, right? Like we got, we got a blue,
Speaker 5:  we got this teal, like bluish teal. We got the pink,
Speaker 5:  we got a purple. It's, it's some lovely colors. This stuff.
Speaker 3:  So this is my first question actually. Neela, you've seen these phones. Apple
Speaker 3:  described the colors as I, I believe the quote was more
Speaker 3:  vibrant. Vibrant was a word that was used.
Speaker 5:  Are they thoughts?
Speaker 3:  You've seen these things. Yeah. Some of them, right? What's the They look
Speaker 3:  great. They look,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they look great. The, the pink is very pink. The blue is very blue.
Speaker 2:  Like they are, they are in fact very vibrant. They're very saturated
Speaker 2:  colors. That's exciting. They, they didn't shy away from them. The phones
Speaker 2:  are cool. They, you know, apple continues to sort of round off the corners
Speaker 2:  of the phones. And then as Alex is saying, the
Speaker 2:  big change to the hardware is the camera control button, which is also
Speaker 2:  in the 16. So you don't get the sense the 16 is missing
Speaker 2:  anything this year. Right. There's a, a whole bunch of camera features. It's
Speaker 2:  not getting as a solar processor. Well
Speaker 5:  It's got one less camera, right? They said it could do
Speaker 5:  four, but it's only got, it's got two actual cameras. They got the 48
Speaker 5:  megapixel fusion camera and then the 12 megapixel ultra
Speaker 5:  wide,
Speaker 3:  Which is not four cameras. It feels very important to say that's not four
Speaker 3:  cameras, that's two, it's not four lenses, it's not four cameras.
Speaker 2:  The way Apple would argue this, and I spent, I mean you
Speaker 2:  can't just like throw the words fusion camera at me and not expect me to
Speaker 2:  ask everyone exactly what that means. So fusion camera
Speaker 3:  Wasn't fusion what they called the sweater mode. Tell us
Speaker 5:  About the
Speaker 2:  Tetra. That's pri that's deep
Speaker 3:  Fusion. That's deep
Speaker 2:  Fusion. Okay. The Tera Prism is on the pro. So fusion camera
Speaker 2:  specifically refers to the idea that you have a 48 megapixel sensor
Speaker 2:  that generally produces 24 megapixel images,
Speaker 2:  but You can run it at 48. And then when you zoom, it doesn't just
Speaker 2:  crop the sensor to get you a 12 megapixel zoom lens. It
Speaker 2:  runs an entirely new photo pipeline. So it, they are
Speaker 2:  treating it like you swapped lens sensor, photo pipeline, everything.
Speaker 2:  So you've got a 12 megapixel zoom lens sitting inside the
Speaker 2:  48 megapixel main camera. You have to believe
Speaker 2:  all of this is true. That's how you get two lenses.
Speaker 2:  That's the argument. That's why it's called the fusion lens is you have 48
Speaker 2:  and then when you run it as a telephoto, it doesn't just crop the sensor,
Speaker 2:  it does all this other stuff to treat it like it's a different sensor.
Speaker 2:  Do you believe it? That's
Speaker 3:  Like me saying. There's me and then there's me with a British accent and
Speaker 3:  that's a whole different guy. Like I just, I don't it.
Speaker 2:  That's Jar. And then, and then the other two, just to be clear, the other
Speaker 2:  two is you have the ultra wide and then when you hold it close to something,
Speaker 2:  it switches to macro. So it's a different camera. So you get four
Speaker 2:  and that one is slightly more believable in a sense, slightly more believable.
Speaker 2:  That one thing isn't far away and one thing is very close.
Speaker 2:  Sure. But I would, the way to think about it's, it's not four cameras or
Speaker 2:  four lenses. It's four modes. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Which is fine. I'm good with that. Four modes I can work with. Lots
Speaker 3:  of cameras have many modes. That seems fine. And I will say all the camera
Speaker 3:  stuff seems solid. Like the, I actually think the, like big
Speaker 3:  improvement to an ultra wide camera is a big deal. And there's been a lot
Speaker 3:  of excitement about it. I think I mostly don't shoot with the 0.5
Speaker 3:  camera on The iPhone because it makes everything kind of fish eyed and weird
Speaker 3:  looking. Yeah. But there are some like genuinely sincerely cool things You
Speaker 3:  can do with that lens that you can't do otherwise. So if like, if
Speaker 3:  they've made that actually work, I actually think that's pretty exciting.
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 5:  This is like real macro mode, right? This isn't just the stuff where I
Speaker 5:  would hold the phone up really close and it, if it focused then
Speaker 5:  I'd get a nice shot and call it macro. No,
Speaker 2:  The 13 Pros I think started doing true macro with their ultra wide.
Speaker 2:  And the pros have had it for a while, but now the regular 16 has it. And
Speaker 2:  really what you're seeing is the regular 16, unless you
Speaker 2:  want all these additional photography features, is
Speaker 2:  basically the, the good phone, which is a first. Like I would've never
Speaker 2:  considered buying a regular iPhone before. I've always bought the pros. I'm
Speaker 2:  still gonna buy a pro because I'm a huge camera nerd. But there's not
Speaker 2:  some piece of this puzzle where I'm like, oh, that's not good for most people
Speaker 2:  like it. This is a great phone. Probably the best straight up iPhone
Speaker 2:  apple's made in quite some time because it is inheriting most of the
Speaker 2:  features of the pro inclu, including the camera control button.
Speaker 3:  Right. And the reason that's happening is a theme we're gonna come back to
Speaker 3:  many times in the course of this episode is ai, right? Like the, the
Speaker 3:  thesis is that these are AI phones. You can shake your head all you want.
Speaker 3:  Neli I'm right, I'm super shaking and we should talk about head about that.
Speaker 3:  But like they, what was Tim Cook's line? Like these are the first devices
Speaker 3:  built from the ground up for Apple Intelligence. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's a British accent. That's it's the same. It's it's
Speaker 2:  it whole. Yeah. They, they started these phones a million years ago. Right?
Speaker 2:  Like obviously I think they, they did the action button.
Speaker 2:  They knew that the number one thing people would use the action button for
Speaker 2:  is the, the camera. They were right. That's the number one thing people used.
Speaker 2:  And so they, they added this other button and I, the, the, it's funny,
Speaker 2:  after the event I'm like scrambling to post photos and I had posted
Speaker 2:  a thing on threads that I still use the same ancient Nikon camera
Speaker 2:  and lens. And I have been since like the beginning
Speaker 2:  and I'm still using it and the photos are still great. And Phil Siller saw
Speaker 2:  me and he was like, that's your old camera, huh? 'cause he, he'd seen my
Speaker 2:  post on threads and we just got talking for a little bit, another major no
Speaker 2:  earth shattering scoops. So I asked him this question like, is this button
Speaker 2:  here because this is a new input method for the phone, right? Is
Speaker 2:  this a camera shutter button? Is this just for camera nerds? Like
Speaker 2:  Phil's a camera nerd? We we talk about cameras every time we, we see each
Speaker 2:  other. Or is it you want people to
Speaker 2:  have their iPhone engage with the world visually, right? You want the AI
Speaker 2:  to be able to see stuff. So you need to put this button right here so You
Speaker 2:  can like open it right away and like look at stuff with your iPhone. and
Speaker 2:  it was basically like, yeah, it's both like, people use their
Speaker 2:  iPhones for cameras all the time. It's convenient. We already see that's
Speaker 2:  happening. But at the same time we have, I, you know, we have cameras on
Speaker 2:  iPads and people use 'em as document scanners and we are just aware, like
Speaker 2:  Apple's just aware of the universe of things the camera
Speaker 2:  is already doing for people like scanning QR codes to get
Speaker 2:  menus at restaurants. So I pushed him on it and he was like, no, it's both.
Speaker 2:  Like, you have to see it as both. And we've seen it as both for a long time.
Speaker 2:  So I think you're right David, that like there's a, a
Speaker 2:  view towards a long-term future where The iPhone is just looking at
Speaker 2:  stuff and being smart about it. And then there's right now, which is people
Speaker 2:  need to open the camera and take a photo and we're in a, this button represents
Speaker 2:  a little bit of a transition, but none of the
Speaker 2:  features are shipping. So it's Right. It's just a camera button.
Speaker 3:  So, okay. This is actually, if I'm being completely honest with you, the
Speaker 3:  single biggest question I have for you, as somebody who has held one of these
Speaker 3:  phones, is it a button all Apple calls? It is camera
Speaker 3:  control. Yeah. Like Apple Studiously avoids calling it a
Speaker 3:  button. And from the description in the keynote, it sounds a little bit like,
Speaker 3:  it's, it's kind of, I I think I, I compared it to like the Mac, a teeny tiny
Speaker 3:  MacBook track pad where it's like mostly doing the haptic thing and it doesn't
Speaker 3:  really move, but it feels like it's moving and You can, you know, move your
Speaker 3:  finger around and it, it's sensitive that way, but it's not like a clicky
Speaker 3:  button, is it? What, what is this thing? Does the button
Speaker 2:  Move? It is, it is a physical, honest to god clicky button. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But that makes me feel bad.
Speaker 2:  I was really
Speaker 3:  Worried. No,
Speaker 2:  It also does the other thing, which is very confusing. And every
Speaker 2:  time I've used it, I've used it now a dozen times, my brain is still trying
Speaker 2:  to figure it out. So, and, and I'm not saying it's like hard to figure out.
Speaker 2:  It's just one of those things you have to use for a little bit and like figure
Speaker 2:  it out. So when you, it's capacitive,
Speaker 2:  the reason they're not calling it a shutter button is 'cause it, it has like
Speaker 2:  multiple functions inside of it. So, and the, and
Speaker 2:  they're all enabled by the fact that it is both extremely pressure sensitive
Speaker 2:  and capacitive. So You can just push it down and it clicks
Speaker 2:  and that'll take a photo like every time that's gonna take a photo. And the
Speaker 2:  new sensors are zero lag. So You can just bang away on even
Speaker 2:  the regular iPhone 16. But also on the, on The iPhone 16 Pro, just taking
Speaker 2:  pictures, zero shutter lag. You're off the races.
Speaker 3:  That's pretty cool. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's cool. If you like, I don't even know how to If. you think about moving
Speaker 2:  your finger, it'll register like a tap. Do you know what I mean? Like
Speaker 2:  you're not, you don't, 'cause you don't want to push it. You wanna like,
Speaker 2:  just like give it a little, little, you know?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Just like I'm thinking about you. And that'll, and that'll open up
Speaker 2:  one menu, And, if you do it twice, you get like the big menu
Speaker 2:  and You can like switch between modes. So like, by default it's like the
Speaker 2:  zoom. So you like hold it down a little bit and you get like the zoom thing
Speaker 2:  and then You can like slide your finger back and forth to Zoom. But You can
Speaker 2:  also click down again and switch to the new photo styles or switch between
Speaker 2:  the lenses or all this other stuff. Eventually you're able to lock
Speaker 2:  exposure and, and focus.
Speaker 3:  I'm like dangerously worried that you're describing like 3D touch
Speaker 3:  or forced touch. Yeah. Both ideas that Apple has had that didn't go super
Speaker 3:  well for Apple. The idea of like, what if we gave you infinite
Speaker 3:  levels of pressure to push and different things happen depending on what
Speaker 3:  you did. And everybody's like, actually this sucks and I can't figure out
Speaker 3:  how to use it.
Speaker 2:  Well, so the the reason it's gonna work is because Apple's not depending
Speaker 2:  on like third party app developers to do anything
Speaker 3:  Fair.
Speaker 2:  They've just, they're just like, here it is. Here's how it works. And You
Speaker 2:  can, like I said, it it is, I have not immediately sussed it out,
Speaker 2:  but You can see how you will. And the thing that's actually the most confusing
Speaker 2:  about it is If, you are used to a MacBook track pad where the click
Speaker 2:  is fake. The fact that it is actually a physical click to take a photo
Speaker 2:  is the thing your brain can't get around, right? Because You can, You can
Speaker 2:  press hard enough to make it do stuff, but then You can press even harder
Speaker 2:  to make it take a photo.
Speaker 5:  Ooh, this is gonna be a mess for people. I'm so excited.
Speaker 2:  It's not, it's something that I I promise you it won't be that messy. It'll
Speaker 2:  just be like a week of very confusing results. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Mean that's gonna be a great week.
Speaker 3:  Well it sounds like the hard part is gonna be all this stuff in the middle.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. If, you just button mash it'll take a picture. Yeah. Which is what
Speaker 3:  most people want to
Speaker 2:  Do. Yeah. and it falls. Right. And then, but then the capacitive stuff is,
Speaker 2:  is wild too because it, it's an iPhone, right? It's iOS. So it has
Speaker 2:  inertia. So when you're like looking at your range of zooms, You can
Speaker 2:  just like slide your finger really fast and it'll just fly to the next de
Speaker 2:  tent. Yeah. Right. Or fly between lenses or If, you have it
Speaker 2:  open to the lens switcher. And there where there's no detents, You can just
Speaker 2:  like go from the farthest zoom to the ultra wide by just like swiping really
Speaker 2:  fast and it'll just like roll. So there, it just as a hardware
Speaker 2:  software appley thing, it's, it is like absolutely not just a
Speaker 2:  button. Like it is like another weird little touch surface with
Speaker 2:  a lot of ideas packed into it. And the idea is
Speaker 2:  for as much as I can tell that you should basically be able to control the
Speaker 2:  entire camera from this button. Hmm. There's parts of it
Speaker 2:  that you can't do, but you should basically be able to,
Speaker 2:  you know, like a, a real camera's, like lots of buttons and knobs and exposure
Speaker 2:  compensation and, and styles and macro. And they've got a lot of
Speaker 2:  those ideas inside the camera control button.
Speaker 5:  What if this becomes like a generational thing? You know how like
Speaker 5:  your parents are always turning the light on on their phone 'cause they kind
Speaker 5:  of screw it up and we're just like, like our brains just can't process
Speaker 5:  it. We'll hit it like an age point where we're like, we just can't use the
Speaker 5:  camera control because it's so complex.
Speaker 5:  Because it does sound like there's like a lot of like, it's like really awesome
Speaker 5:  and that there's a lot of opportunity with it. But also it does sound super
Speaker 5:  complex.
Speaker 2:  I think people are trying to figure out what that middle part where you're
Speaker 2:  lightly tapping is for that might be confusing. But like David
Speaker 2:  is saying, If, you just push the button really hard, it'll take a picture.
Speaker 2:  And that, that part seems very, I will say that there are, there are, we,
Speaker 2:  we have weird hue lights switches in my house. You have to push really hard
Speaker 2:  and people often don't push them hard enough. And so maybe
Speaker 2:  they're just like, won't, maybe they just won't push this button hard enough
Speaker 3:  Maybe. Yeah. So what, what I've found myself wondering about this is I
Speaker 3:  actually get all of the reasons Apple would make this thing. Right? Like
Speaker 3:  it actually makes a lot of sense. It seems like a really useful controller.
Speaker 3:  It also, it makes sense both in, in landscape and
Speaker 3:  vertical mode, which is very clever. Like to make a button that feels like
Speaker 3:  it'll work whether I'm holding my phone like this and using my index finger
Speaker 3:  or holding my phone like this and using my thumb strikes me as very clever.
Speaker 3:  What I don't understand is why this isn't the action button. Like why didn't
Speaker 3:  they ship this last year and call it the action button? That makes way more
Speaker 3:  sense to me than calling it camera control. There's all kinds of interesting
Speaker 3:  stuff you could let developers do with this. It feels like vastly deeper
Speaker 3:  and cooler and more interesting than like, here long press this button and
Speaker 3:  one of eight things will happen.
Speaker 3:  It's possible. The answer is just, it wasn't ready so they shipped it. But
Speaker 3:  like, this seems to me to be what the action button always should have been.
Speaker 2:  I think I disagree with that. I think the, the action button is,
Speaker 2:  we, I mean we talked about this so much last week. The action button is meant
Speaker 2:  to to be a configurable macro button. Sure. and it just
Speaker 2:  happens that most people thought the camera was the most useful macro. But
Speaker 2:  I think apple's all in on the idea that you should just have a button on
Speaker 2:  your phone that opens your transit app or launches a shortcut
Speaker 2:  or it does one of any number of appliance, like things that your
Speaker 2:  phone does.
Speaker 3:  Shout out to all the people who told us about the transit apps, by the way.
Speaker 3:  Yes. We got a lot of feedback from people who use it for their transit apps.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, and I think Apple's like super into this. 'cause what they were
Speaker 2:  doing before was like weird triple clicks of
Speaker 2:  the home button to accomplish these goals. Right now they just have another
Speaker 2:  surface to map things onto. And the
Speaker 2:  fact that everyone is using it for the camera, I think was proof to them
Speaker 2:  that they needed a camera button too.
Speaker 3:  So you think that I, I mean, and I guess you're probably right, like I was
Speaker 3:  thinking that there's a roadmap for this that ends in it being something
Speaker 3:  that like every developer can do stuff with and it becomes like a, a system
Speaker 3:  for controlling how you do lots of things. But what you're saying, and I
Speaker 3:  guess what's probably right, given the fact that it's called camera control
Speaker 3:  is like this thing is about the camera. Like yeah, maybe it will be the camera
Speaker 3:  in lots of apps, but like this is a camera thing. And that is, I
Speaker 3:  I agree with you in that sense that this is like this, this thing has a real
Speaker 3:  sort of statement of purpose that the action button like deliberately
Speaker 3:  does not, do
Speaker 5:  You guys think it means that eventually we don't get that
Speaker 5:  port free Totally smooth glass iPhone?
Speaker 2:  Yes. I I think that that idea is officially put to bed. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I I I don't think they have any interest in that. In fact, since those rumors
Speaker 2:  have started, we've had two physical buttons added to The iPhone
Speaker 2:  And, and I think Apple one realizes, charging
Speaker 2:  wise, these phones are more power hungry than ever. Especially as they start
Speaker 2:  adding AI features to them, people are gonna have to charge their phones
Speaker 2:  more so that port's not going away.
Speaker 2:  And then two, I think the things you want to do, like very quickly on a phone
Speaker 2:  are going to start to take primacy over the idea of opening the home screen
Speaker 2:  and picking an app. And again, the AI part of it
Speaker 2:  where they, they call it visual intelligence where the phone can
Speaker 2:  see the world that I, I think the primacy of that is
Speaker 2:  very, very high. Yeah. And so over time this button might get
Speaker 2:  optimized for some of that. But right now Apple knows, like
Speaker 2:  for a lot of people, The iPhone is a, a web browser, a really good messaging
Speaker 2:  client and a really good camera. And so if they can just be like, now the
Speaker 2:  camera's easier, there's actually a chance they can get you to do other stuff
Speaker 2:  on the phone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well and I think that that pushes the same one behind a lot
Speaker 3:  of what's in like iOS 18, right? Which is more customization, they're pulling
Speaker 3:  more stuff out of apps and onto the lock screen and onto the home screen
Speaker 3:  and into widgets and into live activities. Like the idea that you
Speaker 3:  should be able to do most things on your phone without doing very
Speaker 3:  much feels totally central to like the entire design of The
Speaker 3:  iPhone both hardware and software. And as it happens, I think it's exactly
Speaker 3:  correct and I'm very, very happy about that. Like, we'll see
Speaker 2:  How every app developer feels about this, right? Like, you know,
Speaker 2:  it was not for nothing that Apple very specifically called out. When you
Speaker 2:  do visual intelligence features and you search for a restaurant,
Speaker 2:  like you take a picture of a restaurant, it just tells you what the restaurant
Speaker 2:  is, it's rating and the menu and it's like, where's that coming from? And
Speaker 2:  the answer is Yelp. Right? Can they swap in another provider for
Speaker 2:  Yelp? Yeah, probably in other countries where Yelp isn't like the, the
Speaker 2:  dominant provider of that info, like Apple will swap it. But then they were
Speaker 2:  also very careful to say, if we don't know what's going on, we'll ask Google.
Speaker 2:  And if we recognize that what you're looking at is like a blank
Speaker 2:  homework page, we'll like ask chat GPT to like help you. So they're, they're
Speaker 2:  trying to expand the like universe of third party services they can talk
Speaker 2:  to. The question is whether any of that becomes modular, how any of those
Speaker 2:  services make money, right? No one seems to know.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean that's kind of the whole Apple intelligence question, right?
Speaker 3:  Is like Apple. Apple seems to be building this very
Speaker 3:  simple seeming beautiful thing that it doesn't make any sense how the rest
Speaker 3:  of the ecosystem around it works.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And, and and to be clear, the the weirdest part of these phones,
Speaker 2:  they were announced as the first phones built for Apple intelligence. They're
Speaker 2:  going to launch with none of it. And may, and maybe that's only true for
Speaker 2:  a couple weeks, right? They're, they're launching September 20th is,
Speaker 2:  is the on sale date. You can pre-order 'em, I think next week or the end
Speaker 2:  of this week, 18.1 io 18.1 is supposed to arrive sometime in
Speaker 2:  October with the first set of Apple Intelligence features, right? So it's
Speaker 2:  only a few weeks gap, but that's maybe at most a month gap. Right?
Speaker 2:  But that's a long gap to launch a phone without its highlight features.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 3:  A long gap. It's also, it's launching on 18.1 in beta and it's only
Speaker 3:  launching some of the features, like some of the stuff that shipping is gonna
Speaker 3:  be very cool, right? Like transcriptions and summaries coming to voice memos
Speaker 3:  like that, the, the stuff that's coming to mail where they can rewrite your
Speaker 3:  email, which Apple brought up like 11 times during this event. Like
Speaker 2:  It's what they got.
Speaker 3:  Dear God, stop giving us tools to write worse emails. Like please, I'm
Speaker 2:  Begging you that is right up there with Apple explaining what bigger screens
Speaker 2:  are for. Like You can read an extra
Speaker 3:  Line of text.
Speaker 2:  We are truly killing time in these events at, at some point, like,
Speaker 2:  or Apple thinks everyone is stupid. It might be both, but they're, it might
Speaker 2:  be both the screen's bigger You can have fit more content on a bigger screen
Speaker 2:  is like a regular explanation at Apple event. Right next
Speaker 2:  to, hey, you wrote a bad email and now the robot will write a nice email
Speaker 3:  So, so that our robot on the other end can read it and summarize it for you
Speaker 3:  and then rewrite an, it's just, it's just Apple mail
Speaker 3:  nonsense all the way down from
Speaker 2:  Here on, by the way, the actual flow. We're hitting the boundaries
Speaker 2:  of text handling and interface metaphors in iOS 18
Speaker 2:  with some of the say AI stuff. So If, you wanna like use these
Speaker 2:  features in 19.1, you've got like a long thing in like notes, right?
Speaker 2:  And you wanna summarize it and send an email. You have to select all of it,
Speaker 2:  which is like grab the handle and like scroll all the way down
Speaker 2:  or you know, if some apps have the select all fine and then you have to
Speaker 2:  tap it again to get that select that little menu that like modal popup menu
Speaker 2:  to come back up. And then you hit like writing tools and then it brings up
Speaker 2:  a sheet. And that to me is just bananas.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna say, based on my ongoing ability to like
Speaker 3:  accurately cut and paste things over time, the odds of me
Speaker 3:  getting all three of those taps correct in a row right?
Speaker 3:  Is like one in four. Like
Speaker 5:  So like a video game. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It really is. Is
Speaker 5:  Prince a Persia on your phone? You're gonna have a great time.
Speaker 2:  Well, you know, The iPhone can now play AAA console games. Alex with five.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Assassin's Creed. Sorry, sorry. Sure.
Speaker 2:  Summer even stopped us. Like they did it. They mentioned us. No, but
Speaker 2:  it is just like, if, if that's the thing you're selling and actually Text
Speaker 2:  Ling on an iPhone is is I would say it's messy. It's just, it's
Speaker 2:  not like they've, they've revolutionized it. No,
Speaker 3:  It's pretty inelegant and it has been forever.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's basically the same way it has been since like they added it to
Speaker 2:  The iPhone. You're now at a place where you're like, oh, we're straining
Speaker 2:  the interface metaphors of this in a real way. Yeah. Because yeah, we're
Speaker 2:  asking people to do, to use these new features is move a lot of text
Speaker 2:  around or like take action on a lot of text and it
Speaker 2:  just doesn't, the, the iOS was not like built for that
Speaker 2:  in a particular way and now in the way that a desktop computer like
Speaker 2:  obviously is, and now we might, I hope Apple like takes the opportunity to
Speaker 2:  be like, we should rethink text handling here or like fine cursor control.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But, but there was one AI feature that actually seemed good in
Speaker 5:  this that they, that they pointed out this time, which I don't think they
Speaker 5:  mentioned at WW DC, which is that You can just ask
Speaker 5:  Siri to like tell you how to do stuff on your phone.
Speaker 2:  No, they didn't ask that at wwc, did they? It's that's very much the like,
Speaker 2:  future of user manuals is generative ai. Yeah. Like we have to, we have to
Speaker 2:  boil the ocean in order to make a useful user manual for your
Speaker 2:  iPhone. I mean this, this idea has been around forever.
Speaker 2:  Bixby, Samsung's Bixby is this idea. Yeah, you will talk to your phone and
Speaker 2:  like it'll do stuff but
Speaker 5:  No one's done it well and I just, I keep thinking of all these people who
Speaker 5:  go to Howtos who are using all these other ways to try to figure out how
Speaker 5:  to use their phone and theoretically Apple's gonna make it better.
Speaker 5:  But you have to know to ask,
Speaker 2:  I saw a demo of this today. I don't remember, did it work? It's like a haze
Speaker 2:  of demos. Yeah. They, they were showing me like You can
Speaker 2:  ask it how to do x, y, z feature and it totally worked. Yeah. They were obviously
Speaker 2:  running 18.1 beta, not 18.0, which we'll ship with. but it worked.
Speaker 2:  I mean And, if you really think about all that's happening here is Apple
Speaker 2:  has a model that's running locally on the phone and then they have their
Speaker 2:  own user manuals, which they could load into the model, right? So
Speaker 2:  you're asking a question of a pretty known set of information from their
Speaker 2:  own knowledge base and and whatnot. And yeah. That, that's a pretty straightforward
Speaker 2:  use case that I I think they've, I don't know how much people will use it,
Speaker 2:  but from what I've seen, it works pretty well. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No I think it's like, it could be really useful if they actually promoted
Speaker 5:  it. 'cause I think of all the old people in my life who don't know how to
Speaker 5:  use their phones. Right?
Speaker 2:  But now you gotta get them to, to use Siri. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Now you're gonna be able to be like, no, you asked Siri, don't ask me. You
Speaker 5:  ask Siri now
Speaker 3:  Me out of it. and it assumes that you You can ask Siri in a way that is not
Speaker 3:  prescribed and doesn't have to be a very specific kind of way. And like,
Speaker 3:  again, so much of what Apple is asking us to assume
Speaker 3:  is that after what, 13 years Apple has made
Speaker 3:  Siri good and I just am so not ready to assume that yet.
Speaker 3:  But back to what you were saying Neli about when all this stuff is rolling
Speaker 3:  out, this stuff is rolling out in beta in pieces
Speaker 3:  in October and the, the biggest thing of it, which is
Speaker 2:  This, wait, can I, can I just be really clear about that? 'cause even that
Speaker 2:  is confusing. So it's in beta right now?
Speaker 5:  Yes. You can
Speaker 2:  Technically do it right now. This is weird, right? It's iOS 18.1, public
Speaker 2:  beta is available. You can push the button, You can download it, You can
Speaker 2:  run it. If, you have a 15 Pro You can run Apple Intelligence some stuff
Speaker 2:  right now it's gonna launch in the public release of iOS
Speaker 2:  18.1 sometime in October. And they're
Speaker 3:  Still calling it a beta in the public release. Right. Which
Speaker 2:  Is insane. The the features will be labeled beta in the release. And they've
Speaker 2:  done this a handful of times. They did it with portrait mode. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Free form. The app launched like that I think.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They a couple other things like, like
Speaker 2:  FaceTime audio transcriptions or something launched this way there, there's
Speaker 2:  a handful of this stuff. Deep Fusion technically was in beta, but nobody
Speaker 2:  could see it. No one can still see it. So it's, it's fine.
Speaker 2:  So Apple has this history of doing this, right? Yeah. Particularly with the
Speaker 2:  camera. But now what they're gonna do is they're gonna say huge chunks of
Speaker 2:  this operating system are, are in beta and they're just gonna have the label
Speaker 2:  and the release. So it's not in beta, you have to go get it. It's in
Speaker 2:  the public release. It'll be labeled with the beta, which is a little, that's
Speaker 2:  messy.
Speaker 5:  Which
Speaker 3:  Is kind of like just saying here it is, it might suck. Which is to be fair
Speaker 3:  what all of the AI systems do right now, every, they all have the label at
Speaker 3:  the bottom that's like, this thing might lie to you, we don't know. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Not our problem.
Speaker 5:  It's also kind of what they did at this event when they announced all of
Speaker 5:  this, they were like, and now we're doing Apple Intelligence also. This is
Speaker 5:  just a recap of WW DC.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And all of the features were couched that you will be able to without
Speaker 2:  any hard dates. And So, I, again, I, I don't
Speaker 2:  care how many iPhones Apple sells to quote our friend and mentor
Speaker 2:  Walt Mossberg, I don't give a fuck about your stock price. I just don't.
Speaker 2:  But you know, if one of the questions is, is this worth upgrading? The answer
Speaker 2:  is not in the hardware, the answer is in the software. Right. If, you
Speaker 2:  have a regular iPhone or any pro phone save the 15 Pro
Speaker 2:  to get Apple Intelligence features, you need a new phone. Right.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's a good question. Like, is the new, are the features worth
Speaker 2:  an upgrade? The answer right now is no, because they're
Speaker 2:  vapor. And I will just refer you back to one of the Virgin's longstanding
Speaker 2:  rules right up there with world of no sevens and review. What's in the box
Speaker 2:  is it's a vapor until it ships.
Speaker 3:  Yep.
Speaker 2:  And it hasn't shipped yet. Apple has a great track record of shipping. I
Speaker 2:  I'm not, I don't mean to say this in a pejorative way, but it's vapor until
Speaker 2:  it ships. So you, you just like cannot evaluate this thing. 'cause it's not
Speaker 2:  real in any way, shape, or form.
Speaker 3:  Right. And especially with ai, it's not just shipping, like
Speaker 3:  shipping. Shipping is the very beginning of the battle of making something
Speaker 3:  that's actually any good when it comes to
Speaker 2:  Ai. And part of it is shipping. I, I know in the 18.1 Beta and You can, You
Speaker 2:  can summarize notifications like no one's business. Have you ever
Speaker 2:  looked at a small piece of information and thought to yourself, I wish this
Speaker 2:  piece of information is smaller. Yeah. Apple's got you. Like that You can
Speaker 2:  do that right now. It's all of the rest of it that isn't out yet that has
Speaker 2:  yet to ship. It's all of this private cloud compute stuff, which is
Speaker 2:  up and running and supporting the beta, but it ha actually hasn't scaled
Speaker 2:  and has not actually yet been audited by third parties to prove that it's
Speaker 2:  compliant with Apple's privacy's like Apple's, privacy promises, all of that
Speaker 2:  we don't know yet. Like we just don't know yet. So I, it's, it's just hard
Speaker 2:  to evaluate this phone. Like from the dumbest perspective
Speaker 2:  of like, should I upgrade a phone? I don't know. Like, is is
Speaker 2:  your phone broken? This phone will be much nicer than the phone you have.
Speaker 2:  Will this phone bring you a bunch of cool new AI features? Like I don't Maybe,
Speaker 2:  but I don't know yet. But
Speaker 5:  Your camera will be sick.
Speaker 2:  The, the, well,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, we'll see. Well,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we'll see. It's very hard to evaluate a camera at, at Apple Park.
Speaker 3:  Well, okay, this is actually a good segue back into the, the pros, which
Speaker 3:  we should talk about because obviously there was a ton of focus
Speaker 3:  on the cameras. I mean Right. If you're, if you're buying this thing on day
Speaker 3:  one, the two things you're buying it for hardware wise are the
Speaker 3:  camera upgrades and the camera control. Like, that's, that's it, that's the
Speaker 3:  thing. Right? Unless you like deeply want a phone that is called Desert
Speaker 3:  titanium And. if you, you do, please email me and tell me why.
Speaker 3:  I would love to hear from you because it's called
Speaker 5:  Desert. It sounds cool. It's way better than natural.
Speaker 3:  One of my favorite things that happened today was that as soon as they said
Speaker 3:  Desert Titanium, every single person on our staff with live blog access
Speaker 3:  made a different joke in the live blog Desert Titanium.
Speaker 2:  Can I, can I tell you the, the joke that I did not make in the live blog?
Speaker 2:  Sure,
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Desert Titanium sounds like if one of the mes in Pacific Rim was a stripper
Speaker 3:  And now coming to the
Speaker 2:  Stage. You see what I'm saying?
Speaker 5:  Desert titanium
Speaker 2:  CIO del Toro, get with me. I have an entire idea here
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  Very good. But I know how we can stop Kai attacks and it's sexy.
Speaker 3:  But yeah. With the pros, I'm,
Speaker 2:  That's it. That's it. That's, that's my last VERGE cast to
Speaker 3:  Everybody. That's it. Yeah. That was, we're leaving Neli and Sunnyvale. This
Speaker 3:  is the end possibly of The Verge. Who knows? We're
Speaker 3:  so sorry. but it was always gonna end like this. This is what it was. I'm
Speaker 2:  Just gonna point this out. As far as I know, Jagers are not gendered
Speaker 2:  and this is an equal opportunity, like full
Speaker 2:  spectrum stripper robot situation. Beautiful.
Speaker 5:  Just pulling their metal plates into the ocean.
Speaker 2:  Get m I'm just trying to be inclusive. Yeah. Love
Speaker 3:  Just throwing metal around 2024. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  Desert Titanium,
Speaker 2:  the,
Speaker 3:  The Pro and the Pro Max. It's just the camera this year. Right. Like
Speaker 3:  better, better processor, different colors. Battery life,
Speaker 3:  which I'm gonna get very angry about here in a minute. But like the thing,
Speaker 3:  if you're, if you're thinking regular iPhone versus pro iPhone,
Speaker 3:  you're basically making this decision based on the camera. Right.
Speaker 5:  And bigger display.
Speaker 3:  Okay. And bigger display Fair. Granted, which I will say anecdotally it seems
Speaker 3:  like has turned more people off than on just from what I've heard. Seven,
Speaker 3:  seven
Speaker 5:  Inch phone. That's it's big. I mean mean that's not math. Hold on. Almost
Speaker 5:  seven inches of phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I mean I held it And. if you hold it without holding the 15 pro
Speaker 2:  max in your hand, you're like, ah, it's manageable. And then you hold them
Speaker 2:  next to each other and you're like, well this phone is big and this phone
Speaker 2:  is a surfboard. Oh wow.
Speaker 3:  And you're a max guy. You, so for you to say that is not a big, not small.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's not, it's not anywhere close to a small phone. It's, it's enormous.
Speaker 2:  I love it. I'm gonna, I'm super gonna buy it. Are you, you know, obviously
Speaker 2:  some people buy the pro just for a camera, but then people were also going
Speaker 2:  up to the pro max size because it had the better Zoom lens. Right.
Speaker 2:  And now it's the same Zoom lens on both. So you're not being forced into
Speaker 2:  that biggest phone. You can sort of stop at gigantic
Speaker 2:  and still get kind of the, the best camera system. And I, I think the 48
Speaker 2:  megapixel ultra wide here is a big deal. It's still the ultra
Speaker 2:  wide. It doesn't capture as much light and it's impossible to like really
Speaker 2:  evaluate iPhone cameras at Apple Park. 'cause it, it's like a beautifully
Speaker 2:  lit space no matter where you
Speaker 5:  Are the best lit place you will ever
Speaker 2:  Like exist. Yeah. It's like angelic light from the heavens just like fuses
Speaker 2:  the environment. Right? Yeah. So it's impossible to evaluate. But I took
Speaker 2:  a bunch of photos and obviously the main camera is way better. Obviously
Speaker 2:  the main camera has more modes and all this other stuff and then they, they've,
Speaker 2:  but the having a 48 megapixel ultra means you do get some more detail.
Speaker 2:  You get, you know, it, it's just a better camera than the old ultra wide.
Speaker 2:  And I actually use the Ultra a lot. So I'm pretty excited about it.
Speaker 3:  What do you use the ultra wide for?
Speaker 2:  I'm just often in a space where it's like, I wanna take a picture of Max
Speaker 2:  and I wanna capture the environment that I'm in with Max. Yep. Like here's
Speaker 2:  the whole playground. And like that's a useful, it's just a useful tool.
Speaker 3:  That's exactly my experience, which is why I asked it is constantly like
Speaker 3:  I can either get like the, the shoulders up shot or I can use
Speaker 3:  the ultra wide. So that for me is, it's exactly the same thing. Yeah. But
Speaker 3:  I think for the, the pro, like the reason I, I brought this up when we started
Speaker 3:  talking about the camera thing is the, a big part of the keynote was about
Speaker 3:  all of these new camera modes and all the different ways You can
Speaker 3:  shoot. And the fact that natural is just like a mode now
Speaker 3:  is, is deeply fascinating to me that they're like You can shoot a thousand
Speaker 3:  ways. One of them is regular and and here's a bunch of other ones.
Speaker 3:  And I just feel like, like obviously Nila, you were in the room so you saw
Speaker 3:  this stuff on the screen, which is always hit and miss Everything always
Speaker 3:  looks great on the screen. Has been my experience. But also like, took some
Speaker 3:  pictures and saw 'em on the screen. Like what, what do you make of
Speaker 3:  Apple's sort of million new ideas about photo processing here?
Speaker 2:  Well one, lemme tell you two things about the screen. Okay. Something else
Speaker 2:  Phil Sho told me. So again, they built the Steve Jobs theater. They designed
Speaker 2:  it ages ago and he pointed out to me, they built it for projectors.
Speaker 2:  Like the room is designed for big projectors and then they wanted to do a
Speaker 2:  big LED screen. 'cause that's what everyone does now. So they had to basically
Speaker 2:  engineer their own screen for the theater and it goes past the wings
Speaker 2:  of the stage. So they, to get Oh, wild. To get the size and shape they wanted.
Speaker 2:  That's very apple. And apple designed and engineered their own LED screen,
Speaker 2:  which is hella bright. Let me just tell you. Hella right.
Speaker 2:  The other thing I saw the audio in that room, I, I keep talking about like
Speaker 2:  the room and like it was very cheery in there. It was a little boomy today,
Speaker 2:  unlike other times things were different today at the Steve Jumps.
Speaker 2:  Anyhow. So it's hard to know like
Speaker 2:  all the modes. Yeah. Every time I see Apple's camera team, they basically
Speaker 2:  are like, here we go again. That's their attitude.
Speaker 2:  Attitude towards me. Just it when you walk in, no, they're into it all. You
Speaker 2:  all these companies are run by extremely type A individuals who wanna fight.
Speaker 2:  They would just prefer to win. So it's like, I always have these great conversations.
Speaker 2:  It's always super interesting in their point of view now. Which
Speaker 2:  again, we have to review the phones, we have to see how true this is. It
Speaker 2:  appears to be that they have realized that people are gonna filter
Speaker 2:  the photos anyway. Hmm. Right. So they're like, look, people have
Speaker 2:  a radically different interpretation of what their own skin tone is and we
Speaker 2:  just have to get out of their way. Like that's not for us to decide anymore.
Speaker 2:  So here's all of these options and here's all of these sliders and
Speaker 2:  photo styles have existed on The iPhone for ages. In fact, they
Speaker 2:  started as a response to the Pixel. 'cause you'll remember back when computational
Speaker 2:  photography started and the Pixel team and Mark LaVoy were talking about
Speaker 2:  like, you know, like old painters they liked and
Speaker 2:  shadows and details. The iPhone was like too bright and too even. And we'd
Speaker 2:  be like, we like the pixels contrast. So they added photo styles and one
Speaker 2:  of them was basically like shut up about the pixel,
Speaker 2:  but it was destructive so you could shoot in that mode and that was it. And
Speaker 2:  the reason they're making a big deal about it again is they've re-engineered
Speaker 2:  the photo pipeline so You can change it at will after the shot.
Speaker 2:  Right. And so that means You can capture all the stuff and You can do all,
Speaker 2:  don't call 'em filters. You're very careful to say like this kind of photo
Speaker 2:  prop processing dates back to the 18 hundreds, all this stuff. But the
Speaker 2:  idea is you'll be able to get a much more
Speaker 2:  DSLR type photo with like heavy shadows and heavy detail or
Speaker 2:  a much more modern smartphone ultra tone mapped photo where all shadows have
Speaker 2:  been banished from the face of the Earth never to be spoken again. And now
Speaker 2:  those are controls. Are anyone gonna use these controls? I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Do the power of defaults really matter? And does natural on
Speaker 2:  an iPhone still have to stand for something? It does. Can you
Speaker 2:  evaluate it inside of the angelic light of the Steve Jobs? You cannot.
Speaker 2:  So you have to get it. But I, I think they're starting to see that
Speaker 2:  other, that their users are constantly changing
Speaker 2:  these photos anyway. And so their own point of view has to kind
Speaker 2:  of be a, a good starting plate for all the changes to come.
Speaker 5:  Do you guys use those modes now? 'cause I just realized I've had it set in
Speaker 5:  rich contrast for probably as long as I've had this phone.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  That's pixel mode.
Speaker 3:  That's pixel mode. Oh, that's interesting. Yep.
Speaker 5:  I've been in pixel mode for years.
Speaker 3:  I think that's really telling, right? Like I, I the power of defaults is
Speaker 3:  a really real thing here. Yeah. And I think what I wonder about the pro is
Speaker 3:  whether it is more prone to get people who are
Speaker 3:  more likely to be interested in fussing with those things. Obviously at the
Speaker 3:  very top end, like the kind of people who are shooting the
Speaker 3:  4K one 20 stuff and holding it up in a gimbal and like the people Apple likes
Speaker 3:  to show in these keynotes and in their ads. Those are the people who are
Speaker 3:  gonna use these filters. And I think we'll be psyched about it. Right? Like
Speaker 3:  to have more options to do this stuff, quote unquote in
Speaker 3:  camera is great all for it. But I think
Speaker 3:  the, the like interface question of how you surface this stuff for regular
Speaker 3:  people is really fascinating and really hard. And I think
Speaker 3:  it's kind of how I feel about the camera control thing, right? I think most
Speaker 3:  people will figure out that if I smash this button, it will take a picture
Speaker 3:  and everything more nuanced than that, you start to
Speaker 3:  lose some giant percentage of the number of people who are gonna use the
Speaker 3:  phone. That's
Speaker 5:  Why I keep thinking about this Apple intelligence. Like, I mean obviously
Speaker 5:  it's very easy to to turn it into the personal assistant for your phone
Speaker 5:  settings, but that feels like a a, a win at this point if
Speaker 5:  it really works. That's like the thing you wanna advertise constantly.
Speaker 5:  Tell everybody, look at all these cool settings. It's too hard to remember
Speaker 5:  series.
Speaker 3:  What do you say? Like, make this photo look like the 1980s and if
Speaker 3:  everyone was doing drugs, like
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's exactly what you say. I say like, I want that creepy
Speaker 5:  2000 digital camera vibe. Right.
Speaker 2:  But do you want that, do you wanna say that before you take the photo or
Speaker 2:  after you take the photo? Well,
Speaker 5:  You can do both now as I understand it with the pro,
Speaker 5:  it'll let you change the style after they, they said that that was a big
Speaker 5:  part of the the thing.
Speaker 2:  It will. But there's, you know, there's just parts of taking a photo. Like
Speaker 2:  Yeah. How long is the exposure? Right? Like, do you want to fire the flash
Speaker 2:  If? you want that indie sleeve look like you might wanna fire the flash.
Speaker 2:  Like there's a lot of steps in between. Make it look like this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And just tell the robot to make it look like this.
Speaker 5:  I want the robot to do all of it.
Speaker 3:  Tobble those too.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, so if they can do, pull it off
Speaker 2:  To be, to be clear, once again, none of that is shipping
Speaker 2:  yet. And what app, what Alex is describing in particular is just like
Speaker 2:  us dreaming. Yeah. That that's, that's that you'll be able to just like talk
Speaker 2:  to the phone and we'll do stuff. That's
Speaker 3:  My hope. It's also Apple dreaming that is like, we're not making that up.
Speaker 3:  That's Apple's idea. Right.
Speaker 2:  And Apple wants to plug third party apps in series. They can do this stuff.
Speaker 2:  We're just nowhere cl like that is all pure vapor. Yeah. That's not even,
Speaker 2:  it's gonna ship in the next version of 18. One that's maybe a year away.
Speaker 2:  And what we have now, right now in the camera, particularly pro camera,
Speaker 2:  is infinite customizability. So If, you know what you want,
Speaker 2:  the camera can now get way closer to delivering it. And
Speaker 2:  that is different than are the photos by default more realistic
Speaker 2:  or less over processed? We just don't know. But the idea that it, the
Speaker 2:  camera is now infinitely more flexible in the pro model
Speaker 2:  is, I I think it's born out by just the number of controls you have and
Speaker 2:  the fact that most of the pipelines aren't destructive anymore.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. Which I think is very cool. Alright, we need to take a break.
Speaker 3:  We've been talking about camera buttons for way too long. Any
Speaker 3:  parting thoughts on, on the iPhones? Neela, you've, you've held all the things.
Speaker 3:  Anything that jumped out to you before we stopped talking about phones?
Speaker 2:  The, the promax is really big and all of the phones are really nice in
Speaker 2:  a way that I don't think has been a,
Speaker 3:  I think this is like iPhone five. Nice. Like peak iPhone nice.
Speaker 2:  No, but they are, they're the most refined versions of
Speaker 2:  this design I've seen in, in quite a while. And I, I honestly think
Speaker 2:  the sixteenths, once they get some of the features, they're, they, they'll
Speaker 2:  move like people will buy 'em.
Speaker 3:  Okay. That's very exciting. All right, we gotta take a break. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. We've had the ad break to think. Any, any more
Speaker 3:  phone thoughts? Everybody feel good? I didn't yell about the battery life,
Speaker 3:  but I'm gonna, I'm gonna not yell about the battery life. You, you, you'll
Speaker 3:  have time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I feel like we need to, we need to talk about the processor and the
Speaker 2:  battery life. So they, they kept saying it was the best battery life ever
Speaker 2:  without a number. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Just the best. And they did the, the one that really killed me was there
Speaker 3:  was a moment during the keynote where there was a slide in which they showed
Speaker 3:  the battery meter with the green and then just extended it so there was more
Speaker 3:  green. That doesn't mean anything. What, what am I supposed to do with that?
Speaker 3:  Oh, good. You made the icon longer. Congratulations. That accomplished. I'm
Speaker 3:  so angry at how many times they said battery life. Without giving any actual
Speaker 3:  information about battery life.
Speaker 2:  So, I think distrust them. The 16 Pro Max is supposed to the best battery
Speaker 2:  life ever on iPhone. I'll say my 15 Pro max has garbage battery
Speaker 2:  life. It is, it is absolutely abhorrent. Like it is
Speaker 2:  just bad. So
Speaker 3:  My 15 has deteriorated faster than any iPhone I've ever used.
Speaker 2:  I haven't even looked at the deterioration. I'm just like, oh, it's the middle
Speaker 2:  of the day. I should charge my phone. Ooh. Ooh. That's where I'm, that's
Speaker 2:  where I'm this,
Speaker 3:  That's tough.
Speaker 2:  That's what's not good. But I, the, the, the stats as far as I can tell,
Speaker 2:  what they're talking about is hours of video playback as a proxy for everything
Speaker 2:  else. They just don't want to be like 33 hours of video
Speaker 2:  playback on a slide.
Speaker 3:  We spent a bunch of time last week talking about how stupid a metric that
Speaker 3:  is. So whatever, we can move on.
Speaker 5:  We'll talk about it next week. I frequently
Speaker 3:  Watched or week after, dozens of hours of consecutive offline video on my
Speaker 3:  phone. Do you guys not? Yeah. Is that, yeah. That's not
Speaker 2:  What people do. It's hyper optimized video playback engine. Yeah. Amazing.
Speaker 3:  So you wanted to say something about the processor?
Speaker 2:  The processor, speaking of ultra optimized video playback engines, a lot
Speaker 2:  of our commenters have noticed that the processor
Speaker 2:  upgrades on the phone made for AI don't amount to much
Speaker 2:  like you actually still get, it's like 35 flops, right? Is the,
Speaker 2:  the thing. And that's what you get like the end,
Speaker 5:  But on a phone. Ooh.
Speaker 2:  Well, sure. But that's the same as like last year. Yeah. So I it. I I think
Speaker 2:  the made for AI claims are kind of like running right up against the
Speaker 2:  reality of
Speaker 5:  Reality
Speaker 2:  Phone development times. And I, I think mostly what they've done is just
Speaker 2:  put a bunch of ram in all these phones. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Eight gigs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is they loaded
Speaker 3:  'em up, which is great. Like terrific more Ram is a good thing.
Speaker 5:  They're not each $400 more because Apple put more ram in them is really
Speaker 5:  impressive.
Speaker 3:  Seriously. Yeah. But no, i i, to some extent, the processor
Speaker 3:  thing I think is, is whatever, right? Like, I, I think you're right that
Speaker 3:  If you were going to make like an AI phone that wanted to do all this
Speaker 3:  vastly complicated stuff offline and locally and be awesome.
Speaker 3:  Fine. But like what you have in the a 18 is going to
Speaker 3:  do the job of writing business emails for you perfectly
Speaker 3:  fine. Like we, the, the ceiling of interesting AI
Speaker 3:  features right now is still so much lower on a device like this than the
Speaker 3:  performance ceiling of the device that I'm just not
Speaker 3:  bothered by this.
Speaker 5:  Just you Wait, David, it's gonna write the most beautiful email. I
Speaker 3:  Hope I'm wrong. Like someday in 2036 when Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  actually ships, maybe it'll be amazing. Everything changes really fast. Who
Speaker 3:  knows? It's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be an email that makes you weep. You're gonna be like, how
Speaker 5:  could it, no human could write this. It's too pretty.
Speaker 3:  The thing is I'll never see it. My, my Apple mail will just summarize it
Speaker 3:  for me. I'll never even see it. It's no problems.
Speaker 5:  And that summary will also be beautiful. But we should talk about, we should
Speaker 5:  talk about these AirPods, right? Yeah. Let's
Speaker 3:  Talk AirPods. This was the
Speaker 5:  Most
Speaker 3:  Exciting, I think this was the coolest part of the whole this talking about,
Speaker 3:  was it? I was about to say it was three AirPods. I think it was four AirPods.
Speaker 3:  Will you, will you run this down for us?
Speaker 5:  Well, so yes. Like Yeah. It's four technically. I think
Speaker 5:  it's four. It is four. Well, three.
Speaker 3:  It's like three and a
Speaker 5:  Half. Yeah, we'll go three and a half. We'll go three and a half. Okay. So
Speaker 5:  there's the AirPods four, it's two and You can, they're two flat. No,
Speaker 5:  you we'll get there. We're doing Apple map. It's, it's, it's at least if
Speaker 5:  they think can have four lenses,
Speaker 3:  It might be six or seven.
Speaker 5:  We'll see. We're just gonna keep adding It's two.
Speaker 2:  All right, go ahead. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So they're the AirPods four and there are, Lia is correct. Two
Speaker 5:  versions of them. There's one that's like $129
Speaker 5:  and it's got, you know, it's the new shape and, and all of that stuff.
Speaker 5:  And then there's one that's $179 and that's also got active noise
Speaker 5:  canceling in it. And in both cases there'll be head
Speaker 5:  shake to respond to Siri. I believe the personalized facial
Speaker 5:  audio, is that in both? I'm pretty sure. Yeah. The H two chip is gonna
Speaker 5:  be in both USBC charging case
Speaker 5:  30 hours of battery life. The, the, the battery
Speaker 5:  case is gonna have a little speaker in it so it'll beep beep when you lose
Speaker 5:  it. Which has been hugely helpful with my pros. They rule
Speaker 5:  like these are just, these are really good AirPods. And then
Speaker 5:  just 'cause I have to prove that there's four updates. There's the AirPods
Speaker 5:  max, which are still just $549. That didn't
Speaker 5:  change. But now we get some more colors and You can charge 'em with
Speaker 5:  USBC. You don't have to care about your lightning cable. So technically
Speaker 5:  new AirPod max
Speaker 3:  And just right there, you talked about it longer than Apple did during Keynote.
Speaker 5:  I did. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  It, it was like somebody at Apple was being held hostage until they mentioned
Speaker 3:  the Air Pod Max. Did you list the colors? It was so bizarre. They were like
Speaker 3:  new colors USBC moving up.
Speaker 2:  Okay. They also were like, it's still $549.
Speaker 2:  I don't, the AirPods Maxs are absolutely not a new product.
Speaker 2:  usc, they changed the connector. They should have had a year and a half ago,
Speaker 2:  if not more. If they may two colors. It's the same. We're gonna get 'em the
Speaker 2:  app watch. Same with the Apple Watch Ultra too. We're like, here's a video
Speaker 2:  about how it's black now.
Speaker 2:  It
Speaker 5:  Sure is.
Speaker 3:  I I almost wrote in the live blog when there's a long sweeping shot of
Speaker 3:  the watch band. You know, there's nothing else to tell you. But anyway, so
Speaker 3:  wait, Chris, did you talk about the, the AirPods pros? No. No. And
Speaker 5:  Then this is our fourth set of AirPods. Yeah. The fourth one is The AirPods
Speaker 5:  Pro two, which will not change in
Speaker 5:  any reasonable way, but they, they're new because they're getting
Speaker 5:  hearing aid features.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's cool. New
Speaker 5:  Feature. That means a whole new
Speaker 2:  Audience that
Speaker 5:  Is basically due,
Speaker 2:  That is the single most important aspect of this entire event. But that is
Speaker 2:  not new AirPods. I just wanna be that. It's, they announced two
Speaker 2:  new AirPods and some software features of
Speaker 2:  monumental importance.
Speaker 3:  Can I just admit something right now on this show? I didn't realize until
Speaker 3:  right now that it was just a software update. I thought there had to be something
Speaker 3:  new in the hardware. If you're gonna tell me about how this is a hearing
Speaker 3:  aid. You're telling me this is just a software record?
Speaker 5:  It's the same. It's just software. A
Speaker 3:  Software record software. So if I have existing AirPods Pros, they're gonna
Speaker 3:  get these two. They have
Speaker 5:  To be the two.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you need the AirPods two, AirPod AirPods Pro two,
Speaker 2:  AirPods two Pro two Pro two series
Speaker 5:  AirPods
Speaker 3:  Pro two Attorneys General.
Speaker 2:  You need the H two chip. So you need the, you need the second generation
Speaker 2:  AirPods Pro. and then you need a phone that can run iOS 18.
Speaker 2:  So there's some cutoff on what phone you have. Sure. But If, you have those
Speaker 2:  two things. You can take the hearing test, which which will,
Speaker 2:  you know, apple has to finish its FD clearance. But they, they say they're
Speaker 2:  gonna do it and then they can act as hearing aids for the same battery life
Speaker 2:  as as they get now about six hours.
Speaker 5:  I mean, you, you did the, the f like I'd be remiss if I didn't point out
Speaker 5:  FDA clearance is in fact a thing. They have to still get,
Speaker 2:  They have to still get it. They haven't gotten it yet. Yeah, they, they,
Speaker 2:  they say they're gonna get it around the, around the world as well. They're
Speaker 2:  also very careful with the language. They're not hearing aids. They have
Speaker 2:  a certified hearing aids functionality,
Speaker 5:  Which there's a lot of hearing aids now that work kind of
Speaker 5:  like AirPods. So this feels like a huge deal.
Speaker 2:  Again, I I I, I think I've told this story in the British ask before, but
Speaker 2:  I'll tell it again. The only thing that our government of old people
Speaker 2:  accomplished in the Trump administration is they all got together and passed
Speaker 2:  bipartisan legislation that Trump signed to make hearing aids
Speaker 2:  legal over the counter. Yeah. Because they were all a million years old.
Speaker 2:  Chuck Schumer and Nancy Pelosi and Mitch McConnell and Donald Trump were
Speaker 2:  like, yeah, yeah, we should make hearing aids easier to get. 'cause we're
Speaker 2:  all a billion years old.
Speaker 5:  We can't hear shit.
Speaker 2:  It was, it's a, a triumph of bipartisanship that would, they
Speaker 2:  passed a lot making hearing aids available over the counter in this way.
Speaker 2:  Sony has them, Bose has 'em. A bunch of other companies sprung up. Bose entered
Speaker 2:  the space and they left the space. They came back in with a partner. 'cause
Speaker 2:  they're complicated. I sort of asked about this with Apple Apple's attitude
Speaker 2:  is like, it's not that complicated for us. 'cause we're Apple and then also
Speaker 2:  fascinatingly, their belief is that because they're AirPods
Speaker 2:  they'll be more socially acceptable than hearing aids.
Speaker 3:  I believe that a hundred percent. I think that is by far the most exciting
Speaker 3:  thing about this is like we, we were debating this in the, in the
Speaker 3:  newsroom today, but like we have long since reached the point
Speaker 3:  where just having one AirPod in all the time is completely
Speaker 3:  socially normal and acceptable. Right. Like I, it's You can feel about it
Speaker 3:  however you want, but like that it's just a fact. That's where we world.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 5:  No, I
Speaker 3:  Agree with you. Like one of my favorite things is to see couples walking
Speaker 3:  down the street, holding hands, talking to each other, each with like the
Speaker 3:  opposite AirPod in like it's just life now people do it. And
Speaker 3:  I the fact that
Speaker 2:  Is this something you see couples do or is this something you do in your
Speaker 2:  relationship? I
Speaker 5:  Was, I was like, David, I've never seen this.
Speaker 3:  I would never, I see people doing this all the time. You need to go outside
Speaker 3:  more often. Cramp. I don't know what people do in New Jersey.
Speaker 5:  I was like, apparently they don't hear that in Jersey.
Speaker 3:  But No, but I think the idea, there are lots of interesting questions about,
Speaker 3:  like, I just wanna
Speaker 2:  Point out that David lives in Washington DC home of an infinite variety of
Speaker 2:  government lawyers and contractors. and it sort of makes sense that they've
Speaker 2:  all replaced Blackberry hand with AirPod ear.
Speaker 3:  A hundred percent. A hundred percent. DC was definitely like the last vestige
Speaker 3:  of the huge Bluetooth headset. And they just like, they went straight into
Speaker 3:  wearing AirPods on Hinge dance. It's like, that's just, it's it's,
Speaker 2:  It's an election year and everyone's got one AirPod in is like what David
Speaker 2:  is describing. Alright.
Speaker 3:  It's just Ezra Klein talking to every single person in Washington
Speaker 3:  DC all at the same time. That's just
Speaker 2:  What it is. That's not wrong. Yeah. Makes sense.
Speaker 3:  No, it's, it's you, me and Ezra on a date together at all times. That's great.
Speaker 3:  But, but no, I think the fact that no one would look at you twice for wearing
Speaker 3:  an AirPod in a coffee shop is like a huge part of the reason. This is incredibly
Speaker 3:  compelling. I think it's so cool. But
Speaker 5:  Does this mean that now people are just, I mean people are just gonna talk
Speaker 5:  to you when you have your AirPods in like before it was like a universal
Speaker 5:  sign of don't talk to me. Yes. And now it's gonna be like, I'll talk to you.
Speaker 5:  That might be a hearing aid.
Speaker 2:  If, you zoom out. Apple pitched a pretty weird vision
Speaker 2:  of reality today where you are always wearing
Speaker 2:  AirPods.
Speaker 3:  This is what I'm saying. I don't think that's a vision. I think that's reality.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 2:  But like you're wearing them at, at a concert, you're wearing them to prevent
Speaker 2:  hearing loss. You're in adaptive mode all the time where like on your job
Speaker 2:  site, all of your hearing is being modulated through AirPods. Like
Speaker 2:  they're just prosthetics. Fine. And then I,
Speaker 2:  not to get too in the weeds of weirdness, apple also makes the
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro, which wants to mediate your site. And after a
Speaker 2:  while you're just like, Tim Cook is building a helmet and you're gonna go
Speaker 2:  in the helmet and Apple's gonna manage the world for you and like clean it
Speaker 2:  up for you. And that is a weird vision of the future. But the amount of
Speaker 2:  let, let us put a computer in between you and reality is very high in Apple
Speaker 2:  world right now. That said, and you know, You can feel about wearing
Speaker 2:  AirPods. Isn't
Speaker 5:  That a whole episode of Black Mirror
Speaker 2:  Too? It's Tim Cook builds a helmet. It's a great episode of Black Mirror.
Speaker 2:  All that is to say maybe that's awful. Hit regular people in, in different
Speaker 2:  ways. The actual hearing aid functionality. If they can get
Speaker 2:  more people to take real hearing tests and then wear hearing
Speaker 2:  aids, they will do a great service to the world. Like this is very exciting.
Speaker 2:  And all those competitor hearing aids I was talking about from Sony and Bose
Speaker 2:  and all these other companies, a thousand dollars.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, this could change my Thanksgiving. And
Speaker 2:  They, and they have like bad apps and weird features and all this other stuff.
Speaker 2:  This is what AirPod pros are two 50, right.
Speaker 2:  250 bucks and the hearing test is built into the OS and it is perfectly tuned.
Speaker 2:  And you might have, might not have the weird social acceptability problems
Speaker 2:  that that's a very meaningful, again, i I think it's probably
Speaker 2:  the biggest announcement I made today on, on in the scale of things.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I agree. And the fact that you take that hearing test and not only
Speaker 3:  does it tune the hearing aid stuff, but it tunes everything else in the
Speaker 3:  AirPods to you I think is very cool. Yeah. Like Apple has clearly
Speaker 3:  kind of gone all the way down this road watching them talk about it. It made
Speaker 3:  me think about the stuff that they did for the Vision Pro, which is like,
Speaker 3:  you have to do an incredible amount of work because of the affordances of
Speaker 3:  like the human body. So they had to like invent this new way to scan
Speaker 3:  your face to do it and created this whole crazy pipeline just to get the
Speaker 3:  thing to work on your face. For some reason, this feels like it's
Speaker 3:  in service of like a much cooler, more real thing for people. Which I, I
Speaker 3:  agree. I think it's
Speaker 5:  Possible. But they, they, they've done this before too. Like, like the, the
Speaker 5:  bit where it's supposed to modulate the hearing and stuff. They've done that
Speaker 5:  before. Like that's an accessibility feature now I think where You can put
Speaker 5:  it in, it'll do a hearing test. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They've had the voice captions, they've had transparency mode. They've
Speaker 2:  had live listen, they've done a lot of stuff that walks right
Speaker 2:  up to this line. Yeah. This is just over the line. Like the
Speaker 2:  FDA is gonna tell people these are hearing aid features and mean it and that
Speaker 2:  I think is it at 250 bucks it's just vastly
Speaker 2:  more accessible for so many people.
Speaker 5:  Well I'm just curious the quality of it because some
Speaker 5:  of those changes they've done before, like I've messed with those accessibility
Speaker 5:  features and they're not that great. Like the one where it's supposed to
Speaker 5:  do kind of a little hearing test and and and be like, we're gonna make the
Speaker 5:  sound even better for your ears.
Speaker 5:  I guess my ears are garbage.
Speaker 3:  You don't love your personalized spatial
Speaker 2:  Audio. No, your ears are good. That's
Speaker 3:  The problem.
Speaker 5:  There we go.
Speaker 2:  Right. So If, you are not If you don't have some big as you get older right.
Speaker 2:  You lose your high frequencies. It's like, have you ever watched these like
Speaker 2:  TikTok videos? It's like we can guess how old you are. Oh
Speaker 5:  No. There's a whole thing right now about it's just
Speaker 2:  Remarkable.
Speaker 5:  It's, and this, this wine that people hear
Speaker 5:  apparently the new
Speaker 2:  Oh interesting.
Speaker 5:  Because I've been spending a
Speaker 2:  Lot of time going, it got a super high pitched wine on the
Speaker 5:  Tablets. Yeah. I'm like, oh my god, am I just so old? I didn't hear this
Speaker 5:  wine on the remarkable, right.
Speaker 2:  So you're losing, you might be losing the very, very top end, but as you
Speaker 2:  get older you lose even more or you have different cutouts or what all this
Speaker 2:  stuff happens. So If, you have reasonably good ears. The
Speaker 2:  let's tune it to make it work for you is gonna accomplish nothing. 'cause
Speaker 2:  there's nothing to tune. Okay. If, you have frequency dropouts or other
Speaker 2:  kinds of hearing issues. The tuning will actually overcome it and it
Speaker 2:  will sound clear and rich again. So, oh, will any of this work? I have
Speaker 2:  no idea. Yeah. On AirPods, this is what audiologists do today to tune
Speaker 2:  real hearing aids.
Speaker 5:  You just made my ears sound better, so this is great. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You should be proud of, I mean you can't hear the remarkable, you're getting
Speaker 2:  old Alex, you, you should watch.
Speaker 5:  I know I'm getting old. I can't hear the remarkable, but the, the accessibility
Speaker 5:  feature on AirPods sucks for me. So that means
Speaker 3:  My hair great. I can convince most of those things are just scams perpetrated
Speaker 3:  by young people to make old people feel old. They're not playing sound when
Speaker 3:  they're like, only young people can hear this. This is what I
Speaker 2:  Told about. That's totally how you know you're getting old. That's that's
Speaker 2:  it. We're there.
Speaker 3:  But, but I think the, the thing you just mentioned, NELI, I think is actually
Speaker 3:  like the question of all of the AirPods kind of all the way down the line,
Speaker 3:  not including the max, which are technically a new product, but you know,
Speaker 3:  whatever
Speaker 3:  that can Apple back these really advanced features into the
Speaker 3:  existing product, I think is the question. Right. And even If, you go down
Speaker 3:  to the, the regular AirPods, it's a
Speaker 3:  $50 upgrade to get noise cancellation. And if
Speaker 3:  Apple has figured out how to do like genuinely good
Speaker 3:  a NC inside of an open ear set of headphones,
Speaker 3:  that's a big deal. $50 is a lot of money to spend for
Speaker 3:  that particular upgrade. Especially if you're like, if you're not so
Speaker 3:  price sensitive that you only want the cheapest one, but you're too
Speaker 3:  price sensitive to buy the pros. Like there's a very odd sort of middle ground
Speaker 3:  there that I think Apple is trying to strike. And, and the question of can
Speaker 3:  we bring these advanced features down into a different form factor that is
Speaker 3:  not optimized and designed for those features kind of is the question. And
Speaker 3:  I have no idea. Have you tried these things at all yet?
Speaker 2:  I have not yet. Okay. I don't know if I believe it. Like we have to
Speaker 2:  see it. Yeah. Like noise canceling is pretty dumb
Speaker 2:  technology. It's very clever and you need a lot of processing power to do
Speaker 2:  it. But the idea is pretty dumb, right? You listen to some things that you
Speaker 2:  identify as noise and then you just play back their
Speaker 2:  inverse to cancel out the
Speaker 3:  Sound. The opposite of that noise. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. It's like it's very dumb idea. And the hard parts are
Speaker 2:  like identifying what is noise, making sure you don't, you know, accidentally
Speaker 2:  clip a bunch of useful frequencies, all this other stuff, doing an
Speaker 2:  open ear. You're just not in control of the sound environment. Like sound
Speaker 2:  is literally getting around the headphones. So are they just gonna run
Speaker 2:  a bunch of like white noise cancellation,
Speaker 2:  like super, like will other people be able to hear the cancellation is like
Speaker 2:  kind of what I'm interested
Speaker 3:  In. Oh, that's interesting. Well,
Speaker 5:  I'm also curious. They they have to fit right? Like, like
Speaker 5:  the, the whole thing that they don't have a seal, they just sort of sit in
Speaker 5:  your ear. I I never liked them because they were that leaky. 'cause I could
Speaker 5:  hear everything around me and now I'm gonna be able to hear everything around
Speaker 5:  me, but then sometimes it's gonna be blocking some stuff that feels like
Speaker 5:  a good recipe for like your brain just getting messed up trying to listen
Speaker 5:  to your headphones. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean, we'll see.
Speaker 5:  But it's Apple. I I wouldn't expect they wouldn't break brains with
Speaker 5:  product.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean they're, they're gonna, they're confident It is what I'd say.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think it, it is the sort of thing that
Speaker 3:  it's an odd skew of the product. Like If, you go to Apple's website right
Speaker 3:  now and you go to buy AirPods, the options are AirPods and AirPods with adaptive
Speaker 3:  noise cancellation. And I think If, you have a product that is technically
Speaker 3:  titled AirPods with adaptive Noise cancellation. You should maybe
Speaker 3:  rethink your product SKUs. But like, if, if
Speaker 3:  they've done that, I think suddenly like this becomes at
Speaker 3:  $179, like maybe the pair of headphones that just about
Speaker 3:  everybody should buy.
Speaker 5:  But I don't think that's gonna be the case because of the fit. Like, like
Speaker 5:  the fit on the AirPods is so specific and it works for a lot of
Speaker 5:  people. And if it doesn't work for you, it sucks.
Speaker 3:  That's true of the pros too though. Yeah. Can I
Speaker 2:  Say two things about this? One Apple said without any sourcing that
Speaker 2:  AirPods two are the most popular he iPhone in the world, which I can believe
Speaker 2:  I would just Sure, sure. It's like The Verge is the most popular website
Speaker 2:  in the world. Like Sure. You can believe it. We are by the way. It's true.
Speaker 2:  That's true. And then second, they introduced the new AirPods four
Speaker 2:  with this sort of like, you know, short description how everyone's ears are
Speaker 2:  different. They've measured all the ears and they got to the right chin.
Speaker 2:  They said that
Speaker 5:  The first time
Speaker 2:  They No, no, not even the first time they said that when they announced the
Speaker 2:  wired EarPods
Speaker 2:  with not, I think not even the first iPhone, like with an iPod nano is when
Speaker 2:  EarPods came out, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Because you would ask like, like I've asked them before, Hey,
Speaker 5:  are we ever gonna get different sizes because these are too big for some
Speaker 5:  ears? And they'd be like, no, we did a test and it works for
Speaker 5:  90.9% or whatever, you're fine.
Speaker 3:  But the thing is like that's that's true. Like it turns out
Speaker 3:  that everyone started wearing EarPods and buying
Speaker 3:  iPhones because they worked for most people. Oh
Speaker 5:  No, I can't use the, the original AirPods. I couldn't fit in them at all.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 3:  Had to get rid of them. Well listen Alex, we've established,
Speaker 5:  I've got tiny ear canals. Okay.
Speaker 3:  It's, this
Speaker 5:  Is a very specific problem for
Speaker 3:  Me. Pros fit. You're good with pros, your pros
Speaker 5:  Fit. But I have to use this
Speaker 3:  The opposite. Pros feel awful on me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So Apple announced the EarPods in 2012.
Speaker 2:  It was a Johnny I video, it was alongside The iPhone five and the
Speaker 2:  iPod. It was like, what a year? This is how old they were. And at the
Speaker 2:  time they were like, we asked more than 600 people to test over a hundred
Speaker 2:  iterations of the EarPods. They, we made 'em run on treadmills
Speaker 2:  and extreme heat and cold. They did cardio. They shook their heads up and
Speaker 2:  down and ear pods are like the design that fit the most ears. And now
Speaker 2:  we're like 12 years later and they're like, we did it again. We've once again
Speaker 2:  measured all of the ears in the world and they look a little bit different.
Speaker 2:  And maybe that's true
Speaker 3:  Evolution baby. Sure.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's true. They, they stuck with this design for a long time and, and
Speaker 2:  maybe ears have changed, but I, I think the reason
Speaker 2:  AirPods Pro are the most more popular headphones
Speaker 2:  even are more expensive. Maybe just the word pro in the name. Maybe it's
Speaker 2:  noise canceling. I actually just think they stay in people's ears better.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I I would agree.
Speaker 3:  I do. I I I do agree with that. And I think especially early on, the regular
Speaker 3:  AirPods developed a reputation for falling out of your head. Right? Like
Speaker 3:  there, for years there were all those stories of people like losing the AirPod
Speaker 3:  on the street and it would fall down. And the, whether it was true for you
Speaker 3:  or not, that fear was real. And even, even for somebody like me,
Speaker 3:  it, they fit well in my ears. They don't fall out. I am perpetually terrified
Speaker 3:  they're gonna fall out because they feel loose. Which is actually like the
Speaker 3:  point, right? Yeah. You see people like, that's why I like them because they
Speaker 3:  don't feel like they're smooshed into my head, but it makes me
Speaker 3:  feel like they're gonna fall out all the time. And the pros for better and
Speaker 3:  worse smoosh into your head Yes. And don't feel that way. And I think,
Speaker 3:  I think that is real for people. Like, IIII agree with you. You
Speaker 5:  See people like covering their ears sometimes if they're walking over a great
Speaker 5:  or, or hopp on the train and, and because I think like the, the
Speaker 5:  og AirPods feel kind of like earrings,
Speaker 5:  but then like clip on earrings. This is something you neither one of you
Speaker 5:  probably have a lot of familiarity with. But there, you know, there's earrings
Speaker 5:  that go in your ear and judgment that cramp. They hang right there. That's
Speaker 5:  true. What's, what's that little, little piercing there? David looks great,
Speaker 5:  but people, you know, they like in and the, when you have those clip-ons,
Speaker 5:  you're constantly like holding your hands up because they're gonna fall off.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. and AirPods feel the same way. And nobody wants, nobody wants clip-ons.
Speaker 2:  I just like how much you two are looking at people in their AirPods, like
Speaker 2:  is anthropologists. Yeah. Like David's like there's another couple wearing
Speaker 2:  one AirPod each. And Alex is like, another person's here buffing over a grate.
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 5:  It's nice because then I'm like, oh, I'm not
Speaker 2:  Alone. I'm
Speaker 3:  Fascinated. It's called journalism.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that too.
Speaker 3:  This is also why I read everyone's screens when they're texting on the train.
Speaker 3:  It's journalism.
Speaker 5:  I love it when you find somebody like typing spicy stuff. You're like, oh
Speaker 5:  my god. Little
Speaker 3:  I literal, I had one time, this is a true story, missed my train and
Speaker 3:  rode it for one extra hour because there was a guy I was
Speaker 3:  standing and he was sitting in like the first seat next to me and he was
Speaker 3:  in the middle of breaking up with his girlfriend over text messages. And
Speaker 3:  you
Speaker 2:  Read the whole thing.
Speaker 3:  And I, for one more hour than I needed to just, I,
Speaker 3:  I got through the whole breakup. It was spectacular. It, it involved
Speaker 3:  7,000 words of text messages. Wow. If you made me guess. It was, it was
Speaker 3:  incredible.
Speaker 2:  Were you like Jennifer for one second? You just call her on the phone.
Speaker 3:  Seriously. Right. It's like I'll FaceTime her right now. Like we can do this
Speaker 3:  together. What, what's up? It'll be fine.
Speaker 2:  You
Speaker 5:  Just sit down next to him.
Speaker 2:  I hear her on the market. The guy next to me on the plane here, I swear to
Speaker 2:  God was trying to rot August flight. He failed six hour flight from New York
Speaker 2:  to California. That's tough. Failed. Failed. Just like failed. Then he picked
Speaker 2:  up his phone, started typing in all lower case in notes app for a while.
Speaker 2:  Didn't read it. I did see him text the words I need to write my own narrative
Speaker 2:  to a friend also in lower case. And then
Speaker 2:  weirdest of all on his phone, on on Delta wifi,
Speaker 2:  which is garbage. Started powering through Gmail on
Speaker 2:  the web in Safari with the banner at the top of the screen
Speaker 2:  that said Gmail's better in the app. And I kept wanting to be like, bro,
Speaker 2:  it is better in the app.
Speaker 5:  I love him.
Speaker 3:  I honestly believe in moments like that is it is a, it should be allowed
Speaker 3:  to just reach over and tap the open button that opens it into the app.
Speaker 2:  I really believe that. You just, I was like, how are you using Safari with
Speaker 2:  the, the, the, the address bar on the bottom and you've got,
Speaker 2:  all right, that's fine.
Speaker 3:  That hurts me to hit that. He
Speaker 5:  Needs that, that 6.7 inch iPhone or
Speaker 5:  6.9 inch iPhone. He needs
Speaker 2:  A big one. So You can use You, can use Gmail.
Speaker 3:  Apple can One more line of text. Yeah. Speaking of one more line of text,
Speaker 3:  let's talk about the watches.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they're big.
Speaker 3:  They are big. That's
Speaker 2:  Basically another, another a moment in this keynote where Apple took a minute
Speaker 2:  to explain what You can do with the bigger screen the sees.
Speaker 2:  I would like if anyone's out there If, you could make me a super cut of Apple
Speaker 2:  executives patiently explaining that You can see more content on a bigger
Speaker 2:  screen over the past five years. It, I think it would be amazing.
Speaker 3:  It would also be hours long.
Speaker 3:  So, okay. The, the, the basic rundown on the watches as I understand
Speaker 3:  it is Apple, Watch, Series 10 new design. That looks
Speaker 3:  an awful lot like the old design. It's thinner, it has a bigger screen.
Speaker 3:  It comes in black I would say those are the salient points. It also comes
Speaker 3:  in other colors. Nobody seems to care about those colors. It comes in black.
Speaker 3:  Everybody's pretty excited about that fact. Shiny,
Speaker 2:  Shiny black.
Speaker 3:  Okay. How shiny are we talking? Well, okay, hold on. We'll get to, I wanna
Speaker 3:  talk, I want to hear what you think Neli. But then there's also the watch
Speaker 3:  two, which is nothing at all has changed except now it also comes in
Speaker 3:  black. Which again the
Speaker 2:  Ultra, a lot of two.
Speaker 3:  What did I say?
Speaker 2:  You said watch two son of it. The watch two is, it's
Speaker 2:  dramatic changes since the Apple Watch Series. It's changed
Speaker 3:  A lot since the Watch two If, you have a watch two you're in for
Speaker 2:  A treat. But the Apple watch Ultra two is unchanged. They did, they basically
Speaker 2:  reintroduce the product. They're like the ultra two is great for swimming
Speaker 2:  and rowing and, and diving and also just looking chunky and like you have
Speaker 2:  money also. It's black now then that was the end of that.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 2:  But the, the series 10 is a new design. It looks for
Speaker 2:  all the world, like the old, old design. It's just thinner. It's more rounded
Speaker 2:  on the top and yeah, it comes in polished aluminum black
Speaker 3:  Charges faster, which I think is very exciting. Yeah. But the, the design
Speaker 3:  is the one I'm curious about. 'cause I, my immediate reaction when they said
Speaker 3:  thinner was I, I don't care. Right? Like I, I looked at
Speaker 3:  the watch that was on my wrist and I was like, I don't, I don't know that
Speaker 3:  I've ever wished for this thing to be thinner. It's how I feel about my iPhone.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like every time they make it thinner, I'm like, that's nothing for
Speaker 3:  me. But then there were a bunch of people I saw on, on
Speaker 3:  Threads and elsewhere who were like, oh, you know, just based on like the,
Speaker 3:  the clothes I wear or like how I use my wrist, having something that's thinner
Speaker 3:  is actually really meaningful. So what I'm curious about neli, especially
Speaker 3:  as somebody who wears the chunky one every day, did
Speaker 3:  it feel different like If you had just picked it up. Would you have been
Speaker 3:  able to tell, 'cause it's been years really since you've been able to tell
Speaker 3:  kind of which one you were picking up? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  If you were paying attention. Yeah. Okay. For a normal person
Speaker 2:  you'd be like, the screen's bigger and that would be the thing.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Right.
Speaker 2:  You know how You can tell between a two and a four? 'cause the screen
Speaker 2:  got bigger. Was the four or five of the screen got bigger? I think it was
Speaker 2:  the four, right? I think that's right. So you know, the screen got bigger
Speaker 2:  so You can tell. And then the four to everything else, you couldn't tell.
Speaker 2:  It's that again. So it's like a very minor
Speaker 2:  adjustment, but it's bigger, thinner I think is hard.
Speaker 2:  but it, you know, for all intents and purposes, it's the same design.
Speaker 2:  Like we can lie to ourselves and say it's not the same design. It's the same
Speaker 2:  design.
Speaker 3:  Is the 10 screen now bigger than the ultra screen?
Speaker 2:  Yes. That's the thing they said
Speaker 3:  Wild,
Speaker 5:  Wild. Just the both screens or the 40. 'cause it's a
Speaker 5:  49.
Speaker 3:  No, the the case is the same size, but I guess because they made the
Speaker 3:  screen bigger in the case.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So the, it's now so bigger. There's a 42 and 46
Speaker 5:  are the case sizes. And the screen on both of them is bigger
Speaker 5:  than the ultra?
Speaker 3:  No, it has to just be the 46 to the
Speaker 5:  Bigger one. It has to be,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's a bigger
Speaker 5:  One. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it looks very nice. It looks very cool. You know, the, the
Speaker 2:  highlight features actually sleep apnea detection, not the size.
Speaker 2:  We have to see how well sleep apnea detection works works another FDA clearance
Speaker 2:  situation for Apple. Did
Speaker 3:  Either of you have a moment during the keynote where you were like, oh God,
Speaker 3:  am I about to find out I have sleep apnea. Like I don't know if this is a
Speaker 3:  thing I wanna know about myself.
Speaker 5:  I'm ready. I'm ready to learn. I'm open to new experiences.
Speaker 5:  I don't
Speaker 2:  Like wearing a watch when I sleep. I like
Speaker 3:  You don't sleep with your watch.
Speaker 2:  No, I, I I just, no, thank you.
Speaker 3:  I would say truly sincerely, my single favorite thing
Speaker 3:  about the Apple Watch is how good an alarm clock it is for my body. Like
Speaker 3:  it wakes me up better and easier and more pleasantly
Speaker 3:  than any alarm clock I've ever tried. And that is like two thirds of the
Speaker 3:  reason I wear
Speaker 2:  It. But when do you charge it?
Speaker 3:  I So I actually this is the reason. Faster charging is very exciting to me.
Speaker 3:  I charge it. Typically I will take it off when I go to shower in the morning
Speaker 3:  and I will just leave it on the charger till it's full. Mm. And sometimes
Speaker 3:  that means I leave it there for five days because I just forget about it.
Speaker 3:  But so the idea of actually being able to like put it down, go shower, come
Speaker 3:  back and it has charged, well I think it was 80% in 30 minutes it was supposed
Speaker 3:  to be. Yep. If it, if, if it gets to that suddenly in
Speaker 3:  my own experience Apple watch battery life sort of ceases to be a thing.
Speaker 3:  And I find that very exciting. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But
Speaker 5:  And it's the battery life's gotten really good over the last few years anyway.
Speaker 3:  The ultra is pretty good and I think the ultra, the a little I is still rated
Speaker 3:  like double what the series 10 is. I worry a little about the series 10 bigger
Speaker 3:  screen brighter screen
Speaker 5:  Thinner.
Speaker 3:  Thinner does not typically bode well for good battery. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Oh one, can I just say one thing? Random comment on screens. The
Speaker 2:  screens on The iPhone 1616 Pro can now go
Speaker 2:  down to one knit of brightness. Yes. It's actually wild to look at.
Speaker 2:  You turn the brightness all the way down. It's like the, it's just like a
Speaker 2:  ghost of an image. It's pretty cool.
Speaker 3:  That's actually awesome. Like somebody who uses my phone in bed more than
Speaker 3:  I'm proud of being able to get it like properly dim
Speaker 5:  Happy, get a one knit bed. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's the dream. Like we were talking last week about like e ink
Speaker 3:  devices and like what If you could make your screen not look so blue and
Speaker 3:  bright like one knit of brightness will do it. That'll get you
Speaker 3:  there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, it was very, it was very impressive. And then 2000 hits in in sunlight,
Speaker 2:  which is ridiculous. But yeah,
Speaker 3:  I really like she
Speaker 5:  Accidentally flash it on in bed.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Who was it? Was it Craig or somebody else who was like, sometimes people
Speaker 3:  look at their watches at an angle and it was like, yeah. Thanks dude. People
Speaker 3:  look at their watches at an angle. Yeah, they
Speaker 2:  Crazy. They, the viewing angle of the watch, the series 10 ed
Speaker 2:  is picked. I mean like again, If, you watch this keynote, the number of
Speaker 2:  times where they explain things like basic facts
Speaker 2:  about screens is so no one has seen a screen before
Speaker 2:  is hilarious. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wide angle ed. Yeah. That's like a whole
Speaker 2:  Phrase being used also. And I, and I say this in all compliments
Speaker 2:  as though Apple doesn't already make the best screens consistently in the
Speaker 2:  street. They're like this piece of garbage series not in display.
Speaker 2:  You couldn't even look at it from an angle. It's a terrify fine. Actually
Speaker 2:  no one was worried about that before. No,
Speaker 3:  Not, not a real thing. Wait, I wanna know about the blacks. Talk about the
Speaker 3:  blacks. You, you looked at both watches sincerely. It, it seems like
Speaker 3:  it. Apple had just gotten on stage and said we've changed
Speaker 3:  nothing except both watches now come in black. Everybody would've
Speaker 3:  been psyched and gone home happy. You've seen them both. How do they look
Speaker 3:  in black?
Speaker 2:  To be clear, they said we've changed nothing on one watch, which
Speaker 2:  now comes in black.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Fair. Do that. And I
Speaker 2:  Like, I'm gonna buy that watch. There's
Speaker 3:  A new watch face that does sort of a swirly thing where you can't really
Speaker 3:  tell what time it is. That's fun. Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 2:  I was talking to an Apple person wearing the black ultra too and I, I don't
Speaker 2:  even know what that person was saying. I was
Speaker 5:  Just like, just staring at the watch.
Speaker 2:  I was like, what if I just rob you?
Speaker 3:  But now that watch belongs to you. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like what if that was on my wrist and not yours? So that's great. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  buy that one. The, the shiny aluminum. It is shiny
Speaker 2:  aluminum black. Like it's, it's, it's fine. Like I don't, I dunno
Speaker 2:  what to say about it. It's a, it's a, it's a black metallic, like
Speaker 3:  The shiny worries me because of scratches. Should I be worried about
Speaker 3:  scratches?
Speaker 2:  You know, that thing was so covered in fingerprints when I looked at it.
Speaker 2:  I couldn't tell you if it was scratched or not.
Speaker 3:  You know, also not great.
Speaker 2:  It's just, it's not what you want. Did you notice my pictures of the phone?
Speaker 2:  Also fingerprint city. But everyone puts the phone in cases, so who knows.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's also been, yeah, it's been true for years. Every Apple product has
Speaker 5:  Fingerprint city. But don't have to put this put in cases.
Speaker 5:  Ceramic case,
Speaker 2:  The watch, you don't put a case by the way, the back of the Apple watch Ultra
Speaker 2:  two has special black sapphire glass. I'm gonna, I'm gonna buy this
Speaker 2:  product so fast for no
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. So that was all the big stuff. There's lots of
Speaker 3:  software stuff to talk about, but I feel like that's actually probably better
Speaker 3:  for next week or when
Speaker 2:  It ships.
Speaker 3:  Well that's all, that's it's all shipping next week. All the, well, all the
Speaker 3:  new oss are shipping next week. All the Apple intelligence stuff is shipping
Speaker 3:  someday in the unknown future.
Speaker 2:  If, you are a new Apple Os and you don't have Apple Intelligence.
Speaker 2:  Are you a new Apple OS yet?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, dude, have you seen how You can move the icons around on the grid now?
Speaker 3:  Game changer.
Speaker 2:  I actually, I'm I'm soliciting notes. We're gonna have to review these phones.
Speaker 2:  I don't know how without Apple Intelligence, I'm
Speaker 2:  legitimately like, how, how are we gonna write reviews of phones? So it'll
Speaker 2:  only exist in this form for some number of weeks
Speaker 2:  before the big update comes changes. It's so funny. I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm less optimistic than that. I think, I
Speaker 3:  think there is a, a super solid chance
Speaker 3:  that the actual experience of Apple intelligence is not going to show up
Speaker 3:  in a real way until The iPhone 17.
Speaker 2:  I would agree. Sure.
Speaker 3:  Like I think these phones are The iPhone 15 plus
Speaker 3:  the camera control. And I think, I think everyone who has to review this
Speaker 3:  phone is going to have to spend a deeply hilarious amount of time
Speaker 3:  litigating a button in a way that I think is so fun and so virgin and
Speaker 3:  I'm very jealous to not get to do it. But like the
Speaker 3:  AI stuff is gonna come in these like tiny bits and pieces and if we weren't
Speaker 3:  in a crazy AI moment where everybody had to pretend
Speaker 3:  to have an AI strategy or Wall Street would run away from you, we would just
Speaker 3:  call these things software. They're just features of apps and
Speaker 3:  supposedly we're gonna get game changing Siri that makes everything better
Speaker 3:  and solves phone interfaces forever, someday in the future.
Speaker 3:  I am in no single way holding my breath for any of that to happen on
Speaker 3:  this cycle of this iPhone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree with you. I'm just saying I don't think iOS
Speaker 2:  18 plus camera button is like, there's not a lot there. You know what I mean?
Speaker 2:  As much as I love a camera button and I, most of iPhone reviews that I've
Speaker 2:  ever written have been long meditations on the camera. Happy to do it again
Speaker 5:  Now
Speaker 2:  With a button. Thrilled to do it again. I just, it feels
Speaker 2:  like the reason people will upgrade to this phone
Speaker 2:  is 'cause the AI capabilities will let them do stuff that
Speaker 2:  they couldn't do on their old phone. The old phones are very capable of taking
Speaker 2:  a photo.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean, to be fair, a Apple has been making this particular case
Speaker 3:  since the iPad earlier this
Speaker 3:  spring. Like we're, we're deep into this now and, and Apple has been trying
Speaker 3:  to sell you AI ready devices without real AI to do it with
Speaker 3:  for months now. Yeah, well
Speaker 5:  I thought the AI stuff was largely for investors,
Speaker 5:  less for actual people. That was always kind of my read on Apple
Speaker 5:  ai.
Speaker 2:  I mean my, my number one question is why are they shipping these on September 20th
Speaker 2:  when the AI features are supposed to hit weeks later in October?
Speaker 3:  Again, some features in beta, like I,
Speaker 3:  I don't,
Speaker 2:  This is features aren't that long like fair
Speaker 3:  Or have
Speaker 2:  One to even have this series. The thing where you push the button and
Speaker 2:  Siri is now the border around the screen and set it a little circle.
Speaker 2:  Just gimme that.
Speaker 3:  I I honestly, it's so funny you say that. I was thinking about that this
Speaker 3:  afternoon. If they had just changed nothing else about Siri but made it glow
Speaker 3:  around the edges, everybody immediately would've been like, oh, Siri's better.
Speaker 3:  It just,
Speaker 2:  It would've,
Speaker 3:  It would've, it would've given everybody like a 10% boost in Siri
Speaker 3:  confidence. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  I'm open to to to feedback from y'all on how to review these
Speaker 2:  devices or when, 'cause I'm, I'm honestly
Speaker 2:  curious what would be the best service to everyone? Like a review of a phone
Speaker 2:  that If you buy in November has nothing to do with the phone that you bought
Speaker 2:  is kind of weird in my opinion.
Speaker 3:  Yep. Yeah. What you're actually getting at what I would say was the kind
Speaker 3:  of biggest vibe question that I had for you as somebody who's in the room
Speaker 3:  because Alex and I were not in the room and I would say the overwhelming
Speaker 3:  sense that I got from people both at The Verge and elsewhere. I was
Speaker 3:  getting text messages from people who were like, this is the most boring
Speaker 3:  iPhone launch I can remember. Same that like as, as a,
Speaker 3:  as a big flagship to September event. We talk about this every year, like
Speaker 3:  this is Apple's moment to speak to everyone. Like it is, it is the one that
Speaker 3:  everybody pays attention to. And I would say the overwhelming perception
Speaker 3:  was that it was kind of a bust. Yeah. How did it feel in the
Speaker 3:  room as it was happening?
Speaker 2:  I think this is why I kept notice noting the room was full of people who
Speaker 2:  were just excited to be there, right? Yeah. So they curated the
Speaker 2:  excitement that they needed and it was packed and people were freaking out
Speaker 2:  and they're doing the thing. And that's not to say I wasn't running around
Speaker 2:  trying to take photos and upload them as fast as I can. Like I like doing
Speaker 2:  it. It's like the funnest part of the job. But they had made the space
Speaker 2:  feel very excited and then you like take a step out of it and
Speaker 2:  you're like, okay, these are very iterative phones, like super
Speaker 2:  iterative phones. The headphones
Speaker 2:  upgrades apart from the 1.5 new models
Speaker 2:  are iterative to the point where like one of them didn't even
Speaker 2:  change
Speaker 2:  at all. The wash upgrades are also pretty iterative and
Speaker 2:  there's not any, I gotta have it upgrades unless you
Speaker 2:  really give a shit about the camera button. Right? All of those upgrades
Speaker 2:  are in the software That's Apple's magic, right. Hardware plus software services.
Speaker 2:  and we're just waiting on the big stuff.
Speaker 2:  Like if Apple had said Siri can now do this
Speaker 2:  like app coordination assistant thing that everyone wants to get
Speaker 2:  to, I think everybody would've upgraded the phones tomorrow. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Right. There were a bunch of moments in the keynote like that actually. Like
Speaker 3:  the, there was a moment where in the visual intelligence demo,
Speaker 3:  the guy holds up a phone to a, it was like a concert poster or
Speaker 3:  something I think Some kind of event. Yeah. Yeah. and it was like it'll input
Speaker 3:  the information directly into your calendar when you take that picture. And
Speaker 3:  I was like, if that's, I will buy any phone that will do that for me tomorrow.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's just not Ready's awesome. and it just doesn't exist. There's
Speaker 2:  Also another extremely weird demo where, where somebody walked up to a dog
Speaker 2:  and like asked the phone what kind of dog it was. And our own Kylie
Speaker 2:  Robinson was like, why would you do that? Why would you walk up to a stranger's
Speaker 2:  dog to
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just holding your phone out like this. Why,
Speaker 2:  Why wouldn't you just ask them what kind of dog this?
Speaker 3:  That gave me the same vibes as the the Gemini demo where
Speaker 3:  they were like, use this to write a, for your kid to write a letter to an
Speaker 3:  Olympian. It's like, oh, maybe you don't understand how people live and
Speaker 3:  exist in the world. Like this is actually like bleak as hell and not
Speaker 3:  cool and exciting technology. Yeah. The
Speaker 5:  Dog one. I did think, 'cause this's the same demo you do with the Met Raybans
Speaker 5:  is you put 'em on and you're like, what car is that? What dog is that?
Speaker 3:  But but the thing was he, he walked up to the person holding the dog
Speaker 3:  and the the intimation Is that what he said is not, oh that dog is so
Speaker 3:  cute. What dog is that? He said, can I take a picture of your dog with my
Speaker 3:  phone? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because I wanna know what kind of dog it's, and I don't wanna talk to you.
Speaker 2:  And I would point out you often encounter cars with they're owners,
Speaker 2:  If you encounter a dog without, so like that's, that's like a little bit
Speaker 2:  of an emergency.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You're not like, what breed is this? I better find out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you're like, hold on, stop here dog.
Speaker 5:  You pause. I need to pose.
Speaker 2:  I I I just think, I think that is overwhelmingly the reason why at
Speaker 2:  distance, this one was the a little content free. Like even the
Speaker 2:  feature boxes, right? The bento boxes they put up at the end of every segment.
Speaker 2:  Go look at The iPhone 16 feature box. It says USBC
Speaker 2:  on it.
Speaker 2:  It's like, oh, we, we didn't even have enough to fill up the squares. And
Speaker 2:  so like these are super iterative phones, which whose
Speaker 2:  key feature is the ram and the memory bandwidth to enable
Speaker 2:  all of the AI stuff which isn't shipping. Right? Yeah. So like why would
Speaker 2:  you be excited about it? And I think that's really the gap. I think they
Speaker 2:  should have said we're shipping these phones with the first wave of beta
Speaker 2:  features and just held them three weeks into October. But
Speaker 2:  Apple sells so many phones. So I don't think they can do that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They couldn't afforded to hold it that long. They needed to get it
Speaker 5:  out and if the software is not ready, so be it.
Speaker 3:  And this goes back, Alex, to what you were saying is like the, the reason
Speaker 3:  you do that is Wall Street, right? Like yeah. This is not a thing you do
Speaker 3:  in the service of good user experience. This is a thing you do because we
Speaker 3:  are in a moment where If, you appear to be behind on ai, you will be punished.
Speaker 3:  And that is right or wrong. That is the world in which we live.
Speaker 3:  And so everyone is out here announcing features that aren't going to ship
Speaker 3:  anytime soon or ever because you have to and it's so
Speaker 3:  un apple-like to do that. Yeah. It's so, so, so
Speaker 3:  odd to see Apple tell you its plans. Like this is not what
Speaker 3:  Apple does. This is not what Apple has ever done. And and it has to because
Speaker 3:  it can't build the things yet. Did
Speaker 5:  You guys also notice that it was doing a weird thing where they didn't call
Speaker 5:  it ai, they called it like our Apple intelligence, but they wouldn't call
Speaker 5:  it ai. They would always default to machine learning.
Speaker 3:  I clocked once that he said the word ai, but every other one was some
Speaker 3:  like dance around it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like they were really going outta their way to not sound like Google,
Speaker 5:  to not sound like their competitors in this space. Which is kind of interesting.
Speaker 2:  I mean they have branded Apple intelligence. I they're fine with it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 5:  They, they do have their own ai Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They have multiple AI models. At one point, I believe with the watch If,
Speaker 2:  you go back and watch it. They point out that they're running many models
Speaker 2:  to enable the features you enjoy today. And it's like, great. So it's
Speaker 2:  the same the same as the one I have today.
Speaker 5:  Thanks. Yeah. That, that was just like, why are you talking to investors
Speaker 5:  during this infomercial? You're trying to sell me these phones. Yeah. To
Speaker 5:  the point where you even have buy now like verbiage
Speaker 5:  in your thing. Stop it. It was weird. But let's talk about fine
Speaker 5:  woven because it feels like fine woven might be gone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is good. Before we leave, let's just little bit of accessory news
Speaker 3:  and then we're gonna get outta here. Is
Speaker 2:  This an accessory lightning round?
Speaker 3:  This is an accessory lightning round, but the way we're gonna do this is
Speaker 3:  I'm going to tell you what's happening and if you're not interested, just
Speaker 3:  don't say anything and we'll keep going. It's
Speaker 2:  Gonna be great. I love this. This is great.
Speaker 3:  Thing number one, apple has a faster mag safe charger to go with The
Speaker 3:  iPhone sixteens Q2, which I believe this might
Speaker 3:  be the first time a phone company has actually said Q2 out loud on stage
Speaker 3:  about a phone that people in America can buy. That's very exciting. Yep.
Speaker 5:  I'm excited. We're gonna, there we go. Charge faster. Yay. It's
Speaker 3:  Great. We love a fast charge. Love it. I said this in the lightning bug,
Speaker 3:  but there was a time that Neli made fun of me for having a MagSafe charger.
Speaker 3:  I I was, we were, we were in a, a restaurant somewhere and I slapped the
Speaker 3:  puck onto the back of my phone and Neli made fun of me for like 10 straight
Speaker 3:  minutes. I'm sorry.
Speaker 2:  If. you have a wire connected to a battery.
Speaker 2:  Why would you pick the least efficient way of charging your phone with that
Speaker 2:  wire?
Speaker 3:  Because it, it, it, it flocks. I love the block.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's good noise.
Speaker 2:  I will say I'm a full convert into mag safe batteries.
Speaker 2:  Actually I should have one over here. That, that's what I do now is like
Speaker 2:  the mag safe battery packs because you don't have to deal with the wires.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They get hot and it's inefficient. And, if you have a wire connected
Speaker 2:  to a battery pack, David, you should just plug it into the bottom of the
Speaker 2:  phone.
Speaker 3:  Fuck.
Speaker 5:  Anyway,
Speaker 3:  Next up, like you were mentioning, Crans, So, I, I would actually like you
Speaker 3:  to explain this to me because we thought fine woven was probably dead.
Speaker 3:  Apple didn't say fine, woven is dead, but it kind of seems like fine
Speaker 3:  woven is
Speaker 5:  Dead fine. Just seems like Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Fine. Woven being apple's terrible bad take on
Speaker 3:  leather accessories.
Speaker 5:  Kinda this was their, their, their cloth accessory that was really just plastic
Speaker 5:  that was meant to like replace all the leather and be a lot more ego
Speaker 5:  friendly. And that's probably true. but it also sucked and it got
Speaker 5:  dirty and gross and nobody liked it.
Speaker 3:  Like what if it was leather? But like much worse. Yeah. Much, much worse.
Speaker 5:  And now you can't
Speaker 5:  buy a phone case made of fine woven.
Speaker 5:  There's a, there's a wallet and that, that's about it. We've, we've reached
Speaker 5:  out, we haven't heard anything back yet. The
Speaker 3:  Wallet strikes me as one where they're like, look, we have a bunch of these.
Speaker 3:  We might as well keep it for sale. Yeah. It's like Google with the Chromecast
Speaker 3:  now, where they were like, they have If. you take the TV streamer, they're
Speaker 3:  clearly out on the Chromecast, but they're like, look, there's a room full
Speaker 3:  of these. Like If, you wanna buy it? Yeah, please buy it. Fine. Woven has
Speaker 3:  been dead. I would say since about like a day after it launched.
Speaker 2:  The wallet doesn't require the size and shape of the phone. Right.
Speaker 2:  So like you can't just sell off the excess. Right. You have your iPhone 15
Speaker 2:  Pro Max cases and you don't make iPhone 15 Pro Maxes anymore. You're,
Speaker 2:  you're just like, I don't, can you recycle it? We recycle everything around
Speaker 2:  here. Just turn it into something else, Johnny. We'll see what happens.
Speaker 5:  Fine movement is not fine.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. All right. Next up. I would say one of the stranger stories of the
Speaker 3:  day, Beats famous
Speaker 3:  music company. You may have heard of them before. They make headphones, they
Speaker 3:  weights headphones. LeBron James wears them, made a bunch of iPhone 16 cases.
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  Beats,
Speaker 3:  Beats made iPhone 16 cases. It
Speaker 5:  Feels like a real, it feels like they've been trying to figure out where
Speaker 5:  Beats sits in their lineup, especially as AirPods get better. And their idea
Speaker 5:  is what if Beats is budget? You do cases now.
Speaker 3:  Oh, interesting. Do you, do you think that's where is going My interesting.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause 'cause you they, they, they, they are putting the good tech
Speaker 5:  in their headphones, but the headphones just also aren't
Speaker 5:  don't have that, that kind of ca cash that, that quality feeling. Right.
Speaker 3:  I just feel like my read on it was that Apple was just like, let Beats be
Speaker 3:  Beats. I just wanna say to everybody listening to this, by the way, NELI
Speaker 3:  is furiously Googling because he doesn't believe me that I got this right.
Speaker 3:  Which is how wild it is that Beats is making iPhone 16 cases.
Speaker 2:  I'm just like reading this news.
Speaker 3:  Neli Neli had to fact check me on The. Vergecast. Yeah. Because he didn't
Speaker 3:  believe me that Beats was making iPhone 16 cases. This is, this is all you
Speaker 3:  need to know about this story. They're $49. They exist.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 3:  It. They are cases. They're cases. They look like the Apple cases, but they're
Speaker 3:  by Beats for some reason. They're so, don't
Speaker 2:  Get it. They're so weird.
Speaker 5:  It's so weird.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's very, it's very strange. I
Speaker 2:  Was instructed if I had nothing to say, to say nothing.
Speaker 3:  This is, no, this is great. I'm into it. Perfect. Moving on.
Speaker 3:  Bunch of new watch bands, bunch of new band colors. Can I interest you in
Speaker 3:  in that?
Speaker 5:  Get one on Etsy, it'll be a quarter of the price.
Speaker 2:  Or buy the Burg's own Nomad Blurple band, which is a big hit at Apple Park
Speaker 2:  today.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Oh yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Love that. Many, many compliments.
Speaker 5:  It looks great.
Speaker 3:  I bought that one, which is very good. And I also bought six
Speaker 3:  Apple Watch bands on Amazon for like eight bucks.
Speaker 3:  Loving bits. Can't recommend it highly.
Speaker 2:  Those ones are slowly poisoning. David. And you should buy the Verges Blurple
Speaker 2:  sport band.
Speaker 3:  I do occasionally look at my wrist just to make sure it's not like turning
Speaker 3:  a color. I'm not psyched about Yeah, so far so good. But, but
Speaker 3:  we're, okay. The biggest question I have about accessories Neli is
Speaker 3:  how the camera control is gonna work with cases. This is a question a lot
Speaker 3:  of people are asking. It's this, it's this capacitive kind of flush
Speaker 3:  control, which seems like If you have any kind of raised case at all
Speaker 3:  is gonna be hard to find a way to get your finger inside of.
Speaker 3:  Do you have a sense of how this might work?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, although I think my worry is different than anyone else's worry
Speaker 2:  that can you make a capacitive button on a case connect to
Speaker 2:  a capacitive button on the phone. It's like pretty well and solved, right?
Speaker 2:  They just have to be conductive to each other. Sure. And so Apple's own cases
Speaker 2:  have a button that touches the other button and you're good. If there's
Speaker 2:  any play at all, if there's any space between the two
Speaker 2:  buttons, then that like push a little bit is gonna get weird
Speaker 2:  in that I haven't seen this thing in a case yet, but already it's like
Speaker 2:  to push it, to do the light tap, to bring up the, the various menus
Speaker 2:  or controls is already like, you have to think about how hard you're pushing
Speaker 2:  so you don't accidentally push the button. And so If you have a little play
Speaker 2:  and then you have to push like If you have a cheap case or a bad case that
Speaker 2:  might get weird remains to be seen.
Speaker 5:  That's why Beats is leading the way with how
Speaker 3:  Hard design. I don't beat has it covered?
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 3:  Got Jimmy Iovine has it covered. Don't worry.
Speaker 2:  Do you think Jimmy Iovine's like ever just like looks in the direction of
Speaker 2:  Apple Park? He's like, man I really pulled one over.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he's
Speaker 3:  Make all these almost funny and we still make headphones.
Speaker 2:  There's a, there was a brief, a real period a real thing that happened. Is
Speaker 2:  it Jimmy Iovine, Dr. Dre and Trent Resner were Apple employees and they had
Speaker 2:  no titles except for Jimmy and Dre.
Speaker 3:  Is that true though? That was their title. That
Speaker 2:  Was their title. Jimmy and Dre. That
Speaker 3:  Was the title. Well that's my name. Yeah. Was was Dre Jimmy and Jimmy was
Speaker 3:  Dre. That's the, that's what I want.
Speaker 2:  It'd be great if Apple is like another person gets the title of Dre when
Speaker 2:  Dre left
Speaker 1:  Ary. You
Speaker 3:  Gotta Dre.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  There's some like brand new engineers like you're Dre now. Like
Speaker 2:  have fun
Speaker 5:  Just putting all those weights into a product to make it feel better.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Alright. We have gone way over. We all
Speaker 3:  need to go to sleep and Neli needs to go figure out how to move this lamp.
Speaker 3:  Neli. Any, any parting thoughts for us? Anything we missed? Keep the lamp.
Speaker 3:  Any big feelings about the, the Apple stuff today before we get outta here?
Speaker 2:  I'm very curious to see how people want us to, to evaluate these products,
Speaker 2:  right? Like I, I don't, I don't disagree with the sense that this was kind
Speaker 2:  of a, a small event in its way. I wonder if the
Speaker 2:  products will feel bigger with the Apple intelligence features. So let me
Speaker 2:  know how you want us to, to talk about these. 'cause I suspect the answer
Speaker 2:  is
Speaker 3:  that's like more than just my phone is dying,
Speaker 3:  I need a new one. I'll buy the new one. But is like, is this worth the upgrade?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I, I wanna know all your questions about is this worth the upgrade?
Speaker 3:  So You can email Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline eight six six
Speaker 3:  VERGE one one. We have I would say a bunch more Apple stuff to do
Speaker 3:  over the next couple of weeks. So we'll, we'll have lots of time to talk
Speaker 3:  about this. Send us all of your questions for now. That is it. That's The
Speaker 3:  Vergecast Rock
Speaker 2:  And roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.