# Transcript
ID: ef54bdfe-4e49-416a-b019-172951bbc9cb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5004181698466539995/5625628835471527064/s93290-US-4687s-1719186450.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of super helpful humanoid helper robots:
05:07 - The Verge’s David Pierce and Andy Hawkins discuss the latest at Tesla: new products, new initiatives, and a payday for Elon Musk.
Tesla’s 2024 shareholder meeting: all the news about Elon Musk’s $50 billion payday
Let’s speculate wildly about Tesla’s three mystery vehicles
Tesla shareholders approve Elon Musk’s massive pay package — was there ever any doubt?
Whatever Elon wants, Tesla gets
40:21 - Vee Song joins the show to discuss updates to the Apple Watch, a new Samsung Galaxy Watch, and more wearable news.
Finally, the Apple Watch will let you rest - The Verge
Samsung’s Galaxy Watch FE is its new entry-level smartwatch - The Verge
The Pixel Watch 2 can now detect when you’ve been in a car crash
Apple announces watchOS 11 with new training features and Live Activities
Samsung sues Oura preemptively to block smart ring patent claims
1:02:54 - David and Liam James answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline about weather apps.
Forecast Advisor
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (36 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of super helpful humanoid
Speaker 1:  helper robots. I'm your friend, David Pierce and I am sitting
Speaker 1:  here buying bathroom vanities. So. my wife and
Speaker 1:  I, were having some work done in our house, partly to just like
Speaker 1:  make our bathrooms nicer, but also because one of them is starting to
Speaker 1:  leak. And if you're watching this on YouTube, just outta frame up
Speaker 1:  there is just a growing stain. And. those are the
Speaker 1:  things that start to happen. And, I. just see all of the money that I have
Speaker 1:  in the world start to disappear. So. anyway, we've been starting to do
Speaker 1:  some work on renovating our bathroom, making some changes, and I have
Speaker 1:  discovered that shopping for bathroom vanities is everything that is
Speaker 1:  wrong with online shopping. You go to the one of these websites, Wayfair
Speaker 1:  or Lowe s or Home Depot or Amazon or Pottery Barn or Creighton Barrel.
Speaker 1:  And it's just all the same stuff with different
Speaker 1:  prices. You have to become like a subject matter expertise I now know the
Speaker 1:  difference between solid wood and all the different types of manufactured
Speaker 1:  wood and MDF, which is bad, but only in humid spaces. Like why do I
Speaker 1:  know these things? This is not information I'm interested in knowing. But
Speaker 1:  there isn't really just a place You can go online that's like, here are the
Speaker 1:  good vanities. This is like the endless challenge of shopping on the
Speaker 1:  internet. You can't really trust the reviews because everybody has these
Speaker 1:  paid for review programs. Some of the pictures you see are helpful, some
Speaker 1:  aren't. Some of the one star reviews are just about like weird things that
Speaker 1:  were happening in their house the day that things got delivered. It's just
Speaker 1:  a mess. And so what I've ended up doing for these very expensive pieces
Speaker 1:  of furniture is basically just going online, finding one
Speaker 1:  that looks good, and then Google lensing it. Because what you discover is
Speaker 1:  actually most of these places are just selling the same thing. Much of it
Speaker 1:  comes from China or other countries in Asia where they're just
Speaker 1:  being shipped outta factories. And all these companies sell the same thing
Speaker 1:  under different names often for very different prices. So I find one
Speaker 1:  that I like, I Google lens it, and then I hope to God that there
Speaker 1:  is a set of reviews or helpful pictures or an expert in the field who
Speaker 1:  has talked about this somewhere. And then you go on Reddit to see, because
Speaker 1:  Reddit is the best place to get actual information about things. And everyone
Speaker 1:  on Reddit is just like, go to a local cabinet maker, get this
Speaker 1:  stuff custom made. Do not trust the internet. It's good advice. Honestly,
Speaker 1:  it's probably the correct advice for many things, not just bathroom vanities,
Speaker 1:  but the people are coming tomorrow to start putting new things in my bathroom
Speaker 1:  and I don't have time. So I am fully, fully at
Speaker 1:  the mercy of the internet right now and it's terrifying. Anyway, that's not
Speaker 1:  what we're talking about today. We have a super fun show coming up. We're
Speaker 1:  gonna do two things. First, we're gonna talk about Tesla, because Tesla
Speaker 1:  last week had this big shareholder meeting, approved a huge payday for
Speaker 1:  Elon Musk, but also gave a hint to what the next phase of Tesla
Speaker 1:  is gonna be like. Some new products, some new initiatives at the company.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna bring Andy Hawkins on and talk about all of it, and hopefully
Speaker 1:  only a little about Elon Musk. After that, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 1:  wearables. We have a new app that people are really excited about for
Speaker 1:  tracking your steps and all that stuff. We have a new Apple Watch feature
Speaker 1:  that people are excited about. We have a new Samsung watch that people are
Speaker 1:  excited about. It's just a bunch of interesting, cool kind of fitness
Speaker 1:  and health stuff. And V Song from The Verge and I have been talking a lot
Speaker 1:  about finding more relaxed
Speaker 1:  chill ways to do wearables and fitness instead of the like
Speaker 1:  hyper intense capital F fitness people. How can I just have
Speaker 1:  a wearable that helps without yelling at me about it? So we're gonna do the
Speaker 1:  first part of a little bit of that today and more to come this summer.
Speaker 1:  We also have a hotline question about whether that I'm very excited to talk
Speaker 1:  about and lots more besides all that is coming up in just a sec. But
Speaker 1:  first, I have 65 Lowe's tabs open that all look
Speaker 1:  essentially the same to me, and I have to go figure out which one I'm supposed
Speaker 1:  to buy. Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  shareholder vote because he won, it was, he kind of laid out what he
Speaker 1:  sees as the future for Tesla. He talked about the optimist robots. He talked
Speaker 1:  about wanting to be a data setter company. He talked about full self-driving.
Speaker 1:  He talked about superchargers, they talked about new vehicles. And I just
Speaker 1:  think Tesla is at a really interesting moment right now, and it felt like
Speaker 1:  a good time to talk about it. This company has been so important for so long
Speaker 1:  to the electric vehicle industry, to the whole tech industry, to the
Speaker 1:  world. And this felt like a good moment to kind of check in on where
Speaker 1:  Tesla the company is and where it's headed. And of course,
Speaker 1:  Andy Hawkins is the person to do it with. Andy, welcome back to the show.
Speaker 8:  Hey. Hello. Thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  It's been a minute. There's like just an onslaught of car stuff and
Speaker 1:  I feel like someday we're gonna have to catch up on all of the car stuff,
Speaker 1:  but today it's Tesla
Speaker 8:  Time. I'm here for it.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so I, I have two rules for you upfront and then, and then
Speaker 1:  we're gonna dive in. Rule number one is I'm going to ask you a question about
Speaker 1:  Elon Musk at the beginning, and I'm gonna ask you a question about Elon Musk
Speaker 1:  at the end. And in between we are going to talk about Elon Musk as little
Speaker 1:  as possible. Is that fair?
Speaker 8:  I that sounds more than fair, honestly.
Speaker 1:  Okay, good. And rule number two is less a rule and more of
Speaker 1:  a caveat. And I'm, I'm going to make the caveat that I have and I want you
Speaker 1:  to add or subtract to it as you would like to. Okay. We're about to talk
Speaker 1:  a bunch about plans for Tesla and the company that Tesla plans to be.
Speaker 1:  Elon Musk in particular is known for hyperbole, makes a lot of
Speaker 1:  promises that don't always come true or don't always come true in the timeline.
Speaker 1:  He has what I would call acute shiny object syndrome. And yet
Speaker 1:  I still think all of this is worth digging into and talking about. Is that
Speaker 1:  a fair caveat? Anything you would add or subtract?
Speaker 8:  No, I think that that all sounds more than accurate. I accept your caveat.
Speaker 1:  Good. All right, then beginning Elon Musk question really quick. There was
Speaker 1:  this big shareholder vote last week. This has been really like in some ways,
Speaker 1:  like six years in the making. Just give me the very quick story
Speaker 1:  as to why Tesla shareholders voted again to give Elon Musk
Speaker 1:  many tens of billions of dollars.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so they voted the first time to give him this amount of money
Speaker 8:  or to promise to give him this amount of money back in 2018
Speaker 8:  with, and I'll, I'll use it again. The caveat being that he had to meet certain
Speaker 8:  thresholds in order to actually see the, the, the full amount of the
Speaker 8:  pay package that was approved for him. And he did, he met,
Speaker 8:  met those conditions. Tesla's value exceeded
Speaker 8:  wild leaps and bounds, and everyone's possible imagine of what Tesla could
Speaker 8:  actually be valid. It exceeded in that it was the most valuable car maker
Speaker 8:  in the world by 2021. And he was able to meet
Speaker 8:  these thresholds and his pay package w was vested. Then at the
Speaker 8:  beginning of this year, a lawsuit that had been winding its way through the
Speaker 8:  courts from a Tesla shareholder, this guy Richard Todo,
Speaker 8:  who I believe is also a heavy metal drummer. Amazing. And he only owns amazing,
Speaker 8:  like a handful of shares, which is a kind of a fascinating aspect of all
Speaker 8:  of this. Sued the company and Elon Musk saying that this process
Speaker 8:  was flawed. He should not have been awarded this amount of money and it should
Speaker 8:  get tossed out. A judge in Delaware where Tesla is incorporated,
Speaker 8:  agreed and avoided his pay package in January of
Speaker 8:  2024 that made Elon Musk very upset. And when
Speaker 8:  Elon Musk gets upset, his legion of fans, lots, lots of them
Speaker 8:  who are whom are shareholders also got very upset and they decided
Speaker 8:  to just do the process over again. So for the last several months,
Speaker 8:  they've been, Tesla has been engaged in a pretty aggressive
Speaker 8:  lobbying effort to get its shareholders to once again approve
Speaker 8:  this, this massive pay package, which is upwards of $56 billion,
Speaker 8:  has been said to, to be worth, which would make him the most highly compensated
Speaker 8:  chief executive in modern history. So they went to the shareholders
Speaker 8:  again, said, let's, let's vote for this once more time. Let's show this judge
Speaker 8:  that when we said that we wanted him to get this money, we actually meant
Speaker 8:  it. And lo and behold, Tesla shareholders voted
Speaker 8:  overwhelmingly to award Elon Musk his pay package once again.
Speaker 8:  And that's where we're at. Okay.
Speaker 1:  This is why I think this is actually a good moment to talk about Tesla because
Speaker 1:  there was a moment in the speech that Elon Musk gave after
Speaker 1:  the shareholder vote ended, where I think what he said was, this isn't a
Speaker 1:  new page for Tesla, it's a new book or something. Something like that. I'm
Speaker 1:  paraphrasing. Yeah, that's correct. Okay. And, and then I would say he, he
Speaker 1:  proceeded to say, kind of lay out what he believes the future
Speaker 1:  of Tesla to be. And I just wanna kind of run through a handful of them and,
Speaker 1:  and kind of take your temperature on what you think about all of these big
Speaker 1:  ideas as they pertain to kind of where Tesla is, is going from here. Sure.
Speaker 1:  And I feel like the first place we have to start is with the, the optimist
Speaker 1:  robots. Right. I feel like if you were gonna pick a thing, oh, he would
Speaker 8:  Like you to start there. So I'm sure he'd be very glad that you're starting.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Well, so that, that's actually one of the things I'm most curious about.
Speaker 1:  Is it, it didn't, it didn't feel like cars were the big story. It
Speaker 1:  didn't feel like energy was the big story. It felt like robots was the big
Speaker 1:  story. Why, why robots? How did this become kind of the shiniest thing
Speaker 1:  at Tesla?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so, you know, for years Elon and Tesla have been interested in
Speaker 8:  ai. They have been trying to produce a self-driving car for
Speaker 8:  many, many years now. And Musk has been making numerous
Speaker 8:  grandiose promises about how Tesla's future is actually in
Speaker 8:  autonomy in robotics. And, you know, it's become sort of, you know, kind
Speaker 8:  of like a, a bit of a, an inside joke almost. That, you know, he
Speaker 8:  makes these promises that there's gonna be millions of self-driving vehicles
Speaker 8:  on the road by certain dates. Those dates come and go. Lo and behold, there
Speaker 8:  are no self-driving Teslas that have taken over the road. But we do have
Speaker 8:  is, you know, a series of driver assist products. First there was autopilot,
Speaker 8:  then there was full self-driving. The drivers very much still need to take
Speaker 8:  control, you know, pay attention to their, to the driving tasks. They cannot
Speaker 8:  fall asleep or allow the, the car to drive itself without their
Speaker 8:  attention. So it, it, it seems like there's still a ways to go
Speaker 8:  still before we actually get to this point where Tesla has achieved
Speaker 8:  and solved for autonomy like some other companies have made a lot more progress
Speaker 8:  with. But that said, you know, I think the moment that we really saw this
Speaker 8:  become sort of more than just kind of like a side project of Tesla,
Speaker 8:  but become sort of the core purpose and ethos of the entire
Speaker 8:  company, and obviously of sort of the way that Musk markets the company was
Speaker 8:  around the time that I think OpenAI emerged with chat GBT.
Speaker 8:  And then we started to see sort of the, the spread of AI fever and
Speaker 8:  this become sort of very, very clear a hype cycle that were in the midst
Speaker 8:  of at the moment. and it was clear that the, the things that investors
Speaker 8:  in Wall Street formerly rewarded Tesla for, which was for
Speaker 8:  it being on the vanguard of electrification and sort of changing
Speaker 8:  the way that people think about personally owned vehicles, that was
Speaker 8:  somehow not as exciting anymore. I mean, Tesla was still worth a lot of money,
Speaker 8:  but it was suddenly people were starting, starting to pay more attention
Speaker 8:  to the robotics and the autonomy aspects of the company. And I think Tesla
Speaker 8:  and Elon especially really leaned into that and are now trying
Speaker 8:  to sort of shift the definition of what Tesla is away from being just a
Speaker 8:  car maker to one that is focused primarily on AI and robotics. And that
Speaker 8:  really came out, I think, very strongly during the last earnings call, which
Speaker 8:  w what Elon said, and I'm paraphrasing that if you don't understand that
Speaker 8:  this is what Tesla's all about, that we're an AI company and that we're gonna
Speaker 8:  solve for autonomy, then you just don't understand the Tesla story.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. So the thesis somewhat makes sense to me there, right? That
Speaker 1:  if you, if you solve in the same way that energy inside of cars
Speaker 1:  ultimately lets you solve much bigger, wider sorts of energy problems,
Speaker 1:  solving autonomy inside of cars lets you solve other bigger, more
Speaker 1:  interesting problems. And this is like, this is the version of the world
Speaker 1:  and future that Tesla has always talked about. And again, execution is another
Speaker 1:  thing, but like that version of how to think about what a car can
Speaker 1:  then expand out into sort of makes sense to me, right? That
Speaker 1:  like, again, leaving aside whether it is possible for Tesla or anyone else
Speaker 1:  to build a self-driving car, if You can, it puts you way down the road of
Speaker 1:  solving a bunch of other really interesting problems. This
Speaker 8:  Is sort of fundamentally, I think what Tesla is trying to say
Speaker 8:  into how it Musk is sort of trying to talk about the company, but I think
Speaker 8:  what it belies is that, you know, kind of like something that he maybe would
Speaker 8:  not admit to and what a lot of people inside the company or it, the fans
Speaker 8:  of the company would not really admit to, which is that he's just fundamentally
Speaker 8:  bored with running a car company. Yes. That the car, the car company aspect
Speaker 8:  of this has just become kind of, and, and you said it yourself talking about
Speaker 8:  his like shiny, shiny object syndrome. The car company is not a shiny object
Speaker 8:  anymore. It's not, it, it doesn't hold his interest. And this was so much
Speaker 8:  a part of the lobbying effort in the run up to the shareholder vote coming
Speaker 8:  from the chair of the, of Tesla's board, Robin Denholm on down,
Speaker 8:  talking about how we needed to award Musk this enormous
Speaker 8:  sum of money because we need to hold his attention. Hmm. He has all of these
Speaker 8:  projects, he's got his irons in, in multiple fires,
Speaker 8:  whether it's obviously with X, formerly Twitter,
Speaker 8:  Neuralink, the boring company, SpaceX obviously being the,
Speaker 8:  the granddaddy of them all. And Tesla is just not like keep keeping his
Speaker 8:  attention the same way that it used to. So in order for him
Speaker 8:  to fully devote himself and, and usher Tesla into this
Speaker 8:  next chapter or this next book as he likes to put it, you know, we need to
Speaker 8:  cut him this gigantic check because that's gonna be the way
Speaker 8:  that's going to keep him sort of locked down and focused on what's gonna
Speaker 8:  make Tesla the most successful company. So I, I think that there's an aspect
Speaker 8:  of this like they're trying to solve for, for certain problems that they
Speaker 8:  think autonomy and robotics are gonna help them solve, whether it's around
Speaker 8:  labor or around sort of like the safety around
Speaker 8:  ai. But I think fundamentally really just comes down to like, this dude is
Speaker 8:  spread way too thin and they needed to keep him more consolidated and focused
Speaker 8:  on, on the task at hand.
Speaker 1:  Right. And obviously what shinier cooler thing
Speaker 1:  to think about, both for investors who care a lot about the
Speaker 1:  stock price and for Elon Musk as an executive and just for like the people
Speaker 1:  who follow Tesla than humanoid robots that follow you around your house,
Speaker 1:  right? Like, I can't imagine a thing in this moment of this crazy
Speaker 1:  AI hype cycle that will get more attention from more
Speaker 1:  people than we're gonna build a robot. Like
Speaker 1:  screw your her thing that's on your phone, like, we're gonna build a fricking
Speaker 1:  robot in your house. Like Tesla's thing is to take these things to like the
Speaker 1:  nth degree. Like that feels very in keeping with how this company operates
Speaker 1:  to me.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it 100%. and it was like the musk of the past
Speaker 8:  was coming in, poking his head out a little bit during this, this shareholder
Speaker 8:  meeting where he came out, he did his victory lap, he told everyone how much
Speaker 8:  he loved them and then he just started speaking incredibly hyperbolically
Speaker 8:  about, about how optimists and the, and the humanoid robots and how Tesla
Speaker 8:  was going to have potentially hundreds of robots working in his factory
Speaker 8:  by the end of next year, I think he said. And then he made some comment about
Speaker 8:  how Tesla was ultimately, or the, the robotics industry. I don't, I can't
Speaker 8:  remember if it was exactly Tesla or robotics, but I'm sure he was seeing
Speaker 8:  them as sort of, sort of mutually the same was gonna be worth
Speaker 8:  $25 trillion someday. Which like You can say what
Speaker 8:  you will about Musk in his hyperbolic statements and how he hypes things
Speaker 8:  too much and just sort of goes over the top in describing things. Millions
Speaker 8:  of electric cars solving for autonomy. AI robots, a
Speaker 8:  $25 trillion company is just not nothing that we've ever seen, nor do I
Speaker 8:  think we will see in the history of, of like corporate America
Speaker 8:  or just, you know, the history of, of capitalism. It's just not something
Speaker 8:  that I think a lot of people even think is fundamentally possible.
Speaker 8:  But that said, that's, that was like fully like the, the vibe that he was
Speaker 8:  trying to put out. I think with, with all of
Speaker 1:  This. That makes sense. You have aggressively broken our no Elon Musk rule.
Speaker 1:  I'm very sorry, which means we have to move on. It's very hard to do. And
Speaker 1:  this is like this, this is the strangest thing about this company right now.
Speaker 1:  And we're this, this comes to my Elon Musk question at the end, but let's,
Speaker 1:  let's get back to some car company stuff. Yes, let's do it. Because Tesla
Speaker 1:  is still a car company no matter how it wants to talk about itself. There
Speaker 1:  were three shrouded vehicles up from two shrouded vehicles that we've seen
Speaker 1:  before. They put up the slide. Elon I believe said we have some stuff in
Speaker 1:  the pipeline. You speculated wildly about what these three vehicles
Speaker 1:  might be. Gimme the quick rundown. What do we, what do we think is, is literally
Speaker 1:  under the hood that we're gonna see from Tesla in the near future? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So it was interesting to me because it was one more mystery vehicle than
Speaker 8:  we got last year, which is when they had their investor day and they talked
Speaker 8:  a lot about like the third master plan and about how they were going to use
Speaker 8:  all the sustainable energy in order to shift the world over to a more
Speaker 8:  sustainable energy future. And at that time, you know, the, the criticism
Speaker 8:  against Tesla was that, oh, okay, they're talking high, high-minded about
Speaker 8:  all these things that they want to do. They're losing focus. There's no new
Speaker 8:  car announcement. There was nothing for people to really sink their teeth
Speaker 8:  into except for a lot of these kind of like grandiose statements about
Speaker 8:  what the future of energy was gonna be. Right. There
Speaker 1:  Really hasn't been anything since the cyber truck, right. In terms of like
Speaker 1:  concrete. And that's a long time. If
Speaker 8:  Anything, they've been all over the map. There's been reports about canceling
Speaker 8:  plans for, for a cheap model two type
Speaker 8:  $25,000 ev and then they are back onto it.
Speaker 8:  And it's, it's unclear exactly where there's, where they stand on sort of
Speaker 8:  like what the lineup, the vehicle lineup of the future is going to be. 'cause
Speaker 8:  I, I think because the cyber truck kind of sucked all the oxygen
Speaker 8:  outta the room, it was an enormously difficult task to build up a production
Speaker 8:  sort of scheme around that truck because of how difficult it was to make.
Speaker 8:  And that kind of just, and and obviously too, the company that, you know,
Speaker 8:  a couple months ago went through a huge layoff period where they, you know,
Speaker 8:  they laid off over 10%, maybe even up to 20% of the
Speaker 8:  company was laid off. And now they're actually hiring a lot of those people
Speaker 8:  back because they realize they fired too many of them, which is not the first
Speaker 8:  time that that's happened with Tesla But anyway. So yeah, there was an, an
Speaker 8:  additional mystery vehicle under, under a shroud that they, that they hinted
Speaker 8:  at during this shareholder meeting, two of which looked like had this shape
Speaker 8:  of just regular Teslas. They looked kind of like model threes, you know,
Speaker 8:  something that we can take from that we could say, okay, is is one of those,
Speaker 8:  the model two is one of those the cheaper, smaller, more affordable
Speaker 8:  electric car that they have said that they were gonna make and then said
Speaker 8:  that they weren't. And you know, sort of been flip-flopping and backtracking
Speaker 8:  going all over the place as to whether or not they actually have plans to
Speaker 8:  make this vehicle. Is the other one of those is that maybe the refreshed
Speaker 8:  roadster that we were first promised, I think back in like 2019
Speaker 8:  when they had the event announcing the Tesla semi truck and then
Speaker 8:  the Roadster was sort of like brought out and saying, well, we're gonna read,
Speaker 8:  we're gonna do the Roadster, the original vehicle that, that, you know, launched
Speaker 8:  Tesla.
Speaker 1:  I honestly forgot about that. Like if you, if you had asked me just now is
Speaker 1:  there another Roadster, I would've said no, that was like the first I honestly
Speaker 1:  forgot. And didn't they collect like huge deposits from people for that
Speaker 8:  Too? Yeah, they've, they've taken a ton of deposits definitely over, you
Speaker 8:  know, several millions of dollars worth. But yeah, that doesn't appear to
Speaker 8:  be any closer to production. We, we have not gotten many
Speaker 8:  words. I think he's tweeted a a few times about sort of what the progress
Speaker 8:  is. There's been lots of claims about using like, you know, SpaceX style
Speaker 8:  rockets to make this like the, you know, a a sure. A vehicle that can reach
Speaker 8:  zero to 60 in under two seconds or maybe even a, a mi a second and a half.
Speaker 8:  It's, you know, we're, we're bending the laws of physics. Yeah, it's, it's,
Speaker 8:  it's gonna be a fun time. So one of those vehicles could be that Roadster
Speaker 8:  and then there was a third mystery vehicle which was more boxy shaped, a
Speaker 8:  little bit taller, higher writing, maybe even Vanta shaped. So there was
Speaker 8:  some speculation that this could be a Vanta or at least a, a more
Speaker 8:  sort of high capacity vehicle. This could be the robo taxii that, that Tesla
Speaker 8:  has been talking a lot about. I
Speaker 1:  Was just about to say, do you really think Tesla is gonna make a minivan?
Speaker 1:  I, I think, but in the taxi version of the world that makes more sense to
Speaker 1:  you if they're gonna
Speaker 8:  Make some sort of purpose-built autonomous vehicle, the conventional
Speaker 8:  wisdom is that it needs to be something that is kind of Vanta shaped, that
Speaker 8:  You can fit a lot of people into it. You can, it could maybe be something
Speaker 8:  where there could be some carpooling aspect of it or some ride sharing. So
Speaker 8:  it does seem to be that maybe Tesla is interested in that or is interested
Speaker 8:  in some sort of Vanta type format for its technology. So those
Speaker 8:  were sort of the guesses that I, I've seen and and others have, have
Speaker 8:  talked about is in terms of like what Tesla's future vehicle lineup might
Speaker 8:  look like. Okay.
Speaker 1:  The Robotaxis is supposed to come like this summer, right?
Speaker 8:  Soon. Yeah, August 8th. He said, okay, is gonna be the event for
Speaker 8:  that. I feel
Speaker 1:  Like it's probably then a fairly safe bet to say
Speaker 1:  one of those three is gonna be the robot taxii.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think that that's correct. Okay. And he's, you know, they've been
Speaker 8:  hyping that a lot in a lot of their communications. There have been talks
Speaker 8:  about how it's gonna be somewhat similar design wise to the cyber trucks.
Speaker 8:  So we were gonna see maybe a lot of angularity, something more triangular
Speaker 8:  shaped, perhaps probably not stainless steel, but you know, you never
Speaker 8:  know with this company. But yeah, it's, this is gonna be sort of like what
Speaker 8:  we've all been building towards, right? We've had these driver assist products,
Speaker 8:  we've seen how they behaved out in public. You've got a lot of people, Tesla
Speaker 8:  owners who are big fans of full self driving and autopilot. They think it's
Speaker 8:  great. It takes a lot of the pressure off of driving that. It works fantastically.
Speaker 8:  And then there's just a, a ton of evidence that shows that it's just not
Speaker 8:  what it's built up to be. Right. That it has serious gaps. There's been
Speaker 8:  some studies to show that it can't execute certain maneuvers. There've been
Speaker 8:  hundreds of crashes, dozens of fatalities involving drivers
Speaker 8:  using autopilot. And then there's concerns about how people might be overusing
Speaker 8:  these products more reliant in them than they should. And obviously due to
Speaker 8:  the fact that Tesla markets it in a way that probably leaves a lot of confusion
Speaker 8:  to people,
Speaker 1:  It is called full self-driving after all. Yes, that is, it's, it's hard to
Speaker 1:  not read that the way that it sounds.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I know. It's like, you know, why can't I take my eyes off the road?
Speaker 8:  Why can't I fall asleep? Why can't I climb into the back the backseat and
Speaker 8:  and allow the car to drive me from from that way? Well, because, you know,
Speaker 8:  there are plenty of of warnings that pop up on your screen to say to never
Speaker 8:  do those things. So yeah, it's a, the way that Tesla markets these products
Speaker 8:  and the reality of them are constantly in conflict and
Speaker 8:  we're starting to see some court cases move their way through the system.
Speaker 8:  Some regulators in California, the DMV, the Attorney General,
Speaker 8:  the Department of Justice are, are all investigating Tesla as part,
Speaker 8:  maybe perhaps part of a, a, a criminal investigation to show that they have
Speaker 8:  willfully misguided people in terms of how they've marketed the these
Speaker 8:  this technology.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay. Which makes the robax thing even higher
Speaker 1:  stakes in a bunch of ways.
Speaker 8:  I would say fraught. Fraught is the word
Speaker 1:  Fraught. Iss a good word for it. There you go. Well, and speaking of around
Speaker 1:  that, I think if you assume the robo taxii thing is real and coming
Speaker 1:  this summer, it makes a bunch of the other things that Tesla and Elon Musk
Speaker 1:  are talking about all the more important, right? He mentioned the Tesla network,
Speaker 1:  which is the, the this idea that we've been hearing about for forever, that
Speaker 1:  You can just get out of your car when you get to work and then your car can
Speaker 1:  go be a taxii all day and then come back the supercharger network, which
Speaker 1:  I think we, we've heard a lot of conflicting things about in recent months.
Speaker 1:  The whole theory of like AWS for AI
Speaker 1:  that Tesla is trying to be
Speaker 8:  Oh, that's a good one. This
Speaker 1:  Idea of this like big broad network of Teslas and what that can be
Speaker 1:  in the world feels like it's about to get tested in a pretty
Speaker 1:  real way after a lot of talk over the last few years.
Speaker 1:  And obviously autopilot and self-driving is part of that because like the
Speaker 1:  first part of Robo Taxii means there's not a person, this is not an Uber
Speaker 1:  for Tesla thing, this is a very different thing Tesla is trying to go for
Speaker 1:  and like it feels like that's coming to a head here
Speaker 1:  pretty fast, you know?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean it just sort of goes back to this, this idea that i, I put forward,
Speaker 8:  which is that, you know, they're trying to explore many ways in
Speaker 8:  which they can continue to hype Tesla and to
Speaker 8:  justify the valuation that's, that it's received over the years in ways
Speaker 8:  that don't sort of expose kind of like the fundamental
Speaker 8:  reality of what the company is, which is that it's a car company, but when
Speaker 8:  as soon as you put Tesla alongside of its fellow peers
Speaker 8:  in the auto industry alongside, I don't know, Ford and
Speaker 8:  gm, Chevy Buick, Audi Mercedes, it kind of loses its
Speaker 8:  luster in a lot of ways because we, we know about car companies, we've seen
Speaker 8:  them for decades and decades, you know, over a century now we've had
Speaker 8:  car companies and there's just nothing that, that, the story really
Speaker 8:  doesn't lend itself so well to that kind of like excitement that has
Speaker 8:  surrounded Tesla but also must himself as someone who is like a futurist
Speaker 8:  and is gonna help usher in kind of like this more, this better future that
Speaker 8:  we have planned for us. But, you know, I think it's just really kind of like
Speaker 8:  this tension and I think that that's why he's talking about things like robotic
Speaker 8:  and ai, but even like the AWS stuff, I mean, that's just him
Speaker 8:  spitballing. And I've spoken to a number of, of experts that have said, you
Speaker 8:  know, that that's like the fact that Tesla vehicles are cars
Speaker 8:  that they move around and are go from place to place and it
Speaker 8:  don't have like a fixed location necessarily. It's kind of, you know, sort
Speaker 8:  of undermines the idea of using it as some sort of like distributed
Speaker 8:  network from which to, you know, get like, you know, more bang for your
Speaker 8:  buck in terms of like what an actual electric car can be used for. Which
Speaker 8:  I think, you know, sort of ignores some of the, the real potential be
Speaker 8:  behind EVs, which I think a lot of the other car makers have kind of seized
Speaker 8:  upon, which is things like virtual power plants and sending energy back
Speaker 8:  into the grid or using your EV as sort of like a mobile power
Speaker 8:  generator that can help you out in the midst. You know, if there's a blackout,
Speaker 8:  you know, we're having, there's a heat wave on the east coast this week,
Speaker 8:  there's gonna be heat waves, you know, as part of our future fundamentally
Speaker 8:  like, you know, we'd have to really kind of get, get used to that and EVs
Speaker 8:  could be a real good way to help make sure that people don't, who do lose
Speaker 8:  power, don't use, lose the things that they really need the most, you know,
Speaker 8:  refrigeration and AC and things like that during these times. So, you know,
Speaker 8:  there's a lot of things that e EVs can be used for that that beyond just
Speaker 8:  like driving from from A to B and it doesn't seem like he really has, or
Speaker 8:  the company really has much interest in those things.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that makes sense. So to that point actually, my impression of Tesla
Speaker 1:  for years has been that it was very
Speaker 1:  early to a lot of things and was right about a lot of where things
Speaker 1:  were going beforehand, even leaving all of the good and bad of Elon Musk
Speaker 1:  aside, like Tesla was right about the future pretty early on and
Speaker 1:  correctly bet on a bunch of things including electric vehicles. The
Speaker 1:  story around Tesla the last few years seems to be that it has given
Speaker 1:  up a lot of that lead as a car company, right? And, and that it's the sort
Speaker 1:  of moat that it built for itself has like withered and
Speaker 1:  dried up, I guess to just like destroy that metaphor. Is that fair? Like,
Speaker 1:  is the, what is Tesla's moat as a car company at this point? And, and again,
Speaker 1:  the answer is not allowed to be Elon Musk because we're gonna come back to
Speaker 1:  that, but as a, as a pure like technology and car company,
Speaker 1:  does it have some of that moat and advantage still? Or has it,
Speaker 1:  has the landscape around it just changed? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I think it's, it's kind of a complicated answer because I think in some aspects
Speaker 8:  it does because I think we've seen, you know, the thing that was most often
Speaker 8:  described as Tesla's moat was its supercharger network, right? That it made
Speaker 8:  these cars that people wanted, you know, they were expensive and they were
Speaker 8:  futuristic looking, but it, none of that would've worked if there was not
Speaker 8:  the infrastructure, the charging infrastructure to support the ownership
Speaker 8:  of those vehicles. And so Tesla very smartly realized that it needed to,
Speaker 8:  to build that itself, that it was not gonna get the help from the
Speaker 8:  government or from maybe even like the, the supplier network and
Speaker 8:  the, the, the third party aftermarket industry that exists. It needed to
Speaker 8:  do it itself and it did, and it created what, what is still stands today
Speaker 8:  as being the best and most reliable and most
Speaker 8:  distributed ev charging network that exists on the planet.
Speaker 8:  And they not only did that, but then they opened up that standard,
Speaker 8:  the charging standard that they saw as being sort of more
Speaker 8:  streamlined and cheaper and more sort of technologically
Speaker 8:  proficient. And they opened it up to the rest of the industry and they said,
Speaker 8:  okay, this is not just ours anymore. This is the North American charging
Speaker 8:  standard, the NACS, you all can use this. And Ford was the first to jump
Speaker 8:  on board and then GM followed and then the, all the dominoes soon followed
Speaker 8:  afterwards. And now we have every single major automaker in the world
Speaker 8:  saying that, that not only will they give their own customers, their own
Speaker 8:  EV owners access to Tesla's network, but they will also adopt the plug for
Speaker 8:  themselves on their future EVs. So we're gonna start seeing Ford vehicles
Speaker 8:  and GM vehicles come out with Tesla's plug versus the, the one that exists
Speaker 8:  today, which is the, the CCS plug. And so that is in,
Speaker 8:  in a lot of ways Tesla's moat and still stands today as, as, as Tesla's moat
Speaker 8:  in, in protection against the future. But it was always gonna be the case
Speaker 8:  that it was not gonna be able to maintain the market share that it had. I
Speaker 8:  mean it had the advantage of being first, so therefore it, you know, I think
Speaker 8:  at the most it had over 75% of the EV sales as
Speaker 8:  Tesla's a eventually. And if it was successful, if it could
Speaker 8:  guarantee the fact that it was successful, other companies were, were going
Speaker 8:  to inevitably follow its lead and make their own electric cars. And
Speaker 8:  now you're starting to see that market share shrink, it's now around 50%,
Speaker 8:  its sales are down, its revenue is down, its profits have shrank.
Speaker 8:  And so there's, you know, there's a lot of concern about, you know, sort
Speaker 8:  of Tesla's future as a car company, which it's still for all the
Speaker 8:  bluster about AI and robotics, it still is fundamentally a car company.
Speaker 1:  Right. And is that because Tesla has lost
Speaker 1:  some of its swagger or because everybody else has finally caught up or a
Speaker 1:  little bit of both?
Speaker 8:  I think a little bit of both. I think you've got the fact that it's not just
Speaker 8:  a Tesla anymore. You can go out, You can take a look at these really great
Speaker 8:  electric Hyundais and these great electric Kias, the Ford Mustang Mach e
Speaker 8:  remains a very popular vehicle now you've got electric trucks, you've got
Speaker 8:  the electric F-150 and the Silverado and there's more to come. And then
Speaker 8:  if you don't even like some of those old dusty old legacy car companies,
Speaker 8:  there's Rivian and there's Polestar and there's all these other sort of newer
Speaker 8:  Tesla light companies that have maybe as much of a
Speaker 8:  sheen on them as Tesla did. And maybe you don't like the kind of things that
Speaker 8:  Elon Musk stands for. You don't like the things he says on X, you don't like
Speaker 8:  his positions, his political positions, which have obviously become more
Speaker 8:  conservative and right wing over the last few years. And he's not shy about
Speaker 8:  sharing those with the world. And so if you find that to be abhorrent,
Speaker 8:  You can, you know, there's plenty of other places for you to go. And I think
Speaker 8:  that as we've seen in this presidential election now with, with electric
Speaker 8:  vehicles becoming so politicized that if Republicans are railing
Speaker 8:  against EVs in what you're left with is an entirely a
Speaker 8:  progressive or democratic or left-leaning customer demographic,
Speaker 8:  those people are not going to be willingly gobbling up Tesla's left and right.
Speaker 8:  Maybe they begrudgingly will buy a Tesla because of how good the charging
Speaker 8:  network is or the prices which have come down significantly in
Speaker 8:  the last few years. And now You can get a Tesla, especially a used one for,
Speaker 8:  you know, around 20, $25,000 in a lot of ways we, the
Speaker 8:  $25,000 EV exists and it just happens to be a used model
Speaker 8:  three. So, you know, I think in some ways that it's become a lot more
Speaker 8:  complicated, but then in a lot of other ways, this is the way that it was
Speaker 8:  always going to go, especially if Tesla was as successful as it, it has proven
Speaker 8:  to be. Right.
Speaker 1:  So you, you've brought me to my last Elon Musk question and then, and then
Speaker 1:  I will let you go. I think a lot of this roadmap is really interesting to
Speaker 1:  me. And Tesla deserves credit over the years for pulling off a lot of what
Speaker 1:  it said it was going to do. It's been much weirder than we expected, but
Speaker 1:  Tesla did a lot of the stuff it said it was going to do. And so to the extent
Speaker 1:  that I want to give the company the benefit of the doubt that it has been
Speaker 1:  able to do this in the past, I might be able to do it again. That's one thing.
Speaker 1:  But we've talked about this so much over the years that Elon Musk is Tesla
Speaker 1:  and Tesla is Elon Musk, and I feel like what that means has
Speaker 1:  changed. So I'm curious for, for your read right now in 2024, even
Speaker 1:  different from what it was in 2018, the first time shareholders voted to
Speaker 1:  give him all this money, what is your read on what Elon Musk means to
Speaker 1:  Tesla in sort of this next phase? Like is that that close association
Speaker 1:  was undeniably good for Tesla for a really long time? Say what you will,
Speaker 1:  it just, it just was whether you were a person who liked electric
Speaker 1:  vehicles or a person who owned Tesla stock, victory's all around for
Speaker 1:  a long time there, do you think that's still the case in the next
Speaker 1:  phase of this company? Or has it sort of inexorably changed since
Speaker 1:  2018? I think
Speaker 8:  It's still the case because if you look at the vote totals, you look at the
Speaker 8:  way that people voted their shares, which there were billions of shares that
Speaker 8:  were, that were voted during this, this past shareholder vote, over
Speaker 8:  70% voted in favor of awarding him this pay package,
Speaker 8:  which is a pretty strong sign that people see Tesla and
Speaker 8:  not only Tesla as it is today, but Tesla's future as some
Speaker 8:  sort of undefined robotics company or whatever it is in the future
Speaker 8:  as being inextricably linked to Elon Musk and his
Speaker 8:  ability to be the one that sort of is guiding that ship. So I think that
Speaker 8:  that was a pretty clear sign if we had seen, and it was pretty much, I think
Speaker 8:  the same percent that first awarded him that pay
Speaker 8:  package back in 2018. So there's been six years right
Speaker 8:  between these two votes and we're seeing basically an unchanged vote
Speaker 8:  total. That said, you know, and I talked to a couple of experts in, in the
Speaker 8:  midst of this, if you're someone who bought Tesla shares back in 2011, you
Speaker 8:  are really happy with Elon Musk in the way that he's been leading this company.
Speaker 8:  If you're someone who bought shares in 2023, you have probably a lot of
Speaker 8:  questions and you're, you're probably wondering about what the post musk
Speaker 8:  future is for Tesla. And he was asked that during the shareholder meeting,
Speaker 8:  which he stood on stage and took a lot of questions. Many of them were
Speaker 8:  not great questions, they left a lot to be desired. You know,
Speaker 8:  as one can imagine at a Tesla event of this kind, you're gonna get a lot
Speaker 8:  of like, you know, sort of overt displays of feely and, and I call
Speaker 1:  Them the how are you so terrific questions. Exactly,
Speaker 8:  Yes. I call them sycophant scot questions But. anyway, you
Speaker 8:  got a lot of those types of questions. But somebody did ask him some, some
Speaker 8:  something along the lines of like, you know, you, you're not gonna live forever,
Speaker 8:  which I maybe Musk might disagree with, I know, right? He might, I know a
Speaker 8:  lot of him and his friends are working on that problem right now, but that,
Speaker 8:  that's it. Either they're like, how's your health? Or something along like
Speaker 8:  the lines of that and what's gonna be the future of Tesla? And he gave the
Speaker 8:  vague answer. He is like, I'm very excited and confident in the future of
Speaker 8:  Tesla. There's just no one line being lined up to take the, the reins
Speaker 8:  of this company. In fact, most of the people that could have I think were
Speaker 8:  fired in the last round of layoffs that they had. Most of the, the
Speaker 8:  c-suite executives have departed. There's new people that have just come
Speaker 8:  in, it just does not seem that they have any interest in
Speaker 8:  grooming somebody. And that's it. I mean, Musk is not that old. He's still
Speaker 8:  in his fifties and it probably has, you know,
Speaker 8:  long years ahead of him running this company and it's very clear that that's
Speaker 8:  what the shareholders want, which is why they voted it this way. So it
Speaker 8:  just seems like, you know, yes, the people who have said that Musk is Tesla
Speaker 8:  and Tesla is Musk, that is more accurate today than it ever has
Speaker 8:  been. And I think it's just a question of does he still see himself
Speaker 8:  leading this company and if so, what is his vision of the future? Because
Speaker 8:  that's the one clearly that most people are interested in, in following.
Speaker 1:  Right. and it sounds like very much under that world in
Speaker 1:  which Elon Musk and Tesla are more connected than ever, Tesla
Speaker 1:  is going to look less and less like a car company as time goes on. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It's possible. It's very possible that it becomes, you know, that the car
Speaker 8:  aspect of, of its like business shrinks. But if that's the case,
Speaker 8:  they need to really start to think about how they're gonna replace those
Speaker 8:  revenues. Because right now they're in a bit of a bind because the,
Speaker 8:  you know, it's over 80% of their revenues are automotive. They still,
Speaker 8:  you know, obviously pull in some revenue from, from the energy side of the
Speaker 8:  business and from from battery storage, you know, the, the solar aspect of
Speaker 8:  their, of their business has remained pretty flat. It's not growing nearly
Speaker 8:  as much as I'm sure a lot of analysts would like to see it grow. So there's
Speaker 8:  just nothing really to replace the money yet. And obviously robotics and
Speaker 8:  autonomy and the Tesla network and self-driving cars and the robo robax and
Speaker 8:  all these things remain just far too theoretical
Speaker 8:  for anyone to sort of like hang anything solid on. So I just think
Speaker 8:  that if it wants to be this company that it's, it's setting itself up for,
Speaker 8:  it needs to start to demonstrate how it's actually going to make
Speaker 8:  money. Otherwise, I think a lot of shareholders are gonna feel very much
Speaker 8:  like bag holders at the end of all of this.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, at some point you gotta start selling stuff.
Speaker 8:  That's how it works. That's how, how I'm
Speaker 1:  Told there's a lot of that going on with AI in general right now is is it's,
Speaker 1:  it's all very shiny and at some point you gotta start selling stuff and I
Speaker 1:  think I have a feeling we're headed for a couple years of reckoning on what
Speaker 1:  You can and can't sell when it comes to AI stuff.
Speaker 8:  That sounds about right.
Speaker 1:  Alright Andy, thank you as always.
Speaker 8:  It's my pleasure. Thanks David.
Speaker 9:  Alright,
Speaker 1:  We gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk about wearables
Speaker 10:  if you have an injury that's making it harder to close your rings or maybe
Speaker 10:  you just need a day off, You can pause them for a rest day, week or more
Speaker 10:  and keep your award streak going.
Speaker 1:  The thing where I'm lying on the couch feeling sick or tired
Speaker 1:  or just haven't had time that day to go exercise and my watch is like
Speaker 1:  yelling at me about not closing my rings is the thing that makes me want
Speaker 1:  to take off my Apple Watch. I've actually turned off a lot of the goals,
Speaker 1:  I just try to not worry about that stuff anymore. But I like the idea of
Speaker 1:  being able to care about it and then not care about it But. anyway,
Speaker 1:  that is just one piece of a lot of wearable news.
Speaker 1:  In the last few weeks we've gotten lawsuits from Samsung over
Speaker 1:  Aura's Smart Rings, we've gotten Pixel watch leaks, we've gotten a new
Speaker 1:  Samsung, Galaxy Watch, we've gotten a bunch of FDA News
Speaker 1:  vs. Song has been covering all of this and is deep in the
Speaker 1:  wearable space as anyone who listens to this show will know. So I figured
Speaker 1:  I'd have her just come on and we're just gonna plow through some news and
Speaker 1:  talk about how big a deal any of this really is and take a victory
Speaker 1:  lap on rest days fi song. Welcome back.
Speaker 11:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  You did it. This is the, this is the biggest news in the history of the song
Speaker 1:  at wwdc this year. We're gonna do, I have Apple stuff, Samsung
Speaker 1:  stuff, and Google stuff I want to talk about. But we gotta start with Apple.
Speaker 1:  I'm just, the floor is yours. If You can laugh, You can cry, You can be happy.
Speaker 1:  It's rest days. We got rest days VI
Speaker 11:  Was screaming so loud in my house and like, so I
Speaker 11:  have this one cat who loves to like just annoy me in my room. He likes to
Speaker 11:  sit with me in my office and as soon as they're like, oh and rest days
Speaker 11:  they're gonna be a thing now I was like, yes.
Speaker 11:  So loud. And I was just like typing in the, in The Verge Slack with like
Speaker 11:  so many typos just 'cause I was going like, ha. And I saw that you mentioned
Speaker 11:  in the live blog that somewhere I was like fist pumping. Yes, all of that
Speaker 11:  was happening. And if it wasn't for the fact that I had to like get the
Speaker 11:  watch os 11 blog out, I would've probably just like run around
Speaker 11:  like a crazy person in my office just going like, oh
Speaker 11:  yes, finally, this is so great. So many levels
Speaker 11:  I could, it's just like, and I'm here to wax poetic on it so I will.
Speaker 11:  But like this has been 10 years of the Apple Watch and
Speaker 11:  it, it has been like a feature that I have been wanting for at least eight
Speaker 11:  of those years just because it's, oh my God, where do I start?
Speaker 11:  There's just so many reasons why you need a rest day. And
Speaker 11:  the big one is that we're not machines. And I actually think streaks are
Speaker 11:  quite toxic for the average person because we all
Speaker 11:  know that one Apple watch person who's just like, oh yeah, I
Speaker 11:  was sick, but huh, there's no way I'm breaking my streak.
Speaker 11:  So I just lowered it and went for a walk and I was like, I hear
Speaker 11:  that story so many times and I'm just like, that is the opposite of
Speaker 11:  improving your health that is actively not doing the best
Speaker 11:  thing for your health and your body in that point in time. And
Speaker 11:  then there's, for other people, those notifications are actually
Speaker 11:  extremely demoralizing. Yeah. So when I had Covid, I had it
Speaker 11:  pretty bad. I couldn't really think properly. I don't actually
Speaker 11:  remember a lot of having covid because it was like a bad time. But one thing
Speaker 11:  I really do remember was getting a buzz on my wrist looking and it's like,
Speaker 11:  You can still do it. You can take a 27 minute walk and
Speaker 11:  close that ring. Yes.
Speaker 1:  The thing where it's like, just go for an 11 mile walk, it's only 9:00 PM
Speaker 1:  you'll be fine. It's like, what? No, and
Speaker 11:  It's like I'm, no, actually I am, I have Covid
Speaker 11:  right now. And so I was just so annoyed and I
Speaker 11:  took the watch off and I, and I put it on the charger because that's
Speaker 11:  just how type A I am. I was just like, oh, I'm not gonna throw it across
Speaker 11:  the room. I'm gonna put it very gently on the charger. But
Speaker 11:  that, that kind of impulse. And I have also heard from several
Speaker 11:  of my friends that on their wedding days they either wore their Apple
Speaker 11:  watch on their ankles or gave it to their spouse
Speaker 11:  to carry for them. 'cause they were not gonna break that streak even though
Speaker 11:  it was their wedding day. And I was just like, I, I think,
Speaker 11:  I think we've gotten to a point where the streak is no longer helpful if
Speaker 11:  you are at that point, I think we have lost sight of what the streak is
Speaker 11:  supposed to be. Yep. It, it is a motivational tool and yeah, of
Speaker 11:  course like it is a great way to kind of visualize your
Speaker 11:  consistency. But you know, You can have a weekly streak. You can have a
Speaker 11:  monthly streak. It doesn't have to be a daily streak. And after
Speaker 11:  a certain point it's actually counterintuitive like the, the more into training
Speaker 11:  you go, you're supposed to have rest days, you're supposed to have days
Speaker 11:  where you do absolutely nothing. And on days where you do absolutely
Speaker 11:  nothing, let me tell you, if you have your move ring set at like a thousand
Speaker 11:  calories, like some people do, you're not gonna get a thousand calories
Speaker 11:  of exercise or you should not get a thousand calories of exercise on
Speaker 11:  a rest day. Especially when you're doing something like physically taxing,
Speaker 11:  like any kind of race training, any kind of, especially if you're doing
Speaker 11:  a marathon, those rest days are really important because some people are
Speaker 11:  out here and they're, and they're pounding the pavement for four hour
Speaker 11:  long runs. You're putting an incredible amount of stress on your body. Any
Speaker 11:  athlete will tell you rest is incredibly important. And that's why so
Speaker 11:  many athletes gravitate toward the whoop, they gravitate towards the
Speaker 11:  AA ring because those are prioritizing rest. And everybody else
Speaker 11:  in the industry for the past three, four years has been prioritizing
Speaker 11:  rest in some form and capacity. So to have Apple lag
Speaker 11:  so far behind on that, it was just, it's like the most
Speaker 11:  glaring thing because the Apple Watch is the leader in the smartwatch world,
Speaker 11:  right? It it is like the one that everyone points to. It's the one that's
Speaker 11:  popular. It's, you know, apple does something with smart watches, everybody
Speaker 11:  follows. But the one thing that they really weren't doing for the longest
Speaker 11:  time was sleep tracking. And then on top of sleep tracking rest and recovery
Speaker 11:  was just like close your rings or
Speaker 1:  Else. Yeah, it really, it gets like menacing. And then the, the notification
Speaker 1:  that really did me in was the one the next morning where
Speaker 1:  you wake up and it's like, Ugh, you only closed two rings yesterday.
Speaker 1:  Like parentheses, you pathetic, monster, let's try and do
Speaker 1:  better today. And I get those when I don't wear my watch for
Speaker 1:  a day. And it's like, come on, watch. Like I just wasn't, I didn't have this
Speaker 1:  on. And then I get to the point where I'm like, I go for a walk and I'm not
Speaker 1:  wearing the watch. And all of a sudden you have that feeling of like, oh,
Speaker 1:  it didn't count because I'm, and then, and then it's like, those are the
Speaker 1:  moments where I'm like, oh, this is no longer serving the purpose that I
Speaker 1:  got this to serve for me.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. You know, I, I had that exact experience this weekend. I
Speaker 11:  forgot my watch when we, my friend and I went out to a park and then we
Speaker 11:  went for a hike at that park and I was like, the entire time in my head
Speaker 11:  I was like, it's not going to count. Right? It's not gonna count. And I
Speaker 11:  really hate that. That's not gonna count because this is a very steep hill
Speaker 11:  and like, I'm not getting credit for that. But that's actually, it's
Speaker 11:  super counterintuitive because I still did the hike. I still did the
Speaker 11:  thing that was very good for my body just because the Apple watch didn't
Speaker 11:  acknowledge it. You know, like I, and I think we have to really examine
Speaker 11:  what streaks mean. So like before Apple introduced this ability to pause
Speaker 11:  your, pause your rings, which I downloaded the beta and I've used it since
Speaker 11:  and I like really was just like, oh my God, this is, this is such a nice
Speaker 11:  feeling that I'm not getting punished for that. But before that, I would
Speaker 11:  just, every once in a while, once I got a streak up to like 90 days,
Speaker 11:  I would perfect purposefully break it.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. For your own sanity? Just
Speaker 11:  For my own sanity and just to teach myself that like the streak is not,
Speaker 11:  the streak is not how I define my consistency. Because like I can
Speaker 11:  tell you for the last six years, I haven't gone a week without running or
Speaker 11:  some sort of physical exercise. So I would say that I am consistent in my
Speaker 11:  fitness routine, but you know, life and I'll get a little vulnerable with
Speaker 11:  everybody. My life has not been super easy the last few years
Speaker 11:  just because I've had a lot of like circumstances, namely my entire immediate
Speaker 11:  family died like kind of one after another. And when you go
Speaker 11:  through those life circumstances, the last thing you need is the Apple Watch
Speaker 11:  going, you didn't close two of your rings yesterday.
Speaker 11:  What happened? And you're like, well, well Apple Watch, there was a funeral
Speaker 11:  yesterday. That's what happened. Yeah. I did not go
Speaker 11:  and train my little legs out because I was not
Speaker 11:  having a good day that day. So, you know, I think having that
Speaker 11:  flexibility, allowing that to be within the Alpha watch and then to also
Speaker 11:  have the other fitness features that they introduced, like training load,
Speaker 11:  which, you know, that's not new. Garmin's had that for forever. All like
Speaker 11:  the polars have had that forever. But just like the acknowledgement that
Speaker 11:  there are going to be times where you should not push it, where you should
Speaker 11:  ease off the gas and that overall that will be good for you is is
Speaker 11:  just like, I'm just like, yes.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Well, yeah, that, that context is a really interesting way to think
Speaker 1:  about all of the watch stuff. And like you said, I think the, the Apple watch,
Speaker 1:  we pay attention to it more than most smart watches, but we should because
Speaker 1:  it, it, it, it is the one sort of driving this whole industry in a lot of
Speaker 1:  ways. It really feels like a sort of vibe shift in the Apple
Speaker 1:  watch from like, how do we get you to do more and
Speaker 1:  turn everyone into super athletes and, and put more and more and more
Speaker 1:  data into here? And there's still some of that, right? and it's like if you
Speaker 1:  want to know all of the teeny tiny details of your body, like the watch is
Speaker 1:  getting better and better at that. But at the same time there is this recognition
Speaker 1:  of like, okay, actually maybe the watch's job as it starts to understand
Speaker 1:  you better is to help you not push you. And that those are not the same
Speaker 1:  thing. The
Speaker 11:  Struggle that every single smart watch or fitness tracker has that no other
Speaker 11:  gadget device has is that it is trying to affect behavioral change.
Speaker 11:  And behavioral change is very difficult. We are very
Speaker 11:  ingrained in our habits and building a new habit doesn't actually take
Speaker 11:  21 days. Like some people say it can take 21 days, it could take 66, it
Speaker 11:  could take half a year. So like building change like that,
Speaker 11:  especially when it's physical activity and exercise, which is notoriously,
Speaker 11:  you know, we are not like evolution has not made us crave
Speaker 11:  exercise. If anything, evolution has made us crave the couch and a bag of
Speaker 11:  potato chips because you know, that's, that's just how it is. And so even
Speaker 11:  though you know it's good for you, you know, there are
Speaker 11:  people who love streaks. There are people who love gamification. There are
Speaker 11:  signs that gamification does work to an extent. There are also people
Speaker 11:  like me who are just like bundles of anxiety and nerves
Speaker 11:  and full of burnout. The world is full of things that will make you
Speaker 11:  burnout. Streaks for me personally, are a source of burnout.
Speaker 11:  If I am chasing a streak, that is how I've gotten every single running
Speaker 11:  injury in the past two, three years. That's how I've gotten my calf injuries.
Speaker 11:  That's how I've gotten shin splints. It has been trying to keep streaks
Speaker 11:  going counter to like my achilles tendon or my calf or whatever,
Speaker 11:  saying like, we're a little ouchie right now. Could you take a, could
Speaker 11:  you take a break? Could you walk instead of going on a six mile
Speaker 11:  run? And I'd be like, no body, I will, I will, I have a streak to
Speaker 11:  maintain.
Speaker 1:  I wish they had just called it like, leave me alone. That's all I want from
Speaker 1:  the activity thing is every time it sends a notification, one of the buttons
Speaker 1:  should just be leave me alone. And then it's just, it's just like, my bad,
Speaker 1:  sorry, I'll leave you alone. And then it comes back the next day and it iss
Speaker 1:  like, are we cool now? Can we, can we hang out? Like that's, that's the relationship
Speaker 1:  I wanna have with my Apple watch.
Speaker 11:  I mean same
Speaker 1:  Before we move on, anything else about watchOS 11 that got you particularly
Speaker 1:  excited
Speaker 11:  Live activities? I think that's really fun and cool. I kind of wanna see
Speaker 11:  how well it does. 'cause it really depends on the
Speaker 11:  intelligence being able to tell or suggest a really
Speaker 11:  cool thing to you while the live activities are going. But I'm very
Speaker 11:  curious to see how that plays out on, on the wrist.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that that's a good one. So, okay, competitor time. All
Speaker 1:  of these I would say are the, the ones trying to do Android Apple
Speaker 1:  watches. There are going to be people who don't like that description, but
Speaker 1:  that is what is going on. It's,
Speaker 11:  It's what they're doing, it's just what
Speaker 1:  It is. Let's start with The. Pixel Watch. So we got both some new stuff for
Speaker 1:  The Pixel Watch two and some leaks for The Pixel Watch three.
Speaker 1:  Anything exciting for you in in Pixel Watch land right now?
Speaker 11:  I think bigger Pixel watch, like the rumor is that it's going to be called
Speaker 11:  Pixel Watch xl. So just I, I'm, I'm
Speaker 11:  praying for my future self in a video going The Pixel Watch three
Speaker 11:  xl, if that's actually what they're calling it. 'cause that's a mouthful.
Speaker 11:  But just in terms of that is the biggest complaint that we
Speaker 11:  had with The Pixel Watch two is that it was only one size and
Speaker 11:  ironically it was the smaller size and so people were like, we want a bigger
Speaker 11:  one. When historically smartwatch size complaints have been, this is
Speaker 11:  too big, this is too bulky, make one smaller.
Speaker 11:  So this is like an ongoing conflict that we've had.
Speaker 11:  But I think it just kind of shows that you really can't do one size fits
Speaker 11:  all with smart watches. So for them to have a bigger size, I'm stoked for
Speaker 11:  people. I had a lot of readers just be like, but I have a bigger arm and
Speaker 11:  The Pixel Watch looks stupid on it. and it was like, you know what? Fair,
Speaker 1:  Purely anecdotally, I will say I see Apple Watch Ultras everywhere,
Speaker 1:  like in much higher volume than I expected. 'cause it's a, it's a big
Speaker 1:  watch but I see them everywhere on people of all
Speaker 1:  sizes and all fashion senses. Like the
Speaker 1:  willingness to do the big watch I guess for extra Battery and some extra
Speaker 1:  features like way more of that than I expected when the Ultra came out. Are
Speaker 1:  you wearing an ultra right now? Is that what I just saw
Speaker 11:  That that is an ultra tube
Speaker 1:  And you are not what I would call a large armed person. I
Speaker 11:  Am not a large armed person. I have very tiny bird wrists. But what I
Speaker 11:  will say is that I have been acclimatized to really big watches
Speaker 11:  over the years wearing a lot of garments. So I'm kind of used to the weight
Speaker 11:  at this point. But also my eyesight is so notoriously bad
Speaker 11:  that people keep asking me like, why is your iPhone on the largest font
Speaker 11:  possible? It's like, 'cause I can't read well and the Ultra has
Speaker 11:  a gigantic excrete. Eli has made fun of me many times. He's like, you know,
Speaker 11:  I can read everything on your Apple Watch. And it's like, yes, yes.
Speaker 11:  And you know what, so can I And that's the point.
Speaker 1:  That's the dream. Yeah, that's
Speaker 11:  The dream.
Speaker 1:  No, I agree. I think, I think the bigger pixel watch will be a
Speaker 1:  victory if only again, because it's just more options. And I feel like for
Speaker 1:  me, The, Pixel Watch yes kind of landed in the right zone. It's like
Speaker 1:  about the size I want a smartwatch to be and I like the round,
Speaker 1:  like I was very happy even with the first one. But you're absolutely right
Speaker 1:  that the only way to do this is to have lots of them because people are different
Speaker 1:  and it's like it gets all the weirder when you get to glasses and we'll talk
Speaker 1:  about that another day. But like this is just where we are now.
Speaker 11:  The other thing with The Pixel Watch that it's like a very small thing,
Speaker 11:  but for me as a wearable reviewer, I went, huh is the fact that Car
Speaker 11:  Crashes detection is coming to The Pixel Watch too, because we don't have
Speaker 11:  that on Android yet. And I was like, is this the first time that we're gonna
Speaker 11:  have car crash detection on a smartwatch on Android and yes, yes it
Speaker 11:  is. So that I think is significant in the sense that like, you know,
Speaker 11:  Google was starting so far behind Apple and so far behind Samsung
Speaker 11:  when The Pixel Watch was launched like soon to be three years ago.
Speaker 11:  So a lot of the times when we get these new features, it's like, eh, it's
Speaker 11:  been, it's been done already. And yes, that is true. This is still true
Speaker 11:  here, but the gap is getting smaller. And for me I'm like,
Speaker 11:  yes, finally the gap is getting smaller. I'm so excited about that.
Speaker 11:  So like that's just like a tiny thing because Samsung doesn't have car crash
Speaker 11:  detection for its watches yet. So for Google to be like, Hey
Speaker 11:  we got this.
Speaker 1:  It's progress. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  It's progress. Yeah. And I'm excited to see, it's just like a very small
Speaker 11:  thing that I'm excited to see.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no it's, it's a good one. And I think you're right that Google
Speaker 1:  basically just systematically doing Apple Watch things is the correct
Speaker 1:  thing to do, especially if then it can turn around and be like, oh now it
Speaker 1:  has all the Gemini stuff and we're gonna finally figure out Fitbit. Even
Speaker 1:  though I've essentially given up on the possibility of the Fitbit integration
Speaker 1:  ever making any sense, it won't, You can see the path. This is the thing
Speaker 1:  about The Pixel Watch that drives me so crazy. You can see the path to it
Speaker 1:  being great and I'm, I'm, I'm hopeful at least
Speaker 1:  that Google still seems to care about it. So that's something. But the Fitbit
Speaker 1:  thing will never stop driving either of us crazy. I
Speaker 11:  Don't think it's one can pray, one can pray.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's enough about Fitbit on this particular podcast. Let's talk about
Speaker 1:  Samsung for a minute. You brought up Samsung, it's the one with the new watch
Speaker 1:  that was the, the news of I think last week. Now the Galaxy Watch
Speaker 1:  Fe, anything exciting there? It's cheaper. Yay. For cheaper.
Speaker 11:  It's cheaper. Which, you know, that's notable because the last two years
Speaker 11:  we've seen price increases for the base Galaxy Watch five and the six
Speaker 11:  because inflation, yeah, Samsung's not immune. And that
Speaker 11:  was kind of sad at the time because you know, the Galaxy Watch has
Speaker 11:  historically been kind of competitively priced underpriced for
Speaker 11:  what it is. So it would just be like, oh yeah, you could get the base model
Speaker 11:  for less than $300 and that's pretty, it's pretty solid.
Speaker 11:  And that's like not really the case anymore. It's, I I believe it's about
Speaker 11:  300 now for the base model. So to get the fe, which is
Speaker 11:  1 99 for the Bluetooth only version, that's a solid $200
Speaker 11:  watch, which you know the, the Apple Watch SE is two 50.
Speaker 11:  So starting price. So you're looking at that and you're like, oh okay, okay.
Speaker 11:  But what it really is is that it's a Rebadged Galaxy
Speaker 11:  Watch four. So that's kind of interesting. Interesting. Okay. Like spec
Speaker 11:  wise, spec wise, you are getting the last gen chip and
Speaker 11:  I think once you kind of look at the specs you're like, oh, you're not really
Speaker 11:  giving that much up. But at the same time it's not that exciting
Speaker 11:  because the, the design is very similar. So what are we
Speaker 11:  actually looking here and we are looking at Samsung once again throwing
Speaker 11:  spaghetti at the wall with its lineup and trying to figure out what the
Speaker 11:  hell's gonna work. And I think they're identifying very realistically that,
Speaker 11:  you know, apple does kind of have a winning combination by having a
Speaker 11:  entry level watch for kids and for elderly
Speaker 11:  relatives that people use it for having the base model and then just having
Speaker 11:  this massive ultra for people who want the
Speaker 11:  bestest and the greatest and are like imagining themselves to be
Speaker 11:  hardcore elite athletes or maybe they are hardcore elite athletes. And I
Speaker 11:  think what we can tell from leaks so far is that Samsung is very much
Speaker 11:  aligning itself to kind of have the same lineup. So we have the
Speaker 11:  Fe now and I think it's very telling that that's coming ahead of
Speaker 11:  unpacked because we're, we're gonna have the
Speaker 11:  ostensibly the Galaxy Watch seven and then the Galaxy Watch Ultra
Speaker 11:  is I think the rumored name for it. It's this
Speaker 11:  squirkle looking thing from the leaks on the renders that we've seen.
Speaker 11:  I don't think it like Galaxy Watch, Fe Galaxy Watch
Speaker 11:  Ultra, I think we can point to the other company that they're kind of
Speaker 11:  taking, let's say inspiration from, they're
Speaker 1:  Just leaning into it. They're
Speaker 11:  Just leaning into it. And I don't think it's a wrong move. I think it, I
Speaker 11:  think it's actually quite smart to kind of position themselves as, like
Speaker 11:  you say the Android of the Apple watch of
Speaker 11:  Android is kind of what they're fashioning themselves as. They're just kind
Speaker 11:  of leaning into that. Again, some people are gonna be upset about that.
Speaker 11:  I don't think they really should be, there
Speaker 1:  Are worse things to be at this, at this particular moment in time. I
Speaker 11:  Think they're just kind of going, I think this is what people want. We'll
Speaker 11:  give them what they want and then on top of that we're expecting the Galaxy
Speaker 11:  ring. So that's one way that Samsung can go like, haha, suck it,
Speaker 11:  Google, suck it Apple, we got something that you don't, and it's a Galaxy
Speaker 11:  ring. And so I'm really, I'm really stoked
Speaker 11:  and excited to see what that's gonna look like, especially since they
Speaker 11:  preemptively sued Aura. This
Speaker 1:  Was the next thing I wanted to talk about, which
Speaker 11:  To me was just like, ooh, okay, that's fun.
Speaker 11:  I just got a new smart ring in the mail. I'm currently wearing three,
Speaker 11:  yes, I'm wearing three at the moment so I'll be wearing four just to
Speaker 11:  get like, so I know all the competitors when it ever it is, I'm
Speaker 11:  very excited to see how that goes down for Aura because this is
Speaker 11:  the, this is the first time I think that they've had a competitor that could
Speaker 11:  really, you know, let's, let's be real. 'cause really fuck up their, you
Speaker 11:  know, the thing that they've had for a long time. They've been going out
Speaker 11:  and you know this, this Samsung case, the patent case. They were just like,
Speaker 11:  listen, you done sued Ring Con, you done
Speaker 11:  sued Ultra Human, you done sued Circular, that's the
Speaker 11:  other one. And Samsung just came out and they're like, yeah, we see what
Speaker 11:  you're doing. You have this pattern of just suing people for doing what
Speaker 11:  a smart ring ought to do. So we just wanna preemptively say that
Speaker 11:  we're not infringing on your patents so you can't sue us, which
Speaker 1:  Is an amazing lawsuit to file by the way. Very good.
Speaker 11:  I just can't wait to see what happens because Samsung doing that, that's
Speaker 11:  gonna set a precedent for the other smaller companies. I would be a little
Speaker 11:  stressed if I was Aura and You can tell they are stressed because they
Speaker 11:  just keep dropping features. They keep coming
Speaker 11:  out and being like, we got this new thing and we got this other thing You
Speaker 11:  can, we can tell how old your heart is now we can do this and we have science.
Speaker 11:  And so I'm just really interested to see how that
Speaker 11:  drama is gonna play out over the next few months.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I'm really excited about the Galaxy Ring in particular. I think it's,
Speaker 1:  it's shaping up to be a pretty fun year for watches in that I think to your
Speaker 1:  point, we're gonna have three pretty competitive lineups of
Speaker 1:  smart watches if all of the leaks and stuff come true, which I think is very
Speaker 1:  exciting. But I think the Galaxy ring is going to be really the
Speaker 1:  first like mainstream walk into an
Speaker 1:  electronic store and it's going to be on a shelf in front of you from a company
Speaker 1:  you've heard of Smart Ring and I think that's very exciting and from what
Speaker 1:  we've seen so far, it seems to look nice and it's not
Speaker 1:  humongous. Like I actually have pretty high hopes for this thing and I think
Speaker 1:  if it's good we might start to see this market take off pretty
Speaker 1:  fast.
Speaker 11:  I, I think so if it is, I wanna say 50% as good as what the
Speaker 11:  Aura Ring is, is bringing to the table with the convenience of just like
Speaker 11:  integrating with your Samsung products already. If I was
Speaker 11:  Aura I would be scared.
Speaker 1:  V thank you as always,
Speaker 11:  Thanks for having break.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna do a question
Speaker 1:  from the Vergecast hotline.
Speaker 14:  weather this month and once again I am looking outside at a
Speaker 14:  thunderstorm and my weather app says it's sunny.
Speaker 14:  So the Apple weather app is just terrible. And
Speaker 14:  ever since Apple bought Blue Sky, I have just been
Speaker 14:  struggling for a good app that doesn't sell my privacy. So I'm
Speaker 14:  wondering if The Verge has a 2024
Speaker 14:  recommendation on a good solid
Speaker 14:  weather app on the iPhone that doesn't sell my privacy
Speaker 14:  away. I hope to hear your answers on air. Thanks
Speaker 1:  Steve. You have come to the right place. I am here to tell you you have come
Speaker 1:  to the right place. Liam James is here. Liam, is it fair to say you are the
Speaker 1:  verges preeminent weather nerd? Like is that a fair accusation?
Speaker 9:  I would say I am doing my best to, to fill the very large shoes
Speaker 9:  of Dan Seaford, but I, I am very into the weather.
Speaker 1:  How's the weather station? First of all?
Speaker 9:  The weather station is doing great. It's still same batteries installed
Speaker 9:  on the, the roof of my New York City apartment building illegally,
Speaker 9:  but still sending a signal down to my weather station I. love it. So
Speaker 1:  Part of the reason I brought you on here is that I, I wonder if we are going
Speaker 1:  to get to a point where we tell people that the best thing you should do
Speaker 1:  in order to get a good forecast is install a weather station on your roof
Speaker 1:  like a maniac. Is this a reasonable recommendation you would give to people?
Speaker 9:  No. Okay. It is a completely ridiculous situation, but what can I
Speaker 9:  say? I love gadgets. It all started with our Father's Day gift guide. So
Speaker 9:  really, I mean we've created our own, our own problem to
Speaker 1:  Solve here. This is what we do. Okay. So I have two things I wanna talk
Speaker 1:  about here. One is that, and, and I think you and I are gonna agree on this,
Speaker 1:  the single best and most important piece of advice that I can give you here
Speaker 1:  is a website called Forecast Advisor. Yes. Which people don't know about
Speaker 1:  and people should know about. You go and you plug in either your zip code
Speaker 1:  or your city and your state and it will tell you which of the many
Speaker 1:  data sources that exist is most accurate historically
Speaker 1:  for where you are. Do you use this, Liam? Have you ever, have you ever run
Speaker 1:  this test on yourself?
Speaker 9:  Oh absolutely. Okay. I believe it was actually Dan Seaford who introduced
Speaker 9:  me to this, but yeah, it's not the app so much as it is the
Speaker 9:  source of data your app is pulling from.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So, okay, let's just, let's just do this live for our buddy Steve here.
Speaker 1:  So we'll go to, we'll go to Forecast Advisor dot com, we type in Dallas,
Speaker 1:  Texas where it is currently as we are recording this 95 degrees.
Speaker 1:  Oof. Steve, I'm so, so sorry. And what this says
Speaker 1:  is that for the last month, so May, 2024,
Speaker 1:  the NWS, the National Weather Service Digital Forecast was the most accurate
Speaker 1:  data source at 71.86% of forecast.
Speaker 1:  A low number says a lot about forecast that the best one is
Speaker 1:  only 71% accurate. There are three here that are
Speaker 1:  all basically identical. They're all 71 point something percent
Speaker 1:  accurate. It's the National Weather Service, the Weather Channel, and Aris
Speaker 1:  weather. And then it goes all the way down to, like, the reason this is good
Speaker 1:  is let's say there are
Speaker 1:  1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 other ones
Speaker 1:  and the one all the way at the bottom, which is called persistence was only
Speaker 1:  right 45.71% of the time. So this is like you are looking
Speaker 1:  at a weather forecast that is literally only half accurate.
Speaker 9:  I believe the current Apple built-in Weather app
Speaker 9:  uses the Weather Channel. If I'm correct, what, what was the score for the
Speaker 9:  Weather Channel in Dallas, Texas?
Speaker 1:  So that's second on the list here at
Speaker 1:  71.51%
Speaker 9:  Second at 71% not
Speaker 1:  So great. Yeah, it's, it's tough. Well what's interesting about this though
Speaker 1:  is one of the things that Forecast Advisor shows, I think, and I'm, I'm
Speaker 1:  extrapolating a little bit here, but if you look at it over the last year,
Speaker 1:  and again we're still in Dallas Access, Microsoft, I don't know what
Speaker 1:  it just says Microsoft, which is apparently a weather source was accurate
Speaker 1:  84% of the time. So what it seems like is what we just had in
Speaker 1:  May might have been like an extra volatile month of
Speaker 1:  weather, especially in Dallas, Texas. But like, let's, let's look where you
Speaker 1:  are, Liam, you're in New York. New York for you it's the Weather channel
Speaker 1:  is number 180 3 0.6%. So yeah, Dallas just has some wonky
Speaker 1:  weather going on. Everybody's struggling with Dallas.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's usually in my experience 'cause I've, I've used this service
Speaker 9:  in many cities and the National Weather Service is not usually your
Speaker 9:  top pick for
Speaker 1:  You. The National Weather Service is like fully halfway down the list.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's, it's, I I was surprised to see that be the topic for
Speaker 9:  Dallas, but yeah, it's, it's not the app you're using so
Speaker 9:  much. It is the source. Some of the more nerdy weather apps
Speaker 9:  will allow you to pick from a list of sources. I use the nerdiest of
Speaker 9:  all iOS weather apps, which is carrot weather and it, it has a
Speaker 9:  list of, it looks like almost a dozen sources here for me
Speaker 9:  to choose from. So
Speaker 1:  Carrot was one of the ones I was, I was gonna bring up because it is a
Speaker 1:  beloved app and it's also, I would say, like
Speaker 1:  you said, maybe the wonkiest of weather apps just in terms of like the
Speaker 1:  amount of stuff that You can see. If you want to, I don't use Carrot
Speaker 1:  personally, but you, I would assume as a giant weather nerd love it very
Speaker 1:  much.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean I think a lot of people use Carrot weather because it was the
Speaker 9:  first out of the gate with Apple Watch support. Hmm. But I've stuck with
Speaker 9:  it because they add so many niche nerdy features
Speaker 9:  like being able to pick your sources but also just like
Speaker 9:  You can completely customize the layout for what you want. Things that
Speaker 9:  I'm constantly wanting to see are the humidity
Speaker 9:  percentage and also just like the UV index because
Speaker 9:  it, it wildly swings in New York City and so
Speaker 9:  it's kind of good to know when you should probably put some sunscreen on
Speaker 9:  'cause you're gonna get burn to a crisp when you go outside.
Speaker 1:  Totally. And that's actually another good customization point that not only
Speaker 1:  is the data source really important, but knowing which parts of the forecast
Speaker 1:  you care about. Like I remember when I was in California during all the wildfires,
Speaker 1:  the air quality index became very important. Yeah. And so that was then like
Speaker 1:  a thing that I paid a lot of attention to in the forecast. And having something
Speaker 1:  where You can surface that into either like the home screen of your app or
Speaker 1:  even like a widget on your home screen goes a really long way because glance
Speaker 1:  ability is the whole thing, right? Like you should not have to spend 45 seconds
Speaker 1:  in your weather app to get a sense of what do I need to know before I go
Speaker 1:  outside. Exactly. So I that's, that's a very good one and Carrot does do
Speaker 1:  that very well. Carrot we should say also just got a big update that people
Speaker 1:  are very excited about. I, I honestly think that's a pretty good place to
Speaker 1:  start. It's a, it's a really good weather app.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's a great weather app. They just released a new update that again
Speaker 9:  allows war customization of the, of that like main screen.
Speaker 9:  You see when, when it comes out, I think there's a few other odds and ends
Speaker 9:  goodies that were in there. My backup weather app is
Speaker 9:  just about the nerdiest one. You can get it, it is called ambient
Speaker 9:  weather and it connects over the internet to that weather
Speaker 9:  station you were asking me about earlier. So I have a weather station on
Speaker 9:  my roof that reads all the weather information that you could possibly want.
Speaker 9:  This app allows me to access that weather station from anywhere. So
Speaker 9:  regardless of where I am, I can pull up the same information that's on the
Speaker 9:  cute little LCD screen that's on my desk. So that's my backup weather app.
Speaker 9:  That's
Speaker 1:  Pretty good. I did a big tour of weather apps
Speaker 1:  maybe a year ago. There are a lot of good ones out there, honestly, like
Speaker 1:  e especially if, if you're somebody who really likes to see like weather
Speaker 1:  news and you wanna keep up on sort of weather more broadly, the Weather Channel
Speaker 1:  app has actually gotten a lot better over time and is actually pretty good
Speaker 1:  now. They did a big redesign I think earlier this year. It's still kind
Speaker 1:  of too much for my taste, but it's a very good app. But what I landed on
Speaker 1:  is an app called Hello Weather, which I would say is a lot like Carrot but
Speaker 1:  just kind of less, it's very designy. They have a bunch of really beautiful
Speaker 1:  widgets. But my thing is it has this incredibly good kind of
Speaker 1:  glanceable hour by hour forecast, which I discovered is the only thing I
Speaker 1:  ever actually care about is just like, I wake up in the morning and I'm like,
Speaker 1:  when is it going to be hot? When is it going to rain the end? Like especially
Speaker 1:  for where we are, those are the only two questions that ever really matter.
Speaker 1:  And hello Weather, like Carrot lets you pick from a bunch of different sources.
Speaker 1:  So I did the Forecast Advisor thing. I went through, I picked the most accurate
Speaker 1:  source for me. And at that point it's just about kind of aesthetics,
Speaker 1:  right? Like all the data is the same and I, there's just something about
Speaker 1:  the sort of cleanliness of Hello Weather that I have come to really
Speaker 1:  like.
Speaker 9:  So the, the biggest question I have about this app, the hour by hour
Speaker 9:  weather data, is it the feels like temperature or is it
Speaker 9:  the actual temperature?
Speaker 1:  Liam, that's such a good question. It's such a good question and I'm so glad
Speaker 1:  you asked it. Is the actual temperature, which is the wrong answer, it
Speaker 1:  should be that feels like temperature. Yeah, but what it gives you at the
Speaker 1:  top is it'll show you the actual temperature in big letters and then right
Speaker 1:  underneath it that feels like temperature. So right now as we're recording
Speaker 1:  this, oh okay, it's 87 degrees. It feels like a hundred Cool
Speaker 1:  love summer 2024, but it doesn't give you that hour by hour. And
Speaker 1:  I would argue that it should, but yeah, what I like that it gives you is
Speaker 1:  a, a sort of running change in what matters. So
Speaker 1:  when it's not gonna rain, it'll show you the UV index in the, in the bar
Speaker 1:  graph, but when it's gonna rain it'll show you the precipitation amounts
Speaker 1:  per hour. Smart. So the hour by hour forecast actually shifts based on what
Speaker 1:  is most likely to happen. So on a sunny day like today, the, it tells me
Speaker 1:  the UV index. So they've just done a bunch of very clever things and again,
Speaker 1:  all of this is dependent on the data source to be accurate.
Speaker 1:  But I've gone in and figured out which data source is most accurate. And
Speaker 1:  so now I have this thing, the one thing I hate about Hello Weather is that
Speaker 1:  each data source spews different texts. So in they,
Speaker 1:  they all have this like structured data that just flows into the app, but
Speaker 1:  then they all will also have a description of the forecast and
Speaker 1:  the data source that I picked is AccuWeather, which at least the last time
Speaker 1:  I checked was most accurate for what I am pumps out these really long sort
Speaker 1:  of unhelpful stupid things like this one just says partly sunny and hot
Speaker 1:  semicolon a thunderstorm in spots late this afternoon, semicolon
Speaker 9:  find
Speaker 9:  Yeah, totally agree.
Speaker 1:  Sweet. All right Liam, thank you as always. Of course. Go
Speaker 1:  back to your weather station.
Speaker 9:  I will.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to
Speaker 1:  and