# Transcript
ID: 717f1b09-de8d-4b8c-808f-49878898ef63
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7215121925693810278/7579113407149821892/s93290-US-4901s-1714348636.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of forced app divestiture:
03:07 - The Verge’s David Pierce and Lauren Fiener discuss the latest tech policy bills floating through Congress, including a privacy bill, a generative AI bill, and the TikTok divest-or-ban bill.
TikTok ‘ban’ passes in the House again
TikTok divest-or-ban legislation could suddenly be fast-tracked in the Senate
Lawmakers unveil new bipartisan digital privacy bill after years of impasse
A real privacy law? House lawmakers are optimistic this time
New bill would create public datasets to train AI and incentivize innovation.
34:17 - David talks with Nikola Todorovic and Tye Sheridan about their company Wonder Dynamics, which is creating AI-powered production tools for filmmakers.
1:09:16 - David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about messaging apps.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (25 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Forced
Speaker 2:  App Divesture. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am stuck
Speaker 2:  in my basement because this is the only camera and microphone that I have
Speaker 2:  that works. So I bought this thing that DJ I Osmo Pocket
Speaker 2:  three just to make these intros. I like being out in the world,
Speaker 2:  I like telling you guys what I'm up to. I like doing fun stuff while we record
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast and then it broke. It was just sitting in my bag for
Speaker 2:  reasons that I cannot figure out. Just something about the gimbal
Speaker 2:  stopped working. So now I turn it on and it like sort of
Speaker 2:  spins, but not really. And then I get this error that
Speaker 2:  just says gimbal protection over and over and over again. I don't
Speaker 2:  know how to fix it. I think I know what's wrong. There's a spot that's a
Speaker 2:  little sticky, but the thing about these gimbal cameras is that they're so
Speaker 2:  delicate and so finicky. That's what makes them cool. It's what makes them
Speaker 2:  work. But it basically seems to have broken just because I like put
Speaker 2:  it in my bag and put a rolled up sweater on top of it.
Speaker 2:  Technology man. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna do two things. First, we're gonna talk about this weird sort
Speaker 2:  of run of bills and legislation that we've gotten in
Speaker 2:  Congress recently. All of a sudden, there's tons of momentum again on the
Speaker 2:  TikTok ban, on digital privacy legislation on ai.
Speaker 2:  So we're gonna try to figure out if any of this actually means anything.
Speaker 2:  And if any of this is ever actually likely to become law, then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna play you a bit of a conversation I had at the Chicago
Speaker 2:  Humanities Festival. I talked to two filmmakers who are also
Speaker 2:  the co-founders of an AI startup, which I just think is a fascinating tension.
Speaker 2:  What does it mean to be a creative person in this world
Speaker 2:  we live in right now while also trying to build AI tools
Speaker 2:  that threaten to totally upend the way that we do all of this
Speaker 2:  creative work? We had a really fun conversation. I wasn't planning on putting
Speaker 2:  it on this show, but I really enjoyed it and I think you might as well. All
Speaker 2:  of that is coming up in just a second. But I just watched a YouTube video
Speaker 2:  where basically the way to fix this gimbal is to shove a bunch of
Speaker 2:  post-it notes in here and you know I'll try anything at this
Speaker 2:  point. This is The Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right. My camera's broken, I think forever, but
Speaker 2:  my mic still works. So we soldier on. So we've learned over the last few
Speaker 2:  years to be, let's say skeptical, anytime there's a
Speaker 2:  new tech related bill moving through Congress, we get all these hearings
Speaker 2:  that turn out to be mostly just grandstanding and people trying to
Speaker 2:  score points that they can post on TikTok. We get bills that don't make
Speaker 2:  sense and go nowhere. We get bills that do make sense and go nowhere. And
Speaker 2:  so it feels like by and large we're left with decades old or
Speaker 2:  even centuries old laws and precedents trying to govern the
Speaker 2:  internet. It's not great. But recently there's a sense of momentum in
Speaker 2:  Congress that feels new. There's a new privacy bill that has some real
Speaker 2:  steam. There's a new take on the TikTok ban that is moving really fast and
Speaker 2:  there's even some AI legislation that seems to have at least an
Speaker 2:  outside shot of turning into something. But is any of this for
Speaker 2:  real? And if so, what's different now? Why is this all kind of happening
Speaker 2:  all at once? The verges, Lauren Finer has been covering all of these bills
Speaker 2:  and she is here to help us figure out what's next. Lauren Finer. Hello. Hi.
Speaker 2:  How are you?
Speaker 5:  Doing well,
Speaker 2:  Just another chill week in Lauren's life. Everything
Speaker 5:  Just a normal weekend.
Speaker 2:  I like this for you. Yeah, it's really rude of Congress to continue to do
Speaker 2:  things on weekends.
Speaker 5:  Seriously, this
Speaker 2:  Feels like they need to like go hang out with other people for a couple of
Speaker 2:  days and like give you a break.
Speaker 5:  Go socialize.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so we have a bunch of stuff to talk about, but I feel like the place
Speaker 2:  we should start is probably TikTok, because TikTok is like the thing
Speaker 2:  happening right this minute. So where we left off,
Speaker 2:  I would say on the show is the bill sort of flew through
Speaker 2:  the house subcommittee, flew through the house, hit the Senate, and
Speaker 2:  kind of disappeared. There was a lot of momentum and that all the momentum
Speaker 2:  died. And this was a few weeks ago. We have had a re momentum in, tell me
Speaker 2:  what's been going on. Catch me up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, basically like you said, we had this huge moment in the
Speaker 5:  house where they overwhelmingly passed this bill that could ban
Speaker 5:  TikTok unless it is divested from its Chinese parent
Speaker 5:  company, bite dance within six months. And then you know,
Speaker 5:  next it's on Senate, the Senate to move. And you know, we got a lot of kind
Speaker 5:  of non-committal responses from senators who were in
Speaker 5:  key positions there. So it kind of looked like maybe this thing is just gonna
Speaker 5:  like linger here until everyone kind of forgets about it and moves on.
Speaker 2:  What was your read on that by the way, before we even get to that, I, I found
Speaker 2:  myself wondering a bunch over the last couple of weeks why the Senate seemed
Speaker 2:  content to just let it go. I mean, you have President Biden saying he would
Speaker 2:  sign the law if it hit his desk. Tons of momentum in the
Speaker 2:  house. This thing was going crazy. Like lots of people even in the
Speaker 2:  house, Democrats were for it. Why was the Senate so happy to just sort of
Speaker 2:  let it wither and disappear?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think there's two things like one on just like the more political
Speaker 5:  side, you know, the house is a very different beast from the Senate.
Speaker 5:  The Senate is kind of a more deliberative body in a lot of ways. The house
Speaker 5:  is much larger, you can have a lot more like different personalities.
Speaker 2:  It was a very kind way of putting it by the way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I think like things that move in the house aren't necessarily the same
Speaker 5:  that are gonna move in the Senate. So you know, that's one thing. I think
Speaker 5:  a second thing is that I think there were real concerns with the earlier
Speaker 5:  version of the bill, particularly with the timeline for divestment. You know,
Speaker 5:  I think really, I don't think I really heard from many people at all
Speaker 5:  who thought that six months was a reasonable timeline to have this
Speaker 5:  giant s asset divested from this Chinese parent
Speaker 5:  company. So I think there were real concerns about that and you know,
Speaker 5:  potential constitutional concerns, free speech implications.
Speaker 5:  So I think there were still things that senators really wanted to ponder
Speaker 5:  and maybe hold hearings on and go through the regular process there.
Speaker 5:  So I, that's kind of how I think that was going down at the time.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that makes sense. Okay, so I derailed you so that all happens.
Speaker 2:  Brief pause, what happens next?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so then the house is trying to pass these foreign aid
Speaker 5:  bills basically directing, you know, military and humanitarian
Speaker 5:  aid to places like Israel, Ukraine, Gaza. And
Speaker 5:  so obviously this is something that is high priority in Congress and
Speaker 5:  House speaker Mike Johnson does something interesting and allows a new
Speaker 5:  version of this TikTok bill to get into
Speaker 5:  this foreign aid package. So, you know, I think anyone who
Speaker 5:  follows Congress might understand that a lot of times when we see bills
Speaker 5:  pass into law, it's through like a larger package that has
Speaker 5:  to pass like the National Defense Authorization Act or some
Speaker 5:  sort of, you know, budget for the government or things like that. So that's
Speaker 5:  kind of what happened here is it got packaged in with these bills that are
Speaker 5:  really high priority for Congress to pass. And
Speaker 5:  not only did they kind of bundle this all together, they also
Speaker 5:  changed the bill a little bit so that the timeline for divestment
Speaker 5:  was extended to basically up to a year. So it's really extended
Speaker 5:  to nine months initially. And then if the president sees that
Speaker 5:  there's progress on a deal, he has discretion to extend it essentially
Speaker 5:  another three months. Okay. So up to a year for this deal to be completed,
Speaker 5:  which seemed to kind of assuage a lot of the concerns
Speaker 5:  around it. In particular from senate commerce committee chair Maria
Speaker 5:  Cantwell who'd previously kind of not said anything really definitive
Speaker 5:  about how she felt on the bill, but afterwards said that she supported
Speaker 5:  the updated text of the legislation and that's significant because she
Speaker 5:  leads the committee that would, that under like a normal
Speaker 5:  process would have been considering this bill before it
Speaker 5:  hit the Senate floor.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. Talk me through the politics of the bundling of all of this
Speaker 2:  a little bit. Because like you said, this is the kind of thing that happens
Speaker 2:  relatively frequently that a bunch of bills that either have a little
Speaker 2:  bit to do with each other or nothing to do with each other end up in kind
Speaker 2:  of an all or nothing package. But what do you make of
Speaker 2:  kind of the way this was packaged back together and the way
Speaker 2:  it has sort of gone through this process again?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so I think, you know, like I said, there's kind of these two ways
Speaker 5:  that a bill can pass through Congress. One is that
Speaker 5:  it's packaged together with these other bills that, you know, Congress has
Speaker 5:  to make a decision on one way or another. You know, they can negotiate for
Speaker 5:  certain bills to get out of that must pass package. But
Speaker 5:  you know, there's a lot more politics there and like what are you really
Speaker 5:  gonna stake your ground on? And then the other way is to pass like standalone
Speaker 5:  bills like we saw the first time with this TikTok bill and you know,
Speaker 5:  that requires a lot of kind of resources from Congress in terms of floor
Speaker 5:  time. There's a lot of bills, a lot of legislative priorities that
Speaker 5:  are out there. And so for house leadership to make the
Speaker 5:  time for the TikTok bill as a standalone to get a
Speaker 5:  vote was a big deal in the first place.
Speaker 2:  That's one thing by the way that I think I have underrated in the past
Speaker 2:  with a lot of this stuff is just the sheer logistics
Speaker 2:  of passing a law like this is so much weirder and more complicated than it
Speaker 2:  gets credit for. And like you say, floor time and my brain just goes like,
Speaker 2:  oh right, there's only like so many hours in the day to stand there and talk
Speaker 2:  about these things and everybody, you have hundreds of people with wildly
Speaker 2:  different priorities. So literally just to like go through the time of
Speaker 2:  discussing this thing to get to a vote, you just can't do it with everything.
Speaker 2:  Totally.
Speaker 5:  I mean think about like everything that's like most important to you
Speaker 5:  politically and everything that's most important to like your parents politically
Speaker 5:  and all these people around you and like they could be, you know, in theory
Speaker 5:  equally important, but how do you decide what gets the time to
Speaker 5:  actually get a vote? So that's something that, you know, congress is always
Speaker 5:  juggling. So I think that's definitely right. It's a, it's a big deal. So
Speaker 5:  then packaging this with the other bills, you know, when it's a standalone
Speaker 5:  bill then it's on the Senate to decide when and how to move
Speaker 5:  and you know, that's really up in the air. It's pretty easy to
Speaker 5:  just like throw sand in the gears of Congress and just slow things down.
Speaker 5:  But with this package it kind of forces the
Speaker 5:  senate's hand in a certain way where it makes them have to figure out
Speaker 5:  like, are we going to, are we going to say like this is the issue
Speaker 5:  that makes us not vote for this foreign aid package that, you know, a lot
Speaker 5:  of senators really want. And you know, you have to think like
Speaker 5:  this is a bill that passed overwhelmingly in the house. It's
Speaker 5:  a pretty popular measure. So is that the thing that senators are
Speaker 5:  gonna kind of put their foot down on for why this like otherwise
Speaker 5:  popular and wanted package is not going to pass?
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah, I was, I was looking at it in the, I think the bill, I wrote
Speaker 2:  this down passed 360 to 58 in the house, which for the House of
Speaker 2:  Representatives in the country we live in right now is like pretty nuts to
Speaker 2:  get that broad of vote for just about anything at this
Speaker 2:  moment in time. Right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. And you know, it was interesting I think
Speaker 5:  during the debate around the bill New York Democrat Gregory Meeks,
Speaker 5:  who's the top democrat on the house Foreign Affairs Committee, he was saying
Speaker 5:  that he had opposed the earlier standalone TikTok bill.
Speaker 5:  He said quote out of concern that it would be a broad authorization that
Speaker 5:  could be misused far beyond what we in Washington are currently debating
Speaker 5:  beyond just TikTok. But you know, he was supporting this package of
Speaker 5:  legislation and said quote, the bill took a step
Speaker 5:  in the right direction with a more realistic timeframe for a complex divestiture
Speaker 5:  process. Let me say for the record that I believe this bill is about one
Speaker 5:  company that additional authorities provided to the executive branch
Speaker 5:  are to be interpreted narrowly. So you know, he's saying, you
Speaker 5:  know, look, I didn't really support this the first time around, but you know,
Speaker 5:  given that it's part of this larger package, I think it
Speaker 5:  it's a better bill than it was before. And if we interpret it narrowly like,
Speaker 5:  you know, I'm fine with it.
Speaker 2:  I feel like there are two ways to read that. And I'm curious, which you read
Speaker 2:  it as if, if either one or if there's something I'm missing. One is basically
Speaker 2:  like the Senate saying, oh God, we've lost, like we're sort of
Speaker 2:  forced to do this now. This foreign aid bill is important. We, we are
Speaker 2:  going to have to vote on this and letting this foreign aid bill
Speaker 2:  die at the hands of a TikTok ban is just not worth the fallout.
Speaker 2:  Which on, if, if that is the case, fairly brilliant
Speaker 2:  political machinations by Mike Johnson and the house, like kudos to them
Speaker 2:  for pulling off what seems like it might actually work. The other read is
Speaker 2:  that we have now debated this out long enough and, and we kind of know
Speaker 2:  where it's going and it seems increasingly clear that the end point is not
Speaker 2:  a ban, it is a sale, which makes it specific, right. That that becomes a
Speaker 2:  very unique thing because there just isn't anything else like that out there
Speaker 2:  right now. So everybody is able to just say, you know what, whatever the
Speaker 2:  law actually says, it is basically only going to apply to TikTok. Let's just
Speaker 2:  pass the thing and move on with our lives. Do you have a sense of which,
Speaker 2:  like is this, did the Senate get sort of, you know, outmaneuvered or
Speaker 2:  is there a sense that like we really can solve this problem the way that
Speaker 2:  we want to now?
Speaker 5:  I would tend to think it's more that, you know, we really can solve
Speaker 5:  this problem the way that we want to. Okay. 'cause I, I still go back to
Speaker 5:  the initial vote on this bill in the house was so
Speaker 5:  overwhelmingly in favor of this legislation, even with the six month
Speaker 5:  timeline. You know, to have that kind of broad support for something like
Speaker 5:  this really tells me that, you know, this is a popular
Speaker 5:  measure and you know, the people who are leading this legislation are saying,
Speaker 5:  you know, this is not a ban. We want divestment. That's our goal.
Speaker 5:  So I think that this is something that a lot of
Speaker 5:  lawmakers are really interested in and you know, we've seen
Speaker 5:  support for this sort of thing from the Senate Intel committee leaders.
Speaker 5:  Now you have the senate commerce committee leader on board. There's a lot
Speaker 5:  of support for doing something on TikTok in general and
Speaker 5:  you know, it seems like this is a way to do it that more
Speaker 5:  lawmakers are somewhat comfortable with.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I would just point out again that still it's been all this time and
Speaker 2:  we have yet to hear this unbelievably compelling evidence that supposedly
Speaker 2:  exists for why we have to ban TikTok. But we will leave that aside. I think
Speaker 2:  there, there, there really is the question of like, should we ban TikTok
Speaker 2:  and is it going to happen? And I think I assumed those two things
Speaker 2:  were were sort of gonna run together, but it really seems like at this point
Speaker 2:  we, it might happen. I it feels like the odds of this
Speaker 2:  bill becoming law are pretty high at this point. Like this thing is
Speaker 2:  moving fast and it seems like the momentum is gonna be pretty hard to slow
Speaker 2:  down. Right.
Speaker 5:  I would agree with that. Yeah. I mean I, I would go back to like, you
Speaker 5:  know, look at what this bill is situated within. It's this package
Speaker 5:  for foreign aid that's very popular. Is TikTok going to be the
Speaker 5:  thing that senators say, we're gonna like put our foot
Speaker 5:  down about getting this out of here.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. We don't want to help Ukraine because we don't wanna ban TikTok
Speaker 2:  is a, is a, it's a strange political maneuver for anyone to pull at this
Speaker 2:  moment in time. So what's next in this one? I think last time all
Speaker 2:  this happened, tons of momentum and then it died in the Senate. We are now
Speaker 2:  kind of back at that same spot again. Is it possible it's gonna
Speaker 2:  die in the Senate again?
Speaker 5:  I think this one's really different because you know, foreign aid is something
Speaker 5:  that is, has some time urgency behind it. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  the Senate was supposed to be off this week, but they're actually gonna,
Speaker 5:  you know, come in on their vacation. Aw. And they're going to
Speaker 5:  start doing some like process votes tomorrow. So from
Speaker 5:  what I've read, it seems like they could vote as soon as tomorrow and
Speaker 5:  as late as Wednesday on this measure.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Yeah. I should say we're talking on Monday morning and it's
Speaker 2:  like we have like a little less than 24 hours before this publishes and Lord
Speaker 2:  knows everything could change between now and then. But okay. Let's, let's
Speaker 2:  talk about some of the privacy stuff because I think the other thing that
Speaker 2:  you've been writing a bunch about is this new thing, the American Privacy
Speaker 2:  Rights Act. I went into the first story that you wrote about this in which
Speaker 2:  you were like, there's lots of momentum. People are excited this might actually
Speaker 2:  happen. Being like, aw Lauren, you've been, you've been scammed again into
Speaker 2:  believing that the American government is gonna pass privacy
Speaker 2:  legislation. But it seems like there is a, a sense that we're gonna
Speaker 2:  actually maybe get A real privacy law here at some point in the near future.
Speaker 2:  What is going on with this bill? Why is this the one so far?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, look, I mean when it comes to privacy, I'm never gonna say this is
Speaker 5:  definitely probably gonna happen because I think I've just
Speaker 5:  seen this so many times. Yeah. Over years of covering tech policy
Speaker 5:  where you get a bipartisan bill that seems like a pretty great
Speaker 5:  compromise and everyone's like, like at least happy enough and then it goes
Speaker 5:  nowhere. So I think this is one where we really gotta watch it till
Speaker 5:  the end. But there are some promising signs in this legislation
Speaker 5:  which you know, to be clear is still a discussion draft. It hasn't even been
Speaker 5:  formally introduced yet. But I think the most significant part of it
Speaker 5:  is just who's behind this bill? And that's the head
Speaker 5:  of the house Energy and Commerce committee. Kathy McMorris Rogers, who's
Speaker 5:  a Republican from Washington and the head of the Senate commerce committee
Speaker 5:  chair Maria Cantwell, who's a Democrat from Washington. Maria
Speaker 2:  Cantwell everywhere right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. Big
Speaker 2:  Month from Maria Cantwell.
Speaker 5:  It truly is. And I think her sponsorship is
Speaker 5:  the most significant here because last time around when we had
Speaker 5:  a bipartisan privacy bill in 2022, she
Speaker 5:  was not on board. And that seemed to be the thing that ultimately kind of
Speaker 5:  like slowed down momentum behind this bill that had a lot of
Speaker 5:  bipartisan supporters. It passed overwhelmingly out of the house Energy and
Speaker 5:  commerce committee and then just kind of died off. So I think
Speaker 5:  that's really what's most significant here and what's giving people the most,
Speaker 5:  you know, hope that maybe we could see something this time around.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So I, I feel like, I don't know, I don't know what the, what the like
Speaker 2:  least optimistic it is possible to be while still being optimistic. You
Speaker 2:  know what I mean? You're like, you're like at a, we're at a sort of one outta
Speaker 2:  10 on the optimism scale, but we're, we we're at least somewhere and I feel
Speaker 2:  like there is, there is, there's possibility that this could happen. What
Speaker 2:  about this bill jumps out to you? It seems like I, I was reading through
Speaker 2:  it and there's a bunch of stuff that sounds a lot like what we have in the
Speaker 2:  eu, this idea of transparency and you should be able to control your own
Speaker 2:  data and you should know where it's going. Some of the stuff that's going
Speaker 2:  on in California with the California Privacy Act that went in
Speaker 2:  2018 I think it was. And then again in 2020, what's in this
Speaker 2:  bill that jumped out to you? Anything particularly interesting?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think the thing that stands out the most is the enforcement mechanisms
Speaker 5:  behind the bill because that's something that Senator Cantwell said that,
Speaker 5:  you know, was kind of a sticking point for her with the earlier privacy bill.
Speaker 5:  The A-D-P-P-A. These all have really complicated acronyms
Speaker 5:  and so this bill basically would let
Speaker 5:  individuals sue companies that they feel like have violated
Speaker 5:  their privacy rights. But it would also give companies a chance
Speaker 5:  to correct the things that they're being told they did
Speaker 5:  wrong. So, you know, that's kind of a way to try and balance,
Speaker 5:  you know, a really strong enforcement mechanism that also, you know,
Speaker 5:  kicks in pretty quickly. Consumers can, you know, sue pretty quickly,
Speaker 5:  but also gives companies a chance to correct any mistakes before
Speaker 5:  getting bogged down with lawsuits.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's really interesting. 'cause in the past a lot of the enforcement
Speaker 2:  for this has been kind of hand wavy and some somebody
Speaker 2:  will figure it out, we'll set up an agency kind of thing. And
Speaker 2:  this seems like it was much more directed like who will be in charge of this
Speaker 2:  and what they can do and the penalties will be real. Like even
Speaker 2:  just reading through, there's this like eight page summary of it. I got the
Speaker 2:  sense that like this is, this felt like a real thing more than just sort
Speaker 2:  of some ideas that somebody wrote down.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's right. I think, you know, enforcement was really a key
Speaker 5:  issue for Senator Cantwell, so I think it's not too surprising to see that
Speaker 5:  that was an area that they seemed to spend a lot of time on.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. Is there anything we've learned do you think, from the
Speaker 2:  EU and California? Like tho those are the two that I, I just kept seeing
Speaker 2:  inside of this bill and, and the, I went back and re-read the California
Speaker 2:  one and it even uses a lot of the same terms right, about being able to
Speaker 2:  correct info about you that's online, that's wrong. Having
Speaker 2:  the right to opt out, they can't discriminate against you if they opt out.
Speaker 2:  There's also just like a weird thing all of a sudden in the middle that just
Speaker 2:  says civil rights and algorithms, which felt like a total sort of random
Speaker 2:  detour in the middle of a data privacy legislation. But I thought that was
Speaker 2:  very interesting. I don't know, does it feel like the Congress is sort
Speaker 2:  of learning from what has worked and passed elsewhere? I mean I, I, I use
Speaker 2:  worked in a very kind of loose way because none of it seems to really be
Speaker 2:  working, but at least what has actually been passed into law elsewhere.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think like at a high level there's been a shift from this
Speaker 5:  like notice and consent framework that's basically like,
Speaker 5:  you know, we're gonna tell consumers, you know, what sort of information
Speaker 5:  we're collecting and then you click yes and then we collect it,
Speaker 2:  Which accomplishes nothing. Right? I really believe that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Or and shifted more to this idea of data minimization,
Speaker 5:  which is like, let's like limit how much data is collected in the first place
Speaker 5:  and you have to have a really compelling reason for why you need this information
Speaker 5:  to run your service. And so I think that's something that's reflected in
Speaker 5:  this bill.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's really interesting. Who are they going after with this bill?
Speaker 2:  Have we gotten a sense yet? I mean they have some basic outlines here.
Speaker 2:  I think it's like if you have more than 5 million users
Speaker 2:  in the US or over $250 million in revenue, it's, it's clearly
Speaker 2:  a, this is pushed at big companies especially, right? It talk,
Speaker 2:  it talks a lot about data brokers, but it seems like the companies most affected
Speaker 2:  by this are going to be like the handful of big tech platforms. Like
Speaker 2:  who do you think this is really aimed at?
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. I think, you know, there is concern in congress about,
Speaker 5:  you know, overly burdening small companies and startups
Speaker 5:  and that kind of feeds into these other questions about competition and
Speaker 5:  you know, concerns there. So I think there is an awareness that congress
Speaker 5:  doesn't want to overburden small businesses. So I
Speaker 5:  think large companies are really ones that will be targeted here.
Speaker 5:  And data brokers, it seems like there's, you know, this growing awareness
Speaker 5:  in Congress about how data brokers can move
Speaker 5:  information around, you know, around the time of the original TikTok
Speaker 5:  legislation we saw a separate bill in the house pass around data
Speaker 5:  brokers and you know, sales of US data to foreign adversaries.
Speaker 5:  So I think that's something that is really on lawmakers minds
Speaker 5:  these days.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So like you mentioned, we've, we've seen this a few times. Bills come
Speaker 2:  out that there is some enthusiasm about what
Speaker 2:  normally happens. Like where in the process does a privacy bill usually
Speaker 2:  die?
Speaker 5:  In the past it's been, you know, with the A-D-P-P-A, which was the
Speaker 5:  last time we had a comprehensive privacy bill that had
Speaker 5:  bipartisan support.
Speaker 2:  And that was two years ago, is that
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah, I believe that was in 2022. You know, it passed pretty
Speaker 5:  strongly out of the house Energy and commerce committee and then that was
Speaker 5:  it. So that's the point where we see these things slowed down.
Speaker 5:  I think what's significant here is we have both of the chairs who
Speaker 5:  are in power in their committees on the house and Senate side
Speaker 5:  who are going to be able to move this bill if they want, assuming they
Speaker 5:  can get the votes in their committee. So, you know, we could at this point
Speaker 5:  see both the Senate Commerce Committee and the House Energy and Commerce
Speaker 5:  committee pass this bill once it's introduced and then
Speaker 5:  it'll be up to house and senate leaders to
Speaker 5:  determine again, do they give this bill time on the floor,
Speaker 5:  do they package it in some other legislation? So I think that will be
Speaker 5:  kind of the next point to look out for. And of course, you know, before all
Speaker 5:  that happens, we have to make sure that there's support enough support in
Speaker 5:  the committees for these bills. But I think there really is, you know,
Speaker 5:  widespread support in congress for comprehensive privacy
Speaker 5:  legislation overall. So I, I think, you know, there
Speaker 5:  is some, at least a good amount of political will there.
Speaker 2:  Do you make anything of the timing connection with all of the TikTok
Speaker 2:  stuff? Like are these two things that are happening simultaneously
Speaker 2:  on purpose?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I mean it's a great question. I'm not sure if it's like, you know,
Speaker 5:  on purpose in the sense that they were, you know, moved at this time
Speaker 5:  because of the TikTok legislation. But I think,
Speaker 5:  you know, all of this is kind of like percolating around congress and
Speaker 5:  I think it makes sense in a way that we would start to see privacy
Speaker 5:  legislation come out. You know, when we saw the house vote on the
Speaker 5:  standalone TikTok bill, reporters were asking
Speaker 5:  house committee leaders about, well what about privacy? Because that's
Speaker 5:  something that kind of like underlies a lot of these conversations in the
Speaker 5:  first place. And I, I think I remember Mick Morris Rogers
Speaker 5:  actually kind of saying like, you know, we're still working on that. And
Speaker 5:  at the time I remember thinking like, okay, sure, like, like
Speaker 5:  yeah, we're gonna go back. Maybe they're gonna reintroduce the A DPA, something
Speaker 5:  like that. But then we got this totally new bill with Senator
Speaker 5:  Cantwell and that was kind of a moment of, well okay, maybe
Speaker 5:  some of this has been really happening behind the scenes. So
Speaker 5:  yeah, I think, you know, it is significant that privacy is
Speaker 5:  something that kind of underpins a lot of the other conversations we have
Speaker 5:  around tech policy. But you know, I, I think
Speaker 5:  things often in Congress just move when you can get the political will to
Speaker 5:  do them
Speaker 2:  Well. And that's I think kind of the big open question still to me is,
Speaker 2:  is this moment different in that respect than we've had before? Right. I
Speaker 2:  think the privacy thing in general is so tricky because there is
Speaker 2:  this sort of intellectual understanding that I think most people have come
Speaker 2:  to where we all kind of know there's
Speaker 2:  too much information about us out there and it's bad
Speaker 2:  that there is too much access to it and we kind of have no control over it
Speaker 2:  and it sort of feels intellectually weird. But knowing
Speaker 2:  what that is and what to do about it and what the sort of downstream ramifications
Speaker 2:  are is just complicated enough that
Speaker 2:  it has never really felt like anyone's first priority. It's just kind of
Speaker 2:  a thing that lingers at the back of everybody's mind. But then part of me
Speaker 2:  wonders a, with TikTok becoming this very visceral
Speaker 2:  outpouring of what it looks like when a platform knows you very well, that
Speaker 2:  is one thing that I think has like maybe made it more present
Speaker 2:  to people what's really going on here. But then I also just wonder if this
Speaker 2:  is yet another kind of lark from people
Speaker 2:  who, there's just a, a kind of chorus of folks in Congress who are like,
Speaker 2:  we need privacy legislation. And everybody goes, I agree. And then just kind
Speaker 2:  of goes off to other priorities. But it sounds like even maybe just from
Speaker 2:  like conversations you're having that at least
Speaker 2:  it's moving up the priority list. It might not be the top thing, but at the
Speaker 2:  very least it is a thing people are willingly
Speaker 2:  talking about instead of just sort of waving their hands at and saying, we'll
Speaker 2:  get to that eventually. Is that, is that how it feels just to talk to people
Speaker 2:  right now? I
Speaker 5:  Think basically, I think, you know, I didn't necessarily
Speaker 5:  anticipate that we would get a real conversation around comprehensive
Speaker 5:  privacy this year. You know, it's an election year. I mean
Speaker 2:  There's a lot going on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I think there is this sense that, you know,
Speaker 5:  maybe, maybe this is the time, but you know, I'm hesitant to say that
Speaker 5:  because it's felt like that in the past. But I think there's a certain way
Speaker 5:  you could look at this and say, maybe it would be kind of a good look for
Speaker 5:  Congress to pass a comprehensive privacy bill if they're also passing this
Speaker 5:  TikTok legislation since, you know, I think when TikTok
Speaker 5:  CEO came to testify, some people are talking about, well, aren't all
Speaker 5:  of these problems just like problems with privacy on platforms in
Speaker 5:  general? And some of them are. So I think in a way it would
Speaker 5:  be kind of a good look for Congress to pass comprehensive privacy reform
Speaker 5:  alongside something like that. Is that going to be enough to push them over
Speaker 5:  the edge? You know, I think that's anyone's guess, but at least it
Speaker 5:  seems like these conversations are really happening in a real
Speaker 5:  tangible way, again, around an actual piece of legislation.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree. I think my, my guess is we are a ways away from
Speaker 2:  having an answer to that one, but I think it's gonna be fascinating, especially
Speaker 2:  in an election year when so many people are talking about tech. I think it's,
Speaker 2:  it's gonna come up maybe more than it has even at kind of
Speaker 2:  hot moments in the past. It's gonna be really interesting. Before I let you
Speaker 2:  go, the last one I just wanna touch on briefly is the future of
Speaker 2:  AI Innovation Act, which is another thing that is sort of in the air
Speaker 2:  everybody's talking about, but it's not necessarily exactly clear
Speaker 2:  where we are headed with this. Tell me a little bit about the, the future
Speaker 2:  of AI Innovation Act. What are we doing here?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so this is a bill that was introduced by a bunch
Speaker 5:  of senators that have been involved in AI discussions. Again, we have Senator
Speaker 5:  Cantwell
Speaker 2:  Cantwell man.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We have Senator Todd Young who has been involved
Speaker 5:  in some of the bipartisan work with Senator
Speaker 5:  Schumer around ai. So this bill would basically,
Speaker 5:  it's basically about creating standards around AI
Speaker 5:  and just, you know, spurring innovation. So, you know, it's not really dealing
Speaker 5:  with some of these like nitty gritty issues that we're thinking about with
Speaker 5:  like copyright and things like that. But it's really about just trying to
Speaker 5:  like create a framework for AI to be developed
Speaker 5:  in a safe way and also for innovation to take place.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So this is one of those bills that is like, let's, let's make a plan
Speaker 2:  to make a plan kind of thing. And you have to write that in a very, and I,
Speaker 2:  that feels small when I say it, but there was like, there was that executive
Speaker 2:  order from the White House, which was like a plan to make a plan to make
Speaker 2:  a plan. This is at least like a plan to make a plan. So we're like, we're
Speaker 2:  like inching towards a plan. Yeah, it's, it's
Speaker 5:  Something. Yeah. Yeah, I mean it's certainly a start. I mean I think AI is
Speaker 5:  such a huge issue that that touches on so many different areas that
Speaker 5:  it's hard to imagine just like one piece of legislation being the be all
Speaker 5:  end all of this. So, you know, it's certainly, it, it's a reasonable place
Speaker 5:  to start, I would say. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I still remember the Benedict Evans, who the back when he was a venture capitalist
Speaker 2:  always had this line that we don't regulate cars, we regulate parts of cars,
Speaker 2:  which I think is very smart. And I think AI is gonna end up being the same
Speaker 2:  way. Like instead of if we try to regulate AI as a thing,
Speaker 2:  it's just gonna, it'll never work. And I feel like to some extent we've run
Speaker 2:  into this with, with privacy in the internet. Like we try to regulate the
Speaker 2:  whole internet all at once and it's just impossible. But it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  we can regulate seat belts and we can regulate steering wheels and we can
Speaker 2:  regulate carburetors and we can regulate gas mileage. And it's like that's
Speaker 2:  maybe what we do with ai and this feels like, you know, setting up the,
Speaker 2:  what is it called, the Artificial Intelligence Safety Institute, I think
Speaker 2:  is like, okay, you need a group that is like in charge of looking
Speaker 2:  at this. And that's not anything, but it is a step towards something. And
Speaker 2:  that I sort of appreciate as a, as a way of saying like, okay,
Speaker 2:  AI is too big for one bill that we shove into a foreign aid package.
Speaker 2:  Let's let's start somewhere else.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Also, I think there's certain things that, you know, the
Speaker 5:  American people would probably rather see a specialized agency looking
Speaker 5:  at rather than congress just going ahead and dictating a bunch of rules.
Speaker 5:  So I think that is a significant step.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, fair enough. Alright, well here's hoping that you at least get a weekend
Speaker 2:  next weekend, but Lord only knows this TikTok thing is just gonna keep happening.
Speaker 2:  So I I suspect we will be talking again sooner rather than later.
Speaker 5:  Yes, I'm sure.
Speaker 2:  Awesome. Thanks Lauren. Appreciate it.
Speaker 5:  Thanks David.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. A couple of weeks ago, The Verge did a series of panels
Speaker 2:  at the Chicago Humanities Festival, all about AI and creativity.
Speaker 2:  Our big question basically was what does it mean to be a creative
Speaker 2:  person in a world filled with ai? And how is AI changing
Speaker 2:  the lives and livelihoods of creative people? We had three
Speaker 2:  really fun conversations and I just wanna play you a chunk of mine. I got
Speaker 2:  on stage with Ty Sheridan, who's an actor you might know as Wade Watts, the
Speaker 2:  protagonist in Ready Player one or from movies like X-Men Apocalypse in
Speaker 2:  the Show Wireless along with Nikola Tvi, who is a writer and a
Speaker 2:  visual effects artist. Ty and Nikola are friends, they're collaborators.
Speaker 2:  And as of a few years ago, they're co-founders. They started a company called
Speaker 2:  Wonder Dynamics that brings a bunch of really cool AI tools to the visual
Speaker 2:  effects business. Basically imagine you film a real
Speaker 2:  scene and with like three button clicks you can comp
Speaker 2:  over a regular person and turn it into an animated character.
Speaker 2:  Visual effects with essentially the touch of a button. It's pretty cool.
Speaker 2:  So both Tie and Nikola are right in the center of this really
Speaker 2:  complicated AI moment. So I wanted to talk to them about how they
Speaker 2:  think about ai, how they're trying to build a company, how human
Speaker 2:  creativity and AI can work together and lots more. We had a really good
Speaker 2:  time chatting actually, and I learned a lot so I thought I'd just play you
Speaker 2:  a bit of that conversation. Let's do it.
Speaker 7:  Hello everybody.
Speaker 2:  So I wanna start by telling the story of Wonder Dynamics.
Speaker 7:  Well, we had originally started developing shows together, so Nico and I
Speaker 7:  were both dabbling writing and you know, Nico had had directed it several
Speaker 7:  films and they showed me, I thought he was a really talented filmmaker and
Speaker 7:  obviously a really smart guy. And we just became kind of pals through our,
Speaker 7:  our mutual love of movies and storytelling. And we had started developing
Speaker 7:  a a, a series that had kind of a, it was like, had an interactive
Speaker 7:  element to it and, and, and there wasn't really a technology that existed.
Speaker 7:  So we just kind of built a prototype and that was really the beginning of
Speaker 7:  us getting into technology.
Speaker 8:  It's really the writing that started it. We, we, we wrote a project that
Speaker 8:  we wanted say, and this is gonna sound super meta, but it was about robotics,
Speaker 8:  right? So we're writing this sci-fi series that we wanted to make. And
Speaker 8:  every time you write something as an indie person especially, you have to
Speaker 8:  think about how do I cut my script to afford it? 'cause you can't go out
Speaker 8:  and write dune and hope to get it funded, right? As a, as a
Speaker 8:  filmmaker that hasn't proven itself, especially in visual effects. Most indie
Speaker 8:  filmmakers and visual effects stay away from visual effects and CG 'cause
Speaker 8:  it's so expensive, right? Every single scene or shot you add that has a visual
Speaker 8:  effects element add so much more to your budget and you can't really
Speaker 8:  afford it. So China really started like that. We, we, we, we wrote this and
Speaker 8:  we realized, okay, this would cost about $150 million to make and there's
Speaker 8:  no way we can get that money. And so we started looking at technology, but
Speaker 8:  funny enough we were studying technology as we were riding and it really,
Speaker 8:  this started, you know, from us going really deep in robotics
Speaker 8:  and self-driving cars technology, which is all about understanding the world
Speaker 8:  and space around you, right? That's, that's movement of a GI, which is the
Speaker 8:  computer vision. It's like understanding what a chair is, understanding how
Speaker 8:  much distance I have from something. So that's how it started. Then we started
Speaker 8:  getting deeper, deeper into it and then we started building the tech and
Speaker 8:  realized, okay, this is a bit bigger than just our movies. Let's turn it
Speaker 8:  into a platform and let's really start a company to be focused towards that.
Speaker 8:  And then we'll make our movies down the line. But we, we, we were lucky that
Speaker 8:  we discovered it early before Gene tv I was even a thing we'd
Speaker 8:  internally call it visual ai. There was no, there was no term at the time
Speaker 8:  and we knew it was gonna be. So we built in stealth mode for about close
Speaker 8:  to four years.
Speaker 2:  Just real quick, give me the like 15 second explanation of what Wonder
Speaker 2:  Studio does right now, just for folks who haven't seen it before. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  So essentially if you have seen movies like Avatar, you always have this
Speaker 8:  motion capture suits, the people performing, and then you have a lot of equipment
Speaker 8:  you need to do on set to pick up that data, performance data, et cetera.
Speaker 8:  So we essentially sped up that process and, and let
Speaker 8:  you extract your scene in a 3D space so you can get your performance
Speaker 8:  capture your camera move, capture your lighting capture and get to your final
Speaker 8:  VFX shot much, much quicker than traditional. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The, the demo I've seen is basically it's like a, a person coming out
Speaker 2:  of, I think it's a library or something sort of coming down the stairs of
Speaker 2:  the building and then it wipes and all of a sudden it's, it's a cartoon character
Speaker 2:  doing the same movements in the same place the same way as, and, and you're
Speaker 2:  essentially like automating that out of having tie
Speaker 2:  wear a mocap suit, which I'm assuming is not a lot of fun by the way.
Speaker 7:  It depends on how sweaty you are. You know, if you're a naturally sweaty
Speaker 7:  person, no, it's not that much fun. Fair enough. Also, those volumes,
Speaker 7:  you know, they have all the infrared cameras and sensors in there, they're
Speaker 7:  very warm, so Yeah. Yeah. And the extremely,
Speaker 8:  Extremely expensive as very expensive. That's why you have a lot of, you
Speaker 8:  know, 99% of filmmakers cannot afford production side of things, but post-production
Speaker 8:  is really where, where it gets gets extremely, extremely expensive. Right?
Speaker 8:  So that, that was our mission is like how do we get indie filmmakers to have
Speaker 8:  access to this, which traditionally has always been reserved to high budgets
Speaker 8:  and big studios.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and I think the timing that you guys were dealing with is really
Speaker 2:  interesting because on the one hand you got this massive technical
Speaker 2:  development, right? Like the, the state of the art and everything you're
Speaker 2:  talking about has gone up exponentially over the last few years. On the other
Speaker 2:  hand, we're now talking about this stuff in a cultural way.
Speaker 2:  Like we've been doing all day in a very different way than we were before.
Speaker 2:  You have access to, you know, mountains of data that comes
Speaker 2:  from, in some cases artists who would prefer that their data not be there.
Speaker 2:  And so I'm, I'm really curious as you guys were thinking about like product
Speaker 2:  building especially coming from this sort of creative background. Like what,
Speaker 2:  what should we build? What can we build? Like sort of where, where
Speaker 2:  does the right answer for something like this begin and end? Like are those
Speaker 2:  conversations you're having
Speaker 8:  Ly? Yeah, a lot. Yeah, A lot. And especially from beginning I think we're
Speaker 8:  in a different situation because you know, obviously we've been super fortunate
Speaker 8:  to have some leaders in a space like Joe Ruso, Steven Spielberg, and others
Speaker 8:  who've been on our board obviously ties an actor. So we spent a lot of time
Speaker 8:  and I was a visual effects artist and a supervisor. So
Speaker 8:  we purposely from day one build it with, we're not gonna be
Speaker 8:  generating art, which is gonna extract information, we call it
Speaker 8:  observing nature. So we're observing how the actor is moving and performing.
Speaker 8:  It's still driven by a, by a shot from a cinematographer.
Speaker 8:  The character is still built by an artist. So we are very different than
Speaker 8:  a lot of gen AI companies that you see, which, which are generating pixels
Speaker 8:  by other art for us, you mostly get information in that 3D space. So
Speaker 8:  we're not, not really producing art, we're speeding you up and giving you
Speaker 8:  that scene in 3D space so you can manipulate it. So, and also you'll never
Speaker 8:  see us replace the actor with another human. We only
Speaker 8:  are driving characters that don't exist in the real world. So that's a little
Speaker 8:  bit of a, you know, a thing we had to stop ourself a lot of time. 'cause
Speaker 8:  you get, you get very driven with this innovation and you can,
Speaker 8:  you can go that route and say, you know, I'm, I'm just gonna build, I'm gonna
Speaker 8:  build whatever I want, right? Because I can with this technology. But I think
Speaker 8:  for us it was really important to be ethical in that it's one of those things
Speaker 8:  in a tech company, we call ourself a story company first. 'cause this is
Speaker 8:  a technology to help storytellers, right? A story will
Speaker 8:  always come first for us. So, you know, it is a tough one.
Speaker 8:  It's one of those things that we have a lot of our users that say like, you're
Speaker 8:  one of the, you know, rare ethically built company around this. But
Speaker 8:  it's tough because you do have to pull back for innovation. There's a lot
Speaker 8:  of stuff we've done research internally, right, that we had to pull
Speaker 8:  back a little bit. We've been having this conversation for a long time. We've
Speaker 8:  been telling people three years ago, you know, AI and visual effects is coming.
Speaker 8:  You know, educate yourself. This change is gonna seem extremely drastic
Speaker 8:  overnight, but it's not overnight. This research has been going on in academia,
Speaker 8:  you know, Ivy League schools for, for, for decades now, right? It's just
Speaker 8:  that we are now seeing it extremely accelerated and a lot of innovation you
Speaker 8:  see that comes out, gets viral. It's not from yesterday. It's been built
Speaker 8:  on top on top on top right on that side. So, you know, I, I think
Speaker 8:  the conversation is getting more serious now about, you
Speaker 8:  know, these moral issues for us. I don't
Speaker 8:  think we should see the future where we don't have people on set,
Speaker 8:  we don't have artists working on it, but just someone kind of typing away.
Speaker 8:  I do think it will happen. We wanna be a part of the good side
Speaker 8:  of that story, which is you always gonna have performance arts, you always
Speaker 8:  gonna, I think a lot of people underestimate how hard this thing is. Not
Speaker 8:  ai, I'm talking generally filmmaking. It's extremely hard. All of these
Speaker 8:  artists have incredible high skill sets of that, right?
Speaker 8:  It takes decades to learn some of these things and some of these tools, how
Speaker 8:  to use them properly. So I think this kind of promise, it's
Speaker 8:  one click solution promise, it's a one line away. We're not there yet. I'm
Speaker 8:  talking AI general, not us. Yeah. So I think, I don't think we're gonna replace
Speaker 8:  artists, all of these actors, you know, overnight. I don't think us, I think
Speaker 8:  people will try, they will try, but I think us as audience members, we
Speaker 8:  love that human connection. I don't think all of a sudden everybody's gonna
Speaker 8:  be, you know, I don't have a favorite actor anymore because all the actors
Speaker 8:  I watch are ai, right? I don't think that's gonna happen. Right? So I think
Speaker 8:  that human connection is really important. Sometimes we like art we watch
Speaker 8:  because of the meaning put by a person behind it,
Speaker 8:  not generated something. So I think if you ask me where the future's gonna
Speaker 8:  go, I think it's gonna be combination. There's gonna be some prompt thing
Speaker 8:  that's gonna be a part of it. There's gonna be performance art that's gonna
Speaker 8:  be a part of it, right? Because it's very, think of it this way, we always
Speaker 8:  say this, how do you describe a performance with words?
Speaker 8:  It's very hard. That's why we have directors that say cut five times or
Speaker 8:  I joke title always 20 times with him, right? So 30. But
Speaker 8:  some things we cannot, even, even body movement, we don't have English word
Speaker 8:  for some body movements, right? So I think the performance art will always
Speaker 8:  be there, especially in these, in these kind of cases. So, but let's see
Speaker 8:  where we go is IIII always say it's important that these tools
Speaker 8:  are also built with people in the industry. 'cause if we just let it go on
Speaker 8:  a tech side, it's a very different goal. It's a goal of lemme
Speaker 8:  build a tool that's used by talkers in billions in numbers
Speaker 8:  so I can get higher value for my company, right? I say we need to
Speaker 8:  build alongside artist community. 'cause if you put an artist be behind building
Speaker 8:  something, they will think about it because they'll think about it from their
Speaker 8:  perspective as well.
Speaker 2:  Ty, one of the things you were saying when we were talking the other day
Speaker 2:  that I've been thinking a lot about since is the, the question of basically
Speaker 2:  the upside of these tools is that it gives access to the kind of creative
Speaker 2:  process to more people who, for reasons of
Speaker 2:  money or accessibility or literally where they live in the world,
Speaker 2:  they just couldn't make Hollywood movies, right? Like Hollywood was a, a
Speaker 2:  small group of people in a small place that did this stuff. And now we're
Speaker 2:  getting to the point where these tools and these platforms and these audiences
Speaker 2:  are available to many more people. And I think that's awesome. And I think
Speaker 2:  like anything that I think so gets us there is really great. Is there a
Speaker 2:  flip side to that? Like is is if we democratize all of this stuff
Speaker 2:  and make it all so automated that anybody can use it? I think that's very
Speaker 2:  cool. And also just it feels like it changes what that stuff is in a way
Speaker 2:  that I haven't quite sorted out in my
Speaker 7:  Brain. I think it increases our potential to find original voices. You know,
Speaker 7:  I think what happens when you have a group of people that are surrounded
Speaker 7:  by like-minded individuals, they start to think the same things. It's the
Speaker 7:  same with Hollywood. You know, you have people, you know in one place. It's
Speaker 7:  a very localized industry. And if you want to get a project greenlit, that's
Speaker 7:  where you have to go. You have to go to the executives that are in Hollywood.
Speaker 7:  And I think this
Speaker 2:  Is why we get 600 Marvel movies every day. That's
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So I I I think for us, like, you know, that was the real
Speaker 7:  exciting mission with, with, with our company and the exciting potential
Speaker 7:  is that hey, some, some, a group of kids growing up in
Speaker 7:  the middle of, of, you know, some small town in in Norway or Kenya can,
Speaker 7:  can go out and make a science fiction film that, you know, today it could
Speaker 7:  only be made in Hollywood and do it on a budget. And that's super exciting
Speaker 7:  for us because we don't know where the next James Cameron or Steven Spielberg's
Speaker 7:  gonna come from, you know? And I think giving, you know, thinking even about
Speaker 7:  us, you know, not having a lot of tools growing up, I mean, we would die
Speaker 7:  to have stuff like the tools like this. And I'm not even just saying what,
Speaker 7:  what we're building, but I think the tools that are, that are coming, you
Speaker 7:  know, this, this next generation of filmmakers, I I do, I think the biggest
Speaker 7:  potential there is really to discover original voices and, and yeah. And
Speaker 7:  to, to kind of pave a new path for, for storytelling. And I think
Speaker 7:  Hollywood traditionally prides itself on, you know, stories of
Speaker 7:  inclusivity and, and trying to recognize certain
Speaker 7:  cultures or, or, or, or people that are maybe misunderstood or
Speaker 7:  underrepresented. And I think the way to, to truly do that in, in,
Speaker 7:  in the best and most authentic way is, is to really democratize the tools
Speaker 7:  and, and allow people from all walks of life to go and make these films regardless
Speaker 7:  of their socioeconomical status. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It also makes me think that maybe rather than like, you know, your your
Speaker 2:  close personal friend Steven Spielberg making tons of movies with all
Speaker 2:  of these new tools very soon what actually might happen is that like
Speaker 2:  YouTubers and tiktoks and the people who are making this stuff who have
Speaker 2:  never had access to these kinds of tools at any cost might be able to
Speaker 2:  do this kind of stuff. Like, one thing I've been thinking a lot about is,
Speaker 2:  is dubbing, which is a thing that is AI is all over, like text to speech
Speaker 2:  is starting to get really good speech to text is starting to get really good.
Speaker 2:  And the idea that you could have something that you make that is actually
Speaker 2:  localized successfully in two languages all over the world, I think is
Speaker 2:  very cool and, and super exciting. And we're a long way from the tech of
Speaker 2:  that being sort of perfect. But it's already like the stuff that
Speaker 2:  Squid game was a couple of years ago where you see their mouth moving and
Speaker 2:  you hear the words and they're obviously different. Those two things are
Speaker 2:  coming closer together. And I think that's very,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's also from an actor's perspective,
Speaker 8:  You just revealed, you watched the US version and ethics, so the squid games
Speaker 8:  come on, you have to watch. I
Speaker 2:  Did. I'm not proud of Thatit. Listen, you
Speaker 8:  Gotta watch original with the stuffed
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean from, from, from an actor's perspective, do you, you know, you
Speaker 7:  really want someone else in some other country dubbing your voice in a,
Speaker 7:  in a foreign language. I mean, I I would rather,
Speaker 8:  It's a whole different panel now. We're getting in a whole different panel
Speaker 8:  now.
Speaker 7:  No, I think this No, think it's a good, it's a, it's a, it's a good example.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I think, you know, we can recognize where, you know, AI is start,
Speaker 7:  is starting to be used, you know, to in, in, in some ways to stay true
Speaker 7:  to the performance of, of, of the artist, the original artist. And I think,
Speaker 7:  I think that's awesome. I mean, obviously I, I have a biased perspective
Speaker 7:  probably being an actor, but, well,
Speaker 2:  But, and again, this is like, I've realized a lot of what I'm gonna do here
Speaker 2:  is just like throw weird tensions at you and make you sort them out in front
Speaker 2:  of me. But the thing that I struggle with on that one is like, they're doing
Speaker 2:  this a lot with podcasts too, right? And I host a podcast and we, we get
Speaker 2:  a lot of people who are like, I, I don't speak English. I would like to listen
Speaker 2:  to your stupid podcast. Can I do that? And there are companies out there
Speaker 2:  that are like, we will automatically w you into 60 languages. And on the
Speaker 2:  one hand, super cool. On the other hand, I, I don't know if
Speaker 2:  they're good or I'm going to say what is right. Like, so it,
Speaker 2:  it, there's, it sort of crosses this invisible line where I go from like,
Speaker 2:  oh, access is awesome to like, this feels weird because it's, you're
Speaker 2:  now no longer getting the thing that I did. And that somewhere in there it
Speaker 2:  just starts to, it starts to feel odd.
Speaker 8:  There's definitely those lines. But I think what you were saying earlier
Speaker 8:  is what I think is gonna happen, right? I don't think studios are gonna have
Speaker 8:  issues. I think what the people don't realize, there's so much sacrifice
Speaker 8:  on every project we see, turning things from page to screen is really, really
Speaker 8:  hard. There's always a lot of sacrifice that comes from it. So I think studios
Speaker 8:  are just gonna keep pushing things higher. But I think indie filmmakers,
Speaker 8:  as you mentioned, like, you know, YouTubers, if you remember the days when
Speaker 8:  you know DSLRs came out, right? And you have, people are saying,
Speaker 8:  oh my God, everybody's gonna be able to make a movie now, right? With it.
Speaker 8:  But that doesn't mean those movies were necessarily great because storytelling
Speaker 8:  is, is still hard. Coming up with a good story is still extremely hard,
Speaker 8:  right? So we're gonna open access with these innovations and AI right
Speaker 8:  across the board, which is really exciting. I think what YouTube did, and
Speaker 8:  I always say this, YouTube is a good example of distribution changing, right?
Speaker 8:  So we had open distribution. I think what's happening now with
Speaker 8:  generative AI is that we're changing production. So open production,
Speaker 8:  right? So meaning these kids could come up and express themself and put on
Speaker 8:  YouTube and if they're good people like them, they will find them. Right?
Speaker 8:  There's billions of people watching it. I think now with production, we're
Speaker 8:  gonna have these tools where it was gonna be easier direct line for them
Speaker 8:  to express themself. But again, there's no guarantee. That's good. Right?
Speaker 8:  If you go into masses on the flip side of that, which you were saying, you
Speaker 8:  know, kinda mentioning with Marvel movies, it's, it's a hard thing. I understand
Speaker 8:  both sides. It's a really hard thing for studios. 'cause if you spend
Speaker 8:  $250 million, you need to make 500 to break even, right?
Speaker 8:  And you're spending another a hundred problem in marketing, right? Right.
Speaker 8:  So you can't really take a big risk. And I always say it would
Speaker 8:  almost be impossible to get 2001 space audits at Green Lit today.
Speaker 8:  It's too artsy, right? And I think that's what for us was really excited.
Speaker 8:  Once you get these tools and you bring the price down, you can take higher
Speaker 8:  risks and you can make, you know, visually spectacular films that the
Speaker 8:  young audience would wanna watch, but make a grounded story really about
Speaker 8:  the character, push some narrative push, push some subject matter. That's
Speaker 8:  extremely, extremely important. Right? And if
Speaker 7:  You're, and if you're not spending $200 million, if you're spending 20 on
Speaker 7:  each, you, you can make way more films and employ more artists.
Speaker 2:  When we were talking before, one of you brought up Netflix as, as another
Speaker 2:  sort of wrench in the engine of like what people think that we make and how
Speaker 2:  it changes what things were like. We got different kinds of TV
Speaker 2:  shows because Netflix existed and what that platform wanted. So to some extent,
Speaker 2:  do you think AI is just sort of another in this like long series
Speaker 2:  of changes that Hollywood has been going through forever? Or is there something
Speaker 2:  different about ai?
Speaker 8:  I think it's different because of scale. Okay. I think it's different because
Speaker 8:  it's gonna distribute. It is much, much more. It's not gonna be as localized,
Speaker 8:  but I don't know, I'm, I'm optimistic. I think the beauty of it, the
Speaker 8:  positive side is that democratization we're talking about the negative side
Speaker 8:  is like how much is it gonna affect it? But if you look at through history
Speaker 8:  of Hollywood, kind of al always found its way, right? It
Speaker 8:  always found its way to survive. You know, early days of television, people
Speaker 8:  said movies were over, right? Right. And now that cycle went and kind of
Speaker 8:  repeated itself now, you know, 80 years later with the streaming platform.
Speaker 8:  And then it's coming in a slow recovery on that. So I think storytelling
Speaker 8:  find its way on that. But I do think it's gonna be a big shift. A
Speaker 8:  lot of people in production side, especially below the line, a lot of artists
Speaker 8:  below the line, you know, Ty, I talk a lot about like, what if
Speaker 8:  shooting in person is gonna be like black and mo, black and white movies
Speaker 8:  today you don't see many of them, but you see some, right? But if
Speaker 8:  that happens and go going around. So it's interesting. Nobody really has
Speaker 8:  an answer of, of what that's gonna end up being. But yes, I, again,
Speaker 8:  to repeat like we've been telling people for three, four years, start learning
Speaker 8:  these things, start learning these tools, it's the only way to kind of survive
Speaker 8:  through it. I, I think it's jean's out of the bottom. It's really hard to
Speaker 8:  stop some of these research and some of these innovation. So
Speaker 7:  I think, yeah, I think that was the big thing during the strikes that that
Speaker 7:  didn't happen. You know, people, there was a lot of controversy. People were
Speaker 7:  saying, oh, AI is either bad or good and people were jumping on these, this,
Speaker 7:  you know, spectrum on one extreme end or the other. And no one
Speaker 7:  was really coming together to talk about it and, you know, in an open
Speaker 7:  way and say, Hey, let's educate ourselves on this. And I, I think that's
Speaker 7:  truly what everyone needs to do. It's what the industry needs to do. It's
Speaker 7:  what artists need to do. Artists need to understand exactly how
Speaker 7:  it's gonna change the course of their careers. You know, what benefits it
Speaker 7:  poses, what threats it poses to their careers. I think we, we really, you
Speaker 7:  know, as, as creators have to come together and, and really openly educate
Speaker 7:  ourselves on, on what it means for the future.
Speaker 2:  Do you think there's room to influence that as creatives? I think to
Speaker 2:  to some extent that there's a version of that conversation that basically
Speaker 2:  sounds like, you know, we're, we're screwed. The old way is dead. All
Speaker 2:  we can do is just sort of hunker down and try to move forward. But there's
Speaker 2:  another way that says, and I think this is like talking to folks, especially
Speaker 2:  during the writer strike, there's this question of like, how can we make
Speaker 2:  this better? Like we do, we agree that there are things that chat
Speaker 2:  GPT can do for scripts that are useful, but we have to do that in a way that
Speaker 2:  also works for us as people who have jobs and do creative work. Like can
Speaker 2:  we Yeah. Are, are I my worry with a lot of things about AI is that that tech
Speaker 2:  is getting better faster than we are at dealing with it. And so it's just
Speaker 2:  gonna sort of leave us behind and we're gonna end up at this place of all
Speaker 2:  we can do is just sort of give up and try
Speaker 8:  To survive. No, I I I think it's not getting as fast
Speaker 8:  as you would read online. Okay. It's, it's flashy, but in
Speaker 8:  practic, practically on film, it's still not completely
Speaker 8:  usable. It'll get there. That's one of the reasons we built it that way.
Speaker 8:  'cause we knew there's no way you can push every shot just with ai you'll
Speaker 8:  get 60% there. So you need to give this data to the artist to be able to
Speaker 8:  manipulate it all the way there. So it's still a bit like, you know,
Speaker 8:  flashiness and excitements.
Speaker 7:  We're kind of seeing it now in a way with some films that I think are dominating
Speaker 7:  the box office. I think, you know, audiences are seeing films
Speaker 7:  that they're not enjoying. And yeah, sure, you can argue that that's
Speaker 7:  happened always. But I think ultimately, you know, people will,
Speaker 7:  good stories attract people, you know, and people go and they see a good
Speaker 7:  story and they tell someone about it and then that person goes and they see
Speaker 7:  it and they tell someone else. And so I don't think that will ever stop.
Speaker 7:  You know? And so if you have, let's say a studio or a production company
Speaker 7:  or anyone that thinks, oh well we can just, we can just use AI and
Speaker 7:  replace everyone. Well, if they're not making good stories, it doesn't, it's
Speaker 7:  not gonna matter, right? These, these stories won't be successful because
Speaker 7:  they won't connect with people in an emotional, in a real way. And that's
Speaker 7:  what, that's what artists are good at. That's why we need artists, you know,
Speaker 7:  regardless of what tools they have. And that's, that's always been true since
Speaker 7:  the dawn of time, since we've been telling stories, since we've been, you
Speaker 7:  know, telling stories through art. And I don't think that'll ever change,
Speaker 8:  You know, thinking about making a movie, like, I don't know how many people
Speaker 8:  in this room made a hundred million dollar movie or made a movie,
Speaker 8:  right? How many people would like to make a movie? Ty
Speaker 2:  Should erase stand just that Ty should erase.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  But I'm saying if you ask, you know, a really large group of people, how
Speaker 8:  many would like to be able to make a movie? Most people say, oh, that'd be
Speaker 8:  fine. I would like to do that. Right? I would like to express my feeling
Speaker 8:  and tell people my story. The, the amount of people that get to like make
Speaker 8:  $150 million movie. It's a handful. It's handful of these directors that
Speaker 8:  you get to work. So I think our industry will just grow because of it's not
Speaker 8:  gonna shrink, it will grow. 'cause it's gonna be very, very global. We're
Speaker 8:  talking Hollywood and I always say like storytelling extremely, extremely
Speaker 8:  is extremely important. It should not be dependent on your
Speaker 8:  socioeconomical status. That's why we started this. And I think that's what's
Speaker 8:  important about ai. But yes, you gotta build it responsibly, otherwise you
Speaker 8:  can, it can, it can hurt us long way.
Speaker 2:  Let's just talk about sort of Hollywood more broadly right now. And I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm curious, especially sort of specific AI stuff, you're
Speaker 2:  starting to see work its way into how these things get made. We've talked
Speaker 2:  about dubbing a little bit. We've talked about what you're doing at one with
Speaker 2:  the VXX stuff. Like are there other things that are starting
Speaker 2:  to sort of appear in the filmmaking process and be part of the conversation
Speaker 2:  in Hollywood that are either cool or early versions of
Speaker 2:  something cool?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think Hollywood is, it's, it's odd 'cause it's
Speaker 7:  hypocritical, but Hollywood I think is notoriously standoffish to new technology
Speaker 7:  even though it's, it's an entire industry predicated on the
Speaker 7:  advent of a camera, right? And then thereafter, you know, new, new, new
Speaker 7:  stories and the best movies were making technological advancements,
Speaker 7:  you know, and they wouldn't be possible without those technological advancements.
Speaker 7:  But I think now, you know, there are certain decision makers in
Speaker 7:  Hollywood, and I'm not saying it's everyone, but there are a lot of decision
Speaker 7:  makers in Hollywood who know nothing about technology. They know nothing
Speaker 7:  about how visual effects work really, you know, at, at a very high level
Speaker 7:  maybe. But there, there are people who, who make a lot of decisions and,
Speaker 7:  and I think they don't understand technology at a certain depth. So I
Speaker 7:  think sometimes it's also kind of a, a risk management
Speaker 7:  business too. You know, you have thousands of of artists working
Speaker 7:  in certain pipelines. You can't just, you know, decide to, to use some
Speaker 7:  AI tool and change that entire pipeline overnight. No one's ever gonna go
Speaker 7:  for that. And that's, that's one reason why, you know, we built Wonder Studio
Speaker 7:  the way we did so that it plugged in directly to the pipeline that artists
Speaker 7:  were used to, that that productions were using could actually utilize this
Speaker 7:  tool. It's, it's not a black box, right? So yeah, I think
Speaker 7:  the industry's kinda been battered over the past few years. I mean I think
Speaker 7:  it's fair to say, you know, we had Covid, which was a major dent in
Speaker 7:  the global box office and you know, then we had the streaming wars and
Speaker 7:  you know, digital distribution has been, the landscape of digital distribution
Speaker 7:  has been changing and distribution at large has been changing and
Speaker 7:  now the strikes and AI and so it's just, it's kind of, yeah,
Speaker 7:  it's been a rumble tumble past few years. Yeah, I think people are, are
Speaker 7:  really trying to understand like, you know, what, how can we come out of
Speaker 7:  this? And, and you know, are, are we actually on stable ground now and
Speaker 7:  can we go in green light films and if so, how much risk can we take? What
Speaker 7:  tools can we utilize? So I think it's, it's really like we're in a discovery
Speaker 7:  phase right now and I think people are trying new things. I think people
Speaker 7:  are really starting to test a lot of things behind closed doors. So
Speaker 7:  I do think this will be the year where we really start to see a lot of new
Speaker 7:  use cases and, and, and we've seen, we've seen a few, but I do think there'll
Speaker 7:  be more significant, you know, examples that we'll see in the next year.
Speaker 8:  A lot of the tech is not, not there yet. A lot of tech is really good to
Speaker 8:  push it to something that you can put on social media, but film's different.
Speaker 8:  You gotta get it up to eight K, it needs to be crisp. And also, you know,
Speaker 8:  we said like this kind of age of generative AI has been last year, year and
Speaker 8:  a half. But you know, storytelling and film is all about collaboration
Speaker 8:  and back and forth. Like you turn in your shot to a director or editor
Speaker 8:  and they're gonna give you back notes and sometimes you're gonna have, they're
Speaker 8:  called passes, sometimes you're gonna have up to 20 of them and the changes
Speaker 8:  are gonna be so specific, right? And so these generative AI tools
Speaker 8:  just haven't gotten there yet that you can edit the fine, the finest
Speaker 8:  pixels of that. And that's the limitation of 2D space a little bit in that
Speaker 8:  side because you can generate something that's really cool but it's a little
Speaker 8:  bit off how do I fix it? I think it'll get better. Also, we haven't seen
Speaker 8:  really performance, so it hasn't been used. I mean a lot of these text video,
Speaker 8:  they don't yet know how to generate performance completely on that side.
Speaker 8:  So I think a lot of, a lot of filmmakers are still kinda exploring it. So
Speaker 8:  the promise is big, but we're not completely there yet.
Speaker 2:  I read somewhere that actors are starting to put in their contracts that
Speaker 2:  they have to use VFX to make them look however many years younger
Speaker 2:  or you know, remove the lines. I thought you were saying there's a budget
Speaker 2:  just for like wrinkle removal on Tom Cruise's face.
Speaker 8:  I can't, I can't confirm that
Speaker 8:  I did used, I did used to do that early in my career. There you go. It was
Speaker 8:  just, it was just removing people's under eyes and and
Speaker 8:  stuff like that. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Budget but not Tom Cruise. He's ageless. Tom Cruise Don't
Speaker 8:  Come after me. Yeah, no, never.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so
Speaker 7:  I thought Tom Cruise is ai
Speaker 2:  That's,
Speaker 8:  There is an AI meta that's metaphysics, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yes, that is,
Speaker 2:  That's true. Alright, if, let's, let's, we're gonna run outta time here soon.
Speaker 2:  So let's take some questions if folks have questions.
Speaker 9:  Hi, can you quantify the
Speaker 9:  access that you're talking about, the democratization? What is the pricing
Speaker 9:  model of your product and what are the price, the cost
Speaker 9:  savings that you promise your clients when you go in for a pitch and across
Speaker 9:  what tasks I'm curious about? Good question. Kinda the material
Speaker 9:  benefits of the, of the product.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, no, that's a great question. When I say democratization, I mean
Speaker 8:  AI in general where it's going. We're not saying we're the only player out
Speaker 8:  there that's just gonna democratize the entire plan.
Speaker 2:  You're just in it for the money. Yeah, that's,
Speaker 8:  That's a very big promise. I'm talking in the general, for us, we,
Speaker 8:  we really see savings up to 60, 70% going aspect.
Speaker 8:  The, the thing that we're really saving people on production side, you need
Speaker 8:  a lot of these hardware, not just the motion capture suit. You need to track
Speaker 8:  your camera, which is additional hardware. You need all the sensors, which
Speaker 8:  is more price on the hardware. And then in post-production, there's a lot
Speaker 8:  of these monotone tasks that really take, take we weeks sometimes that
Speaker 8:  we brought down to two hours on the side. So we've seen quite a bit of
Speaker 8:  significant change. Again, it really depends, you know, and
Speaker 8:  we just spoke earlier in visual effects. You have something called easy,
Speaker 8:  medium and hard shots. And usually when you bid a project you say, okay,
Speaker 8:  I have 2000 shots, 500 is gonna be easy, about a thousand
Speaker 8:  is gonna be medium and then 500 is gonna be hard. So what we did
Speaker 8:  is kind of brought down some of those hard to be medium and medium to be
Speaker 8:  easy. So that really where, where the savings come on. And what we've seen
Speaker 8:  also what's really interesting is a lot of our users are, because
Speaker 8:  our tool goes from $20 a month to, to a hundred dollars a
Speaker 8:  month. So we really built this to be affordable. Traditionally if you use
Speaker 8:  mocap sometimes you're gonna spend $30,000 a day to do that, right? So there's
Speaker 8:  a drastic, drastic change there. But you know, we were talking earlier, it's
Speaker 8:  like our goal is to open it up free as well as a part of that. The only reason
Speaker 8:  as a startup you can't do that because you, these computers, you know, we
Speaker 8:  made it as a web browser so everybody can, accessibility was a big one for
Speaker 8:  us. So everybody can access it, but that means you have the cloud cost.
Speaker 8:  But I always say cloud's not a actual cloud up there that's free. It's, you
Speaker 8:  know, Amazon has a workstation somewhere that you have to pay by the hour,
Speaker 8:  right? So that, that is a cost on us. You know, even Chad, GPT, they're spending
Speaker 8:  millions of dollars a second when someone's prompting someone's, you know,
Speaker 8:  someone's gotta pay for that. So for us as a startup, we picked it
Speaker 8:  in a route where we're not gonna go out to raise hundreds of millions of
Speaker 8:  dollars just to get higher numbers. So we can claim we have, you know,
Speaker 8:  hundreds of millions of users, right? We did end up close to a million of
Speaker 8:  users in our platform, but the hard part there is like, okay,
Speaker 8:  we can't open it up yet until we bring the cost down for us. So we can, we
Speaker 8:  can make sure that this can run for a long time. Totally. All right,
Speaker 10:  Let's do a couple more. Do you guys have any thoughts around
Speaker 10:  the, the end game for materials being created
Speaker 10:  these days? Like at the movie theater for instance, are we gonna
Speaker 10:  see changes in how we view these new products At
Speaker 10:  some point it seems like going to the movies has
Speaker 10:  fundamentally changed. I don't know if it was the pandemic or what have
Speaker 10:  you, but now we are at these inflection points with the ai,
Speaker 10:  the new ways that we inhabit spaces. Do you have any thoughts around
Speaker 10:  that?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I mean I think yeah we will continue to see that change, you know,
Speaker 7:  will it ever go away entirely? I don't think so. I think people will go
Speaker 7:  to the, go to the movies and they may be sitting in a virtual cinema but
Speaker 7:  they might be watching movies till, I don't think that'll ever go away. I
Speaker 7:  think that's a very special experience. But I do think with new advancements,
Speaker 7:  you know, we will see new mediums that are extremely compelling. I, I
Speaker 7:  especially think interactive for games is gonna be huge obviously.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we'll continue to see new mediums as technology continues to evolve.
Speaker 7:  But I don't know if we're we'll ever lose, you know, there there's gonna
Speaker 7:  be some form of nostalgia of like, oh I love going to see a movie in a theater
Speaker 7:  surrounded by other people on a huge screen. And I don't, I hope we'll never
Speaker 7:  lose that.
Speaker 11:  I'm wondering if you have a POV on like other industries outside of
Speaker 11:  Hollywood, whether it's like Nollywood or Bollywood, are they embracing
Speaker 11:  AI more and like maybe seeing that as an opportunity to even like skyrocket
Speaker 11:  closer to Hollywood?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, definitely. We've seen like one of our first users have been from,
Speaker 8:  from Nollywood and, and different ones and we've seen it definitely happen
Speaker 8:  to me that's, that's exciting 'cause I think we'll get, we'll get more chances
Speaker 8:  'cause especially in like CG and visual effects, a lot of these smaller markets
Speaker 8:  really wanna do the same thing that H is doing, but they either didn't have
Speaker 8:  the know-how or the budgets needed to do that, right? Or
Speaker 7:  The production equipment. They just don't have the hardware.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah, exactly. So that's where, that's where it's really exciting.
Speaker 8:  We, we, we've seen a lot and I think there's a, a stat somewhere
Speaker 8:  Ollywood is making more films per month than something about like
Speaker 8:  Hollywood than one more industry combined. Wow. Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's quite
Speaker 8:  fascinating and if you start looking into it, it's, it's crazy quantity of
Speaker 8:  it. But again, as you mentioned earlier, like if we have good dubbing and
Speaker 8:  stuff that comes out, we might probably see more of those films, right? Because
Speaker 8:  I always joke my girlfriend doesn't like to watch films with subtitles, which
Speaker 8:  is again terrible for me, right? 'cause I love to watch foreign
Speaker 8:  films. I
Speaker 2:  Can't look at my phone and read subtitles at the same time.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I know, I know. She said, she says she doesn't like to read movies
Speaker 8:  and I just, I can't hear her say that every, every, every time. But I do
Speaker 8:  think like a lot of audience actually doesn't like to read sub. So if we
Speaker 8:  figure out a way, how do we bring these foreign films more and make people
Speaker 8:  comfortable to watch it, it will it, it will help on that side.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But our, our, we have, we have users all over the world from
Speaker 7:  Japan to China to England, Norway,
Speaker 7:  US, Mexico, south America. Yeah, we have users kind of globally,
Speaker 8:  But I think general outside of our platform, yeah we're seeing a lot more
Speaker 8:  AI usage on that side. Everybody's trying to figure out, what's exciting
Speaker 8:  is sometimes you think you see things going on YouTube that just some keep
Speaker 8:  came up with a new pipeline. It's extremely promising. And I was like, wow,
Speaker 8:  that's very interesting. This is, you know, if this kid goes out you could
Speaker 8:  raise $10 million on idea on a startup because this is a really good
Speaker 8:  pipeline but it's one kid sitting at the computer and researching things.
Speaker 8:  I think that's the exciting part and we, we said it's kinda like equal starting
Speaker 8:  point for everyone. That's the fear of it. But that's also to
Speaker 8:  me, the exciting part of it is meaning like, oh everybody has a chance to
Speaker 8:  figure out how to do this. And obviously, you know, the traditional kind
Speaker 8:  of gatekeepers will be worried about that
Speaker 7:  And may and maybe at some point, you know, maybe those gatekeepers even get
Speaker 7:  replaced by people who are telling better stories, who are coming up with
Speaker 7:  more efficient ways to, to tell those and you know, it's better for the world
Speaker 7:  maybe
Speaker 2:  Here's hoping, alright, I could talk to you guys about this for hours and
Speaker 2:  I also didn't ask you a single question about Ready Player one, so you should
Speaker 2:  be grateful.
Speaker 12:  All right Nico, this
Speaker 7:  One's great. We gotta
Speaker 2:  Go. Ty, Nico, Nicola, thank you so much for doing this. I think this is really
Speaker 2:  fun.
Speaker 12:  Thank you. Of course. Thanks for having us, for having us. Thanks everyone.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we'll be back to do a question
Speaker 2:  from the Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  We are back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  VERGE one one and the email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all
Speaker 2:  your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show every week.
Speaker 2:  Thank you. by the way, to everybody who keeps reaching out about the books
Speaker 2:  Palmer, that is like the most intriguing device according to The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast hotline in a long time. I'm getting one and I'm going to have a
Speaker 2:  lot to say with Alex on this show very soon. Get ready this
Speaker 2:  week we have a question from Braden.
Speaker 17:  Hey David, this is Braden from Utah. Why has
Speaker 17:  iMessage not improved? I mean that like I remember when
Speaker 17:  like I 10 happened and Game Pigeon was a thing where you could play
Speaker 17:  games through iMessage with your friends. It was the coolest
Speaker 17:  thing. And I still play game pitching games with my friends and family
Speaker 17:  to this day, but I remember in 2016, that's eight years
Speaker 17:  ago, I was like, dang, this is cool now. But think of
Speaker 17:  the things people will make with this, how there will be other things to
Speaker 17:  do in iMessage. And currently like
Speaker 17:  the list has not grown at all. It is game pigeon
Speaker 17:  gifts and then weird apps that want to be in your messages that don't belong
Speaker 17:  there. And it's just like, don't you feel like iMessage
Speaker 17:  held more promises and just haven't fulfilled? Does The Vergecast
Speaker 17:  play game pigeon games together? What are your thoughts? I wanna hear 'em.
Speaker 2:  This is actually something I've done a lot of reporting about over the last
Speaker 2:  couple of years. Not necessarily with iMessage specifically, but with
Speaker 2:  messaging apps in general. And I think you can look at the whole world of
Speaker 2:  messaging apps to kind of answer the question. So the thing that turns out
Speaker 2:  to be true about messaging apps is that a, you can't
Speaker 2:  really build a business on a messaging app. There's just no real
Speaker 2:  evidence that lots of people will pay you lots of money for a
Speaker 2:  way to talk to their friends, right? Like the idea of a texting app is so
Speaker 2:  commoditized at this point that there's really no business to be had there.
Speaker 2:  So if you are a messaging company, let's say Snapchat
Speaker 2:  or WhatsApp or Telegram or iMessage,
Speaker 2:  in this case, you have to figure out a way to be successful that
Speaker 2:  isn't just messaging, right? If you and I messaging each other
Speaker 2:  is never going to be a business, and I, I believe that it's not, you have
Speaker 2:  to figure out something else to do. So you essentially have two options.
Speaker 2:  You can either try to build stuff around messaging, which
Speaker 2:  is like what Snapchat does with things like
Speaker 2:  Snapchat originals and Spotlight and all the creator stuff that they've been
Speaker 2:  doing. And stories frankly is a way around messaging stuff
Speaker 2:  so that you come to the app to do messaging and you
Speaker 2:  stay to do everything else and that's where all the money is, right? That's
Speaker 2:  essentially what WeChat is. WeChat's whole idea was to build
Speaker 2:  an entire universe around the place that people go to communicate with their
Speaker 2:  friends. That's a real business. You can do it. It's a tricky thing to get
Speaker 2:  right from a UI perspective. I think Snap has been through this in
Speaker 2:  a bunch of complicated ways, trying to say, okay, you came here for a messaging
Speaker 2:  app, how do we get you into all of the things that we can do to make money?
Speaker 2:  But that is one way to do it. That's also I would say what WhatsApp is
Speaker 2:  doing with things like business messaging. WhatsApp is really interested
Speaker 2:  in getting you to get menus or
Speaker 2:  business hours or things like that through WhatsApp. That's a thing people
Speaker 2:  are doing kind of informally anyway. And they would really, really,
Speaker 2:  really like to bring that into the WhatsApp ecosystem. That's
Speaker 2:  also a way they can make money, they can charge businesses for those services.
Speaker 2:  They can take a portion of money that gets moved around inside of these things.
Speaker 2:  But again, all of this is kind of ancillary to, this is where you message
Speaker 2:  your friends. The other way to do it is to try to figure out a way to
Speaker 2:  insert experiences into the place where you message with your friends.
Speaker 2:  And this is where it gets really messy. I think about like
Speaker 2:  Google Aloe is probably the best example of this. If you remember that this
Speaker 2:  messaging app Google made from years ago and its big idea was that you
Speaker 2:  could bring an AI system at that time, you know, Google assistant
Speaker 2:  into your chat with your friends. So you could say, you know, we're
Speaker 2:  planning to go to dinner or we're planning to go to the movies, let's buy
Speaker 2:  movie tickets. And you could actually buy movie tickets inside of your
Speaker 2:  chat with your friends. Cool idea. In theory, I think
Speaker 2:  this is also where things like games like Braden was talking about or this
Speaker 2:  idea that we can have experiences together inside of our chat
Speaker 2:  window seems cool. Emphasis on seams
Speaker 2:  in reality, this ends up being a pain. It's very hard for these apps
Speaker 2:  to find a way to sort of insert themselves or add these services or even
Speaker 2:  make you aware of these services without getting in the way of just you talking
Speaker 2:  to your friends. And if you think about it, the idea of screwing up
Speaker 2:  your chat interface with your friends is like totally untenable.
Speaker 2:  People just won't do it, right? You get to the point where I wanna have
Speaker 2:  messages back and forth with my friends and if you change that or screw
Speaker 2:  it up, disaster. And I think in a funny way, apple has
Speaker 2:  been trying to almost do it without fully doing it
Speaker 2:  for a really long time. There was the iMessage app store where you could
Speaker 2:  send stuff, but that had an incredible discovery problem. Like most people,
Speaker 2:  I don't think knew the iMessage app store existed. It was buried in a
Speaker 2:  menu in the iOS keyboard when you were in iMessage
Speaker 2:  that didn't really work. Now there's this new menu where you can send stuff
Speaker 2:  that works a little bit better, but that menu is really slow and kind of
Speaker 2:  awkward. But I think what Apple would really like to do is
Speaker 2:  make messages a full on internet platform in a
Speaker 2:  very real way. You should be able to send somebody a
Speaker 2:  link to tic-tac toe and it just expands. And you can play
Speaker 2:  tic-tac toe inside of the iMessage window right there without ever leaving
Speaker 2:  the app. If you think of it right now, a lot of this stuff is just links,
Speaker 2:  right? Like if I wanna play a game with you, I send you a link, you tap on
Speaker 2:  the link and we go play the game. That's actually a pretty good user experience.
Speaker 2:  So to bring that into the messaging system is a pretty
Speaker 2:  tall order. And to do it in a way that doesn't disrupt anything else or
Speaker 2:  threaten to take your data or break encryption in these encrypted
Speaker 2:  messaging apps. It's just hard. People want private messaging, they want
Speaker 2:  simple messaging and they wanna be able to talk to their friends and to add
Speaker 2:  things to that is borderline impossible. That said,
Speaker 2:  they're gonna keep trying. They are just going to keep trying. There are
Speaker 2:  too many people spending too much time in messaging apps for these companies
Speaker 2:  to not try and find ways to insert themselves. And so you'll see more stuff
Speaker 2:  like this that inside of things like Slack and Discord, you're
Speaker 2:  already starting to see these fuller web-like experiences you can
Speaker 2:  have just inside of a chat window. I think that's where we're headed
Speaker 2:  in certain ways, but I also think that's gonna make basic
Speaker 2:  messaging apps like Signal and WhatsApp and frankly
Speaker 2:  iMessage all the more valuable to people. 'cause that's where you go to just
Speaker 2:  talk and that is like the main thing we wanna do on the internet. Think
Speaker 2:  about how annoying Gmail ads are. You're like, I just wanna look at my emails
Speaker 2:  and you're showing me a bunch of ads at the top of my inbox for some reason.
Speaker 2:  Add that to your text messages with friends and family, which
Speaker 2:  are even more intimate and even more important. And that just sucks. People
Speaker 2:  will run away from that. And if you're Apple, again,
Speaker 2:  iMessage is one of the core things that keeps people using
Speaker 2:  iPhones. Being a blue bubble is a very important thing. And so if you make
Speaker 2:  people hate iMessage to the point where they'll start using WhatsApp, that's
Speaker 2:  a huge, huge risk for Apple. So Apple is in this tricky spot, just like
Speaker 2:  everybody who makes a messaging app of saying messaging is so important,
Speaker 2:  we wanna build a business out of it. It's where people are, it's what people
Speaker 2:  wanna do. But if we do it even slightly wrong, people will
Speaker 2:  run away. And that kills a huge amount of any kind of
Speaker 2:  moat and advantage that we have to keep people in that tension
Speaker 2:  mostly means we get to keep our simple good messaging apps, but
Speaker 2:  that tension may not last forever. And I think it's gonna be really interesting
Speaker 2:  because it is abundantly clear to everyone who makes an app
Speaker 2:  that if you can get people to message inside of it, they will live inside
Speaker 2:  of your app and that becomes very powerful. You don't wanna screw it up,
Speaker 2:  but it's a powerful thing to have going for you. So we'll see. I would bet
Speaker 2:  we're gonna see a lot more experimentation inside of these apps,
Speaker 2:  especially these kind of just outside of messaging
Speaker 2:  things where like, I can send you a game in the way
Speaker 2:  that I send you a gif, or I can send you an interactive
Speaker 2:  poll inside of a group chat. That's the kind of stuff that's already coming
Speaker 2:  to WhatsApp and I think you'll start to see that in more places. But
Speaker 2:  I sort of hope we never get these like massively interactive full web
Speaker 2:  experiences. I do not need a chat bot in my messaging system.
Speaker 2:  I just, I just don't. This thing where you can talk to an AI chat bot,
Speaker 2:  like you talk to a person, fine, do not put an AI bot in my group
Speaker 2:  chats. Meta Apple, Google, whoever else. I don't
Speaker 2:  want that. I don't think anybody does, but they're probably gonna do it.
Speaker 2:  We'll see. Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today.
Speaker 2:  Thanks to everybody who came on the show, and thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more on everything we talked about at The Verge dot com. We'll
Speaker 2:  put a bunch of Lauren's stuff
Speaker 2:  send us