# Transcript
ID: cb6e359a-f3fd-491a-b26d-98f765fa8f58
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4929868331226918152/-4523534272599170979/s93290-US-4427s-1716767983.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of Arm-based chipsets:
03:08 - The Verge’s Tom Warren and David Pierce discuss the announcements from Microsoft’s Surface event, including the new Arm-powered Surface Laptop, and Copilot Plus PCs.
Microsoft’s Surface AI event: news, rumors, and lots of Qualcomm laptops
Microsoft announces an Arm-powered Surface Laptop
Microsoft’s new Surface Pro gets an OLED display for the first time
Microsoft announces Copilot Plus PCs with built-in AI hardware
The new, faster Surface Pro is Microsoft's all-purpose AI PC
Recall is Microsoft’s key to unlocking the future of PCs
27:29 -Verge senior AI reporter Kylie Robison joins the show to chat about OpenAI’s GPT-4o demo and where we’re headed in the next few years of AI.
ChatGPT is getting a Mac app
OpenAI’s custom GPT Store is now open to all for free
OpenAI releases GPT-4o, a faster model that’s free for all ChatGPT users
ChatGPT will be able to talk to you like Scarlett Johansson in Her
OpenAI pulls its Scarlett Johansson-like voice for ChatGPT
OpenAI chief scientist Ilya Sutskever is officially leaving
OpenAI researcher resigns, claiming safety has taken ‘a backseat to shiny products’
We tried out the Project Astra demo at Google I/O which worked well un... | tech | TikTok
57:40 - Nilay Patel answers a question about iPads for this week’s Vergecast Hotline.
Apple iPad Pro (2024) review: the best tablet money can buy
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (35 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Arm based chipsets.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently in the woods in the middle
Speaker 2:  of nowhere in Virginia at an Airbnb. So the last seven
Speaker 2:  days have been my wife's birthday, mother's Day and our wedding
Speaker 2:  anniversary all in the course of a week. If, you get to choose
Speaker 2:  in your life to do all those things at once or spread them out through the
Speaker 2:  year. I highly recommend spreading them out through the year, but this is
Speaker 2:  what we have. So every year we try to like combine all these
Speaker 2:  celebrations and just go find a place in the woods with bad internet
Speaker 2:  and no cell connectivity and just relax for a couple of days.
Speaker 2:  I cannot recommend enough every once in a while just finding somewhere where
Speaker 2:  you can't be online, whether you want to or not and just lean into it
Speaker 2:  for a couple days. It's the best, but I'm in the woods. But The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast goes on. We have an awesome show for you today. We actually have
Speaker 2:  a lot to get to. It is like the Newsiest time in
Speaker 2:  recent memory and there's a lot of fun stuff to talk about today on the show,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about two things. We're gonna talk about the surface event
Speaker 2:  that just happened where Microsoft kind of unveiled both its new
Speaker 2:  devices, but also what seems to be an entirely new generation
Speaker 2:  of laptops and Windows PCs. There's a lot going on. There's some big
Speaker 2:  huge promises. We're gonna talk about all of it. We're also gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  OpenAI. I know we've been talking about the OpenAI event from last week and
Speaker 2:  Google, Gemini and this whole AI space that we're in right now. A lot
Speaker 2:  over the last couple of weeks, but I can't stop thinking about it, especially
Speaker 2:  what OpenAI believes is the future and how we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  to computers going forward. Lots to get to. On that front, we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  to Kylie Robinson, our new AI reporter about all of it. We also have a
Speaker 2:  question about iPads on The Vergecast hotline because we also can't stop
Speaker 2:  talking about iPads. Lots to do in this episode. All that is coming up in
Speaker 2:  just a second, but I just heard the hot tub motor go off, which
Speaker 2:  means it's hot enough, which means it's hot tub time. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  build them with 5G and other connectivity because people will actually take
Speaker 2:  them away from the charger. Windows tablets would suddenly make a lot more
Speaker 2:  sense for a lot of people. So would more portable Windows gaming devices.
Speaker 2:  It all sounds awesome. It also, I should say is a thing we have
Speaker 2:  been promised many, many times. Qualcomm has
Speaker 2:  been claiming that the next one was the one for years. Everything was gonna
Speaker 2:  be the year of Windows on arm. I'm skeptical of all of it.
Speaker 2:  Well yesterday that new generation of PCs showed up.
Speaker 2:  Microsoft had a big event to launch new surfaces. Lots of other companies
Speaker 2:  announced Snapdragon devices of their own. Our own Tom Warren
Speaker 2:  is at the event in Seattle to catch us up on all of it. Hi Tom.
Speaker 7:  Hello there.
Speaker 2:  How's life in Seattle?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's good. It's sunny. It's not raining so I can't complain.
Speaker 2:  I did appreciate that the weather came up like three times at the beginning
Speaker 2:  of the event this morning. They were very happy that it was a sunny day in
Speaker 2:  Seattle. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean the last, they put us all in the tent today, so the last time
Speaker 7:  they did that it was like mudslides all around the tent. So I'm, I'm, I'm
Speaker 7:  glad that's not happened.
Speaker 2:  Oh boy. Yeah. So tell me a little bit about this event. This was a, an event
Speaker 2:  we've known was coming for a while. It's the day before Microsoft build,
Speaker 2:  but it's not Microsoft build like give me the vibes of the event
Speaker 2:  a little bit.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so obviously we kind of knew that that they'd been working on these
Speaker 7:  sort of like arm powered PCs and kind of like the event sort of
Speaker 7:  talked us through this sort of reinvention of Windows, which is
Speaker 7:  Microsoft's promised a bunch on on sort of Windows on arm previously. But
Speaker 7:  it does feel like it's slightly different this time mainly because these
Speaker 7:  devices have got more performance and battery life, all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 7:  But also because all the OEMs are actually doing their own variants of what
Speaker 7:  they're calling these copilot plus PCs and they're actually like the
Speaker 7:  top tier variants of their, their Windows laptops. So it's not like they're
Speaker 7:  just shoving these chips into some mid-range laptops and just coordinated
Speaker 7:  that. They're like I quote all in on these copilot
Speaker 7:  plus PCs. So the event kind of ran that down. Why those, why that matters,
Speaker 7:  the performance versus the map care. 'cause Microsoft thinks that this is
Speaker 7:  kind of like their moment to sort of beat the microcare, which is kind of
Speaker 7:  interesting. And then some of the AI sort of features that these, these new
Speaker 7:  laptops enable. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  There's a lot of confidence coming outta Microsoft in this event. Like I
Speaker 2:  feel like normally I'm used to sort of the the Panos pane era where he would
Speaker 2:  come out and sort of tell you how lovely a device is and try to convince
Speaker 2:  you of how wonderful it is and how much the team cared about it. And this
Speaker 2:  felt like a very different Microsoft. They just came out and were like, we
Speaker 2:  did it folks like here, here's the stuff. Check it out, let's go. Was that
Speaker 2:  what it felt like in the room?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it definitely felt a a little bit different than some because the previous
Speaker 7:  surface event that they had last year, it was like literally like days after
Speaker 7:  we knew panels were leaving and that felt like, oh that's right. It was like
Speaker 7:  a kind of like a funeral to surface. It felt like the like Surface was dying
Speaker 7:  or something. It was, it was a really odd event. This one, it just feels
Speaker 7:  like the surface is like the, the platform, like the essentially the the
Speaker 7:  showpiece for this platform for these new advances on Windows and
Speaker 7:  arm and that's kind of, they didn't make surface like the most
Speaker 7:  important thing, but it wasn't the least important thing. It was kind of,
Speaker 7:  you know, just just there to sort of back up that that that they are serious
Speaker 7:  about this transition to arm.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So talk to me about the, the copilot plus PCs thing because
Speaker 2:  you and I have been on this show for the last couple of months, I would say
Speaker 2:  relatively consistently making fun of the idea of an AI
Speaker 2:  pc, right? Which just generally means nothing. But this
Speaker 2:  time Microsoft came out and and much more clearly tried to define
Speaker 2:  what a copilot plus PC is and what makes it different and what makes it
Speaker 2:  special and why this kind of deserves its own category of
Speaker 2:  PCs. Like what, what makes a copilot plus pc? A copilot plus
Speaker 2:  pc?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, exactly. Like they previously had these AI PCs that were
Speaker 7:  kind of like, they were trying to sell it on this AI vision or Windows, but
Speaker 7:  they didn't quite have the performance essentially inside for them to actually
Speaker 7:  enable these AI features that a part of these copilot plus pieces. So
Speaker 7:  essentially what they are is, I think the way Microsoft's define them is
Speaker 7:  that the NPU The new processing units, it's a new chip or I wouldn't say
Speaker 7:  it's necessarily new, but it's new to sort of Windows a new chip
Speaker 7:  that will basically accelerate these AI tasks. So they've got this new
Speaker 7:  recall feature which essentially say you are working on your laptop
Speaker 7:  and like you saw an elephant two weeks ago and you're like, where, where
Speaker 7:  did I see that damn elephant? Was it in a tab, like was it in an email? Like
Speaker 7:  sure I saw it. And then you can just type in Elephant and it will be like,
Speaker 7:  okay, I saw this in your email and it doesn't need to like see the words
Speaker 7:  that you've typed like Elephant it, it will literally understand that that
Speaker 7:  is an elephant. So it's quite good for, for recalling like those memories
Speaker 7:  from your everyday use of, of Windows very similar to a a Mac
Speaker 7:  OS app called Rewind, which does a similar thing but obviously this is built
Speaker 7:  in, it's leveraging the actual N Ps, it's not hitting the CPU or GPU to sort
Speaker 7:  of do this. So you can just do these whilst you're watching videos or
Speaker 7:  processing, I don't know, like Premier Pro or something like that and it's
Speaker 7:  not gonna hit that performance. There's also like live captions and they
Speaker 7:  showed like translation there, which was, was pretty cool, but you can't
Speaker 7:  like save that stuff. So it's just, so say you wanted to watch a sort listen
Speaker 7:  or watch to a podcast that was in Japanese, you could literally just load
Speaker 7:  it up and it would just do that life life translation for you. So that that,
Speaker 7:  that was pretty cool.
Speaker 2:  I have to say I thought recall was really cool. Yeah. And I actually thought
Speaker 2:  in general Microsoft did a really good job of not only explaining
Speaker 2:  why you want lots of power on your computer but also
Speaker 2:  showing the kinds of features that you can do on your device
Speaker 2:  when you have this stuff. Like the translation was a good example where you
Speaker 2:  were able to have like multiple languages being translated to each other
Speaker 2:  in multiple, in real time on a video call, which is the kind of thing you
Speaker 2:  genuinely only can do on device 'cause you're sending all that to the cloud,
Speaker 2:  it just falls apart. Right. But, and with, with the live captions and some
Speaker 2:  of the edit image editing stuff, they did a really good job of saying like,
Speaker 2:  this is actually what you need all of that power locally in order to do.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like for me recall, which is I think if I remember correctly,
Speaker 2:  all private, all on device, not uploaded anywhere. Not even leaving your
Speaker 2:  computer like really, really smart way to show this
Speaker 2:  is what you can do when you have this thing on your computer. Like I found
Speaker 2:  that very compelling.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think recall was probably the, is their sort of flagship feature
Speaker 7:  for, for this AI stuff. But they did also show, which was just kind of
Speaker 7:  more forward looking and wasn't like a complete demo experience, but
Speaker 7:  they showed some of the stuff where you could have like this copilot experience
Speaker 7:  in a game like an Xbox game on Windows. So there was like a
Speaker 7:  really cool demo and I dunno if this, this came through very well on the
Speaker 7:  live blog, so definitely check out their demo of it. But it was essentially
Speaker 7:  someone was playing Minecraft and then the copilot was like
Speaker 7:  teaching the person how to craft in the game 'cause it could actually see
Speaker 7:  obviously what what you were seeing. So it it, it knew and that was like,
Speaker 7:  that was pretty cool and it was like a zombie in Minecraft appeared and they
Speaker 7:  were like, oh no, there's a zombie, you better run away. Like it was like
Speaker 7:  literally guiding them around the game as if they, it was like their friend
Speaker 7:  sitting beside them. So that was like a really good hint at
Speaker 7:  where this could go when you've got all this sort of on-device AI models
Speaker 7:  running in the background and can actually see everything you're doing. And
Speaker 7:  I thought that one was, that one was particularly cool.
Speaker 2:  That is really cool. Yeah. On the recall one, we, we talked when you were
Speaker 2:  reporting on this, I think it was called AI Explorer was the code name that
Speaker 2:  you had found out about, is that right?
Speaker 7:  Yes, that's right.
Speaker 2:  We were debating whether it was gonna seem very cool or
Speaker 2:  very creepy having seen the thing in action. Where do you land cool or creepy?
Speaker 7:  I think it's in the middle. Right? Okay. Definitely. Because it is kind of
Speaker 7:  creepy that they are taking basically a snapshot of everything you do on
Speaker 7:  your pc. They say there's obviously a way to manage that. You can like disable
Speaker 7:  it per app or on particular websites and stuff. But there, there is
Speaker 7:  still the fact that it's running at all times in the background and and capturing
Speaker 7:  everything you do. But then again, so is like your web browsing history,
Speaker 7:  you know, that's always captured in in your browser. Not quite to the degree
Speaker 7:  of like seeing it per se. So I think there, there is definitely
Speaker 7:  a a, a creepiness to it, but I, I wonder if people will sort of
Speaker 7:  see past that for the, for the, for the actual functionality that it enables.
Speaker 7:  And it's all local. I am speaking to one of their security VPs
Speaker 7:  shortly, so to sort of find out how they're gonna protect against malicious
Speaker 7:  activity. 'cause you can imagine someone getting in through some sort of
Speaker 7:  flaw and then, I don't know, using these AI models to cause chaos on
Speaker 7:  your PC and search for stuff. Sure. And there's, there's potential there.
Speaker 7:  So I'm curious how they've actually secured it beyond the sort of vague promises
Speaker 7:  that they had on on stage. But yeah, I think it's definitely in, in between.
Speaker 7:  I think there's gonna be a bunch of people that will disable this on the
Speaker 7:  hardware that they buy. But then I think the, the things that it enables
Speaker 7:  particularly around that like sort of Minecraft demo in the future, I think,
Speaker 7:  I think it's gonna be worth the trade off. Right. As long as they can keep
Speaker 7:  it secure. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I mean the the demos like that where it, it can collaborate with
Speaker 2:  you as you're using your computer is like, that's the stuff that both Microsoft
Speaker 2:  and others show these bits and pieces of that I'm always like, oh I get it
Speaker 2:  now. Like that's, yeah, that's the kind of stuff I actually want AI for
Speaker 2:  not to, you know, write me business emails but like help me do the things
Speaker 2:  I'm trying to do better. Yeah. And in a sort of automated
Speaker 2:  proactive way like that, that's pretty
Speaker 7:  Cool. Yeah. Being being assistive and sort of like helping you along
Speaker 7:  your way is, is definitely the way that I would prefer to see AI go than
Speaker 7:  try and sort of replace you essentially. Right. Totally.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So let's talk about the devices. So the two big new ones from
Speaker 2:  Microsoft, the Surface Laptop and the Surface Pro. No numbers,
Speaker 2:  which really throws me off. Were just, it's just this No, are there numbers?
Speaker 7:  They're sneaky numbers. So the Surface Pros called the Surface Pro
Speaker 7:  11th Edition, which is very Microsoft as you can imagine, but they're, they're
Speaker 7:  very
Speaker 2:  Microsoft.
Speaker 7:  They're kind of just referring it to as the Surface Pro right. Or the Copilot
Speaker 7:  plus Surface Pro If. you want to get even more Microsoft. But yeah, like
Speaker 7:  essentially there are no numbers.
Speaker 2:  Okay. You've seen them both. I would say my takeaway just from
Speaker 2:  reading the live blog and and seeing the specs and stuff is
Speaker 2:  basically similar-ish footprints. Like I think the
Speaker 2:  Surface Pro in particular is exactly the same size as before and the whole
Speaker 2:  pitch is like gigantic massive internal upgrade that kind of changes
Speaker 2:  everything. Is that reasonable?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I I mean on the Surface Pro they've got new ed
Speaker 7:  display model, which is, which is nice. That's good to have OLED on there.
Speaker 7:  It's not tandem like the I iPad Pro. I think that that Dell's
Speaker 7:  XPS actually is. So you've got The new display option there. But
Speaker 7:  yeah, overall the actual device looks very similar. But they have done
Speaker 7:  one really cool thing that I like is the, the type cover now, you know from
Speaker 7:  Review needs for years, the, the whole lap ability argument with the
Speaker 7:  Surface Pros raged for like a decade now. Yep. And they've actually,
Speaker 7:  what they've done is they've reinforced it. So there's actually, I
Speaker 7:  I couldn't really get it to bounce honestly when I was using on a desk.
Speaker 2:  Really?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, and you know how it usually flexes and you get that weird bounce. It's
Speaker 7:  really annoying when you're trying to write like a, a long document. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  As soon you start typing fast the whole thing sort of feels like it's wiggling
Speaker 2:  underneath you. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like it doesn't do that anymore. There's still that a very
Speaker 7:  slight flex, but like it's not really near as bad and I tried up my,
Speaker 7:  my lap as well. Same it, it was the same and it's because they basically
Speaker 7:  reinforce the, the base of the the surface keyboard. They put a battery in
Speaker 7:  it now. So, so the actual track pad is a little bit larger and it has haptic
Speaker 7:  feedback and it has a Bluetooth chip inside there. So you pull it away from
Speaker 7:  the display and you can actually use it wirelessly. So it's not like just
Speaker 7:  this dumb keyboard when you, when you pull it off anymore. So some pretty
Speaker 7:  cool keyboard upgrades and you can also use the old keyboards If you, If
Speaker 7:  you want to. Yeah. And that, that and the display, I'd say are the biggest
Speaker 7:  things that you would notice on the outside. It's obviously the inside is
Speaker 7:  they're actually Qualcomm power now. So it's Windows and Arm, the Snapdragon
Speaker 7:  X Elite and, and the plus in, in the Surface Pro depending on, you know,
Speaker 7:  which model you go for and playing around with it for like a good, you know,
Speaker 7:  10, 20 minutes. It does, it just does feel like a regular Windows
Speaker 7:  laptop. Right. Especially when everything is running native on there. I we
Speaker 7:  really need to review these to like check out these, these big claims that
Speaker 7:  Microsoft's making. But yeah, it feels like super slick and, and and fast
Speaker 7:  and speedy as you would kind of expect you, I don't think you'd necessarily
Speaker 7:  think that this was an arm laptop. Put it that way.
Speaker 2:  That's really exciting. I mean, and I think that sounds, as you say it almost
Speaker 2:  like faint praise, but I just wanna make sure like it's, it's really not
Speaker 2:  faint praise. No. Given what we've seen from Windows
Speaker 2:  on Arm in the past, like you could tell on the last
Speaker 2:  generation Surface Pro whether you were using the Intel model or the
Speaker 2:  Qualcomm model. Yes. Like immediately, like immediately you could tell the
Speaker 2:  difference. Yeah. And so just the fact that you pick it up and it just feels
Speaker 2:  like a Windows laptop is already an enormous win. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Exactly. Like it does it, I couldn't get it to like really lag,
Speaker 7:  you know? I know I wasn't really pushing it and we will, like I say faint
Speaker 7:  praise because we have to check this out when we review it. But for, from
Speaker 7:  everything I can see it does look like they might have done it this time,
Speaker 7:  but it really is gonna come down to the app compatibility and they, they,
Speaker 7:  they've made some big promises about you emulator and I think just the
Speaker 7:  pure fact that these chips are a lot better, they're sort of brute forcing
Speaker 7:  their way through this in, in many ways, but they're not doing it in a way
Speaker 7:  that's gonna kill the battery life either. Which is interesting 'cause they're
Speaker 7:  making big claims about that as well. It's like 16 hours browsing the web,
Speaker 7:  like 20 hour plus hours If you're watching local video. So if that
Speaker 7:  actually holds up or anywhere close to it, then yeah that's gonna
Speaker 7:  be very competitive compared to sort of the MacBook Air. Whereas usually,
Speaker 7:  but when Microsoft says they have like a 10 hour battery life pc, it's usually
Speaker 7:  five hours, you know, so
Speaker 2:  Well and you got to see, if I remember correctly, like you actually got to
Speaker 2:  see them run these demos next to a
Speaker 2:  MacBook Air. Right. I find Microsoft's whole fascination right now with the
Speaker 2:  MacBook Air and the M three chip in particular really fascinating, but just
Speaker 2:  the fact that they put you in a room and tested the
Speaker 2:  MacBook Air next to The new surfaces is just wild
Speaker 2:  to me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I spent an hour watching a ton of demos that's ranging
Speaker 7:  from like CNA Bench and Geek Bench, you know, like the sort of the, the basic
Speaker 7:  PC benchmarks all the way up to like they, they made scripts for like
Speaker 7:  doing Photoshop filters, which I, they showed some of those on stage and
Speaker 7:  then some AI tasks and yeah, I'd say out of that hour, probably
Speaker 7:  at least every five minutes the MacBook Air was mentioned. Like, I'm not
Speaker 7:  joking, I'm not over exaggerating. It was literally wow, relentless.
Speaker 2:  Why is Microsoft so obsessed with the MacBook Air? I
Speaker 7:  Think because they know that they've fallen behind that like premium
Speaker 7:  set of devices over the past few years since, since Apple transitioned
Speaker 7:  to the M1. They, they've really been behind and Intel hasn't
Speaker 7:  like got them there on battery life or performance to sort of match that,
Speaker 7:  that kind of great offering from from Apple. So they, they, I think their
Speaker 7:  confidence is like, yeah, we're finally here, you know, we, we can be competitive
Speaker 7:  or if not better and we can do it with all these AI sort of features on top.
Speaker 7:  There you go Apple, you know, we're here. Yeah. So it's definitely a
Speaker 7:  new level of confidence.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that makes sense. And speaking of that, actually I was very confused
Speaker 2:  by the fact that Microsoft, at the beginning of the event set a bunch about
Speaker 2:  how all the OEMs, all the chip makers, everybody's in that
Speaker 2:  this co-pilot plus PCs thing is, is like an industry
Speaker 2:  wide move and then spent the whole rest of the hour
Speaker 2:  talking about Qualcomm power devices. What, what is, what do you make of
Speaker 2:  that?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, they kind of did this thing like there was like oh A MD and, and then
Speaker 7:  you're all gonna gonna have these co-pilot plus PCs, you know, soon, but,
Speaker 7:  but not right now. So we, we, we've been partnering with Qualcomm to do this.
Speaker 7:  I think they're kind of, I think they're downplaying a little bit their arm
Speaker 7:  transition there because obviously they want this to be all partner focused.
Speaker 7:  That's the whole idea of Windows. But they, they've made such a big effort
Speaker 7:  even in all those demos. Like there was no mention of Intel and, and a MD,
Speaker 7:  you know, like it was all about these Qualcomm devices all about the transition
Speaker 7:  to Arm, like all about how they've recompiled the kernel and
Speaker 7:  done all this, this work in the background so that they're confident that
Speaker 7:  ARM is finally gonna be, you know, competitive with the Intel
Speaker 7:  based models that, that we have of, of surface devices right now.
Speaker 7:  So I think they, they kind of had to throw a bone to Intel and a MD and had
Speaker 7:  to have them included obviously in this event. And I'm not, that's not terribly
Speaker 7:  surprising, but their stage presence was, was very little compared to
Speaker 7:  all the arm talk that they had on stage. Right. It was all, all of those
Speaker 7:  AI experiences were lit up by a combination of these new chips.
Speaker 7:  So it's gonna be interesting to see when Intel and a MD can actually have
Speaker 7:  an answer with the NPUs that are as performant. 'cause
Speaker 7:  they're already, like they're talking these chips are 45 tops
Speaker 7:  whereas the Intel ones are like less than 10 right now. So by the
Speaker 7:  time Intel matches will Qualcomm then jump ahead. Like it's gonna be
Speaker 7:  interesting to see where the roadmap sort of pans out here.
Speaker 2:  I did enjoy this wasn't the spec heaviest event
Speaker 2:  ever, which I thought was really interesting. They spent a lot of time doing
Speaker 2:  like app demos and a lot less time talking about
Speaker 2:  the details of how these chips work and all that stuff. Right. But they did
Speaker 2:  keep talking about 45 trillion operations per second
Speaker 2:  over and over and over. Yes. That was like the one spec they said like 10
Speaker 2:  times. Yeah they did. It
Speaker 7:  Was very
Speaker 2:  Funny. It was like they are, they're like, our chip is so fast and we're,
Speaker 2:  we're going to remind you 11 times during this event
Speaker 2:  how fast our chips are. 'cause they're so proud of their fast chips.
Speaker 7:  Exactly. And depending on how they calculate it and we'll have to see, I
Speaker 7:  think it will be faster for AI operations than the M four perhaps. So
Speaker 7:  it's gonna be interesting when that roadmap shakes out. 'cause
Speaker 7:  obviously Qualcomm have had arm chips for years and they've never been quite
Speaker 7:  this performant and, and they acquired Nuvia and I think that is the key
Speaker 7:  to why these chips are different. And I think that's, that's the key 'cause
Speaker 7:  that, that those Nuvia chips were, were built by X apple engineers. So it's
Speaker 7:  almost like Right. Yeah. That, so they, they're building the windows silicon.
Speaker 7:  So I think, I think that is the key to why this all feels a little bit different
Speaker 7:  is that the chips are actually performing like you would expect them to.
Speaker 2:  So does all that add up to this being the moment
Speaker 2:  Microsoft seems to want it to be like the, the sense I got reading your reporting
Speaker 2:  and, and from talking to you about this for the last couple of months is
Speaker 2:  that this is kind of a day Microsoft has had circled on the
Speaker 2:  calendar for two years as like yeah this is the beginning of The new era
Speaker 2:  of Windows. We have the power, we have the AI stuff.
Speaker 2:  Copilot is starting to get there. Like the there along with this, there were,
Speaker 2:  I think every OEM on planet Earth announced a bunch of copilot
Speaker 2:  plus PCs. Like right. This, this was clearly designed
Speaker 2:  to be sort of the beginning of an era of Windows PCs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you think it got what it was trying to do?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think so. I think I, I was surprised by some of the AI features that
Speaker 7:  they showed on stage. I think those, those looked really promising. So I
Speaker 7:  wasn't expecting as much of the AI features as, as they showed and
Speaker 7:  just coming to campus this morning, it's like they literally have like
Speaker 7:  signage everywhere. It's like The new AI of era has is is here
Speaker 7:  sort of thing. So they, they're obviously like very confident in it and what
Speaker 7:  they showed and just, just playing around with the devices. It, it does feel
Speaker 7:  like something is different here. Like this is definitely different from
Speaker 7:  like the 2018 push and definitely different from the Surface RT push. So
Speaker 7:  yeah, I mean I wanna try 'em out. I wanna review them next month and, and
Speaker 7:  and give them a good sort of spin just to see if this is actually, you know,
Speaker 7:  this can replace my own laptop and see that if, if they can really
Speaker 7:  nail that battery life, then yeah. I dunno, I dunno what Intel and a
Speaker 7:  MD are gonna do. 'cause I know Qualcomm might have delivered it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I feel like you and I are in exactly the same Headspace, which is like,
Speaker 2:  I desperately want this to be everything that they said it would be. 'cause
Speaker 2:  it would be so much fun if the whole Windows ecosystem just kind of leveled
Speaker 2:  up. But also we've been burned on this specific promise several times in
Speaker 2:  the past.
Speaker 7:  It's like, if I sound cautious, it's because of those two burn moments in
Speaker 7:  the past.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. But it does, I I think if it's, if it's ever gonna happen, it feels
Speaker 2:  like it might happen right now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think if it, if it doesn't happen right now, then I mean they've
Speaker 7:  blown it, right? Like everything that they've showed in all the, all these
Speaker 7:  big promises, it'll be pretty crazy if if they, it doesn't
Speaker 7:  live up to that. You know, if, if the performance isn't there, these AI features
Speaker 7:  don't work properly or like the battery life just sucks, then Microsoft's
Speaker 7:  blown it. Right? So they kind of have to have done it this time. Otherwise
Speaker 7:  there's a lot on the line given the way that they've been talking and the,
Speaker 7:  the confidence that they're, that they're putting into this.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Yeah. I realized going in that there were a
Speaker 2:  bunch of people who bought iPad Pros last week who were looking at the Surface
Speaker 2:  Pro this week being like, oh maybe I wanna surface Pro. And it's like, oh,
Speaker 2:  if Microsoft's doing that, they've done it, they're back.
Speaker 7:  That's true. Yeah. It's not, it's not as thin and and like as sexy
Speaker 7:  hardware as the iPad Pro I'd say. But yeah, I mean,
Speaker 2:  But it runs all my apps
Speaker 7:  Tom. Yeah, it runs all your apps. You can actually use it. Yeah. So and you,
Speaker 7:  when you're processing in video and you tap a notification, it's not
Speaker 7:  gonna kill that video in the background like it's an actual os. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, a hundred percent. Alright Tom, you got meetings to get to. Thank you
Speaker 2:  for, for jumping on and doing this. I appreciate it. Yeah, no worries. Good
Speaker 2:  luck with the rest of your stuff in Redmond.
Speaker 7:  Alright, thank you. I'll speak to you soon.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break. But actually real quick before we do, you
Speaker 2:  can subscribe now to Tom's new newsletter called Notepad about all things
Speaker 2:  Microsoft. I'll put a
Speaker 2:  last Monday in which the company announced s GPT four oh and a
Speaker 2:  super personable, maybe even flirty voice assistant.
Speaker 2:  Hey,
Speaker 9:  T s GPT, I'm Mark. How are you?
Speaker 10:  Oh, mark, I'm doing great. Thanks for asking. How
Speaker 10:  about you? So I'm on stage right
Speaker 2:  Now, If, you hear that clip and you're like, oh, weird. That sounds like
Speaker 2:  Scarlett Johannson in her. Well, so did everybody else.
Speaker 2:  I mean, listen to this from her.
Speaker 11:  Okay, let's start with your emails. You have several thousand emails regarding
Speaker 11:  LA Weekly, but it looks like you haven't worked there in many years.
Speaker 2:  And now this clip from the OpenAI event.
Speaker 10:  Ah, I see it now. You wrote down three
Speaker 10:  x plus one equals four. Yep.
Speaker 12:  Let's work. Exactly. So what's
Speaker 2:  The first? I could do this forever because the similarities are deeply uncanny.
Speaker 2:  But here's just one more. This is from the s GPT four oh demo. When one
Speaker 2:  of the researchers wrote iHeart Chat s GPT on a piece of paper and then held
Speaker 2:  up his phone camera so it could see it.
Speaker 10:  Of course. I'd love to see what you wrote. Show it to me. Whenever you're
Speaker 10:  ready.
Speaker 12:  Okay, so this is what I wrote down. What do you see?
Speaker 10:  Oh, I see. I love chat s GPT. That's so
Speaker 10:  sweet of you.
Speaker 2:  And now here's a moment from her.
Speaker 13:  You're beautiful.
Speaker 13:  Thank you Theodore.
Speaker 13:  I'm kissing your head.
Speaker 2:  Side note by the way, her is such a good movie, If. you haven't
Speaker 2:  seen it or haven't seen it in a while. Do it. It's even better than I remembered.
Speaker 2:  And given everything that has happened with AI over the last couple of years,
Speaker 2:  it hits different now anyway, other than the fact that the actual product
Speaker 2:  that exists in the world doesn't work quite as well and sounds a little more
Speaker 2:  robotic than the one in the movie. I mean, the vibes here are very
Speaker 2:  similar, both in the product in general and in the Voice
Speaker 2:  specifically to the point where actually over the weekend, OpenAI pulled
Speaker 2:  the voice that you're hearing here, which was named Sky from the product
Speaker 2:  altogether. OpenAI said it wasn't trying to mimic Scarlett Johansen
Speaker 2:  in her, which I find very hard to believe for reasons we'll get into. But
Speaker 2:  then on Monday night, just before this episode went out, Scarlett
Speaker 2:  Johanssen actually gave a statement saying that last September,
Speaker 2:  OpenAI had contacted her about being the voice of s GPT four oh.
Speaker 2:  And as many as two days before, like two days
Speaker 2:  before the event in which they revealed s GPT four oh with this
Speaker 2:  new voice, with this new flirty personality. They were still contacting
Speaker 2:  her, trying to get her to reconsider and do the voice. It's all very strange.
Speaker 2:  And this is the kind of thing we just don't have a lot of history of dealing
Speaker 2:  with. There's just not a lot of precedent for this kind of story.
Speaker 2:  And in general, there are a lot of questions here about what we learned from
Speaker 2:  that s GPT four oh demo and what OpenAI is really up to here
Speaker 2:  and where we're headed in the next few years of ai. And to talk through all
Speaker 2:  of that stuff and more, I grabbed Kylie Robinson, the verges new senior AI
Speaker 2:  reporter, Kylie Robinson. Welcome To. The Vergecast.
Speaker 14:  Thank you for having me.
Speaker 2:  This is what day nine for you at The Verge as we're recording this?
Speaker 14:  Precisely, yes.
Speaker 2:  And you've already been in like 465 news cycles.
Speaker 14:  That is a hundred percent correct. Maybe one more today, but yes,
Speaker 14:  exactly.
Speaker 2:  Has it been so far? How is, how are your first nine days at The Verge?
Speaker 14:  It is so fantastic. It's pure chaos and I think a lot of people looking
Speaker 14:  are like, why are you doing all this? Are they killing you? No, it's because
Speaker 14:  it's so fun and I can't stop agreeing to write stuff. So it's been great.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you fit in very well in that respect. Mostly I wanna talk about OpenAI.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there's a lot going on, but I think to me, like what's been
Speaker 2:  interesting is there's been a ton of news the last two weeks and the only
Speaker 2:  thing I can think about is that OpenAI demo, oh my God. 27
Speaker 2:  minutes of just like super awkward OpenAI
Speaker 2:  interactions and I can't stop thinking about it. I don't know. So I'm mostly
Speaker 2:  just curious. You've been covering a OpenAI for a long time. You've been
Speaker 2:  thinking about this company, you've been thinking about AI for a while. You're
Speaker 2:  our senior AI reporter. What did you make of that event? There were all these
Speaker 2:  rumors leading up to this about what OpenAI was gonna do. They did it
Speaker 2:  ahead of Google io. I have to assume deliberately, there were lots of
Speaker 2:  rumors. None of those rumors turned out to be true. This was like this other
Speaker 2:  thing. Like what, where was your head during that event? What were you thinking
Speaker 2:  about?
Speaker 14:  Well, I was really excited for it to be this huge, huge thing.
Speaker 14:  They, they built it up so much. So you know, the rumors were,
Speaker 14:  it's gonna be a search engine that rivals perplexity in Google. It's going
Speaker 14:  to be s GPT five. So when we got s GPT four, oh it's
Speaker 14:  cool. It is how natural this is. It's very sci-fi.
Speaker 14:  But I, I did my first TikTok for The Verge and my
Speaker 14:  takeaway was this is so flirty. Do do we need flirty ai?
Speaker 14:  I don't think so. Just like, you know, not to throw OpenAI completely under
Speaker 14:  the bus. I said the same about X AI's grok. Like do we need a
Speaker 14:  sarcastic snarky ai? I'm not sure. Like
Speaker 14:  yeah, let's get, let's get some other advancements first before it starts
Speaker 14:  being mean and flirty. Some people in the TikTok comments did not agree.
Speaker 14:  These Gen Zers were like, do not take away my, my AI girlfriend please.
Speaker 14:  The announcements. It was interesting. It's not a huge leap forward. I think
Speaker 14:  they definitely wanted to get in front of io. I did talk to the
Speaker 14:  CTO Mira Mirati in a very short briefing after the launch and
Speaker 14:  I asked like, Hey, why today? And she's like, you're asking because of
Speaker 14:  io. And I'm like, well of course. And she said, you know, we didn't even
Speaker 14:  know IO was happening. I'm like, okay,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, cool. I mean that's just, just a lie. That's like not even a good,
Speaker 2:  yeah,
Speaker 14:  I'm like, okay, we're not taking the bait. All right, moving on. But yeah,
Speaker 14:  so it was interesting. Obviously I went to IO and I thought,
Speaker 14:  you know, this stuff is really cool. It was a two hour long keynote. I was
Speaker 14:  there in person. Pretty brutal. But yeah, s GPT
Speaker 14:  4.0, it's cool. It has a long way to go. It kind of feels like the rumors
Speaker 14:  in the AI reporting world is that they had something bigger
Speaker 14:  that wasn't ready in time. So they're like, here's 4.0 Microsoft build
Speaker 14:  is coming up at the end of this month. So I'm kind of
Speaker 14:  expecting something bigger for that. But yeah, it was an interesting demo.
Speaker 14:  Flirty,
Speaker 2:  Talk to me about the flirty thing because I, I confessed, this is the thing
Speaker 2:  I can't stop thinking about. Right. And like you pointed out in the middle
Speaker 2:  of it, like this is just her. And I think Sam Altman even said like
Speaker 2:  referenced her before Mira ti was like, no we're not doing a her thing. Which
Speaker 2:  is like again, obviously not true. Yeah, they're obviously doing a her thing.
Speaker 2:  I'm so torn on this and I'm curious how you're thinking about it. On the
Speaker 2:  one hand, I totally understand why it makes sense for these things to like
Speaker 2:  be fun to talk to. Right. And I don't know if flirty is the correct
Speaker 2:  version of fun to talk to. But again, I think this, this push towards like
Speaker 2:  if you're gonna spend all your time interacting with this thing, it should
Speaker 2:  be enjoyable to interact with and not just some like cold metal robot
Speaker 2:  that you talk to. I totally understand that. I also think that is like a
Speaker 2:  mess. Yeah. And just is for OpenAI and for everybody else will
Speaker 2:  cause as many problems as it solves maybe more
Speaker 2:  and is gonna make all of this really weird before the technology is
Speaker 2:  nearly good enough to actually have any of this work. Like her is a fun
Speaker 2:  example because like she doesn't get basic facts wrong all the time in her.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Like importantly, it's very good technology. Yes. It's not
Speaker 2:  just like flirty Scarlett Johansson but very dumb. Like
Speaker 2:  that's not, that's not what they're doing. And I don't know, I just cannot
Speaker 2:  wrap my head around whether this like 11-year-old movie
Speaker 2:  about a voice assistant is the correct place for us
Speaker 2:  to be going even though I kind of understand why we're going that way. I
Speaker 2:  don't know. And I feel like everybody has had very visceral reactions to
Speaker 2:  it. So I'm curious what, what yours has been.
Speaker 14:  You know, a lot of tech reporters have said like please for the love of
Speaker 14:  God, can these tech executives finish the movies? Like see how it ends,
Speaker 14:  right? Yeah, no, not convinced. We need flirty AI
Speaker 14:  before we have accurate ai. And something I noticed during Google
Speaker 14:  io is that when they were demoing their similar
Speaker 14:  assistance, it was on video, it was not live. And versus
Speaker 14:  open AI's demo was live. So you got to see all the flubs and
Speaker 14:  if the listeners have seen Neli break the
Speaker 14:  AI product,
Speaker 2:  We'll put it in the show notes. It's very good. If, you haven't seen it.
Speaker 14:  It's very good. I was sitting in the press lounge and they came back, they're
Speaker 14:  like, NELI broke it twice. Which is what I expected. That's the goal. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Yes, exactly. So yeah, flirty AI
Speaker 14:  as a tech reporter, it just makes me like, okay, can we, can we do better
Speaker 14:  than this? I don't wanna completely drag them because it is cool that
Speaker 14:  we're finally getting like a working Siri. I was just thinking before we
Speaker 14:  started this episode, when I use Siri almost exclusively as a timer
Speaker 14:  because it doesn't work for anything else. I do laundry and it's
Speaker 14:  50 minutes every time and it always thinks 15 minutes no matter how hard
Speaker 14:  I try. That's how mostly useless it is. So I have to say 55.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Yeah. So flirty AI not super useful. Feels
Speaker 14:  purposeful. Obviously MIRIs said, you know, not the case.
Speaker 14:  She said someone else in the audience asked me that. I don't know, I don't
Speaker 14:  know where they're getting that from. It's just sounds so natural. And I'm
Speaker 14:  like, and and then meanwhile Altman is like her on Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. He just tweeted the word her, didn't he? Yes
Speaker 14:  He did. Yeah. So, and he said, I've been at, I think it was a
Speaker 14:  Dreamforce or something at a conference and he said her was his favorite
Speaker 14:  movie and all his tech reporters were like, noted.
Speaker 14:  So yeah, I think they're trying to inch towards that reality. I don't know,
Speaker 14:  I feel a bunch of different ways about it. What, what were you thinking
Speaker 14:  when you saw it?
Speaker 2:  I thought it was really impressive and I, I just keep coming back to
Speaker 2:  like the immediate reaction. Everybody had to chat s GPT,
Speaker 2:  which is like, I can't believe it's this good. Which is yes,
Speaker 2:  both a compliment and an insult. Right? Like it's not very good. Yes. But
Speaker 2:  it is genuinely impressive that it is as good as it is. Yes. And I feel like
Speaker 2:  I, I've spent a lot of time reporting on AI in the last year and a half and
Speaker 2:  trying to constantly calibrate that, that it's impressive that it's
Speaker 2:  as good as it is and it's also not very good. Like both of those things
Speaker 2:  are true. And it is so hard to hold both of the idea, both of those
Speaker 2:  ideas in your head at the same time. And this to me was like that too. Like
Speaker 2:  I actually went back and watched, it's like a 26 minute video. Everybody
Speaker 2:  should watch it. It's, it's weird and awkward and delightful, but it's
Speaker 2:  actually like, it screws up a lot like a lot in the demo. And again
Speaker 2:  that's like, it's fine. This is new early technology, they're having fun.
Speaker 2:  This is not, they didn't promise that it was perfect. They just sort of showed
Speaker 2:  how it worked. But it screwed up a lot and nobody talked about it. Right?
Speaker 2:  Everybody came to the end of that thing and all over the internet, the immediate
Speaker 2:  reaction was basically like OpenAI just destroyed all of the
Speaker 2:  AI competitors forever. It is leaps and bounds ahead of everybody else.
Speaker 2:  This is the only thing that there is forever and ever. And I just don't
Speaker 2:  think that's true. Like it's cool and it, it, it's a good
Speaker 2:  demo and the fact that it feels it all like a person and does
Speaker 2:  convincing, sounding like ums and laughs and yes. What
Speaker 2:  was it he showed the like I iHeart Yeah. s GPT four. Oh. And
Speaker 2:  it was like, oh that's so sweet. Like yeah. That is both impressive
Speaker 2:  and nothing simultaneously. Exactly.
Speaker 14:  Exactly. I think a really good example of that too, it's like an
Speaker 14:  OpenAI effect is with soa people are like, this has just put all
Speaker 14:  of these text to video AI companies out of business and people like to say
Speaker 14:  they launched it, but neither of us can use it. None. It's still in demo
Speaker 14:  mode. So you know, people are like, wow, OpenAI destroyed everyone. It's,
Speaker 14:  you know, this technology is not even out yet and clearly it
Speaker 14:  has a long way to go when you see it breaking in demos. So yes,
Speaker 14:  it's very hard to hold both of those at the same time. And day nine at The
Speaker 14:  Verge, I'm still figuring out how to balance that.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's tough and I'm curious, I think the SOA thing is actually an interesting
Speaker 2:  example because OpenAI was perceived to have this big lead, right? Like
Speaker 2:  it, it kicked off a lot of this stuff with Chat s GPT, it has been the company
Speaker 2:  we have talked about the most as we talk about ai. But now, like you said,
Speaker 2:  we're in developer conference season, Google just announced, I would say
Speaker 2:  in a significant lead, more polished and less interesting
Speaker 2:  way. Yeah. A lot of the same stuff that OpenAI and Chat s
Speaker 2:  GPT have been doing for a while. Microsoft today, as you're hearing this,
Speaker 2:  is presumably gonna launch some of the same stuff potentially with its own
Speaker 2:  technology. Apple is likely to do some of the same stuff potentially with
Speaker 2:  OpenAI and Thro is out here doing stuff. There's just a million competitors
Speaker 2:  now. So I feel like, one thing I've been thinking about and I'm, I'm curious
Speaker 2:  how you are thinking about this as you like try to sort of map out this
Speaker 2:  space in your mind. Like where is OpenAI in the
Speaker 2:  AI world right now? Is it still winning the race? Does it feel like
Speaker 14:  In the hype perhaps Fair?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 14:  They get, they get a lot of hype, rightfully so. They do deliver a lot of
Speaker 14:  mind bending sci-fi kind of stuff. And that's part of why I joined this
Speaker 14:  beat. 'cause wow, I, you know, I loved reading sci-fi books. This is all
Speaker 14:  very weird and fun. Totally. I was speaking to someone at a major AI
Speaker 14:  company who said that essentially everyone's just you this year, you're
Speaker 14:  just gonna see them leapfrog over each other as they all go towards the
Speaker 14:  same thing. You know, they're all sort of training models in the same
Speaker 14:  way. They're all trying to deliver the same products. So it's
Speaker 14:  hard to say like, tomorrow things can change this, this
Speaker 14:  beat, this technology moves so fast. I felt this way when Sora
Speaker 14:  came out because I had just interviewed the CEO of Runway for
Speaker 14:  a piece.
Speaker 2:  What's Runway?
Speaker 14:  Runway is a text to video startup, AI
Speaker 14:  generative startup. And they helped create everything
Speaker 14:  everywhere all at once. So some of the AI tech was used in that. So
Speaker 14:  they're a very cool company and I thought when I saw their demo, this is
Speaker 14:  Sci-Fi and cool. But then SOA came out and I was like, oh my god,
Speaker 14:  this is crazy. And I sent it to the runway CEO and he was like, welcome
Speaker 14:  to our world. Like things change so quickly every day.
Speaker 14:  So who, how is AI in the race? Like where are they in the, in the
Speaker 14:  race there's still leaps and bounds ahead of maybe you know,
Speaker 14:  someone like Amazon. But things can change at any point
Speaker 14:  and I think we're gonna see that a lot this year. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I do. I've come to think that that is why it's so chaotic
Speaker 2:  is because there is this sense that this is like a land grab moment and
Speaker 2:  it's all happening so fast that you actually still kind of can
Speaker 2:  catch up. Like I, I remember a year ago hearing stories from people that
Speaker 2:  were like, oh only a few companies are gonna be able to do this training
Speaker 2:  the models is so expensive and so hard it's not gonna work. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 2:  there's some truth to that, but also there is so much open
Speaker 2:  space in this market right now and there's so much money in it that it feels
Speaker 2:  like we're probably at least a couple of years away from any of this feeling
Speaker 2:  at all settled. And so if you're a company that is like, we wanna find a
Speaker 2:  place to make a lot of money very quickly and we kind of think we can win
Speaker 2:  because no one really has yet. Yeah. This is probably the place to do it
Speaker 2:  for better and for worse.
Speaker 14:  Definitely. I agree. So
Speaker 2:  You mentioned all of these companies sort of working towards the same thing
Speaker 2:  like that the, the North Star is coming into view. What do you feel like
Speaker 2:  that thing is that everybody has pointed towards,
Speaker 14:  You know, as an avid Vergecast, a fan and listener, I've been hearing
Speaker 14:  you talk about hardware in your ears and I think
Speaker 14:  it was Meta a scoop came out from the information about Meta doing like
Speaker 14:  headphones or ai. Yes. I thought I was at
Speaker 14:  a south by party and we were going around asking questions about technology
Speaker 14:  and something I said that's way ahead of its time is hardware, like this
Speaker 14:  AI hardware. Which turned out to be true. That was a couple months before
Speaker 14:  we saw the R one and the humane pin. Something that was really shocking
Speaker 14:  to me as I joined this beat is how much these AI companies are
Speaker 14:  investing in robotics and bringing this AI into like a physical plane. 'cause
Speaker 14:  I thought that that's way off. We're not gonna be there anytime soon. But
Speaker 14:  they're seemingly investing quite hard into
Speaker 14:  like you, you have the Ray Band meta, the Meta Ray bands. It looks like
Speaker 14:  Sam Altman is doing something with Love from, which is Johnny
Speaker 14:  Ives startup. So where is this headed? I think we're gonna see more of those
Speaker 14:  conversational AI assistance we have
Speaker 14:  what we saw at Google io. I would kind of love this world where
Speaker 14:  AI's doing everything for me. 'cause I have too many emails and too many
Speaker 14:  notifications, but I'm also pretty torn on how they're using
Speaker 14:  my data. Yeah. Obviously. But yeah, so I think we're gonna see
Speaker 14:  more advances in in hardware. I'm
Speaker 2:  So surprised to hear you say you think hardware is the thing. Like it's,
Speaker 2:  it is music to my gadget loving years. But like
Speaker 2:  I've been wondering at this moment after Humane
Speaker 2:  failed so badly and Rabbit failed so badly and like those companies aren't
Speaker 2:  dead and this stuff moves fast. Yes. And like the My Rabbit R one updates
Speaker 2:  like every other day at this point and it's ridiculous. But that one
Speaker 2:  particular version of that kind of thing is just clearly not
Speaker 2:  gonna work. Right? Yes. And I think it was very telling to me that that OpenAI
Speaker 2:  demo, they're just sitting there talking into a phone. Yes. And I, I saw
Speaker 2:  a bunch of people pointing that out out that like, this is actually the
Speaker 2:  way that we do this is we sit here and I hold my phone in my hand and I talk
Speaker 2:  to it. And that is the interface for AI that we are doing right now. And
Speaker 2:  I have a lot of theories about why that's not the case forever. But I did
Speaker 2:  kind of wonder like, are we, are we gonna put off the stream for five years
Speaker 2:  in order to let some of that stuff get better and then we'll worry about
Speaker 2:  the hardware because phones are great and they'll get us where we need to
Speaker 2:  go. But I have to say, I find it's very exciting to me that these companies
Speaker 2:  are still buying into the idea that hardware is part of
Speaker 2:  the equation. If maybe not the whole thing. At least not for now.
Speaker 14:  See this is where you, you know a lot about this, but I
Speaker 14:  was surprised obviously that they're doing anything in hardware that they
Speaker 14:  still think that this is the case because the humane pin and the R one
Speaker 14:  as nifty as they seem to be, I, I kind of think they're just
Speaker 14:  destined to be in drawers collecting dust and not really the next big thing.
Speaker 14:  But Yep. I'm wondering If, you have any tinfoil hat theories about it being
Speaker 14:  an iPhone on stage? 'cause I thought, you know, there is for, for the listener,
Speaker 14:  there's reports that OpenAI and Apple are gonna do this deal where
Speaker 14:  chat s GPT is integrated into the iPhone, which everyone's like, oh my God,
Speaker 14:  once again Siri might work. That could be great. I do see the future
Speaker 14:  just, I mean who, who doesn't wanna just carry their iPhone instead of multiple
Speaker 14:  devices? Like you've mentioned, when I say hardware, just as you've
Speaker 14:  said on The, Vergecast headphones, glasses, I think you said you're
Speaker 14:  not into the glasses idea. I wear glasses, so seems perfect to me.
Speaker 2:  I think If, you wear glasses, it is like a perfect obvious place to
Speaker 2:  go for me. Like I have the, I have the Meta ray band glasses and my
Speaker 2:  problem is, I don't know how long it takes, this is just gonna be, David
Speaker 2:  complains about wearing glasses for a minute. But my problem is how long
Speaker 2:  does it take to wear glasses before you stop noticing that you're wearing
Speaker 2:  glasses? Because I have these, they have like, they have clear lenses, they're
Speaker 2:  transitions, they're actually really useful. I like having a mom all day,
Speaker 2:  but I never stop noticing that I'm wearing glasses and it drives me kind
Speaker 2:  of nuts. And part of that is 'cause they're heavy. But part of that I think
Speaker 2:  is also just like, it's going to be hard to convince people who don't wear
Speaker 2:  glasses to wear glasses.
Speaker 14:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  But maybe I just need to wear them longer. Like do I just need to put these
Speaker 2:  on for three days and I'll get used to it? Well
Speaker 14:  It's taken me about 20 years of wearing glasses to
Speaker 14:  be fair. So I don't even notice them on my face. But Well the
Speaker 14:  answer to that is if meta makes this earbud push, I don't know, If you read
Speaker 14:  the article, but they're still working out some of the kinks reportedly,
Speaker 14:  well
Speaker 2:  'cause it was earbuds with cameras in them, right? Yeah. Which is just the
Speaker 2:  wildest idea. But
Speaker 14:  You feel like they're like found out that If, you have long hair, the cameras
Speaker 14:  are gonna be covered because obviously, and one of my favorite parts
Speaker 14:  is that they're figuring out how to stop it from being too hot, which is,
Speaker 14:  I think something that was experienced with the, the humane pin is that
Speaker 14:  people were like, this is getting really hot. So, you know, catching fire
Speaker 14:  in your ears doesn't sound like a great product. I hope they work that out,
Speaker 14:  especially for you since you can't wear glasses.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm bullish on the idea of headphones being the next thing. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  again, it's partly just as a, as a conduit to your phone, which I think works
Speaker 2:  fine. Exactly. I wanna go back to your point about the iPhone because one
Speaker 2:  of the things that OpenAI, I think this was Sam Altman who said it,
Speaker 2:  that there's a new chat s GPT app for the Mac. And there were a lot
Speaker 2:  of people who I would say reasonably asked, where's the Windows app?
Speaker 2:  Microsoft owns an enormous percentage of your company. You have been partners
Speaker 2:  with them for forever. Like, what the hell? And I think it was
Speaker 2:  Sam, right? Who just said sort of offhandedly like, oh, Mac is just where
Speaker 2:  our users are. Yeah. And then there's an iPhone on stage and it's like, how
Speaker 2:  many conspiracy theories should I read into Yes. Those two facts You tell
Speaker 2:  me.
Speaker 14:  You know, okay. My, my tinfoil hat is that there's beef, I've been told
Speaker 14:  that it's not necessarily true, not by anyone, like just from
Speaker 14:  coworkers from Tom. Tom was like, I have opinions about this, but
Speaker 14:  I just think that there's beef. I I was covering OpenAI during
Speaker 14:  the, the Ouster, the meltdown, and I'm just imagining Satya during
Speaker 14:  his Thanksgiving week, like, dammit, like, why do I have to deal with this?
Speaker 14:  He's on Pivot, he's on like CNBC.
Speaker 14:  So I think what we are, we're seeing with inflection, them
Speaker 14:  bringing in inflection, it seems like there's sort of this potential
Speaker 14:  Apple deal that it feels like there's this decoupling because both are
Speaker 14:  realizing that they've relied so much on the other, and that it's like a
Speaker 14:  codependent relationship. They're like, maybe we should take some time apart
Speaker 14:  is where I see this going, especially with the iPhone on stage, the Mac
Speaker 14:  app. It feels like there's a lot of signs, but that's just my like tinfoil
Speaker 14:  hat for now.
Speaker 2:  I do think it is generally true that companies do that kind of stuff
Speaker 2:  on purpose, I think is is a thing that I have learned over the years is that
Speaker 2:  you, you wanna just think, oh, they just like brought up their phone and
Speaker 2:  did it. And it's like, no. Even the stuff that looks like it's not thought
Speaker 2:  through and rehearsed is usually pretty thought through and rehearsed and
Speaker 2:  is not an accident. And exactly. There was a conversation about what
Speaker 2:  phone they would use for that demo. I'm very confident about that fact. And
Speaker 2:  I think, I mean, to your point, like part of the reason I find this space
Speaker 2:  so fascinating right now is it feels like that uncoupling you're talking
Speaker 2:  about is literally happening like right now in real time at Insane
Speaker 2:  Speeds. Yes. Like between Google IO and WWDC,
Speaker 2:  which is essentially what, like four weeks, we are going to potentially
Speaker 2:  like completely upend the economics of the AI industry.
Speaker 2:  It it like insane, like you think about what the Google search deal
Speaker 2:  has done for Apple and all the regulatory stuff that, that has causing the
Speaker 2:  amount of money that changes hands. And like If, you put something like that
Speaker 2:  into the iPhone through OpenAI, it blows up that whole industry in a crazy
Speaker 2:  way. Or if they just like randomly pick Anthropic, which to me is the most
Speaker 2:  chaotic answer and I would love for that to happen.
Speaker 14:  Delicious. Yes. Just
Speaker 2:  Go open source, be like we went with Meta, we, we did Llama like Apple
Speaker 2:  Siri powered by Llama and just blow up the world. It'd be amazing. But it
Speaker 2:  just feels like all of this was starting not to settle,
Speaker 2:  but to sort of be understandable. You kind of knew where everybody was and
Speaker 2:  what they were working on. And now it feels like between all these relationships
Speaker 2:  and I think especially with Apple, kind of, all of the balls are up in the
Speaker 2:  air again, in a really interesting way.
Speaker 14:  Yes. And something I've been thinking about a lot is sometimes these
Speaker 14:  AI researchers are like, we're building s GPT five. And it's hard to predict
Speaker 14:  what it's gonna do. It's hard to predict what any of this is gonna do. And
Speaker 14:  that's strange as a reporter and just a human in this world. Like,
Speaker 14:  we don't know how this is going to change our lives at any point. Do
Speaker 2:  You think that's part of why they're leaning in on the like
Speaker 2:  flirty personality side of it? Because if it's, if it's delightful, you don't,
Speaker 2:  it doesn't matter that like, yes, having fun with it becomes the
Speaker 2:  point and not the, is it any good at tasks, which is what they wanna get
Speaker 2:  to eventually.
Speaker 14:  I've heard this point before and you know, starting as an AI reporter, people
Speaker 14:  told me not to anthropomorphize the the
Speaker 14:  technology because then it takes the blame off the company
Speaker 14:  and they can blame the ai. So I'm so cognizant of that as I report
Speaker 14:  and then they come out with Flirty AI and it's like,
Speaker 14:  like I'm confused because I think OpenAI also said at some points,
Speaker 14:  you know, it's tech, it's not human. And we saw that
Speaker 14:  with the Google guy who was like, this is real and it's human and
Speaker 14:  you know, so you know, to see all of that and
Speaker 14:  then go, here's your flirty AI girlfriend, like her, it feels
Speaker 14:  strange. But yes, I do think it's an interesting
Speaker 14:  critique to have, like, look over here, this is fun. Don't pay attention
Speaker 14:  to how it barely works, I think is part of the point.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I agree. I will say by the way, that The new York Times has cornered
Speaker 2:  the horny AI beat, so we're gonna have to find, we have to find something
Speaker 2:  else for you to do. I'm really sorry you just, you were too late to the game
Speaker 2:  for the horny AI beat. It's just you can't have it.
Speaker 14:  I was wondering if I could say this on The Vergecast. I, this is a huge
Speaker 14:  day for Kevin Rus. I forgot to message him about it. Yes. He's gonna have
Speaker 14:  10 more girlfriends by the time we finish this.
Speaker 2:  Kevin Rus vindicated every day just gets better and better to be Kevin Rus.
Speaker 2:  Kevin, we love you. Come on The Verge cast. One more thing before I let you
Speaker 2:  go. You mentioned the, the brief Sam Ouster and the one
Speaker 2:  other bit of OpenAI News last week was that Ilya
Speaker 2:  Suki, who was a big part of that story is leaving
Speaker 2:  OpenAI for Good. What do you, what do you make of that story? What do you
Speaker 2:  know about what's going on there? Oh
Speaker 14:  My God, that was about 4:00 PM while I was at Google io and I was like,
Speaker 14:  oh my God. Oh no, no more news. Please. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  that seemed to have caused other people to leave OpenAI as
Speaker 14:  well. The sort of IA cult inside of OpenAI.
Speaker 14:  I don't know, I think I'm really hoping we get some fun
Speaker 14:  discovery maybe from the XAI lawsuit against them to figure out
Speaker 14:  what went down. Not to be totally off course, but when the
Speaker 14:  government is deciding to ban TikTok and everyone's like, where's the receipts?
Speaker 14:  What, what happened? Similarly here, what is happening at
Speaker 14:  OpenAI that caused all this drama and now Ilya is leaving and
Speaker 14:  it all feels very strange. My thoughts are we need
Speaker 14:  a lot more information. I think that is sort of owed
Speaker 14:  as this changes people's lives and how they interact with technology.
Speaker 14:  The meme is what, what does Ilya know? Where is Ilya? I think
Speaker 14:  we deserve some answers there. I don't think we're gonna get them from OpenAI.
Speaker 14:  We're gonna get them from great AI reporters who dig into it. But
Speaker 14:  it's strange. It's really strange.
Speaker 2:  I mean, I, I would think the, the most simple way to read it is
Speaker 2:  that that divide that everyone sort of ascribed
Speaker 2:  the issues to but then kind of waved off was the like doing
Speaker 2:  AI for good versus doing AI for profit. The fact that not only did
Speaker 2:  IA leave, but then a bunch of people, like you said in the IA cult
Speaker 2:  also left suggest to me that that divide or whatever the
Speaker 2:  divide was still exists. And there was some reporting that said
Speaker 2:  Ilya basically never came back to work after all of this. And so it, it,
Speaker 2:  it, it definitely suggests to me that whatever happened last fall is
Speaker 2:  not done happening. Like Sam won in whatever that looks like.
Speaker 2:  But whatever is going on inside of that company seems to still be going on
Speaker 2:  inside of that company.
Speaker 14:  I agree. I think that Rift is still there. The reporting suggests that
Speaker 14:  it was like what EAC versus the Decels people who want this to
Speaker 14:  move fast and people who want this to be a research lab that's
Speaker 14:  for good. I think that Rift is still there and I think that's something
Speaker 14:  you're gonna continue to see in this AI race. I think
Speaker 14:  the people who wanna make money are gonna continue coming out on top as
Speaker 14:  we see here though.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the, I mean as of right now, I think just thinking about Google io,
Speaker 2:  it's like why did they make any of these choices? And the answer is like,
Speaker 2:  oh 'cause there's so much money in it right now, right this minute, there's
Speaker 2:  so much money in it. And will there be forever? Who knows? But there
Speaker 2:  is a lot right now and it is making everybody do truly wild stuff.
Speaker 14:  Yes, exactly that.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, well we're gonna have to have you come back on when
Speaker 2:  we get more stuff from Apple and Build and everybody else. So
Speaker 2:  welcome to hell. And by hell I mean The Vergecast. Kylie, thank you for being
Speaker 2:  here.
Speaker 14:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta
Speaker 16:  you at today explained.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  Send us all of your questions. We've gotten a lot of iPad questions and I
Speaker 2:  think at some point here we're gonna stop answering iPad questions but we
Speaker 2:  try to do at least one on the show every week and at some point we'll stop
Speaker 2:  talking about iPads but this week we have a question about iPads and it comes
Speaker 2:  from Clifton.
Speaker 18:  Hi, this is Clifton from Tacoma, Washington. I was just listening to
Speaker 18:  the case for the iPad Pro podcast and in your comparison
Speaker 18:  to the iPad and the MacBook, I was wondering do you think that
Speaker 18:  the majority of that want for Mac OS on the iPad would go away if Apple
Speaker 18:  just made a touch screen MacBook also on the same token,
Speaker 18:  do you think that if they made a two in one that the work
Speaker 18:  case for pros on the iPad would go away and it would probably just go back
Speaker 18:  as a media consumption device? I think it is similar to
Speaker 18:  Apple thinking. They know what customers want instead of actually doing
Speaker 18:  what customers want. Thanks, I appreciate it. So
Speaker 2:  There's like a big thinky thing at the end there that I kind of wanna ignore
Speaker 2:  for now. Neli Patella is here. Hi Neli. Hey we've like talked
Speaker 2:  around this for two weeks and also like 10 years. So like
Speaker 2:  let's just talk about this like what what do we want from Apple is? I feel
Speaker 2:  like basically the question being asked here, there's the iPad, there's the
Speaker 2:  MacBook and somewhere in the middle there is this idea of like a perfect
Speaker 2:  device that would solve all of our problems. What is it?
Speaker 19:  I think it's an iPad that doesn't have a totally restricted application
Speaker 19:  model. Like that's the problem. The problem is not that it doesn't run Mac
Speaker 19:  Os, what Mac OS represents to people is freedom, right? I can just use this
Speaker 19:  thing like a computer and developers can show up and fill the
Speaker 19:  gaps that Apple has left open. You cannot do that on an iPad.
Speaker 19:  So it's just whatever Apple wants you to do. And if they would just
Speaker 19:  let go, I think these things would evolve on very different
Speaker 19:  trajectories and they just won't let go. Which I guess comes
Speaker 19:  back to what do we want Apple to do?
Speaker 2:  Well I think I, I largely agree like I got a bunch of crap on
Speaker 2:  threads because I posted something to the effect of like I agree that I don't
Speaker 2:  want huge sweeping changes to the iPad but it would be nice to be able to
Speaker 2:  put Windows where I want them to. And a bunch of people like you could put
Speaker 2:  Windows wherever you want and I'm looking at it right now. I can see nine
Speaker 2:  different apps on my Mac right now. I can see them all And that is not how
Speaker 2:  it works on the iPad and there are like a million little things like that
Speaker 2:  to me. But the evolution thing, I'm curious how you think about it.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think the case a lot of people would make is that If, you just let
Speaker 2:  both of these things kind of be everything that eventually
Speaker 2:  they would just crash into each other and the iPad and the Mac would essentially
Speaker 2:  be the same thing. But you don't think that's the case?
Speaker 19:  I don't. I think about a lot of iPad use cases that I see that I think are
Speaker 19:  really interesting. I'm married to a lawyer. Some lawyers show up at
Speaker 19:  meetings with iPads just to sign contracts and get through them. You
Speaker 19:  don't need a Mac laptop for that, right? You don't even, you don't even
Speaker 19:  need the keyboard case for that.
Speaker 2:  Right. And also the fact by the way that it lies flat on a desk or
Speaker 2:  table is actually really important. Like I was thinking about this just form
Speaker 2:  factor wise, right? Like If, you just put a touchscreen on the Mac, does
Speaker 2:  it suddenly solve all of your iPad problems? And like no, because drawing
Speaker 2:  like that sucks. Signing things like that sucks. Like having a
Speaker 2:  thing that just lies down like a piece of paper on a table does change things.
Speaker 2:  I think you're
Speaker 19:  Right. I will note that you have to put a case on some of these iPads so
Speaker 19:  you can actually live fly. But you know, I, I agree with you. There's just
Speaker 19:  a bunch of places where you want to computer in a tablet form factor. That
Speaker 19:  is where the interface is natively touch. Great. Again, we
Speaker 19:  get notes from people who are like interior designers and architects who
Speaker 19:  are like, this thing is my computer. I walk around taking pictures with
Speaker 19:  it and showing people things and drawing on it all day long
Speaker 19:  and I, I kill a battery in my iPad every day, which is admittedly not so
Speaker 19:  hard to do, but there's just a world of use cases that way.
Speaker 19:  And then there's a world of use cases for the laptop form factor. And I
Speaker 19:  think the problem is Apple thinks the form factor
Speaker 19:  is important and not the use cases. Hmm. So they're like, we'll just make
Speaker 19:  it a laptop and now it's a laptop replacement. And I think most people are
Speaker 19:  like, well I use my laptop for all these things and it can't do those things.
Speaker 19:  Right. And then I I, this is just me imposing
Speaker 19:  a belief on Apple. I think Apple wants computers to be
Speaker 19:  easier than the market wants them to be. You know, like people
Speaker 19:  you give a kid a laptop like just crazy stuff starts happening. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 19:  Like they, they start to expand on the boundary of what you can even do
Speaker 19:  with some of these applications. That's really cool. I've seen
Speaker 19:  entire graphic design businesses that have existed
Speaker 19:  by teenagers using the Instagram create mode in ways that no
Speaker 19:  Instagram product manager ever thought that thing would be used. That's
Speaker 19:  the beauty of computers. And to whatever extent that has not
Speaker 19:  happened on the iPad. I think that's the tragedy. And I think it's because
Speaker 19:  of the restrictions in the operating system. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I I tend to agree but I think something you said at the, at the very beginning
Speaker 2:  of this I think is is very striking. Which is the assumption that the best
Speaker 2:  version of this thing is closer to an iPad that does
Speaker 2:  more stuff than it is to a Mac with a touchscreen. Right. Because I think
Speaker 2:  like If you, just to boil this question all the way down, it's like does
Speaker 2:  a Mac with a touchscreen solve all of our problems? And I think the answer
Speaker 2:  is clearly no. And I'm not even sure it solves many of our
Speaker 2:  problems. Like I actually, I look at my Mac and I'm like, I don't know how
Speaker 2:  often I want a touchscreen on this thing. And I think to me when I look at
Speaker 2:  the iPad, the best version of that is so much more interesting than
Speaker 2:  kind of the next version of a Mac. If that makes sense.
Speaker 19:  I'm confident the criticism we will get, because you said that is from a
Speaker 19:  bunch of Windows people who use touchscreens on their Windows PCs all day
Speaker 19:  long and they're like, this is great. Sure. Actually being able to, I think
Speaker 19:  Tom Warren has published a version of this piece. Again, we've had this
Speaker 19:  conversation for so long, I can't tell you if it was a decade ago or yesterday,
Speaker 19:  right. Tom Warren published like touching the screen on a
Speaker 19:  PC is pretty good 'cause we've been talking about it for a long time and
Speaker 19:  it is pretty good. The people who use computers that way, they get used
Speaker 19:  to it. They like it. To me it's, it's really just about the application
Speaker 19:  model and in particular on the Mac because the web browsers are so
Speaker 19:  good and you can run different web browsing engines and
Speaker 19:  Chrome and Safari and whatever else. There's a richness to the experience
Speaker 19:  that you just get. You can just have a lot of the latest things on a Mac
Speaker 19:  because all of the latest things tend to run in the web browser. All of
Speaker 19:  the AI in the world is happening in web browsers. Right. You cannot do that
Speaker 19:  on an iPad like the web browser still pretty much mobile safari. They fake
Speaker 19:  it in different ways. Right. And it's just that, it's that, right? It's
Speaker 19:  Apple has just restricted a bunch of stuff maybe to protect
Speaker 19:  Apple's business model maybe 'cause they have an idealistic vision of what
Speaker 19:  an iPad user should do or how they should work or how easy it should be
Speaker 19:  or to keep you safe or secure, whatever you want to believe about
Speaker 19:  why this has happened. It has happened. And I think those are the limits
Speaker 19:  that people keep bopping up against and saying, oh just let this be a Mac.
Speaker 19:  'cause the, the Mac represents those limits going away and I, I really do
Speaker 19:  think you can see it, you know, on other kinds of tablets that If
Speaker 19:  you let that form factor evolve, it will head
Speaker 19:  towards different places. Like I think it would be really interesting if
Speaker 19:  the solution to the input problem, especially with all the AI we have now,
Speaker 19:  isn't just put a keyboard on it. Right. Like we, we, we just haven't
Speaker 19:  like tried. Yeah. Because we are like maybe the, maybe everything
Speaker 19:  will just, you know how like everything evolves into be a crab. It's like
Speaker 19:  everything is evolving to be a laptop again and like, I don't know, maybe
Speaker 19:  there's some other ways to do
Speaker 2:  It. Well yeah and that's the thing I think like when, when people have asked
Speaker 2:  me over the last few weeks like why are you so hung up on the idea that Apple
Speaker 2:  should or could or ought to make this thing more like a laptop. I just
Speaker 2:  find myself wanting to hold the thing up with the magic keyboard and be like,
Speaker 2:  because Apple made it a laptop. Like The two
Speaker 2:  accessories this company has invested in are a pencil which makes perfect
Speaker 2:  sense and is extremely iPad and I actually think is like iPad plus pencil
Speaker 2:  is by far the most compelling case for an iPad in
Speaker 2:  every way you can imagine. Or it's a laptop. Yeah. Like they just, it just
Speaker 2:  looks like a laptop. It acts like a laptop but the Gmail app is worse. Like
Speaker 2:  that's just, that's the difference and I'm sort of with you in that sense.
Speaker 2:  But like to the Windows point, right, the Surface rhymes
Speaker 2:  with an iPad. I would say almost more than it rhymes with a
Speaker 2:  Mac, right? Like it runs Windows and it can do all the stuff. But in terms
Speaker 2:  of like the spirit of that device, it's so much an
Speaker 2:  iPad. Yeah. And I think actually like Microsoft got that really right And
Speaker 2:  just has not really solved a lot of the software stuff around Windows. Like
Speaker 2:  the surface isn't everything. It could be because of Windows in the same
Speaker 2:  way that iPad is like hamstrung by iPad os but in completely radically separate
Speaker 2:  ways. Well
Speaker 19:  It's two companies reacting to the web in totally different ways. Microsoft
Speaker 19:  just lost to the web. Yeah. No one's developing hot shit win 32
Speaker 19:  applications for the the surface outside of games. Right? You just have
Speaker 19:  to like set those aside. But like the hottest new applications
Speaker 19:  in the world happen on the web. Like that is a thing that's just true.
Speaker 19:  The web has become the dominant place to deploy desktop applications.
Speaker 19:  Great. Microsoft reacted to it by just letting go, by being like, you know
Speaker 19:  what? We built Azure, put your web applications on our cloud service and
Speaker 19:  run OpenAI on our cloud service and we'll make the money there and whatever.
Speaker 19:  We'll just try to get you to use Edge. Yeah. And that is one reaction
Speaker 19:  a big company I make especially 'cause they lost in mobile, they basically
Speaker 19:  had no choice. Apple's response to it is like, no, no that
Speaker 19:  won't happen at all sir. Right. And on our tablet you will
Speaker 19:  deploy applications for the iPad, you will use the app store
Speaker 19:  and indeed there are some cool iPad apps because of it. That's
Speaker 19:  great. Like procreate is an entire company that exists to develop
Speaker 19:  iPad apps and use the iPad in the way that Apple wants people to use. That
Speaker 19:  is great. That's a success story. But there's not a lot of great iPad apps.
Speaker 19:  Like they squeeze the balloon and it didn't get a lot bigger.
Speaker 19:  Like mostly the air went out. There's some balance in there. But you can
Speaker 19:  see those are two reactions to the same problem.
Speaker 2:  All I keep thinking as you say that is like, boy it's ridiculous that Google
Speaker 2:  never figured out how to make decent hardware out of this that like
Speaker 2:  this circling Google did around Chromebooks and Android tablets
Speaker 2:  and all this stuff. Like nobody should be more incentivized to figure out
Speaker 2:  how to do this well than Google. And it just didn't. And that makes me angry.
Speaker 2:  And I just look at my Pixel book and I'm like, God, you could have been something.
Speaker 2:  It
Speaker 19:  Could have been great. I mean I famously bought my mother a Chromebook Pixel
Speaker 19:  the thousand dollar Chromebook several years ago. She still uses it. Yeah.
Speaker 19:  Because it was easier to use than a Windows PC or a Mac.
Speaker 19:  Like you open a Mac today, it has 50 different interface paradigms all happening
Speaker 19:  at you at once. There's a launchpad and Mac apps and a web browser and it's
Speaker 19:  trying to get you to use Safari and all this other stuff has ha And you
Speaker 19:  can run iPad apps and it has an app store but you can also, and it's like
Speaker 19:  that's too much. Like actually just go to a bunch of
Speaker 19:  webpages and use whatever you need to use. There is, and here's a really
Speaker 19:  nice piece of hardware to do. It is pretty good. And I think you
Speaker 19:  look at kind of all the like the steam decks of the world that are running
Speaker 19:  games and Linux now and you're like, oh you could build a kick ass Chromebook
Speaker 19:  right now and is any, is anyone gonna do it? It's like, I don't know. Like
Speaker 19:  we, we've come a long way from the iPad where I'm like, you could build
Speaker 19:  a kick ass Chromebook. But that feels like one version of computing
Speaker 19:  where the restraints are lifted and it does everything everyone wants. And
Speaker 19:  the simplicity that Apple's chasing with the iPad is still there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I really do agree with, and you said this on last Friday, show that
Speaker 2:  a desktop web browser, like a true great desktop web
Speaker 2:  browsing environment would immediately solve a lot of people's iPad problems.
Speaker 2:  I think that's, I think that's really real.
Speaker 19:  Yeah. Let us just run Chrome. Look honestly, maybe it'll destroy the battery,
Speaker 19:  it'll light on fire. Like Chrome has a lot of problems. But If, you just
Speaker 19:  let me use an iPad like a Chromebook, eh, you know, like
Speaker 19:  I would still buy the hardware, I would still pay for Apple's various services.
Speaker 19:  I would still need iCloud storage. Like you'll make your money Tim. But
Speaker 19:  like, let me use the computer the way I want to. So
Speaker 2:  Maybe, maybe part of the reason people want a touchscreen MacBook
Speaker 2:  is that that seems like the more likely way to get
Speaker 2:  closer to that perfect middle. Because I think the iPad thing you're describing
Speaker 2:  is like, what if we just blew up the whole way Apple thinks about itself
Speaker 2:  and that'd be cool but seems less likely than there
Speaker 2:  might be a touchscreen on a MacBook. And Mark Germin has reported
Speaker 2:  that Apple's considering that again like it, it has seemed anathema to Apple
Speaker 2:  for a long time. But I, I would track that as probably a more likely
Speaker 2:  sort of nudge towards the perfect all things for all people computer
Speaker 2:  than let's upend the app model entirely.
Speaker 19:  Well I think there's two ways of thinking about it. One, at some point you're
Speaker 19:  just like, it's an M four and it's a keyboard and a screen.
Speaker 19:  They should be the same.
Speaker 2:  I mean I would assume by the way that they will be like, I suspect we are
Speaker 2:  going to get a Mac with basically these exact same specs before very long.
Speaker 19:  Yeah. The only difference between a Mac and an iPad is that Mac doesn't
Speaker 19:  have a random LIDAR sensor and a camera on the back. Sure,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Fine.
Speaker 19:  But I think the other thing that is happening is in Europe
Speaker 19:  there's a bunch of regulations that say you have to let other web browsers
Speaker 19:  on these devices with their own engines and maybe someone just makes a
Speaker 19:  great desktop web browser with the desktop Chrome engine
Speaker 19:  maybe. And like and I, I think as we've already seen with emulators, it
Speaker 19:  really recontextualizes what you can do when you get out of apple's
Speaker 19:  restrictions or those restrictions fade away and other people are allowed
Speaker 19:  to use the hardware to their advantage. So I think that's, the iPad is in
Speaker 19:  all the regulations now there, you know, there's some back and forth on
Speaker 19:  it but they the Europeans or Europeans and they're like, no, we're taking
Speaker 19:  that too. Great. So I, I just think there's something else that might
Speaker 19:  but people still use their laptops. Like I, I can look at our own
Speaker 2:  MacBook. It would all be fine. Alright, we should go Neli. Thank you as always.
Speaker 19:  See ya.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who came
Speaker 2:  on the show and thank you especially as always for listening. There's lots
Speaker 2:  more on everything we talked about at The Verge dot com, tons from the surface
Speaker 2:  event and all The new Microsoft things, all of our OpenAI coverage,
Speaker 2:  everything about iPads, all of it. We'll put it in the show notes, but also
Speaker 2:  read The Verge dot com. It is just a crazy newsy week. Microsoft build
Speaker 2:  is today. Developer conferences are everywhere. AI stuff is everywhere. There's
Speaker 2:  just a ton going on. As always. If, you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or PC recommendations for me? You can always email us at vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 VERGE one. One.
Speaker 2:  Like I said, I love hearing from you. We have a Slack room that just pumps
Speaker 2:  in every voicemail and we get to listen to it. It's so much fun. It is my
Speaker 2:  absolute favorite thing both about maybe my job and definitely about being
Speaker 2:  in Slack. If, you've got ideas, thoughts, questions. Keep it all coming.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Angel Marino, Liam James, and Will Pour The. Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex
Speaker 2:  and I will be back on Friday to talk more about, build more about AI and
Speaker 2:  everything else going on in tech this week. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll.