# Transcript
ID: 54a13a32-9574-4caf-9383-ff5c124390b8
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5272608857897820425/1577091959878667776/s93290-US-7258s-1734690057.mp3
Description: Happy holidays! Before we disappear into family time and catching up on our favorite shows, we have one more episode for you. And it's 90 minutes of deep nerdery about the smart home. Every year, we try to dig into one standard or spec that has impacted our lives this year, and we couldn't think of anything more potentially great and occasionally infuriating than Matter. Matter is supposed to be the protocol that makes the smart home work — so, uh, how's that going? The Verge's Jennifer Pattison Tuohy joins to discuss the state of the smart home, before we play a game to see how well we understand things. Then, Home Assistant creator Paulus Schoutsen tells us what it's like to try and make Matter work, and where we might be headed next year.
Speaker 3:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Eli's new wifi
Speaker 3:  equipped oven, which I think has just been delivered very recently. Neli
Speaker 3:  sells here. Hi Neli.
Speaker 4:  We have new oven and new dishwasher. These are our big Black Friday purchases.
Speaker 4:  They, they use different apps. This is gonna be a real theme.
Speaker 3:  This is uni. Ironically, what we are here to talk about, gen two is also
Speaker 3:  here. Hi Jen.
Speaker 5:  Hi. Happy to be here. Happy holidays.
Speaker 3:  This is our holiday spectacular and this year, If you didn't
Speaker 3:  already know from the title of this episode, our topic has matter
Speaker 3:  and the smart home that both is and is not and will solve all of our
Speaker 3:  problems and will make us all miserable until the end of time. And so we're
Speaker 3:  gonna, we're gonna dig deep into this. We, we have some time with Paul
Speaker 3:  who runs Home Assistant later on. We're gonna play some games, but I think
Speaker 3:  we should, we should just level set here first. And Jen, I
Speaker 3:  think you are the correct person to do this for us. Before Neil, I gets too
Speaker 3:  deep into his feelings about the smartness of his appliances that have just
Speaker 3:  arrived. Let's just talk about where both what matter is and where it is
Speaker 3:  is kind of in the world right now. So like truly, let's start from nothing.
Speaker 3:  Okay. If you were living under a rock until
Speaker 3:  six minutes before you press play on this podcast, what is matter?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so Matter is a open
Speaker 6:  source standard for the smart Home. It is created,
Speaker 6:  it was created by over 200 different companies spearheaded by
Speaker 6:  some of the big players. Apple, Google, Samsung, Amazon.
Speaker 6:  It is designed as a communication and
Speaker 6:  interoperability protocol for your smart home. Basically, it's
Speaker 6:  designed to make any smart connected device that you buy,
Speaker 6:  microwave, dishwasher, fridge, smart light,
Speaker 6:  smart lock, be able to talk to each other in your home, communicate
Speaker 6:  locally in your home, as well as communicate to a smart home platform
Speaker 6:  like Apple Home, Home Assistant, Google Home, so that
Speaker 6:  we couldn control those devices locally. We couldn use
Speaker 6:  your smart home on any platform that you like. This is one of the
Speaker 6:  key sort of features of Matter is that because all of the big
Speaker 6:  platforms are onboard, that any matter device should work
Speaker 6:  with any smart home platform. And you know, the
Speaker 6:  manufacturers don't have to develop individual partnerships with different
Speaker 6:  companies in order to work with Apple HomeKit or to work with Amazon Alexa.
Speaker 6:  If you work with Matter, you should be compatible with all the platforms.
Speaker 6:  So it's designed to make the smart home simpler,
Speaker 6:  more reliable, more secure, and much more
Speaker 6:  interoperable.
Speaker 3:  So in theory, NELI buys on Black Friday
Speaker 3:  some fancy new stove and dishwasher. Yes. Sticks
Speaker 3:  it in, plugs it in Magic smart home
Speaker 6:  In theory. How's that going,
Speaker 3:  NELI? How'd go? How we doing? It's
Speaker 4:  Not, it's not going great. Not going way. I wanna be clear that our microwave
Speaker 4:  in refrigerator are also have different apps.
Speaker 6:  Okay. This is
Speaker 4:  Just the, this is the nature of the beast, but it's also, we have a bunch
Speaker 4:  of smart plugs in our house and a Lutron light switch system,
Speaker 4:  and that isn't part of matter. And then we have Phillips Hu Lights in one
Speaker 4:  room. And that isn't part of matter. I, I suspect
Speaker 4:  no matter what we do, we'll be drawn to talking about smart vacuum
Speaker 4:  cleaners like the heat death of the universe. Just that
Speaker 4:  is the black hole of all smart home gadgets. It feels like none of those
Speaker 4:  around, but there's, I I'm aware that the standard is coming to, to support
Speaker 4:  it. Yes.
Speaker 6:  And this is,
Speaker 4:  There's, there's just a lot of that.
Speaker 6:  Yes, it's coming. There is a lot of that. That is true.
Speaker 6:  But it's a standard. Right? And it's only been around two years to be, to
Speaker 6:  give it some, some wiggle room. That's not a long time
Speaker 6:  in the scope of developing a standard. Although it was launched and
Speaker 6:  announced 2019, it took them a couple of
Speaker 6:  years to get all the ducks in a row. And, which
Speaker 3:  I think to be fair, given, given what happened after 2019, right? I think
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm very forgiving of things happening slowly. Yes.
Speaker 4:  No, that was your time to focus.
Speaker 3:  We all got into like sourdough baking you like there's no time for connectivity
Speaker 3:  Sanders.
Speaker 6:  Well, but we also all kind of got into our homes a bit more and into the
Speaker 6:  home that is, it was kind of a, in a way, a good moment for the smart home.
Speaker 6:  But it, what they've been doing since the launch is adding
Speaker 6:  more device types, more support for features
Speaker 6:  part that are part of the devices that you use. But ultimately
Speaker 6:  the, the idea of matter is just this connectivity layer, like the plumbing
Speaker 6:  for your smart home, the wifi for your smart home. You know, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  the connectivity that will enable you to do all of the fancy
Speaker 6:  things that you might want to do with your smart home. Like have your smart
Speaker 6:  lights turn on in the morning when you say good morning, or when you walk
Speaker 6:  past a motion sensor or have your smart locks lock and your lights
Speaker 6:  turn off and your thermostat adjust at night when you say goodnight. And
Speaker 6:  there's also more sort of ambitious ideas about like whole home energy
Speaker 6:  management. And this is where smart appliances come into play
Speaker 6:  having, you know, because the, the butt of the internet of things jokes is
Speaker 6:  other fridges and the dishwashers and the microbes. Like, why do I need to
Speaker 6:  connect these devices to wifi? What, what benefit do I get other than an
Speaker 6:  alert on my phone telling me that my dishwasher's done? Which actually is
Speaker 6:  quite
Speaker 3:  Useful. Mine plays like a six minute long song every time it's finished.
Speaker 3:  So I, I feel like I know pretty successfully when it's done.
Speaker 6:  But w once we can connect all the energy devices on our homes,
Speaker 6:  including things like home battery storage systems, solar panels,
Speaker 6:  HVAC systems, all of that to home energy
Speaker 6:  management platform, we couldn, you know, can see some potential there for
Speaker 6:  saving energy, saving money. There are some use cases sort of down the
Speaker 6:  line that are more than just the fun, the shades are gonna go up when you
Speaker 6:  say good morning, which are fun and we like those things, but there's, there's
Speaker 6:  a big, you know, there's a big whole sort of long goal of
Speaker 6:  what's the smart home use case could be. It is a long term
Speaker 6:  goal. And I think we are, we have not got very far
Speaker 6:  in the first two years.
Speaker 3:  Fair. Yeah. To that end, you, you have prepared for us a, a report
Speaker 3:  card of what is real and what is not, which is, I feel like every time you
Speaker 3:  come on the show and we talk about this, it's, it's like what if this is
Speaker 3:  actually real in real life for real people. Yeah. And that
Speaker 3:  is like the eternal question of matter. And one, I suspect we're gonna spend
Speaker 3:  a bunch of time here talking about, do you wanna take us through the, the
Speaker 3:  report card you've given for matter so far? Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And you know, it's the end of the year, so, and I have two teenagers
Speaker 6:  in high school, so report cards are heavily on my mind. This is also
Speaker 3:  This, this is a useful place to start. How tough a parent are you when it
Speaker 3:  comes? Like are you the, like why is this a minus not an a plus kind of parent?
Speaker 3:  Or are you like, oh, tight a D is technically passing. Great job,
Speaker 6:  I'm going with that one. Oh wow.
Speaker 4:  See, my, my dad in particular was If you get straight A's, I
Speaker 4:  won't care about how much additional trouble you get into
Speaker 6:  Ah, that's a good,
Speaker 4:  Which is an incredible incentive. He did end up talking to every principal
Speaker 4:  I ever had.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I, I don't know that the smart home is there. Like it hasn't earned that
Speaker 4:  grace.
Speaker 3:  You definitely strike me as somebody who got a lot of parent teacher conferences
Speaker 3:  that were like, he has the highest grade in the class, but he is a gigantic
Speaker 3:  pain. Can you fix that? And your parents were just like you said, he is getting
Speaker 3:  the highest grade in the class. So we're cool that
Speaker 4:  That is more, that was more or less my father's coach. I just want to be
Speaker 4:  very clear, that is not where matter is at all.
Speaker 4:  No, like you're not like, this is so good. I will put up with
Speaker 6:  The fact I with anything, the
Speaker 4:  Kitchen's on fire, right? It's much more like, are you here?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Matters is getting the parent teaching conference where
Speaker 4:  It's so first grade Jen. Yeah. Present at
Speaker 4:  attendance.
Speaker 6:  Okay, attendance. Oh. Oh that's a tough one.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think actually 2024 we kind of felt like matter
Speaker 6:  was maybe playing a little bit of hooky
Speaker 6:  Because that, that wasn't, I mean we had so much momentum in the
Speaker 6:  first year. There was a lot of new devices, a lot of new device types,
Speaker 6:  a lot of companies jumping on board. This last year was a little quieter.
Speaker 6:  And also we had two spec releases, which they promised and they were very
Speaker 6:  much kind of fixing problems. The biggest thing that I've
Speaker 6:  been sort of disappointed with this year has been that we're not, we have
Speaker 6:  not seen a ton of new products, especially in these new categories, which
Speaker 6:  are really kind of new to the smart home. Like the home energy management
Speaker 6:  and the appliances. There isn't, there just haven't been a lot of
Speaker 6:  of new devices that have come to market. So it's like the
Speaker 6:  system and the infrastructure's there. So you know, the school's there, but
Speaker 6:  you know, maybe they didn't actually show up toward the classes,
Speaker 3:  Which is pretty important, I would say. Yes, it is in the, the school existing
Speaker 3:  is is good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. It's
Speaker 3:  Not the whole job. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's, that's my sort of biggest downgrade
Speaker 6:  here isn't really matters problem, but it's the platform's problem.
Speaker 6:  So we have these device types that have all been added in the last
Speaker 6:  year or two, like robot vacuums, but the platform support
Speaker 6:  has been very slow and spotty and,
Speaker 4:  But but platform support, you mean Apple and Google, right?
Speaker 6:  I mean the ecosystems, the smart home ecosystems. Yeah. Who you know, and
Speaker 6:  that's interoperability. Working with every ecosystem
Speaker 6:  is kind of the, the most consumer facing element of matter. Like
Speaker 6:  oh great, I can buy this smart lock or this smart plug and I don't need to
Speaker 6:  worry whether it works with Apple or works with Alexa. If it works with Matter,
Speaker 6:  it will work with whichever smart and platform I want to use. And I may start
Speaker 6:  out with Apple Home and then decide, actually I wanna upgrade and work with
Speaker 6:  Home Assistant as we will talk about later. But Als, you know, and I can
Speaker 6:  do that without having to go buy new products because everything works with
Speaker 6:  everything. However, you know that that falls apart when
Speaker 6:  we say, oh, this Smart fridge is matter compatible, there
Speaker 6:  is one out there that we couldn buy. I'm guessing it's not the one you bought,
Speaker 6:  Eli, sadly. But I go to my Apple Home
Speaker 6:  app and I scan my matter code thinking well it's matter And it works with
Speaker 6:  Apple and no, because Apple doesn't support fridges yet. You know, there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of this. So we're still waiting for the ecosystems to catch up
Speaker 6:  with support for what the CSA connectivity
Speaker 6:  Standards Alliance, the group behind Matter is rolling out with each new
Speaker 6:  spec and each new spec release when we're getting two a year.
Speaker 6:  So that there's, there's about, they're getting a, the, the ecosystems are
Speaker 6:  getting like a C minus there at the moment. There just isn't. That's
Speaker 4:  Great enough. I just wanna be clear that that's great inflation. Great
Speaker 6:  Inflation.
Speaker 3:  I don't know, I feel like a C is a strong, like you tried, you didn't
Speaker 3:  try a lot, but you did try. You, you filled out
Speaker 3:  all the answers on the test,
Speaker 3:  which is just C you did the whole scan tr C, C.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well and the other problem we have there is that these were all supposed
Speaker 6:  to be device types are supposed to work in one platform
Speaker 6:  or on two platforms or three platforms or up to five platforms, right? So
Speaker 6:  when you add something to Google Home, you should then be able to put it
Speaker 6:  in Samsung Smart things relatively easily. That process
Speaker 6:  for different, not in every case, but in a lot of cases has been very
Speaker 6:  difficult, doesn't always work and frustrating to use.
Speaker 6:  And that is where I would say we, we, they get a D for
Speaker 6:  that kind of interoperability fair. And the CSA basically came along and
Speaker 6:  said, we actually have to fix this and tell you how to do it because you're
Speaker 6:  not doing it yourself very well.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well can, can I just put that it, make that very real for
Speaker 4:  listeners. What, what you're describing is I set up my house
Speaker 4:  in Apple home on my phone, right? I'm like, here are all
Speaker 4:  the rooms in my house, there's a bedroom, there's a bathroom, there's a garage,
Speaker 4:  there's a front door, whatever that is. And then the second I want to
Speaker 4:  use that in Google Home or Samsung Smart things, I
Speaker 4:  gotta do it all again. Right? Like that level of
Speaker 4:  interoperability just doesn't exist anywhere.
Speaker 6:  Well and not completely do it all again. Like that's what you used to have
Speaker 6:  to do. You used to have to then like, you know, reset up a device
Speaker 6:  entirely. But now there is some communication. So
Speaker 6:  you go into your home Apple Home app, you take a code
Speaker 6:  and then you go into your Smart Things app and you paste that code in.
Speaker 6:  And that's supposed to make it like that's slightly fewer steps than
Speaker 6:  it would've been prior where you might have to link to your Samsung account
Speaker 6:  and connect to the cloud and put in your password and your username and then
Speaker 6:  sync the devices and rename the devices in your platform, your new
Speaker 6:  ecosystem. So there's a, there's some fewer steps with Matter
Speaker 6:  multimin and it's all working locally. No cloud dependency, no need to
Speaker 6:  sign up for an account. Well I mean you need to sign up for a Google Home
Speaker 6:  or a Samsung account, but depending on the platform you're using. But what
Speaker 6:  we are not getting yet, what they've promised us now and
Speaker 6:  that's coming, hopefully coming soon, is a theme of
Speaker 6:  this for sure is that you're going to be able to, when
Speaker 6:  you set something up in, in Google Home, if you've already authorized
Speaker 6:  Samsung Smart things, it will automatically show up in that
Speaker 6:  other platform, which is how it should have worked from the beginning. That's
Speaker 6:  how everyone assumed it was gonna work. Like this is how interoperability
Speaker 6:  should work and that is something that they've said that they are working
Speaker 6:  hard on and that we should see hopefully next year. So
Speaker 6:  I dunno, maybe a C for effort.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm sorry Jen, you're so kind.
Speaker 6:  I'm be too kind.
Speaker 4:  C for
Speaker 3:  Effort. Did you guys get effort grades in school?
Speaker 6:  No. Completion grades? My, my kids get completion grades. As long as you
Speaker 6:  just finish the work. This
Speaker 4:  Is why American competitiveness is falling off the charts.
Speaker 3:  Our letter grades were like the actual grade that you deserved, but then
Speaker 3:  you would also get a one, two or three for effort and a one was like
Speaker 3:  doing your best. A two was like, you're fine, you're here sometimes. And
Speaker 3:  a three was like, you're not trying hard enough. And like the great accomplishment
Speaker 3:  was to get like an A plus three in a class, which is like you're doing the
Speaker 3:  least but crushing it really
Speaker 6:  Good. And I mean like
Speaker 3:  I feel like matters effort, grades could use a little work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well
Speaker 6:  I know Nila, you look very perplexed, But first of
Speaker 3:  All I
Speaker 4:  You talking about like, you take the test, you get a hundred percent and
Speaker 4:  then you move on and you smoke cigarettes behind the Fieldhouse. Like that
Speaker 4:  was school for me, but I with matter like C
Speaker 4:  for effort is a real, I see, I see that there is
Speaker 4:  effort. I think I'm just stuck on the,
Speaker 4:  the end. Everyone agrees on what the end product is. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 4:  just, you buy whatever you want And it all works together. And maybe there's
Speaker 4:  a little bit of setup, like you need to tell the Google Home like, hey, I
Speaker 4:  already have a smart home. Like there's smart lights and all these
Speaker 4:  rooms. Like go find them. And it needs to immediately learn
Speaker 4:  everything that you've set up in whatever other system, right? You've already
Speaker 4:  set up all your rooms in Alexa and you've already assigned all the lights
Speaker 4:  to whatever rooms and then you buy a Google Nest hub. 'cause you want the
Speaker 4:  photo frame feature And it already just knows what you're talking about.
Speaker 4:  It just feels like the industry, there's a negative incentive
Speaker 4:  to do that. Like they don't want to, they know they have to, right?
Speaker 4:  They, they know that in order for any of this to happen at scale
Speaker 4:  for mainstream consumers, they've got, they've got to make this all work.
Speaker 4:  They've got to make it simpler. They, none of them wanna make light bulbs
Speaker 4:  and light switches on their own. Like as much as I think there's probably
Speaker 4:  a proprietary Apple light bulbs somewhere in a design lab like Apple knows
Speaker 4:  that's a bad product for it to make. So it, it needs the ecosystem
Speaker 4:  to be cross compatible. And indeed, I think Jen, they, they basically like
Speaker 4:  gave HomeKit to matter. They're like, just use this. Yeah. Like we
Speaker 4:  made it, it's pretty good. Just use it. But there's still the negative
Speaker 4:  incentive of we should put all of our effort into making it work all the
Speaker 4:  way, all the effort is on like what if we lit up the vacuum cleaner
Speaker 4:  support or what if my, the only reason to use
Speaker 4:  the app on my fridge is there's a button in the app that makes it make ice
Speaker 4:  faster for 12 hours. Right? That's it is an amazing
Speaker 4:  button. Incredible button. And like sometimes I'm on the couch,
Speaker 4:  I'm like, fuck yeah. More ice. Like I hit the button and like, I can't
Speaker 4:  imagine that some Apple designer's gonna put that button in the control set.
Speaker 4:  Like it's never gonna happen. Right? Like there's all this effort on doing
Speaker 4:  this stuff that isn't even gonna be useful stuff And it doesn't feel like
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of effort on I think what you're calling multimin. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Where you just buy something and it's like, I'm in your smart house. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like here's all the controls. It's super interoperable and like exactly what
Speaker 4:  you wanted. And that, that to me is like, that's not a C, that's like
Speaker 4:  D minus for multimin effort.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well you're right. There's no incentive for them to do it. But if they
Speaker 6:  don't make, if matter doesn't work at its basic foundational level,
Speaker 6:  then it, it takes away the incentive for them
Speaker 6:  to use matter in the first place. Like it's, it's a real sort of flywheel
Speaker 6:  here in that they need, they need matter because we need to make the
Speaker 6:  smart home simpler. It is too complicated for people these days, you know,
Speaker 6:  for most average homeowners who are looking or you know,
Speaker 6:  renters who are looking to smarten their home, it's too complicated.
Speaker 6:  And this, the entire purpose here is to make it easier, but
Speaker 6:  it's like the swan, you know, it's meant to look all sleek
Speaker 6:  and wonderful on top, but on the underneath it's like crazed because
Speaker 6:  there's so much that has to happen to make it easy. It's very hard
Speaker 6:  to make something simple.
Speaker 3:  And it does feel like you as the user still have to know too much of that
Speaker 3:  stuff. Like we just have to get to the point where border
Speaker 3:  router is not a terminal person
Speaker 6:  Needs, needs to know not
Speaker 3:  Something. Yeah. And it doesn't feel like we're there yet.
Speaker 6:  That's what they're pushing for though. And that's what I hear, I hear from
Speaker 6:  the CSA all the time. It's like you shouldn't need to know about what matter
Speaker 6:  is, it should just work. Just like you don't need really, most people don't
Speaker 6:  really know what Bluetooth is or what wifi is or what electricity like
Speaker 6:  it. You just plug it in And it Well,
Speaker 4:  Can I just disagree? First of all, I have a number of things to say about
Speaker 4:  this one. Most people are so deeply
Speaker 4:  painfully aware of Bluetooth.
Speaker 3:  Jen, I'm so angry. You just bought our Bluetooth. This just this, this just,
Speaker 3:  this just completely derailed If you our fun holiday episode because now
Speaker 3:  Neil's gonna be mad about for
Speaker 4:  An Christmas
Speaker 4:  thoughts on Bluetooth. I'm just saying like, I hear companies say
Speaker 4:  this all the time. Most people should know how it works. Like Yeah, it should.
Speaker 4:  It's just magic. And it's like, dude, everybody is constantly like, my Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  doesn't connect, my car doesn't work. Like yeah, super. What is the wifi
Speaker 4:  password is a thing people say every day of their lives. Like you're aware
Speaker 4:  of this stuff. Yes. Whether or not you want to be, it's how it works.
Speaker 4:  And then I think that that is a rhetorical
Speaker 4:  move that in particular the, the matter folks use
Speaker 4:  because it doesn't work. So If you knew how it was supposed to work, you
Speaker 4:  knew if it was working or not, you'd be able to evaluate whether it was good,
Speaker 4:  whether
Speaker 6:  It was any good. Yes. Right.
Speaker 4:  And we're just at this turn where it's like, well if we just pretend it's
Speaker 4:  magic, you'll be like, that magic's a little less good than the magic I thought.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, that doesn't make any sense. It just doesn't work. And that,
Speaker 4:  like that to me is like,
Speaker 4:  I want more people to have smart, I I think it's cool to have a smart house,
Speaker 4:  like a bunch of my house is smart. It's neat. Yeah. But it's,
Speaker 4:  it's at its best when it is invisible. But making it invisible required
Speaker 4:  me to know how to make it like to know what I wanted to
Speaker 4:  disappear.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. And like there's just a part where it's like, just let it be a computer.
Speaker 4:  Just just say this is a computer and we couldn use it.
Speaker 4:  And then a lot of people I think will dive head first and being like, I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna do some computer stuff.
Speaker 6:  Well I don't think that's, I think that's where we're gonna get eventually
Speaker 6:  it will, there will be sort of a system in our homes, just like we have
Speaker 6:  an electrical panel, we're gonna have a smart home panel that is
Speaker 6:  controlling because, but I think we have to get to the point where the use
Speaker 6:  cases are more compelling for the average user. Mm. Like people
Speaker 6:  need to want to do more than just have their lights turn on when they walk
Speaker 6:  into a room. There needs to be compelling reasons to make your home smart
Speaker 6:  beyond just single, single use cases. Like having a smart lock because
Speaker 6:  you always lose your keys or having a smart garage door opener
Speaker 6:  because you've insist on having your door open automatically as you
Speaker 6:  drive around the corner. Yeah. Because
Speaker 3:  The button right above your head is too hard to press.
Speaker 6:  You know, and, and there are things, there are things that we're seeing coming
Speaker 6:  through matter and through other areas like energy management where I, you
Speaker 6:  could see that the, those kind of use cases are, you know, going to
Speaker 6:  bring the smart home into sharper focus. And I feel like once we get to think
Speaker 6:  those kind of clearer use cases that come from outside of the smart home
Speaker 6:  as well from you know, your electricity company or your cable company
Speaker 6:  who are bringing these types of features into your home, then we might start
Speaker 6:  to see more mass adoption around the smart home and
Speaker 6:  companies jumping into it. And that's what matter is gonna hopefully help
Speaker 6:  with making it easier for companies to come into
Speaker 6:  the smart home. Like we're already seeing, and this is one area where I give
Speaker 6:  them a good grade, more devices. We are not seeing, I haven't seen
Speaker 6:  enough new device types like fridges and stuff, but
Speaker 6:  we are seeing more less expensive gadgets that we couldn
Speaker 6:  go and buy that are gonna work with all the smart home platforms. So there
Speaker 6:  are a lot more Apple Home compatible devices now with Matter for example,
Speaker 6:  than there were even, you know, a year ago we couldn buy a
Speaker 6:  smart switch for like $20 now that will work with Apple Home.
Speaker 6:  That did not used to be the case. It was like $50 If you were lucky
Speaker 6:  If you got it on sale. So we are seeing, you know, it become more
Speaker 6:  accessible, I guess Matter is helping make more
Speaker 6:  gadgets more accessible and you know, we are also,
Speaker 6:  we haven't, I am hearing some complaints from manufacturers that it is
Speaker 6:  still very expensive and complicated to be a matter device and
Speaker 6:  that's a bit of a roadblock because it's only gonna work when there
Speaker 6:  are more, when there's critical mass, when there's a lot that works with
Speaker 6:  Matter. Matter can't be a niche protocol like ZigBee or
Speaker 6:  Z-Wave has been. It, it has to be more general and
Speaker 6:  more mass market.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Matter can't be an upgrade. Like I feel like it's very important that
Speaker 3:  Matter cannot cost more in order for this to work. Yeah. And like ultimately
Speaker 3:  you would want all this smart home stuff to be the
Speaker 3:  cost of the regular things. Right? Right. Mila keeps telling me how great
Speaker 3:  the Lutron Seder light switches are. Yeah. And the yeah, the
Speaker 3:  Kade stuff looks awesome. Holy god. Is it expensive? Expensive.
Speaker 3:  And So I like, we we get to a point where it's like I'm, I'm fine with it
Speaker 3:  being a little more expensive where it's like you, you get, you get more
Speaker 3:  features, it should be a little more but to like five or 10 x the price of
Speaker 3:  my light switch in order to connect it to the internet is just, you're just
Speaker 3:  gonna lose almost everybody.
Speaker 6:  And you know, those are actually their cheapest products. Yeah. Lutron, I
Speaker 6:  guess Lutron's actually in the high end. Yeah, I know. And
Speaker 6:  Lutron is part of the CSA but they have not done anything with Matter and
Speaker 6:  there's a few companies like
Speaker 3:  That who're just counting all their money. They're like, we we're, we're
Speaker 3:  good.
Speaker 4:  They're good, don't worry about it.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 6:  Mean, they've said to me, you know, we're just, we are here, we're we're
Speaker 6:  talking. We want to see what it's, what value it could bring
Speaker 6:  our customers. And at the moment I guess they don't see anything, any value
Speaker 6:  because they already work with all the platforms and they already work locally
Speaker 6:  in your home, but you have to have a bridge. So, and
Speaker 6:  that's one area that matter has, has failed miserably. And
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna give it a really bad grade, is being, being
Speaker 6:  getting rid of bridges and hubs and apps. That was one of the big
Speaker 6:  promises of Matter. Simplicity, no bridges, no
Speaker 6:  hubs and and easy to set up and No,
Speaker 6:  but actually we can, can
Speaker 4:  I use the, the Lutron example not to Cape for Lutron, but
Speaker 4:  I, we, we have Canda switches the hub, there's a hub, you have to buy a little
Speaker 4:  hub. It's itty bitty thing. Right. And, and you look at it,
Speaker 4:  you're like, this will never reach my entire house. But I think Lutron has
Speaker 4:  their, they bought, they bought their own little slice of wireless spectrum
Speaker 4:  so they're just able to do it and like this little hub just like
Speaker 4:  works like light sutures are outside, they're upstairs, they're in the attic,
Speaker 4:  they're in the basement and this one hub is able to talk to them all. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And most other smart home things do not do that. No.
Speaker 4:  Like Ring I think runs on Z-Wave and you need to put Ring
Speaker 4:  extend like little Z-Wave extenders all over your house to cover the whole
Speaker 4:  house for
Speaker 6:  The security system.
Speaker 4:  For the security system for like the door sensors and whatever else. And
Speaker 4:  like, that's the reality of so many of these products is like
Speaker 4:  the radio protocols, If you don't have great wifi throughout your house,
Speaker 4:  matter might fall down and then you, you're like, well then Matter is gonna
Speaker 4:  come with this other protocol called Thread. Thread. Yeah. Which is the,
Speaker 4:  the radio protocol that matter should run on, which is lower power. And now
Speaker 4:  we need to have thread border routers in HomeKit Minis and
Speaker 4:  arrows and whatever else is gonna have 'em. And that stuff doesn't all talk
Speaker 4:  to each other yet. And you're kind of just like, well I get why the Lutron
Speaker 4:  switch is really expensive, right? Like this one itty bitty, it works
Speaker 4:  like it looks like nothing. Like it looks like it shouldn't work and it's
Speaker 4:  like in a closet in my basement And it totally works great. And that's what
Speaker 4:  everyone's competing with.
Speaker 6:  Well and it's, it's kind of a shame because as you'd mentioned,
Speaker 6:  matter was created with several different
Speaker 6:  sub protocols, standards and what was already there. Like Apple
Speaker 6:  donated Home kit, Amazon donated, donated fast pair,
Speaker 6:  Google helped with casting. Like there, there are so many
Speaker 6:  things that different companies came together to bring to
Speaker 6:  matter and if only Luron could have brought its we
Speaker 6:  donating your custom spectrum. Yeah. Instead of
Speaker 6:  threat. Not, I mean threat has its use cases in some areas.
Speaker 6:  Lighting has been one area that it does. They've tried to shoehorn lighting
Speaker 6:  into thread And it just doesn't seem to be working very well. And we've been
Speaker 6:  running into a lot of issues. Nano Leaf and the Cara Nano Leaf, which was
Speaker 6:  all in on Thread has really backpedaled and has created
Speaker 6:  its own its own protocol. Perfect. Perfect.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, there've been issues with Thread. I mean Thread was supposed to,
Speaker 6:  so Matter doesn't have to work on thread just to make that clear. We couldn
Speaker 6:  have Matter without thread. We couldn have matter over wifi and in theory
Speaker 6:  Matter could work over other protocols too, which just hasn't, that hasn't
Speaker 6:  happened yet, but we've got Matter over. You've got But Thread also needs
Speaker 6:  a software layer. It needs an application layer. So Thread has to have Matter
Speaker 6:  or it can have HomeKit or it could have another application layer, which
Speaker 6:  is, you know, so that's getting sort of into the specky details. But you,
Speaker 6:  we couldn have Matter without Thread. Thread was developed specifically to
Speaker 6:  be an IOT protocol, which is, and for the smart home,
Speaker 6:  which is why a lot of people put a lot of faith into it thinking it's going
Speaker 6:  to solve a lot of these problems that we've already sh that we've shoehorned
Speaker 6:  other protocols into like Bluetooth, there are lots of Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  mesh smart lights out there. I still see companies launching Bluetooth mesh
Speaker 6:  Smart lights and I'm like, why are you doing this?
Speaker 6:  But that and Thread is supposed to, you know, it's low power,
Speaker 6:  low bandwidth mesh networking. It has all of these
Speaker 6:  what sound like great
Speaker 6:  attributes for a smart home. But it's, it, the Launch
Speaker 6:  with Matter I think and into such a, a small protocol
Speaker 6:  into such a big space has has caused some
Speaker 6:  significant problems and thread released. It's
Speaker 6:  1.4 Pro Spec this year, which was basically
Speaker 6:  we've seen how thread's working in the real world and now here's everything
Speaker 6:  we're gonna fix to make it work properly. And people are interested
Speaker 6:  in thread. Like I get comments all the time on my articles like why isn't
Speaker 6:  this work with Thread? Why are there so few thread devices I want thread
Speaker 6:  in my home. It's reliable, it works well, but it
Speaker 6:  yeah, it's the, the two together have, have caused a lot of
Speaker 6:  it's two standards working from two with,
Speaker 6:  and I hear this a lot from the CSA, you know, we are a member driven organization,
Speaker 6:  lots of us are talking to create this, so there's no one person kind of leading
Speaker 6:  it and The Thread group's the same. I mean Apple, Google, Samsung,
Speaker 6:  they're all part of The Thread group as well. Apple and Google are all
Speaker 6:  in on thread though, and I think that's why we're seeing so much momentum
Speaker 6:  or so much push for thread. But you're not seeing it so
Speaker 6:  much from the other platforms that, I mean there are long for
Speaker 6:  the ride, but Apple and Google are the ones that are really pushing it,
Speaker 6:  which
Speaker 4:  Is, and Apple can't just do the thing it usually does, which is like, here's
Speaker 4:  the new MacBook, it has no radios except for a thread radio. Right, right.
Speaker 4:  Like that's how Apple Drive
Speaker 6:  Would like to do that. They would, I
Speaker 4:  Mean there's, there's random thread radios and like the new phones and no
Speaker 4:  one knows why. Like they're doing kind of the move they usually do, but
Speaker 4:  with USBC or whatever. Yeah. They were just like, yeah, we took everything
Speaker 4:  else away. Like, would you like to use your MacBook? Right. Welcome to Dongle
Speaker 4:  Town. Like you, they can't do that with Thread in the same way. No, And it
Speaker 4:  feels like that's because no one can just make the push in that way.
Speaker 4:  It's going very slowly.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. What's the line of Camel is just a horse designed by committee, right?
Speaker 3:  Like it feels like this is, it is, this is the camel of the smart
Speaker 3:  home right now.
Speaker 4:  It does feel like every holiday spectacular episode just ends with the, the
Speaker 4:  slow, somewhat depressing reveal that it's just politics.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of politics in this one that is for
Speaker 4:  Sure does how does, how does the standard work and it's like people yell
Speaker 4:  at each other until they die.
Speaker 3:  Well on that holiday, you know, Jen, give us, give us a
Speaker 3:  big overall matter grade and then we're gonna take a break and play some
Speaker 3:  games. What do you think matters? 2024.
Speaker 3:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  Wow. I'm gonna, I'm gonna have to go with a D
Speaker 4:  Present.
Speaker 3:  Present D Yeah, it showed up.
Speaker 6:  It showed up, it made some effort. Okay. It got a few
Speaker 6:  things right, but it's still got a lot of room for improvement.
Speaker 3:  I think the D is right because it's like, it's like the grade you give to
Speaker 3:  the kid who's like not doing great, but you kind of don't want them to be
Speaker 3:  your problem anymore so you just sort of pass them onto the next year. Wow.
Speaker 4:  I feel like I learned, I've learned so much about both of your
Speaker 3:  Stories. I'm not, not saying I was that kid, I'm just saying people in history
Speaker 3:  have been that kid that there's just like, you go be somebody else's
Speaker 3:  problem And it feels like, feels like that's, that's where we are with matter.
Speaker 3:  It's like it's it's it's moving on. There's a lot,
Speaker 6:  It's going along. There's a lot of potential. I am, I know you, we love this
Speaker 6:  word, but there really is, I mean the foundation
Speaker 6:  is there, there's just a lot of building work we that still needs to be done,
Speaker 3:  But the vibes seem good. The people who need to think matter is gonna work
Speaker 3:  still think matter is gonna work, right?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. I need to say you are completely wrong from your predictions at
Speaker 6:  the same, sorry, I should have started.
Speaker 3:  I hope I'm wrong. To be clear,
Speaker 4:  What was your prediction? That matter would just go
Speaker 3:  Away. That everybody's gonna give up on matter,
Speaker 6:  Just give up on matter by the end of 2025
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. Liam James, our producer and
Speaker 3:  mc and game show host is here. Liam High.
Speaker 1:  Hey everybody, it's, it's that time, it's our annual tradition to
Speaker 1:  play some games around the spec that we've picked out and
Speaker 1:  also it just kinda gives me a chance as your producer to play evil
Speaker 1:  games with you and make you look silly in front of everyone. So really this
Speaker 1:  is my favorite time
Speaker 3:  Of year. You should also play these games with your family by the way. Oh
Speaker 3:  yeah. Everybody told me last year that USBC Bingo was a big hit all around,
Speaker 3:  all around the tree. People loved it.
Speaker 1:  I love that. Yeah. Okay, great. We're gonna start with the match game.
Speaker 1:  Oh God, please pull out your match game cards.
Speaker 4:  This, if we give this to people to print out and they hand this out to their
Speaker 4:  family,
Speaker 6:  We will be doing the CSAA big favorite educating
Speaker 1:  The
Speaker 3:  Public. If you'd like your family to not wanna speak to you for several days,
Speaker 3:  please suggest playing this game.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Lemme tell you how it goes. On the left of your, of your player
Speaker 1:  card, you have seven different matter
Speaker 1:  specific things. I'm just gonna be as vague as I can and
Speaker 1:  on the right you have the descriptions,
Speaker 1:  definitions, really of those seven things, what each of you
Speaker 1:  need to do is draw lines from the items listed on
Speaker 1:  the left to the definitions on the right. We will
Speaker 1:  give you two minutes to
Speaker 4:  Complete that. Some of these words are obviously fake
Speaker 3:  Of course,
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 1:  I don't
Speaker 4:  Out think matter, fabric is a real word. Consumer are deny that some of these
Speaker 4:  are fake.
Speaker 1:  Let me read them out for the audience. So we've got matter device, smart
Speaker 1:  home hub matter, administrator matter,
Speaker 1:  fabric matter, controller thread,
Speaker 1:  border router and matter bridge.
Speaker 3:  And you're telling me that these are all different things?
Speaker 1:  These are all different things. I would've
Speaker 3:  Told you three of these are synonyms. These,
Speaker 1:  These items and the definitions were pulled from the CSA
Speaker 1:  website. So, okay. Right from the source. All right. Alright, I'll start
Speaker 1:  your two minute timer. Now
Speaker 4:  Can these things be defined as themselves? There's some real
Speaker 4:  tautologies here. I would point out,
Speaker 6:  Alright, I'm done. Do it Jen. It's very messy
Speaker 6:  looking though.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I'll think I, I can't say that this is
Speaker 4:  easy to follow.
Speaker 3:  Mine is unhinged.
Speaker 4:  I don't know why I chose curving lines instead of straight lines.
Speaker 1:  Curving lines.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, mine. Mine looks very,
Speaker 3:  I should have just written the words next to each other.
Speaker 6:  I know. I think I, that's what I
Speaker 4:  See what I'm saying. Do that. What I, this is not normal.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. You got a little swoopy thing going on. I'm into
Speaker 1:  That. Okay. Is is everybody done? Yes.
Speaker 4:  And it as done as we're gonna be. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think the way we should do this is I'm gonna go to each one of the
Speaker 1:  seven and I'll go to one each one of you
Speaker 1:  and you tell me what you pick.
Speaker 3:  Honor system. Jen, no cheating.
Speaker 1:  Well, I'm not gonna tell you who is right until you each answer. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Matter device
Speaker 1:  Neli, what did you pick from matter device as the definition,
Speaker 4:  A matter device is a smart home hardware product that supports matter.
Speaker 4:  And I just want to be clear, these definitions are from the CSA, correct?
Speaker 4:  Yes. The CSA has de devi de defined a lot of things
Speaker 4:  as themselves,
Speaker 4:  like the technological definitions here are out of control. A matter device
Speaker 4:  is a smart home product that supports matter. That's
Speaker 1:  It. So it could be connected to and controlled by matter
Speaker 3:  Controller. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay, great. Jen, what did you choose?
Speaker 6:  The same
Speaker 1:  One. The same one, okay. And David? I
Speaker 3:  Said the same thing. Okay. A smart home hardware product that supports matters
Speaker 3:  so that it can be connected to and controlled by a matter controller. Right.
Speaker 3:  You are also, but then also if it's matter, it does matter. And so it matters
Speaker 4:  The, and then the devious thing, the CSA here is they lull you into
Speaker 4:  a false sense of security by defining everything as itself. A matter device
Speaker 4:  is a matter device and then they're like, and here's some other bullshit.
Speaker 1:  You are all correct. You each get three points. Hey, for
Speaker 1:  the correct answer there. Woo-hoo. Okay, moving on. Smart Home
Speaker 1:  hub Neli, what did you choose for that one?
Speaker 4:  A smart home hub is typically a connection point in the home for multiple
Speaker 4:  smart home devices. Usually specific to the vendor that has provided it,
Speaker 4:  which I disagree with, but that's what I picked.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it isn't, it's not a great description actually. I agree.
Speaker 4:  We couldn tell the CSA has really shaded it. Yeah. To be like
Speaker 4:  these suck, you should use matter because
Speaker 6:  It's not typically specific to a vendor.
Speaker 1:  Did you go with that same answer? I did,
Speaker 6:  Yes. Sorry.
Speaker 1:  And David,
Speaker 3:  I went with the same thing. I all, I picked something else until the very
Speaker 3:  last second and then switched to this one.
Speaker 1:  Okay, tell me what the answer is. You chose again Eli.
Speaker 4:  Typically a connection point in the home for multiple smart home devices.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I missed the word typically. That is correct. You all got it right?
Speaker 1:  Wow. Yay.
Speaker 6:  I was not expecting this.
Speaker 4:  Oh, don't worry. The dumb ones are coming.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Alright, our next one is Matter
Speaker 1:  Administrator Neli. Which one did you pick for that?
Speaker 4:  An entity that can control matter devices. The user has
Speaker 4:  connected functionality can be built into many types of hardware devices
Speaker 4:  like phones always powered smartphone hubs that provide local and remote
Speaker 4:  controls, smart switches, buttons or even mobile apps.
Speaker 4:  I challenge the listener to, to
Speaker 4:  distinguish between, it can be a phone or an app on your phone.
Speaker 3:  What if your whole phone was a light switch? Think about that.
Speaker 4:  I have one phone for every
Speaker 3:  App. This is good. This is, we disagree for the first time. I had something
Speaker 3:  else for this one.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's, I had that one.
Speaker 1:  That's the one you chose as well? Yes. Okay. And David, which one
Speaker 3:  Did you pick? I said a device or application that creates, maintains and
Speaker 3:  manages security and privileges for all device on the fabric.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah. And this round,
Speaker 4:  Which by the way that definition it sounds like it came directly out of Dune.
Speaker 4:  Welcome to the fabric. We manage the fabric.
Speaker 1:  Alright, our, our scores are finally diverging on that round.
Speaker 1:  Mila and Jenna, I'm sorry to tell you. You got that one wrong David, let's
Speaker 1:  go was correct? No,
Speaker 6:  No. Oh no.
Speaker 4:  This is
Speaker 6:  Like got them the wrong way round. This
Speaker 4:  Is one it begins to fall apart. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Alright.
Speaker 6:  Because matter controllers are the ones that manage the,
Speaker 3:  I'm not gonna lie, security. As soon as Jen disagreed with me, I instantly
Speaker 3:  put an X next to my thing. I was like, there's no chance. You should, you
Speaker 3:  should be. I have
Speaker 6:  This right. You should have been. You need to double check this one, Liam.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  I will. We will. We will have
Speaker 6:  A judge. But you're right. So matter admins and matter controllers are
Speaker 6:  very, very, very, very, very close together. I'm
Speaker 3:  Hearing so many excuses
Speaker 6:  Now. No, but matter. No,
Speaker 4:  You understand a
Speaker 6:  Matter, this is what a fabric,
Speaker 4:  A matter administrator is just a bureaucrat in the government
Speaker 4:  and a matter controller controls the spice.
Speaker 3:  Please. My father was a matter, I'm a
Speaker 4:  Fabric.
Speaker 4:  Do you understand?
Speaker 1:  Okay, moving on. Matter fabric neli, which one did you
Speaker 1:  pick for matter? Fabric.
Speaker 4:  Who knows man.
Speaker 4:  This is the one that I think the CSA is trolling us by
Speaker 4:  defining the thing as itself. So a matter of fabric matter devices are connected
Speaker 4:  together on a virtual network within a home called a matter fabric. Yes.
Speaker 4:  A virtual private network over which matter devices, admins and controllers
Speaker 4:  communicate with each other.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Liam, I think you straight up put the answer in the one. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. As soon as I saw that
Speaker 3:  This is a, I'm sorry we thought this a host error. It's like Jen Jennings
Speaker 3:  just says the name of the thing when he is giving the clue on Jeopardy.
Speaker 1:  I apologize to the audience. Okay. Did we all
Speaker 3:  Get that one right? Did everyone get that one right? We all got that one.
Speaker 3:  All right. That
Speaker 1:  Was a
Speaker 3:  Freebie. Fabulous.
Speaker 1:  Three points for
Speaker 3:  All. I just wanna point out I'm crushing it right now.
Speaker 1:  My
Speaker 3:  Confidence is through the roof.
Speaker 1:  It's all the hat. It's the hat. It's all the hat. It's bringing you good
Speaker 1:  vibes. Alright. Matter controller, Eli, which one did you
Speaker 1:  choose from? Matter Controller.
Speaker 4:  Why do I always go first? I chose
Speaker 1:  Because it's easier for me to score.
Speaker 4:  I see Matter controller is a device or application that creates,
Speaker 4:  maintains and manages security and privileges for all devices on the fabric.
Speaker 4:  Wrong
Speaker 1:  Jen, which
Speaker 4:  I believe is what Jen would've picked.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Jen, that's what I don't
Speaker 1:  We Jen, that's what because we are
Speaker 4:  Correct.
Speaker 3:  David, what did you pick? An entity that can control matter devices.
Speaker 3:  The user has connected functionality can be built into many types of hardware
Speaker 3:  devices. Like phones always powered smart hubs that provide local and remote
Speaker 3:  control. Smart switches and buttons or even mobile apps
Speaker 4:  Just for the listener. Right? Take this out of the weird bureaucracy of
Speaker 4:  a bunch of nerds. Designing a smart home standard and take this again into
Speaker 4:  your favorite sci-fi fantasy world Dune, for example, which I keep
Speaker 4:  referencing. Who has the higher rank in Dune? The administrator
Speaker 4:  or the controller?
Speaker 4:  Hmm. See what I'm saying makes sense to me.
Speaker 3:  It's interesting. Yeah. I do feel like the administrator is the one who gets
Speaker 3:  to press all the buttons though the controller like stands behind their chair
Speaker 3:  and yells things, but the administrator is the one who's like getting stuff
Speaker 3:  done. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The controller is obviously palpatine.
Speaker 3:  Yes, correct. But like have any real power.
Speaker 3:  Think about that.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. You know what the, the difference here, and I didn't actually read
Speaker 6:  this properly, is that it says device or application,
Speaker 6:  whereas for the matter administrator it says an
Speaker 6:  entity. So a matter controller Like
Speaker 4:  A ghost. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  An entity is definitely above a controller and an administrator by the way.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Matter entity is what's truly in charge here.
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 6:  So, so the administrator
Speaker 4:  Floating spirit of matter.
Speaker 6:  This is, this is, although it does say actually If you see at the bottom
Speaker 6:  of that one an entity, it does say, or even mobile apps. So
Speaker 6:  it's also applications and apps.
Speaker 3:  Both of these definitions are just like they do some stuff, whatever we want.
Speaker 3:  I don't know.
Speaker 6:  They're basically the same thing. Which they are essentially the same thing.
Speaker 6:  It's just a controller needs to be a physical device.
Speaker 4:  Although, no, that's not true.
Speaker 6:  I know. Well, so they originally said the apps could be controllers, but
Speaker 6:  that how So I That has actually changed.
Speaker 6:  And apps can't ne can't be controllers on their own. They can only be
Speaker 6:  administrators. So these are actually app date
Speaker 6:  and I the Cs a's website.
Speaker 4:  You're getting away with so much because you have that accent and I want
Speaker 4:  you to,
Speaker 6:  But yeah, If you read, both of these descriptions are exactly the same.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Stories
Speaker 3:  Matter.
Speaker 3:  It's a, it's a thing for matter Devices is the answer to every single one
Speaker 3:  on,
Speaker 6:  But I'm just so excited that the man who said matter is not going to exist
Speaker 6:  in a year is the one that's gonna win the quiz.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying right now our disagreement does not, it just, it, the,
Speaker 4:  the root of this disagreement is whether you think an administrator is a
Speaker 4:  higher rank than a controller. Right? That's what it's Right. A controller
Speaker 4:  is just like we couldn turn the lights on and off. An administrator is, I
Speaker 4:  I you we couldn kick people outta the fabric.
Speaker 3:  Neli, I'm the entity now. Holy Ghost,
Speaker 6:  It's Christmas.
Speaker 3:  Alright, let's
Speaker 1:  Keep going. Yeah. Well for the purposes of of scoring, I want to
Speaker 1:  make it official that Dave got that one right. Neli
Speaker 1:  Jen, I'm sorry
Speaker 4:  I, but I would, I just pointing out that the connectivity standards association
Speaker 4:  got it wrong.
Speaker 3:  This is how Neli got hundreds on his tests. By the way. Our just
Speaker 4:  Argue my way
Speaker 6:  On arguing.
Speaker 3:  We've got two more.
Speaker 4:  Two was wrong.
Speaker 3:  We've
Speaker 1:  Got two more. The next one our favorite, The Thread border
Speaker 1:  router Neli. Which one did you choose for
Speaker 4:  That? This another one that appeared to be a def, like a tautological definition,
Speaker 4:  a thread. Border router enables thread devices to connect to the local network
Speaker 4:  so they're able to communicate with other IP based devices built on technology
Speaker 4:  such as wifi or ethernet.
Speaker 1:  Yes. What'd you pick
Speaker 6:  That one?
Speaker 1:  Same one, David? Yes.
Speaker 3:  This was the closest I came to getting one wrong because I'm a genius
Speaker 3:  and again, there are going to be two in a row that sound very much exactly
Speaker 3:  the same, but I said the same thing.
Speaker 1:  Okay, great. You all got it. Correct. Three points for everyone.
Speaker 1:  Last one matter. Bridge
Speaker 4:  Matter bridge translates from one protocol to another allowing non matter
Speaker 4:  smart home devices such as those using ZigBee or Z-Wave to
Speaker 4:  connect to, what else? A matter Fabric.
Speaker 6:  Fabric.
Speaker 6:  And that was all that's left. So yeah,
Speaker 3:  It was got
Speaker 6:  That one
Speaker 3:  This holiday season. Connect to the fabric, everybody
Speaker 1:  Connect to
Speaker 3:  The fabric. Go home to your families, connect to the fabric. Alright,
Speaker 4:  We are all one on the fabric.
Speaker 3:  I just, this is what a perfect score looks like. Look
Speaker 6:  At that. Yeah. We're going to, we're going to appeal to the higher power
Speaker 6:  Eli, to the entity, to the entity.
Speaker 6:  I will get the CSA to fix their website.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's, that's,
Speaker 3:  That's how you
Speaker 4:  Really win the test. You're like, I changed the book.
Speaker 3:  You instantly win if we couldn. Yeah, that's if we couldn change, but you
Speaker 3:  have to do it before this episode publishes. That's, those are the rules.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  I can look, I can see the argument for administrator outranking controller,
Speaker 4:  but I'm just saying in the, in the dune universe, the, the
Speaker 4:  controller, you know, that's like a heavy word. Administrator
Speaker 4:  is never a heavy word. It's just you're like, I'm an administrator.
Speaker 4:  It's like, great. Get outta here gray suit. Like I'm not talking
Speaker 3:  To you. The border routers are just those like weird planes that just take
Speaker 3:  people around. Yeah, that's, that's a border router. It doesn't do anything.
Speaker 3:  It just kind of crashes Occasionally.
Speaker 4:  The drones. The drones over New Jersey are border routers.
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  I think we can all agree what we learned from this game is that matter is
Speaker 1:  way more complicated than it might seem. At first glance. The
Speaker 4:  Spice must flow.
Speaker 1:  The spice must flow. Alright, we're gonna move on to our second and final
Speaker 1:  game. But before we do, I want to just quickly let our
Speaker 1:  fans know what the scores are thus far.
Speaker 3:  David is dominant.
Speaker 1:  Neli Patel has 12 points so far, as does
Speaker 1:  Jen Tui and David is leading the pack right now with
Speaker 1:  18 points.
Speaker 3:  Woo. I will say just very quickly, having looked at the next game,
Speaker 3:  this is still up in the air.
Speaker 3:  David's lead is
Speaker 4:  Not safe. I also wanna make it clear that I know very little about Dune.
Speaker 4:  I watched both of those movies. I slept through the first one. The second
Speaker 4:  one was better. Never read the books. Please do not quibble with me about
Speaker 4:  Dune. It's very important to me. Quibble with the CSA,
Speaker 3:  But only on Dune related grounds.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, send them notes about Dune. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We're gonna do Matter. Mad Libs,
Speaker 1:  if you're not familiar with Mad Libs, mad Libs is a pre-written sentence
Speaker 1:  with a bunch of blanks in it and a bunch of choices for those blanks for
Speaker 1:  you to fill in to make the sentence complete and make sense. So I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  read out the sentence and the word choices and we'll give you two minutes
Speaker 1:  to fill them in. Just like last time.
Speaker 3:  No looking while he reads it. Okay. No. Starting early,
Speaker 1:  Formally known as blank. Blank is a unified connectivity
Speaker 1:  standard developed by the blank. The protocol aims to ensure reliable,
Speaker 1:  secure, and seamless communication between smart home devices regardless
Speaker 1:  of brand or platform. It works through blank, blank, and blank.
Speaker 1:  So it can be added to devices that support any of these protocols
Speaker 1:  matter's. Key advantage is that it uses a standardized blank
Speaker 1:  matter lets you blank and use its devices across blank for more
Speaker 1:  choice and control so you don't end up stuck on one platform.
Speaker 1:  Your word choices are ecosystem or ecosystems.
Speaker 1:  Bluetooth matter, IP protocol, wifi,
Speaker 1:  chip thread, C, S, A, and pair
Speaker 3:  Matter lets you blank should be the official tagline of the
Speaker 3:  CSA.
Speaker 1:  All right, we starting?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Real Vergecast nerds know the first one because Dieter thought it was
Speaker 4:  very funny. I have a question. It works through blank, blank and
Speaker 4:  blank. Does the order matter? No.
Speaker 6:  I do have a correction for that one too for you. But
Speaker 1:  It's so funny. I wanted to run these by you, but then I was like, but I need,
Speaker 1:  I need her to play the game.
Speaker 6:  That wouldn't be fair.
Speaker 4:  Which
Speaker 3:  Word am I missing?
Speaker 3:  I'm not super confident.
Speaker 3:  Okay, I'm ready.
Speaker 1:  Okay. It's looking like everyone is done. Let's reveal our answers.
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna go one at a time, slightly different order. Let's start with you
Speaker 1:  Jen. If you could read out the sentence you completed.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Formally known as chip
Speaker 6:  matter is a unified connectivity standard developed by the CSA.
Speaker 6:  The protocol aims to ensure reliable, secure, and seamless
Speaker 6:  communication between smart home devices, regardless of the brand or platform.
Speaker 6:  It works through wifi thread and Bluetooth, so it can be added
Speaker 6:  to devices that support any of these protocols matters. Key
Speaker 6:  advantage is that it uses a standardized IP. Protocol
Speaker 6:  matter lets you pair and use its devices across ecosystems for more
Speaker 6:  choice and control so you don't end up stuck on one platform.
Speaker 4:  Nailed it.
Speaker 1:  Alright. I can't tell you the WW what you got yet.
Speaker 1:  Next we'll have David.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Now Nervous. Formerly known as chip matter
Speaker 3:  is a unified connectivity standard developed by the CSA. The protocol aims
Speaker 3:  to ensure reliable, secure, and seamless communication. By the way, you should
Speaker 3:  have made all those blanks and just made us fill them in
Speaker 3:  reliable, secure, and seamless. I legitimately think we all might have gotten
Speaker 3:  with no prompting. It's just the most like tech companies speak of all time
Speaker 3:  anyway. The protocol aims to ensure reliable, secure, and seamless communication
Speaker 3:  between smart home devices, regardless of the brand or platform. It works
Speaker 3:  through thread, wifi and Bluetooth so it can be added to devices that support
Speaker 3:  any of these protocols matter's. Key advantage is that it uses a standardized
Speaker 3:  ecosystem, which I think is wrong. Jen sounded right. Matter lets you pair
Speaker 3:  and use its devices across IP protocol, which also sounds wrong. I think
Speaker 3:  Jen is right for more choice and control so you don't end up stuck on one
Speaker 3:  platform.
Speaker 1:  Okay. And Neli, what's yours?
Speaker 4:  I, I was also correct and I had the exact same answers as Jen.
Speaker 3:  Well that worked out great for me last time. So
Speaker 4:  Formerly known as Chip Matters Unified Connectivity Standard developed by
Speaker 4:  the CSA, blah blah, blah, other sentence. It works through thread, wifi
Speaker 4:  and Bluetooth. So we couldn be adding device and support any these protocols.
Speaker 4:  Key advantage is use a standardized IP protocol that lets you pair and use
Speaker 4:  its devices across ecosystems for more choice and control so
Speaker 4:  you don't end up stuck on one platform. And we couldn please the controller.
Speaker 3:  Did we all write thread wifi and Bluetooth in that order?
Speaker 4:  Yes. Because I think we all immediately thought of thread first. Just
Speaker 3:  APO of nothing. That's kind of wild. And it three blanks. Three.
Speaker 4:  Well I know Brainstorm, we know it's thread. We're like, well WiFi's there
Speaker 4:  and they're like fucking, is it Bluetooth?
Speaker 6:  Well Bluetooth is not a protocol of matter. It's only an onboarding
Speaker 6:  protocol. The other one is ethernet.
Speaker 4:  Liam, I want for the listener. Liam has had no response to this
Speaker 4:  information. Liam, Liam's all listening.
Speaker 6:  Sorry.
Speaker 4:  Kidding. Anyone? Anyone? Just like nothing. Like the most nothing
Speaker 4:  just happened.
Speaker 3:  Jen's over here angling for extra credit. Extra
Speaker 6:  Credit, extra credit. I've gotta be David.
Speaker 4:  I've never seen anyone react less
Speaker 6:  Anything
Speaker 4:  Than Liam just react
Speaker 6:  To that. Sorry,
Speaker 1:  I was scoring
Speaker 4:  My scoring. No, that's not happening. That didn't happen.
Speaker 6:  Nope. Nope.
Speaker 1:  I mean, to be honest with you, that is mostly how I deal with you in in day
Speaker 1:  to day. So
Speaker 4:  Just like nothing will happen.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's an effective strategy.
Speaker 1:  Alright. Listeners are winner of this round
Speaker 1:  is Jen and Eli who got every answer correct.
Speaker 1:  However, David got a little messed up there in the end. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  he flipped ecosystem and IP protocol. You know how
Speaker 3:  Sometimes you say something out loud and you're like, that wasn't it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like it was. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Sorry.
Speaker 3:  You know, as a standardized ecosystem is just like not, that's not it guys,
Speaker 4:  I hear you. I, you know, I hear you confuse ecosystem in I in IP protocol.
Speaker 3:  I mean, if I had an Nickel
Speaker 4:  Man day, you're
Speaker 6:  Where?
Speaker 1:  Hang
Speaker 3:  On, let me send you that over ecosystem. It is like, it happens constantly.
Speaker 4:  The last protocol, by the way, is ethernet. Bluetooth is just an onboarding
Speaker 4:  protocol. Liam,
Speaker 3:  Which I said first If you guys remember, I was the first
Speaker 3:  one to bring that up.
Speaker 1:  So I had not planned for this and I should have, but
Speaker 1:  did we tie, we have you tie a three way tie. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Yay.
Speaker 1:  So you're all winners with 39 points.
Speaker 6:  Woo-hoo.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 4:  First one to get away from the desk in return with a matter device
Speaker 4:  wins.
Speaker 1:  Go.
Speaker 3:  Jen could do it without,
Speaker 4:  I want That's my phone. My phone, which is technically a matter controller.
Speaker 3:  Jen already has two. Have
Speaker 1:  A lot. Jen has two.
Speaker 6:  Wait,
Speaker 4:  Okay. You showed up with a
Speaker 6:  Smart, you know, get up. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right. Jen wins.
Speaker 6:  Jen wins.
Speaker 1:  Jen wins. Fair enough.
Speaker 6:  I thought
Speaker 4:  I was being so smart with the phone thing and she showed up with the
Speaker 3:  Yeah, Neela is like, I've subverted the system and Jens like, I have all
Speaker 3:  the device,
Speaker 6:  Them all. I have another one.
Speaker 1:  Jen probably has an example of all seven of the items
Speaker 1:  from the match game on her desk right now. So,
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 1:  There you go.
Speaker 1:  Well,
Speaker 3:  We never
Speaker 1:  Had a chance. Thank you for joining us for another fun round of games.
Speaker 1:  Jen, you are our winner this year. I'm not sure what that means
Speaker 1:  yet, but we'll do
Speaker 4:  Do something special. It means she's the new controller.
Speaker 3:  Jen is the entity. I
Speaker 6:  Know. I'm the admin
Speaker 1:  Bcast controller.
Speaker 6:  What am I?
Speaker 4:  Jen runs the fabric now,
Speaker 3:  Jen. Yeah, right.
Speaker 6:  I'm the fabric master. I'm the fabric master. That is it There. It is done.
Speaker 6:  I'm until
Speaker 3:  The CSA
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 3:  Done. We've, it's been decided.
Speaker 4:  All right, we
Speaker 3:  Gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk with
Speaker 3:  Paul from Home Assistant about the future of all of this. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. We have a guest. Paul Chuan is here. Hello. Welcome.
Speaker 3:  Hey, how's
Speaker 8:  It going? Can
Speaker 3:  We talk about your sweater just for a second? This is really good audio,
Speaker 3:  So I Sure. Good. But this is, this is the rare episode that I'm perfectly
Speaker 3:  happy talking about Visual. Thanks. Can you just describe your Christmas
Speaker 3:  sweater just very quickly?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so I'm wearing the, the GitHub Christmas sweater. So it has like
Speaker 8:  big GitHub letters on it. It's red, black, and green. And then all the different
Speaker 8:  icons that you normally see when you're working on GitHub. They're like spread
Speaker 8:  out over the sleeves and the chest and the, the shoulders. It's
Speaker 8:  stuff,
Speaker 3:  It's very good. So we, we asked you
Speaker 1:  Smart home n
Speaker 3:  It it really is, it's, it is truly like it is both very on brandand and
Speaker 3:  very good. I'm very, I'm very happy to have it. So can you just describe
Speaker 3:  what you do a little bit? We asked you to come on here because you, you work
Speaker 3:  on and created Home Assistant and we're gonna talk about matter and all this
Speaker 3:  stuff. But you, you, you sort of purview and like job title has actually
Speaker 3:  changed a bit recently. Yeah. So can you just sort of describe the shape
Speaker 3:  of that for us?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, right. So I'm the president of the Open Home Foundation. This is a
Speaker 8:  relatively new foundation. We started in April. It's now the owner of the
Speaker 8:  Home Assistant open source project. It's the owner of the ESP Home Open
Speaker 8:  Source project are, and a bunch of other open source projects that are
Speaker 8:  kind of the other two are built upon. Our goal is to really
Speaker 8:  build a smart home build around privacy choice and sustainability. So
Speaker 8:  we built that. We are doing that by building technology. So in a way how
Speaker 8:  Mozilla builds Firefox, we are building Home Assistant ESP Home.
Speaker 8:  We are just by existing, we are influencing and
Speaker 8:  steering the iot market. I feel like, you know, Google the Apples, you see
Speaker 8:  that they look at us, we talk to them, we know that they know what we
Speaker 8:  are doing and they kind of take that into consideration or like they learn
Speaker 8:  from that. Their product managers will talk to people in our community. So
Speaker 8:  we are maybe not the biggest smart home platform out there. We are the
Speaker 8:  biggest open source project in the world and also the biggest open source
Speaker 8:  smart home platform. But we have a lot of influence in the market that way.
Speaker 3:  You're definitely the biggest super nerdy smart home system. Yes. Right?
Speaker 3:  Like I think that's a fair Yes. That's a fair place to say, okay
Speaker 8:  We ac we actually tell people like they everybody, we are never
Speaker 8:  anyone's first smart home platform. Everybody starts with a Google and
Speaker 8:  Amazon or an Apple, a smart home. And then when they outgrow
Speaker 8:  it for whatever reasons, privacy, more integrations, they
Speaker 8:  want history, they will come to Home Assistant. And then
Speaker 8:  there's like people like Neli that go to hoops.
Speaker 6:  Oh, got that one in soon.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's rough
Speaker 4:  By the way. Switch from hoops to HomeBridge. We can get into it
Speaker 3:  That,
Speaker 8:  That'll be the next holiday special. Yeah. Yeah. Garage door openers.
Speaker 3:  God help us all.
Speaker 4:  But wait, actually garage door openers are like the thing, right? There are
Speaker 4:  all of, this is how I think about Home Assistant. There are all of these
Speaker 4:  disparate smart devices in your house.
Speaker 4:  Most of them cannot talk to each other. Yeah. The plan is
Speaker 4:  for matter to fix it on some timeline and in the
Speaker 4:  meantime you have products like Home Assistant and HomeBridge and everything
Speaker 4:  else. That is basically the fanciest middleware
Speaker 4:  to bridge everything into one platform and then expose control to
Speaker 4:  your smartphone in some way. Yeah. And that seems
Speaker 4:  like it will never be defeated. Like it, I, in my mind, Home Assistant will
Speaker 4:  never be defeated even if matter shows up and works perfectly. Because every
Speaker 4:  time I use my smart home, there's one thing that isn't gonna
Speaker 4:  work on matter. Whether that's the garage door or whether it's the toaster
Speaker 4:  or whatever it is, it's easier to bridge that into a common platform and
Speaker 4:  then send it out than to be like, I will replace everything with
Speaker 4:  a matter device.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well what But Matter will help Home Assistant too, right? It'll make
Speaker 6:  it a lot easier for Home Assistant to exist and to do these integrations.
Speaker 6:  Correct. I mean it's not a direct competitor to any in any way. No, not at
Speaker 6:  all. It's helping Grow Home Assistant.
Speaker 4:  Is it helping Jen,
Speaker 6:  Let's just follow
Speaker 3:  It. Is it helping? What a good full question. At its core,
Speaker 8:  Like Matter is a local standard, right? It allows devices to
Speaker 8:  talk locally to the Smart Home Hub. There is no
Speaker 8:  previously like, or even today there's like vacuums that will just only talk
Speaker 8:  to the cloud. You have an app, you're standing next to the vacuum, you go
Speaker 8:  through the cloud back to the vacuum, your internet is down. You cannot
Speaker 8:  start your vacuum like a room or something because it just, the cloud is
Speaker 8:  necessary with Matter. Your phone will talk through Home
Speaker 8:  Assistant locally and Home Assistant will talk directly to vacuums. This,
Speaker 8:  this is coming by the way, this is not
Speaker 6:  Waiting
Speaker 8:  On, on that one. I mean, and you'll, you'll hear me say this a lot. This
Speaker 8:  is gonna be theoretically the promise because a lot of this is not there
Speaker 8:  yet. But yeah, we're gonna be able to talk locally to these
Speaker 8:  devices. So I think in general it is good because for the first
Speaker 8:  time in history, there's a smart home standards and this gets a little bit
Speaker 8:  nerdy, but it works over ip, right? So it means you have wifi,
Speaker 8:  which we all have in our houses. We couldn already run matter. And that
Speaker 8:  means that out of the box without extra radios, an Android
Speaker 8:  phone and iPhone can walk work with Matter. And everybody has to Google Home
Speaker 8:  app. Everybody has the Apple Home app because they're pre-installed, which
Speaker 8:  means that all of a sudden, If you need to make a business case, why am I
Speaker 8:  gonna choose matter? Well, there's, I don't know how many billion smartphones
Speaker 8:  in the world. That's all matter supported, right? So, oh, I'm going to use
Speaker 8:  matter, which means there's, there's gonna be a lot more devices that can
Speaker 8:  work locally.
Speaker 6:  Would you say that matter is? No. So the way that matter came in
Speaker 6:  guns blazing was, you know, one protocol to rule rule them all. I feel
Speaker 6:  like you don't agree with that. I may be wrong.
Speaker 6:  No. Are the other protocols, do they still have a space here or is Matter
Speaker 6:  gonna
Speaker 8:  Right? Well that's, I mean disclosure, I am, there's other smart home protocols
Speaker 8:  and I'm on the board of the Z-Wave Alliance, right? Which is one of these
Speaker 8:  other protocols. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Can you tell me If you guys are working on building a giant headquarter shaped
Speaker 4:  like a Z this is the only thing the Z-Wave Alliance should do.
Speaker 8:  Not that I'm aware of. All
Speaker 4:  Right. Well,
Speaker 8:  But, but for example, If you look at like, you know, a
Speaker 8:  Z-Wave, like the Z-Wave works with
Speaker 8:  QR codes that you pre-set up some a device And it doesn't
Speaker 8:  work over ip. And If you buy a house, you
Speaker 8:  wifi is not pre-installed, right? You always bring your own wifi router,
Speaker 8:  but you cannot set up a meta device without a wifi router, right? So
Speaker 8:  if you're thinking about I want to have a smart home pre-installed with
Speaker 8:  stuff because that's how I wanna sell it to new people that move into homes
Speaker 8:  that currently to date does not work with matter. Right? So just on
Speaker 8:  purely on that fact, we need more smart home standards to kind of make that
Speaker 8:  bridge and have that onboarding. Now can everything be eventually
Speaker 8:  one day solve the matter? Yes. Will this take a long, long time
Speaker 8:  also? Yes.
Speaker 4:  One of the things that I'm curious about with Home Assistant in particular
Speaker 4:  is that it is the central platform, right? To me, the, the
Speaker 4:  big mistake of the smart home for quite a long time has been the idea
Speaker 4:  that we need to move it out of our houses and into someone's cloud, right?
Speaker 4:  I mean, and so many devices I have effectively rely on on some cloud
Speaker 4:  service to operate even to turn on or off. And
Speaker 4:  the idea that I should have a server in my basement that actually runs my
Speaker 4:  home and connects to everything, it seems very powerful. It also
Speaker 4:  seems, and I'm sure Jen has this experience all the time, when you talk to
Speaker 4:  anyone about that idea, they're like, that's too hard. No one will ever do
Speaker 4:  that. But then you're describing, well we need to like pre-build houses with
Speaker 4:  smart homes in them with smart homes stuff in them. And you kind of end up
Speaker 4:  right back at, well there needs to be a server in the basement, So I can
Speaker 4:  just sell that with the house. How do you square all of that? Because that's
Speaker 4:  what I, that's what I want, yeah. Is to say my house has a computer in it
Speaker 4:  and I can just go look at that computer and tell you if it's working or broken,
Speaker 4:  which is what Home Assistant provides for a lot of people. But that's not
Speaker 4:  where the market is at all.
Speaker 8:  Right? And I think that's the, the problem that we're seeing in the market
Speaker 8:  is that If you, the moment you standardize something, it's commoditized.
Speaker 8:  You cannot innovate. We look at, so people will
Speaker 8:  go through the cloud to get these fancy effects are going. I think the, the,
Speaker 8:  the server, like a server is just a box nowadays, right? Like you,
Speaker 8:  you look at your Philips U Hub, like that's a server,
Speaker 8:  it's a small server, but the Home Assistant server for example is not that
Speaker 8:  much bigger. You don't need to rack, you don't need more than two watts
Speaker 8:  to power like a Home Assistant box. So I think we have
Speaker 8:  to like, just like how we have electricity meters, how we have
Speaker 8:  routers, how we have cable modems. I think having a device there
Speaker 8:  to run your smart home is the future. And you know, I
Speaker 8:  talk to other people and they say, well you're gonna have a box that runs
Speaker 8:  your AI agents, right? Like you don't have that in your fridge.
Speaker 8:  You have a box that can power all the AI in all the different devices.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that matter makes it more likely that will end up with
Speaker 4:  more people having a local server? Whether it's just a RAs rate PI or not?
Speaker 4:  Like you describe Matter as a local protocol that sort of implies
Speaker 4:  that you're gonna have a, some thing in your house that will run everything.
Speaker 8:  I think so, yes. I think that there are players that are trying to push all
Speaker 8:  the matter data to the cloud where to do all the processing. But I
Speaker 8:  believe that most people are also seeing like, oh, ongoing cloud costs. Like
Speaker 8:  the industry is starting to realize a little bit like we're doing, like you,
Speaker 8:  you see Google, they're pushing some stuff. Local Samsung is pushing some
Speaker 8:  stuff local, they, they see the speed. I mean maybe
Speaker 8:  this is more wasteful thinking from my end because this is where I want to
Speaker 8:  be. But yeah, I hope it goes there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I am really curious how you're thinking about Matter as a, as a product
Speaker 3:  guy right now. Because on the one hand, you, you work on Home Assistant,
Speaker 3:  which is is for people who are like by and large willing to do a little
Speaker 3:  bit of work to make this stuff work. And to me's point, like you eventually
Speaker 3:  hit a point with the smart home stuff where you either have to do this or
Speaker 3:  you, you have hit the ceiling of what we couldn do in the smart home. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  What matters seems to promise is it like, it sort of lowers the barrier
Speaker 3:  to entry at the very bottom of it. Like the thing Jen keeps telling me every
Speaker 3:  time we come on the show and I get sad about Matter and she tells me it's
Speaker 3:  gonna be fine is like, it just makes all of this easier, right? Like it,
Speaker 3:  it just, it makes building a smart home from nothing work.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And that's very powerful. And I think just in terms of like getting
Speaker 3:  people into this market, that's really valuable. But for you specifically,
Speaker 3:  like I went through and read a bunch of the documentation and, and forum
Speaker 3:  posts about Matter over the last year. So, and the response is so funny 'cause
Speaker 3:  it's a mix of people being like, oh this sounds cool. And a bunch of people
Speaker 3:  being like, well I don't care about any of this. This solves no problems
Speaker 3:  that I currently have. Yeah. So I am curious like for how, how relevant does
Speaker 3:  matter feel to something like Home Assistant?
Speaker 8:  So I think it is relevant and it's mainly like the IP based
Speaker 8:  thing. The wifi based, the matter can have cameras, none of the
Speaker 8:  other smart home standards can have cameras. Vacuums have never made it to
Speaker 8:  Z-Wave or ZigBee and they'll probably never come. Like Z-Wave is honestly
Speaker 8:  more like a home security standard, right? They have all the sensors,
Speaker 8:  it, ZigBee is similar setup
Speaker 8:  matter is actually kind of skipping some of these sensors, which is why sometimes
Speaker 8:  in the smart home industry people are annoyed with like, oh it doesn't even
Speaker 8:  do energy monitoring. And like, well right now that is slowly coming, but
Speaker 8:  in the meantime cameras are coming, right? And like vacuums have launched
Speaker 8:  as specification, not yet as firmware, but there's no product
Speaker 8:  yet. But there's,
Speaker 4:  There's, yes, we've
Speaker 6:  Launched something, we've been deep into this, we've
Speaker 3:  Launched the idea of vacuums. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So I think there's a lot of good stuff coming out of the Just
Speaker 8:  Matter can do devices differently because they have more bandwidth.
Speaker 8:  Now I, I think, you know, when we talk about matter, there's like this, this,
Speaker 8:  I keep saying IP and wifi because those are the good parts of matter, right?
Speaker 8:  There's the threat part of Matter and like we couldn do a whole
Speaker 8:  episode about like, that is pretty bad shit show.
Speaker 8:  Like that's just
Speaker 4:  Wait Thread's a shit show. Yes. Why is Thread a shit show? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Give us the three minutes on that.
Speaker 8:  So when they started Thread, they decided that with wifi it's too
Speaker 8:  hard that people need to set up a network name and a password and that's
Speaker 8:  then print it on the router cable modem and people have to go dig into it
Speaker 8:  and see it. And so they decided we're not gonna let people deal with this.
Speaker 8:  We are gonna create automatically a thread network, configure a name and
Speaker 8:  a key and then we'll just send it to all the devices and you never have to
Speaker 8:  know the network name and the network key. Then the second part
Speaker 8:  is it's a standard. Everybody's gonna be able, it's a message standard. Everybody's
Speaker 8:  gonna create border routers. So you're gonna have like five border routers,
Speaker 8:  one from Apple, one from Google, one from Samsung, one from Home Assistant.
Speaker 8:  They all need to have this network key. The third part is now we
Speaker 8:  need this network key that you set up, for example, in your Google Home or
Speaker 8:  your Apple home to the Home Assistant hub or to the Samsung hub.
Speaker 8:  They forgot that part.
Speaker 3:  I'm
Speaker 6:  So glad you explained it. You explained it so well pal. 'cause it is so
Speaker 6:  confusing. But yes, the, like, this is where we've all ended up with multiple
Speaker 6:  thread networks in our home. And so devices aren't connecting. And the best
Speaker 4:  Part I do and that shows with you Jen, is you say things like we've all ended
Speaker 4:  up with multiple thread networks and, and it's true. I think the average
Speaker 4:  American, when I look at these election results, they are pissed about having
Speaker 3:  Multiple
Speaker 4:  Thread networks in there. I I have multiple thread networks in I have, but
Speaker 4:  this is like, you see the like bits and bobs right of like, we're gonna start
Speaker 4:  sharing network keys in in the Euro app. Yeah. Are you just saying
Speaker 4:  that's not coming to anything?
Speaker 8:  I mean they're trying to fix it now, but they, nobody really wants to open
Speaker 8:  up enough. So for example, there's a new threat credential
Speaker 8:  sharing that like The Thread group and the CSA have kind of collaborated
Speaker 8:  on, but it's not anything more than just sharing QR codes
Speaker 8:  through documentation and how we couldn get your credentials and copy
Speaker 8:  paste it into the next app. Like there are iOS and
Speaker 8:  Android APIs, they just don't work
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 6:  I that's Well and Home Assistant is one of the few ways we couldn actually
Speaker 6:  manually force all of your third border routers to work together. But it
Speaker 6:  is a process and it's not necessarily, you know, one we would
Speaker 6:  recommend to all the people that voted.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And it and it's not gonna be successful. Right.
Speaker 4:  Wait, So I, I guess I have a question for both of you expressed in different
Speaker 4:  ways and Paul we'll start with you because you represent the Z-Wave Alliance,
Speaker 4:  the bitter rivals to thread, I believe the
Speaker 3:  Evil empire.
Speaker 4:  I'm so mad that there's not a CS shaped building. You have a bias in favor
Speaker 4:  of, of the Z Wave alliance. I have a bias in favor of novelty buildings,
Speaker 4:  but like when I think about Matter, when we work with Jen on, on
Speaker 4:  coverage of matter devices thread is just a long further ride, right?
Speaker 4:  It it's just like one, these things happen together,
Speaker 4:  then the big unlock happens, right? We couldn just go to the store and buy
Speaker 4:  anything and you get matter over a threat and you get this low power power
Speaker 4:  saving network that automatically heals And it can reach everyone in your
Speaker 4:  house. And you're, you're saying that's just not happening.
Speaker 8:  It is only happening If you stick to an existing, like
Speaker 8:  a single ecosystem. So If you have everything Apple or everything Google,
Speaker 8:  you're going to have a good time. But the truth is, is that the smart home
Speaker 8:  doesn't work that way, right? We have this piecemeal together of
Speaker 8:  equipment we have bought over the years and Couldn can't just ask somebody,
Speaker 8:  throw away everything, buy everything, Google. Now we couldn use this lock,
Speaker 3:  Right? That's the problem we're trying to solve. Paul, are you telling me
Speaker 3:  we've solved No problems?
Speaker 8:  Not yet. Okay.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 8:  I, this is the thing. I think they, they are aware of it and they're like
Speaker 8:  the, the thing is they have all these companies together and they are, they
Speaker 8:  have all these, you know, they're businesses, right? They wanna make money,
Speaker 8:  they wanna protect their ecosystems, but they are also part of an alliance
Speaker 8:  that creates an open standard about sharing these things. And so
Speaker 8:  trying to find that balance is hard. And we see
Speaker 8:  companies where their border router has bugs. They know that these bugs exist
Speaker 8:  with other platforms when they exist book themselves, their
Speaker 8:  smart home controller talks directly to the border router bypassing the normal
Speaker 8:  route. So people don't experience the bug in their own ecosystem. But
Speaker 8:  we are all experiencing these books where you step out of that ecosystem.
Speaker 8:  So
Speaker 3:  What, what is the matter protocol like to work with right now? I mean, one
Speaker 3:  thing, Neil and I have spent a lot of time this year talking about activity
Speaker 3:  pub another of like everybody's favorite protocols that will save everything
Speaker 3:  and, and has shipped no products. Yeah. Right? And we keep talking to people
Speaker 3:  who are like, this protocol is full of good ideas. It wants to do all the
Speaker 3:  right things And it is just fundamentally like somewhere between
Speaker 3:  unfinished and broken in a bunch of really important ways. And they're all
Speaker 3:  like, we'll get there someday. Long history sweep, whatever
Speaker 3:  is matter. Is matter like a good technical protocol at this point?
Speaker 8:  Yes, mostly. Okay. So the, the good thing
Speaker 8:  about Matter is that they actually took everything from ZigBee. They took
Speaker 8:  everything they learned from HomeKit, they took everything from Google and
Speaker 8:  Amazon and they all said, we Couldn use all our stuff, all our knowledge.
Speaker 8:  We're not gonna like just let's build the best thing ever. And they built
Speaker 8:  something that is very good. For example, they built into it that we
Speaker 8:  couldn every meta device can be connected to five different smart home hubs
Speaker 8:  at the same time. And from the Home Assistant app, we couldn share a meta
Speaker 8:  device to Google Home. And now Google Home can control the device and has
Speaker 8:  its own encrypted secure connection. The downside of all these
Speaker 8:  adding the best features that they could think of is, okay,
Speaker 8:  now we need bigger chips in our light bulbs because we need to have five
Speaker 8:  encrypted connections to these five smart home hubs. And so,
Speaker 8:  and then like the SDK started kept growing, right? And so the, there's now
Speaker 8:  more memory and so these, the light bulbs are getting more expensive or
Speaker 8:  matter, you set it up with a QR code, but the QR codes only for the first
Speaker 8:  time you set up the meta device afterwards you have to go to, for example,
Speaker 8:  Home Assistant and share it to Apple or to Google. You cannot use that QR
Speaker 8:  code again. But people don't know, they just use the QR code all the time,
Speaker 8:  right? So that it, they just kind of security gets in the way of usability
Speaker 8:  there. And so there's a lot of good stuff just at the pure
Speaker 8:  foundational level of like authentication onboarding where we
Speaker 8:  get to like the layer of like, oh, how good is it for energy
Speaker 8:  monitoring all this stuff. I think that stuff will come like that just takes
Speaker 8:  time for people to agree. Then of course, I mean the whole
Speaker 8:  the I feel like matter, like it gets a little bit overhyped. They release
Speaker 8:  a new specification. Everybody makes all these articles, right? Like meta
Speaker 8:  1.4 is here, 1.3 is there,
Speaker 3:  Jen's right here, ice
Speaker 4:  Cold Follower,
Speaker 3:  We couldn just say it to Jen, she's right here.
Speaker 8:  And then
Speaker 4:  I don't say nice things about that always though
Speaker 4:  she's smiling in that way. British people smile when they're pissed off.
Speaker 8:  It works in Home Assistant usually by the way within two weeks. But then
Speaker 8:  device manufacturers are like, well I'm not gonna release a meta firmer for
Speaker 8:  my vacuum because there's no controller supporting vacuums. And then the
Speaker 8:  controllers are like, why am I gonna add vacuums if there's no products that
Speaker 8:  use vacuum? And so everybody's kind of looking at each other and kind of
Speaker 8:  figuring it out and at some point somebody breaks like the dam, right? And
Speaker 8:  then like, oh, now we're having matter vacuums because that is a thing. And
Speaker 8:  I mean, yeah. So this is there, there's, it takes a while for something
Speaker 8:  to be added to matter and be able available as a matter product
Speaker 8:  that we couldn use.
Speaker 4:  I feel like I'm learning a lot about the politics of the smart vacuum industry,
Speaker 4:  like without having learned anything. But lemme can I just ask
Speaker 4:  you a question? Like the dream, like what we talk about is
Speaker 4:  you buy a bunch of stuff, you plug it into your house and then you're just
Speaker 4:  able to sort of control it from anywhere. Yeah. Right. My Google home, I
Speaker 4:  should just be able to say, turn on the lights in the kitchen and just knows
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm not setting up a floor plan on five different platforms,
Speaker 4:  which is the thing you end up doing now. Yeah. You know, I, I can, my wife
Speaker 4:  won't use anything unless it's control center on her iPhone. No other
Speaker 4:  smart home platform exists except control center on the iPhone. So that is
Speaker 4:  why I prioritized a bunch of stuff I prioritize, but I know that Home
Speaker 4:  Assistant has much smarter automations, right? Yeah. In, in a variety of
Speaker 4:  ways. I know that Google and Amazon want to throw AI at
Speaker 4:  a bunch of automation ish things they keep talking about. I would love to
Speaker 4:  use that stuff and try it out. And that's, to me, that's what matter is supposed
Speaker 4:  to do, right? Is just show me all the devices everywhere without a
Speaker 4:  ton of complicated setup. And it, what I'm getting from you is that is
Speaker 4:  we're not close to that. We're not,
Speaker 8:  Not
Speaker 4:  At all. You still need a central platform and all these things can talk to
Speaker 4:  a central platform.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And that's,
Speaker 4:  Do you think that's going away? Is there a timeline for Matter solves that
Speaker 4:  and evaporates the central platform?
Speaker 8:  I think that it'll never go fully away because the moment something is part
Speaker 8:  of matter, it is a standardized, it's commoditized. You cannot innovate.
Speaker 8:  And so there's companies that drive on innovation, they wanna push the
Speaker 8:  boundaries and that will never be able to be fully captured in matter. So
Speaker 8:  you're going to have extra systems that with their own APIs and
Speaker 8:  that goes into a Google, into a Home Assistant. And then how
Speaker 8:  do you get it from Google into Home Assistant? You cannot, anything that's
Speaker 8:  in Home Assistant, we couldn push to Apple, you push to Google, that is all
Speaker 8:  like integrated correctly. So I don't think it's going fully
Speaker 8:  away, it's just that more and more default things
Speaker 8:  in a way. So light bulbs or logs, those will all go over matter.
Speaker 8:  And the more complicated things like media players, like that's gonna be,
Speaker 8:  that's a hot mess. Like control, pausing, play, that's fine. But like
Speaker 8:  browsing your library and setting, putting on your Christmas playlist, there's
Speaker 8:  no way that's gonna be a matter in the next five years or ever.
Speaker 3:  But do you think this is actually a thing I've, I've been wondering about
Speaker 3:  a lot because I, I saw something that was like when Matter comes to TVs,
Speaker 3:  that's when everything's again, I was like, okay, I don't even have time
Speaker 3:  to think about
Speaker 4:  We wrote that article too. I just wanna be clear. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  No, we probably did, but I've, I've started wondering
Speaker 3:  like there's a, there's a version of the thing that you just described where
Speaker 3:  it's like matter sort of handles the very basics and then there's interesting
Speaker 3:  competition and innovation on top of that. Yeah. That actually strikes me
Speaker 3:  as a not terrible outcome. That's the's whole point really. But then there's
Speaker 3:  another version of it. But then the question on top of that, right? Is how
Speaker 3:  much do you push down into that protocol? And I, I just, I
Speaker 3:  I wonder what that balance looks like over time. Because the question of
Speaker 3:  like, what is an interesting innovation that I did and what should just be
Speaker 3:  baked in by default to every one of these devices feels like the most
Speaker 3:  sliding scale, slippery slope of all time. You
Speaker 8:  Know, we're a member of the CSA alliance, which is the alliance that makes
Speaker 8:  matter. And when you go to these member meetings and you talk to people,
Speaker 8:  they wanna put everything in matter, right? Like, oh, manage your
Speaker 8:  wireless router manage like, because that connects to matter in a way. Let
Speaker 8:  your wireless router should be part of meta or everything that is
Speaker 8:  electronics in your house should be part of matter. They believe that this
Speaker 8:  is kind of the, the vision is we have solved onboarding,
Speaker 8:  commissioning of devices and sharing devices between smart home controllers.
Speaker 8:  We can use that as a base layer of, well, smart home is the first
Speaker 8:  thing. Maybe wireless routers, well we couldn say we couldn consider that
Speaker 8:  smart home, but maybe your car will be better. Who knows?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think who knows is the right, I mean, Jen, go ahead.
Speaker 6:  It is is the fundamental foundation that they were trying to
Speaker 6:  fix and then it does feel like it's maybe got a little ahead of itself, but,
Speaker 6:  but it sounds like what you're talking about from the technical perspective
Speaker 6:  is that that foundation is solid. Yeah, And it works
Speaker 6:  And it does as it's said on the tin. It's just that when we bring
Speaker 6:  this, the interoperability side or the, the, the platforms,
Speaker 6:  the different app, the different manufacturers who all are implementing things
Speaker 6:  in different ways and perhaps that's where we're seeing some of this
Speaker 6:  friction and difficult user experiences. But so
Speaker 6:  it's really, it is that and and Home Assistant it seems
Speaker 6:  from, from my perspective, watching what's changed with the company
Speaker 6:  over the last year or two is matter is actually helping push Home
Speaker 6:  Assistant to become more of a mainstream platform and not
Speaker 6:  just the way you connect everything that couldn't connect to HomeKit.
Speaker 6:  So that in that sense matter is, is succeeding in its in its
Speaker 6:  goal, which is give it a simple foundation that
Speaker 6:  every smart home device can use and then companies can innovate
Speaker 6:  and build experiences on top of matter. Is that, I mean,
Speaker 6:  would
Speaker 8:  You say that's Yeah, I mean that's that would be very nice.
Speaker 6:  Well
Speaker 4:  Can I, I just have these like extremely dumb questions. Yeah. Like what
Speaker 4:  is a smart home? Like that's where my brain is. It feels like the
Speaker 4:  product that everyone's trying to build is a smart home. Yes. Not a light
Speaker 4:  switch. And none of this stuff has solved the problem of
Speaker 4:  where in the computing landscape is your home, like as
Speaker 4:  a product. It's just how do we shove a bunch of stuff together? Like
Speaker 4:  to me, the big unlock of the smart home is that when we wake up in the morning
Speaker 4:  and they, a little sensor in our hallway detects motion, the lights in the
Speaker 4:  kitchen turn on and they're, I you can't buy that outta the box. Like, I
Speaker 4:  had to be like that. This is what I would like to have happen. I need a Phillips
Speaker 4:  hue hub that has adaptive lighting that the, like all the way down to where
Speaker 4:  will I program this logic of sensor is on after
Speaker 4:  sunrise and lights go on in this mode. And I, I had
Speaker 4:  to figure all that out And it feels like matter doesn't solve that. It just
Speaker 4:  puts all the devices somewhere such that someone else can solve that and,
Speaker 4:  but that seems like there will be no demand for a million matter
Speaker 4:  devices unless anyone can articulate the value of having a bunch of
Speaker 4:  smart devices.
Speaker 8:  Well I think this is where Google and Apple show what they
Speaker 8:  want, right? They wanna be competing on who can make a smart home
Speaker 8:  platform. They don't wanna make light bulbs. There's no margin on light bulbs,
Speaker 8:  right? So it's a bit like those Android TV we couldn buy,
Speaker 4:  But once you start putting a bunch of DRAM in the light bulbs, it feels like
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 8:  Just can't stop thinking about the
Speaker 4:  Sentence you ram prices. We need more chips in the light bulbs. Like I just
Speaker 4:  can't, that is in my brain, you's gonna be like this eight gigs of memory
Speaker 4:  in the light bulb will cost $500.
Speaker 8:  That's why your Apple watches as powerful as the first iPhone, right? This
Speaker 8:  is like my light bulb
Speaker 4:  Anyway, sorry I interrupt. Keep going. So they're, they're competing with
Speaker 4:  the platform
Speaker 8:  But they have, well they compet compete on that level. So they just want,
Speaker 8:  it's a bit like UB, they just want all the data and control and then they
Speaker 8:  can build innovative or user facing experiences. It's a bit
Speaker 8:  like, I don't know the vendor of my light switches here that are not smart,
Speaker 8:  right? Because I just use them, they work, electricity just works. I
Speaker 8:  don't know who made my cables all that stuff. And they just wanna commoditize
Speaker 8:  the light bulb. A smart light bulb should be you just plug it in, you scan
Speaker 8:  the QR code, now it's part of your smart home and then you are living
Speaker 8:  in your Google world, in your Apple world and do these kind of things. But
Speaker 8:  of course, because homelessness is at the same level operating as Google
Speaker 8:  and Apple, we bring everything together. We are seeing a huge benefit from
Speaker 8:  this because we also get all that data now, right?
Speaker 4:  So here's the reveal of my little story, which is the motion sensor in the
Speaker 4:  hallway is the motion sensor in my Eco B thermostat, which is
Speaker 4:  bridged right all the way into all of this stuff
Speaker 4:  with some, I don't even know, it's some combination of home bridge and home
Speaker 4:  kid. And it's just like, there's just a mess of like emergent behaviors that
Speaker 4:  turn on the lights in the morning and one day it's gonna wake up and kill
Speaker 4:  us all right? Like I don't know exactly how that computer works, but it works
Speaker 4:  and, but it's that thing which is like there's already a motion sensor here
Speaker 4:  and I should be able to just get at it and use it to program other stuff.
Speaker 4:  And that again, like I don't think Apple and Google see that is like
Speaker 4:  you're buying all this stuff with all these redundant capabilities in your
Speaker 4:  house. Like turning on a light in the morning is like an incredible signal
Speaker 4:  about a bunch of other stuff that should happen, right? Yeah. Are you doing
Speaker 4:  that in Home Assistant? Is that letting you say, okay, like as Jen is saying,
Speaker 4:  matter let's you bring more stuff directly into Home Assistant instead of
Speaker 4:  just serving as the bridge. Is that now saying, okay we can, we can
Speaker 4:  show people like, because we now have, now we're
Speaker 4:  able to compete on the platform level with Apple and Google. We're not all
Speaker 4:  trying to build custom light switches. We're gonna make this smart home platform
Speaker 4:  more powerful or capable or even more interesting.
Speaker 8:  I mean, well that's always the thing we've been doing, right? It's like to
Speaker 8:  build on top, like we built getting all the devices into a single
Speaker 8:  place was only because we wanna build stuff on top and we added like, you
Speaker 8:  know, the APIs are open, anyone else is messing with it. There's third
Speaker 8:  party dashboards and automation engines and AI that's all plugging into Home
Speaker 8:  Assistant because nobody else wants to, nobody wants to solve that problem
Speaker 8:  of getting all that data into a single place. I think that
Speaker 8:  when you're talking about like your motion sensor, that is a super interesting
Speaker 8:  use case and bring it all together. Very impressive. But If you look
Speaker 8:  at like, I just push buttons until lights turn. I, I'm not trying to, right,
Speaker 8:  but If you, If you look at Apple, well I think they're more interested right
Speaker 8:  now in robot arms or iPads, thingies, right? Like
Speaker 8:  there's of course, yeah there's this is they have different
Speaker 8:  priorities but also their apps are installed on a billion phones. So they
Speaker 8:  must have like this is the entryway into the smartphone smart home
Speaker 8:  world and just getting everything into a UI that we couldn
Speaker 8:  control it is already like the first step and they're happy if like the
Speaker 8:  majority of the people can do that. Where in Home Assistant you get to Home
Speaker 8:  Assistant because you had a problem you couldn't solve, we can solve
Speaker 8:  it for you. We give you all the knobs and tools like it's the most extensive
Speaker 8:  toolkit, which is also what confuses people sometimes because there's so
Speaker 8:  much data on your screen. But then everything is possible
Speaker 8:  as, as long as we couldn dream up the solution. So Nili, you're
Speaker 8:  able to dream this up. I think the majority of the people like our parents,
Speaker 8:  they're not gonna think, oh, if there's a motion sensor here, then I can
Speaker 8:  turn on the light there. That will not cross their mind. So there is a
Speaker 8:  gap that we need to solve in every smart home
Speaker 8:  platform in a way that we can tell the user, we see that you
Speaker 8:  act like this every morning or we see you doing this or this is
Speaker 8:  an idea we couldn do and then they can apply it.
Speaker 6:  Well and that's, that comes from the smart home platform. But then what matter
Speaker 6:  I think is gonna help with is that exact problem that Neli had was finding
Speaker 6:  a device that was gonna trigger his lights. So because Matter
Speaker 6:  provides device, device communication in your home,
Speaker 6:  we couldn now, and this has happened now I think Eve has devices like this
Speaker 6:  that we couldn combine, we couldn buy a device that has been bound already.
Speaker 6:  So when you get your light bulbs, it'll come bound with a smart
Speaker 6:  switch that, so then you just put them in your house and they will work.
Speaker 6:  You don't have to go through any kind of setup process in the app to get
Speaker 6:  it to turn on the lights when you want it to. But then we couldn use an app
Speaker 6:  or a smart home platform to add that extra layer like the adaptive lighting
Speaker 6:  so that it turns on the lights at the right time of day to the right time
Speaker 6:  of temperature. So it is, you know, you've basically got three layers. You've
Speaker 6:  got the communication foundation layer, then you've got the devices
Speaker 6:  and because the device manufacturer who makes that switch and that
Speaker 6:  light that can be bound together through binding,
Speaker 6:  can now work with all the platforms through matter without having to
Speaker 6:  have spent all of their time and resources for a small startup
Speaker 6:  or a open source home platform
Speaker 6:  working with all these big platforms like Apple Home and Google,
Speaker 6:  they can put their resources into developing a, into developing a better
Speaker 6:  product and then work with these platforms on top those, that's like the
Speaker 6:  three layer cake really. Yeah. Of what matters.
Speaker 8:  That is the theory binding devices together has
Speaker 8:  never, ever worked ZigBee Z-Wave the
Speaker 8:  the, the technology works, but explaining it to the user that
Speaker 8:  this device publishes these signals and we couldn wire them up to that signal
Speaker 8:  and then now the motion sensor who's turning on the light is responsible
Speaker 8:  for turning off the light because they turned it on, right? They have to
Speaker 8:  turn it off. Is that this new signal, is that built into the motion sensor
Speaker 8:  like in home system? Because we have all these different technologies, we
Speaker 8:  have that tech feature like tucked away. Nobody ever really uses it. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, can lemme ask a, a very, lemme put, let me just try to do a
Speaker 4:  metaphor here. Bluetooth was invented in, oh my god,
Speaker 4:  1997, right? Air AirPods took until 2016,
Speaker 4:  right? The ultimate Bluetooth device, the thing that everybody wanted in
Speaker 4:  the end in Apple had to make like a special Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  to do it. That's a long time. That's 20 years. Yeah. Where are we on that?
Speaker 4:  More than 20 years, right? Yeah, it's 20, 21 years, something like that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I am, I don't think we couldn have like an AirPods moment
Speaker 8:  for matter because you are always working with all these different devices.
Speaker 8:  So yes, maybe there will be a, maybe if Apple makes a light bulb,
Speaker 8:  it'll work perfectly within their system. But then people
Speaker 8:  need to have that everything into one ecosystem, right? Like Apple always
Speaker 8:  has the, the benefit of controlling the whole stack. They have
Speaker 8:  your MacBook, they have your iPhone and then your AirPods and they can automatically
Speaker 8:  switch and do all the magic in Matter world. That is just not gonna happen.
Speaker 8:  You might have your Google threat border router or you might have a
Speaker 8:  ZigBee light bulb that goes through your smart home system or something.
Speaker 8:  Right? And every, if everything has to work together, I think that will be
Speaker 8:  hard.
Speaker 3:  I remember Jen said to me like o over a year ago that like,
Speaker 3:  if I could just convince you to renovate your entire house all at once, this
Speaker 3:  is actually a really easy problem to solve.
Speaker 3:  The problem is that that's not a real thing that anyone,
Speaker 4:  But you still won't be able to get a garage door, right? There's like the,
Speaker 4:  the garage door companies have no incentive to use matter. The
Speaker 4:  the companies I see that I have a lot of incentive to use matter are the
Speaker 4:  big appliance companies because they, I think they do not want
Speaker 4:  to suffer cloud costs for the entire life of an appliance.
Speaker 4:  And they, I, I think they know that a subscription fee
Speaker 4:  for the garbage features they offer in their apps will never fly. So
Speaker 4:  it matters great for them. They're like, you're stuff's on wifi, like the
Speaker 4:  timer on off, you get a notification, we can just do this in the standard.
Speaker 4:  You're good to go. Then there's the super commodity stuff like light
Speaker 4:  bulbs and those smart plug outlets and stuff where it's
Speaker 4:  very hard. Everything in the middle. Even the robot vacuum seems like
Speaker 4:  political drama times a thousand.
Speaker 8:  Oh for sure.
Speaker 4:  Do you see that getting any better that we'll just have a base layer of commodity
Speaker 4:  stuff or base level of commodity connectivity and then we're gonna layer
Speaker 4:  on top because that's what you really want. That's USP, that's Bluetooth,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. There's a base layer of Bluetooth and there's Apple being like
Speaker 4:  AirPods special Bluetooth, but it's still Bluetooth.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I think that we will see more things being commoditized And
Speaker 8:  it is at some point, like robot vacuums, they just keep adding more features.
Speaker 8:  Now, right now they have AI automatically creating a gallery of the pets
Speaker 8:  when they photo it, when they drive past vacuuming and that will never make
Speaker 8:  it to matter, right? 'cause they try to get you
Speaker 3:  I'm okay with that. I just wanna say on the record, I'm okay with that. That
Speaker 3:  doesn't need to be part of the protocol.
Speaker 3:  The full mugshot gallery. Yeah, I'm, I'm good. We couldn leave that
Speaker 3:  proprietary,
Speaker 8:  But we we're gonna see more things commoditized. But I think there will be
Speaker 8:  always things, people always want to have you use their app, right?
Speaker 8:  The business benefit. I've talked to garage door opener manufacturers
Speaker 8:  that are not MyQ and they're like, we would love to work with you, but
Speaker 8:  also we have business cases and how if it's in Home Assistant, our
Speaker 8:  business cases fall flat because people could just use Home Assistant and
Speaker 8:  use everything else and that's competing with our own business. And I'm like,
Speaker 8:  yeah, but this is what users want. But that's just, you know,
Speaker 3:  I think there's the question of like how long is
Speaker 3:  matter going to take I think is like maybe year, how long has it big
Speaker 3:  string, maybe the heat death of the universe, like I used to say. But I am
Speaker 3:  curious, like for you, as you're thinking about even just like the next 12
Speaker 3:  months, it feels like you're, you're describing this really interesting race
Speaker 3:  where Matter is going to try to sort of contain
Speaker 3:  more devices
Speaker 3:  everything else more accessible to more people. Yeah. What does that race
Speaker 3:  look like over the next 12 months?
Speaker 8:  That's a good question.
Speaker 8:  I think we are, I think, you know, meta will just keep chugging along, right?
Speaker 8:  Like there will be like, you know, we'll celebrate the new specs. We'll see
Speaker 8:  like one or two new devices being capable
Speaker 8:  like to be implemented and then like, you know, in two, in two years, three
Speaker 8:  years they'll arrive. I think where matter can shine will be
Speaker 8:  energy management in the home. I think there's a lot of people talking about
Speaker 8:  I want to charge my car when it's the solar power is like
Speaker 8:  being very, giving me cheap energy for example. I think
Speaker 8:  that's something where, okay, you have three, four devices that need to speak
Speaker 8:  matter. You have a smart home controller that isn't just for smart
Speaker 8:  home, but this energy specific, you just have a smart
Speaker 8:  matter energy controller device that is just
Speaker 8:  controlling your car, the charger and plugs into your solar
Speaker 8:  panels and just that piece can run over there. I think that
Speaker 8:  with Home Assistant, we have all that data. We are, like I said before, we're
Speaker 8:  a toolkit. We make tool, we make like the toolbox, right? Like with all the
Speaker 8:  tools, our dream is to make more solutions, but then you need
Speaker 8:  like a team. Oh, now, now we have a team of three people just looking at
Speaker 8:  energy. There's a, and we're doing that, we're working with like universities
Speaker 8:  nowadays, but that's just like years in the making to get there.
Speaker 8:  So for us, we're just keep chugging along, just adding all the devices as
Speaker 8:  they come and see kind of what grows in our ecosystem.
Speaker 3:  And are you, you're, you're cool with being a, a power user thing for a while?
Speaker 3:  I feel like there's part of me that says, like, on principle, you shouldn't
Speaker 3:  have to like know what Raspberry pie is to be good at the smart home,
Speaker 3:  but it also feels like that's just where we're gonna be for a while.
Speaker 8:  We, we have ready-made hubs, right? We couldn buy a Home Assistant green,
Speaker 8:  $99 and you have Home Assistant. But I think I'm, we always
Speaker 8:  wanna be power users. Now the how much of a power
Speaker 8:  user you have to be that will like get lower and lower. But I don't
Speaker 8:  wanna, like a person shouldn't like start with Home Assistant. They will
Speaker 8:  always, I, I see this whole journey of like, you have first five smart apps,
Speaker 8:  you don't even realize you have a smart home. Then you go with Google Apple,
Speaker 8:  you run into limitations, then you get to Home Assistant. And I think that
Speaker 8:  journey, it shouldn't change because people come to Home Assistant,
Speaker 8:  they have at least some knowledge. They have a problem they wanna solve And
Speaker 8:  it will help them find the right tools. And we get familiar with the system.
Speaker 6:  Well, I know one of the things you've said you're working on is that sort
Speaker 6:  of spousal approval factor too, like making the smart home easier
Speaker 6:  to control for the rest of the home. Like, so like Eli's point about the
Speaker 6:  Apple Control center, I mean, having an easy interface
Speaker 6:  because it's great if you've got someone that's willing to do the
Speaker 6:  tinkering, but then to be able to, because the smart home is not personal.
Speaker 6:  It's not just for one person. Most of the time there are other people, whether
Speaker 6:  you live with them or they're visiting who are coming into your home that
Speaker 6:  need to be able to interact. And that I think is a really interesting, I
Speaker 6:  mean, that's something that very few platforms have really successfully
Speaker 6:  solved.
Speaker 8:  It's,
Speaker 4:  It's zero in fact.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. We even thought about if we should add a survey button that users
Speaker 8:  that are not the admin can give feedback to their admin what they like on
Speaker 8:  the dashboard. That's,
Speaker 3:  That's good.
Speaker 3:  That's very good. My, my survey button is just my wife yells at me. I will
Speaker 3:  never forget the moment that I, I rigged up one of the lights in our, our
Speaker 3:  newborn baby's room. And then I, I turned it off with the app
Speaker 3:  and then she went in and tried to turn it on and I was like, oh no, couldn,
Speaker 3:  can't you have to turn it on with the app? Because I turned it and she was
Speaker 3:  like, what in the holy hell are you talking about? And that was the end of,
Speaker 3:  that was the end of my smart home. I don't
Speaker 4:  Have the, I don't have the deep insight. I just know that you screwed up.
Speaker 3:  Sure I did.
Speaker 4:  Anna. Whatever Anna said is right.
Speaker 3:  It's correct and Matter will fix it in 2068.
Speaker 6:  You heard it here.
Speaker 3:  All right. Any, any you guys have any more questions before we let our, our
Speaker 3:  friend Pauler go?
Speaker 4:  I just have one, just a pickup. And maybe we use this and we done, I'm curious.
Speaker 4:  You see the whole ecosystem, right? There's the big companies doing all the
Speaker 4:  big company stuff. There's a proliferation of apparently ruthless vacuum
Speaker 4:  manufacturers who are gonna solve this problem. Then there's this class
Speaker 4:  of smart home gadget companies that seems to exist
Speaker 4:  to make the commodity stuff. Like me Ross is just like, smart plugs have
Speaker 4:  however many shapes and size of a smart plug you want. Yeah. There, there's
Speaker 4:  a million of them. Are those sustainable businesses in
Speaker 4:  a world of matter? Like, does that standard enable more of those companies
Speaker 4:  to exist because they seem like betting on them
Speaker 4:  to run my home. If, I don't know if the company's gonna last and the
Speaker 4:  cloud server might go down and the firm updates might never be there and
Speaker 4:  their security problem, like, does matter solve that problem where that stuff
Speaker 4:  stays more stable and those companies get to exist longer? Or is it they're
Speaker 4:  just taking advantage of the opportunity?
Speaker 8:  We need a re stabilization, like I think a lot of middle level
Speaker 8:  companies will go away. The more luxury light bulbs like phis U have a reason
Speaker 8:  to exist. They have like quality lights, ecosystem at the bo at the
Speaker 8:  bottom of the, like the cheaper market. It's just gonna be a race to the
Speaker 8:  bottom, right? And then it's not about you download the firmware like from
Speaker 8:  Expressive provides the tips. For example, they have firmware for their light
Speaker 8:  bulbs. You don't need to even know about matter. You just built this.
Speaker 8:  And it really becomes a race on logistics. Who gets it the cheapest to be
Speaker 8:  in the shop when the user or consumer is buying a light bulb?
Speaker 8:  Will those companies exist? Well, if they use the expressive firmware as
Speaker 8:  is expressive will do the firmware updates actually. And Matter has
Speaker 8:  a way to distribute these. And like for example, home systems can install
Speaker 8:  matter firmware updates. And so we, that is a possibility.
Speaker 8:  Will it work that way? Or should the one that actually
Speaker 8:  put the expressive tip in sign off on something, I don't know, maybe that
Speaker 8:  will go wrong. It will probably go wrong.
Speaker 8:  Is a light bulb very important to be secure as in
Speaker 8:  more so with matter because we're talking ip, right? Threat
Speaker 8:  devices could also, certain border routers allow
Speaker 8:  threat device to talk to the internet. Bad idea. It is possible.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, we need better security. So
Speaker 8:  yeah, it's a sit. So,
Speaker 6:  But you'd still be able to use, you'd still be able to use that
Speaker 6:  Miro if Miro went out business? Yes. And it was a matter plug, you would
Speaker 6:  still be able to use that mi erase plug? Oh, yes. Yes. And you would still
Speaker 6:  be able to use it in Home Assistant because it's a local, so you wouldn't
Speaker 6:  lose the functionality. But yes, the up there is still a lot of fuzziness
Speaker 6:  around the firmware updating and how that's gonna work. 'cause originally
Speaker 6:  it was intended that it would all go through matter and then that hasn't.
Speaker 6:  That's sort of coming in. Yeah, we, because that has to go through the platform.
Speaker 6:  So yes, that's still an area where it's, it's, it's murky.
Speaker 8:  We have the firmware updates working, but then there was a bunch of firmwares
Speaker 8:  on the, like it's, it's weird. It's kind of a blockchain place where the
Speaker 8:  store firmwares don't, that's a different story, but
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 8:  It was invented when blockchains were a hype. So they have a distributed
Speaker 8:  ledger. They don't call it blockchain. Oh my God. But that's where the firmware
Speaker 8:  are stored. But there are certain firmware stored there that are incorrect.
Speaker 8:  So we upload it to a plug and we break the plug. And then who's responsible?
Speaker 8:  Like we just got your firmware from the blockchain, like who put it on the
Speaker 8:  blockchain? That person is, that company's responsible, but they're like,
Speaker 8:  but I uploaded it to your light bulb. And so yeah, there's firmware updates
Speaker 8:  are definitely not solved yet.
Speaker 3:  Who put it on the blockchain is the Christmas song that needs to exist.
Speaker 3:  Anyway. All right. We, we should, we should let you go. We should get outta
Speaker 3:  here. We're ending all of this as soon as you said it's a shit show. So don't
Speaker 3:  even, don't even worry. It's
Speaker 8:  Okay. Good.
Speaker 3:  There's no coming, there's no improving on that. But Paul,
Speaker 3:  thank you so much for doing this with us. This was incredibly fun. Awesome.
Speaker 3:  We appreciate it.
Speaker 3:  All right, we got one more quick thing to do and then we're gonna get outta
Speaker 3:  here and go do holiday things. This is The Vergecast hotline. As always,
Speaker 3:  we couldn call 8 6 6 VERGE one one email vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 3:  dot com. We love all of your questions. We are off for the next couple of
Speaker 3:  weeks, but we will still be listening to every single hotline question and
Speaker 3:  reading every single email several times because it's just
Speaker 3:  a delightful way to spend my time over the holidays. Liam, who's the sponsor
Speaker 3:  for the hotline, this week's
Speaker 1:  Vergecast hotline is presented by Amazon Q, the new generative AI
Speaker 1:  assistant from
Speaker 9:  AWS.
Speaker 3:  Beautiful. All right. Jen, I have not prepared you for what this is, but
Speaker 3:  this is a thing you and I have talked about before. So I'm just gonna play
Speaker 3:  the question. We'll go where we go. Sound good? Okay.
Speaker 6:  Sounds good. All
Speaker 3:  Right.
Speaker 9:  Hey there, this is Keith from West Des Moines, Iowa.
Speaker 9:  I'm calling as I have been encountering a problem more and more over
Speaker 9:  recent years and this Thanksgiving it felt like it came to a head.
Speaker 9:  You know, over the years I've accumulated a number of recipes online that
Speaker 9:  I like, and I just threw those in a bookmark and would come back to 'em
Speaker 9:  down the road whenever I wanted to make that recipe. But given,
Speaker 9:  you know, the, the way Google handles search engine
Speaker 9:  optimization and referrals and all that stuff, these
Speaker 9:  recipes are increasingly just no longer present. I often
Speaker 9:  can find them on archive.org and can track down what
Speaker 9:  they looked like in, you know, 2012 or what have you, and can
Speaker 9:  recover those recipes. But it feels like those
Speaker 9:  weeds are getting more and more tenuous. I was wondering if there's maybe
Speaker 9:  an app that I could be using to collect some of these recipes together
Speaker 9:  with the idea being that a, I can preserve them So I don't need to worry
Speaker 9:  about losing them down the road. And then ideally it would be something
Speaker 9:  where perhaps I could put these recipes in such a format that I could
Speaker 9:  use some of my smart devices to help me, you know, go through
Speaker 9:  the actual process of cooking if I've rendered these recipes
Speaker 9:  in a more readable format for the devices. Anyway,
Speaker 9:  I hope that, you know, you may be able to give me some weeds on things that
Speaker 9:  might help me. So my Thanksgiving next year is a little bit more straightforward.
Speaker 9:  Thank you so much. Have a good day.
Speaker 3:  Jen, you see why I've brought you this question?
Speaker 6:  Yes. I feel his pain as well.
Speaker 3:  So I, I have a couple of of ideas to throw out and things that I've tried,
Speaker 3:  but I'm, I'm very curious to hear for you, especially as a person who is
Speaker 3:  very committed to the idea of like integrating all of this stuff into your
Speaker 3:  smartphone or your smart home setup, how you're making all of this work.
Speaker 3:  Tell us about your setup right now
Speaker 6:  In terms of recipes. I have been using the Samsung Food
Speaker 6:  app for a while that does what, what he's asking,
Speaker 6:  which is pulls all the data and puts it into
Speaker 6:  the Samsung Food app. And so it's not actually a link
Speaker 6:  to the recipe, although there is a link in there, but you have
Speaker 6:  all the data. But the problem is the link is still there
Speaker 6:  and he, the issue he's having is he's going to these links and they've,
Speaker 6:  they've gone away. So right now, the way the Samsung food apps
Speaker 6:  works, depending on what app, what the format of
Speaker 6:  your recipe was, it does actually pull the
Speaker 6:  ingredients. So you get all the ingredients, then it, a separate tab has
Speaker 6:  all the step-by-step instructions. And then we
Speaker 6:  couldn click and actually read the, the full recipe on in all its
Speaker 6:  glory. It also in theory works with things like TikTok recipes and Instagram
Speaker 6:  recipes, though I've never managed to get it to do that, which is a little
Speaker 6:  more complicated. But the Samsung food app is so, and,
Speaker 6:  and just to make this, because I love the smart kitchen, the, one of the
Speaker 6:  main reasons I use it is because I can pull it up on my smart fridge
Speaker 6:  and then I have the big screen recipe, which is key 'cause Oh, that's
Speaker 3:  Actually really nice.
Speaker 6:  Use your phone when you're cooking and looking at recipes. It's never good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And some recipes will have this feature where we couldn like
Speaker 6:  force the phone to stay open so that it doesn't lock while you are using
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They call it like cook mode or whatever.
Speaker 6:  Right. Cook mode. Yeah. That's useful. But my absolute favorite sort of
Speaker 6:  fail safe recipe app that I dumped all my recipes in to over the years
Speaker 6:  and they never go away is paprika. Mm.
Speaker 6:  Which I love. Its
Speaker 3:  Paprika has been around forever.
Speaker 6:  Has been around forever. Yeah. And that's a good thing, you know, like it's
Speaker 6:  still there. Right. So my recipes are all still there. So I'm, I've
Speaker 6:  been trying the Samsung food thing sort of as, as an experiment and it's
Speaker 6:  got some interesting features, but paprika is still my, my go-to. And then
Speaker 6:  I will pull it up on my iPad. I haven't found a way
Speaker 6:  to pull it up on a smart display though, which is, you know, I,
Speaker 6:  I'm more and more getting, I've been testing the 21 inch Echo show and for,
Speaker 6:  for cooking recipes in the kitchen, it's like, oh, so much
Speaker 6:  space. We
Speaker 3:  Couldn also like slice things on top of it. Just, that's, that's what we
Speaker 3:  need. Honestly, I have never thought about this until right now, but a smart
Speaker 3:  display that is also a cutting board is a thing that should exist. And I
Speaker 3:  want it very badly.
Speaker 6:  Actually, Bosch did actually make that. Did they really? It was at c Can
Speaker 6:  I buy it? ES No, it was at CES like 2018
Speaker 6:  I wanna say. And it was, well it was like a projector that projected
Speaker 6:  your recipe or different things onto your countertop. Yes,
Speaker 6:  yes. You're right. That's what we
Speaker 3:  Need. Yes. I want this. Okay. So I, paprika is a really good app
Speaker 3:  and is is one of the ones I was gonna suggest. I would just throw two other
Speaker 3:  ones in. There's an app called PESTLE that is also
Speaker 3:  very good and does very similar things. And it,
Speaker 3:  as far as I understand, does a really good job
Speaker 3:  of pulling recipes out of TikTok and Instagram.
Speaker 3:  Ah, yeah. I'm really glad you mentioned that actually. 'cause this is one
Speaker 3:  of the things that I have been looking for personally. I use an app mostly
Speaker 3:  for recipes called Mela, MELA. It's
Speaker 3:  made by the same guy who makes reader the RSS reader app. It's just like
Speaker 3:  lovely and beautifully designed and it's very plain text and I really like
Speaker 3:  it. But increasingly I'm finding
Speaker 3:  recipes I want to try on social. You see like, oh those cinnamon
Speaker 3:  buns look really good. And so the question of like, can you extract something
Speaker 3:  out of that actually becomes really interesting. And I haven't played with
Speaker 3:  pestle enough to be able to say this with great certainty for myself. But
Speaker 3:  I hear really good things that its ability to import a recipe
Speaker 3:  from Instagram or TikTok is very good.
Speaker 6:  I don't know how that's possible though, because they're not actual recipes
Speaker 6:  half the time.
Speaker 3:  I mean, that's true. It's
Speaker 6:  Only just some person throwing things in a bowl and it's
Speaker 3:  Just like 11 pounds of butter and some spaghetti and they're like, look,
Speaker 3:  it's muffins. It's like that can't possibly be muffins. I like, I know
Speaker 3:  enough to know that's not muffins,
Speaker 3:  but a but apparent people say it works. So that's one I would say. And the
Speaker 3:  other one is Crouton. Oh yes. Which another one that
Speaker 3:  people really like and has done some really interesting stuff over
Speaker 3:  recent years to make itself work. And Kreton does a really
Speaker 3:  good job of like making
Speaker 3:  your grocery list for you. Like the, some of these apps, which I really like
Speaker 3:  you, we couldn like meal plan inside of them. Yeah. Are you a meal
Speaker 3:  planner?
Speaker 6:  I've tried to be.
Speaker 3:  I really aspire to be
Speaker 6:  A meal planner. No, that is an aspirational thing. Yeah. It's just that two
Speaker 6:  hours sit down on a Sunday evening plan for the week. It just never happens.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But one thing, If you are a meal planner, one thing some of these apps
Speaker 3:  will do is you basically mark the recipes you're gonna make And it will actually
Speaker 3:  make a shopping list for you and just be like, here are all the things that
Speaker 3:  you need in order to make all of this food.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Samsung food does that for you too. Super clever. And then we couldn
Speaker 6:  like super clever. Send it to Instacart.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's, it's a really good idea. And If you are more organized
Speaker 3:  than I am,
Speaker 6:  I highly recommend it. Then you'll have like two teaspoons of paprika on
Speaker 6:  your shopping list.
Speaker 3:  I know there is that. And then it's like, oh, instead I'll just go to Costco
Speaker 3:  and buy eight pounds of it. I'll never use. And I will say this is one thing
Speaker 3:  where like we've talked about this sort of Samsung vision for
Speaker 3:  the kitchen it, and I find it really compelling for exactly that reason,
Speaker 3:  right? 'cause we couldn go, you should be able to go both ways or you should
Speaker 3:  be able to say, here's what I wanna make. Tell me what I need. Or
Speaker 3:  I have these eight ingredients in my fridge, what can I make with it? And
Speaker 3:  it feels like Samsung is the closest to being able to do Yeah. All of that
Speaker 3:  kind of coherently in one place.
Speaker 6:  One place. Well, and they, and they just actually this week announced
Speaker 6:  new screens in devices, which, you know, I know we don't like the
Speaker 6:  screens everywhere, but you know, a little screen on top of your cooktop
Speaker 6:  that's actually showing you your recipe as you're cooking it. Oh yeah. I
Speaker 6:  can see use case there. And they've also met, made a smaller screen for the
Speaker 6:  fridge. So If you wa If you like the idea of having your recipe on your fridge,
Speaker 6:  but you don't like the idea of the 25 inch screen or whatever the size is,
Speaker 6:  they now have the s the family hub fridge has a smaller screen. Oh.
Speaker 6:  So we couldn. But yeah, the screens, and
Speaker 3:  I thought you were saying like a fridge magnet, but it's a screen. Can you
Speaker 3:  just stick
Speaker 6:  It a pun? Well that's, I've seen people do that with iPads. Like, oh, use
Speaker 6:  them, them in their kitchen as recipe to do recipes
Speaker 6:  and put it on a magnetic mount. But because
Speaker 3:  Mine goes on top of the toaster, that's where my iPad goes. See
Speaker 6:  I know, I'm just, the dangers, the dangers of
Speaker 3:  IPads in the, it's a disaster of
Speaker 6:  Idea in the kitchen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I have ruined at least one magic keyboard just with
Speaker 3:  spilling and things. Oh, I'm a very aggressive whisker. It turns
Speaker 3:  out. And that is bad for Apple iPad
Speaker 6:  Keyboards. So they're like fabricy keyboards. Yeah. Ooh. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But, so here's my question about Samsung food is If you didn't have any other
Speaker 3:  Samsung stuff, but you just wanted one of these like recipe organizers
Speaker 3:  to some extent, they're all samey a little bit. They have the
Speaker 3:  same kinds of features you're just picking on like design and platforms and
Speaker 3:  stuff. Like purely on its own. Is Samsung food good
Speaker 3:  enough that you would tell people to like give it a whirl?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Yeah. Okay. 'cause it was based on Whisk, which was one of the original
Speaker 6:  smart recipe apps. I mean that's basically, it is whisk now. It does have
Speaker 6:  a lot of ads in it. That's the only downside. But rest, If you, If you use
Speaker 6:  recipes on the internet, you are used to ads.
Speaker 6:  But we couldn pay to get rid of the ads. And then there's a lot of
Speaker 6:  recipe apps actually you do have to pay for, I think paprika, I had to pay
Speaker 6:  for it. I think it was very expensive, but I think it was like $7 or something.
Speaker 6:  Which at the time, but eight years ago was quite a lot for an app.
Speaker 6:  But yes, I do, I do like it. It works well. It's the
Speaker 6:  you, the layout to get from the main, main Samsung food
Speaker 6:  page to your recipes that you've saved. That's not an easy process. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  They're trying, there's a lot of, and a lot of recipe apps will do this,
Speaker 6:  I've noticed. Like trying to show you, suggest to you what you should cook
Speaker 6:  as opposed to I know what I'm gonna cook. I need to go find my recipe. Just
Speaker 6:  let me, let me add it. Get rid of all the cruft. But if you're looking for
Speaker 6:  inspiration ideas, we couldn add your food list to it. And we did this
Speaker 6:  whole thing on The Vergecast Yeah. A while back where you know, now they've
Speaker 6:  actually made that a lot easier to do. We couldn just scan food And it will
Speaker 6:  add it to your list. And so it it, we couldn sort of say, you
Speaker 6:  know, what should I cook tonight? Suggest from my list what food I have in
Speaker 6:  my house or snap a picture of the food you have And it can
Speaker 6:  suggest food recipes you could make with that food. I haven't found
Speaker 6:  that useful at all. It's a neat idea. It
Speaker 6:  is a neat,
Speaker 3:  But at some point it might be easier to just type the words into a search
Speaker 6:  Engine. Yeah. Yeah. The one thing I haven't tried that I really wanna try
Speaker 6:  is apparently if you're at a restaurant and you're eating a dish that you
Speaker 6:  love, we couldn snap a picture of the dish And it will create the recipe
Speaker 6:  for you. Oh, that's cool. Which would be very neat. Yeah. That
Speaker 3:  Would be for me, it would just be like, how do I make Chick-fil-A chicken
Speaker 3:  nuggets in my house? Yes. That's all I wanna know.
Speaker 6:  Air fryer. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's true. I bought one and I have used it two times and this holiday season
Speaker 3:  is when David becomes an air fryer genius. It's happening.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I'm excited for you. Thank
Speaker 3:  You. I appreciate that. All right. So Samsung food, paprika,
Speaker 3:  pestle, crouton, Mila, somewhere in there is one that will work for you.
Speaker 3:  Yes. It feels good. Try 'em all. Save recipes. Yeah. Like it is true that
Speaker 3:  all of these recipe sites are very fleeting things. Get weird.
Speaker 3:  Visit them, look at them, print
Speaker 6:  Them out.
Speaker 3:  Print them out. They need your clicks to exist. But
Speaker 3:  save the recipes because they will not be around forever. Alright Jen, thank
Speaker 3:  you for doing all of this. We people should know, we basically sprung this
Speaker 3:  entire thing on you last minute and then you won the game, which is incredibly
Speaker 3:  rude. But thank you for doing this whole thing with us. This is very fun.
Speaker 6:  It was really fun. I enjoyed it. It was a lovely way to
Speaker 6:  celebrate the spectacular holiday season
Speaker 3:  And next year better than a D. Okay. That's the goal.
Speaker 3:  That's the goal. We're goal, we're just matter matters. Just shows
Speaker 6:  Improvement. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  C minus next year. It's all,
Speaker 6:  I mean, my kids have a lot of D's, so D isn't bad in my mind.
Speaker 6:  Listen,
Speaker 3:  It's still passing. That's all you need. All right, Jen, thank you.
Speaker 6:  I know, I just learned that you know that that is still a passing grade.
Speaker 6:  I thought. I always thought it was a c.
Speaker 6:  I really hope my grand, their grandparents don't listen to this.
Speaker 3:  Listen, everybody's just at her doing their best, Jen, that's all. It's the
Speaker 3:  holidays. All right, thank you.
Speaker 6:  All right. Bye-bye. Thanks.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Will Pour and Eric Gomez. And that's it. We'll
Speaker 1:  see you next week.