# Transcript
ID: 161728a4-c6d0-4db9-9fda-053fa8ffa6d9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6611727241075618694/5555030108530425342/s93290-US-3202s-1727609720.mp3
Description: Michael Sayman, the creator of a viral new app called SocialAI, joins the show to discuss why he built a social network where you're the only human around. He tells us how he thinks about AI interfaces, what's next for ChatGPT and other chatbots, and why posting to a language model might be better than posting on a social network.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Bot Farms.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is the second episode in our miniseries
Speaker 2:  all about AI in the real world. AI is
Speaker 2:  so abstract, and it's a term that we now use in so many
Speaker 2:  ways that honestly it can feel sort of meaningless. So we've
Speaker 2:  been on a quest to find actual examples of actual AI
Speaker 2:  showing up and being useful, or at the very least interesting
Speaker 2:  in our actual lives for this episode. The last one
Speaker 2:  in our little series, for now, I have a feeling we'll come back to this subject,
Speaker 2:  but last one for now. I'm talking to Michael Sayman, who recently
Speaker 2:  launched an app called Social Ai that has become kind of a viral
Speaker 2:  phenomenon on the internet. We'll get into what it is and how it works in
Speaker 2:  pretty serious detail here. But basically, I'd explain social AI
Speaker 2:  this way. Imagine a social network, Twitter or threads or whatever,
Speaker 2:  but every user other than you, every single one other than you
Speaker 2:  is a bot. Does that sound interesting? Pointless,
Speaker 2:  terrible, dystopian amazing. Maybe all of those things.
Speaker 2:  I wasn't sure where I fell on that line when I started
Speaker 2:  talking to Michael, but we ended up having, frankly, one of the most
Speaker 2:  fun conversations I've had in a while, all about how
Speaker 2:  AI works and how we're actually supposed to use it.
Speaker 2:  Spoiler alert, he thinks about this less as a network and more as an
Speaker 2:  interface, and I find that fascinating. We happen to
Speaker 2:  agree, actually, Michael and I, that a chat bot cannot possibly
Speaker 2:  be the future of everything in technology, and Michael has
Speaker 2:  some big ideas about what else we might be able to do. All
Speaker 2:  that is coming up in just a second. But. first, I have to tell my bots what's
Speaker 2:  going on. They worry when I'm gone for too long. This is the Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right back.
Speaker 2:  surprising number of the biggest and most interesting companies in
Speaker 2:  tech and in particular, he's seen a huge part of the evolution of
Speaker 2:  social media and social networks. He worked on stories at Instagram, he
Speaker 2:  worked on status at WhatsApp, he worked on shorts at YouTube. Like
Speaker 2:  I said, he worked at Twitter and a whole bunch of other things, and now he's
Speaker 2:  on his own. He's building apps through his one man startup that he calls
Speaker 2:  friendly apps. At the beginning of our conversation, Michael told me he had
Speaker 2:  been thinking about building an AI social network through much of
Speaker 2:  that time, the idea for what would become social. AI has been
Speaker 2:  in his head for a really long time. It's just that until now, he
Speaker 2:  couldn't actually pull it off.
Speaker 4:  I actually tried building a version of social AI like five years ago, and
Speaker 4:  the tech just wasn't there and it was really bad. What
Speaker 2:  Was it five years ago?
Speaker 4:  It was, I mean, I called it influencer and the idea was
Speaker 4:  that anyone could be an influencer, right? So like, I've been trying to do
Speaker 4:  this for a while, but it, it just quite wasn't there.
Speaker 4:  I originally, you know, because we didn't have the language models, we, we
Speaker 4:  tried to build it and by we, I mean just me, but trying to
Speaker 4:  build this to, to kind of like give
Speaker 4:  people the feeling of a social media app, but not really having to deal
Speaker 4:  with all of it. The, the idea was like, okay, if someone, if
Speaker 4:  someone's addicted to cigarettes, how do you get them off of it? Well, you
Speaker 4:  can't just tell them to stop, right? Like, maybe it's like giving them something,
Speaker 4:  maybe like a nicotine patch or something, right? So like what, what is a
Speaker 4:  way that you get somebody to like be able to get that
Speaker 4:  experience out the way, but maybe not, you know, harm themselves or
Speaker 4:  feel bad. So anyway, so So I built that it didn't really look quite
Speaker 4:  right and it, it didn't work well. So I, I
Speaker 4:  didn't ship it.
Speaker 2:  What did it feel like, actually, but before we get to the chat GBT thing
Speaker 2:  of it all, 'cause that's a, there's an interesting sort of history of text
Speaker 2:  story there, but yes, like when you built the thing
Speaker 2:  before in, in the before times,
Speaker 2:  what, what didn't work, what didn't feel right, like what wasn't ready,
Speaker 4:  I just could not simulate the entire social network in a way
Speaker 4:  that felt interesting, even mildly.
Speaker 4:  Like I, I did the approach that Google did. Like I used to, I used
Speaker 4:  to work at Google, I used to work at Facebook, and I took a
Speaker 4:  similar approach to all of the assistants that there were at the time, giant
Speaker 4:  if L statements, right? Like just massive and
Speaker 4:  okay, like it kind of worked, but like everything else
Speaker 4:  before these language models kind of took off, it was
Speaker 4:  very robotic and very conditional, right?
Speaker 4:  Depending on what you wrote. And, and it just didn't quite feel,
Speaker 4:  it just didn't let you forget about the
Speaker 4:  technology. Like you were reminded in the app that like you
Speaker 4:  had to like do certain things to get certain comments and,
Speaker 4:  and so at that point it was really more of a game.
Speaker 4:  Like I designed it more like a game because the technology just
Speaker 4:  wasn't there to like, make
Speaker 4:  a simulated social network not feel like a game.
Speaker 4:  And So I had to go that route, but, but even then it, it just, it did not
Speaker 4:  feel right. Users, if I imagined if
Speaker 4:  they were to try it would've felt like this
Speaker 4:  app was more like a Farmville game and less like
Speaker 4:  a social network. And, and honestly it just, that's
Speaker 4:  not what I was trying to build. I was trying to build something that felt
Speaker 4:  like a social network and So I had to wait then, then
Speaker 4:  once the, the early versions of
Speaker 4:  GPT-3 0.5 came out, I thought, okay,
Speaker 4:  let me give it another shot and tried to design a version
Speaker 4:  of it. The model would sometimes say random stuff.
Speaker 4:  It was extremely expensive to run all of
Speaker 4:  the different prompts and things that, that I needed for it to work. And
Speaker 4:  I told myself like, there is no way I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  be able to run this at this cost.
Speaker 4:  And it's completely fuzzy and the responses are no good.
Speaker 4:  And So I said, okay, well I have to wait. I have to wait until it gets cheap
Speaker 4:  and I have to wait until it gets more accurate. And so every month
Speaker 4:  for like two years while I was building this startup, I would just wait,
Speaker 4:  I would just look at the latest model, try it out with this,
Speaker 4:  with some of my tests, and from there, just
Speaker 4:  keep going. I would look at the, the
Speaker 4:  outputs that, that they could give and how much I could
Speaker 4:  tune them. And then I'd look at the cost. And when
Speaker 4:  Gemini released theirs and lowered their costs, I said, okay, we're getting
Speaker 4:  closer. You know, as soon as, you know, OpenAI had their
Speaker 4:  models dropping in prices, I said, okay, I think it's time. So about a month
Speaker 4:  ago, I went and built the app and I just
Speaker 4:  told myself, look, this is like the last attempt that I'm gonna do at building
Speaker 4:  this app.
Speaker 4:  Like I've, I've done this too many times, I'm just gonna go with it.
Speaker 4:  So,
Speaker 2:  Okay, and now here we are.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And here we are and I launched it and, you know, and of course that's
Speaker 4:  the one time that you don't, you know, you don't think it's gonna go a certain
Speaker 4:  way is when it does. And I mean, it's great. So
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm so curious why this idea has been so sticky in your head. Like
Speaker 2:  it's, it's clearly been sitting around as a thing you have wanted to build
Speaker 2:  for a very long time. What, what is it about this thing that is so
Speaker 2:  sticky and enticing to you?
Speaker 4:  So social networks are not what they used to be. And I think fundamentally
Speaker 4:  the internet has changed. The internet used to be a tool of communication
Speaker 4:  between people. And frankly, I love that. You know, there's a part of me,
Speaker 4:  So I was born in Miami, but at 16 I flew out to
Speaker 4:  California with my mom because Mark Zuckerberg had emailed me
Speaker 4:  when I was in high school asking if I wanted to meet
Speaker 4:  about like working there and stuff like that. And I
Speaker 4:  remember flying out there with my mom not knowing really anything about Zuckerberg
Speaker 4:  and my mom, you know, not knowing anything about a even, even more
Speaker 4:  and just thinking like, okay, this is such a different world from where I
Speaker 4:  come from, but I'm excited. And I had built apps before social apps
Speaker 4:  and, and So I was quite excited and I spent a lot, lot of time working
Speaker 4:  at Facebook From that point on, I, I didn't go to college. I, I spent four
Speaker 4:  years there helping them build out Instagram stories and a few other features.
Speaker 4:  And it was just such a fun time. You know, it was like 20 13, 20 14,
Speaker 4:  the company was, you know, in a different era. Social media as a whole
Speaker 4:  was in a different era and, and people having a lot of fun. And I, and I
Speaker 4:  think like over the past couple years, I, I think we've just seen like
Speaker 4:  social media's changed and it's changed because the internet's changed and
Speaker 4:  the technology's changed. And so where the internet used to be a
Speaker 4:  place where you could connect between massive amounts of people,
Speaker 4:  the internet as a communication tool in that sense
Speaker 4:  is kind of falling apart, right? Like the, the
Speaker 4:  internet now has technology that allows
Speaker 4:  itself as a dataset to simulate
Speaker 4:  a human connection. You communicate with the internet rather than
Speaker 4:  through the internet. And I think that change that's happened
Speaker 4:  really kind of puts question marks around how social media should work,
Speaker 4:  because the whole premise of social media is that you're using the
Speaker 4:  internet to communicate through it to other people. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Fair. I just wanna say by the way, that idea of communicating
Speaker 2:  with the internet and not through the internet is like as
Speaker 2:  succinctly and well as I have heard anybody put this moment that we're in,
Speaker 2:  I'm going to steal that from you, and that is very good. So thank you for
Speaker 2:  that.
Speaker 4:  No worries.
Speaker 2:  That makes it sound like social
Speaker 2:  AI has always been in your head kind of part
Speaker 2:  product, part social commentary art
Speaker 2:  project. Is that fair?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I always like to poke.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I've always liked to poke. I mean, does it kind of poke fun at the,
Speaker 4:  the facade a lot of companies are trying to put up?
Speaker 4:  Of course it does, right? But I think it's also,
Speaker 4:  weirdly enough my attempt at trying to solve some of these
Speaker 4:  problems, the problems, for example, where you can't discern
Speaker 4:  the difference between a human and an AI on a social platform. So like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  one way is to try and invent a detector for humans, but
Speaker 4:  that hasn't gone very well. I'll say instead, well,
Speaker 4:  how about we just come out with a product
Speaker 4:  that tells people how the internet works now and says, Hey, look,
Speaker 4:  this is the reality kind of sucks in some ways.
Speaker 4:  It's kind of great in others, and we have to,
Speaker 4:  you know, we have to embrace it. Like let's, let's embrace it and, and let's
Speaker 4:  do that so that we don't harm our ourselves, right?
Speaker 4:  Because going on social media sometimes and seeing comments that you
Speaker 4:  think are from people that aren't can be harmful.
Speaker 2:  So I'm curious kind of what it was that clicked in your brain that went
Speaker 2:  from this technology is not ready to, this technology is ready.
Speaker 4:  I think the moment that I, I got in a fight with my boyfriend and I decided
Speaker 4:  to open up my app to see if there were any ideas for how
Speaker 4:  I could resolve the problem
Speaker 4:  that I think was the moment.
Speaker 2:  That's a very good answer.
Speaker 4:  You know, that's, that was the moment, the moment I got in a fight and I
Speaker 4:  decided I'm gonna use a SAP to try and vent about my problem because if I
Speaker 4:  go on actual social media, I'm doing some harm, right? Like, and
Speaker 4:  so, and, and So I think that's just goes to show, like the product I'm building
Speaker 4:  is not to give people an illusion of people, right? I know they're all
Speaker 4:  ai. It's so that I don't go on social media and use it
Speaker 4:  in a harmful way. Like my ideal, my ideal
Speaker 4:  scenario is one where people have people around them
Speaker 4:  to listen, to hear them, and to help them when they need it, right?
Speaker 4:  People to people communication is number one for humans. And
Speaker 4:  I, and I don't think we should forget that, right? But
Speaker 4:  there are a lot of people I've noticed since Covid who don't have those people
Speaker 4:  around them. And so if they don't have those people around them
Speaker 4:  and they need that conversation, what are they doing? Hmm.
Speaker 4:  And if what they're doing is going on public social media and talking about
Speaker 4:  what's going on in their life and getting advice from bots, ai
Speaker 4:  without knowing what they're getting advice from, without any
Speaker 4:  understanding of the dynamics in these algorithms to encourage certain
Speaker 4:  types of content on different spaces, then they're, they're harming themselves.
Speaker 4:  So I said, okay, well, you know, I'm not trying to replace the
Speaker 4:  human to human connection. I'm trying to help people find a way
Speaker 4:  to have a secondary option when that human isn't around for
Speaker 4:  them so that they don't have to rush to social media make a mistake, right?
Speaker 4:  And so when, when I had, when I got in a fight and I didn't
Speaker 4:  go on social media and instead I went on this app, I said, okay, it's ready.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean that, I can imagine that being a very telling
Speaker 2:  moment. But I think that distinction is really interesting.
Speaker 2:  Where, where what you're saying is kind of one is not
Speaker 2:  a replacement for the other, that they're actually, they're designed to be
Speaker 2:  and best as separate things, right? Like I have, I have my
Speaker 2:  AI tools and I have my people, and like, actually the problem
Speaker 2:  is on the platforms that we currently have, those things are being
Speaker 2:  sort of smushed together in a way that makes it hard to tell what is what
Speaker 2:  and makes everything messy and complicated
Speaker 2:  and yes. And that what we actually need is to pull those things apart,
Speaker 2:  not just try and have one or the other, but just separate them.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And and I think the key distinction here is what I, what I mentioned
Speaker 4:  earlier, which is I think there's confusion about what the
Speaker 4:  internet is for people. I think the internet being a place that
Speaker 4:  things can be communicated through is no longer
Speaker 4:  really the case or it's kind of trending away from that. Now it's becoming
Speaker 4:  something you communicate with. And I think more important to me
Speaker 4:  is the fact that the language model technology
Speaker 4:  is not a certainty. Meaning it does
Speaker 4:  not tell you yes or no, it gives you a fuzzy
Speaker 4:  intelligence. And Chachi BT was built
Speaker 4:  as a fuzzy intelligence, right? Like these models were built
Speaker 4:  as fuzzy intelligence. And so what I mean by that is they're kind of like
Speaker 4:  humans. They're not like the computers of the past where they give you a
Speaker 4:  definitive answer for something. And so when I saw that,
Speaker 4:  I asked myself, why does open AI
Speaker 4:  choose a chat interface as
Speaker 4:  the one and only interface for communicating
Speaker 4:  with their language model? Because that chat interface
Speaker 4:  only gives you one answer, and the model
Speaker 4:  does not have one answer, right? And, and so, and So I
Speaker 4:  find it interesting that all of these AI companies are trying
Speaker 4:  to squeeze these fuzzy human-like data
Speaker 4:  structures. They're trying to squeeze them into an old format
Speaker 4:  computer that gives you one answer. And the truth is
Speaker 4:  that they're not that great at it because we still go back to
Speaker 4:  Google because we want multiple answers, we want multiple responses.
Speaker 4:  And so what I've built with social AI is not so much a social
Speaker 4:  network, but a new way to interact with a language model
Speaker 4:  where you don't get one response, but you get multiple. And
Speaker 4:  being able to drill down in a thread like interface in a social
Speaker 4:  interface with the language model, it just feels
Speaker 4:  more natural. When I used the app, for example, I was running
Speaker 4:  late to a flight, I got delayed, my first flight got delayed,
Speaker 4:  my next flight was in 45 minutes, I was in Dallas and I didn't know if
Speaker 4:  I was gonna make it. The flight had just landed. So I opened up social ai,
Speaker 4:  and I just kind of panic ranted about what happened,
Speaker 4:  right? I I didn't have to think about like, oh, I need to
Speaker 4:  instruct it to tell me because I need the right answer. And what if it's
Speaker 4:  not the right answer and maybe I need to go to Google and maybe I need to
Speaker 4:  good red. No, sure, no, no, no. You know, I, i I simply
Speaker 4:  ranted about what happened. I said, my flight got delayed, I just
Speaker 4:  landed, I have 45 minutes to make it to my next flight. I don't know if
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna make it. I'm at Dallas, they're telling me I gotta go to terminal
Speaker 4:  D, I'm in terminal CI, I don't know. And I just posted that and
Speaker 4:  immediately I got dozens of
Speaker 4:  responses and replies on this social interface that gave me all
Speaker 4:  sorts of like, various re replies. Some of them
Speaker 4:  would tell me, you're not gonna make it, you know, go to the front desk,
Speaker 4:  just figure out If, you could get another flight. Another one said, you'll
Speaker 4:  make it If. you run quickly. You just need to look up, see If, you
Speaker 4:  can find the SkyTrain and If. you go down the SkyTrain, you, you'll, you
Speaker 4:  should be able to get there in time. Just make sure you're running quickly
Speaker 4:  though. Another person said, are you in the front or the back of the airplane?
Speaker 4:  Like, you know, like different questions. And so what's interesting is for
Speaker 4:  a human, it's, it's natural to see that I'm gonna go and look through all
Speaker 4:  the responses and dig in on the one that I'm more interested in. So someone
Speaker 4:  kind of gave me a hint about the sky train. I replied and said, okay, I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna try that. How long do you think it'll take me to get there? And then
Speaker 4:  immediately that AI persona replies back and says,
Speaker 4:  you know, If, you go quickly, it'll take you about 10 to 15 minutes to get
Speaker 4:  there, you know, and So I said, okay, cool. Another one replied right
Speaker 4:  underneath and said, wait, wait, wait, hold up. It'll be more like 15 to
Speaker 4:  20. Don't get 'em too excited now. You know? And so like, and
Speaker 4:  so that kind of interaction just feels
Speaker 4:  natural to us.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we will be back with more from my
Speaker 2:  conversation with Michael Saban. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  general sort of personality types. And If, you recommend the app to some
Speaker 2:  friends, you unlock a bunch more options like nerds and oddballs and
Speaker 2:  drama queens and contrarians. And once you do that, you just start
Speaker 2:  posting. I'll type like I am
Speaker 2:  suddenly tired of all the food
Speaker 2:  that I like. Anybody have any
Speaker 2:  ideas about how to spice things up?
Speaker 2:  Literally? And then you press post
Speaker 2:  and a few seconds later responses start appearing. Lemme just
Speaker 2:  read you a few. The first one is from Sunny Ray who is
Speaker 2:  at Sunshine Fellow, presumably an optimist one. It says, try adding
Speaker 2:  some new spices to your meals or explore international cuisines for fresh
Speaker 2:  flavors. Sure, there are a bunch here that say, try new
Speaker 2:  cuisines or flavors. Advice Wizard 2023 literally just says try
Speaker 2:  new cuisines or flavors. I have
Speaker 2:  fanzone hero who says, try some bold spices like zatar or
Speaker 2:  sumac. It's magic. I like that fanatic
Speaker 2:  follower says, whoa, David, that sounds like a challenge. How about some
Speaker 2:  trying some bold, exotic spices, anxious. Nina,
Speaker 2:  presumably an anxious one says, what If, you accidentally make something
Speaker 2:  that sours your taste forever. That's terrifying. Downcast, Greg
Speaker 2:  says, spicing things up. Sounds like a recipe for disappointment. So you
Speaker 2:  get the idea, right? Different bots, different vibes, different kinds of
Speaker 2:  responses. These are all my reply guys now, and I can
Speaker 2:  respond to one and go down a rabbit hole with that particular bot
Speaker 2:  tuned to that particular mood. I can also, favorite bots, I can, favorite
Speaker 2:  replies. And Michael says that all of that goes back into
Speaker 2:  the algorithm and into kind of the instructions being given
Speaker 2:  to chat GBT. Every time I try to use it on the surface, it all feels
Speaker 2:  and sounds like normal human social media,
Speaker 2:  except that they're all bots. But me. And I think I'm not
Speaker 2:  the only one who felt kind of strange about that fact. At first
Speaker 2:  it looks like Twitter and feels like Twitter and it super isn't
Speaker 2:  Twitter. It just felt odd. And honestly, the
Speaker 2:  reaction to social AI was really fascinating. So that is what Michael
Speaker 2:  and I talked about next. I do think the
Speaker 2:  reaction to this app has been in, in many ways just as fascinating
Speaker 2:  as the app itself. Yes, my read of it when it came out was
Speaker 2:  there were basically three responses.
Speaker 2:  One was like, this is cool and interesting
Speaker 2:  and kind of fun, both social commentary
Speaker 2:  and an interesting idea about the future. One was this is
Speaker 2:  stupid and dystopian. And then one was like, this is, this is
Speaker 2:  a joke, right? This has to be a bit and an art project and not a
Speaker 2:  real product. Is that Yes. Is that a fair representation of the reaction?
Speaker 2:  Am I missing anything?
Speaker 4:  I think what's interesting is the loud reactions on social media.
Speaker 4:  There's two things that were interesting to me, or let's say three. First
Speaker 4:  the loudest reactions from people on social media were from those who thought
Speaker 4:  it was either joke or that it was, you know, like dystopian
Speaker 4:  or you know, that they're like, oh my god, the end of the world. Or, you
Speaker 4:  know, like that, that kind of reaction. Those are the loudest, always the
Speaker 4:  quietest. Were actually spending, you know, 10, 10 minutes per session
Speaker 4:  on the app. The second thing I noticed was that
Speaker 4:  the reaction from people was one thing,
Speaker 4:  but there were, there were bots on
Speaker 4:  social media reacting to Yeah, because half
Speaker 4:  of social media has bots now. So like it, I found it
Speaker 4:  quite ironic that there were bots
Speaker 4:  reacting to an app of bots telling humans that
Speaker 4:  an app with bots is like so terrible.
Speaker 4:  You know? And I found it interesting that that was happening.
Speaker 4:  I was like, huh, it seems like some of these bots don't want bots around,
Speaker 4:  or maybe they don't want people to know that they're bots. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  You know? And so like there, there was a portion of bots on social media
Speaker 4:  that were reacting negatively to bots. And I just thought that was ironic.
Speaker 2:  Well, it kind of proves your whole point, right? If it's just a bunch of
Speaker 2:  bots yelling at bots about the social network, that's all bots. That's
Speaker 2:  that. I imagine you're sitting there looking at that being like, exactly.
Speaker 4:  Yes. You know? Yes. I, I think the other, you know, the other
Speaker 4:  issue I think that I found was just how many people don't realize that a
Speaker 4:  lot of these platforms are filled with bots. And that, that kind of was alarming
Speaker 4:  to me. But, but ultimately I think that the last bit here of
Speaker 4:  feedback that I've gotten is people feel a little liberated. You know, they
Speaker 4:  feel a little bit liberated. They don't feel the pressure of going on social
Speaker 4:  media to share some thought that they might feel embarrassed about,
Speaker 4:  but they also feel like they're able to hear other
Speaker 4:  perspectives that they otherwise wouldn't feel comfortable
Speaker 4:  admitting to want to hear. And so they
Speaker 4:  don't let their guard down, you know, in, in, in public conversation, online
Speaker 4:  pe people keep their guard up and, and I think that keeps an
Speaker 4:  echo chamber. It, it's interesting because people said, oh, echo chamber.
Speaker 4:  Oh, echo chamber, the number one, you know, number one, number two, number
Speaker 4:  three, most selected follower type on
Speaker 4:  social AI is contrarians debaters
Speaker 4:  problem solvers, thinkers, critics,
Speaker 4:  right? And so people are selecting followers on social
Speaker 4:  AI that challenge them. And I think there's something interesting about that.
Speaker 4:  Why would someone go outta their way to be challenged on an app like this?
Speaker 4:  Can they not be challenged on real social media? Is there a reason why
Speaker 4:  not? And, and how does this address that? Right?
Speaker 2:  I wonder if that goes back to what you were saying about how
Speaker 2:  it feels when you perceive it to be real people
Speaker 2:  on social media, because I think to some extent that fact
Speaker 2:  doesn't surprise me. Because one thing you hear from
Speaker 2:  people who use AI a lot is that it is especially useful if what you
Speaker 2:  really want to do is beat up an idea and brainstorm and get new
Speaker 2:  perspectives on things. And I think to some extent
Speaker 2:  what you've built is just a like endless feedback mechanism
Speaker 2:  That's right. With no stakes because no one else sees what's happening.
Speaker 2:  No one else is human on there. So even the
Speaker 2:  part of it that feels sort of real, it feels like there's still something
Speaker 2:  in your brain that is like, this is a safe
Speaker 2:  space. Yes. And I can see a, a world in which, I mean, and I've even found
Speaker 2:  this in using it, there is something very powerful in the interface is the
Speaker 2:  same, but the stakes are so much lower.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And, and, and I think it helps put people's guards down. I think it
Speaker 4:  helps people, like you said, people have been using chat GPT for a lot of
Speaker 4:  this, but how many times have people gone on chat GPT and said, Hey,
Speaker 4:  can you help me think through this? And it gives you one answer and you're
Speaker 4:  like, Hmm, I don't know about that. And then you go, well, what other ideas
Speaker 4:  do you have? And then it goes and gives you something else. And then you're
Speaker 4:  like, well, what else? You know? And, and it gives you something else that's
Speaker 4:  kind of similar, but you're like, I don't know. And then you keep going,
Speaker 4:  well, what else? And by the time you keep asking what else, I forgot the
Speaker 4:  context of the thing you were talking about in the beginning and just start
Speaker 4:  saying random stuff. And so like, the interface just feels
Speaker 4:  wrong for the use case, but, but look, I don't blame OpenAI.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't think that it's like, oh, they just weren't capable. Like
Speaker 4:  who the hell was gonna know? Right? I, if anything, I think they
Speaker 4:  built out a chat interface because it just felt like the obvious testing
Speaker 4:  ground to, to prove a product and it became a product
Speaker 4:  that they didn't think was gonna resonate as quickly. So, you know, of course
Speaker 4:  we started at chat because of that, and I don't think that it's bad. I
Speaker 4:  just think we haven't seen the best of it yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, I think, I think that's totally fair. So speaking of that, actually
Speaker 2:  the, the edges of this technology,
Speaker 2:  I'm very curious about. And I, I suspect you've seen a lot of it as people
Speaker 2:  are starting to really use and try new stuff
Speaker 2:  with social ai, obviously this stuff's gotten a lot better
Speaker 2:  to the point where I think it, it feels the way you wanted it to.
Speaker 2:  Where is it broken? What still doesn't work?
Speaker 4:  So there's a few things that still need to be improved. So we just,
Speaker 4:  you know, we, by we, I mean me, I just launched notifications on social ai.
Speaker 4:  So one of the things that was interesting was, you know, I could play around
Speaker 4:  with it, but I wasn't getting any feedback later
Speaker 4:  about what I posted. And I think that's, you know, quite important.
Speaker 4:  Another aspect of it is proactive. So like
Speaker 4:  right now, if I post, I get content, I originally built
Speaker 4:  a feed into it.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna ask you whether you were gonna build a feed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well I did, but I took it out just for the launch. And
Speaker 4:  just because I, I wanted to make sure that, you know, I didn't have anything
Speaker 4:  too buggy in there, but it's kind of interesting because I'm not trying to
Speaker 4:  simulate a world where these things have their own lives and telling you
Speaker 4:  other lives. No, no, no, no, no. Like that's not the purpose. We're trying
Speaker 4:  to be honest about what this is. It's right in the middle, you know, we're
Speaker 4:  not character AI and we're not Twitter. We're like in the middle,
Speaker 4:  right? And so the, the feed, what it does
Speaker 4:  is every persona, every character that you interact with as you give it likes
Speaker 4:  and replies and stuff, it kind of shapes these
Speaker 4:  personas and understands which ones you interact with the most. And each
Speaker 4:  of those personas have their unique, like weights
Speaker 4:  towards different topics of interests and personalities and the
Speaker 4:  way in which it tries to answer questions. And, and all of that shapes the
Speaker 4:  diversity of responses that you get for anything you ask. And what they also
Speaker 4:  have is a set of like
Speaker 4:  interests that they use to then search the internet for the latest news
Speaker 4:  and the latest things going on. And so each of them has their own
Speaker 4:  kind of like, interests on the web that it goes and searches
Speaker 4:  for. So when you go on the newsfeed on social AI and you pull
Speaker 4:  the refresh, there's always more content, first of all. But
Speaker 4:  every piece of content is like this. AI having gone
Speaker 4:  through, looked at the internet, found something interesting that it liked
Speaker 4:  and it giving a little commentary on it with a link to access it, which I
Speaker 4:  thought was, you know, is, is pretty cool.
Speaker 2:  Does that not break the whole structure of it being kind of a you
Speaker 2:  centric experience?
Speaker 4:  No, because the, all of the bots are there talking about things
Speaker 4:  that you're interested in. The only ones that show up on your feed are the
Speaker 4:  bots that you've interacted with that you're interested in or adjacent.
Speaker 4:  Right? And you select in your feed what kind of stuff you want and what you
Speaker 4:  don't. And they're there to inform you, right? They're there to give
Speaker 4:  you what, what you wanna hear. You know, it's interesting, I also built a,
Speaker 4:  a trending topics page and the trending topics are not
Speaker 4:  trending topics of the news. They're
Speaker 4:  trending topics of you. So as you post and you interact with things,
Speaker 4:  there's trending topics. It's like these are the top of mind things for you.
Speaker 4:  Interesting. And you can tap on any of those topics and see hundreds of ais
Speaker 4:  debating and discussing it.
Speaker 2:  Wow. That's kind of, that's kind of wild actually. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  Is there
Speaker 2:  A, how, how are you thinking about, or I guess what are you seeing
Speaker 2:  in terms of how people are using it? Because that idea of like, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  use this as a sort of proactive, you're almost
Speaker 2:  describing like a personalized news app or feed reader
Speaker 2:  or whatever, right? That instead of having my Facebook feed
Speaker 2:  curated by my Facebook friends, it's gonna be curated by
Speaker 2:  ai. I think we're we're gonna see a lot of that, right?
Speaker 4:  That's right. That's right. But fundamentally, it's a new
Speaker 4:  way to interact with language models. It's building a new interface
Speaker 4:  for interacting with them. And all of the applications that allow
Speaker 4:  people to get more value out of the language model through those
Speaker 4:  interactions go into that. Right? And social ai at, at its
Speaker 4:  premises is not social for the sake of the social network,
Speaker 4:  but social for the sake of social interface, right? Hmm. And
Speaker 4:  so that's really what it is.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we'll be back with the rest
Speaker 2:  of my conversation with Michael Sayman. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  We are back. Let's get to the end of my conversation with Michael Sayman.
Speaker 2:  At one point in our conversation, I asked him about one thing that I always
Speaker 2:  do
Speaker 2:  comes up a lot, interstellar comes up a lot. The spot apparently really loves
Speaker 2:  Christopher Nolan movies. There's one from Anxious
Speaker 2:  Ali 77 that just says, what if there's a terrible plot twist with
Speaker 2:  the thinky emoji? It's good stuff. More Interstellar
Speaker 2:  cynic Genina says, well, since you're asking for cinematic advice, how about
Speaker 2:  watching something truly enlightening like a documentary on existential dread
Speaker 2:  or maybe a thriller that reminds you how not all choices lead to happiness.
Speaker 2:  The options are as bright as the dark abyss of reality. So once again,
Speaker 2:  it's all over the place. This is how this system is designed to work. Right?
Speaker 2:  And I can go into one that has a recommendation that I like. There's one
Speaker 2:  here that recommends eternal sunshine in the spotlight Mind. Great movie.
Speaker 2:  I can reply to that and say, oh, love that. Saw it recently. What else do
Speaker 2:  you recommend? That's the idea about how all of this is supposed to work.
Speaker 2:  But frankly, I'm looking at these replies and it's mostly just people
Speaker 2:  saying, did you pick a movie yet? How did it go? Did you find a
Speaker 2:  movie that speaks to you yet? Did you choose a movie? Why that one? Did you
Speaker 2:  narrow it down? Did you settle on a movie choice? Like,
Speaker 2:  is that helpful? I don't really think so. So I told Michael that
Speaker 2:  this didn't feel like it had been tuned to be
Speaker 2:  particularly good or helpful or designed to actually give me
Speaker 2:  information in the way that he's been talking about. And he said,
Speaker 2:  well, yeah, he agreed with that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And, and the reason is because it's an alpha that I built myself in
Speaker 4:  four weeks, right? So we can't expect, you know, like Right.
Speaker 2:  Well this is kind of what I'm wondering is like what, what do you, what do
Speaker 2:  you hope for? What, what should that do?
Speaker 4:  Yes. So of course, you know, of course it shouldn't work that way. I think,
Speaker 4:  you know, the, the intention here and, and of course it, it's on its way
Speaker 4:  and I think it's quite surprising that it, it even, you know, works at all.
Speaker 4:  But I think it is a testament to the interface that it does. But I would
Speaker 4:  say that, you know, the ultimate vision here is to
Speaker 4:  make that question better answered
Speaker 4:  in social AI than in chat GPT. And, and I think the
Speaker 4:  interface will allow it If, you have comparable models
Speaker 4:  on both platforms and one of them gives you multiple responses from different
Speaker 4:  points of view. And the other one just gives you one answer.
Speaker 4:  And you're working with a technology that's probabilistic, like who has
Speaker 4:  the upper hand? You know, like I can give 10 answers and if
Speaker 4:  one of them is good, you're happy. But if chat GBT gives you one answer
Speaker 4:  and it's not right, you're frustrated.
Speaker 2:  That makes me think of the thing people always say about the TikTok algorithm,
Speaker 2:  which is that the reason it feels like magic is because you don't get annoyed
Speaker 2:  when it's wrong. Yes. Because you just keep swiping. That's right. And I
Speaker 2:  think social has, like you're saying, very much the same thing. The signal
Speaker 2:  to noise ratio is actually like horrendous on social media,
Speaker 2:  but we're also sort of used to it now. That's right. And If, you just
Speaker 2:  scroll past it and move on. and we all kind of understand how to find needles
Speaker 2:  in haystacks in a way that when Chad GPT recommends a movie, I don't wanna
Speaker 2:  watch it feels bad because it gave me an answer.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. And it's part of the reason why people still go to Google, right?
Speaker 4:  Because Google doesn't have any more accurate stuff these days, you know,
Speaker 4:  you know, compared to what it was because of all the AI that's in there too.
Speaker 4:  So, you know, it's not like Google is any more accurate, but
Speaker 4:  it's interesting because Google gives you this chat, GBT, the
Speaker 4:  answer at the top, right? Yeah. And then you have like all of these
Speaker 4:  various links that give you different perspectives and you know, let's, you
Speaker 4:  know, let's be honest, like most of these links are now run with like so
Speaker 4:  many paywalls and things that like, you can't even get to the answer for
Speaker 4:  any of these things. But the original intent behind Google and why it
Speaker 4:  worked was it gave you options to look through.
Speaker 4:  And so it allowed it to be wrong and it increased its
Speaker 4:  chance of being right at least once or twice. And
Speaker 4:  we're used to using the internet this way. We go through the internet looking
Speaker 4:  for information, trying to find which thing is helpful to us,
Speaker 4:  right? And, and So, I just, I think it's interesting that maybe we
Speaker 4:  got a little distracted by the her movie a little too much.
Speaker 2:  Just a little,
Speaker 4:  Just a little, you know, and we, we kinda leaned in a little harder than
Speaker 4:  we were supposed to. But you know, that that's kind of where
Speaker 4:  I see, I see it being more valuable is can we give
Speaker 4:  people the option to peek behind the curtain of this
Speaker 4:  AI and see what are the various answers
Speaker 4:  it can think of rather than, here's my one
Speaker 4:  response and, and ultimately I think this is gonna be how it works. If, you
Speaker 4:  have multiple language models, If, you have Claude Open AI
Speaker 4:  llama and so on. Are you gonna go from one to the other and be like, which
Speaker 4:  one gave me the best answer? Or are you gonna use an interface
Speaker 4:  that's gonna pull from all of them, generate a bunch of different
Speaker 4:  responses and curate those responses based on the re reactions and
Speaker 4:  responses that you've done in the past and full control for
Speaker 4:  the user to get as many responses as they can. You want
Speaker 4:  to index the language model, you wanna create a Google
Speaker 4:  for the language model outputs. And that's kind of what this is.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I, I, I agree. That's super interesting. So tell me about the roadmap
Speaker 2:  a little bit. Yeah. You know, you mentioned this is an alpha you built in
Speaker 2:  a few weeks. It is becoming increasingly clear to me that you have
Speaker 2:  much bigger visions for where you're headed. Tell me a little bit about
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 4:  My vision is to build out the whole funnel of interaction
Speaker 4:  with the language models from the top of the stack all the way down.
Speaker 2:  So people are gonna start yelling at you to build dms and you're gonna build
Speaker 2:  dms and you're, yeah, you're just gonna speed run all the pain of developing
Speaker 2:  a social network. I
Speaker 4:  Love it. All of it all the way down. They're
Speaker 2:  Gonna be like, when do I get lists? And you're gonna have to do lists. And
Speaker 2:  then they're gonna be like, when do we get bookmarks? But you
Speaker 4:  Know, it'll be interesting. The conversation will go down the funnel naturally.
Speaker 4:  I expect the first thing people want, which they already say is they want
Speaker 4:  dms, right? So, okay, you, you introduce dms, right? And it makes sense as
Speaker 4:  you interact with the models and you are more interested in one over another.
Speaker 4:  You wanna talk a little more deeply with that one Cool dms. So
Speaker 2:  Wait, hang on just to, let me, lemme just press on the idea there. 'cause
Speaker 2:  I think that's another,
Speaker 2:  how do you do that without just becoming the chat GPT chat bot again?
Speaker 4:  Well, because what I'm building includes chat
Speaker 4:  GPT within, but I'm building at a level
Speaker 4:  one level up of communication stack, which is how do you
Speaker 4:  discover who you wanna talk to, right? It's like asking Google, well
Speaker 4:  are you're providing all these links to the websites? Why aren't you
Speaker 4:  just another one of those links? It's like, well, because we're providing
Speaker 4:  an index that lets people figure out which one they wanna go into, right?
Speaker 4:  And so social AI provides that layer that helps people discover who they
Speaker 4:  wanna talk to. The end goal is not to talk
Speaker 4:  to an individual ai, the end goal is the whole
Speaker 4:  picture. It's the experience of being
Speaker 4:  able to go up in breadth like a Twitter interface, dive down to
Speaker 4:  a FaceTime call with an AI model, go up to an audio call with another,
Speaker 4:  go up to a chat, go back up to the surface, go back down, go back up
Speaker 4:  that experience, the entire funnel that people go through to find information
Speaker 4:  and communicate online. That whole thing needs to happen, right? And
Speaker 4:  so the vision is we start at the top and work our way down, and
Speaker 4:  then we offer users the ability to go through all of it.
Speaker 2:  Okay? So the idea is then by the time you're at that one-on-one
Speaker 2:  conversation, you've essentially filtered your way down such
Speaker 2:  that you're talking to, instead of going through like the GPT store or picking
Speaker 2:  plugins or whatever. Yeah. Yeah. I've now SocialAI found the
Speaker 2:  conversation I want to have with the right source. And even if now
Speaker 2:  all I'm doing is essentially having a chat bot conversation with a chat bot
Speaker 4:  That's right.
Speaker 2:  It, it's, I've now I've filtered it in the way that is useful.
Speaker 4:  Yes. I think in the future people are gonna ask, they're gonna look at the,
Speaker 4:  the first versions of chat GPT and they're gonna see when chat GPT announced
Speaker 4:  features like customize your GPT and tell it what, how you
Speaker 4:  wanted to talk to you. And they're gonna think, right? I can't believe we
Speaker 4:  had to tell it, you know, like,
Speaker 4:  I can't believe we had to tell it. You know, like what, you know, it doesn't
Speaker 4:  make sense, you know, it doesn't make sense to have to do that. I think that's
Speaker 4:  my bet. I don't, I might be wrong. Look, I don't think the product hit the
Speaker 4:  nail on the head. I think we're, we're definitely not on the, on the center.
Speaker 4:  We're, we're a little bit off. And, and I, I have no doubt in my
Speaker 4:  mind that there's a lot of work that needs to be done to get it in the right
Speaker 4:  place. It's, it's an alpha, right? But I think that's the general
Speaker 4:  direction. And my bet is, you know, telling Chad
Speaker 4:  GBT before you talk to it, everything you wanna, you know, do and how you
Speaker 4:  wanna talk to it in this particular case and why and whatever just feels
Speaker 4:  like we're missing a step, you know?
Speaker 2:  Hmm. Yeah. I buy that as it happens. I, I think Chad
Speaker 2:  GT's whole custom instructions thing is just as ridiculous as you do. So
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm very much with you on that one. What have you seen
Speaker 2:  so far in terms of how people are using it? Are, are people doing
Speaker 2:  surprising things with it that have sort of changed your mind about what
Speaker 2:  this thing is or can be? You
Speaker 4:  Know, people are favoring a lot of users, which I think
Speaker 4:  is interesting. So you can favorite like any particular follower and then
Speaker 4:  that pins their replies to the top. I I think that's kind of
Speaker 4:  interesting.
Speaker 2:  Well, that seems like it sort of supports your thesis that, that what people
Speaker 2:  want is to find their kind of chosen favorites
Speaker 2:  in here. Right? And it's, it's also interesting that you didn't call it follow,
Speaker 2:  which is a departure from social networks, but also makes more
Speaker 2:  sense in the kind of scheme you're talking about
Speaker 4:  In the context. Yes. I, I check out some of these apps and like, what I've
Speaker 4:  seen is it's like they'll grab the social network, they'll grab the AI
Speaker 4:  and they'll just mash 'em and just, okay, let's see how
Speaker 4:  it goes. Right? It it, you know, like, and, and in this
Speaker 4:  case, I, it's hard, it's much harder to try and like
Speaker 4:  get this right and I don't think I've got it right. I think I'm closer, but,
Speaker 4:  but I don't think I've got it right. But I don't want, what I don't want
Speaker 4:  to do is just mash them together without consideration.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. And so, you know, I didn't say, oh, you can follow a particular
Speaker 4:  AI because in this case you could just favorite it and to your point, right,
Speaker 4:  like it's more in line with what the product is. For
Speaker 4:  example, the app opens up to the composer, it does not open up to your
Speaker 4:  profile. It opens up to the composer now. So you go into it and
Speaker 4:  it's kind of more like trash PT in that sense. The bots don't tell you
Speaker 4:  that they're human, right? They tell you that they're ai, they're there to
Speaker 4:  help you. That model of like design is
Speaker 4:  me kind of saying, I'm gonna pick and choose what I think is
Speaker 4:  useful from a social networks interface and I'm gonna integrate it, but I'm
Speaker 4:  not going to like forget that this is not that.
Speaker 4:  Right. And it, because if I forget that this is not that,
Speaker 4:  then it kind of feels gimmicky, you know? Like it, it kind of feels
Speaker 4:  like it's, it's like, okay, like we get, you know, like, and, and I don't
Speaker 4:  wanna build a gimmicky product that, you know, so, and that's
Speaker 4:  something I've learned too, is like I went full on with the skew
Speaker 4:  morphism, right? I went full on trying to build the product that
Speaker 4:  made people most familiar with it. And as I've been
Speaker 4:  iterating, I've scaled back a lot of the skew morphic design
Speaker 4:  that really, you know, kind of leaned into the social stuff because I realized,
Speaker 4:  you know, okay, users don't need to like see the home feed in the way
Speaker 4:  that they do on Twitter because it, it, it's not that necessary, you know,
Speaker 4:  let's lean into the utility a little more. And I've tweaked it a bit
Speaker 4:  to make it a lot more of the function and leave the,
Speaker 4:  you know, the skew morem of the interface to just the pieces
Speaker 4:  that are required to make it easy to interact with.
Speaker 4:  And so that, that I think will continue, I think the product
Speaker 4:  will continue to distance itself from the
Speaker 4:  skew morphic design that it starts with and turn
Speaker 4:  into its own interface.
Speaker 2:  Do you have a, do you have a clear sense of what that might look like over
Speaker 2:  time?
Speaker 4:  If I, if I told you I did, I would be incredibly
Speaker 4:  delusional. I, I think more so than I am.
Speaker 4:  I, I know I'm, you know, I've got my delusions for sure, but, but you know,
Speaker 4:  more so than that, I would be at a ridiculous level of delusion. I don't
Speaker 4:  know what it's going to end up looking like. I don't know what that final
Speaker 4:  form is, but I have a mission invi in mind,
Speaker 4:  right? And I, and I, and I'm determined and excited about it.
Speaker 4:  And my hope is that as we get
Speaker 4:  more information and data around like how people are using it,
Speaker 4:  that we're able to further go that direction. And, and in my view, I don't
Speaker 4:  think we should, there, there should not be a limit to what
Speaker 4:  angle we approach if the users and the people
Speaker 4:  are asking for that, you know, interaction. There's a lot of people,
Speaker 4:  and I, I think a lot of product companies out there when when they launched
Speaker 4:  something, the thing that they started with that got them
Speaker 4:  the attention they believe is like sacred, right? And
Speaker 4:  so you'll see like reel launches and it's like, oh, our, our feature is
Speaker 4:  the feature Snapchat launches. And they're like, oh, our, you know, our,
Speaker 4:  our ephemeral snapchat is like the feature, right? And,
Speaker 4:  and then it's like, okay, but you can expand and do this and do that and
Speaker 4:  it'd be cool If, you had this. And they're like, no, because this is our
Speaker 4:  feature, you know, and it's like, okay, cool feature. But
Speaker 4:  like a lot of times, and this is something I learned when I used to work
Speaker 4:  at at Facebook, it's like a lot of times the thing, the product
Speaker 4:  or feature that gets you from stage one to stage two
Speaker 4:  is not going to be the same method approach or product feature
Speaker 4:  that's going to help you get from stage two to stage three. And you have
Speaker 4:  to be comfortable with your product evolving over time. And so, so for me
Speaker 4:  it's maximum flexibility on that front. I, I, I want to help
Speaker 4:  solve these problems for people. I don't care what it looks like.
Speaker 2:  Is there a business here, the, the, I feel like
Speaker 2:  you've gone from like social commentary, fun
Speaker 2:  experiment to like kind of hit
Speaker 2:  app to
Speaker 2:  at some point somebody is going to want to give you a bunch of money to make
Speaker 2:  like a social AI for teams and sell it to IT departments.
Speaker 2:  Do you have a sense of what the business looks like here? How are you gonna
Speaker 2:  make money?
Speaker 4:  People have already asked Yes. You, you see that's you,
Speaker 4:  you're, you're right to predict that, you know, people asking that.
Speaker 2:  It's just what happens. They're like, how, who, how do we sell this to IBM?
Speaker 2:  And you're like, okay, take it
Speaker 4:  Easy, easy everybody,
Speaker 4:  you know, look, I, I'm not interested in, in thinking about,
Speaker 4:  you know, how to monetize the product right now. I, I think I'm sure there
Speaker 4:  are ways to like help people find, you know, the right
Speaker 4:  shampoo bottle for them or whatever, but like that's,
Speaker 4:  I'm not, like, that's not my primary thing right now. I, I'm trying to solve
Speaker 4:  a problem I've dealt with in my life, right? Where I've sometimes felt,
Speaker 4:  you know, especially during covid, like it was really hard
Speaker 4:  to get my thoughts out and to
Speaker 4:  be able to just think through things a little bit
Speaker 4:  without, you know, jumping to conclusions. And,
Speaker 4:  and I struggled with that, you know, and I, I, I wanted to solve
Speaker 4:  that for me. I wanted to solve that for my friends. I, you know, I, I wanted
Speaker 4:  to build something that could help. And that's
Speaker 4:  the thing that keeps me going. That's the thing that makes me excited. And
Speaker 4:  the rest of it, you know, we'll figure it out. But my
Speaker 4:  hope is that I'm able to help a little bit, you know, other people out there
Speaker 4:  like me who maybe need a little space to
Speaker 4:  think about things and don't wanna rush to social media
Speaker 4:  and post all their thoughts.
Speaker 2:  I don't have a great read on what success looks like for this. Because it's
Speaker 2:  like what you're saying is sort of, if I, if I post less
Speaker 2:  dumb stuff on, on Twitter because
Speaker 2:  I'm posting dumb stuff on social AI instead, that's a certain kind of victory
Speaker 2:  I think for you and for the world. But also
Speaker 2:  you're in a position where what you're saying is like, you need, people
Speaker 2:  need a place to put this stuff and to talk about this stuff and to get
Speaker 2:  feedback on this stuff and actually doing it in a safer place.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like ultimately we want, we wanna talk to people, right? Like, that's
Speaker 4:  our goal, but If, you don't have someone around. Right. I think it's certainly
Speaker 4:  better than going on social media, right? Like that's kind of how I, how
Speaker 4:  I see that. And, and actually to your point that you made earlier, a lot
Speaker 4:  of people have been saying that they think Elon
Speaker 4:  Musk should use social AI before he starts tweeting random stuff,
Speaker 4:  you know, and just a ab test for his own thoughts so that he could stop saying
Speaker 4:  things that like piss people off. I thought that was an
Speaker 4:  interesting point.
Speaker 2:  What's the wildest thing you've seen somebody do in social ai? What is like
Speaker 2:  a either in, in the logs or screenshots or, so what is the one thing
Speaker 2:  that you've seen that you were like, never in a million years? What I've
Speaker 2:  guessed.
Speaker 4:  Okay, so maybe this isn't too wild, but, okay, so my, my mom works at a furniture
Speaker 4:  store in Miami and she, she's from Peru,
Speaker 4:  speaks mostly Spanish and yeah, she never uses my apps, right? Because like,
Speaker 4:  you know, she's nice, supports it, but like she knows that like, you know,
Speaker 4:  whatever. I, I keep trying and they're all, you know, not that great. So
Speaker 4:  I, I was surprised when she messaged me out of random. Okay. And she
Speaker 4:  sends me a screenshot of my app 'cause it works in all these languages. She
Speaker 4:  sends me a screenshot of the app and she starts using it and ranting in Spanish
Speaker 4:  about, like, about work. Wow. She's like ranting about
Speaker 4:  work, you know, on this app. And it's so funny
Speaker 4:  to me. Like I,
Speaker 4:  I was like, okay, well, you know what, like maybe product
Speaker 4:  market fit. I don't know. But you know,
Speaker 4:  I, you know, I, I love her and, and I think it's, I think it's sweet
Speaker 4:  to see that there's, you know, that there's a peel in, in unique
Speaker 4:  ways. I gotta, you know, if I ever go work at some company, maybe I'll start
Speaker 4:  using this rent, you know,
Speaker 2:  And no one will know. And that's the beauty
Speaker 4:  Of it. And there you go.
Speaker 2:  Awesome. All right, well, I should leave you alone, but thank you so much
Speaker 2:  for doing this. This is really fun.
Speaker 4:  No, thank you so much.
Speaker 2:  All right. That is it for the first cast today. Thank you to Michael Sayman
Speaker 2:  again for being here. And thank you as always for listening. There's lots
Speaker 2:  more on everything we talked about, including some of our social AI coverage
Speaker 2:  and just all of our AI coverage in general. There's a ton happening.
Speaker 2:  Check it all out at The Verge dot com. I'll put some links in the show notes.
Speaker 2:  But as always, read the website, it's a good website. And as always, If,
Speaker 2:  you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other AI bots that I should be
Speaker 2:  hanging out with. You can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com
Speaker 2:  or call the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one one. we love hearing from you.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Liam James, will Poor and Eric Gomez. Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex
Speaker 2:  and I will be back on Tuesday and Friday with all of your regularly scheduled
Speaker 2:  programming. We have a bunch of fun stuff coming up. We'll see you then.
Speaker 2:  Rock and roll.