# Transcript
ID: 104a71c6-1815-482a-9b4d-ae00be00bf5e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/285115196806288049/-7351152687757378521/s93290-US-5407s-1704469650.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz kick off the new year with a preview of what we're excited to see at CES 2024 next week, but not before a brief discussion on copyright, the open web, and the first movements of a battle between The New York Times and OpenAI.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of Quantum Technology.
Speaker 4:  Ooh,
Speaker 3:  You ready? It's, we're like leading up into the CES hype. We gotta
Speaker 3:  start making up buzzwords left and right, the AI
Speaker 3:  powered podcast of Quantum Dots. Now with more ai,
Speaker 3:  please stop us. Best Buy.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend, NELI. I'm, it's been a, it's been a a minute. We, the last
Speaker 3:  time we spoke to you was last year. Welcome back. It's good. See you again.
Speaker 3:  Alex Transit is here.
Speaker 4:  I am here in my mom's house. That's why I have a creepy
Speaker 4:  background.
Speaker 3:  You do have a real mom's house vibe? Yes. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Flowers. Graduation photo of someone guitar
Speaker 4:  from my brother's like guitar years. You
Speaker 3:  Got the little posable figurine guy.
Speaker 4:  Dunno what that's about, but I got it.
Speaker 3:  The dress making, I believe
Speaker 4:  That's how they do it.
Speaker 3:  David. Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  What is the age at which you get to have like a chair that is your
Speaker 5:  chair? I'd like to be that person. Like Alex. You're in a
Speaker 5:  chair that like be like is a person's chair. Yeah. This is, you know what
Speaker 5:  I mean? Yeah. I think's like that's not your chair. That's someone's chair.
Speaker 5:  And I would like a chair. That is mine.
Speaker 3:  You're in your own home. At any moment you can acquire a chair.
Speaker 5:  I know, but it's like, it just feels wrong. Like if I went and tried to buy
Speaker 5:  a Lazboy right now, they'd be like, get outta here. You're not ready. You
Speaker 5:  haven't earned this yet.
Speaker 4:  That's what you know when your wife is like, it's okay. Get the Lazboy. You'd
Speaker 4:  be like, I hit it. I'm at that age.
Speaker 3:  If that happened, I'd be like, this relationship is like she's, there's someone
Speaker 3:  else. That's how I would know if she was like, I've given up on you. You
Speaker 3:  may have a lazy boy. I, I would know some other information
Speaker 3:  that I, I wouldn't once to know. Anyway, there's a lot of news. It's been
Speaker 3:  a, it's a very slow period of sort of iterative
Speaker 3:  things, but some things happened before the break that we should talk about.
Speaker 3:  And then we are headed into CES and the trickle of CES
Speaker 3:  News is, you can see that we're gonna have a
Speaker 3:  pretty noisy CES in Vegas. There might not be a lot of
Speaker 3:  stuff, but there's gonna be a lot of news, if that makes any sense.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like the trends are converging on CES for just
Speaker 3:  for example, I I think we're gonna hear a lot about Windows laptops with
Speaker 3:  various AI features in them. Yeah. Based on the fact that Microsoft just
Speaker 3:  announced an AI button on Windows keyboards is coming.
Speaker 4:  Oh it's, it's here. We we're gonna talk about that when I talk about the
Speaker 4:  Dell XPS laptops co button.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's gonna be a very CES e CES. I think like I think
Speaker 5:  we've, we've spent the last don don't know decade watching it become
Speaker 5:  kind of less and less CES e in the sense
Speaker 5:  that it either was teeny tiny upgrades to mostly
Speaker 5:  mature products or like weird wacky
Speaker 5:  nonsense from Europe that no one was ever gonna buy, but seemed potentially
Speaker 5:  interesting. And now we're back in a place where there's like
Speaker 5:  new kinds of gadgets, new ideas about gadgets, new stuff. And
Speaker 5:  there's like somewhere in there is stuff people are actually gonna
Speaker 5:  buy. Yeah. And it feels like CES has not been about things that people might
Speaker 5:  actually buy in a while. And I'm kind of excited about it
Speaker 3:  All, right. I'm gonna make myself sound like an ancient wizard. Is it like,
Speaker 3:  like a man with a chair basically?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  I started writing about gadgets before, before the iPhone existed.
Speaker 5:  Like 1958.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just went to Neli Ageing. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I started writing about those big mechanical typewriters, you know. No, but
Speaker 3:  you know, sort of like 2006, 2007 there were smartphones but we parked them
Speaker 3:  on End Gadget Mobile because our gadget audience on End
Speaker 3:  Gadget was like, what are these weird European smartphones? Get them out
Speaker 3:  of our face.
Speaker 5:  They were like, netbooks are nothing
Speaker 3:  This, that's where we were. Yeah. And so CES every year was
Speaker 3:  basically how gadget stores would get
Speaker 3:  stocked like this. This is where the buyers from Best Buy would like
Speaker 3:  go and like figure out what would be in their store for the next year. And
Speaker 3:  they were just full of gadgets like AV
Speaker 3:  receivers and weird TV I, lots and lots of weird TV
Speaker 3:  ideas. An infinite amount of weird TV ideas.
Speaker 3:  And then all that stuff converged into phones. And even TVs became
Speaker 3:  basically Android tablets that you hang on the wall. Like if you think about
Speaker 3:  a modern television, they've got an arm processor, they're running some
Speaker 3:  Linux variant very often. Android sometimes ties in like
Speaker 3:  they're just big tablets. You hang on the wall. So all the stuff converged
Speaker 3:  into computers and CS got boring because almost
Speaker 3:  every product involved you having to believe that Panasonic
Speaker 3:  was good at making software.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's like don, don't dunno about that.
Speaker 4:  So what a Panasonic believe that
Speaker 3:  Many of these companies fully believed it or they, or like remember there
Speaker 3:  was a year that like Sam, the big announcement CSS was that Samsung bought
Speaker 3:  smart things and they're gonna like take over home automation. And it's like,
Speaker 3:  oh, we all really believe, oops. Like I don Dunno if you've
Speaker 3:  used smart things lately.
Speaker 3:  I have it on my frame tv. It's a weird, weird product all the way around.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, the point of this is we're just back at a place where there's
Speaker 3:  a little bit of what you might call it de convergence happening. And
Speaker 3:  I say this every year about css 'cause they're always catch. But you can
Speaker 3:  just see that there's interest in things outside of the phone. And AI
Speaker 3:  is like the thing that is not totally
Speaker 3:  dependent on Apple letting it exist. So it's just like happening in more
Speaker 3:  and more places. And I think that's just like fundamentally interesting.
Speaker 3:  but it, and but for the most part CSS is like where sales
Speaker 3:  people go to do sales stuff. Yeah. And where tech
Speaker 3:  reporters go to be like, what's happening here? Yeah. And it's like maybe
Speaker 3:  this year after several pandemic years and with the emergence of ai,
Speaker 3:  maybe this year the balance will shift a little bit back towards interesting
Speaker 3:  things. We, we, we will have to see. It's
Speaker 5:  At least weird stuff from companies with
Speaker 5:  resources to make that weird stuff and sell it to you. Right. I feel
Speaker 5:  like Samsung for so long has just
Speaker 5:  made slightly better versions of all of its stuff and then been like, look
Speaker 5:  at this refrigerator. Yeah. That's where our innovation lies. And
Speaker 5:  now we're coming back to, and I think this is a trend of this whole year
Speaker 5:  and it, I mean it goes to your point about the co-pilot button on Windows
Speaker 5:  computers. Like we are coming back to these incredibly mature devices
Speaker 5:  that I think are gonna start to change faster and in bigger ways than they
Speaker 5:  have in a while, largely because of ai. But everybody is kind of like
Speaker 5:  ground up re-imagining all of their devices, including the ones
Speaker 5:  that haven't been touched in a while for this next phase. It's gonna get
Speaker 5:  weird and a lot of it's gonna get much worse. But just from a pure, like
Speaker 5:  I like covering gadgets perspective. It's gonna be so fun.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm, I'm, I haven't gone in years. I'm excited to go and
Speaker 3:  have a conversation about something other than whether a huge
Speaker 3:  dependency on the smartphone will kill whatever product I'm looking at.
Speaker 5:  Totally.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which is basically what we've been doing for years. Yeah. Before we
Speaker 3:  get into that, which we will get into, we should talk about the big news
Speaker 3:  that happened while we were on break that is deeply related to whether
Speaker 3:  the AI industry can continue the way it is currently going.
Speaker 3:  The New York Times has sued OpenAI for copyright
Speaker 3:  infringement. They are far from the first to
Speaker 3:  Sue OpenAI for copyright infringement. Sarah Silverman, other famous authors
Speaker 3:  have sued OpenAI. George R. Martin in a different case has sued
Speaker 3:  OpenAI. But in classic times fashion, now that
Speaker 3:  they have sued OpenAI, they're covering it as though this is
Speaker 3:  the watershed moment as though this is the one that's stopping our brain.
Speaker 3:  They're like the, a pivotal moment for AI has arrived now that we have
Speaker 3:  sued, have sued OpenAI. You can, you can
Speaker 3:  believe about that. What you will. I think it's, it's
Speaker 5:  In reality. Aren't all of these cases destined to kind of merge together
Speaker 5:  into one the people versus AI kind of case?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So they, I think it's the Sarah Silverman case filed in the same
Speaker 3:  court. They've assigned the Times case to the same judge because they've
Speaker 3:  been deemed related. A lot of the fundamental legal questions are
Speaker 3:  just the same here. So I, you should go read the Times' complaint.
Speaker 3:  It is well written. Very often we point this out, but a lot of
Speaker 3:  these filings are written for the public to read.
Speaker 3:  And their relationship to the actual questions that are determined in the
Speaker 3:  court are potentially quite fuzzy. Like this,
Speaker 3:  this thing is a, is a, a piece of marketing. Yeah. And like that's what a
Speaker 3:  good complaint is supposed to be. But that means also it is very readable.
Speaker 3:  It is not like a technical document or a technical legal argument. It's just
Speaker 3:  a list of problems. For example, you can just ask cha a
Speaker 3:  BT to tell you to recite a Times article at you
Speaker 3:  and it will just do it. Which implies a number of things.
Speaker 3:  First. That OpenAI has a database of New York Times
Speaker 3:  articles that it is made, which you need permission to
Speaker 3:  make. Like that. That's just a very straightforward, did you have permission
Speaker 3:  to make all of these copies of Times articles?
Speaker 5:  Okay. But wait, can we, can we pause on that immediately? Yeah. Because that
Speaker 5:  is like the, the thing you have beaten into my head over the many years that
Speaker 5:  I've known you Eli, is copyright laws about copies. Right. Like fundamentally
Speaker 5:  it is about things that
Speaker 3:  One believes me get copy. But you do. I do. I'm very happy that you,
Speaker 5:  I've learned this. I've known you a long time and I have finally learned
Speaker 5:  this and a lot of the talking that I've seen about
Speaker 5:  this case, which like fundamentally the Times makes a lot of allegations
Speaker 5:  and we should talk about them. 'cause I think they're really interesting
Speaker 5:  in ways that some of the other cases have not been as
Speaker 5:  straightforward about that thing you're describing where like you can tell
Speaker 5:  that chat GPT knows New York Times articles because it will tell you about
Speaker 5:  them. But I think what I have not figured out and what
Speaker 5:  everybody has been sort of talking in circles about in this
Speaker 5:  is, is this actually a copyright thing at all? Like
Speaker 5:  is it against the law for OpenAI and Chat GPT
Speaker 5:  to know the contents of a New York Times article? I've read a
Speaker 5:  New York Times article. If I tell you about a New York Times article, is
Speaker 5:  that copyright infringement? Is that even remotely the same thing? Like,
Speaker 5:  just like first principles? Yeah. Can you just make sense of this for me?
Speaker 5:  'cause I feel like I've read every direction of this and I have no idea where
Speaker 5:  to land.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So the most important first principle is that no one knows how fair
Speaker 3:  use cases will get decided. Perfect. Ever. Like first
Speaker 5:  Principle is blurred lines.
Speaker 3:  Anyone making that argument to you is definitely
Speaker 3:  doing it for money. Sure. You know what I mean? Like they're all coin flips.
Speaker 3:  David mentioned blurred lines. I will just say this again. I'm at the point
Speaker 3:  where I'm a soundboard about fair use cases and blurred lines. Like
Speaker 3:  I, I gave this argument on CNBC and the anchors looked at me like they didn't
Speaker 3:  know what blurred line was. And I was like, Emily Rakowski. And they're like,
Speaker 3:  oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  So Blurred lines, the Robin Thick song with Pharrell Williams, Marvin Gay's
Speaker 3:  Estate is like, Hey, that sounds like a Marvin Gaye song. And they sued Marvin
Speaker 3:  Gaye's estate preemptively Oh, the way around to get a court. No. That way
Speaker 3:  they pre preemptively sued Marvin Gaye to get a court to say, no,
Speaker 3:  this isn't copyright infringement. Because they hadn't used a note. They
Speaker 3:  hadn't used a chord, they just used like a vibe.
Speaker 3:  I did a, a decoder episode with Charlie Harding about this that we can link
Speaker 3:  to. It's just a vibe. Like he's a musicologist. He's like, this is just a
Speaker 3:  vibe. And they lost the jury was like,
Speaker 3:  no, like you Robin Thick are kind of like an
Speaker 3:  unsympathetic defending, like this song's kinda weird.
Speaker 3:  There's like whatever. For whatever reason they lost, they paid the money
Speaker 3:  years later just recently, Marvin Gaye's Estate Emboldened by
Speaker 3:  this Sues Ed Sheeran 'cause Shape of You
Speaker 3:  has the chords of a Marvin Gaye song in it that so much so that
Speaker 3:  he like plays them all together in concert. Like he like transitions from
Speaker 3:  one song. And Ed Sheeran vastly more
Speaker 3:  sympathetic defendant,
Speaker 3:  old floppy hair is like Anna, you need colds. You know, like,
Speaker 3:  and he wins
Speaker 3:  just objectively, he has used more of the Marvin Gay song or
Speaker 3:  what you might consider as the Marvin and he wins. That is a total coin flip
Speaker 3:  just dead ahead coin flip. You do not know, and you
Speaker 3:  shouldn't have that permissioning based on whether you think Robin thick
Speaker 3:  is more or less sympathetic than Ed. She like that's a bad place
Speaker 3:  Yes. To live. So
Speaker 5:  The only approach here, like total nihilism, nobody knows anything. Nothing
Speaker 5:  matters that,
Speaker 3:  That's what I'm saying right now. Like I, people have asked me, what do you
Speaker 3:  think will happen? Like what do you think should happen? And I just keep
Speaker 3:  reminding everyone that fair use law is literal coin
Speaker 3:  flips every time they are legally supposed to be coin
Speaker 3:  flips. They're all supposed to be evaluated on case by case basis. So that
Speaker 3:  one thing is not supposed to be precedent for the next thing. So even if
Speaker 3:  you think, okay, Robin Thick won or lost,
Speaker 3:  that doesn't give Ed Sheeran a rule to follow, which is how he ended up back
Speaker 3:  in court and then he won. And now no one has a rule like you
Speaker 3:  just move on to the next song and try again. Right. So this is a really weird
Speaker 3:  murky area of the law. So that's like just the first, when you talk about
Speaker 3:  first principles, the only, like the thing that I will just put in everyone's
Speaker 3:  brain is that no one knows what's gonna happen. The first
Speaker 5:  Principle is that there are no
Speaker 3:  Principles. It's in fair use law. There is just chaos. Like
Speaker 3:  it is, it is supposed to be chaos because times
Speaker 3:  change. Our attitudes about remixing and copying change,
Speaker 3:  the specifics of each use and reuse are totally different.
Speaker 3:  And the law is sort of designed to make you fight it out like
Speaker 3:  that. It's very much where, where they want it to be. I mean, artistically
Speaker 3:  that sounds right. Whether that's what it should be is like a different question.
Speaker 3:  Especially at internet scale. Like again, this law is written
Speaker 3:  in 1976. Many things have happened
Speaker 3:  between smartphones for example, just recently
Speaker 3:  the internet not contemplated. So like there's, there's
Speaker 3:  just something that's disconnected there. But more specifically to your point
Speaker 3:  David, now that I've answered your question with everything is chaos.
Speaker 3:  The first thing you look at is like, did you make a copy? Even if you wanna
Speaker 3:  make a fair use argument, A fair use argument is what they call an
Speaker 3:  affirmative defense. So it is, but you're like, you
Speaker 3:  did copyright infringement and you're like, yes I did do it,
Speaker 3:  but let me tell you it's fine and here's why it's fine.
Speaker 3:  And you have to, you have to accept that you've made some
Speaker 3:  copies without permission. Right. That you didn't have a license to copy
Speaker 3:  the entire database of New York Times article or scrape the entire website.
Speaker 3:  You didn't get permission, you don't have a license, but your use of it in
Speaker 3:  the end was fair for X, Y, Z reasons. And there's all these reasons you can
Speaker 3:  go into, to
Speaker 5:  Even make a fair use case. I have to forfeit my copyright infringement
Speaker 5:  case because what I then have to say is, yes, I took it, but I'm
Speaker 5:  doing something transformative or you know,
Speaker 5:  useful or whatever with it such that it's okay. But I have to, I have to
Speaker 5:  say at the beginning, yes I did make a copy in order to be able to do that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You just have to, you have, you just have to give that up. Okay. And
Speaker 3:  that is complicated in a lot of cases for a lot of reasons. It is less complicated
Speaker 3:  in the case of computers because
Speaker 3:  anything a computer does is a copy. Like merely taking a text
Speaker 3:  file out of memory and putting it on a display involves making
Speaker 3:  several copies along the way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's a copy of the New York Times article that I'm reading right
Speaker 5:  now, somewhere in a cache on my computer
Speaker 3:  And it hundreds of different cash points across the internet. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  to enable to load fast. And all of those I will remind everyone over and
Speaker 3:  over again, all of those were litigated. The thing I'm saying about loading
Speaker 3:  bits from memory, from one place on the computer to another straight up that
Speaker 3:  was litigated. You can go read MAI versus peak systems a case that may
Speaker 3:  be like spitting mad in law school because it's so stupid.
Speaker 3:  Where one company sued another company that was installing its software without
Speaker 3:  permission and said the co the illegal copy here is when
Speaker 3:  your people copy our bits from a disc to memory
Speaker 3:  to load it onto a computer. And they, they won like they, that was copyright.
Speaker 3:  The court was like, yep, that's a copy. And the law was rewritten to protect
Speaker 3:  what are called ephemeral copies that let like the internet work
Speaker 3:  because it is obviously a bad policy outcome to say copying things from disc
Speaker 3:  to memory is actionable copyright infringement. That's just using a computer.
Speaker 3:  So here we have this like total unknown. Can you take, make a
Speaker 3:  database of the internet and then do stuff with it such
Speaker 3:  that you can spit back out the internet. don
Speaker 3:  don't know. I I think probably there should be
Speaker 3:  some payments in the mix there, right? That, that, that seems
Speaker 3:  like the thing that should happen here, right? Is like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  like OpenAI has a gigantic valuation. They need
Speaker 3:  this data to train their systems. If you need the data to make your valuation
Speaker 3:  exist, you probably have to trade some of your valuation back to the
Speaker 3:  people that made the data in the first place. Like Right. That's just abstract.
Speaker 3:  That's not me carrying much journalism or whatever. That's just like, if
Speaker 3:  that is the raw material of your business, you should probably pay for the
Speaker 3:  raw material of your business. Well
Speaker 4:  And they, they've made deals too, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They made a big deal with Axel Springer, which publishes Business Insider.
Speaker 3:  I think that's, it's not a very lucrative deal. It it's quoted at like
Speaker 3:  $10 million over a number of years. Oof. Which
Speaker 3:  is right. Yeah. Yeah. $10 million is divid 10 divided by
Speaker 3:  any number over one, over a number of years is like you're making a couple
Speaker 3:  million dollars a year. Right? Yeah. Like that's what that sounds like. So
Speaker 3:  like the deals are not very lucrative, but I think all, a lot of
Speaker 3:  companies rather get paid than spend 10 years in court. And I think the
Speaker 3:  time is like, no, we're gonna spend 10 years in court. I think Sarah Silverman
Speaker 3:  is like, we'll spend 10, she'll spend 10 years in court. George, RR Martin,
Speaker 3:  that dude, he's gotta finish the book. Like he's happy to litigate this through
Speaker 3:  before
Speaker 5:  He's not gonna do it. Doesn't have to now. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So like, I, I just think like this case is a big deal and the Times is gonna
Speaker 3:  fight it pretty vociferously.
Speaker 3:  But the argument here from all the companies, from Google, from OpenAI, from
Speaker 3:  whoever, is this is fair use. We're gonna make the copies, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  do stuff to the copies and that is fine because
Speaker 3:  we're, you know, we're, we're creating a new product based on those copies,
Speaker 3:  which is basically what sample or like sampling and music is
Speaker 3:  supposed to do. even that, that is all licensed now. Like you get to a place
Speaker 3:  where you make the argument about everything being a remix long enough and
Speaker 3:  then you run out of original work to remix 'cause you've destroyed the market
Speaker 3:  for it and then you start paying for it. So like the music industry
Speaker 3:  by and large has sorted this out, right? There's just a lot of payments
Speaker 3:  going on for publishing, for interpolation, for rewriting, for sample
Speaker 3:  clearance in a way that in the eighties when all this happened,
Speaker 3:  like, you know, the Beastie Boys never cleared a single sample.
Speaker 3:  Like they just didn't do it. And they, there's so many in that record that
Speaker 3:  that, you know, the argument is you can't now no major label
Speaker 3:  runs that way anymore. Like they've built a market for remixing work
Speaker 3:  and you have to expect that OpenAI and the others will have to create a market
Speaker 3:  for remixing the data that they're ingesting.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I do think a, a huge amount of that market you're talking about
Speaker 5:  comes from nobody wanting to go to court. And I think in
Speaker 5:  this case, what you have, like you said, is a couple of parties that are
Speaker 5:  really, really psyched about going to court and, and actually
Speaker 5:  hashing this out no matter how it goes. It's gonna be really interesting.
Speaker 5:  But I think this is one of those things that strikes me as two
Speaker 5:  separate issues. And I feel like we've talked about this a bunch with these
Speaker 5:  companies recently. There is the kind of what feels right as a person in
Speaker 5:  the world case, and then there's the like is this,
Speaker 5:  does this match to what we understand to be our laws in the country? Right?
Speaker 5:  Because the thing you're describing about the times and paying for the raw
Speaker 5:  materials of your stuff, there are debates about this, right? All the AI
Speaker 5:  companies say these things won't exist if we have to pay the billions of
Speaker 5:  dollars of money required to get the data to make them. Which I find deeply
Speaker 5:  hilarious because that just means you acknowledge that it's worth money and
Speaker 5:  you're just stealing it for free. But leaving that aside, the idea
Speaker 5:  that the Times and whoever else has stuff that's going
Speaker 5:  into the training data for chat GPT and all these other things that
Speaker 5:  those parties should be compensated seems obvious. Right? Like I, I don't
Speaker 5:  think you can make a super compelling case that says OpenAI and
Speaker 5:  Google and everybody else should just have free access to the entire internet
Speaker 5:  forever to do with whatever they want, including compete with
Speaker 5:  all of those publications.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean, take your hypothetical from earlier
Speaker 3:  and just remove AI from the equation and just sort of
Speaker 3:  run them as they were normal products. You David Pierce have
Speaker 3:  memorized the entire New York Times and for, and you've not compensated them
Speaker 3:  for it. Right. And for a small fee, you'll just tell anyone what's in the
Speaker 3:  times today. Right. That's copyright infringement direct,
Speaker 3:  like directly there. There's no getting around it. Right.
Speaker 5:  It's also impressive.
Speaker 3:  It's it, but, and, and the reason that we don't like sit around
Speaker 3:  worrying about it is because you can't do that. Right? Right. Like, human
Speaker 3:  memory is so fallible. President Barack
Speaker 3:  Obama under decoder said the, the genius thing about the human memory is
Speaker 3:  that it changes everything all the time. This is like, this was his argument
Speaker 3:  when he was talking about copyright law and ai. He's like, your memories
Speaker 3:  change things Andis don't, and So I think, and his argument was like, human
Speaker 3:  creativity will be forever unsurpassed. Which, you know,
Speaker 5:  Thanks.
Speaker 3:  He's a, he's, he's famously a very hopeful man.
Speaker 5:  But like Mike Masnick at Tech Dart wrote a smart piece about this after the,
Speaker 5:  the lawsuit came out. And one of the things that he said was that if the
Speaker 5:  Times wins, it opens up the times to a lot of issues because the
Speaker 5:  Times is famous for basically taking and building
Speaker 5:  on work done by other reporters elsewhere without giving them credit. And
Speaker 5:  people at, you know, smaller blogs and sites have been yelling at the times
Speaker 5:  about this for forever. And anyone who aggregates anything on the
Speaker 5:  internet could suddenly be open to these same things because just by
Speaker 5:  taking something and knowing it and doing something with it, you open yourself
Speaker 5:  up to copyright infringement. And that's like, that strikes me as like a,
Speaker 5:  a ways down that road. But I think is is not a totally impossible outcome.
Speaker 5:  But again, all of this is like, I think there, there is a case to
Speaker 5:  be made pretty simply that it just feels right that
Speaker 5:  everyone who is helping make this thing for these enormously profitable companies
Speaker 5:  should be compensated in some way. Right.
Speaker 3:  Well, so two things. One, open eyes isn't profitable
Speaker 3:  yet just burning money, but they are collecting a ton of investment dollars.
Speaker 3:  Sure. So like that's interesting. Yeah. But the product itself is not yet
Speaker 3:  profitable.
Speaker 5:  Microsoft is pretty profitable.
Speaker 3:  M Microsoft is pretty profitable Google. Right. But like these products right
Speaker 3:  now represent sort of rising costs and not falling costs.
Speaker 5:  That's fair. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. Like every hit on a one, whatever tensor unit or
Speaker 3:  GPU that they're using to run these things, it costs more money than an average
Speaker 3:  Google search or whatever. Yeah. So there, there's some like interesting
Speaker 3:  economics that it, they're not quite as profitable as everyone wants them
Speaker 3:  to be. Sure. But everyone can see the future in which they're extraordinarily.
Speaker 5:  But also does that matter, like in, in copyright infringement, does, does
Speaker 5:  your company valuation make a difference?
Speaker 3:  No, I, but I think that's the moral case. It doesn't make a difference. Copyright
Speaker 3:  infringement. Copyright infringement. This notion that there's some sort
Speaker 3:  of big taking happening economically, I think
Speaker 3:  provides ammunition to the moral argument that you're making, which is like,
Speaker 3:  you should, you should get compensated for this use. You just,
Speaker 3:  there's gotta be money at the other end of the line. Right. And like that
Speaker 3:  is sort of as yet unproven. I think everyone believes that there will be
Speaker 3:  a lot of money at the end of the line. I believe there will be a lot of money
Speaker 3:  at the end of the line and you should sort out the economics early. That
Speaker 3:  all makes sense. But the money isn't actually at the end. We're not actually
Speaker 3:  at the end of the line. So that's just one, one thing I like.
Speaker 5:  But I I will say just one other thought to that and then you should keep
Speaker 5:  going. Yeah. Is that like
Speaker 5:  there's a weird thing in this where kind of everybody loses, right? Because
Speaker 5:  if OpenAI is, is taking the New York
Speaker 5:  Times information to make a thing that loses tons of money, but
Speaker 5:  in so doing is taking readership away from the New York Times because it
Speaker 5:  can answer some of the questions people might have otherwise gone to the
Speaker 5:  New York Times for and even tell you about New York Times articles, the
Speaker 5:  New York Times also loses. So you're, you're stealing my money in order to
Speaker 5:  not have any money. Right. Which is kind of a wild current version of affairs.
Speaker 3:  I agree. And th and there's a weird zero sum notion
Speaker 3:  to the value of information embedded in there. Sure. That is hard to
Speaker 3:  unpack. Like it costs the New York Times a lot of
Speaker 3:  money to generate the reporting. It costs us a lot of money to generate the
Speaker 3:  reporting and then everyone sort of believes that it should be
Speaker 3:  free. I don don't know, like yeah, I know how much it costs to employ
Speaker 3:  our
Speaker 3:  staff. We we should make more money than it costs to run our business.
Speaker 3:  That that argument plays in every part of the
Speaker 3:  world except journalism on the
Speaker 3:  internet. Like that's very weird. And like you can see, you know, the reaction
Speaker 3:  to that across the sort of media landscape is more paywalls are going up.
Speaker 3:  Like people are trying to value the information at what they think the market
Speaker 3:  should value it at. And that is working and not working in different ways.
Speaker 3:  The other thing I wanna say is I love Mike Masek. I think he's very smart.
Speaker 3:  I protect her at all the time. People should protect her. This is the place
Speaker 3:  where I I I tend to disagree with Mike and I am a
Speaker 3:  copyright minimalist. I would say. Like I worry about the
Speaker 3:  expansion of copyright law all the time. That's how I started my career as
Speaker 3:  a lawyer. That's like what I've written about a long time. But I, I think
Speaker 3:  sometimes Mike just devalues everything to zero too quickly and
Speaker 3:  embedded in the argument that he makes in that piece. Which again, you should
Speaker 3:  go read, I love tech, you should read tech art all the time.
Speaker 3:  Is the notion that the time work is not valuable. That
Speaker 3:  the times insisting that its work has value unto itself
Speaker 3:  somehow is hypocritical. Because then everyone else can
Speaker 3:  insist that their work also has value, which will destroy the New York Times.
Speaker 3:  There's, there's something in there that I, I think on the internet we're
Speaker 3:  getting to a place where more and more people are insisting that their
Speaker 3:  digital work has value unto itself. Not just
Speaker 3:  as a, a rapper around some advertising or like
Speaker 3:  a rapper around some like influencer merch hustle or like
Speaker 3:  whatever. And that's like, that's just new. The joke I keep making with Addie
Speaker 3:  Robertson, our policy editor, is that we came up in a time when
Speaker 3:  the dominant like vibe on the internet was everything is a remix.
Speaker 3:  And now every the vibe on the internet is, fuck you pay me. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  that's good. Right? I like that. Yeah. Like that's a big shift. It's a big
Speaker 3:  culture shift. Like it's hard for me to wrap my head around it 'cause I am
Speaker 3:  very much of the, everything is a remix school, but you just, you
Speaker 3:  you, it there has to be like, some money has to flow
Speaker 3:  to original creators and it, it isn't happening at scale on
Speaker 3:  any of the social platforms. Like every influencer
Speaker 3:  is pivoting into selling you goods. Like whether it's water
Speaker 3:  bottles or shoes or Mr. Mobile just launched a, a
Speaker 3:  keyboard case. The iPhone today. Like it's fine. Like that's what the,
Speaker 3:  all their businesses are going there because there isn't enough value in
Speaker 3:  the content itself on the platforms. I mean that's why they're boxing. Like
Speaker 3:  literally there are fighting every YouTubers are becoming professional boxers
Speaker 3:  because that's how you, you can now buy a bottle of prime that is just Logan
Speaker 3:  Paul's blood. Ugh.
Speaker 3:  That's not true. Okay. I I will be remiss if I
Speaker 3:  don't do this. It will take a little longer, but it's the actual legal
Speaker 3:  nerd thing that we should do to talk about fair use. And there's one
Speaker 3:  point in here that I, I want to make before we, we break and talk about css.
Speaker 3:  So the fair use analysis, which I have pointed out is always chaos,
Speaker 3:  always a coin flip. But there is a legal analysis, like you can go
Speaker 3:  read the statute. There are four factors to consider an nefarious analysis.
Speaker 3:  So just think about OpenAI in a times in this way. So the four
Speaker 3:  factors the judge is supposed to consider the purpose and character of your
Speaker 3:  use. What are you using it for? The nature of the copyrighted
Speaker 3:  work, the amount and substantiality of the proportion
Speaker 3:  taken, how much of the work you're using and the effect
Speaker 3:  of the use upon the potential market for the original work. So
Speaker 3:  if I take your thing and I make something based on it and then I destroy
Speaker 3:  the market for your thing, I've lost, it's not fair. Right. That's an
Speaker 3:  unfair use of the work. So this is, I think
Speaker 3:  this is why it's always a coin flip because in every single case these four
Speaker 3:  factors are weighted differently. Sometimes judges wake up and they have
Speaker 3:  different ideas about what the market for art looks like in Amer. Like this
Speaker 3:  is why it's a coin flip because these factors are different every time and
Speaker 3:  different people evaluate them. But the one I would point to
Speaker 3:  here for the times that they, I would guess that they lean on the most
Speaker 3:  is the fourth factor. Yep. The effect of the use upon the market for the
Speaker 3:  original work. Because it is sort of undeniable that the purpose of open
Speaker 3:  AI's use is to do the things the times does.
Speaker 3:  Right. You ask it questions, it delivers you answers that potentially were
Speaker 3:  first generated by the New York Times. The nature of the work is it's
Speaker 3:  attack the amount and substantiality of proportion take. Well it's all of
Speaker 3:  it. Yeah. There's, that's it's all of it. So what's what's
Speaker 3:  the one with the wiggle room in it? Yeah. It's the effect of the
Speaker 3:  use on the potential market. And if the times can prove that
Speaker 3:  OpenAI is replacing the market for the New York Times by
Speaker 3:  copying the New York Times. If I had to make one prediction, I would say
Speaker 3:  it's this fourth factor, the market factor that is the most heavily
Speaker 3:  weighted and the one that gets discussed the most. Well,
Speaker 5:  And there's, there's a bunch of that in the complaint even, right? Like the,
Speaker 5:  the time talks a bunch about trademark dilution and the idea that
Speaker 5:  the, the chat GPT hallucinating
Speaker 5:  New York Times articles and attributing
Speaker 5:  product recommendations to the Wirecutter that didn't come from Wirecutter.
Speaker 5:  That that kind of thing is actually bad for the New York Times as a
Speaker 5:  competitor in the market of good and valuable information. And again, like
Speaker 5:  you said, this thing where you can just basically have it read you paragraph
Speaker 5:  by paragraph a New York Times article, like it's, it's already
Speaker 5:  seeming to push past this idea that it's illegal to have a database full
Speaker 5:  of our things. I think it would like to make that case, but it seems to have
Speaker 5:  quickly jumped past that too. By doing this, you're making the times look
Speaker 5:  worse and trying to steal our business. And I think at least of the cases
Speaker 5:  that I've seen, that is the step beyond a lot of the
Speaker 5:  other stuff that I've seen. Not just, it's illegal for chat GBT to have trained
Speaker 5:  on this data, but it is actually turning it back around in ways that harm
Speaker 5:  us. So I, I think you're right. And I think the Times is, is gonna push that
Speaker 5:  pretty hard. I mean an amazing amount of this complaint is just
Speaker 5:  like examples of conversations with chat GPT about New York Times
Speaker 5:  articles, which again, to your point about these things being marketing is,
Speaker 5:  is not accidental.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This thing is made to make the argument for us
Speaker 3:  to read to you on this podcast for news anchors to read. You know, like
Speaker 3:  that's what complaints are for. Eventually they're gonna have to make more
Speaker 3:  pleadings and actually have a trial. And the thing that is crazy about all
Speaker 3:  this is if the time settles with OpenAI,
Speaker 3:  it doesn't mean anything for the next case to come along because the, the,
Speaker 3:  there's no fair use precedent here. So I, I think some of these cases
Speaker 3:  will like run to ground. But what you don't have
Speaker 3:  is a music industry that is invested in its own
Speaker 3:  survival as the music industry to develop a whole bunch of deal structures
Speaker 3:  around sampling and interpolation, which they have done. Like it has taken
Speaker 3:  them several decades to do. But there's a whole business model
Speaker 3:  for like publishing rights and sampling in the music industry because it's
Speaker 3:  a closed ecosystem. You're like, I'm gonna take some music and make some
Speaker 3:  more music based off of it. I'll give you this example. Major record labels
Speaker 3:  have songwriter workshops where they get a bunch of songwriters, they take
Speaker 3:  their own catalog of old hits and say write new songs based on these hits
Speaker 3:  because they know that's the safest way to, to sample their own work
Speaker 3:  and they can trade on some nostalgia. That is a totally wild a like if you
Speaker 3:  said this would be happening in the eighties at the dawn of hip hop, like
Speaker 3:  people think you were crazy, but they've built an, they've
Speaker 3:  built a legal and financial ecosystem around this
Speaker 3:  copyright problem of sampling that is actually now generated. Here's how
Speaker 3:  songs are written. There's none of that on the internet. Like there's, there's
Speaker 3:  no closed ecosystem of news providers and tech platforms and YouTube
Speaker 3:  creators. It's all gonna get together in a room and be like, how are we gonna
Speaker 3:  do this? There's just chaos.
Speaker 5:  So hypothetically if say the CEO of
Speaker 5:  Amazon were to buy one of America's
Speaker 5:  largest national newspapers,
Speaker 5:  would that, would that you know, close the ecosystem a little bit and maybe
Speaker 5:  another one like bought Time magazine,
Speaker 5:  like hypothetically if these tech companies started to buy these media
Speaker 5:  organizations like May maybe, maybe we'd start to see something like that.
Speaker 3:  So that would be hilarious if like all the
Speaker 3:  entire Salesforce UI was based on the Taylor Swift article and the time
Speaker 3:  magazine. It was just like, she's great I don Dunno what you're asking about.
Speaker 3:  I can't increase your sales, but she's amazing. That's actually what
Speaker 3:  Salesforce is. AI should be, just talk to your clients about Taylor Swift
Speaker 3:  number of times. Taylor Swift was mentioned on this call,
Speaker 3:  but the Amazon examples better. So Jeff Bezos owns the Washington
Speaker 3:  Post and he obviously has a huge controlling stake in Amazon. If you get
Speaker 3:  to the place where the purpose of the Washington Post is not to make money
Speaker 3:  as the Washington Post, but it's to serve as a cost center for
Speaker 3:  training Amazon's ai. That's a weird reason to do journalism. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And like you can, you can like skip to that ending pretty fast in a lot of
Speaker 3:  these cases
Speaker 3:  like faster than you think. The purpose of X,
Speaker 3:  you can argue is to serve as training data for grok.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Now
Speaker 3:  That's the argument Elon Musk is making. Like, is that
Speaker 3:  what we want? Is that, is that the right incentive to, to make
Speaker 3:  content so that we can mush it all together and spit it out as
Speaker 3:  AI somewhere else? Like I don't I don know the answer to that question. That
Speaker 3:  does not a appeal to me. I don Dunno if it appeals to you,
Speaker 3:  but that's, you can quickly get to the end result where even if the AI companies
Speaker 3:  are paying millions of dollars in fees to journalism companies or media
Speaker 3:  companies or YouTube creators or whatever because there's more margin on
Speaker 3:  the other end of owning the AI tool. Well then
Speaker 3:  a bunch of YouTube creators are basically working for the AI tool.
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 3:  That that's, we that's weird.
Speaker 4:  That supposes that the AI tool will like actually make that kind
Speaker 4:  of money.
Speaker 3:  Right. Which is what I said, like I don't Yeah, we're not at that place yet
Speaker 3:  actually. So you you it's, I I find it tempting to skip to the end of like,
Speaker 3:  what does YouTube look like in the world where Barred can summarize a YouTube
Speaker 3:  video and it's like none of that is good right now. Like, it's
Speaker 3:  like, I mean just that's a problem. Google wishes it had no, but
Speaker 4:  To some extent it's already doing that. Right? Because so many YouTube videos
Speaker 4:  are now made to the algorithm, right? Yeah. Like they're already many made
Speaker 4:  to
Speaker 3:  Many TikTok videos are made to an AI algorithm. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So it's just like, okay, that, that homogenization that we see on YouTube
Speaker 4:  just gets like accelerated.
Speaker 3:  I cannot wait for the New York Times to adopt the Mr. Beast style. Yes.
Speaker 3:  For all journalism. Oh my god. This is how we're, I was wondering how we're
Speaker 3:  gonna cover the election and it's just straight rips of Mr. Beast
Speaker 3:  videos about tech policy. Oh
Speaker 5:  Man. Every, every picture on the homepage of the New York Times is just
Speaker 5:  the reporter with their mouth open making a face.
Speaker 4:  No, it's closed now, right? It's closed now.
Speaker 5:  Oh you're right. It's, yeah, it's, your mouth is closed and there's something
Speaker 5:  gold and a bunch of money behind you
Speaker 3:  And it's just New York Times
Speaker 3:  reporter. Look, it would, it would certainly be interesting. That's all I'm
Speaker 3:  saying. All right? We gotta take a break. I'm, I talked about copyright law
Speaker 3:  for two. This is my my fault. We're gonna watch the chart in Apple podcast
Speaker 3:  be like you know I did it
Speaker 3:  again. All right. We're gonna take a break, we're gonna come back, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna talk about some css. We'll grab back
Speaker 7:  Investments offered through Robinhood Financial LLC
Speaker 7:  investing is risky.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we're back. That's all the copyright law talk. Will there be a little
Speaker 3:  more copyright
Speaker 5:  Law? I was gonna say you've made that promise before.
Speaker 4:  Don't don't believe them guys.
Speaker 3:  It's my favorite. It's the only law that works on the internet telling you
Speaker 3:  this is true. It's also the law that might break Google in the end,
Speaker 3:  which is fascinating to think about. Okay, that's enough. That's enough.
Speaker 3:  We should talk about cs. CS is coming in a week. We're going, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  be there. Yes. I would say there's, there's a bunch of stuff
Speaker 3:  here that has been announced pre css.
Speaker 3:  I always wonder if they announced the best stuff early to get the early wave
Speaker 3:  of hype or this is just the, hey
Speaker 3:  pay attention to us. The real stuff is coming.
Speaker 4:  I think it's like both I think, I think it depends on the company. Some
Speaker 4:  companies are like I wanna get my cool stuff out early. But most companies
Speaker 4:  are like, I wanna get some fun stuff out, tease
Speaker 4:  you and then do the really cool stuff later.
Speaker 3:  Yeah and nothing will have a price or a ship date. Yeah, all of it will
Speaker 3:  be like the weirdest render you've ever seen and then you can come see it
Speaker 3:  in person or a
Speaker 4:  Booth or it'll be a sticker
Speaker 5:  Or it is the thing you are most likely to buy but is kind of the
Speaker 5:  least interesting, right? Like the, if you're gonna release a spec
Speaker 5:  update to your already existing laptop, do it before CES because
Speaker 5:  by the time we get there nobody caress. 'cause everybody is like drowning
Speaker 5:  in weird flying iPhone cases. But
Speaker 5:  if you have something that is like here is an actual product that actual
Speaker 5:  people will probably buy, this is when some of this stuff comes out. That's
Speaker 5:  why we're seeing a lot of like monitor upgrades and
Speaker 5:  you know, spec bumps to laptops and things like that. And then I think you
Speaker 5:  get to CES and that's when they're like, have you seen these speakers? They're
Speaker 5:  62 feet tall and they cost $5 million
Speaker 3:  CES and they're just me standing in front of me like exactly. This is why
Speaker 3:  I do what I do. I'm home again All.
Speaker 3:  right. So I'm just gonna read a few of them that I think are incredible.
Speaker 3:  LG released what like a speaker system. I don know how what, how to
Speaker 3:  describe this thing. It's a speaker with vacuum tubes in it and it transparent
Speaker 3:  ed display on the front of it that displays the name of the song in like
Speaker 3:  old time font. Yeah. I want this thing so badly. It's sick.
Speaker 3:  It's so stupid. It is so dumb. but it ISS
Speaker 3:  so cool. It
Speaker 4:  Just is like a Kickstarter that somehow LG made
Speaker 4:  real
Speaker 3:  That's exactly right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like a 2014 Kickstarter and they're like no we're just gonna sell this thing
Speaker 4:  and put LG sample
Speaker 3:  On it. It's so cool. Like ridiculously cool. Big
Speaker 3:  vacuum tubes. Little vacuum tubes. Old
Speaker 3:  timey fonts. I'm not even sure if it's recasting the name
Speaker 3:  of the song into the old timey font or if they just found
Speaker 3:  a song whose album cover is in an old timey font. Do you know what I mean?
Speaker 3:  Like don don't know what's going on here. Exactly. I just know that this
Speaker 3:  picture of this, it's a black and white picture of a guy leaning back in
Speaker 3:  a chair but then the speaker system is in color but then it's
Speaker 3:  actually not in color. It's just the orange of the vacuum tubes is the color.
Speaker 4:  It's GI ceia.
Speaker 3:  It's per it's perfect. It's so good. It's a very CSS product. I'm very
Speaker 3:  excited about it. I'm gonna go look at it a lot. Then there's been a bunch
Speaker 3:  of display news that I'll just read quickly 'cause it's a bunch of gaming
Speaker 3:  monitors. Samsung now has more ole gaming monitors.
Speaker 3:  Some of them have up to 360 hertz refresh rates,
Speaker 3:  which I believe is many times faster than human perception. But good for
Speaker 3:  Samsung. Hell yeah. And then LG has topped Samsung with a
Speaker 3:  27 inch OLED that has a 480 hertz refresher
Speaker 5:  In your face.
Speaker 3:  Samsung. So we are, we are just doing like watt war
Speaker 3:  horsepower war specs. Is
Speaker 5:  This the new thing? This actually kind of makes sense that if, if we're definitely
Speaker 5:  in a phase where the best way to sell a really fancy monitor
Speaker 5:  is to sell really great gameplay to gamers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that's who buys your fancy monitors. And I think we're
Speaker 5:  just in a place now where we're just gonna be on like a crazy
Speaker 5:  hertz refresh rate arm race and eventually Samsung
Speaker 5:  is gonna be like we did it everybody 10 80.
Speaker 4:  I think it'll be more like everybody will start to realize they don't actually
Speaker 4:  need that and most of their games will never take advantage of it
Speaker 4:  and it's probably not worth their money. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But that's like three years from now. Oh yeah. After a bunch of people buy
Speaker 5:  monitors out after the 10 80 hurts would ever notice. Right. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  It's after and then we'll be like, oh remember that phase Weird.
Speaker 3:  Well, So I, just to be specific, the LG display is
Speaker 3:  480 hertz at 10 80 p which is, I think
Speaker 3:  that's why a bunch of monitors hit 1440 for a minute. That was the
Speaker 3:  sweet spot of resolution and and refresh rate and So I think what this
Speaker 3:  actually signals is you're gonna get faster refresh rates at the resolutions
Speaker 3:  you actually wanna run at. And then, and then you have to make some sort
Speaker 3:  of decisions about what you prioritize. But yeah, it, this is just a spec
Speaker 3:  war and I'm here for it. Absolutely. I, I want to be very clear that
Speaker 3:  anytime LG and Samsung decide to engage in a display spec
Speaker 3:  war, you just call me. I'll be there a hundred percent. We're we're gonna
Speaker 3:  cover every ounce of that spec war. 'cause display spec wars are what this
Speaker 3:  business is made of.
Speaker 5:  I also still really like this trend where everybody is putting smart TV
Speaker 5:  stuff into computer monitors.
Speaker 4:  It's the best.
Speaker 5:  It's so good. Like, like just to have a thing that's like I have a
Speaker 5:  32 inch screen and I can, it is my television and my
Speaker 5:  gaming monitor and my computer monitor and it does all those things pretty,
Speaker 5:  it's like I love it. It's
Speaker 4:  Great. Can you imagine being a college student and having that like I'm just
Speaker 4:  like, why I want that. I know I'm gonna go back to college just So I can
Speaker 4:  have this monitor experience but then I'm gonna be in the dorm one night
Speaker 4:  and be like, wait,
Speaker 5:  I like having
Speaker 3:  A house. I just want to be clear. Both of you are are very senior. Editorial
Speaker 3:  staffers.com David's like, I can't wait till I can own a chair
Speaker 3:  And Alex is like, I'm gonna go back to college to get a monitor.
Speaker 3:  It's good. We all need dreams and hopes and aspirations.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Our dreams just going backwards or forwards rapidly in time.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna get a chair guys. It's gonna be my chair.
Speaker 4:  He's gonna have his name on the
Speaker 5:  Back. You have to earn comfort me. Like Yeah, don't forget that.
Speaker 3:  All. right. The last little display one I want to call out and then we should
Speaker 3:  do this is lightning round. Is this LG projector that looks like an old
Speaker 3:  bell and Howell film projector. Like it this, it's
Speaker 3:  a handle but it looks like a crank on the side. It's called the cine beam
Speaker 3:  cube. Cube is spelled with a q extraordinarily important to
Speaker 3:  note that it's spelled with a Q. It weighs 3.2
Speaker 3:  pounds. It's just a little bit shorter
Speaker 3:  than an iPhone. So it's itty bitty and it can do 120 inch image
Speaker 3:  at 4K.
Speaker 3:  It's pretty dimm. It's it's 500. It's not, it's not great
Speaker 3:  but it is so pretty. It's
Speaker 5:  Beautiful.
Speaker 3:  It also, it runs web oss of
Speaker 5:  Course. So, I. I really think back to like what we were talking about, about
Speaker 5:  the kind of disintermediating phones as a thing. I think this is
Speaker 5:  one way it's gonna happen. I think we're gonna get this really
Speaker 5:  cool run of like furniture
Speaker 5:  gadgets that I'm really excited about. Like we, we spent a long time with
Speaker 5:  all the smart speakers and all this stuff being like, what if we made
Speaker 5:  everything in your house more gadgety and it looked more like the
Speaker 5:  future. Yeah. And everybody said that sucks. And then like with
Speaker 5:  TVs and like the, the Samsung frame, which I know you haven't have many feelings
Speaker 5:  about. We've, we've kind of gone back to like, what if these things actually
Speaker 5:  looked, you know, nice and looked designed
Speaker 5:  and looked like they belonged in your house and weren't just sort of dropped
Speaker 5:  out of a Best Buy. And I think you're starting to see it from some of these
Speaker 5:  bigger companies too. These things are all kind of like
Speaker 5:  special edition larks right now. But you really get the sense that these
Speaker 5:  companies are testing the waters to see like if we made a thing that doesn't
Speaker 5:  look like a big fat white piece of plastic,
Speaker 5:  would people buy that? And like I know for me the answer is yes and I really
Speaker 5:  hope it is for other people too. 'cause I think design like this is what
Speaker 5:  a projector should look like. Yeah. I'm so
Speaker 3:  Cool as hell. Yeah. What what's funny though about all of that
Speaker 3:  is, you know, old projectors look this way. Partially beautiful, but
Speaker 3:  partially 'cause form followed function. Like they were very utilitarian
Speaker 3:  products. This is just a projector. Like
Speaker 3:  this is just an arm chip in some, I'm guessing some like very
Speaker 3:  standard off the shelf projector parts that they have. They have lying around
Speaker 3:  and they've made it beautiful. They've made it look like the old form,
Speaker 3:  like the old function. And we haven't, we
Speaker 3:  haven't quite figured out like, oh you could just make it really, really
Speaker 3:  small. Like, oh we should make it bigger and like beautiful And like that
Speaker 3:  is interesting to me. The Frame TV is like a deeply fascinating product to
Speaker 3:  me. Why I as, as somebody who now owns A Frame TV in a frame,
Speaker 3:  I'll rant about this product all day and all night. First of all, have you
Speaker 3:  used Smart Things? What what?
Speaker 4:  I used it like four years ago. Horrible.
Speaker 3:  So the Frame TV is fascinating 'cause Samsung will just tell you this is
Speaker 3:  a TV that's designed to be off and people buy it because they, they
Speaker 3:  they realize that their TV is off more than on. Yeah. And so it should be
Speaker 3:  beautiful when it's off, which is just wildly interesting. Second, if you
Speaker 3:  actually put a frame on it, you destroy the functionality of a Frame tv.
Speaker 3:  This is a true thing that I will talk about at length. 'cause it blocks all
Speaker 3:  the sensors in the front.
Speaker 5:  Neli has assigned like a half dozen stories investigating the Frame tv, what
Speaker 5:  went wrong with his frame tv.
Speaker 3:  I think a tech product that is a bad TV that kind of
Speaker 3:  doesn't work when you do what you're supposed to do with it and is still
Speaker 3:  the bestselling tech product and category is a fat, like is
Speaker 3:  a cultural object. Yeah. We should just think about that more. Totally agree.
Speaker 4:  It's kind of like what happened was for a long time when they were making
Speaker 4:  technology for like going in the homes, they wanted it to make it look cool
Speaker 4:  and like, or they wanted to make it look like it was meant for anyone
Speaker 4:  and not be scary. That's why they had all the wood paneling and stuff like
Speaker 4:  that. Yeah. And then one day they were like, oh, we can just go like balls
Speaker 4:  to the wall, do whatever we want, like do our spec wars,
Speaker 4:  get to 10 80 hertz. We can do all of that and have fun with it and not worry
Speaker 4:  about the design factor. And now they're starting to realize like they're
Speaker 4:  starting to hit a lot of those limits on like, on a lot of the technology.
Speaker 4:  And so they're like, okay, what do we have left? Oh, we can actually make
Speaker 4:  it not look like garbage.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well there's such a, there's such an interesting
Speaker 5:  philosophical shift underneath what you just described too, right? Because
Speaker 5:  we, we went through this whole long phase where technology was exciting because
Speaker 5:  it was technology, right? And you kind of wanted the things in your life
Speaker 5:  to scream technology. Yeah. And I feel like we are headed into
Speaker 5:  something very different from that that is going to be like, technology
Speaker 5:  is not supposed to be everywhere and
Speaker 5:  scream its name in my face all the time. It's supposed to like blend
Speaker 5:  into my life and surroundings. And I think like if that's this next generation
Speaker 5:  and the design is sort of the leader of that, it's gonna change a lot
Speaker 5:  of things in really interesting ways. But I think you're right. I think that
Speaker 5:  is at least where a lot of people are pushing us right
Speaker 5:  now is out of this thing where it's like everything I have looks more and
Speaker 5:  more like a gadget and my house just becomes one big gadget to like, I have
Speaker 5:  more gadgets but they don't show themselves the same way. Yeah. Well
Speaker 4:  We're seeing it too in like how, how people are moving that into different
Speaker 4:  spaces in their house, right? Like, like the, the office is not in the
Speaker 4:  kitchen, it's not in the dining room. Generally speaking, it's often a room.
Speaker 4:  The home theater is another one, like most people's home theaters probably
Speaker 4:  isn't the same room where they do other just like hanging out stuff. It's
Speaker 4:  probably cool and dark and I wanna own every, like all $10,000 worth of
Speaker 4:  equipment.
Speaker 5:  Do you have one of those in your dorm room also?
Speaker 4:  I will, I will when I go back to school.
Speaker 3:  Okay, cool. No, the, the theater thing is really interesting and I'm sure
Speaker 3:  we'll see this at CSS a bunch. This is why Soundbars exist as a
Speaker 3:  category. Yeah. 'cause people didn't wanna put five speakers in their house.
Speaker 3:  Now if you're me, you wanna put 12 speakers in there. So that's a very different
Speaker 3:  approach. But most people are like, no, what about one inconspicuous black
Speaker 3:  bar under the tv? That sounds good. Leave everything else out. And that more
Speaker 3:  or less one. The thing you're talking about David, is what we used to call
Speaker 3:  like the ambient computer. Like several years ago, this was the theme that
Speaker 3:  the computers would disappear on the walls and we would just like talk to
Speaker 3:  Alexa. And that really didn't play out. And
Speaker 3:  I think the twist here that is interesting, and again, this is just one 500
Speaker 3:  lumen projector, but the twist here that is interesting is that things are
Speaker 3:  designed to be seen. Yeah. Right? They're, they're designed to be beautiful
Speaker 3:  objects. And because you can take the smartphone
Speaker 3:  supply chain and say, okay, now your computer monitor also has its
Speaker 3:  own operating system and its own arm processor. And also
Speaker 3:  by the way, it's like easier to, to get a bunch of streaming services on
Speaker 3:  this weird custom computer than on your desktop computer. Yep. So we'll just
Speaker 3:  like run it over here or we can make a little projector or whatever
Speaker 3:  we, we want to do. Using all these commodity smartphone pieces,
Speaker 3:  you're seeing more technology, more complete computers put into different
Speaker 3:  things as like single purpose things that actually
Speaker 3:  work well. And that lets you get to the design element of it. Whereas before,
Speaker 3:  I think the idea of putting a computer in anything
Speaker 3:  required, like an awful lot of computer. Yes. Yeah. And that
Speaker 3:  made everything ugly. And that now all that stuff is just teeny tiny and
Speaker 3:  small and cheap because we've had smartphones for so long.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that's right. And I think we're gonna see a ton of that at
Speaker 5:  CES, including some of the stuff we've seen already
Speaker 3:  All. right. So let's wrap up this little CES previous segment by doing a
Speaker 3:  CES lightning round. Then the third segment will just be a regular, none
Speaker 3:  of these are never quick. I don't know why we pretend it's lightning. Please
Speaker 3:  buy the lightning round. Someone show up.
Speaker 3:  You can have it. We'll rename it for you. It's fine. This is the one thing
Speaker 3:  where I will abandon my journalistic ethics and just sell, sell, sell
Speaker 4:  The Samsung frame land.
Speaker 3:  You tell me. Yeah. The whatever kind of refrigerator you want me to hawk.
Speaker 3:  You got it. What's that weird brand that just makes the retro fridges? You
Speaker 3:  want the lightning round?
Speaker 4:  Seg
Speaker 3:  Smeg, lightning rounds ground Chilled by Smeg.
Speaker 3:  You got it. Oh boy. Anything, just show up. His name is Andrew Ze.
Speaker 3:  He's our, he's our, he's our director of like network integrations or whatever.
Speaker 3:  Its, you just talk to him. He'll, he'll write him a check. He got you. He'll
Speaker 3:  say whatever you want. All, right? Alex, what's your CS line?
Speaker 4:  So this one is, they announced it before CES. They're gonna show 'em off
Speaker 4:  at CES, but Dell has redone the whole XPS
Speaker 4:  lineup. The XPS 13 plus has gone away. but it is
Speaker 4:  also, which is also
Speaker 5:  'cause it's sucked,
Speaker 4:  But it is also technically the, the new XPS 13.
Speaker 4:  It, it's using a lot of the same stuff. But then they've,
Speaker 4:  they've gotten rid of the 15 inch and the 17 inch. Those will both
Speaker 4:  still be around, you'll still be able to buy the old version for a while,
Speaker 4:  but they're not gonna be doing big upgrades to it. And instead you're getting
Speaker 4:  a 14 and a 16 inch. And the 14 inch I'm
Speaker 4:  really excited about because it's only like a pound more than the 13
Speaker 4:  inch, which I don't carry my computer everywhere, so that's not bad for me.
Speaker 4:  It gets you like a much larger battery. I think it goes up to 69.5 watts
Speaker 4:  per hour versus the previous one, which was 55 watts
Speaker 4:  per hour. And it gets you discrete graphics and that's just really
Speaker 4:  exciting. And also there's a little tiny copilot button, but they like
Speaker 4:  hadn't figured out the rounding. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  This is one of the funniest pictures we have ever run
Speaker 4:  With the just little sticker.
Speaker 3:  The sticker on the carpi.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They hadn't figured out. They, they like, they didn't get the, they
Speaker 4:  they, they didn't get it until the last minute. And so they're like, okay
Speaker 4:  sticker. We already made these laptops.
Speaker 4:  Boops. Thanks. Thanks Microsoft.
Speaker 3:  The sticker's a little fuzzy. It, everything about this picture is perfect.
Speaker 4:  I love it. Thank you Amelia for taking beautiful photos. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's just, it's just, what is this the, is this the menu button that they
Speaker 5:  just literally put a little sticker over with the
Speaker 4:  Co-pilot and now I'll go co-pilot, which just, it really, I know everybody's
Speaker 4:  very excited about the co-pilot button, but for me Maybe, it was because
Speaker 4:  I first experienced it with the Dell XPS, I had big like
Speaker 4:  Cortana vibes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, yeah. I mean look, this is the dream for Microsoft, right? Yeah. It's
Speaker 3:  like there's a button, an assistant shows up, you ask at some things
Speaker 3:  that lies to your face and tries to bang you and move on with your day.
Speaker 3:  That was the original Pitch for Clippy. Clippy
Speaker 5:  Clippy tries to bang you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. don don't want that Could be get away. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's somehow worse.
Speaker 4:  Those eyes,
Speaker 3:  The fact that I keep insisting that Bing is trying to bang you, they haven't
Speaker 3:  said a word to me about it, is like very funny
Speaker 5:  To me. Yeah. The silence is deafening Microsoft,
Speaker 3:  They're
Speaker 4:  Gonna get
Speaker 3:  You for click. Not one email, not one text, not one LinkedIn
Speaker 3:  message from some aggrieved Bing product manager. They're just like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  definitely tried to bang a bunch of people did.
Speaker 5:  Did
Speaker 4:  Sure did.
Speaker 3:  All right. David, what do you
Speaker 5:  Got? Mine is, and I have, I literally have to load the page so
Speaker 5:  that I can tell you the name because the name just breaks my heart every
Speaker 5:  time I say it out loud. The Samsung 2024
Speaker 5:  bespoke four-door Flex Refrigerator with AI Family Hub Plus. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Which is the Samsung iest thing to ever Samsung.
Speaker 5:  It is Samsung's new smart fridge. I love, love,
Speaker 5:  love that Samsung is all in on smart fridges. Like this company
Speaker 5:  will not abandon the idea that your fridge
Speaker 5:  should be the biggest and most important screen in your house.
Speaker 5:  And I think that rules, and I hope it never changes.
Speaker 5:  So, and like, and, and I actually think like, I have two thoughts about this.
Speaker 5:  One is that we're going to see just, just
Speaker 5:  infinite gadgets at CES that are just gadget plus chat. GPT
Speaker 5:  like name a thing plus chat, GPT. And they'll be like, is this anything?
Speaker 5:  And I'll just be wandering through the Venetian being like, that's nothing.
Speaker 5:  That's nothing. That's nothing. You can't just put chat GPT in it. That's
Speaker 5:  still, it's still nothing. But then the other thing is going to be
Speaker 5:  companies that are further ahead of the game trying to figure out
Speaker 5:  what cool stuff you can actually do with some of these
Speaker 5:  AI tools. And Samsung has been doing this for a while. It's had some
Speaker 5:  fun slash bizarre ideas about what you can do with a camera
Speaker 5:  inside of your fridge. And this one in particular,
Speaker 5:  it uses a camera inside of your fridge to not just figure out what you
Speaker 5:  have, but to help you identify recipes that you can cook
Speaker 5:  with what you have in the fridge. Which for me is like the dream, right?
Speaker 5:  It's like you wanna open it up and be like, okay, I have, I have broccoli
Speaker 5:  and pasta and a half a thing of Worcestershire sauce. Like what can I make
Speaker 5:  for dinner? And it'll just tell you that's like, that is, if you
Speaker 3:  Can't figure out what to do with broccoli and pasta and Worcester around
Speaker 3:  here, you mix the broccoli with the pasta and you set the wors syrup aside,
Speaker 3:  throw
Speaker 5:  The worre sauce, you
Speaker 3:  Drizzle it on. You're like, not today. Weird sauce.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 5:  That's, I mean you
Speaker 3:  Should, I can, I can. I just, I like, I I support your dream. I can I just
Speaker 3:  point out the most hilarious limitation of the dream as expressed
Speaker 3:  in this refrigerator. Sure. The AI camera can only recognize
Speaker 3:  33 different systems. Yeah. So if, if you were just like
Speaker 3:  a little bit out of Samsung strike zone of 33 foods it
Speaker 3:  knows about, it's like don don't know man, you're on your own.
Speaker 5:  Just one small clarification. It can, it can identify up to 33
Speaker 5:  food, I
Speaker 3:  Guess
Speaker 3:  33 is the dream.
Speaker 5:  Does it have to be like specific brands?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That unclear. I will say the touchscreen has a, a TikTok
Speaker 3:  app and a YouTube app. Oh, that's what I mean. And standing in front of your
Speaker 3:  fridge scrolling TikTok videos
Speaker 3:  actually kind of amazing. Like honestly kind of an like, I'm
Speaker 3:  gonna go try to have that experience. I mean,
Speaker 5:  How have you, have you never done the thing where there's something in the
Speaker 5:  microwave for 60 seconds and you're like, oh, I'm just gonna look at four
Speaker 5:  tiktoks while I do this. You could do that on your fridge. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The screen's huge. And the way that I'm gonna choose to express that desire
Speaker 3:  is not by pulling out my $1,500 state-of-the-art phone.
Speaker 3:  It's by using the computer in my fridge.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't see what the problem is.
Speaker 3:  By the way. Deciding who in the family gets to determine the TikTok algorithm
Speaker 3:  or even the TikTok account loaded onto the refrigerator.
Speaker 5:  Who the fridge. I think you gotta give the fridge its own algorithm. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If the fridge gets its own account, I think
Speaker 3:  Fridge gets its own. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's like the truly one of the most dangerous and destabilizing pieces
Speaker 3:  of technology you can introduce them to. Any family is
Speaker 3:  full-size TikTok on the fridge and you're like, whose account
Speaker 3:  is gonna sign into this TikTok? I don't know about that.
Speaker 5:  It's a lot of trust. I
Speaker 3:  Our, we have an LG by the way. LG has a, a smart platform called Think,
Speaker 3:  think Q that looks exactly like smart things. I know everyone
Speaker 3:  always wants to dunk on Xiaomi and Huawei for exactly copying iOS.
Speaker 3:  The fact that LG and Samsung have exactly copied their bad smart home
Speaker 3:  experiences. Very funny. Very funny. So we now
Speaker 3:  have a thank you microwave and a thank you fridge.
Speaker 3:  The microwave will send you a notification when it is done, which is
Speaker 3:  the least useful notification in the world. Because
Speaker 3:  how long, like getting a notification on your phone for something that you've
Speaker 3:  set for a minute, it's like not useful.
Speaker 4:  People used to roast turkeys in 'em. Maybe, maybe you're
Speaker 3:  Roast
Speaker 5:  A, a Turkey, turn your microwave and just sprint out the front door.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I'm out. I'm gone.
Speaker 3:  You ours is over our stove. So you can also tell whatever voice
Speaker 3:  assistant to turn on the light and the fan. And my wife was like, but
Speaker 3:  the button is right there.
Speaker 3:  And then our refrigerator will not send me notifications for when it thinks
Speaker 3:  our ice is too old. And it's like, throw away your ice. And I've,
Speaker 3:  I've never even considered this before. And I don dunno why I have any of
Speaker 3:  these notifications turned on or why I've even connected any of these devices
Speaker 3:  to the internet. To the begin. Wait, I've,
Speaker 5:  Are you supposed to throw away your ice?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I was like quietly Googling
Speaker 3:  Straight up. I got a notification. It's like, it's been seven days.
Speaker 3:  Please discard your ice so we can make you fresh ice
Speaker 5:  Seven days. And if you had said a year, I would've been like, oh, I've never,
Speaker 5:  I've still never done that. Like,
Speaker 3:  So our old fridge didn't have an ice maker. So. I, you know, I, we
Speaker 3:  bought the most ice maker. It can make four kinds of ice. My good man.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, what a luxury. And then it turns out we don't use ice.
Speaker 3:  So now I just have like a fridge full of ice and the fridge is like, get
Speaker 3:  this ice outta me. And that is the relationship I have with technology. Now
Speaker 5:  Listen, if you aren't listening to this and you know, if you're supposed
Speaker 5:  to replace your ice every seven days, please email us Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 5:  dot com. If you're an expert on ice replacement situations in
Speaker 5:  fridges. I need to know this please.
Speaker 3:  I think LG is in the pocket of big one.
Speaker 5:  That's what I, that's where I'm at right now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's also someone who's been installing a lot of new smart lights
Speaker 3:  switches. I think Lutron is in the pocket of big wire nut. Oh yeah. Because
Speaker 3:  God bless the Lutron switch. But that's a lot of wire nuts.
Speaker 3:  You're just packing 'em in that box and screwing it tight.
Speaker 4:  What's your lightning round?
Speaker 3:  So mine is the TV stuff. We're getting some glimmers of the TV stuff.
Speaker 3:  There's two trends that I think are really interesting in TVs this year.
Speaker 3:  One, they're bringing AI to settings.
Speaker 3:  So actually if you go back years now, AI has
Speaker 3:  been at CS for years because every TV company is like, look at our AI pic
Speaker 3:  picture processing and upscaling. Like they've been talking about it forever
Speaker 3:  and ever and ever. And everyone's like, haha, AI in this year it's gonna
Speaker 3:  be outta control because now the AI can can lie to you.
Speaker 3:  But they've been doing AI and upscaling for years and years and years to
Speaker 3:  get, you know, to upscale your horrible seven 20 P Fox NFL broadcast
Speaker 3:  to 4K. They've applied a lot of AI to that at the panel level. So they're
Speaker 3:  gonna do more and more of that this year. The thing that they're all doing
Speaker 3:  is they're applying it to settings. So they're gonna say, okay, we are gonna
Speaker 3:  recognize your content and adjust to the settings of the tv.
Speaker 3:  So you won't have to switch between game mode and cinema mode or whatever.
Speaker 3:  We'll recognize, okay, you're playing a video game, we're gonna switch you
Speaker 3:  to the highest refresh rate. Lowest latency of the whole thing. Okay.
Speaker 3:  You're watching a movie that's Tom Cruise's face. We're gonna put you in
Speaker 3:  Tom Cruise mode. We, which is fascinating. They should have done this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's a good idea. Wait,
Speaker 4:  But why does that require ai? Couldn't that just require
Speaker 4:  acknowledging that you've changed inputs
Speaker 3:  You, well you can already do input level settings, but if you have Yeah,
Speaker 3:  if your input level setting is like an Xbox, knowing
Speaker 3:  what kind of content is coming outta the Xbox, actually. Okay. Really hard,
Speaker 3:  right? Like the Xbox either needs to communicate with the tv, which
Speaker 3:  given the state of HMI seems unlikely. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What was the name of that thing? That the, the box that had all the inputs
Speaker 5:  that pr, the cavo, that was the, one of the things it tried to do
Speaker 5:  was figure out what you're watching and actually like to
Speaker 5:  the experience based on literally the content on the screen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The cavo is different 'cause it was a universal remote. So its whole
Speaker 3:  Pitch was like, you tell us what you want and we'll know what you have
Speaker 3:  and we'll deliver that. Like we'll click around the Apple TV interface for
Speaker 3:  you's. Right. And because it was machine learning, it wouldn't be brittle.
Speaker 3:  Like if you wanna do a most universal or most, if you wanna do
Speaker 3:  a macro, you're like, okay, press power, wait four seconds, click right.
Speaker 3:  Three times wait. You know, like, and that is all inherently brittle and
Speaker 3:  broken. The Cavo is like, we will look at the screen and we'll make sure
Speaker 3:  we're gonna click on the Hulu app. We'll click on the Hulu app, we'll see
Speaker 3:  what's on the screen. We'll find the thing you want. It did not work.
Speaker 3:  That company pivoted to selling video conferencing solutions for nursing
Speaker 3:  homes. This is a true story, but the idea that you can recognize
Speaker 3:  it's on the screen and take action on it. Kind of an old idea.
Speaker 3:  Advertising on Connected TVs has worked this way for a very long time.
Speaker 3:  Really weird stuff. But automatic a CR automatic content recognition
Speaker 3:  has been built into most panels for a long time. So the TV manufacturers
Speaker 3:  know what you're watching, they can sell ads against it, which isn't great.
Speaker 3:  And now they're gonna finally start doing a useful thing with that technology,
Speaker 3:  which is saying, okay, it's a movie. We're gonna put you in the best mode
Speaker 3:  for this movie. Roku is gonna announce new Roku Pro
Speaker 3:  mini LED TVs, they've got smart picture modes.
Speaker 3:  Their Pitch is 90% of people never change the settings on the tv. This will
Speaker 3:  help a lot of people. They're also Roku's gonna do mini L led d TVs. They're
Speaker 3:  gonna make higher end TVs that I think is really interesting. Mini LED is
Speaker 3:  gonna be everywhere at CS SU. Yeah. And then Sony is not gonna announce new
Speaker 3:  TVs. Sony is off the TV cycle at css, which is
Speaker 3:  fascinating. The Sony 8 95 quantum oled, that was
Speaker 3:  the flagship TV of last year, just hit in October. Oh geez. So Sony
Speaker 3:  is just way off this cycle. They're just doing whatever they want, but they
Speaker 3:  previewed. We've got a bunch of mini LED tech coming this year that's better
Speaker 3:  than before. So like they're still making CSS announcements, which
Speaker 3:  is fascinating. And then LG announced its next generation
Speaker 3:  of OLEDs kind of minor bumps from last year. But the, the big news is
Speaker 3:  MLA, its multiple lens array technology is gonna hit the 83 inch size and
Speaker 3:  the G three. And then they've got smaller versions of its
Speaker 3:  ones that are wireless, which means you plug all your stuff into a
Speaker 3:  box on the other side of your room, but you still have to plug your TV into
Speaker 3:  the wall. Which don don't know man. But so like sort of
Speaker 3:  iterative on the OLED side. And then I think huge strides in the mini
Speaker 3:  LED side, which is gonna be really interesting because many
Speaker 3:  LEDs are cheaper. They're just LCD screens with really, really advanced backlights.
Speaker 3:  But the backlights are getting simultaneously more advanced and more interesting
Speaker 3:  and cheaper. Right. So they're, they're gonna crash right into oed. So I
Speaker 3:  just bought an A 95. My thesis is that the TVs going on my
Speaker 3:  wall for like a decade. Spending money on a TV is actually a pretty good
Speaker 3:  investment. And I came this close to buying an
Speaker 3:  X 95. Like, so shout out to Val Electronics in Scarsdale.
Speaker 3:  I went, they had two calibrated Sony TVs like Cal not in retail mode, like
Speaker 3:  calibrated a 95 next to an X 95. A 95 is
Speaker 3:  the Oad X 95 is the mini LED. And I was like this
Speaker 3:  close to my next
Speaker 4:  95. What was, what were they playing on it?
Speaker 3:  They were playing some, you know, dark stereo
Speaker 5:  Story. I literally, I
Speaker 3:  Feel like, like look at this lizard. I want
Speaker 5:  Know a how many hours you spent standing between the two of them
Speaker 5:  and, and quit and like bouncing how close you got to one and then you'd walk
Speaker 5:  over the other like, did you bring a, did you bring a loop? Did you bring
Speaker 5:  a microscope? Like did you, did you bring your trusty Nikon
Speaker 5:  macro lens to take pictures of the pixels? Like they just closed and left
Speaker 5:  you in there overnight. They were like, we'll see you tomorrow, let us know.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. but it was like me alone in a dark store with like various
Speaker 3:  $30,000, like BW speakers,
Speaker 3:  hugely expensive. I was just like in heaven. And then this
Speaker 3:  store, they're the ones who run this thing on YouTube called the King of
Speaker 3:  tv. Shootouts been new here for like 20 years. And so like they calibrate
Speaker 3:  everything. It's like beautiful. Ugh, So I. Like, but I came this close my,
Speaker 3:  the next, it's the mini a d Tech is so close. It's like,
Speaker 3:  it's right there. And I think at CSS we're gonna see the next
Speaker 3:  evolution of it across a number of manufacturers. And then Sony's gonna show
Speaker 3:  us some more stuff this year. And the point I always make is if you pay attention
Speaker 3:  to displays, like one, it's fun. 'cause it's just a, it's a
Speaker 3:  stakeless spec war, right? Like, it's not like will
Speaker 3:  TikTok ruin democracy? You know, it's like will this display look sick or
Speaker 3:  not? Is like all you need to know. But if you keep
Speaker 3:  track of it, you can kind of tell what kind of devices we're gonna get a
Speaker 3:  few years down the line. Yeah. Right. Because the, the display is usually
Speaker 3:  the thing that limits the foreign factor of any device you're talking about.
Speaker 3:  And so TVs are where you kind of get the, the state of the artie, state of
Speaker 3:  the art and that stuff just trickles down to everything else. And I I, the
Speaker 3:  mini LED moment is like, we're right here.
Speaker 3:  We're spending the extra money in an OLED for a lot of people isn't gonna
Speaker 3:  be worth it. Ugh. Which I think is fascinating. That's
Speaker 4:  Gonna suck. I like to be smug about my oled.
Speaker 3:  I love, look, I just, I bought, I didn't buy the X 95, I bought the 8 95.
Speaker 3:  'cause I wanna, I wanna be smug. Yeah. I wanna look at that thing and just
Speaker 3:  feel a wave of smugness every time I look
Speaker 4:  At it. Like I need to know what, know what I'm gonna be smug about in four
Speaker 4:  to five years.
Speaker 3:  Here's what I'm smug about. I now have access to the world's most useless
Speaker 3:  streaming service. Bravia core.
Speaker 4:  You get the really good reds on Spider-Man though,
Speaker 3:  You get the really good reds, it's, it streams in pure stream. It streams
Speaker 3:  80 megabits per second on Bravia core. But you can stream four movies
Speaker 3:  and three of them are Spider-Man.
Speaker 3:  And as soon
Speaker 5:  As you turn it on Comcast calls and says, are you running a Bitcoin mine
Speaker 5:  out of your house?
Speaker 3:  Exactly. But one of the movies on Broadway Corps that had access
Speaker 3:  to, 'cause they changed the library all the time, was a remaster in IMAX
Speaker 3:  of the original Ghostbusters. And I was like, I'm in heaven.
Speaker 3:  Like this is a kind of, it was kind of like a bad 4K upscale. Like
Speaker 4:  You like see the pores, but they're weird looking. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You know, there's like too much contrast. You were Alex what was the one
Speaker 3:  you were pointing out the other day? You, you quick posted about there was
Speaker 3:  something that just got upscaled and it looks really bad. Well, they're
Speaker 4:  Doing it a bunch with everything like YouTube. On YouTube right now, if you
Speaker 4:  go and look up an old trailer, almost all of them have been upscaled. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And you're just like, oh, that's weird.
Speaker 3:  I sat and re-watched all of Ghostbusters in this bad upscale, I mean, it
Speaker 3:  looked in, it looked insane in some ways. Like just like two
Speaker 3:  contrasty. Like that's the thing I always catch with these bad upscales.
Speaker 3:  Like it's like two contrasty and some things like blown out in weird ways.
Speaker 3:  But then I was like, I'm reading the titles of the name tags
Speaker 4:  Because you can, this
Speaker 3:  Is a movie I watched a hundred times on VHS on a 13 inch screen. And I'm
Speaker 3:  like, look at, look at all those words that are on the screen.
Speaker 4:  How is Slimer beautiful?
Speaker 3:  I mean, you look no, like, parts of it are blurry. Like, 'cause you know,
Speaker 3:  the old lenses weren't perfectly sharp across Yeah. The whole frame.
Speaker 3:  And they were sh and like, you know, they sh a lot of that movie is shot
Speaker 3:  at night. So there's like a lot of film grain that's g getting re upscale.
Speaker 3:  Like none of this looked good. I do not think you should buy a Sony TV for
Speaker 3:  this experience. But in terms of things I am smug about
Speaker 3:  having had this experience because I own this TV very high on the list.
Speaker 3:  Like I need a shirt that's just like Bravia Stan. And everyone's like, what
Speaker 3:  are you watching? And I'm like, nothing Air Force one. I gotta
Speaker 3:  go
Speaker 4:  Got rid of your Netflix account years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm watching four movies on Bravia court. Meanwhile,
Speaker 5:  I was just making plans to watch Oppenheimer on my iPad on the way to Vegas
Speaker 5:  next week.
Speaker 4:  Christopher Nolan is gonna be behind you on the plane.
Speaker 4:  Like, be careful
Speaker 3:  All. right. We gotta take a break. As you can tell, I'm very excited to go
Speaker 3:  look at TVs at css. We're gonna take a break. We're gonna come back with
Speaker 3:  a non CSS lighting round. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  We're back the lightning round, not sponsored by Smeg. It's
Speaker 3:  un chill.
Speaker 4:  We're lightning.
Speaker 3:  This poor company is like a great business selling retro fridges in the back
Speaker 3:  of office max. And they're like, boss,
Speaker 5:  Whatever man. We said Smeg like 10 times already on this podcast. They're
Speaker 5:  doing fine.
Speaker 4:  Weird name, weird name. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Our Google results are blowing up today. Someone's got
Speaker 3:  the Google or you know, it's like, what is going, they
Speaker 3:  they're, they're adorable. They're, they look like the fifties only using
Speaker 3:  modern pay us the money. And I'll finish the sentence smg,
Speaker 5:  The modern what? smg
Speaker 3:  By the way, in case you're wondering this is not how you generate sales.
Speaker 3:  I don't know how I think that should be very clear to everyone. That's not
Speaker 3:  my side of the business at all. But I'm very clear that this isn't how you
Speaker 3:  do it by threatening the maker of a retro refrigerator.
Speaker 3:  But if you know the good people at Smeg, if you know Alan Smeg, you know,
Speaker 3:  call him up. All, right?
Speaker 3:  I don't know if his name is Alan.
Speaker 4:  It's probably not Last name's. Probably not. Smeg.
Speaker 3:  Lightning round part two, non css. David, what got, so
Speaker 5:  There was this patent that came out this week. We think we're
Speaker 5:  about three weeks-ish away from Division
Speaker 5:  Pro launch from Apple. That's the, the word on the street I think is like
Speaker 5:  January 25th, 26th seems to be
Speaker 5:  what that means. Who knows. but it, it appears to be imminent that this thing
Speaker 5:  is coming. And one of the things that came out this
Speaker 5:  week was that Apple was granted a patent
Speaker 5:  for stuff to put on the outside of the
Speaker 5:  display. So if you remember, one of the things that the Vision Pro will do
Speaker 5:  is essentially give you googly eyes on the front of your Vision
Speaker 5:  Pro so that you can sort of look through them and it's like creepy
Speaker 5:  and weird and I hate it, but it's
Speaker 5:  technologically kind of cool. But what it turns out happened is that Apple,
Speaker 5:  including Jony Ive, who's named as an inventor on this patent, had a bunch
Speaker 5:  of ideas about what it might do with an external screen
Speaker 5:  on your face. And I think they're awesome.
Speaker 5:  There's, one of the ideas is just that you could have the words
Speaker 5:  do not disturb written on the outside of your face.
Speaker 3:  One of them
Speaker 5:  Could just project the weather on the outside screen.
Speaker 3:  I love the, the weather one is incredible. So
Speaker 5:  Useful, incredible, incredible. It could show
Speaker 3:  Your, all of the rest of these are sort of like, I see the weather one is
Speaker 3:  spectacular,
Speaker 5:  Incredible. It's spectacular. I agree. It could show your eyes in a bunch
Speaker 5:  of different shapes, including like zoom icons in
Speaker 5:  front of each of your eyes for when you're on a video call, it could show
Speaker 5:  a, a play button. Like if you're playing YouTube, it could show a
Speaker 5:  screensaver. Like it's, there's so many ideas
Speaker 5:  here, and this all reminds me of like early Apple Watch when they were just
Speaker 5:  like, here's a bunch of wacky features. You can send
Speaker 5:  your heartbeat to somebody or draw on your wrist to draw on somebody else's
Speaker 5:  wrist. And this feels so in line with that to me, where they're just
Speaker 5:  like, what can we do with a screen on your face? And Jony Ive is just like
Speaker 5:  hearts.
Speaker 4:  I I I'm missing the, the heartbeat thing though on the Apple watch.
Speaker 4:  That was, was it,
Speaker 4:  it was like creepy.
Speaker 3:  Did did you ever do it?
Speaker 4:  I mean, just to be like creepy to people. It's, it's from, that's how I do
Speaker 4:  the walkie-talkie now too, is just to be creepy. Never to like actually
Speaker 4:  communicate with another human being.
Speaker 3:  Oh see, I I, my wife and I are constantly
Speaker 4:  Using the walkie-talkie. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's, it's, it's really quite good. And actually now our house does not,
Speaker 3:  it's not necessary, but we still do it. So I will walkie talkie her and she'll
Speaker 3:  just yell up the stairs.
Speaker 5:  That's great
Speaker 3:  Technology, everybody.
Speaker 5:  But I think the, the thing I like about this is one thing Apple has always
Speaker 5:  been really good at is taking things that are otherwise kind
Speaker 5:  of problems and making them sort of iconic. Like all the way back to the,
Speaker 5:  the white headphones on the silhouette in the iPod commercials. Like it
Speaker 5:  took the cable of your headphones and turned it into a thing. Right? And
Speaker 5:  it, like, it did the same thing with AirPods, which are objectively ugly,
Speaker 5:  but it made them like culturally cool. And I think
Speaker 5:  Apple's gonna try to do the same thing with the Vision Pro
Speaker 5:  in some way. It's going to try to make it like, no, this is not a stupid
Speaker 5:  thing you wear on your face because it gives you stuff like this is a cool
Speaker 5:  thing for your face, which is a hard sell to make.
Speaker 5:  But I think Apple's gonna try. But yet as, as Jay
Speaker 5:  pointed out in this story that he wrote, we still have not seen,
Speaker 5:  as far as I know anyway, an Apple executive Tim Cook or otherwise
Speaker 5:  with a Vision Pro on their face. And
Speaker 5:  it is, it is very rare that one of these things comes out and is not
Speaker 5:  instantly made a meme. And so for Apple
Speaker 5:  to both simultaneously pursue this idea of like, how do we do more and
Speaker 5:  more and more and more and more with a screen on your face and
Speaker 5:  let's maybe hide the fact that it's a screen on your face for as long as
Speaker 5:  we possibly can.
Speaker 5:  I just, we're like a few weeks away from figuring out which one of those
Speaker 5:  is gonna win in the real world. And I think it's fascinating. I'm
Speaker 4:  Excited for Tim Cook's digital Eyes.
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook just like giving interviews and he gets bored and the weather pops
Speaker 5:  up is just gonna be incredible. Like I cannot wait
Speaker 4:  The little play side, you
Speaker 3:  Can go read the post and look at the pictures. The actual claims of this
Speaker 3:  patent are very small.
Speaker 3:  Like the actual thing that is being patented, a wearable electronic device
Speaker 3:  with a camera in it that's captures images of your, the wearer's face
Speaker 3:  and then a display in the housing that displays images of the wearer's face
Speaker 3:  the images based on the captured images. And then it
Speaker 3:  a sensor that detects the position of the observer
Speaker 3:  so they can point the images. Right. That's the whole thing. That's the whole
Speaker 3:  patent. Oh and the usual thing that they, they stick, they stick
Speaker 3:  this in all computer patents now they're like a computing system that does
Speaker 3:  it. And it's like, yeah, we, we understand the patent office doesn't understand
Speaker 3:  computers.
Speaker 5:  There's not a small person inside doing it for you. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Exactly. That's, that's, it's always fascinating to
Speaker 3:  read what actual apple's actually claiming in these. 'cause they, they'll
Speaker 3:  put a lot of pictures in these and as everyone knows, you gotta read the
Speaker 3:  actual claims and the claims are here are just like we put a camera in it
Speaker 3:  and it display on the outside. That's the whole claim of this patent. And
Speaker 3:  then Jony, I've got to do some pictures. I will say if you walk around in
Speaker 3:  an Apple Vision Pro just displaying to people the weather in Cupertino, California,
Speaker 3:  it's very good. Like the
Speaker 4:  Idea, they don't even change the weather. It's always gonna be Cupertino.
Speaker 5:  I think if you wear one of these, you should be obligated to be showing your
Speaker 5:  TikTok feed on the outside of it at all times.
Speaker 10:  That's
Speaker 4:  Shame.
Speaker 3:  CS is next week. Apple has said Vision Pro is coming early 2024.
Speaker 3:  A lot of rumbles out in the world. I would bet there's some sort of Vision
Speaker 3:  Pro announcement that interferes.
Speaker 5:  Apple loves up staging. CES loves it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah, I bet you're right. So, I. That, that's just my bet. I
Speaker 3:  don't, I don't have any insight into on that. I just based on history.
Speaker 3:  Remember one year at css Apple was like, we have an event. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  the iPhone's now in Verizon. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Cool.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's the same one.
Speaker 3:  All, right? Cranz what you got?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so it is with like great sadness. I say that
Speaker 4:  Amazon is moving to advertising starting in
Speaker 4:  January 29th. That means you're gonna have to watch ads if you
Speaker 4:  have Amazon Prime. Unless
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 4:  Crazy. You wanna pay extra. But it's also like, it was always
Speaker 4:  inevitable. It was always gonna happen. They were, nobody was shy about putting
Speaker 4:  ads on these things when they, when they started with the maybe Netflix.
Speaker 4:  But everybody else was always like, yeah, ads is is somewhere in a forecast
Speaker 4:  for us. So now it's just like, okay. And for
Speaker 4:  Amazon, a company who we don't actually know how many people watch their
Speaker 4:  shows, we just know they have all of the subscribers because everybody has
Speaker 4:  Amazon Prime. This makes a lot of sense. 'cause now they can make,
Speaker 5:  Well I think we can confidently say it's not very many based
Speaker 5:  on the success of their big shows that they have.
Speaker 4:  Which ones? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Wom Reacher. Hey there's the Boys. The Boys is
Speaker 4:  Good. It's richer and Boys. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's a show. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Everybody's dad watches reachers. Like you two are gonna be
Speaker 4:  watching it soon. You don't know it, isn't
Speaker 3:  It just singular reacher? It's
Speaker 4:  It's reacher. Yeah, you're right. It's just reacher.
Speaker 3:  It's like the James Cameron sequels Reachers.
Speaker 4:  It's coming for you guys. Just
Speaker 5:  A lot of tall, quiet men running around small towns in America.
Speaker 3:  The only thing I know about Reacher is I saw a t who's the main actor. I
Speaker 3:  don't even know, I just saw a TikTok with him where he was saying that the
Speaker 3:  amount of muscle that he has to carry on his body to portray reacher is actually
Speaker 3:  causing a physical toll on his body. Wow. Oh no. He's like, imagine walking
Speaker 3:  up a flight of stairs, but you're holding two 40 pound dumbbells. That's
Speaker 3:  my life, Lord.
Speaker 4:  That's a lot. That's too much muscle.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. He was like, yeah, but it's worth it because I'm, I'm reacher. Soon
Speaker 3:  as starting the sequel reachers direct way change games,
Speaker 3:  it is inevitable that all these streaming services are doing ads. Like everyone
Speaker 3:  watching Netflix turn on ads and make more money. Amazon is
Speaker 3:  actually a secretly huge player in the ads business. Yeah. Like a huge player
Speaker 3:  in the ads business. It's, it's Meta, Google and Amazon. And
Speaker 3:  of course they're gonna do connected TV ads, but it's kind of
Speaker 3:  gross. Like the whole point of prime is like not that, right?
Speaker 3:  Like you pay Amazon the money up front to get all the good service on the
Speaker 3:  backend. Yeah. And now it's like, now it's just cable. You just,
Speaker 3:  I'm paying for cable then shipping,
Speaker 4:  I think for them it's like, okay, you get free shipping, you get whatever
Speaker 4:  other stuff comes with Prime and now you also get free cable and if you
Speaker 4:  wanna get rid of the, the ads on your cable, you can give us even more money
Speaker 4:  every month. And four people are gonna do that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No one write us a note if you're gonna pay
Speaker 3:  for the ad free tier of Amazon Prime video. I wanna meet you.
Speaker 3:  I feel like I could meet you individual.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like that, that's a scalable proposition is I wanna meet all of
Speaker 5:  You don. You could fit all of those people in like a single Dave and Busters.
Speaker 5:  Like no question
Speaker 3:  We're gonna have a party sponsored by, you
Speaker 3:  know who you are
Speaker 3:  All. right? I have two. 'cause I, I added one 'cause it's so
Speaker 3:  funny. But my first one is
Speaker 3:  Alma Drafthouse runs Sony Digital Cinema projectors.
Speaker 3:  And they had some sort of certificate timeout over the break
Speaker 3:  and they just stopped showing movies.
Speaker 5:  It's so brutal.
Speaker 4:  It's, and that's like, they're the, they're supposed to be the good company.
Speaker 4:  They're supposed to be like the good movie theater that like actually
Speaker 4:  cares about how they screen things. So for them to like drop the ball this
Speaker 4:  bad is Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So it's, it's unclear what happened. We've read a bunch of forum posts from
Speaker 3:  like theater employees and like projectionists, one amazing thing about the
Speaker 3:  internet is you're like, man, I, I wonder if there's a community online that's
Speaker 3:  deep in the weeds of this and you're like, oh, it's the projectionist forums.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, obviously. So there's, there's people like explaining what
Speaker 3:  happened, you know, they're like man the company. But, but it feels like,
Speaker 3:  David, I know you read a bunch of this stuff too and we're gonna write a
Speaker 3:  story on it. 'cause it's, it is very, it's like perfectly ver Strike House.
Speaker 3:  There's a lot of DRM involved in digital
Speaker 3:  projection. Like you send a movie to a movie theater, there's a bunch
Speaker 3:  of DRM steps in being able to play back that digital file. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And somewhere between the projector and the file,
Speaker 3:  there was a certificate timeout and no one, like, no one caught saw it
Speaker 5:  Coming. Yeah. That, that's about as far as I've gotten down the rabbit hole.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. And Sony kind of
Speaker 5:  increasingly has no interest in this business. And these things are
Speaker 5:  notoriously brittle anyway. Like remember we did that story a few months
Speaker 5:  ago about the IMAX theaters that still crucially rely on a
Speaker 5:  Palm pilot and are now emulating a palm pilot on an iPad. And we're like
Speaker 5:  the, the true nature of the tape and strings that hold these things
Speaker 5:  together is just unbelievable. Even if you're at Alamo
Speaker 5:  Drafthouse and care deeply about how this stuff works, these folks
Speaker 5:  just
Speaker 5:  don't upgrade the equipment unless they have to. And meanwhile, the
Speaker 5:  equipment on which these movies are made is increasingly high tech. And
Speaker 5:  the way that they're being shipped around is increasingly digital and
Speaker 5:  increasingly high tech. And to your point, these companies are taking more
Speaker 5:  and more care to lock this stuff down. Especially with
Speaker 5:  big important movies like the, these things are more carefully controlled
Speaker 5:  than ever. They're not just shipping giant reels around the country nearly
Speaker 5:  the way that they used to. It. It, a lot of this is happening online.
Speaker 5:  It's mostly happening digitally now. Like it, there are just so many more
Speaker 5:  places for it to break in these old weird systems than there used to be.
Speaker 5:  And if you're Alamo, there's just like nothing you can do. You just
Speaker 5:  update the firmware and hope for the best.
Speaker 4:  I think, I think the, the suggestion from a lot of those projectionists though
Speaker 4:  is that like Alamo probably did mess up here. Yeah. And there's been like
Speaker 4:  a lot of talk about like in the theater community about Alamo and it's kind
Speaker 4:  of decline. And so this is kind of like an indication of that decline.
Speaker 4:  They've, they've been rough since like 2017. So
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But like there's, there's no such thing as like a full stack movie
Speaker 5:  theater. Right? Like a MC is not out here making its own projectors so
Speaker 5:  that it can show you the movie better. Like everybody is still reliant on
Speaker 5:  this crazy chain that is not really designed to
Speaker 5:  make the process seamless and good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's supposed to be as complex as possible. 'cause they don't want
Speaker 4:  like a young projectionist to be like, Ooh, let me just upload this
Speaker 4:  to BitTorrent. Gonna have a good time. Beautiful film.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Can I tell a story for my youth?
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  When I was in high school, my friend Allison's dad was the manager of the
Speaker 3:  local movie theater and somehow this emboldened us to believe as
Speaker 3:  we were walking out of a movie that we could pick up the reels of Austin
Speaker 3:  Powers two, the film reels of Austin Powers two and sprint them to
Speaker 3:  our park. They were very heavy. We
Speaker 3:  got nowhere before. We were just stopped by a group of theater employees
Speaker 3:  going, what are you doing? And we're, we don't know.
Speaker 5:  What was your plan? Like, like wind this all the way back for me. What was
Speaker 5:  the idea outcome to this story?
Speaker 3:  We
Speaker 4:  Did You have a projector
Speaker 3:  Still stuff. I don't know. High school. Racine, Wisconsin. We saw the reels
Speaker 3:  to Austin Paris too. We're like, now we'll have them. I was like
Speaker 3:  16 years old. It's, but it's burned into my brain how heavy
Speaker 3:  they were like, you know that oh this is a mistake.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But then you're too far in. Yeah. Is
Speaker 4:  There like a who as soon as you picked them up
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The second you pick 'em up Yeah. You're, it's already over. Even if
Speaker 3:  by simply trying to pick them up, you've, you've realized you've made
Speaker 3:  a horrible mistake.
Speaker 4:  Fun fact, the opening sequence for that movie is you
Speaker 4:  couldn't play it on, on Twitch now because they, they just Oh,
Speaker 3:  Just of the nudity rules. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  'cause of the implied nudity rule. And that's the whole first like second
Speaker 4:  chunk of the movie.
Speaker 3:  I, you know, it's probably for the best.
Speaker 4:  Where were you watching it now?
Speaker 3:  There's, there's a time and a place for the opening sequence of Austin Powers
Speaker 3:  two. And don don't know if it's Twitch, I, to be honest with
Speaker 3:  you. It's, it's on Bra Corps in 80 megabits per second. Crystal
Speaker 3:  clear Purestream. See
Speaker 4:  Every strand of Chest hair
Speaker 3:  Speaking of stealing things, the Kia boys are back. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And Kia has a new plan to stop them. So if you're aware of the Kia Boys,
Speaker 3:  you can, it's apparently very easy to steal many, many Kia and Hyundai
Speaker 3:  cars. So Kia is acknowledged this problem. They're getting sued by various
Speaker 3:  states who say Kia is negligent because they've made their cars too easy
Speaker 3:  to steal. Very funny outcome. A deeply funny
Speaker 3:  outcome. Kia is doing like software updates, Hyundai's doing software
Speaker 3:  updates. They're shipping out like, like steering wheel locks
Speaker 3:  like the club to people. It's all very funny. Now there're, in addition
Speaker 3:  to this, there's a press release. They're shipping out devices
Speaker 3:  to protect the ignition column. Incredible,
Speaker 3:  incredible line in this press release. This is a bullet under the headline
Speaker 3:  in bold device reinforces ignition cylinder body to
Speaker 3:  guard against theft methods popularized on social media.
Speaker 5:  Wow.
Speaker 3:  It's very good.
Speaker 5:  It's one of those things that you write and you're like, what has the world
Speaker 5:  become like, what are we doing here?
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 3:  Very good. And then in order to make it clear
Speaker 3:  to the Kia Boys that you've installed this device that are giving everybody
Speaker 3:  a sticker. So now your, your car can have a sticker that says
Speaker 3:  Stay away Kia Boys, boys. We have a device that reinforces
Speaker 3:  ignition cylinder body and stuff.
Speaker 5:  No chance whatsoever that that'll backfire. None.
Speaker 5:  That sticker will solve all of your problems. For
Speaker 3:  Sure. Another bullet in this press release, second wave of local
Speaker 3:  software upgrade clinics also planned in coordination with local Kia dealers
Speaker 3:  in key cities across the us
Speaker 3:  Yep. Software upgrade clinics at the Kia dealer. If you have a Kia on it,
Speaker 3:  go get your car fixed. 'cause the Kia boys are on the loose
Speaker 4:  Only park it in the garage.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's, there are Kias in my family and I have family members who are
Speaker 3:  like, I gotta get this thing in the garage. I'm like,
Speaker 5:  Nila, do you think if you were a teen right now you'd be a Kia boy? I feel
Speaker 5:  like there's like, like the same neli that is stealing Austin Power's. Two
Speaker 5:  reels is definitely out here. Being a Kia boy right
Speaker 5:  now,
Speaker 4:  Just be like, nah, take a car.
Speaker 3:  I think it is very good that I was not a teenager in the age of social media.
Speaker 3:  That's what I got for you. I think I would've,
Speaker 3:  I would've, I would've turned out differently. Fair. Probably in jail.
Speaker 3:  That seems like the most likely outcome of teenage Eli plus the internet.
Speaker 3:  All. right? That's it. We're way over as always. There was an extended
Speaker 3:  copyright loss segment for which I apologize. Nothing.
Speaker 3:  Zero apologies for that. And also zero apologies to the local
Speaker 3:  refrigerator factory, which would sponsor the lightning round immediately.
Speaker 3:  I like how they're turned into a local refrigerator factory. Yeah, just around
Speaker 3:  the corner.
Speaker 3:  I'm coming over there. We're gonna CSS next week. We'll have a
Speaker 3:  ton of coverage. I we have two Vergecast, right? Yep. At css. So
Speaker 3:  two Verge casts from CSS historically are craziest Vergecast of the year
Speaker 3:  because we're all sleep deprived. Just tons of coverage on the
Speaker 3:  site. CSS is where the year really kicks off. So I'm excited to go look at
Speaker 3:  some gadgets, see a bunch of people, do a bunch of reporting and obviously
Speaker 3:  talk to all of you on the Red Chest. So we'll see you next week at cs. That's
Speaker 3:  the Rich Chest rock roll.
Speaker 9:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 9:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The
Speaker 9:  Vergecast is a production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. The
Speaker 9:  show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed
Speaker 9:  and edited by Xander Adams. And that's it. We'll see you next week. We'll.