# Transcript
ID: 9fdcc7cd-e5e8-4ba5-bdd2-c4342fc05493
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-790081317567212073/-5078279979367184378/s93290-US-4448s-1733262735.mp3
Description: The Verge's Thomas Ricker joins the show with an update on his question to live the #vanlife. He shares stories about Starlink Mini, the new Peak Design backpack everyone loves, converting a Sprinter van to a mobile apartment, and more. Then, The Verge's Andru Marino takes us through his tests on a bunch of new creator- and social-friendly microphones, which plug into your phone and promise to make everything sound better. Finally, we answer a question about web browsers on the Vergecast Hotline.
(Don't forget to send us your questions about The Verge and The Vergecast for next week's episode! Call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com with all your most meta questions.)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast. Van
Speaker 2:  Toilets. I'm your friend David Pierce. And can I just complain about something
Speaker 2:  just for one quick second? When did video games become
Speaker 2:  homework? So it was just the Thanksgiving holiday in the United States, which
Speaker 2:  means I spent a few days mostly not in front of screens,
Speaker 2:  playing games with my family and reading. It was also my kids' birthday.
Speaker 2:  So we did a lot of birthday stuff and then I come back and I turn
Speaker 2:  on my switch to play some FIFA or EA sports FC whatever you
Speaker 2:  wanna call it. And it's like here's all the limited edition Black Friday
Speaker 2:  stuff that you missed and now everyone you play against is way ahead of you
Speaker 2:  because they got all these cool upgrades and things that you didn't because
Speaker 2:  you weren't on your console for 12 hours a day all weekend.
Speaker 2:  I generally love that video games are more multiplayer than ever and
Speaker 2:  are more sort of global than ever and that there are lots of different modes
Speaker 2:  and ways to compete and you're kind of doing other things against real people
Speaker 2:  all the time. But that comes now with this idea that you have to be
Speaker 2:  in it all the time or risk being left behind. I get why
Speaker 2:  the game companies do it. I hate it. I hate the feeling like I have
Speaker 2:  to be in a discord and I have to grind. People call it a grind. Now
Speaker 2:  video games are not supposed to be a grind. I
Speaker 2:  hate it. I'm going to keep doing it and I'm going to keep playing it because
Speaker 2:  ultimately I like the game. And the game is fun when you're good at it and
Speaker 2:  it's less fun when you're bad at it. And that is what these companies know
Speaker 2:  and it's how they get you. But it drives me nuts. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  that is not what we're here to talk about today. We are here to do two things.
Speaker 2:  We're back from Thanksgiving. We got lots to do. News is still happening,
Speaker 2:  lots to talk about. First we're gonna talk to Thomas Ricker, who is the verges,
Speaker 2:  I guess like unofficial Vanlife correspondent. He is gonna
Speaker 2:  tell us about his adventures with new outdoor batteries. He's tested a backpack.
Speaker 2:  A lot of people are really interested in. He tested starlink Mini, which
Speaker 2:  I have lots of questions about. He's gonna give us the rundown on all the
Speaker 2:  new stuff for kind of outdoor adventurous living. Then we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  to Andrew Marino about microphones. We've done a lot of these tests with
Speaker 2:  Andrew and I'm actually really excited about this one. He's been testing
Speaker 2:  some of the new creator mics, the DJI ones and the road ones. The ones that
Speaker 2:  you can just kind of clip to a collar and connect to your phone or your camera
Speaker 2:  that make it really easy to get good audio almost anywhere.
Speaker 2:  He has some really fun takeaways and I'm gonna quiz him and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna hear on some of how these actually sound.
Speaker 2:  The answer spoiler alert is don't use that stupid one that everybody uses
Speaker 2:  on TikTok, the like lapel mic that people just hold like this drives me nuts
Speaker 2:  as you're gonna hear. Sounds awful. Don't use it. We also have
Speaker 2:  a hotline about web browsers that I'm very excited about because as you know,
Speaker 2:  web browsers are near and dear to my heart. All of that is coming up in just
Speaker 2:  a second. But first. Even as I'm saying this, I realize I have to go play
Speaker 2:  FIFA now because there's like some stuff I need to get and some
Speaker 2:  XP I gotta get in order to catch up. So I'm gonna go finish that, get caught
Speaker 2:  up and then we're gonna get into it. This is The Vergecast, we'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 5:  roadmap of product features we've always wanted to add. So If, you can help
Speaker 5:  support us by signing up at The Verge dot com slash subs and If, you can't.
Speaker 5:  We'll do everything we can to earn your support in the future.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Alright, I have played some EA sports
Speaker 2:  fc, I've done my best. I still missed a bunch of stuff, but I'm
Speaker 2:  slightly caught up. I'm doing my best to not spend a lot of money inside
Speaker 2:  of this game, so help me stay strong and we will
Speaker 2:  aggressively lose to very good players together all the time. Alright,
Speaker 2:  let's get into it. First up, Vanlife Thomas Ricker was on the show
Speaker 2:  a while ago to talk about some of the gear that he's been using on his
Speaker 2:  adventures. Thomas is potentially the coolest person at The
Speaker 2:  Verge. He's always like on a Friday afternoon like, oh, I have to leave a
Speaker 2:  few minutes early, I'm going kite surfing for the weekend. Or like, oh, I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna be out of touch for nine days because I'm Glacier hiking or
Speaker 2:  whatever. He is forever on adventures and is
Speaker 2:  forever trying to find the right tech to take on his adventures. It's been
Speaker 2:  a minute since we caught up with him and he's also been reviewing a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch of interesting stuff, whether it's power sources or
Speaker 2:  batteries that go with those power sources or he did a really fun review
Speaker 2:  of some cooking gear on the site. He got a new Peak Design
Speaker 2:  backpack. People are excited about So I figured we'd just have him on and
Speaker 2:  run down some of what's new, what's made it into his setup, how he's feeling
Speaker 2:  about his adventures, what works, what doesn't, where we can go next. And
Speaker 2:  listen, I can't have his adventures. I'm not cool enough, but I
Speaker 2:  can live vicariously through Thomas. So that's what we're gonna do here.
Speaker 2:  Let's get into it. Thomas Ricker. Hello.
Speaker 4:  Hello. David Pierce. How are you doing?
Speaker 2:  I'm good. You are the only person. I think this is a fun question
Speaker 2:  to ask on a podcast, but where in the world are you right now?
Speaker 4:  Today I'm actually at home in Amsterdam. I am arranging to pick up my
Speaker 4:  van hopefully next week. I got a couple weeks off, had a lot of holiday
Speaker 4:  that accumulated by the end of the year. So hopefully I can
Speaker 4:  maybe disappear into the black forest of Germany. I don't know, we'll see
Speaker 4:  what happens.
Speaker 2:  Well, okay, I was gonna ask, do you have, are, is the van being worked on,
Speaker 2:  but this is where I actually wanna start. You haven't been on the show in
Speaker 2:  a while and the last time you were on, you just kind of gave us a
Speaker 2:  rundown of like your your vanlife gear and I have some stuff I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about. You've been reviewing a lot of gadgets, but mostly I just want to
Speaker 2:  get like a, a current picture of the setup. What's in your
Speaker 2:  van slash bag slash I don't know, bike
Speaker 2:  sack these days? What's new to the setup?
Speaker 4:  I'm not, man, I'm not even sure that we had bought the van last time we spoke,
Speaker 4:  but at the beginning of the summer we actually, I guess it was
Speaker 4:  in the spring, we pulled the trigger on a, on a kind of a lifelong dream.
Speaker 4:  We've been saving for a long time and we bought a
Speaker 4:  Mercedes-Benz Sprinter. It sounds fancy 'cause it's a
Speaker 4:  Mercedes-Benz, but this is basically the delivery truck that DHL uses and
Speaker 4:  everybody else here in, in Europe. It's a cargo van.
Speaker 4:  So I'm also old now. And while it was really
Speaker 4:  interesting the idea of rebuilding it myself, learning how to do that,
Speaker 4:  I don't have time to make a bunch of mistakes fair. I also don't have a
Speaker 4:  garage to do that work. So I farmed it out to a local van
Speaker 4:  builder. I've actually written a few stories with this guy. That's how I
Speaker 4:  met him. So just decided to, to hire him to,
Speaker 4:  to help with the build. But we're doing it in phases, that's why. So we did
Speaker 4:  a first phase. We traveled around Portugal and northern Spain for the summer.
Speaker 4:  That was like, that took a, a month or two to do that build and now it's
Speaker 4:  back to get it ready for winter. 'cause we want to take it like
Speaker 4:  park at a ski resort and just go snowboarding for a
Speaker 4:  few weeks. There's a, there's a certain amount of freedom and things you
Speaker 4:  can do. Hobbies, you can pursue If, you have your whole home with you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So that's kind of what we're doing.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So what's in this current build, like you said, getting it ready for
Speaker 2:  the winter. What does that actually entail?
Speaker 4:  So the big thing is getting the diesel heater set up.
Speaker 4:  Right now we're just using the, the, the standard heater that comes with
Speaker 4:  the Mercedes-Benz. It's a optional thing. Van builders, there's a, a
Speaker 4:  wide variety of heating options. You often do an aftermarket thing that you
Speaker 4:  stick under a seat. Ours comes standard or ours comes from
Speaker 4:  Mercedes. So it's nice 'cause you can use it from an app. You can like
Speaker 4:  turn it on when you're remote, you can have it running and you can monitor
Speaker 4:  the, the temperature while you're on the ski slopes, for example.
Speaker 4:  But we put a storage bench on top of it and inside that storage bench
Speaker 4:  is our toilet. So we have to properly route
Speaker 4:  that heating so it doesn't heat up our toilet too much
Speaker 2:  Because like a, like a warm toilet is a nice thing. A a two warm toilet
Speaker 2:  problems.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And this is small space and there are smell issues potentially.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, we're trying to, we're trying to do that. So that's what, that's
Speaker 4:  what he's doing and he says he is got it ready for a first test.
Speaker 4:  So I'll hopefully have that ready this weekend.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's really exciting. Is this, like, I would imagine the, the moment
Speaker 2:  you get the van for the winter is like a, like a real sort of
Speaker 2:  sending off on your voyage kind of moment, like setting sail on the ship
Speaker 2:  hundreds of years ago, kind of vibe.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and, and I'm brand new to this So I have a lot of questions. I mean
Speaker 4:  we, we, we put on these, these big rugged four by four off-road tires.
Speaker 4:  We have a lift kit on it, but like certain countries have certain
Speaker 4:  requirements for chains. Like do I need to put chains when I'm driving through
Speaker 4:  Austria? So there's just a lot of preparation that has to take
Speaker 4:  place to, to even get onto the road for the first time. But then
Speaker 4:  there's, it is also a matter of packing and unpacking. 'cause it is a small
Speaker 4:  amount of space for a van. It is a huge, what we call the garage. So all
Speaker 4:  that space for storage in the back. But now we're swapping out like our kite
Speaker 4:  surfing gear for snowboarding stuff. We have to figure out what to do
Speaker 4:  when the boots are wet and icy and snowy and how we can collect that
Speaker 4:  moisture that's gonna develop when things melt inside the van. What do we
Speaker 4:  store on the outside of the van? We also have cargo like attached to the
Speaker 4:  back, which looks really, really cool. I'm not sure how functional
Speaker 4:  it's gonna be yet, but we're gonna find out. Okay. Like, I don't know if
Speaker 4:  my, if like, do I put my boots back there? Are they gonna be frozen when
Speaker 4:  I pick them up in the morning? Do I have to keep those inside? So yeah, like
Speaker 4:  I said, I'm, I'm totally new to this. So it's a big learning curve, but there
Speaker 4:  are so many great forums and, and and a community as well
Speaker 4:  that's very willing to help.
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm struck by how much more sort of
Speaker 2:  straightforwardly practical a lot of this stuff is than I would think. Like,
Speaker 2:  I think when, when you, you see, you know, YouTube videos are like shows
Speaker 2:  that they've made over the years about making this kind of stuff and it's
Speaker 2:  all like cool flashy stuff that you can do and
Speaker 2:  interesting, like bells and whistles you can add to these things. But you're
Speaker 2:  talking about like heating and I, I was going back through a bunch of stories
Speaker 2:  you've written through this journey and you're like, you are obsessed with
Speaker 2:  how to power things and, and it's just, it's such a
Speaker 2:  simple thing but in the guise of what you're talking about, like, it, it's,
Speaker 2:  it's just so simple and straightforward and you're thinking a lot less about
Speaker 2:  like, do I use Alexa or do I use HomeKit? And you're just like,
Speaker 2:  where does the water go?
Speaker 4:  Oh, exactly. And like even on the electricity side, you have to decide are
Speaker 4:  you gonna do a 12 volt or 48 volt system? And the pros and cons of
Speaker 4:  that because there's weight limits. You go with the, the higher voltage and
Speaker 4:  you can do smaller gauge wires or is it higher gauge? I never can
Speaker 4:  remember anyways, the narrower cables and as a result you have less
Speaker 4:  weight and there's weight restrictions, at least in Europe. And so If, you
Speaker 4:  go over the weight, then suddenly you need a different kind of class of driver's
Speaker 4:  license. So there's a lot of small things you have to consider just to get
Speaker 4:  on the road and to then to keep everything powered. But yeah, water for
Speaker 4:  the winter, what do you do? So it doesn't freeze. Some, some people put these
Speaker 4:  giant water containers below their vans, or at least it's, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's in uninsulated parts of, of the van. And if it's
Speaker 4:  not heated, it's gonna freeze and then you don't have any water when you're
Speaker 4:  parked that. Yeah. It's just a tremendous amount you have to think about.
Speaker 4:  But for me it's fun. It's, it's like a, it's a massive puzzle and it's a
Speaker 4:  big learning curve, but it's all stuff. I mean it's tech, it's, it's all
Speaker 4:  stuff i I like to do anyways. Yeah. And the amount of gadgets that
Speaker 4:  I've uncovered through this, like I it's just a whole new playground
Speaker 4:  to explore.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I wanna talk about all of those, but let's talk about power first.
Speaker 2:  You, you, I know for years have been on this like, how do I do
Speaker 2:  battery solar power combinations in a way that
Speaker 2:  is like relatively cheap, relatively light and as effective as
Speaker 2:  possible. Is that a, is that, is that a good summation of, of the journey
Speaker 2:  here?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. And and stuff that you can reuse as well. Hmm. Because If, you
Speaker 4:  put it in one location and it's nice to be able to use it
Speaker 4:  somewhere else. 'cause if, like, you can have a, a system installed
Speaker 4:  in your house and wouldn't it be nice if If you disappear in your RV for
Speaker 4:  the summer that you can remove that? 'cause it's a huge investment and you
Speaker 4:  can put it in the RV and then you can reuse it there. So power is a, is a,
Speaker 4:  is a big thing that I believe is changing. I think there's a,
Speaker 4:  you have these, these dedicated, well I call them solar
Speaker 4:  generators, but anyways, they're giant batteries and they have
Speaker 4:  solar controllers. So you can attach a system of solar
Speaker 4:  panels onto your roof. You can do folding panels as well that you have
Speaker 4:  out, out on the side. But it's going to collect that and manage
Speaker 4:  the voltage properly. So it charges those batteries at the most optimum way
Speaker 4:  that it can. But these are all self-contained batteries.
Speaker 4:  The other route is to go with something in Van World, it's mostly from a
Speaker 4:  company called Viron Systems. And then you have, you need an electrician
Speaker 4:  or at least that level of knowledge to figure out yeah, all
Speaker 4:  the components that you need to hook up and all the wiring and everything
Speaker 4:  else. Now it's all self-contained in these boxes that are sold by EcoFlow
Speaker 4:  and Blue Eddie and a number of other companies that, I mean the,
Speaker 4:  the list is growing every day. Only problem is all these companies, all those,
Speaker 4:  some of them have us addresses that. Every one of 'em comes outta China because
Speaker 4:  those lithium ion battery packs, that's where everything is produced
Speaker 4:  and that's where all the solar panels are increasingly coming from.
Speaker 4:  The nice thing about that having all this capacity and, and all
Speaker 4:  this product is that the prices have been coming down, but now the
Speaker 4:  tariffs are being applied on top of that. So it's, it's, it's kind of
Speaker 4:  difficult, but at least at the moment, historically the prices are way cheaper
Speaker 4:  for batteries and solar than ever. Solar is way more efficient. So
Speaker 4:  I, instead of doing these piecemeal systems, like from the companies like
Speaker 4:  Viron systems, I think the way to go is to get these self-contained boxes.
Speaker 4:  These solar generators, you can use it at home. Like
Speaker 4:  EcoFlow makes a a, a balcony solar system.
Speaker 4:  So when you're home you can have it charging and pumping energy back into
Speaker 4:  the house. Now that's a controversial thing. It is, at
Speaker 4:  least in most of Europe, it is considered safe within limits. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  I think they go up to between 600 and 800 watts. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's legal. Okay. 'cause they just plug right into your electrical
Speaker 4:  socket on in your house. Oh wow. So it seems super weird, but yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's, that's
Speaker 2:  A bold thing to just plug into the wall.
Speaker 4:  It felt really bad. When I, and I asked lots and lots of questions. I talked
Speaker 4:  to all my engineering friends and my electrician friends and they said, oh,
Speaker 4:  it should be okay. And it's, it's approved So, I did it slowly, but
Speaker 4:  then, but anyways, but then, you know, you can have it charging at home.
Speaker 4:  You have that big battery. 'cause those batteries are like 50 cents to, you
Speaker 4:  know, between 50 and 70 cents per watt hour. And they're
Speaker 4:  like, the one that I'm testing right now in the van is eight
Speaker 4:  kilowatt hours. Wow. So that's a $5,000 battery.
Speaker 4:  You, you don't want that just sitting idle. You wanna be able to use that
Speaker 4:  as much as you can. So it's here in the house when,
Speaker 4:  you know, connected to a balcony system when, you know, when I'm at home
Speaker 4:  and then when I'm in the van, I can just wheel it outta the house. It's not
Speaker 4:  light, it's like a hundred pounds or more, but then I can put it in the van
Speaker 4:  and continue to use it. Then If, you get one of these vicn systems, it's
Speaker 4:  just stuck in the van all the time. And yeah, that's not ideal.
Speaker 2:  And that does seem like a good outcome actually, to have something that is
Speaker 2:  sort of scalable in the way that you're describing. Like, I feel like for
Speaker 2:  you, the white whale is then to be able to take sort of one part out of that
Speaker 2:  system and put it in a backpack for your weekend. And I feel like all of
Speaker 2:  the stories about this stuff that I see you, you writing outta, like that's
Speaker 2:  the one piece that's missing where you're like, they've done this thing that
Speaker 2:  I can, it can, it can heat a room, it works on electricity, it's great,
Speaker 2:  it is too damn big to carry with you anywhere. And it's like that, that is
Speaker 2:  the one sort of magical piece of this system that still seems to be missing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The, the physics of of needing giant
Speaker 4:  I think it's, it's like 20 euro a month really. So yeah. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's by region and you know, everybody said that, you know, it's now, now
Speaker 4:  available in the US Those are the news, those are the headlines. But it had
Speaker 4:  already been in South American countries. I think there were five countries
Speaker 4:  before the US 'cause that's their primary market for the many. Right, right.
Speaker 4:  So it's priced accordingly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. Alright. Two more things I wanna ask you about and then I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  let you go here. The first is the Peak Design backpack that
Speaker 2:  you ended. Love it. For years, like years,
Speaker 2:  every bag nerd I knew talked about the Peak Design
Speaker 2:  25 liter backpack. It was like just enough of a
Speaker 2:  camera first bag that I never bought one, but I feel like
Speaker 2:  I should have. And now there's a new one. Everybody seems to love it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Tell me about it. Why is this thing so great?
Speaker 4:  Oh, I, I ran, I ran into the problem of going
Speaker 4:  back to my review from eight years ago and I called it perfect. Right?
Speaker 4:  And eight years ago it was perfect for me. Yeah, it was perfect for my
Speaker 4:  needs. But as we've been talking about, I like to go remote now
Speaker 4:  and I can't carry two or three different bags with me. I need
Speaker 4:  one bag that can do everything. The Peak Design, the new bag, the old bag
Speaker 4:  is, is a camera bag. So it's heavy, it's durable.
Speaker 4:  It has the, all the camera, the flexible inserts already built into it, right?
Speaker 4:  The new bag, which by the way, the review unit they sent me is in
Speaker 4:  white, Arctic white. And it looks like I'm walking through, I don't know,
Speaker 4:  2001 a Space Odyssey. It's this sci-fi white color. It's just fantastic.
Speaker 4:  Totally imp practical. It's pretty, yeah, it's, I would never, maybe
Speaker 4:  I would buy it. Verin bought it, our video producer, he bought it.
Speaker 4:  I don't know if I would
Speaker 2:  The fact that even the company is like, eh, it's gonna turn yellow over time
Speaker 2:  is is a real, is a real turnoff for me. I'm not gonna lie. It looks great
Speaker 2:  when you first get it though. It looks so good. It looks
Speaker 4:  Fantastic, but, okay, so first impressions, it,
Speaker 4:  it, it lacks that structure of the old, of the old bag. So
Speaker 4:  it took me a while to get to figure out what this thing was. 'cause it, it's
Speaker 4:  a, it's a, it's basically a lightweight nylon bag with a laptop sleeve.
Speaker 4:  And it's not until you delve into the ecosystem of Peak Design products
Speaker 4:  that this thing becomes really good because
Speaker 4:  sometimes you only want that lightweight nylon bag. Like if you're going
Speaker 4:  to the gym, you stuff some things in there. You have a maybe a day trip day
Speaker 4:  hike, you're only bringing maybe a drone. It already has its own protective
Speaker 4:  case. So you can use that. But if you're really a camera
Speaker 4:  nerd or you got lots of gadgets, you got all the, maybe you're carrying a
Speaker 4:  drone action cam and some other stuff. They have the, the
Speaker 4:  camera insert camera cubes is what they call them. But
Speaker 4:  that's another like the medium as they call it. It's not quite small, not
Speaker 4:  quite medium. But the s medium and it fits perfect in the 25 liter Peak Design
Speaker 4:  outdoor bag that is another 70 euro on top of
Speaker 4:  the, I forget what it was, 230 something So I.
Speaker 2:  Think it's two 50. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  You're already up to 300 and then If, you start adding a couple more accessories.
Speaker 4:  You could easily push this thing up to 400 euro. So it's not cheap. But
Speaker 4:  camera bags are not cheap.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say it's the, in the scheme of really good camera bags, that's
Speaker 2:  like upper middle class I've seen much crazier
Speaker 4:  Exactly. Prices. And they do have a lifetime warranty. So if anything breaks,
Speaker 4:  any of the straps, any of those things, the yellow wing is not covered. If,
Speaker 4:  you get the white one. Unfortunately it comes in black and some kind of purplish
Speaker 4:  color. But using it for God, I had it
Speaker 4:  for two months 'cause there was some complications of receiving it and whatnot.
Speaker 4:  And I also wanted to wait before posting it until it got off the Kickstarter
Speaker 4:  campaign. 'cause I hate sending people to Kickstarter for a purchase fair.
Speaker 4:  But the day that it went live on, on the Peak Design website is when we posted
Speaker 4:  a review and I had been using it for, I don't know,
Speaker 4:  yeah. Two months at that point. And I absolutely love it.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely love it. So I feel really bad about like,
Speaker 4:  like I, I can't pull the trigger myself 'cause I feel like I'm betraying
Speaker 4:  my old Peak Design bag that I bought. So I, I, I put
Speaker 4:  it on my Christmas list and then I'll let hopefully my wife do it for me.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So the the modular thing is the thing I was most torn on
Speaker 2:  reading your review. 'cause on the one hand, the thing you're describing
Speaker 2:  sort of makes sense, right? You can, it can be a bunch of different things
Speaker 2:  depending on what you need. On the other hand, that just sounds like a lot
Speaker 2:  of work. And I feel like what, what I don't wanna do is like manage my
Speaker 2:  cargo day in and day out. Like the, the thing I have loved about bags that
Speaker 2:  I've had is the ones that I find that on purpose or by accident just
Speaker 2:  already have the pouches for everything I need. Where they're like, oh David,
Speaker 2:  do you need a place to put your gross sneakers? Here's a place that we made
Speaker 2:  for you. Like, those are the things that I love and I can see the appeal
Speaker 2:  of sort of building that yourself, but it also just feels like it might be
Speaker 2:  a lot of work. And like you said, a lot of additional things to buy on top
Speaker 2:  of the expensive thing that I've already bought.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I I mean that's a good point. But I, what I, what I settled
Speaker 4:  on is like, I don't always need all my camera stuff. I don't need my, all
Speaker 4:  my drones. So if I can have a
Speaker 4:  container for that, a soft shell container put everything in, it's already
Speaker 4:  organized for me. And I just remove that in and out. And I always know where
Speaker 4:  all my tech gear and this is really important when you're in a van 'cause
Speaker 4:  you have to know where all that stuff is. Yeah. So for me, I can just take
Speaker 4:  that cube out, I can put it aside, I then take the bag and I can just load
Speaker 4:  it up with, with all my day hiking material. Or I can put it back
Speaker 4:  in if I'm doing a, like a VERGE review or something, I'll put that in with
Speaker 4:  all my other stuff. So for me that modularity was, was a key selling
Speaker 4:  point. So
Speaker 2:  You you think of it like the, the camera lives in the cube all the time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then you just sort of stack whatever cubes you need for that day
Speaker 2:  into the bag.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. And you can get multiple cubes. It actually fits two different cubes.
Speaker 4:  And they also have soft shell bags that you can store
Speaker 4:  gear in If, you want If you wanna do that. But again, If you, if
Speaker 4:  you're, yeah, if you're, if you're living in a van, you want to, everything
Speaker 4:  is kind of modular anyway. So fair. It's a, it's a, it's a nice
Speaker 4:  extension for the bag. Okay. But for, for my needs, this is now a
Speaker 4:  better bag. I felt bad calling it perfect. 'cause it's, I've got a lot of,
Speaker 4:  I'm always gonna have lots of complaints. Like I, the the drawstring that
Speaker 4:  that pulls the top pouch closed is, I think it's a bit inelegant.
Speaker 4:  The cord get in the way when you're pulling a jacket in and out or whatever.
Speaker 4:  But you know, you're looking for perfection when you're spending 300 euro
Speaker 4:  or $300 on a bag.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Yeah. That's fair. All right. And you, you mentioned the last
Speaker 2:  thing I wanna talk about, which is that you've become a drone guy.
Speaker 4:  I am not a drone guy. I am a selfie drone guy. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay.
Speaker 4:  I tried drones in the past and I, nobody seems to talk about how bad
Speaker 4:  DJI software is. I think it's atrocious. I think the user experience is
Speaker 4:  just terrible. But drone people have been living with these drones
Speaker 4:  for a long time. They understand how the software works.
Speaker 2:  I think it's like Photoshop now where it's like If, you don't, if you've
Speaker 2:  never seen it before, it is literally borderline
Speaker 2:  unusable. But there are people now who have spent a long time
Speaker 2:  trying to figure it out. But also, one of my theories is that DJI figured
Speaker 2:  out a long time ago that it was easier to teach the drones to fly themselves
Speaker 2:  than it was to make better software. So they've just done that. So they're
Speaker 2:  like, their hope is that you just don't even have to use the app because
Speaker 2:  the drone is fine. Don't even worry about it,
Speaker 4:  Man. I mean, that's the thing. So I, I went, I did a bike packing trick
Speaker 4:  trip this summer with a friend of mine and you know, I don't want to, I see
Speaker 4:  DC rainmaker and people, they've got the controller mounted on their handlebars
Speaker 4:  and they're, you know, they're, they're talking to, they're doing all this
Speaker 4:  stuff all the time. But he's, he's been doing this stuff for, I don't know,
Speaker 4:  a decade.
Speaker 4:  I just want something super simple. I push a button, set it up to fly and
Speaker 4:  then it'll fill me. Right. And this also works for gadgets. Like if I have
Speaker 4:  to do a backpack, some of my backpack photos are, are taken by drones. 'cause
Speaker 4:  you know, I can either ask my wife to do it. She does, she's not a huge fan
Speaker 4:  of that. Or a friend or I just do it myself and I'd rather just be
Speaker 4:  self-sufficient and do it, do it myself. But no
Speaker 4:  controller required it just select between one of six modes. If I want to,
Speaker 4:  I can tweak it in the, in the, in the app. But it's very rare that I have
Speaker 4:  to do that. And now we have two of these really great selfie drones.
Speaker 4:  There's the, the original Hover air, I guess it's not even the original,
Speaker 4:  it's like second generation hover air X one. They just came out with two
Speaker 4:  new ones. Maxim Pro, I think they are, but now they're really expensive.
Speaker 4:  The nice thing about the old ones, I think they were
Speaker 4:  2 99, 3 9, 3 49 or something, depending
Speaker 4:  upon the sales. But this DJI neo that just came out now, it
Speaker 4:  was a little undercooked when they launched it. Like you couldn't do vertical
Speaker 4:  video. It wasn't fast enough to chase you on a bike, for example.
Speaker 4:  But they've recently, just in the two or three months since it launched,
Speaker 4:  they've already updated the firmware to do all those things and it only
Speaker 4:  costs $199, which is insane. And
Speaker 4:  you can buy a controller If you want and you can buy goggles, If, you wanna
Speaker 4:  do, what is it first FPV, first person viewing?
Speaker 4:  I don't know what that's called. I, I don't care about that. I have no interest
Speaker 4:  in doing that. I just want something that's going to, you know, follow me,
Speaker 4:  take pictures, upload it to Instagram or whatever, you know, maybe I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  have a vanlife influencer account at some point, who knows? But it's just
Speaker 4:  dumb. It's so dumb. It's so easy. It just makes me love it. But
Speaker 4:  as soon as you, I have to use a controller, I'm out. I'm done.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I have landed in the same place and I actually, I sort of turned
Speaker 2:  out of drones for a long time because it was just more complicated
Speaker 2:  than it was fun for me. And it was like, I didn't have a purpose for it.
Speaker 2:  I even, even the photography of it was just purely sort of fun.
Speaker 2:  I wasn't doing anything with any of it. And it got to the point where I was
Speaker 2:  like, this is so fiddly. And so yeah, just annoying that
Speaker 2:  even the fun stuff I get out of it is not, the juice is not worth the squeeze,
Speaker 2:  you know, know. And then, yeah, this is why I'm so interested in the neo,
Speaker 2:  because like you said, $200 and does a bunch of
Speaker 2:  cool stuff without any worries or requiring
Speaker 2:  any work on your part. That to me is like when drones start to get really
Speaker 2:  interesting. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I do worry. I think, I think the headline on the, on the news article was
Speaker 4:  basically, oh God, these things are gonna be everywhere. I do think that
Speaker 4:  there's this, there's this risk that we're just gonna
Speaker 4:  pollute national parks and whatever with these selfie drones and they are
Speaker 4:  noisy, right? Yeah. You can't get away from it and they're gonna bump into
Speaker 4:  people If, you pass somebody on a trail, like I've, I've come close to passing
Speaker 4:  somebody on a trail on a bike. I had to stop, pull over, but then the drones
Speaker 4:  just hovering there right above the, right, above the trail. And I had to
Speaker 4:  run over and grab it and flip it over. And I'm just one guy at the beginning.
Speaker 4:  But what's gonna happen when after Christmas, you know,
Speaker 4:  everybody's got a 1 99 Neo and they're flooding
Speaker 4:  the parks and the ski slopes and whatever, and there this weird gray area
Speaker 4:  of regulation, they're probably illegal, but it doesn't
Speaker 4:  feel like it's illegal. Like I'm not do, I'm just pushing a button. I set
Speaker 4:  a lt, right. It doesn't feel like a huge risk, but, and then yeah, I mean
Speaker 4:  you, well in Europe it's complicated as you're traveling between countries.
Speaker 4:  Do you, do I have to register or do I not? But
Speaker 4:  yeah, it's sometimes though the technology comes along before the regulation
Speaker 4:  is ready and then this is definitely gonna be one of those cases. I I, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it is, it is both more and less complicated than like the bigger
Speaker 2:  drones that you can fly further, right? Where like those, we should
Speaker 2:  have lots of rules about those, right? Like I can fly this drone
Speaker 2:  theoretically miles away from me. Like yet we should have lots of rules about
Speaker 2:  those drones. But this thing that is just circling my head as I go on a bike
Speaker 2:  path, you're right. It doesn't feel, that just feels like a thing that I
Speaker 2:  have that doesn't feel like a thing anyone else even needs to be worried
Speaker 2:  about. But you add one of those to every person you see on the path.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And suddenly we have a whole new set of problems and it I do agree,
Speaker 2:  it does feel like that's coming.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they do go fast. Now the once, now that the neo
Speaker 4:  software has been updated, it'll go like 32 kilometers per hour. I think
Speaker 4:  that is in, that's like over 20 miles per hour I believe.
Speaker 2:  That's like fast for sure.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And if that's following you and slams into somebody that, that you're
Speaker 4:  passing, that is a collision that's gonna hurt. Even though the props are
Speaker 4:  covered with guards, it's, it's gonna hurt. Yeah. So yeah, there's a, there's
Speaker 4:  a risk here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Fair enough. All right, well I should let you go, but once you've,
Speaker 2:  once you've done this winter tour with the sprinter, you gotta, you gotta
Speaker 2:  come back and give us a, give us a sprinter review.
Speaker 4:  Got, if I survive, I absolutely will.
Speaker 2:  Maybe we'll do it from the top of a ski slope and you can just, you can just
Speaker 2:  write off that whole trip as a work expense. It'll be amazing. I'll
Speaker 4:  Have a starlink mini and a backpack and the drone hovering
Speaker 2:  now that you don't even really notice them, even though it's like a giant
Speaker 2:  square plastic brick on someone's chest as they talk to you. But
Speaker 2:  these things are also really useful. We use them for VERGE cast things all
Speaker 2:  the time. We use them for our video team all the time. So Andrew put all
Speaker 2:  these to the test and I figured now would be a good time to have him come
Speaker 2:  on and both play a little bit for us and we can see how it all sounds
Speaker 2:  and decide which one of these is actually worth, you know,
Speaker 2:  sticking onto your chest when you two are making videos. Let's get into it.
Speaker 2:  Andrew Marino, welcome back to the show.
Speaker 6:  Hey David,
Speaker 2:  It's been a minute. It's nice to have you back on the first cast. Yeah, what's
Speaker 6:  Up?
Speaker 2:  You left us rudely to go make videos about microphones
Speaker 2:  and now I've brought you back because this is what happens to you. You can't
Speaker 2:  avoid us forever.
Speaker 6:  It's a full circle.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. So, okay, I realized in just recording the
Speaker 2:  intro for this that I don't even know what to call this like class of
Speaker 2:  microphones that you've been testing here. So like what, what are these things?
Speaker 2:  How do you think about these mics?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they're like wireless microphone systems for your phone. It's like
Speaker 6:  consumer grade wireless microphone systems. That's pretty good. We've had
Speaker 6:  wireless microphone systems and broadcasting and video production now
Speaker 6:  it's a lot easier. Just use it plugging into your phone or your, whatever
Speaker 6:  your little computers are.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Do you remember years ago when I think it was sure made that thing
Speaker 2:  that actually plugged into the lightning port and had that little like flippy
Speaker 2:  microphone Yes. That you could, I loved that thing. I used that thing every
Speaker 2:  day. I
Speaker 6:  Still have it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I still have it here. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I love it. It sounded great. Yeah, it really
Speaker 2:  Did. And it was like as a, as a like voice memo thing. It was, it was great.
Speaker 2:  I remember I did a thing with NPR one time on the phone and they
Speaker 2:  were so excited about how good I sounded and I was like, it was like the
Speaker 2:  great reveal of my life that I got to tell a public radio producer that I
Speaker 2:  was on this incredible Sure microphone. But anyway, so what I
Speaker 2:  see these microphones mostly used for is like social
Speaker 2:  clips, right? These are like the, the like little plastic squares you
Speaker 2:  see on everyone's shirt and sweater and hat all over social. Is that the
Speaker 2:  main use case for these?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, totally. Like we wouldn't, these companies wouldn't be making all these
Speaker 6:  if it weren't for TikTok and Instagram and all that
Speaker 2:  And they've gotten better pretty fast it seems
Speaker 2:  to me. Yes.
Speaker 6:  With even just within the year these companies like Road and DJI
Speaker 6:  are just upgrading these models to be lighter
Speaker 6:  or like have more features, have better charging cases.
Speaker 6:  It's all very exciting. Like this past two years of, of audio
Speaker 6:  devices.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's cool. So yeah, what is kind of the state of the art right now?
Speaker 2:  Like you, you got five or six of them in, what do they have in common? Like
Speaker 2:  what's the good stuff you can get now?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the big ones are like, these are coming in like
Speaker 6:  AirPod cases. Basically. You have these little transmitters that
Speaker 6:  have mics on them, you pop 'em in a little case and then
Speaker 6:  you have a little receiver that you pop right into your phone. So
Speaker 6:  Road just came out with a road wireless micro
Speaker 6:  that is just a, it's like a little bigger than an AirPods case and it plugs
Speaker 6:  right into your phone. I really like that one. Sure. Also makes one,
Speaker 6:  that's a little case that you can just pair via Bluetooth to your
Speaker 6:  phone. And DGI of course has the
Speaker 6:  MIC two and the MIC mini, which are these little
Speaker 6:  microphones that you can plug into basically anything. So it's all
Speaker 6:  like very versatile and pretty well
Speaker 6:  made versus what we are having to deal with before with
Speaker 6:  Bluetooth headphones and stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean I, I have a set here that is like a, a
Speaker 2:  thing that plugs into a headphone jack that my phone doesn't have anymore
Speaker 2:  and then a, a whole receiver and it's like, there's like four
Speaker 2:  cables associated with it. It's just a bad time. It sounds good, but it is
Speaker 2:  like I had to carry a bag of gear just to get this thing right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a lot, it was a lot clunkier before and it's getting more
Speaker 6:  easier to just like not have to tie a rubber band around your phone
Speaker 6:  to keep all this gear attached to your stuff.
Speaker 2:  What about on the phone side? Are, do these all have like companion apps
Speaker 2:  or are they just supposed to be better microphones? I've always been torn
Speaker 2:  about like do I want a bunch of fancy features or do I just want this thing
Speaker 2:  to pretend to be my microphone on my phone and just
Speaker 2:  sound better?
Speaker 6:  Yes. This is where the differences come in here. DGI
Speaker 6:  has all their wireless microphones. You can
Speaker 6:  do a lot of the customization like gain and, and turning
Speaker 6:  on noise cancellation through just the
Speaker 6:  hardware receiver road, their little
Speaker 6:  micro wireless microphone. You can only control the gain
Speaker 6:  and all that stuff through the app. They also have like a
Speaker 6:  video app that they want you to use when you're making
Speaker 6:  video with these things. The video doesn't look as good as the
Speaker 6:  native iPhone app when I was trying it, which was
Speaker 6:  concerning.
Speaker 2:  That also just seems instinctively kind of weird. The idea that I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  make videos in an app based on which microphone I'm using
Speaker 2:  just feels like the wrong order of operations of how I'm going to
Speaker 2:  do stuff.
Speaker 6:  Totally. And if also if you're making this stuff within these video
Speaker 6:  creation apps like TikTok and Instagram, like you don't want to
Speaker 6:  go back and forth between apps to like, like adjust the gain and all that,
Speaker 2:  You know? Yeah, yeah. The thing you described about having some of the controls
Speaker 2:  on the case itself feels like the right one, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If the receiver that you just plug in the bottom of your phone, you
Speaker 6:  can adjust the gain on this little knob on the DJI mic mini. And
Speaker 6:  so when you're recording, say within the TikTok app, you can adjust the game
Speaker 6:  from there and you don't have to switch apps or anything like that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that is really handy. So let's just, let's just cut right to the chase
Speaker 2:  here. Which one's the best? You've tested them all, everybody expected
Speaker 2:  you to not pick one in the video. This is, this is my favorite thing about
Speaker 2:  the video you made is you just ruthlessly trolled everyone on the
Speaker 2:  internet who refuses to just pick winners who won.
Speaker 6:  Yes. So when we factor in price and audio quality and
Speaker 6:  functionality,
Speaker 6:  state that there, I went with the DGI, Mike Mini, which
Speaker 6:  has this nice carrying case and the mics are
Speaker 6:  really tiny now. So when you clip 'em on your shirt, they're
Speaker 6:  not as noticeable as those big squares you notice on, on all these
Speaker 6:  videos. So, I really like that, the compactness and
Speaker 6:  it is $170, which is, you know,
Speaker 6:  compared to a lot of these they go up to in 350 range. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I think sure is. The whole package is $500.
Speaker 6:  So price, audio quality and functionality like
Speaker 6:  DJI, mc, Minney was really impressive.
Speaker 2:  How small is it, like you, you, you've mentioned, you mentioned that it's
Speaker 2:  small, it's, that matters more to me than I expected.
Speaker 2:  Having now used these a lot, I notice every
Speaker 2:  like percentage of an ounce 'cause it just, it just like pulls on your shirt
Speaker 2:  and they, they seem huge. Like how small are we talking that
Speaker 2:  this thing has actually gotten?
Speaker 6:  Yes. So it's about half the size as they were before. And
Speaker 6:  the thing also is like a lot of these you could just tuck underneath
Speaker 6:  your shirt and then use the magnet without a clip to just
Speaker 6:  hold onto your shirt that way. I never really liked doing that because you,
Speaker 6:  you have to deal with rust, your clothes rustling and all that. And it gets
Speaker 6:  a little muffled. So, I always like keeping them outside of the clothes,
Speaker 6:  like in the open air. So, which is why I don't
Speaker 6:  usually like the bigger ones. Right. I usually would like to prefer
Speaker 6:  to plug in a external wireless lavalier. Sometimes that
Speaker 6:  gets a little annoying. We did a whole video shoot in, we went from
Speaker 6:  San Francisco to LA in our hydrogen car if VERGE listeners
Speaker 6:  may remember, we talked to a lot of car drivers that
Speaker 6:  were like going in to pump their gas and we wanted to talk to them really
Speaker 6:  quickly. And I just wanted like, here put, I need to put this on your shirt
Speaker 6:  really quickly. And like a lot of If, you look at the video, a lot of them
Speaker 6:  have these big chunky squares on their shirt. And now that the
Speaker 6:  DJI ones are a lot smaller, it's less noticeable. You know,
Speaker 6:  it's just a little, it's not distracting in the video.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it is, I will say all a huge improvement over what it
Speaker 2:  was before, which is snaking a a wire up,
Speaker 2:  someone's back and yeah, you as the producer having to say, sorry, I just
Speaker 2:  have to reach up your shirt for a second here and I'm gonna touch your butt
Speaker 2:  while I clip this thing to it. And it is very good that we,
Speaker 2:  we seem to be leaving those days behind.
Speaker 6:  Yes, I have done that in a traditional broadcast setting
Speaker 6:  and it is very awkward experience.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's not a good time. So you, you mentioned that
Speaker 2:  the, the DJI is kind of the best combination of things. Are there,
Speaker 2:  does it have competitors that beat it in one way or another? Like if all
Speaker 2:  I care about is pure, raw best sound, don't care. What else? Is it
Speaker 2:  somebody other than DJI who wins?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Okay. I would like to just mention now I'm currently
Speaker 6:  recording with the DJI Mike Mini for this whole
Speaker 6:  recording. Okay. So the one that I really like,
Speaker 6:  and it's a company that is known for its audio quality is Sennheiser.
Speaker 6:  They just came out with this thing called the Profile Wireless.
Speaker 6:  It's, it is just a big like stick
Speaker 6:  audio thing, but you can just press this little, there's a little
Speaker 6:  button. It has all these little receivers in
Speaker 6:  here that you could just clip on. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Clever. So the, the thing you're holding looks like a sort of
Speaker 2:  chunky handheld microphone. Yeah. And you can use it as that. Yes. It sounds
Speaker 2:  like If you want to, but then you can also just pull the little receiver
Speaker 2:  out and clip it on.
Speaker 6:  Yep. And then you can Yeah, the transmitter
Speaker 2:  Or the transmitter, yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then you can pop the receiver out too. Plug
Speaker 6:  that right into your phone and Sennheiser
Speaker 6:  that one was the best audio quality to me. Okay. It also has, one of
Speaker 6:  my favorite features on these is a backup recording button. So you can
Speaker 6:  just press this little red button on the device,
Speaker 6:  on the transmitter and it will record the audio locally onto
Speaker 6:  the mic. Oh,
Speaker 2:  That's helpful.
Speaker 6:  So you don't have to go through wireless,
Speaker 6:  you know, run into any issues with signal to noise
Speaker 6:  ratios and all that and it's perfectly there If you, something happens on
Speaker 6:  your recorder, you have this backup recording that's actually helped me
Speaker 6:  so many times in, in these kinds of situations.
Speaker 2:  I was just about to say, I had not thought about this until you just mentioned
Speaker 2:  that, but the problem I've had with these microphones over the years, including
Speaker 2:  all the way back to that, that sure one that I could plug into my phone was
Speaker 2:  sometimes my phone just wouldn't use it.
Speaker 2:  I would, I would press record on something and it would just pick a different
Speaker 2:  microphone to record from and I, and I wouldn't notice until afterwards because
Speaker 2:  the thing was connected. It all seemed to be working, but then it was like
Speaker 2:  I opened voice memos and hit record and the wrong mic picks up and
Speaker 2:  you're just sort of hosed because phones are not very good at like
Speaker 2:  giving you a, a menu to tell you when it's switching from microphone to microphone.
Speaker 2:  Has that gotten better in general? Like are phones better at this game than
Speaker 2:  they used to be?
Speaker 6:  I think so. Okay. I was very skeptical of this as like the
Speaker 6:  iPhone is like, it's hard to, when you're
Speaker 6:  in the phone app or the camera app, it's hard to like
Speaker 6:  know what audio source you're using. Right. So you kind of just have to trust
Speaker 6:  it, recognized it. Android is better at this so you can actually like choose
Speaker 6:  the audio source. But I was always scared of that
Speaker 6:  So, I would always use an external, like another app to confirm because
Speaker 6:  you know, the Roads app will tell you what specifically the
Speaker 6:  interface you're using is. But it has, phones have gotten a lot better at
Speaker 6:  this. That being said, phones microphones have gotten a lot better that
Speaker 6:  in general. So there's that too.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's actually a good question. How do you feel like these
Speaker 2:  compare? Obviously there's a usability difference where you don't have to
Speaker 2:  hold your phone up to your face, which goes a really long way. But in terms
Speaker 2:  of audio quality, you're right that the internal microphone
Speaker 2:  on your phone, If, you have a recent high-end phone is
Speaker 2:  probably very good. Are these still kind of like a, like
Speaker 2:  a full level or two up from that even as they get smaller and cheaper
Speaker 2:  and easier to use?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, totally. I think so there's, there's some plus and minuses like, and
Speaker 6:  smartphones, you get stereo recording a lot. So If, you
Speaker 6:  really want like an ambient track when you're like
Speaker 6:  recording a scene with your phone. That I like using that
Speaker 6:  stereo recording sometimes. But there is some, a lot of color,
Speaker 6:  especially the iPhone. There's a lot like brighter sounding,
Speaker 6:  like it's a lot of high end in the recordings. It's a little less
Speaker 6:  controllable. So I in general, like especially Sennheiser
Speaker 6:  insurer, like they've been developing this technology for so long. So
Speaker 6:  they do sound a lot better than the traditional just holding your phone
Speaker 6:  up to your face, especially in post-production. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Are these companies doing something different with these
Speaker 2:  mics because of the way that they're gonna be used? I mean, you know, Sennheiser
Speaker 2:  and Road and all these other companies make other microphones. I'm on a,
Speaker 2:  I'm on a sure mic on a road stand right now recording this. So they all know
Speaker 2:  how to make like a high-end microphone. But these are like you're saying
Speaker 2:  at the beginning, sort of a very specific thing for a very specific use case
Speaker 2:  as you test them. Can you tell these are like designed to be used on
Speaker 2:  TikTok in some meaningful way?
Speaker 6:  Not, not really. Okay. I mean more when you looking at the,
Speaker 6:  the app side of it, but these are all like omnidirectional
Speaker 6:  microphones that, you know, lavaliers on like any,
Speaker 6:  you know, live set have been using for, for decades. So
Speaker 6:  there's not much different for that. It is like, because
Speaker 6:  you're moving around and you're outside and you wanna make sure it's, you
Speaker 6:  know, it's on your shirt, it's getting you when you're turning your head
Speaker 6:  and all that. So it's more like the performance side of it.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. Yeah. I, I do wonder how much they're learning to
Speaker 2:  do to compensate for people who don't have a ton of experience
Speaker 2:  using mics who are suddenly clipping mics to themselves. Sure. And like the
Speaker 2:  thing you just said about being able to sort of swivel your head is like
Speaker 2:  that's a big one, right? You most people have terrible mic technique and
Speaker 2:  understanding how to talk into a microphone is a thing that takes real practice.
Speaker 2:  And so for something like this, like I would assume a lot of these companies
Speaker 2:  are spending time trying to think about, okay, what weird places are people
Speaker 2:  going to stick this and how are they gonna use it and how can we
Speaker 2:  account for that? And, and again, I think it makes sense that a lot of that
Speaker 2:  is going into the software and stuff that's actually being built into phones.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, totally. Like there's 32 bit float, which is like
Speaker 6:  recording at a bit rate that is gonna prevent you from
Speaker 6:  clipping audio, which is a big problem
Speaker 6:  in like any microphone where you're not Yeah. You're not
Speaker 6:  monitoring the levels of these microphones with your headphones or even
Speaker 6:  seeing levels on some on any of these. There's that and then there's also
Speaker 6:  the noise cancellation, So I, I should have mentioned that like DJI has a
Speaker 6:  noise softener basically will take a lot of the background
Speaker 6:  noise out, which you know, is something you're not gonna be going in
Speaker 6:  your computer and trying to dial down if you're just going into
Speaker 6:  TikTok most of the time.
Speaker 2:  Right. Not everybody has a you to make everything sound incredible all the
Speaker 2:  time. I highly recommend it by the way, If, you can have an Andrew
Speaker 2:  to do it. I recommend having an Andrew. Let's, I I want to
Speaker 2:  hear a couple of these and, and test them a little bit, but I am curious
Speaker 2:  to have, are, are there any other sort of standout features from some of
Speaker 2:  the ones that you tested that you're like, oh, if only I could borrow this
Speaker 2:  and stick it on the DJI It would be even better.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so what DJI two has
Speaker 6:  is like audio levels. You can see the audio levels on the receiver. Mm.
Speaker 6:  That's a really nifty one. Also being able to plug in an external
Speaker 6:  lavalier, which a lot, some of the higher end of these do the road
Speaker 6:  wireless models do and that of course the backup
Speaker 6:  feature like right. That like onboard recording
Speaker 6:  is. So it's just like once you have that you don't wanna not use
Speaker 6:  it anymore.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That, that makes total sense. You know what I mean? Alright, so you're
Speaker 2:  on the DJI, which sounds very good. I'm, I'm super impressed.
Speaker 2:  Cool. Cool. I wanted, I wanna try the worst one you tried.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But before we do that, what can we try just like one of the others,
Speaker 2:  I'm curious to see kind of the, the range of quality we're looking at here.
Speaker 2:  So let's, let's just switch to one of the other ones you liked, like slightly
Speaker 2:  less and I'm just curious if I can even tell the difference in the audio.
Speaker 6:  Sure, yeah, let's use the Road Wireless Micro, which is just
Speaker 6:  plugs right into with USBC.
Speaker 2:  All right. So now you're on, you're on the road, the Road Micro, is that
Speaker 2:  what you called it?
Speaker 6:  Yes. The Road Wireless Micro just came out last month.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I would say it's, we're we're like kind of in range. Yeah. This feels,
Speaker 2:  I mean you're, you're in a pretty quiet room. Yeah. But this,
Speaker 2:  this sounds, I don't know, like maybe slightly more compressed,
Speaker 2:  but I also think I'm probably listening for it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I doubt you'll hear much of a difference. Like if like
Speaker 6:  listeners are listening on their phone or a Bluetooth speaker or something
Speaker 6:  like that,
Speaker 2:  Whenever we do these, I think about my wife who listens to podcasts just
Speaker 2:  out the speaker of her 4-year-old phone. Yeah. And I'm like, this must sound
Speaker 2:  like nothing to you, Anna. Like, she's just like, what do you mean these
Speaker 2:  all sound terrible.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it's, it's really nifty but I, I like it because it's super compact.
Speaker 6:  I just keep in my pocket like all the time and like I plugged in my
Speaker 6:  laptop, which is cool, which I didn't get to in the video, but yeah, you
Speaker 6:  plug it in via USBC, you can also plug it into your laptop If, you have that.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 2:  That is actually pretty handy. Yeah. Being able to like, yay for
Speaker 2:  universal charging ports. Right. But being able to just kind of have a plug
Speaker 2:  and play mic into any device that you have goes a
Speaker 2:  surprising long way. Like I've, I give a lot of people
Speaker 2:  the same speech about how important it is to sound good on video calls
Speaker 2:  and this is the kind of thing that you might even, like if you're giving
Speaker 2:  a presentation or at work, this might be useful in that same way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. People have told me that they want something like that for home,
Speaker 6:  for their like zoom call. So I'm like, oh it's, it's interesting. You're
Speaker 6:  gonna like walk around your kitchen while you're on the call, just have
Speaker 6:  it clipped to your, to your shirt. So yeah. That's
Speaker 2:  Cool. It's kind of a good idea. Yeah. You could sound like you're sitting
Speaker 2:  right at your computer but just be like aimlessly wandering around your house
Speaker 2:  with AirPods and a fancy microphone. The
Speaker 6:  Mic doesn't move. You do. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty good. We should start a company and that's the tagline. It's
Speaker 2:  gonna be incredible. Alright, let's try one more and the one I wanna
Speaker 2:  try is the, the like the TikTok microphone.
Speaker 2:  I think everybody knows the one I'm talking about, but you got the one. Yes,
Speaker 2:  that is the one and I would like to hear how it sounds. Okay,
Speaker 6:  Let's do it.
Speaker 2:  All right. You're now in the software that I'm seeing as USB audio
Speaker 2:  1.0 which already feels alarming. How we doing?
Speaker 6:  Okay, can you hear me now? Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, this is what I knew this was gonna It's bad.
Speaker 2:  It's like, it's just, it's just bad. It's,
Speaker 2:  you sound like someone who put their AirPods in
Speaker 2:  wrong. I've been noticing a lot that people wear their AirPods wrong.
Speaker 2:  Have you ever noticed this? The people who wear them so that they're sort
Speaker 2:  of sticking directly out of their head. It's like they've screwed them into
Speaker 2:  far into their air canals and they just, it's like, it's like you have antenna
Speaker 2:  coming out of your ears. That's what you sound like. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I have seen someone in the office not gonna lie with wearing air puts like
Speaker 6:  that
Speaker 2:  Listen name and shame Andrew, it's time.
Speaker 2:  So first of all, what is this Mike?
Speaker 6:  It's a good question because I don't really know. The
Speaker 6:  box that came in says the K eight wireless microphone. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I've seen this on TikTok without that branding, the same box without that
Speaker 6:  branding, it is just kind of this generic wireless
Speaker 6:  microphone that you plug into your phone has. And then
Speaker 6:  one little other thing that you clip on your shirt with the mic
Speaker 6:  and I've like, people are like hawking these on TikTok for five
Speaker 6:  bucks.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's the one you can find a million identical looking
Speaker 2:  ones on like Ali Express and the TikTok shop and Amazon and
Speaker 2:  like I assume they're all the same thing from like a giant
Speaker 2:  bin in a factory somewhere in China. That's what it
Speaker 6:  Seems to be. Yeah. Yeah. I went, I bought another one recently just to see
Speaker 6:  if it was the same and it was exactly the same. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay. Yeah. And this is, this has become
Speaker 2:  the TikTok microphone. Is it just 'cause it's cheap? Like every, everybody's
Speaker 2:  just like, oh this sounds better than my phone and it's cheap. Even though
Speaker 2:  I would say it demonstrably does not sound better than your phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, totally. It it's like because it was, you know,
Speaker 6:  sold on one of these like bulk shops where you can get a whole bunch and
Speaker 6:  and and drop ship them but you know, it
Speaker 6:  isolates your voice more. It does versus like the phone is gonna be like,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna pick up a lot of other things in the room. A lot of people record
Speaker 6:  in their car so this If you hold this up
Speaker 6:  to your, your mouth in the car, maybe you won't get as
Speaker 6:  like a boxier sound than usual.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there is something to that, that at least you have something sort
Speaker 2:  of close and directional and that's helpful. Like that is the basic mic
Speaker 2:  technique we give most people, but I still feel like this is much worse than
Speaker 2:  holding up the, the white ear pod microphone to your mouth.
Speaker 2:  Like if you're gonna hold a microphone, that one sounds much better than
Speaker 2:  this one does.
Speaker 6:  Totally. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I guess it is $20 versus $5. But like I'm gonna, I'm gonna go ahead and say
Speaker 2:  that's worth the $15 investment.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And who knows how long these are gonna be for that price. Like I, I've
Speaker 6:  seen them on Amazon for like $30. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah that's fair. Alright, switch back to the good mic So I. Don't have to
Speaker 2:  listen to this anymore. And then I have a couple more questions and we'll
Speaker 2:  let you go.
Speaker 6:  Okay, great.
Speaker 2:  All right. Are we back to a good mic?
Speaker 6:  I think So I, how
Speaker 2:  Do, we're back to a good mic. This sounds good. Is this the DJI again?
Speaker 6:  This is the Sen Heiser profile Wireless. I figured since we
Speaker 6:  I mentioned it, I wanted to demonstrate how it sounded.
Speaker 2:  It does sound good. I yeah, they're all kind of right in range. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  That this is, which is good news honestly. Especially I feel
Speaker 2:  like DJ's thing is just as good
Speaker 2:  a little wacky to figure out and cheaper. It's like keeps
Speaker 2:  working for
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah. I was skeptical of their mics because they're not
Speaker 6:  a microphone company, but it yeah, they they're pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's, that's super exciting. So, okay. You think if I am, if
Speaker 2:  I'm like a creator, starting a TikTok channel
Speaker 2:  DJI into my phone into the TikTok app is like a perfectly viable
Speaker 2:  mic video strategy. We feel good about that.
Speaker 6:  Yes, totally. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's awesome. That feels like a win. This is like, that is a, that's a
Speaker 2:  big level up for a lot of people pretty fast.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And also If, you end up like getting a better camera and
Speaker 6:  you're not using just your phone. You can still use this with another camera,
Speaker 6:  which is, is really what is a big difference between that and the
Speaker 6:  Road Mini or the Road micro because you can only use this
Speaker 6:  with the US like something with the USB port. Right. Taking audio in. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's, that's very cool. So are you, are you using these mics in your
Speaker 2:  own gear now? What's your new setup?
Speaker 6:  Yes. This past year or two we've kind of like stopped carrying around the
Speaker 6:  bulky professional wireless microphone systems when
Speaker 6:  we're like running around. I remember at CES last year, we
Speaker 6:  didn't really use those. We used the road, the wireless GoTo
Speaker 6:  for most of our stuff we were doing out in the field. And
Speaker 6:  yeah. And for c ees, I would love to carry around this Sennheiser
Speaker 6:  kit because it's super compact. It's got this neat carrying case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That, I mean it goes a really long way and I think to me the
Speaker 2:  next step then
Speaker 2:  it kind of feels like getting much smaller is maybe not super
Speaker 2:  useful. It feels like the next step is starting to solve some of the UI stuff.
Speaker 2:  Right. Because I feel like especially the things that are connected to the
Speaker 2:  phone, there's just not great sort of really
Speaker 2:  fine grained manual control in the way that you can do like
Speaker 2:  pretty professional stuff with your video camera at this point. It feels
Speaker 2:  like audio still has a little bit of catching up there, but maybe that's
Speaker 2:  the next thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think you're sacrificing a lot of stuff by making them smaller. So
Speaker 6:  there's gonna be some happy medium there where like maybe the receiver's
Speaker 6:  a little bigger that you can adjust some settings, but the
Speaker 6:  mics are still kind of tiny. Yeah. So they don't show up on screen, you know.
Speaker 2:  That is fair. Okay, last thing and then you're gonna go, you have, you are
Speaker 2:  the person who knows the answer to this question. Where is the correct place
Speaker 2:  on your person to put the mic to do this?
Speaker 6:  So I always like going like two buttons down
Speaker 6:  on, on like a dress shirt. Okay. It's a very specific
Speaker 6:  type of way to dress so it's not accurate for everyone. But
Speaker 2:  You're kind of like right at like mid chest height it seems like at that
Speaker 2:  point. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Totally. Like If, you just, you put it where your, you know where your heart
Speaker 6:  is is like a good Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, okay. Right in the middle. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Totally.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So not on the brim of my hat, which is a thing that I saw somebody
Speaker 2:  do and thought that was very cool and wanted steal.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's an interesting idea. They're omnidirectional so it's not,
Speaker 6:  it's not gonna not pick up your voice,
Speaker 6:  but it'll, it's a little silly. It's, it's obviously for,
Speaker 6:  for aesthetic purposes.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. All right. Well this is as, as someone who ends up always
Speaker 2:  putting it on my collar and then it like droops all weird. This is good advice.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. Like wherever your, your hand goes when you say the pledge of
Speaker 2:  allegiance, that's where you put the mic.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, totally. And now these have mic little magnets on them. You can
Speaker 6:  really just, you can clip 'em on anywhere on your clothing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. The magnet over the clip thing is a huge upgrade. Yeah. Cannot
Speaker 2:  recommend that enough. Alright Andrew, thank you for coming back. It's nice
Speaker 2:  to see you. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  do a segment on The Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Support
Speaker 6:  For this episode comes from A-W-S-A-W-S
Speaker 3:  Generated AI gives you the tools to power your business forward with the
Speaker 3:  security and speed of the world's most experienced cloud.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all of
Speaker 2:  your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show every week.
Speaker 2:  A reminder next week we are doing a full meta
Speaker 2:  episode about The Vergecast and The Verge. So If, you have questions, we've
Speaker 2:  gotten a bunch of really fun ones already, but if there's ever something
Speaker 2:  you've wanted to know about how The Vergecast works, how we make the show,
Speaker 2:  how we decide what goes on in the show, what we're doing when we're
Speaker 2:  not recording the show, how The Verge works, the future of media, all kinds
Speaker 2:  of stuff, anything you wanna know, call us eight six six VERGE
Speaker 2:  one, one email us vergecast to The Verge dot com. We love hearing all of
Speaker 2:  your questions and we're gonna do as many of the meta ones as we can next
Speaker 2:  week. This week we have a question about web browsers.
Speaker 7:  Hi, this is Joey from Portland, Oregon and I have a question about web
Speaker 7:  browsers. Just watching your latest or listen your latest Vergecast
Speaker 7:  about, you know, Chrome and, and I was just thinking just recently
Speaker 7:  I, I started switching, I'm using Chrome to
Speaker 7:  safari on my MacBook Air and you know, just
Speaker 7:  heard that like it's more efficient and you know, it's a little, it's a little
Speaker 7:  faster but definitely closely uses less battery and I haven't really
Speaker 7:  noticed that. I mean I haven't done extensive testing but
Speaker 7:  I, like most people, I live in the browser for the most part and
Speaker 7:  I use safari extensions, I use extensions
Speaker 7:  and seems like it's about the same battery life doesn't really see any
Speaker 7:  faster. So is is that really true? Is, is
Speaker 7:  Safari really noticeably like more efficient?
Speaker 7:  Be curious to your thoughts. Thanks, bye.
Speaker 2:  One of the reasons I really like this question is that it's really hard to
Speaker 2:  test this question. Browsers are complicated
Speaker 2:  because they're so much more than just one individual thing. Like
Speaker 2:  the way that you use your browser is so personal
Speaker 2:  and so unique to you maybe even in ways that you
Speaker 2:  don't understand, right? Think about the number of tabs that you have open,
Speaker 2:  whether you tend to use multiple windows with tabs
Speaker 2:  or just have one window with a thousand tabs in it. Are
Speaker 2:  you a bookmarks person? Do you have lots of extensions? Are you
Speaker 2:  constantly running like really intense web apps like Gmail
Speaker 2:  or Figma or Canva or things like that? Or are you the kind of
Speaker 2:  person who is just like opening a web browser, going to cnn.com looking
Speaker 2:  at some news and then moving on into your day? Maybe no other piece of
Speaker 2:  software is so varied in its use that way
Speaker 2:  than a web browser. So it's very hard for anyone to say
Speaker 2:  here is the best web browser for x, y, or Z reason, right? I think one
Speaker 2:  reason people think Safari is the best Mac browser is
Speaker 2:  just that it's so well integrated with all of Apple's other
Speaker 2:  products and its operating systems. There's actually not real
Speaker 2:  evidence anywhere that I can find that Safari is faster or more performant
Speaker 2:  or better for battery life in any meaningful way. It's just
Speaker 2:  that it is so sort of deeply integrated inside of the system
Speaker 2:  that it feels better, the share sheet works better, you can open things and
Speaker 2:  move them around more quickly. It feels the macies
Speaker 2:  of the Mac browsers and it feels the iPhones of the iPhone browsers the same
Speaker 2:  way that Chrome does on Android. Like you can run other browsers
Speaker 2:  on a Chromebook than Chrome but it's gonna feel worse even if
Speaker 2:  it's just as fast. So all of that is to say, I think figuring
Speaker 2:  out which browser is for you, you should think much more about
Speaker 2:  UI and which services you use than really
Speaker 2:  throwing your lot behind one product or another. Like I said, there aren't
Speaker 2:  a lot of ways to kind of apples to apples compare one browser to
Speaker 2:  the other. But there is one benchmark that I like, it's called Speedometer
Speaker 2:  3.0 from Browser Bench and it tries to mimic
Speaker 2:  using a web app. It's like a to-do list thing that is trying to move stuff
Speaker 2:  around. So it executes JavaScript and tries to run stuff in the background
Speaker 2:  and also, you know, loads news pages. And the idea is just a sort of
Speaker 2:  normal web usage. It's not a perfect benchmark, I
Speaker 2:  don't think any benchmark of anything is perfect, but at least you get some
Speaker 2:  kind of apples to apples rough performance metric for how a browser
Speaker 2:  works. I tested it on seven browsers on my Mac
Speaker 2:  Mini and let me just read you the scores. So hire is better. Chrome
Speaker 2:  came in first with 48.2, safari got
Speaker 2:  47.4 not super far down. Then there was Brave
Speaker 2:  44.7, edge 44.5. So basically the same between those
Speaker 2:  two. Firefox, 41.4, arc 38.3 and
Speaker 2:  DuckDuckGo 38.1. Reasonable range top to
Speaker 2:  bottom there. But they all have a bit of a margin of error in them.
Speaker 2:  And realistically you might notice a performance
Speaker 2:  difference between like Chrome at the very top and DuckDuckGo at the very
Speaker 2:  bottom. But like should you use Chrome or Safari based on the
Speaker 2:  0.8 points between them, no, there are other
Speaker 2:  reasons that that browser will feel better or worse to you than
Speaker 2:  the raw performance score of how it does on this one benchmark. All
Speaker 2:  of this is to say I think browsers are fascinating for this exact reason,
Speaker 2:  right? It's not a question of optimizing
Speaker 2:  ruthlessly for one specific use case. Browsers are all things to all
Speaker 2:  people. And what I would do is basically
Speaker 2:  try to figure out the UI that works for you. Whether you want
Speaker 2:  Chrome which has more sort of accessibility to extensions
Speaker 2:  and does a better job, I think with some bookmarklets or you want Safari,
Speaker 2:  which is simple to a fault and just keeps everything very straightforward.
Speaker 2:  Or you want something like Arc, which has really weird ideas about UI
Speaker 2:  or you want Brave, which has a lot of additional features and stuff built
Speaker 2:  into the browser, you kind of can't pick wrong, right? There are a lot of
Speaker 2:  browsers out there, a bunch of them are really good. None of them have
Speaker 2:  any sort of obviously huge increase and
Speaker 2:  killer app over any of the others. So ultimately what I would say
Speaker 2:  is try a bunch of different browsers and just see what works for you and
Speaker 2:  don't really worry about spending a ton of time trying to optimize for
Speaker 2:  performance. I will say If, you open a lot of
Speaker 2:  tabs, it will crush your memory and it will crush your battery life. And
Speaker 2:  anecdotally I cannot prove this, but anecdotally Chrome seems to be the worst
Speaker 2:  at that. That when I have a hundred Chrome tabs open, it just
Speaker 2:  destroys every computer I've ever used in a way that no other browser does.
Speaker 2:  I can't prove that, but that is how it feels to me. But in general, the best
Speaker 2:  thing you can do for your performance and your battery life is manage your
Speaker 2:  tabs slightly better so that you're not running so many different
Speaker 2:  versions of any of these browsers at a time. But beyond that,
Speaker 2:  just pick the browser you like the best and use it and don't worry about
Speaker 2:  the rest. And that is actually a pretty good place to be. Lots of different
Speaker 2:  ideas about browsers out there. Give them all a try. I have seven on my computer
Speaker 2:  now because I downloaded them all and I'm gonna keep 'em and I'm gonna try
Speaker 2:  'em 'cause this is the life I've chosen for myself. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who's on the show
Speaker 2:  and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything we
Speaker 2:  talked about all of Thomas Riker's reviews, Andrew Marino's, great videos,
Speaker 2:  lots of stuff that we've done on browsers, all of that, I'll put in the show
Speaker 2:  notes. But as always, read the website. It's December, but the news keeps
Speaker 2:  happening. We have tons of great gift guides. Some of the like Cyber Monday,
Speaker 2:  black Friday deals are still kicking around, so keep it locked on the
Speaker 2:  website. Lots of good stuff going on. And like I said before, If, you have
Speaker 2:  thoughts, questions, feelings, or other browsers I should download.
Speaker 2:  You can always email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline.
Speaker 2:  It's six six VERGE one one. Like I said, we're doing a meta episode
Speaker 2:  about all things VERGE and vergecast in the future of media and podcasts
Speaker 2:  and whatever else you wanna talk about next Tuesday. So getting our questions
Speaker 2:  as soon as you can and we will answer as many of them on the show as we possibly
Speaker 2:  can. This show is produced by Liam James Wil Pour and Eric Gomez.
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast is a VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  Neli and I'll be back on Friday to talk about all the news,
Speaker 2:  the Intel CEO stuff, some crazy stuff going on in the streaming world and
Speaker 2:  lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll