# Transcript
ID: 369ef2df-6949-434a-9a1b-df398382b1b0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4845369631941694826/-5125746174128096082/s93290-US-5598s-1709289488.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel and David Pierce talk through the weird and winding history of Apple's "secret" car project now that it's officially dead. And later, senior policy reporter Lauren Feiner makes her Vergecast debut to catch us up on the arguments made this week in the Supreme Court about online speech and the First Amendment.
Speaker 5:  Hello And Welcome to Vergecast. The flagship podcast of the Apple car.
Speaker 2:  In that it, we've spent a lot of money and it doesn't exist.
Speaker 5:  That's The Vergecast everybody. $10 billion in a decade later and
Speaker 5:  we have more to show for it than Apple does with the car project.
Speaker 5:  We did. I'm your friend NELI. David. Pierce is here.
Speaker 2:  Hi. We're in the studio. This is very exciting.
Speaker 5:  We, David and I are together. Like they saying cable news, Alex Cranz is
Speaker 5:  off this week. That's what they say. That's all the time. Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 5:  I like it. That's just the thing they say, you know, to explain it. No further
Speaker 5:  explanation even no Alex is, should we say it?
Speaker 2:  She's sick. She's sick. Yeah. She'll be okay. Yeah. Send Alex nice
Speaker 2:  vibes. Anything else? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Happy vibes. Alex. But Lauren Feiner, our new policy
Speaker 5:  reporter is gonna join us in the second segment to talk about the Supreme
Speaker 5:  court hearing
Speaker 5:  Parade of justice about free speech
Speaker 5:  on the internet, which is one of, you know, that's what you come to the show
Speaker 5:  for. What
Speaker 2:  Gadgets does YouTube weigh mean? Like how
Speaker 5:  Much does
Speaker 2:  YouTube weigh?
Speaker 5:  It's a real thing that came up. We'll get to that but we should start
Speaker 5:  with news. The news of the week, which is Apple
Speaker 5:  killed their car project
Speaker 2:  After so many almost and kind of
Speaker 2:  and False starts and what? Like almost exactly a decade
Speaker 2:  of work. Right? So it was, it was gonna be
Speaker 2:  a car kind of like Tesla and then it was gonna be a self-driving car kind
Speaker 2:  of like Waymo and then I think it was gonna be a car, kind of like a Tesla
Speaker 2:  again and now it's going to be nothing.
Speaker 5:  Oh there, there are three more twisted. Were there more?
Speaker 2:  I'm
Speaker 5:  Sure there were then they were gonna focus on making the software
Speaker 5:  for other cars. Oh right. That was a, that was a weird twist in there.
Speaker 5:  Then they were gonna buy the platform for like an EV
Speaker 5:  platform from Hyundai and put Apple stuff on top of that and Hyundai would
Speaker 5:  turn into Foxconn and Hyundai was like, no, we are a car maker.
Speaker 5:  We, no, don't do that to us. Yeah. Then Foxconn was like, we're gonna build
Speaker 5:  cars
Speaker 5:  Foxcon there like at least 10 more twists and turns in there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it's really fascinating though 'cause I think If you rewind
Speaker 2:  10 years ago to when this was gonna happen. It was the moment
Speaker 2:  that everybody was saying all cars will be self-driving
Speaker 2:  and the world will have completely changed and everything will be on the
Speaker 2:  road by like 2020. Yeah. And that was that people earnestly believed that
Speaker 2:  like Uber was saying that Lyft was saying that all the car companies were
Speaker 2:  saying that Elon Musk was saying that there was this certainty that by
Speaker 2:  2020 the whole idea of owning a car
Speaker 2:  was going to have disappeared and there were going to be fleets of robots
Speaker 2:  roaming the streets everywhere. Yeah. And that just could
Speaker 2:  not be further from the truth. At this particular
Speaker 5:  Moment in time, there are some robots roaming the streets of San Francisco.
Speaker 5:  There
Speaker 2:  Are a few robots, well Andy Hawkins who wrote a couple of great pieces about
Speaker 2:  this this week, made the point that it's actually not that hard at this moment
Speaker 2:  in time to strap a camera to the top of a Toyota Highlander and put it
Speaker 2:  on the roads. And that's true but it's, it is such a
Speaker 2:  fascinating like counterfactual of history. If it had gone differently
Speaker 2:  and we had solved kind of those core tenets of self-driving technology,
Speaker 2:  would Apple have released a car? What would it have been? Mostly? I'm just
Speaker 2:  sad that we don't get to see the thing that Apple was building. Like I feel
Speaker 2:  like Apple, well
Speaker 5:  We should back up because I really want to talk about what Apple may or may
Speaker 5:  not have been building for quite a long time.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  But the, the thing we're talking about was Apple sent out a memo to its
Speaker 5:  employees
Speaker 5:  just saying we're shutting down the car project and those employees will
Speaker 5:  be moved to to generative ai
Speaker 2:  I believe 2000 employees, which the number that was reported
Speaker 5:  And that project has been both bigger and smaller than that over time. Right.
Speaker 5:  They've been working on this for 10 years. It's one of the worst kept secrets
Speaker 5:  in Silicon Valley. There are apple cars just driving the streets,
Speaker 5:  collecting training data you might call it.
Speaker 2:  Well we should say there are Apple owned cars. Yeah. Doing that. They are
Speaker 2:  not Apple cars.
Speaker 5:  But then Apple doesn't do Toyota. What is an Apple carers by the way? They
Speaker 5:  buy Lexuses.
Speaker 2:  Oh you're right. That's true.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna put that
Speaker 2:  Fancy Highlanders
Speaker 5:  Do fancier highlanders than than your average self-driving car company.
Speaker 5:  So the projects started in the moment David
Speaker 5:  is describing, which is Apple needed its next big thing
Speaker 5:  and apple size markets are hard to come by. So they,
Speaker 5:  it was healthcare and cars, right? Or the next thing can like move the needle
Speaker 5:  on Apple's revenue. And they decided healthcare, they do a bunch of
Speaker 5:  watch stuff and then cars always
Speaker 5:  seemed like a lark. Like to me it always seemed like what are you doing?
Speaker 5:  Okay. but it has been 10 years of
Speaker 5:  people coming and going from that division of Apple called Project
Speaker 5:  Titan. And this last turn they took
Speaker 5:  Kevin Lynch who ran the watch and said, you're in charge of it. And I think
Speaker 5:  he was like, well
Speaker 5:  what if I'm not, this is nothing. Yeah. What if I don't do this? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well I think it it Kevin Lynch being the one in charge is a funny example
Speaker 2:  because he launched the Apple Watch and was very much the one
Speaker 2:  who spearheaded that project. And to his credit was also a big part
Speaker 2:  of how Apple discovered what the Apple Watch was. Yeah. Right. Because we've
Speaker 2:  talked about many times in the show the Apple Watch was made because Apple
Speaker 2:  wanted to make a watch like it. That was the beginning of the story Johnny.
Speaker 2:  I was like, what if watch And that's how it started. And so Apple over time
Speaker 2:  figured out what it could be, what it should be, how it could work, who it
Speaker 2:  would be for. And it has worked like kudos to that team. They, they got
Speaker 2:  there, they figured it out. And my assumption is that the car
Speaker 2:  is sort of the same way where like you're saying Apple looked around and
Speaker 2:  said, okay, what's a huge market? Oh cars, let's make a car. And then
Speaker 2:  at some point somebody had to sit down and go, what do we do?
Speaker 2:  What is that?
Speaker 5:  So there's a story that comes up over and over again. It's in some of the
Speaker 5:  reporting today and the times we had trip nickel on
Speaker 5:  the show a while back. It was in his book about Apple and just sort of the
Speaker 5:  fight between Tim Cook and Johnny. Ive in the post jobs era
Speaker 5:  and the story has come up several times now. Johnny, ive built a
Speaker 5:  model of a car with no steering wheel and he sat Tim Cook down in
Speaker 5:  it and they pretended they were on a drive while an actor, this is true.
Speaker 5:  An actor pretended to be Siri and pretended to talk to them
Speaker 5:  as they went on their pretend
Speaker 2:  Ride and tell them them like the name of restaurants that they were going
Speaker 2:  by and stuff like that. It was supposed to be, that was the interface for
Speaker 2:  the car was Siri. Which is terrifying.
Speaker 5:  I just want everyone to sit with that for a minute and imagine
Speaker 5:  like these, when you think about Tim Cook, imagine him going on a pretend
Speaker 5:  car ride with Johnny. Ive actor actor. It really, the most actor does
Speaker 5:  pretend Siri.
Speaker 2:  It's the most like CES vaporware demo from a company
Speaker 2:  in China you've never heard of and will never hear from again. Thing that
Speaker 2:  I've ever heard.
Speaker 5:  But it's also like, does Johnny, ive not think Tim Cook has any power of
Speaker 5:  imagination because I could be like, here's what it's gonna be like. You're
Speaker 5:  gonna sit in the car and drive around here, we gonna talk to you. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  I don't need that acted out for me. Like
Speaker 5:  I like I get it. It
Speaker 2:  Doesn't help to have an actor go, that's a Dwayne Reed.
Speaker 5:  It's, I don't need that. Like it's in the mind's
Speaker 5:  eye, you know? I got it. I should close your eyes. Everybody pull over
Speaker 5:  your car. Imagine your car's driving itself and like serious, like
Speaker 5:  there's a hospital. Like that's all you need to do.
Speaker 5:  I, I think about that moment all the time. It's like just Johnny, I think
Speaker 5:  to cook can't imagine the most basic thing you can imagine
Speaker 5:  about a self-driving car. There
Speaker 2:  Are seats.
Speaker 5:  The end, I made a beautiful chair for you. Sit in it and pretend it's a car.
Speaker 5:  So that demo apparently convinced them that this is The future of the car
Speaker 5:  and they wanted to do the big thing which is
Speaker 5:  self-driving Siri car. Right. No steering wheel. Which is
Speaker 5:  I think like that's the apple level innovation leap.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And I think at that time that's where If, you Apple, you say,
Speaker 2:  okay, there is a thing we can do that is different. Right? Yeah. 'cause if
Speaker 2:  if, if you're Apple and you're just saying, oh let's make a pretty good SUV
Speaker 2:  like that, that's not what Apple does. But If you
Speaker 2:  believed as they did at that time that in a decade the
Speaker 2:  whole way we experience cars would be different. You can see how
Speaker 2:  you would talk yourself into oh it's just gonna be screens you sit in
Speaker 2:  instead of screens. Seriously. Like it's, and
Speaker 5:  We can take 30% of those screens too.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Like literally it's like the services business in a car is gonna
Speaker 2:  be nuts someday.
Speaker 5:  And by the way, all the car makers believe this. Yeah. This is why GM took
Speaker 5:  CarPlay out of its cars. Like down the line. The idea that you'll roll
Speaker 5:  around in a shopping mall. It, everyone's very excited about the
Speaker 5:  city.
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent. And I feel like the tension has been, there has been this
Speaker 2:  incredible sort of whipsawing hype around self-driving
Speaker 2:  and it seems like whipsawing strategy inside of Apple
Speaker 2:  as a result. And every once in a while they've just been like, oh crap, that's
Speaker 2:  not gonna work. We should just build a car. And then somebody's like, why
Speaker 2:  the hell are we just building a car? And then somebody else is like, but
Speaker 2:  what if it drove itself and they're like,
Speaker 5:  We're back big. Just hire 2000 engineers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That part, that's the other term that I think is interesting. There's
Speaker 5:  all these rumors they try to buy Tesla, they investigated it. I think
Speaker 5:  Elon has like said things that Apple has denied over the course of
Speaker 5:  the past decade
Speaker 2:  About their interest. Well there was some reporting around this that Elon,
Speaker 2:  Elon and Tim Cook did have some conversation about it Apple
Speaker 2:  wasn't interested in also Elon would only do it if he was made the CEO EO
Speaker 2:  of Apple, which is just an incredible That's great. I have no, I like a
Speaker 2:  perfectly in character for Elon Musk BI have no idea if it's true, but I
Speaker 2:  I am choosing to believe that that is,
Speaker 5:  That's a very, that's a very truthy Yeah. you know, it just feels good. It
Speaker 5:  does feel good to rattle that what is true is that Johnny and I have sat
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook down in a pretend car and they went on a pretend ride,
Speaker 5:  which I just will never, like that's when you know like Tim Cook should like,
Speaker 5:  so this is your No we're not doing this.
Speaker 2:  And it wasn't even a car, it was like a couch. Yeah. By all it was just,
Speaker 2:  it was just a seat.
Speaker 5:  It's just very good. I just want everyone, it's fine. I want you to use your
Speaker 5:  imagination to imagine them using their imaginations. Just think
Speaker 5:  about it.
Speaker 2:  Do you think there was like fake wind?
Speaker 5:  I can't stop thinking about this. Was
Speaker 2:  Somebody scrolling a picture past also like
Speaker 5:  These are not, I would say
Speaker 5:  mirthful personalities. Like they were taking all this very seriously.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. These are two very serious people. It just, just imagine it
Speaker 5:  just like, I don't know like act it out with your friends. See If, you
Speaker 5:  can even get through it.
Speaker 5:  I can't get over it. Okay, so then you got, we should buy Tesla. We
Speaker 5:  can't do self-driving technologies there. We should just build a car. And
Speaker 5:  this is when you were like, what does it look like? I cannot stop thinking
Speaker 5:  about the moments when Apple was like, okay,
Speaker 5:  what does a car look like? Because a car in the
Speaker 5:  United States at this point in time looks like a mid-size crossover. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Arguably the least designed forward shape for a car.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like here's a shoe. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's just a Subaru. Like all cars are Subarus now. It's just
Speaker 5:  What it is. It's like old Toyotas were angry Robot Subarus, new
Speaker 5:  Toyotas are sort of like mean fish Subarus. Like
Speaker 5:  it's all the same slightly
Speaker 2:  Racy Subarus. Yeah. Slightly tall Subarus. It's
Speaker 2:  just Subarus all the way down man.
Speaker 5:  And so the idea that Apple's gonna like deliver a hot
Speaker 5:  looking mid-size crossover, right. Is
Speaker 5:  very funny. Yes. Like very funny. Like mid-size crossovers look so
Speaker 5:  much the same that the new Ferrari SUV looks
Speaker 5:  almost exactly like a Buick. Like there are, there is
Speaker 5:  a new Buick that looks almost exactly like a Ferrari that looks almost
Speaker 5:  exactly like a Mazda. And it's like Apple entering this market and being
Speaker 5:  like design everyone. Right.
Speaker 2:  Well and to some extent that is the result of
Speaker 2:  literal decades of work from these companies. And again,
Speaker 2:  some of the reporting around this has been that Apple basically it
Speaker 2:  infuriated everybody who came to work on the carb because it said we're not
Speaker 2:  doing anything the way the car industry has done things. We're gonna, you
Speaker 2:  know, operate from first principles. Oh God. Which you can imagine means
Speaker 2:  there's a meeting run by Johnny Ive where he's like, what if the wheels weren't
Speaker 2:  round just as like a thought experiment. What other
Speaker 2:  shape could a wheel be?
Speaker 5:  No, it's Johnny Ab. He'd be like, the answer must be so simple. It seems
Speaker 5:  obvious. Everyone's like round wheels dude. Nailed it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like what if it just hovers? And they're like, no Johnny, that's not it.
Speaker 2:  But, and and, and so from all the way down it's like this is what Tesla
Speaker 2:  experienced too. Like it turns out there aren't actually all that many ways
Speaker 2:  to make a car and you can, you can litigate forever whether that's a good
Speaker 2:  thing or a bad thing. The way the regulation works, the way the industry
Speaker 2:  works, the e economies of scale. Like there aren't that many ways to make
Speaker 2:  a car and If, you try to get weird with it, you make a cyber truck,
Speaker 2:  there's that. But Apple basically tried to
Speaker 2:  do a thing that I think it just couldn't do. And again, I wish we had
Speaker 2:  gotten to see what it would look like. I think there's some reporting
Speaker 5:  Someone at
Speaker 2:  Apple is re it is their moral responsibility to just like
Speaker 2:  post the slide deck, post the keynote file. Show me some showing
Speaker 2:  the designs.
Speaker 5:  So there is a little bit of reporting in the Times today. There's actually
Speaker 5:  a lot of great senses in this time space. But there's the Mr I but this paragraph
Speaker 5:  jumped out Mr. I and his team of designers through concepts for a car that
Speaker 5:  would look like a European minivan such as the Fiat multi plus
Speaker 5:  600, which has half a dozen windows in a curving roof.
Speaker 5:  It had no steering wheel and we controlled by Apple's virtual assistant Siri.
Speaker 5:  So it was a minivan they made steering
Speaker 2:  Wheel. Yeah. And there was some reporting in there that one of the like big
Speaker 2:  innovative things they were gonna do is put a, a polymer on the sunroof
Speaker 2:  so that you didn't get heat in the sunroof. And it's like that
Speaker 2:  is the extent to which you are allowed to innovate in cars is polymers on
Speaker 2:  the sunroof. Right. Like otherwise we pretty much did it for what
Speaker 2:  cars are for now. We've pretty much done it.
Speaker 5:  Can I just point out the Fiat 600 multiple looks exactly
Speaker 5:  like a VW bus. Like it is the most Johnny I thing to be like, so it's a
Speaker 5:  VW bus where we picked a weirder fiat version of it.
Speaker 2:  It's a European one.
Speaker 5:  So is the VW bus. No, no. It's a fiat this time.
Speaker 5:  All of that is just the silliest to me. Yes. And I think app, the reality
Speaker 5:  of what a car is to people, like apple's full of car nerds
Speaker 5:  like Eddie Q is on a board of Ferrari. I think Aston Martin
Speaker 5:  has the new version of CarPlay because Phil Schiller just like
Speaker 5:  went there and was like, look I own so many of these.
Speaker 5:  Like just let's let's make it happen. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And Johnny i's a big car guy. Like it's it is, it is very much in
Speaker 2:  the DNA of that company to love cars. Yeah. Wasn't it jobs who got the, like
Speaker 2:  the new Mercedes every six months so that he didn't have to have a license
Speaker 2:  plate. Yes. That's good. Like that's the make a car without a license
Speaker 2:  plate Apple. Like there, there it is. We did it. But that's
Speaker 2:  like I, I keep coming around to this question of
Speaker 2:  was this ever going to work? It is. So for Apple, a
Speaker 2:  backwards way of making great products, which is just like we found a huge
Speaker 2:  market, let's go do something there. Yeah. But I do also think If you If
Speaker 2:  you twist the world a little differently and self-driving technology is much
Speaker 2:  further along and the regulation is much further along and we're doing better
Speaker 2:  at all of that.
Speaker 2:  I think it's not crazy to imagine that at some point we are due for a big
Speaker 2:  reinvention of what a car is. But
Speaker 5:  Also I just, again, I'm just going to, I wanna come back to this
Speaker 5:  Johnny, I sat Tim Cook down in 2015 Yeah. In a fake
Speaker 5:  car and said, what I'd like to do is build a hundred thousand dollars
Speaker 5:  bus with no steering wheel. And they were like, let's
Speaker 5:  spend 10 years on this. And that is, that's not
Speaker 5:  just backwards, right. That's like we're not even gonna move the market
Speaker 5:  to like, we're not even gonna move enough units to make revenue
Speaker 5:  to make this worth it.
Speaker 2:  Right. I mean we just talked the other week on the show about the fact that
Speaker 2:  the market $400,000 SUVs turns out to not be huge. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it's hurting a lot of companies because everyone who wants a hundred
Speaker 2:  thousand dollars electric SUV already got one and there aren't very many
Speaker 2:  of them.
Speaker 5:  They're doing dumb stuff in their hummers. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2:  They're
Speaker 5:  Not gonna buy it. They are not gonna buy a bus. No. And the, the real market
Speaker 5:  for cars is coming down, weighed it back down to Earth and to
Speaker 5:  operate at scale, I think you do to sell a hundred thousand dollars car If
Speaker 5:  you Apple, you do need it to drive itself. Yeah. So then you can't get it
Speaker 5:  to drive itself and now you gotta make a $50,000 car or
Speaker 5:  $70,000 car and now you are in just some of the most overheated
Speaker 5:  territory that exists in cars. You're up against luxury, you're up against
Speaker 5:  BMW and Mercedes and Audi like all those companies.
Speaker 5:  Lexus, you got your own self-driving Lexuses already. Yeah. Like if you're
Speaker 5:  Apple and you have a self-driving Lexus, you have to be like, can we make
Speaker 5:  something better than the Lexus we put a camera on?
Speaker 2:  Right. Did we just do it already?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You could just buy, apple could just buy Lexus's, put an
Speaker 5:  Apple logo on them and resell the Lexus and Apple car. And that I think is
Speaker 5:  like a real problem for them. Yeah. The thing that I
Speaker 5:  keep coming back to that same moment 10 years ago,
Speaker 5:  that is when like the height of their weird TV ambitions.
Speaker 2:  Well it was, it was really when Johnny was feeling himself the most
Speaker 2:  was like peak Johnny Ive, in terms of just having insane
Speaker 2:  ideas about what everything should be. And some of those things were the
Speaker 2:  butterfly keyboard and some of those things were the Apple watch. And it
Speaker 2:  just like Apple had a real weird moment for a couple of years there because
Speaker 2:  Johnny, ive was both kind of disengaging and just sort of
Speaker 2:  lobbing insane ideas into Apple's design studio at all times.
Speaker 5:  Well this is, I believe, and this
Speaker 2:  Is the most expensive one I think,
Speaker 5:  I believe this is has this moment has been described as when
Speaker 5:  Apple thought it was a fashion company. Mm.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And they, they had hired a bunch of fashion executives and the sort of like
Speaker 5:  computer nerds were like, you should make the MacBooks thicker and work well.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, what if they had no ports? Right. We sold all the ports
Speaker 5:  back to you with $39 a piece and the the keyboards didn't work.
Speaker 5:  Oh, also we're gonna make the phone so thin that, that they have no battery
Speaker 5:  life. Huh. And like that fashion conception of the
Speaker 5:  company was, was real. Yeah. Like that was a real thing that happened at
Speaker 5:  Apple. And this turn lately from the company is
Speaker 5:  much more like we make computers. Like we make so much computers, we made
Speaker 5:  a face computer. Like it's the most Yeah. There's nothing fashion
Speaker 5:  about the Vision Pro except that it looks like a pair of expensive ski goggles.
Speaker 5:  But I don't think that is fashion in the way that No, the 2015 Apple
Speaker 5:  would've thought about it as fashion. Right.
Speaker 2:  Hermes is not making one of those for you anytime soon. That
Speaker 5:  Would be incredible. We did, there was a, a tweet today
Speaker 5:  of a man who wore the Vision Pro to his wedding.
Speaker 5:  Oh wow. The song showed it to me and she, and the, the bride is just like,
Speaker 5:  what are you doing?
Speaker 2:  That's love right there. That is love
Speaker 5:  The look on her face. Wow. It is very, it is exactly what you would expect.
Speaker 5:  If.
Speaker 2:  You could read his vows though. They'd be right there right in front of you.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God. That would be so that's what I'm
Speaker 2:  Saying. You could have it on a window. Look at her, look at the vows. She
Speaker 2:  can see her eyes, the googly eyes.
Speaker 5:  I'm in on this. Don't do this. I don't know, don't do this. If you're
Speaker 5:  listening to this, David is joking and he is proposing a bad idea.
Speaker 5:  That's not an instruction. That 2015 Apple, the, the
Speaker 5:  weird fashion Apple,
Speaker 5:  the thing that was happening like right next in the company at the same time
Speaker 5:  was they were,
Speaker 5:  they were still trying to make good on this promise that Steve Jobs had
Speaker 5:  figured out the tv. Right. And so like the thought experiment I've been thinking
Speaker 5:  about since reading about the card getting shut down, it's like what if they
Speaker 5:  just made a tv?
Speaker 2:  Mm. What if they put all those resources at a television? Right?
Speaker 5:  What if they were just like, it's a great TV and it has
Speaker 5:  a built-in cable service and you're gonna pay us a monthly fee to have the
Speaker 5:  sickest TV in your house. And like, and it
Speaker 5:  probably would've taken all the market share from the high end of the TV
Speaker 5:  industry 'cause that's what Apple does and they would've had a business like
Speaker 5:  a real business selling a thing that people like.
Speaker 2:  Well and ironically in the same way that the
Speaker 2:  self-driving car world has not gone the direction Apple expected,
Speaker 2:  the TV world has gone exactly the way you would want it to if
Speaker 2:  you're Apple. Yeah. Like TVs are a services business. TVs are
Speaker 2:  sort of slowly inching towards becoming the center of a smart home, which
Speaker 2:  we know Apple is very interested in. TVs are are a hub device for lots of
Speaker 2:  other devices. Like in a way it actually makes more sense today for Apple
Speaker 2:  to try to build a television than it ever has in the past. Both for Apple's
Speaker 2:  business and just like the world. Yeah. And it is really interesting to think
Speaker 2:  like what if they had spent $10 million trying to build the
Speaker 2:  greatest TV the world has ever known instead of trying to build a car that
Speaker 2:  actually I don't think there was ever really gonna be any real demand for
Speaker 2:  anyway.
Speaker 5:  Well, so you know, the arguments against TV at that time were
Speaker 5:  the TV upgrade cycles are too long and the margins are too low. Right.
Speaker 5:  And it's like those are good arguments at the time now it's like,
Speaker 5:  yo, do you know how long the iPad upgrade cycle is? 1000 years?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like no one upgrades and they're like, I have an iPad, it does the
Speaker 5:  three apps. I need Sometimes, I can circle things.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna have this iPad until I,
Speaker 2:  My mom is finally hitting the point where some of her apps won't update on
Speaker 2:  her iPad. So she's starting to think about it and I was like, okay, how old
Speaker 2:  do you think it is? She was like, I don't know. Like it's probably like four
Speaker 2:  years old, eight and a half years old, her
Speaker 5:  IPad
Speaker 2:  And it's just now to the point where she's like, it's been a little slow
Speaker 2:  for a while but now there's actually a handful of things I can't do. And
Speaker 2:  I was like, honestly the fact that you just made it eight and a half years
Speaker 2:  without even really thinking about it on this device is pretty
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's a credit apple, right? Yeah, absolutely. They do the software
Speaker 5:  updates, the, the things last like all credit to them, but that's very
Speaker 5:  funny. Yeah. That they were so wor they, this is a reason not to do TV and
Speaker 5:  now it's like people hold on their phones for a million years, they hold
Speaker 5:  on iPads for and all of their revenue is services. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, oh you could have just had that business this whole time.
Speaker 5:  You could have had that business instead of allowing, I dunno, Roku to become
Speaker 5:  a huge competitor. Right. Instead of allowing Amazon to be the number one
Speaker 5:  provider of cheap TVs to everybody so they could,
Speaker 2:  And the ad business on TV is booming, which Apple has been perpetually interested
Speaker 2:  in building a real ad business. Like it's kind of, it's
Speaker 5:  Also there, it's just very funny to me to be like they all the reasons
Speaker 5:  they didn't do a TV were like worse reasons to not do something
Speaker 5:  than all the reasons they should not have made a car. Like
Speaker 5:  I'm sure people are gonna laugh at us that we started talking about the car
Speaker 5:  and we ended up with Apple should make a tv, I think Apple should make a
Speaker 5:  TV but they should have done it a million years ago. Right. In instead
Speaker 5:  of this thing, which some of the reporting here is fascinating
Speaker 5:  that one of the reasons they had the car project was because the engineers
Speaker 5:  were bored after doing the watch wanted the next big thing and Tim Cook didn't
Speaker 5:  want them to go to Tesla. Right. And it's like, well If, you got a bunch
Speaker 5:  of engineers and you're like do a fake car, like you haven't accomplished
Speaker 5:  anything.
Speaker 2:  Build me a thing Johnny and I considered,
Speaker 5:  It's like there's no, you literally now at this point have not accomplished
Speaker 5:  anything. Right. But even at the time it's like
Speaker 5:  all we all we're spending money and you not going to Tesla is a weird,
Speaker 5:  there's a weird logic in there. Yeah. Because it's not like they
Speaker 5:  were, they were working on the iPhone the whole time. Right. They were working
Speaker 5:  on a car that wasn't shipping. Right.
Speaker 2:  Well and I also, I I wonder how much the
Speaker 2:  part of the story that is all these folks being moved to generative AI
Speaker 2:  is actually about just sort of being smart about resources
Speaker 2:  in a complicated time in the economy. I would believe that in
Speaker 2:  almost every case that it actually makes more sense for Apple to
Speaker 2:  have its highly paid employees working on a thing that
Speaker 2:  everyone agrees is going to be a gigantic growth industry in a lot of ways
Speaker 2:  in the next decade versus kind of continuing on this lark.
Speaker 2:  But it's Apple. Like Apple can afford to do both those things at the same
Speaker 2:  time if it wanted to. So it does mean that at some point there was someone
Speaker 2:  within Apple who was just like, it's time to call this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that person was Tim Cook. I
Speaker 2:  Think you're
Speaker 5:  Probably right. I think he is like, I'm no closer to this couch moving than
Speaker 5:  I was before.
Speaker 2:  And also Siri potentially worse than 10 years ago.
Speaker 5:  Like, dude, I have put the chat GBT shortcut on my
Speaker 5:  action button and it's just like very obvious what Apple should do with Siri.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Kill it and give it to chat GBT
Speaker 5:  They should buy open ai. Like, I don't know. And Siri just now makes horrifying
Speaker 5:  videos of people lighting things on fire.
Speaker 5:  Like Siri, show me a picture of my family and it's like, which is,
Speaker 5:  sorry, I, I just keep, I keep looking at videos generated by Soar up by Open
Speaker 5:  AI and I'm like, this shouldn't threaten anyone because all of these videos
Speaker 5:  are slightly terrifying. Yeah. You see the one of the guys
Speaker 5:  smoking No. Where he like magics the cigarette up in his hand, it sort
Speaker 5:  of like lights on fire and then it brings it to his mouth. That's badass.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. I love that. I just wanna read this line from the Times piece,
Speaker 5:  which again, it's full of just cutting aside effectively
Speaker 2:  The story's really good. We'll we'll put it in the show notes. It's, everyone
Speaker 2:  should read it
Speaker 5:  But at the end of it,
Speaker 5:  I mean just, I'm just gonna read it to you. Apple's dead car project will
Speaker 5:  be survived by its underlying technologies.
Speaker 5:  It's like, oh now you're just writing an obituary. Yeah. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  The comedy plants, this is loved by many in
Speaker 2:  The community.
Speaker 5:  No, this is the auto cutting line in your interviews on Wednesday with the
Speaker 5:  New York Times, people who worked on the project praised the decision to
Speaker 5:  shutter it. That's bad.
Speaker 2:  Brutal.
Speaker 5:  That's bad. Yeah, it's a lot. I think it is In is
Speaker 5:  fascinating to consider what if they built the other thing, it's fascinating
Speaker 5:  to consider this decision in the context of deciding to launch the Vision
Speaker 5:  Pro, which by all accounts, you know, I think
Speaker 5:  some people have given it back. There's some reports on the return rates,
Speaker 5:  there's some, but like people know what it is now. No more mystery, no
Speaker 5:  more hype balloon. It's a VR headset that some people really like and some
Speaker 5:  people do not. And they have a long way to go for that to become a mainstream
Speaker 5:  project. And it's like you decided to launch this thing that kind of doesn't
Speaker 5:  work just to learn something about what you need to do. Right.
Speaker 5:  And you never shipped one mid-size crossover.
Speaker 2:  I mean, I actually don't think that's that complicated. And we should move
Speaker 2:  on from this. Yeah. This is, the Apple car is going to loom large
Speaker 2:  in my life forever, so I'm sure we'll talk about it again. But I think with
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro, I see two big differences. One
Speaker 2:  is that it's a thing Apple can just do, right?
Speaker 2:  Like you can't just put a car on the road and see what happens.
Speaker 2:  We've seen a bunch of that. It's gone real bad. Yeah. And Apple
Speaker 2:  to its credit not interested in playing that kind of game. But it's also
Speaker 2:  a lower stakes thing for Apple to try to
Speaker 2:  figure out in so many ways. Right? It's, it's an ecosystem. Apple can control.
Speaker 2:  It's a game, it can sort of play on its own, at its own pace. You don't have
Speaker 2:  to be responsive to this gigantic car market that is moving
Speaker 2:  in lots of directions all at the same time. Like I, I had the same thought
Speaker 2:  that both of these things feel like unfinished experiments. And it's interesting
Speaker 2:  that one launched and the other didn't. but it also seems like
Speaker 2:  the experiment that is the Vision Pro is a lot easier to tolerate being a
Speaker 2:  mess than a self drive self-driving car.
Speaker 5:  Fair. Yeah. Fair. But I, I just think there's some part of Apple. It's very
Speaker 5:  different, right? That's like, well let's see what happens. Right? Like that's
Speaker 5:  not Apple. And I think with the Vision Pro there's like a, there's
Speaker 5:  a gap between how the company's talking about that product as though it is
Speaker 5:  finished in The future and the reality of that product, which is what is
Speaker 5:  as good as it gets. Yeah. Agreed. Right? Like let's see what happens in like
Speaker 5:  the Apple Watch. Let's see where this needs to go versus the, the car, which
Speaker 5:  is just 10 years of where
Speaker 2:  It needs to go is away
Speaker 5:  Where needs to go. Alright, we should take a break. We're gonna come back.
Speaker 5:  Warren Fine's gonna join us and we're gonna talk about what happened to the
Speaker 5:  Supreme court this week.
Speaker 5:  We're back. Lauren Feiner here. Welcome Lauren. Thanks.
Speaker 1:  First time on The. Vergecast. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Excited about it.
Speaker 5:  Lauren is our brand new policy reporter here at The. Verge, very
Speaker 5:  exciting because the policy news is off and running already
Speaker 5:  in 2024 and it's election year. So welcome. Thank you. Nope, no pressure.
Speaker 5:  And when I say the policy news is already up and going this week, there was
Speaker 5:  a very big Supreme court hearing about two bills in Texas
Speaker 5:  and Florida that purport to regulate how big platforms can
Speaker 5:  do content moderation. I, the listeners are not gonna be
Speaker 5:  surprised to know that. I think both of them are blatantly constitutional
Speaker 5:  'cause they're, they're government speech regulations at their core and that's
Speaker 5:  why they're in front of the Supreme court. Tell us what's going on with that
Speaker 5:  hearing, how it got there where we are.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, so these laws, each of them are a little bit different, but they're
Speaker 12:  both essentially trying to get the tech platforms, you know,
Speaker 12:  think of the major platforms, meta, Google, YouTube, Twitter,
Speaker 12:  Twitter or now x to
Speaker 12:  regulate, to enforce their policies in ways
Speaker 12:  that would be consistent or not discriminate
Speaker 12:  by viewpoint between different users. So they're basically trying
Speaker 12:  to tell the platforms what they have to host on their sites.
Speaker 2:  And the genesis of both of them is like the, the
Speaker 2:  worries about conservative censorship on social media. Right? Is that, is
Speaker 2:  that where both of these came from?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, exactly. Okay. I mean they were enacted in 2021
Speaker 12:  after Donald Trump notably was kicked off of
Speaker 12:  major platforms. Yeah. After January 6th, so Oh,
Speaker 2:  Okay. So it was literally a direct response to that. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Okay. Pretty direct. But you know, I think these censorship concerns have
Speaker 12:  been existing in the Republican party for a while. So. I. Don't think that's
Speaker 12:  necessarily the only thing, but definitely drove a lot more conversation
Speaker 12:  around that.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And this case seems like it was made to go to the Supreme court.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. Right. Like this has kind of always been, you've been saying this
Speaker 2:  sort of all along like it was destined Yeah. To be one of the ones,
Speaker 5:  Not to get too into the procedural history here, but what you have
Speaker 5:  is a law in Texas and a law in Florida. They're in different court
Speaker 5:  systems, like they're in different circuits. So I think it was Texas
Speaker 5:  got stayed and Florida got to go through and then the appeals courts
Speaker 5:  disagreed and then that's how you get to the
Speaker 2:  Oh the Supreme court. So it was like a, who's right about what this should
Speaker 2:  be Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I's in this, in this corner of the country this bill is going through and
Speaker 5:  in this corner of the country, the court saying it's unconstitutional. You've
Speaker 5:  got a circuit split, you've got a first Amendment problem.
Speaker 5:  Clarence Thomas would you like a word? Like, and he's
Speaker 2:  Been begging for this very kind of case for years
Speaker 5:  And now he wants very badly. Yeah. So that actually I think is the,
Speaker 5:  the piece of the puzzle I think is the most important. These are conservative
Speaker 5:  states with the conservative we're governors, conservative attorney generals,
Speaker 5:  they're mad that Donald Trump gets kicked off the platforms and in response
Speaker 5:  they pass these laws that on their face are like, here are some rules we
Speaker 5:  think the platforms should follow. And then on in the details are like,
Speaker 5:  and here's how we would like you to moderate Facebook. Right, right. Which
Speaker 5:  is just again, straightforwardly a government speech
Speaker 5:  regulation. Right. But they're, it's conservatives making the government
Speaker 5:  speech regulation. So in the run up to this, did anybody reckon with that?
Speaker 5:  'cause usually the conservatives don't like a regulation
Speaker 5:  is my understanding of conservative principles. I
Speaker 12:  Mean you've got a lot of really strange alliances or you know, just
Speaker 12:  seeing where people stand on this because even net choice has a lot of
Speaker 12:  conservatives.
Speaker 5:  Net choice is the, the lobbying firm.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Net Choice is the trade association that represents like pretty much
Speaker 12:  all the major platforms and they're the ones that have brought
Speaker 12:  this to the Supreme court essentially. And you know, they have
Speaker 12:  conservatives high up in their organization and you know, they
Speaker 12:  feel strongly that this shouldn't be law So I think where you see people
Speaker 12:  netting out on this varies a lot. It's,
Speaker 12:  you know, no longer something I think that we really see falling on like
Speaker 12:  conservative or liberal. It's really based on, you know,
Speaker 12:  other forms. Like is it more populist? Yeah. Or is it more just like
Speaker 12:  traditional conservative.
Speaker 5:  That's one of the things that I just think is utterly fascinating about this
Speaker 5:  is these platforms are really big. They have the re they
Speaker 5:  have the revenues of a country. Like they, I think
Speaker 5:  Facebook has more revenue like by GDP than like some countries.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, Google definitely does. Like these are just big, rich
Speaker 5:  companies are global. It's hard to think about who or how you could regulate
Speaker 5:  them. They don't have competition, which is weird
Speaker 5:  and someone from YouTube is gonna like jump through the wall and be like
Speaker 5:  TikTok, but like not really, you know? Right. And then in particular in the,
Speaker 5:  in the sort of Donald Trump moment, they all took the same action
Speaker 5:  And so it's like they're not even competing to have like we have the platform
Speaker 5:  with the most Donald Trump. Like they all took the same kind of action
Speaker 5:  and it's like who would regulate them? And it's very, it just, to me it's
Speaker 5:  particularly strange that you have conservative states
Speaker 5:  who are like, we're gonna just pass regulations about these platforms. And
Speaker 5:  it, I think for most people that that's
Speaker 5:  counterintuitive. But like you're saying there's other ways of perceiving
Speaker 5:  these laws like far more populist obviously like
Speaker 5:  hating on big tech companies is very popular in Washington DC
Speaker 12:  Yeah. And I think you're actually seeing like another weird alignment on
Speaker 12:  just like the competition question here because we've seen
Speaker 12:  some like more usually more liberal like
Speaker 12:  competition groups saying like, Hey, you know, we don't necessarily love
Speaker 12:  these laws but we're concerned about them being struck down. And then what
Speaker 12:  that means for just never being able to regulate the tech companies. Yes.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Interesting. Yeah. So I think you have like another weird alignment
Speaker 12:  where you see like more liberal groups saying something like that and
Speaker 12:  kind of taking the Republican ag side, even if they
Speaker 12:  don't totally agree, but just being more fearful about what would happen
Speaker 12:  if you know these laws are struck down and what would that means for The
Speaker 12:  future of tech regulation in general. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  There's been a lot of that over the last few years I think where yeah, where
Speaker 2:  there are some people who are like, I want regulation but not this.
Speaker 2:  And then others who are like, we can't overregulate but we have to
Speaker 2:  regulate. It's like wait.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a lot.
Speaker 2:  Everybody's trying to find this like maybe impossible
Speaker 2:  middle ground that everyone is convinced exists. And you had a great quote
Speaker 2:  in the piece you wrote leading up to the, the hearing on Monday
Speaker 2:  where they were basically like, I've never seen the regulation that does
Speaker 2:  what I think needs to be done, but I'm still convinced that it exists or
Speaker 2:  is possible. Yeah. And I think we've now spent a long time
Speaker 2:  trying to figure it out if it's possible. And it doesn't necessarily seem
Speaker 2:  like we're any closer to it than we were of like this
Speaker 2:  nuanced perfect thing that addresses the right things and not the wrong things.
Speaker 2:  And a lot of what they talked about in this hearing was all the wrong things
Speaker 2:  that this, these bills might address if they're put into law.
Speaker 2:  And I don't know, it just all feels like every time we try to do this in
Speaker 2:  a small way, it all becomes sort of the size of the universe because that's
Speaker 2:  what happens on these platforms and everybody just kind of like
Speaker 2:  runs and hides and no one knows who they're gonna end up with at the end
Speaker 2:  of it. It's very strange. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  I think that's what you saw a lot of the justices struggling with on Monday
Speaker 12:  was just like, where does the, where does this end? Like if we
Speaker 12:  strike down these laws, can we have no tech regulation then?
Speaker 12:  And I think that's what concerned them about how these cases were
Speaker 12:  brought to them is like, do we have to make like a huge sweeping
Speaker 12:  statement on future regulation or can we like
Speaker 12:  tailor this to certain companies and or like certain
Speaker 12:  forms of companies that are really engaged in like expression.
Speaker 2:  What was the vibe of the hearing? Like I think the, the Supreme court justices
Speaker 2:  have been pretty honest over the years about not being the
Speaker 2:  greatest at understanding technology. Like I think it was Elena Kagan
Speaker 2:  who said like, we're not the nine foremost experts on the internet. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Not that long ago.
Speaker 5:  And I just wanna point out that that's bad.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Like it's like you should try harder get Gen Z on the
Speaker 5:  Supreme
Speaker 2:  Court now let's go,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, like you're nine unelected weirdos. You get to decide everything
Speaker 5:  you about American life. Figure out how to use your phone man. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 5:  I dunno,
Speaker 2:  Sorry. No, I agree. I'm with you. But there's still, and I think part of
Speaker 2:  why we've seen the Supreme court not take these huge stances yet is because
Speaker 2:  of that they seem sort of unwilling to make things Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Make big SW gestures. Sorry I just don't by caveman lawyer like figure
Speaker 5:  it out dude. Oh sure. No listen
Speaker 2:  This is, if we litigate, is the Supreme court a good idea?
Speaker 5:  How will we use our abundant power? Like shut up. I dunno. You're there.
Speaker 5:  You're there for life. All right. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  But what was it, what was it like in the room? Like actually kind of watching
Speaker 2:  them ask these questions and try to figure this out in real time? What were
Speaker 2:  the vibes like?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, So I wasn't in the room directly but just listening to the arguments
Speaker 12:  I think, and especially compared to last year when we had
Speaker 12:  Gonzalez v Google, which was a case about section two 30 and that
Speaker 2:  Which Supreme court ended up pretty much just punting on. Yeah. They're like,
Speaker 2:  ah, we don't know.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. And I think it was those arguments where Kagan said that quote that
Speaker 12:  you said, okay. And you know those arguments you could tell they're
Speaker 12:  really struggling with like how does the technology work and what are the
Speaker 12:  implications? And so that was a question I had going in was like, are we
Speaker 12:  gonna see the same thing this time? But what
Speaker 12:  first Amendment experts I talked to before the hearing told me
Speaker 12:  were basically like, you know, this is really a case about the first Amendment.
Speaker 12:  Whereas like that was section two 30 that was a little bit more in the weeds.
Speaker 12:  This court, they know the first Amendment, they're pretty strong on the
Speaker 12:  first Amendment. So you know, I think there was a feeling that they would
Speaker 12:  be on a little bit more stable ground there just like knowing what they
Speaker 12:  would be talking about or the sorts of questions they should be asking.
Speaker 12:  And yeah, it's about the technology and like how things work, but
Speaker 12:  fundamentally it's a first Amendment question about, you know, can you regulate
Speaker 12:  businesses around speech So I. Think we saw more of that
Speaker 12:  confidence in this hearing compared to the Gonzalez arguments
Speaker 12:  where you know, you were more able to see like they're asking questions
Speaker 12:  that get to the heart of the first Amendment and yeah, So I,
Speaker 12:  I think there was more of a sense that they knew what they were coming in
Speaker 12:  here wanting to do, but at the same time I think they
Speaker 12:  were struggling with figurine out how they were going
Speaker 12:  to rule on this because the cases came to them
Speaker 12:  as facial challenges. Meaning that net choices basically
Speaker 12:  asking for kind of an all or nothing ruling
Speaker 12:  here. Like can you just say like, this category of
Speaker 12:  law is bad as opposed to saying like,
Speaker 12:  you know, we think that this, these laws as applied to these
Speaker 12:  companies or these circumstances should not be allowed.
Speaker 12:  Okay. And that would give them a little bit more flexibility. So, I think
Speaker 12:  when what you saw was the justices kind of prodding at
Speaker 12:  what are the like outward bounds of what we could do here. And you know,
Speaker 12:  we heard them asking about Etsy and Uber and it's like what do these companies
Speaker 12:  have to do with anything? But I think that's where you see
Speaker 12:  them trying to figure out like, is there a way to do this where we don't
Speaker 12:  preclude any regulation of the tech companies and like maybe
Speaker 12:  we focus in on the companies that really are engaged in speech.
Speaker 2:  What did Etsy and Uber have to do with anything?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean I think basically they're saying like, you know, can this
Speaker 12:  apply to like any tech company? Like, you know,
Speaker 12:  Etsy has some speech in that, you know, you could leave comments on
Speaker 12:  a, a seller, a seller's site or something like that. Or you know, Uber
Speaker 12:  you can chat with the driver.
Speaker 5:  I would just point out Etsy is one of the most dramatic websites in the entire,
Speaker 5:  like it is constant moderation driver. Oh yeah. Like all the time.
Speaker 5:  Casey Newton a Platformer and Zoe reported out that in
Speaker 5:  the middle of the Israel Palestine war Etsy
Speaker 5:  is like moderating whether or not you can sell stuff that says from the river
Speaker 5:  to the sea on it. Mm. That's a straight content moderation. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  should the government force a store to carry products
Speaker 5:  it doesn't want to sell is like an open question. Right. So, I The justice
Speaker 5:  is being like, what about Etsy is like, no dude. Like Etsy is f full of
Speaker 5:  con it's full of user generated content that the company moderates. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, of course this touches Etsy and it, I, there is a
Speaker 5:  a moment in this hearing where there was like some debate about what a
Speaker 5:  website is and I had the reaction like, well this is why The Verge exists.
Speaker 5:  Like the Supreme Court is like, what is a website? I was like, well here
Speaker 5:  we go. That just comes Kool-Aid manning into the room. Like I'll tell you,
Speaker 5:  our publication is founded the inside that knowing what a website is will
Speaker 5:  be very important to The future of the world. Like here we are.
Speaker 5:  And the lawyer for Net Choice was like, we can just set aside
Speaker 5:  Gmail and these other problems you've raised. 'cause this law definitely
Speaker 5:  covers websites. And I was like, Gmail's a website
Speaker 5:  famously a website. Like that's how most people
Speaker 5:  experience Gmail. And you would just have this like really
Speaker 5:  fine sort of
Speaker 5:  philosophical delineation of things that all feel like the same thing
Speaker 5:  and like the Supreme court inventing these categories. And it felt to me
Speaker 5:  like they wanted to find a category that was like, what if we just
Speaker 5:  regulate Facebook? Right. What, what? And it kept, I believe they kept calling
Speaker 5:  them the classic social media networks Mm. As though that was like a
Speaker 5:  well-defined, it's like
Speaker 2:  In the antitrust thing where all of these fights end up being about market
Speaker 2:  definition. Yeah. It feels like with so much of this stuff, it's just
Speaker 2:  how do you draw the boundaries around this thing that we can talk about
Speaker 2:  Facebook and Reddit and x and
Speaker 2:  a couple of other things without talking about any comment,
Speaker 2:  anyone leaves anywhere on the internet and it just seems it's so leaky.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. As you get down and it just gets, it just gets murkier and murkier
Speaker 2:  as you get bigger. And I think the question of like, can the government tell
Speaker 2:  Facebook how to moderate Facebook is again sort of on its face unconstitutional.
Speaker 2:  Right.
Speaker 5:  And that's by the way she Lauren said facial challenge. Literally that is
Speaker 5:  what that refers to. Yeah. Like on its face is this law unconstitutional?
Speaker 5:  Right. And it not as applied or like in this place the government
Speaker 5:  use this law to do this thing that's bad, which is the justices I think we're
Speaker 5:  kind of openly hoping that maybe they could just like kick it back to the
Speaker 5:  court and like do some other stuff or the case we brought in some other way
Speaker 5:  based on some thing that had actually been done as opposed to this big
Speaker 5:  question of like speech regulations, good or bad. Because they
Speaker 5:  kind of wanna be like sometimes good.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Right. Also, the courts stop these laws from going into effect so
Speaker 12:  early on that there's not really a super developed record for the
Speaker 12:  justices to look at or you know, to see in the real world like, well what
Speaker 12:  sort of bad things happened under this law? What sort of good things happened?
Speaker 12:  Interesting. So, you know, I think some of them were grasping at like, okay,
Speaker 12:  whoa, what do we even do with this? Yeah. We don't really know how this
Speaker 12:  will work out.
Speaker 5:  We have some clips in the argument of various justices asking what
Speaker 5:  I would call searching existential questions. This
Speaker 5:  bookstore is, one is interesting, it's Amy Coney Barrett. What's she, what's
Speaker 5:  she trying to ask here?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, so Amy Coney Barrett was basically trying to get at like our,
Speaker 12:  you know, If you are talking about how these
Speaker 12:  platforms organize content. Isn't that just a judgment? Like
Speaker 12:  isn't all organization judgment? So that's what she was trying to get at
Speaker 12:  here and she was giving the example of a bookstore as kind of
Speaker 12:  an analogy so we could listen to what she said there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's from the clip. They
Speaker 13:  Have to present information to a consumer in some sort of
Speaker 13:  organized way and that there's a limited enough amount of information that
Speaker 13:  the, the consumer can absorb it. And don't all
Speaker 13:  methods of organization reflect some kind of judgment? I mean, could you
Speaker 13:  tell, could Florida enact a law telling bookstores that they have to put
Speaker 13:  everything out by alphabetical order and that they can't organize or put
Speaker 13:  some things closer to the front of the store that they think, you know,
Speaker 13:  their customers will wanna buy
Speaker 5:  So I just wanna point out it is very likely that the Ron DeSantis version
Speaker 5:  of Florida passes along, I was
Speaker 2:  About to say the same
Speaker 5:  Thing. Like that is totally in character for 2024 Florida. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And eventually they'll ban all books that start with d like just for some
Speaker 2:  reason. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No, it's Disney. Get 'em outta here. By the way, DeSantis
Speaker 5:  now on the record saying our don't say gay bill one too far because too many
Speaker 5:  books are getting banned. It's like, well that's what happens, dude. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What's, that's, that's why we don't ban books in America's just a thing that
Speaker 5:  happens.
Speaker 5:  So that to me right, is If. you have any kind of
Speaker 5:  algorithmic If, you have a platform with tons and tons of content. You have
Speaker 5:  any kind of algorithmic filtering you, you need, you have to have it. Otherwise
Speaker 5:  there'll be a fire hose of everything and that will make your platform unusable.
Speaker 5:  And so the, the distinction there that I think I struggle with, everybody
Speaker 5:  struggle with is it makes sense to say you can't tell the bookstore owner
Speaker 5:  how to organize the bookstore when you get to an algorithm saying,
Speaker 5:  here's some stuff that we think you will engage with.
Speaker 5:  Is that like an editorial, first Amendment decision? I think the argument
Speaker 5:  some people make is like, that's not like that should at least be transparent
Speaker 5:  or we should at least give people some control over it. Or these
Speaker 5:  companies are so powerful that the government does have some interest in
Speaker 5:  being like, here's how those should work. But I, I, I don't
Speaker 5:  know, like, it seems like when we talk about this realignment,
Speaker 5:  you, you mentioned liberal antitrust people, that's Tim Wu who's
Speaker 5:  been on the show. He's the one who's like, these are just algorithms, they're
Speaker 5:  not like a newspaper regulate away. Where did the court come down to that?
Speaker 12:  You know, I think we don't know yet where they fall on it. I think,
Speaker 12:  you know, through that questioning, I think we could infer
Speaker 12:  that Amy Coney Barrett is a little bit skeptical of
Speaker 12:  how organization is different from speech
Speaker 12:  itself because she's saying is an organization a judgment?
Speaker 12:  And you know, we saw Florida Solicitor General who was arguing to say like,
Speaker 12:  well you know, the organization is really different here.
Speaker 12:  And he later said, you know, this is, you know,
Speaker 12:  we're not saying how platforms have to organize their content. But then
Speaker 12:  in kind of the same fret is talking about how the law does talk about shadow
Speaker 12:  banning, which is inherently organizing content.
Speaker 2:  Right? Shadow Banning is just taking the book and putting it all the way
Speaker 2:  at the back of the bookstore
Speaker 5:  And importantly not telling the book. Right.
Speaker 2:  Right. Well and I think to your point, one of the things that it seems like
Speaker 2:  is being talked about kind of underneath all of this is that it seems like
Speaker 2:  what these bills want is for it to be a lot more work
Speaker 2:  to ban somebody or remove content. And that it should essentially have to
Speaker 2:  be a person who presses the button and then fills out a form about why they
Speaker 2:  press the button. And I think part of the outcome of that would
Speaker 2:  very clearly be to make it harder to do that moderation. Just because you
Speaker 2:  can't have an algorithm that just pulls stuff out. You essentially have to
Speaker 2:  document every single time that happens. And also to make
Speaker 2:  it so that it is more transparent but sort of more arduous
Speaker 2:  in the name of being more transparent. So I think they wanna make it look
Speaker 2:  less like a series of algorithms that can make these kinds of decisions and
Speaker 2:  more like literally people curating a bookstore. And then I think you're
Speaker 2:  having a very different conversation about what all of this looks like, but
Speaker 2:  that's just so far away from how these systems work now. And I think one
Speaker 2:  of the things that the tech companies have argued, right, is that this thing
Speaker 2:  you're arguing for where there has to be like a person in a room writing
Speaker 2:  a paragraph about every single post that we take off of Facebook is like
Speaker 2:  preposterous and impossible, right? And so it just feels like I, I don't
Speaker 2:  know, I don't know how to connect those ideas in my head that we're talking
Speaker 2:  about algorithms, but we're also talking about a person who is like, let
Speaker 2:  me tell you why I kicked your post off of Facebook because you are, you were
Speaker 2:  mean to everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  The transparency thing, I think they didn't get into as much
Speaker 12:  in these arguments as the, what are called the must carry
Speaker 12:  provisions that platforms have to carry certain content. But
Speaker 12:  I think that's definitely an important element of it too. And I think, you
Speaker 12:  know, you, you could see why someone would wanna know if they're kicked
Speaker 12:  off a platform, why that happened or you know, why something's not being
Speaker 12:  shown to their followers as much. But I
Speaker 12:  think the tech companies would say like that's a huge
Speaker 12:  like resource suck. And also maybe it's gonna make it harder for
Speaker 12:  newer entrants to do to do that because you know, yeah
Speaker 12:  Facebook can tell everyone here's why you were kicked off our platform.
Speaker 12:  But a newer platform is not really gonna have the resources to do that.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. And one of the arguments that has been made kind of around all
Speaker 2:  of this is that any of these regulations just entrench the huge
Speaker 2:  platforms that can afford to do this kind of moderation and take on the litigation
Speaker 2:  risk and pay out the lawyers. Whereas If, you want to start a new
Speaker 2:  thing, good luck, you're gonna get sued by everyone who doesn't like a post
Speaker 2:  the
Speaker 5:  Da. But this is the alignment problem again. But I don't wanna say alignment
Speaker 5:  problem 'cause that's an AI phrase. This is the weird political like
Speaker 5:  shuffle that's happening is like the conservatives are
Speaker 5:  like, what if we had a bunch of regulated monopolies, right? So we'll have
Speaker 5:  like four companies and they'll just like do what we say and then a bunch
Speaker 5:  of liberal academics who are like, we should have more competition are like,
Speaker 5:  what if we also did some speech regulations And it's like, what is
Speaker 5:  happening?
Speaker 2:  Do you hear yourselves? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like wait, what is going on here? Like I don't, who are you people Have you,
Speaker 5:  did you, did you all like literally wake up in the wrong house today?
Speaker 5:  Like I don't understand what's going on. I think we heard a lot of
Speaker 5:  echoes of that split on sort of the right flank of the court and it's a six
Speaker 5:  three court. So it's like the whole court is a right flank right now, but
Speaker 5:  you have far more conservative members on that majority and far
Speaker 5:  less conservative members. And Sam
Speaker 5:  Alito and Clarence Thomas were like, these are common carriers. They have
Speaker 5:  to carry everything. They're Thomas kept on bringing up section two 30
Speaker 5:  like over and over again 'cause he hates it so much. Like he was just like
Speaker 5:  sputtering and everyone's like, that has nothing to do with this. And then
Speaker 5:  you heard Brett Kavanaugh say that like to me like,
Speaker 5:  you know, I'm old, like the funniest things that would like get say in the
Speaker 5:  slash do forums when people would get banned on the slash dot forums. You're
Speaker 5:  like, you're censoring me And somebody be like the government, only the government
Speaker 5:  can censor you. You don't have any first Amendment rights. Like this is like
Speaker 5:  old internet forum poster stuff. So Alito is saying,
Speaker 5:  isn't content moderation just another word for censorship?
Speaker 5:  And that's very Orwellian. Like, we've like made this fake name for this
Speaker 5:  horrible thing and we have a clip of Kavanaugh arguing
Speaker 5:  with Alito and saying, hold on, can we play that clip?
Speaker 14:  Just wanna follow up on justice Alitos questions. And I think he
Speaker 14:  asks a good thought provoking important question and
Speaker 14:  used the term Orwellian. When I think of Orwellian, I think of the state,
Speaker 14:  not the private sector, not private individuals. Maybe people have different
Speaker 14:  conceptions of Orwellian, but the state taking over
Speaker 14:  media like in some other countries and in to, we
Speaker 14:  made clear, the court made clear that we don't wanna be that that
Speaker 14:  country
Speaker 2:  In Supreme court parlance that's such a sick bird
Speaker 5:  Is like maybe you have a different definition of Orwellian. It's stupid and
Speaker 5:  wrong.
Speaker 5:  Have you actually read George Orwell, sir?
Speaker 2:  I think starting an insult with so and so asked a very good,
Speaker 2:  thoughtful question is amazing
Speaker 5:  And it's your fellow
Speaker 2:  Supreme fundamentally misunderstands everything about everything. Yeah, it's
Speaker 2:  very,
Speaker 5:  So that's right. There's a, that's weird. Like that's on the right and that
Speaker 5:  you can see that split between should we use some speech regulations? Should
Speaker 5:  we like dress them up or should we be the
Speaker 5:  place with the first Amendment? Did you, do you see that like indicating
Speaker 5:  how it might go?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean I think,
Speaker 12:  I think that, you know, if you're seeing like Kavanaugh and Amy Coney Barrett
Speaker 12:  asking these questions, you know, I think you're probably gonna see the
Speaker 12:  liberal justices aligned in in some way on those kinds of things.
Speaker 12:  you know, I think maybe we'll still see Alito and Clarence
Speaker 12:  Thomas out on their own.
Speaker 5:  Clarence Thomas is gonna issue a one page descent that just says, fuck Section
Speaker 5:  two 30. Yeah. Sign Clarence. you know, just like in
Speaker 5:  Crayon.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, but I mean I think that's kind of, it's a somewhat good sign for net
Speaker 12:  choice that, you know, they're seeing these alignments, but
Speaker 12:  at the same time, you know, from analysis I've seen after
Speaker 12:  the arguments, I think, you know, net choices is maybe not gonna get as
Speaker 12:  sweeping of a decision as they had hoped for because the
Speaker 12:  justices we're looking for like, you know, where can we regulate tech
Speaker 12:  companies or where could we at least leave open the option that that could
Speaker 12:  happen? And like, do we really have to rule in a way that
Speaker 12:  says like any kind of law, like this is like for sure
Speaker 12:  unconstitutional.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This might be just a stupid procedural question, but is this the kind
Speaker 2:  of thing where net choice can come in and say we'd like
Speaker 2:  a gigantic sweeping epic decision one way
Speaker 2:  or the other? Like this is the moment gavel down on the internet and the
Speaker 2:  Supreme court can say like, no, but we are gonna do this very tiny thing
Speaker 2:  in the middle that way. That's pretty
Speaker 5:  Much exactly what the Supreme court loves to do. That's their favorite move.
Speaker 5:  Okay. By far. Like in the history of the Supreme court.
Speaker 2:  But I mean in this case, especially like net choice is very loudly saying
Speaker 2:  this is gigantic. And the Supreme Court can be like, shut up, we're still
Speaker 2:  gonna do this tiny thing. They can still do that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What, what ways do you think they could do that? Lauren? Yeah,
Speaker 12:  From what I've seen it, it seems like they could probably just, you know,
Speaker 12:  remand this to the lower courts and say like, you need to develop a fuller
Speaker 12:  record or, you know, just kind of give more guidance on, you know, how
Speaker 12:  you should be deciding this. So yeah, they can, they can throw it back to
Speaker 12:  the lower courts and just, you know, kind of, or carve out some
Speaker 12:  middle path of how they wanna decide this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The justices did in the oral arguments, ask the lawyers for both sides
Speaker 5:  several times. How would you write this opinion? Let's just straight up like,
Speaker 5:  what, what would, what would you do?
Speaker 2:  Here's my laptop. You do it
Speaker 5:  Because it is such a fundamentally complicated thing, right? In
Speaker 5:  particular two state attorneys general, when you're like, actually write
Speaker 5:  the rule and enforce it, it's pretty easy to trip them up and the
Speaker 5:  justices were able to trip them up over and over again. For example,
Speaker 5:  let me come back to noted forum poster Brett Kavanaugh.
Speaker 5:  That man is definitely like a poster in his area. Oh yeah. You can feel it.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. There is a great daily beast headline that was like, God, help us,
Speaker 5:  Brett Kavanaugh might save their first Amendment. Like that's, that's his
Speaker 5:  vibe. Literally. He's reminding them
Speaker 5:  that the first Amendment is about the government. Can we play that clip
Speaker 14:  In your opening remarks? You said the design of the first Amendment
Speaker 14:  is to prevent suppression of speech end quote.
Speaker 14:  And you left out what I understand to be three key words in the first
Speaker 14:  Amendment, or to describe the first Amendment by the
Speaker 14:  government. Do you agree by the government is what the first
Speaker 14:  Amendment is targeting? I,
Speaker 15:  I do agree with that, your Honor, but I don't agree that there is no first
Speaker 15:  Amendment interest in allowing the people's representatives to
Speaker 15:  promote the free exchange of ideas.
Speaker 2:  Another sick burn by Kavanaugh though, like seriously as, as like
Speaker 2:  Supreme court shadiness goes like he's tearing it up. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Tearing it up. He's just like, what are you doing, man? And that's, again,
Speaker 5:  that's on the right. Like I, I think you would expect these kinds of questions
Speaker 5:  from the three liberal justices. They're not obviously as
Speaker 5:  motivated by the banning of Donald Trump as some of the conservative
Speaker 5:  justices. And then Kavanaugh is just like, hold up like
Speaker 5:  by the government. Like that's the thing, right? Like, and this argument
Speaker 5:  in response that he got, which is the people's representatives, like our
Speaker 5:  lawmakers have some, they should pass laws that
Speaker 5:  allow for the free exchange of ideas is like kind of a new argument.
Speaker 5:  Mm. Right. Like the, the idea that we need government speech
Speaker 5:  regulations so that Facebook doesn't suppress, like that's a
Speaker 5:  winding path of logic that
Speaker 5:  I think is like a hard sell.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean I think, you know, it seems like
Speaker 12:  no one has figured out how to do this in a clean way. How to pass
Speaker 12:  speech laws for the internet that don't run afoul of the first Amendment,
Speaker 12:  but do get the sort of outcomes that people want on the internet. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  So I. I mean, I don't really know what the answer will be if there is a
Speaker 12:  way to do that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 2:  This is such a new problem, right? I mean I think they, they talked a lot
Speaker 2:  about newspapers in this case. I think one of the, one of the big open questions
Speaker 2:  is can you regulate Facebook? Like you would regulate a newspaper?
Speaker 2:  And I don't know what the answer will be, but it seems like, no, for
Speaker 2:  lots of reasons, but one of them is that, like, it, imagine if every single
Speaker 2:  person on earth got the same newspaper, like maybe we would think about it
Speaker 2:  differently. And that is fundamentally what something like Facebook is.
Speaker 2:  And it, and, and, and I guess this is where my favorite quote from the whole
Speaker 2:  thing was, it, was it Alito that asked how much YouTube would weigh if it
Speaker 2:  was a newspaper? Oh,
Speaker 12:  I forget who it
Speaker 2:  Was. I think it was Alito, I could be wrong, but one of them asked if YouTube
Speaker 2:  was a newspaper, how much would it weigh? Which is on its face a totally
Speaker 2:  insane question, but actually kind of in context makes sense. Because the
Speaker 2:  question is like, can we talk about these new things in the way that we talked
Speaker 2:  about these old things? And I, I, I don't know the answer
Speaker 5:  By the way is 50,000 pounds, that's
Speaker 2:  How much YouTube would weigh.
Speaker 5:  The Washington Post literally has a headline, oh here's a headline. Here's
Speaker 5:  how much a YouTube newspaper would weigh Justice Alito.
Speaker 2:  That
Speaker 5:  Seems low. And they, they calculated it at 50,000 pounds. It seems
Speaker 5:  low 1 billion words of daily YouTube output.
Speaker 5:  50,000 pounds newspaper. That's the answer. I mean, fair
Speaker 2:  Enough. They asked an answer just as Alito,
Speaker 5:  It's a big newspaper, it's a long article. Like it's
Speaker 5:  a very long
Speaker 5:  Okay, continue.
Speaker 2:  But no, but I think that's, that's kind of been the central question of a
Speaker 2:  lot of these things, right? Is can we talk about these platforms in the
Speaker 2:  way that we've talked about anything else before them? And
Speaker 2:  nobody seems to know the answer to that. Even like what is the precedent
Speaker 2:  we're looking at here? Nobody quite knows.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I I think that was kind of a question with the, you know, concept
Speaker 12:  of editorial discretion and you know, talking about a, a case that
Speaker 12:  came before that looked at the Miami Herald and can they be compelled to
Speaker 12:  print an op-ed?
Speaker 12:  And you know, on the one hand you could see the similarities
Speaker 12:  to the Miami Herald and Facebook on the other hand, you might think like,
Speaker 12:  does what Facebook's doing is that really editorial discretion? There's
Speaker 12:  so much information. Like they're not really parsing through
Speaker 12:  all of it. There's just certain things that are flagged or certain things
Speaker 12:  they're looking at. It's, you know, but does that constitute having like
Speaker 12:  an editorial vision? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  And I think we can confidently say that Facebook does not have an editorial
Speaker 5:  vision. It's just, just people yelling at each other in neighborhoods and
Speaker 5:  Facebook marketplace. Yeah, those, that's, those are two,
Speaker 2:  Two things but's how what Facebook is there for, right? Like that's not,
Speaker 2:  they, they all at various points have tried to do editorial things and it
Speaker 2:  mostly goes quite badly. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We should wrap this up. We dunno what's gonna happen. We're expecting an
Speaker 5:  answer in June.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, probably in June or before then.
Speaker 5:  The one thing that I, that didn't come up that I, I hope someone
Speaker 5:  mentions to the Supreme court justices is that
Speaker 5:  there's actually quite a bit of competition. Like
Speaker 5:  Donald Trump owns a social network, his reaction to being kicked off
Speaker 5:  the platforms was to start his own platform. If, you
Speaker 5:  would like to hear from Donald Trump, you, his tweets are available to you.
Speaker 5:  Right. And like there are TikTok does exist and
Speaker 5:  whatever our government currently wants to think about TikTok, it certainly
Speaker 5:  exists right now. Yeah. And that to me is like, well If, you
Speaker 5:  want the platforms with looser rules. You,
Speaker 5:  you can go get them, they're available to you. And that should be,
Speaker 5:  to me it seems like that's the solution. And I think the thing that is probably
Speaker 5:  frustrating to a bunch of folks is that to build a healthy business with
Speaker 5:  happy customers, you usually have to ban the assholes.
Speaker 5:  Like that's just how it goes. Right? But I don't think YouTube is lacking
Speaker 5:  for conservative voices. I don't think Facebook is lacking for
Speaker 5:  conservative voices. But I, but it doesn't seem like,
Speaker 5:  it seems like the, it seems like our government at every level, the Supreme
Speaker 5:  Court, congress, whatever, all these hearings constantly forget that many
Speaker 5:  other platforms exist and sometimes they forget that anything but Twitter
Speaker 5:  exists, right? Yeah. They're like, ask Mark Zuckerberg about Twitter. Do
Speaker 5:  you see any hint of like a more expansive scope? Is that why they
Speaker 5:  were talking about Uber and Etsy so much? Or was that just confusion?
Speaker 12:  I think that's a little bit different, but I think on the question of competition,
Speaker 12:  you know, it makes me think about Ken Buck, the Republican representative
Speaker 12:  who's actually on his way out of Congress.
Speaker 12:  you know, he was a big champion of new antitrust laws
Speaker 12:  for the tech companies. And he did think about it as
Speaker 12:  like, you know what, I do care about censorship on the internet, but
Speaker 12:  I think the way to fix that is to have more competition on the internet
Speaker 12:  to have more platforms. And so he dealt, he looked
Speaker 12:  at that question from the lens of competition,
Speaker 12:  but you know, notably he's leaving Congress
Speaker 12:  and you know, his view isn't shared by
Speaker 12:  maybe the majority of Republicans. I think there is a contingent that does
Speaker 12:  feel like competition might be the answer, but there hasn't been
Speaker 12:  enough brought on board to make these antitrust reforms
Speaker 12:  be able to pass in the house or the Senate yet
Speaker 12:  So I think, you know, there is, there are like seedlings of that
Speaker 12:  thought, but I don't know how far that's gotten us yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it's, it's why all of the stuff happening simultaneously
Speaker 2:  with these cases and the antitrust cases is so interesting because they so
Speaker 2:  directly speak to each other. Yeah. For exactly what you're talking about.
Speaker 2:  Like the, the antitrust cases are about the competition that would
Speaker 2:  theoretically solve some of these problems. And by solving some of these
Speaker 2:  problems in other ways with moderation and things like that, we're actually
Speaker 2:  changing the way that the competitive landscape is going to look on the internet.
Speaker 2:  And so these things are just going to keep spinning around each other it
Speaker 2:  seems like for a long time until somebody plants some kind of
Speaker 2:  regulatory or you know, I don't know, legal flag. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And then a lot of things are gonna start to fall out it seems like. And what
Speaker 2:  I wonder for you before we go is does this feel like it has
Speaker 2:  a chance to be the moment the Supreme court
Speaker 2:  sort of plants a flag in some way or another? I think Clarence
Speaker 2:  Thomas in particular has been waiting for his chance for
Speaker 2:  so long now to have strong, loud, aggressive feelings about this in
Speaker 2:  official paperwork. And I think there, there was some indication that this
Speaker 2:  had the chance to be a moment for the Supreme court to really
Speaker 2:  have a strong opinion where it has been so wishy-washy in
Speaker 2:  other cases coming out of the hearing on Monday. Do you have any sense leaning
Speaker 2:  one way or the other about whether this is gonna end up being kind of small
Speaker 2:  or big?
Speaker 12:  I think, you know, if they take some sort of middle route, I still think
Speaker 12:  even that will be pretty significant because anything that says, you know,
Speaker 12:  these kinds of tech platforms are allowed to
Speaker 12:  decide what they carry on their platforms, that's a big deal. Yeah. To have
Speaker 12:  that affirmed by the Supreme court if that's what happens. And you
Speaker 12:  know, at the same time if the court says, you know, we're gonna deal with
Speaker 12:  this little piece of it, but we're not gonna deal with these other things,
Speaker 12:  I think that's also a big deal because they're saying, Hey, we could still
Speaker 12:  regulate the platforms in these other ways, or we're at least leaving open
Speaker 12:  the possibility that there's a constitutional law here that could be created.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, that's right. And you know, we'll see that go up to the Supreme court
Speaker 12:  at some point too probably. But at least you know,
Speaker 12:  we have a better, we'll have a better sense of what's in the realm of
Speaker 12:  possibility or not. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It does seem like we're due for one of these a year. Yeah. For the rest of
Speaker 2:  our lives.
Speaker 5:  She's Clarence Thomas being like, section two 30, get outta my face.
Speaker 5:  He hates it so much. She's given speeches about how much she hates it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it's, oh it's actually like many things with Clarence Thomas. I'm unclear
Speaker 5:  why I would, that's not like a fully reasoned argument. Alright,
Speaker 5:  we'll be through 30 extra minutes of Duncan and Clarence Thomas in a bonus
Speaker 5:  episode. That'll be coming up. Totally kidding. We gotta take a break, but
Speaker 5:  Lauren's gonna stick around. We got a lightning round. We'll be right back.
Speaker 16:  safely.
Speaker 5:  We're back 30 minutes by CL toms.
Speaker 5:  Here we go. Does anybody ever call him Clary toms
Speaker 2:  Cl Toms I think that's the last thing you do when you call 'em cl toms.
Speaker 5:  Look, I am very proud to be American. I think one of the most American things
Speaker 5:  you can do is make relentless fun of the Supreme Court. They're a bunch of
Speaker 5:  weirdos and
Speaker 2:  They'll never see it because they don't know how to use their phones.
Speaker 5:  It's like, it doesn't matter who they are. Liberal, conservative. Just make
Speaker 5:  fun of them. Just like, what? What are you nerds doing? It's great.
Speaker 5:  That's my first Amendment, right? I love that. Bring it Clary.
Speaker 5:  All right. Like
Speaker 5:  vote Patel. That's my whole platform.
Speaker 5:  I will, I will roast these nerds every day of my term. Is your
Speaker 5:  president? It's beautiful. Vote Patel
Speaker 2:  The neg platform.
Speaker 5:  It was, you should go listen the audio of the hearing. It's, it's good. It's
Speaker 5:  important. I just think it's funny to make fun of nerd. Okay, cut
Speaker 5:  that part out.
Speaker 5:  All right. Lightning round. There's actually a lot in this lightning round.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Lauren, you're our guest. Do you wanna go first?
Speaker 12:  Sure. Yeah. So I chose the story about
Speaker 12:  Google, CEO, saying that the Gemini AI
Speaker 12:  diversity mishap was completely unacceptable.
Speaker 12:  So I thought this was an interesting story because it's basically
Speaker 12:  If, you hadn't seen Google's Gemini
Speaker 12:  generated racially diverse Nazis. Yeah. Which very good is
Speaker 12:  kind of offensive for strange reasons.
Speaker 2:  I just wanna say, we talked about this on last week's show for like 45 minutes
Speaker 2:  and that is such a better summation than anything else we can,
Speaker 2:  which is strange for various
Speaker 5:  Reasons.
Speaker 5:  It's so good. It's, I'll say it is, it's also, it's okay
Speaker 5:  to point out. It is hilarious. Oh yeah, yeah. It is the funniest shit
Speaker 5:  in the entire world.
Speaker 2:  It, the fact that it happened is funny. The response was funny. Yeah. The
Speaker 2:  fact that it went all the way up to Sundar Phai having to like send a long
Speaker 2:  internal memo about it.
Speaker 5:  Thompson sent out a newsletter that's like, Sundar should be fired. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because of the black pope that he made is like, dude, everybody
Speaker 5:  just like, just turn the knobs down. Yeah. All of it's funny.
Speaker 5:  Like open some very smart people being the dumbest
Speaker 5:  and carry on. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  I mean I think it is, it's a amusing way that
Speaker 12:  this happened. It also could have happened in a way less amusing way. So
Speaker 12:  I think we're fortunate that it's something that's funny to talk about,
Speaker 12:  but I think Sundar Chi is clearly seeing this as like, you know,
Speaker 12:  this could have been way worse. And like, we can't keep having these errors
Speaker 12:  and it just reminds me how like, you know, OpenAI releasing
Speaker 12:  chat GBT when it did just like spurred all of these
Speaker 12:  companies like racing to put out their own, you know,
Speaker 12:  competitors. And like, here we are with this, like kind of,
Speaker 12:  I don't know, maybe this was a product of being rushed and you know, having
Speaker 12:  something really strange and like uncomfortable happening as a
Speaker 12:  result. And you know, maybe this is some kind of reset for Google thinking.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I mean, yeah.
Speaker 2:  It, do you remember that phase where Mark Zuckerberg was just
Speaker 2:  reflexively apologizing for everything? Yeah. There, there was like a two
Speaker 2:  year phase where anytime anything happened on the internet, Zuck would like
Speaker 2:  do a video in which he like very earnestly apologized. That to me feels like
Speaker 2:  the, the Sundar Phai era we're heading into right now. Where he's just like,
Speaker 2:  whatever is happening. I'm so sorry. We'll, we're doing our best. I
Speaker 2:  don't, I don't understand how we got here or what weird thing we
Speaker 2:  put into Gemini to make it do this, but I'm so sorry. No, they know and we'll
Speaker 2:  do better. They
Speaker 5:  Were like, robot be less racist. Yeah. And the robot was like, so
Speaker 5:  not racist that we're racist again. Like that's what we're doing.
Speaker 5:  I mean, this is, to me, every part of this is funny. So, right,
Speaker 5:  like Google famously did not release its chat bots
Speaker 5:  because they were afraid of bad outcomes and misalignment and bad things
Speaker 5:  happening. Open AI, as you point out, released it, Google gets kicked in
Speaker 5:  the butt, they start releasing things left and right And then you have an
Speaker 5:  entire move of people called effective Accelerationist who are like,
Speaker 5:  no rules, like all the ai, we can like do it. And they're the people who
Speaker 5:  are like, Google went too fast here. Their AI is too woke. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  this is the thing you want,
Speaker 5:  the thing you want is to just like, but not like that put like, but not with
Speaker 5:  so many black people. And it's like, you guys should shut up.
Speaker 5:  Like you should stop saying what you're saying. It's very revealing
Speaker 5:  because the problem with the other AI is it only made white people and you
Speaker 5:  were cool with that.
Speaker 5:  And now it's like, well we, because it's
Speaker 2:  Progress or something.
Speaker 5:  Now we, now you're like, the AI that only makes black people is like that.
Speaker 5:  It's like, you should shut up. Like yeah, you should, you should point out
Speaker 5:  to Google that a that like a racially diverse picture of
Speaker 5:  Nazis is very funny and probably not the intended outcome. And then you should
Speaker 5:  stop talking about how mad you are about it.
Speaker 5:  I just, I just think you should be quiet.
Speaker 2:  And also no one is out here with any actual good ideas about what is
Speaker 2:  supposed to happen in any of these cases. Yeah. They're like, I wanted to
Speaker 2:  be perfectly historically accurate and also help me dream up
Speaker 2:  new things and create things that no human could ever come up with. And it's
Speaker 2:  like, well what? Yeah.
Speaker 12:  I dunno. It kind of just makes you think like, okay, maybe this is a really
Speaker 12:  human thing. Like how do you program, like we want diversity, but not
Speaker 12:  in like historically accurate depictions of Nazis.
Speaker 12:  Like,
Speaker 5:  Do you think there's a whiteboard at Google that's just like labeled the
Speaker 5:  Hamilton conundrum? you know, it's like, should
Speaker 5:  Lynn Manel Miranda be able to use shed menno to make
Speaker 5:  Hamilton too? Well, do you
Speaker 2:  Remember that drill tweet from a million years ago where he's like turning
Speaker 2:  a huge dial that says racism and looking at and looking at the crowd like
Speaker 2:  I'm a contestant on the prizes. Right? Like, that's what Suit our vagina
Speaker 2:  is doing.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. That's where we are. Tr truly every part
Speaker 5:  of this is funny. I can't get, and I just, I'm, I I
Speaker 5:  beg you, if you're like, what I'm mad about is the computer made drawings
Speaker 5:  of black people just shut up. I it will go better for you
Speaker 5:  over time. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well, and also to your point about Google being forced to catch up on all
Speaker 2:  of this stuff, you've got to assume Sundar Phai is also sitting in meetings
Speaker 2:  going, this is why we did this slowly. Yeah. You idiots like
Speaker 2:  this. Google has had this technology forever. Like,
Speaker 2:  and Google loves to remind you that like, oh, what's the T in GPT? Like
Speaker 2:  we did that. That's, that's a Google thing that we did. It's Transformers.
Speaker 2:  We made them and Google was taking it very slowly and then
Speaker 2:  OpenAI just like yoed its way onto the internet. And now here
Speaker 2:  we are. And so like, and like Mark Zuckerberg made the heel
Speaker 2:  turn to being like, I don't care. I just make glasses now. Like Sundar's
Speaker 2:  next move is just to be like, yeah, morons, this is what she wanted. Welcome
Speaker 2:  to the world you asked for.
Speaker 5:  It might be amazing. It might be the best move Sundar ever did. That's
Speaker 5:  what I'm saying. Here's what you wanted Morons. Yeah. But totally out of
Speaker 5:  character. I can't even imagine him saying the word morons.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go get it like an AI voice cleaner. It's just, it,
Speaker 5:  it'll just be sundari issuing like devastating burns to people.
Speaker 5:  He's a very polite man. Yes. We're working to get him on decoder and I hope
Speaker 5:  that we didn't just kill that. We'll see what we will see what happens. I'll,
Speaker 5:  that whole episode of decoder will be like, will you say the word morons
Speaker 5:  to me?
Speaker 2:  Just get him to say each phone name and then we can put it together and he'll
Speaker 2:  say it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I've got a lightning round. I forgot to mention the Lightning round
Speaker 5:  is sponsored this week. Oh yeah. But not for money because
Speaker 5:  no one is that dumb. If. you would like to pay us money. This is the only
Speaker 5:  time I will say the name of a sponsor round. I will sell my integrity If.
Speaker 5:  you sponsor the lightning round for money. But we are not,
Speaker 5:  we didn't take money this week. We took a, an excellent, hilarious tip from
Speaker 5:  our friend Christopher who is the, this week's sponsored Lightning who
Speaker 5:  said,
Speaker 5:  how did you miss this Smeg News? Which is an incredible sentence.
Speaker 2:  My smeg Google alerts really letting me down
Speaker 5:  If. you recall Smeg is a maker of quirky refrigerators.
Speaker 5:  you know the retro refrigerator company
Speaker 2:  As you do? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They have a collaboration with fiat. They've made a Fiat
Speaker 5:  500 with a refrigerator.
Speaker 5:  What That's true. It's, it's the, the seg 500
Speaker 5:  on the Smeg five on the Smeg website.
Speaker 5:  Here's the first line. What is the fridge doing underneath the
Speaker 5:  bonnet of a Fiat 500
Speaker 5:  Smeg and Fiat merge form and function to create an extraordinary item for
Speaker 5:  the Fiat 500 design collection. Because the refrigerator is not just an electrical
Speaker 5:  appliance and a bonnet is not just a car part.
Speaker 2:  Hell yeah. This seems like
Speaker 5:  An April Fool's joke. Then there's a picture of a Fiat 500
Speaker 5:  and it says, an iconic place for food with an arrow pointing to the trunk
Speaker 5:  of the car. It's all true.
Speaker 2:  I would like to make t-shirts that have just on the stomach the phrase an
Speaker 2:  iconic place for food.
Speaker 5:  These two made in Italy brands they've already met in 1950s. It's like a
Speaker 5:  meat. Cute. Aw. And they like, they've been trying to get a fridge that
Speaker 2:  The snake, the snake 500 sounds like, like the last NASCAR race.
Speaker 2:  You've, that ever happens.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You win a fridge at the end
Speaker 5:  For me. Vittorio, this keeps going by the way, actually,
Speaker 5:  there's a lot here. Thank, thank you Christopher again for sponsoring Walking
Speaker 5:  Around Indeed with, with this link, CEO of Smeg Vittorio.
Speaker 5:  Brett Deani. He said, for me, creating the SEG 500 was above
Speaker 5:  all a matter of personal honor.
Speaker 2:  Seriously,
Speaker 5:  Man. This is,
Speaker 2:  This is about my family's legacy.
Speaker 5:  Wait, I you're not that you said that as a joke. That is the
Speaker 5:  rest of the quote. Are you serious? I strongly holy,
Speaker 5:  I strongly believe in this project that pays tribute to the memory of my
Speaker 5:  grandfather. When he founded Seg after the Second World War,
Speaker 5:  one of his first collaborations was creating refrigerators with fiat.
Speaker 2:  Incredible.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's just the whole whatever link to it. Thank you Christopher, for
Speaker 5:  like sponsoring the lightning round with the smeg 500. No thanks to Smeg
Speaker 5:  who paid us no money for this. Yeah. Alright. David, what's yours?
Speaker 2:  I don't know anymore. Mine is. So M wc, the Mobile
Speaker 2:  World Congress in Barcelona. Barcelona. Barcelona
Speaker 2:  was this week surprisingly newsy. MWC, John Porter and
Speaker 2:  Allison Johnson are on our team. We're gonna have them on Tuesdays show to
Speaker 2:  give us the whole rundown. But the, the most personally exciting thing that
Speaker 2:  happened was we actually got like a first person demo of the Humane
Speaker 2:  ai Pin, the mysterious gadget that I'm only,
Speaker 2:  I'm like 90%. It's real. Like
Speaker 5:  I'm not, it's real now. Sam Scheffer is like making videos on the streets
Speaker 5:  of New York with it. Sam, by the way, I keep show it to, to me.
Speaker 5:  Bring it, bring it over. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Come on the show Sam. We'd love to have you back. The people need it. But
Speaker 2:  Alison got a demo. She got to see some at work and had a really interesting
Speaker 2:  experience with it. Like the thing about this Pin, I'm desperate to
Speaker 2:  actually test this thing out because it seems like they did a lot of cool
Speaker 2:  technology to it. Yeah. Like the projector thing seems to work.
Speaker 2:  She had it take a picture and it identified her as a person with a Verge
Speaker 2:  lanyard and all the other stuff in the background. Like seriously impressive
Speaker 2:  technology going in here. But Allison also sort of landed on the question
Speaker 2:  that I think a lot of us have been asking about this device. It's like, what
Speaker 2:  on earth is any of this for? Yeah. Like you made a neat thing that
Speaker 2:  does some of the stuff that you said it was gonna do. It also was super slow
Speaker 2:  and I think overheated on the show floor. Very good. That's like conference
Speaker 2:  demo stuff, whatever. I'll leave that alone. But she kind of got to the end
Speaker 2:  and was like, why, why is this?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It does seem so you can watch a video of it, of that
Speaker 5:  demo while the places we post videos.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think I saw it on our TikTok. Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  A good one. Yeah. Find a Scrolly video place and look for the fridge and
Speaker 5:  it's nine. She asked a question. 19 seconds go by before the answer. That's
Speaker 5:  tough. Oh, that's brutal. That's tough. That's that's not good
Speaker 2:  In which she like made small talk with the person
Speaker 5:  And, and then I started talking and interrupted. Yeah. And I was like, oh,
Speaker 5:  it's doing, it's like I don't know about this. Yeah. She did say,
Speaker 5:  and I think this is a lesson to everyone. She's like, this gadget would be
Speaker 5:  so much cooler if this company wasn't so overbearingly serious about itself.
Speaker 5:  Mm. Right. Like if you're like, this will change the nature of culture
Speaker 5:  and it's like you made a laser that says like your name. I,
Speaker 2:  Well what's funny is like, I think there's been this interesting thing now
Speaker 2:  where we have the, the rabbit R one and we have the Humane ai Pin and they're
Speaker 2:  very much like racing each other to be kind of the nifty AI gadget that everybody's
Speaker 2:  excited about rabbit's. CEO is just like nakedly out
Speaker 2:  there trying to beat Humane to market, which I think is so funny. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  they've just played this so differently Right. Where, where Jesse, the CEO
Speaker 2:  of Rabbit has been out there basically being like, this is like a silly fun
Speaker 2:  thing that we made. We think it's cool. Let's see what happens. Maybe this
Speaker 2:  will be The future. And you're right. And Humane is actually being like,
Speaker 2:  we have changed the paradigm of your life. Yeah. And they're,
Speaker 2:  they just like seem sad in a room together. And it's like, what, what are,
Speaker 2:  what is happening are
Speaker 5:  Doing. I feel like they, everyone is doing a Steve Jobs impression, but they
Speaker 5:  never watched any Steve Jobs videos. Yes. Do you know what I mean? Like it's
Speaker 5:  like they're doing an impression of who was, it was Fast be Steve Jobs,
Speaker 5:  who's like
Speaker 2:  Very,
Speaker 5:  He's like very serious all the time and like very intense and like the real
Speaker 5:  Steve Jobs is like kind of a goofball.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If. you go back and watch. I went back for some reason not that long
Speaker 2:  ago and watched his first iPad reveal. Yeah. It's the most
Speaker 2:  casual, relaxed like man sitting on a chair using a web browser
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Is the whole vibe of the thing. And it was, yeah. He would make jokes.
Speaker 2:  He was funny. Yeah. He was silly. Like that was their whole vibe. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  now everybody remembers him as this like dictator presenter. Yeah. Who
Speaker 5:  Was like, yeah. It's like he would get on stage like, so these are our competitors
Speaker 5:  products. They fucking suck. Huh? Look at this piece of shit. You're like,
Speaker 5:  here's what I made. It's pretty awesome. Yeah. Right. And like every, like
Speaker 5:  the Humane, I dunno, there's something that's like everyone's doing an impression
Speaker 5:  of the wrong thing.
Speaker 2:  Even Apple kind of is increasingly getting serious in, in a way that
Speaker 2:  feels kind of ajoy. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think it's, they're doing an impression of those like the Johnny Ive
Speaker 5:  design videos 'cause Johnny, I didn't like to be on stage. Yeah. So they
Speaker 5:  would make these videos and be like, what is plastic I've invented? It's
Speaker 5:  very beautiful. you know, it's like, what are you doing? And it's
Speaker 5:  like, that didn't work. What worked was the other guy who was like, you know
Speaker 5:  what? I love his records now I put a thousand of 'em in your pocket. Huh?
Speaker 5:  He
Speaker 2:  Pulled the MacBook air out of a sleeve. It was sick. But anyway, so the Humane
Speaker 2:  Pin is supposed to ship, I think at the end of March is the last thing that
Speaker 2:  we've heard that has slipped a little, but it iss close enough that I think
Speaker 2:  we're gonna get these things for real soon. I bought one. I'm very excited
Speaker 2:  about it. I can't believe If,
Speaker 5:  You bought one. I
Speaker 2:  Have so many questions about why I spent
Speaker 2:  $700 on a Humane ai
Speaker 5:  Pin.
Speaker 2:  But I am fascinated by this thing. And every, every little step I get
Speaker 2:  towards being able to make a phone call with a projector when you
Speaker 5:  Come all it, when you're a kid outta the house at 18 and be like, I don't
Speaker 5:  have money for college. I hope you hand them the human AI Pin,
Speaker 2:  I'll frame it be like, this is
Speaker 5:  Your gift. This is for you in lieu of a college education.
Speaker 5:  This thing, it takes
Speaker 2:  19, sell this my son and go on your way.
Speaker 5:  This thing will describe with medium accuracy what you are currently
Speaker 5:  looking at. 19 seconds later.
Speaker 5:  It's like, I am the person wearing The Verge la that's me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. All right. NELI, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  I think I, I'm gonna pick two. I'm gonna pick two. I'm sorry. I'm gonna pick
Speaker 5:  two. I'm shocked. I one, I'm, I'm gonna start with the fun one. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Okay. As you all know, Lauren doesn't know, as
Speaker 5:  David knows Lauren, you're gonna find out I have one dream as editor in chief
Speaker 5:  of The Verge, which is for David to file a story to me and for
Speaker 5:  me to mark it up with a red pen. That's all I want. Very old school.
Speaker 5:  Very old school. I also would love a glass walled
Speaker 5:  conference room where we print out the layout of the magazine and I just
Speaker 5:  move the pages around best. We don't the best have a print magazine. So that
Speaker 5:  dream has long since been, I've just had to let it go. you know, so you,
Speaker 5:  I'm never gonna play professional basketball. I'm never gonna move pages
Speaker 5:  of print magazine around a glass wall conference room. The New York Mag people
Speaker 5:  have a conference room in this office, like stare at it all the time. They're
Speaker 5:  just moving
Speaker 2:  Pages. Do you ever go just move pages around just to see if they notice
Speaker 5:  Blow up the magazine? Yeah. The red pen thing. No.
Speaker 5:  One thing I could do is I could have David print out his Google Docs and
Speaker 5:  Circle pen. Sadly, we don't live in the same place.
Speaker 2:  That's not the reason. Just to be clear, that's not the reason. I don't know
Speaker 2:  about that.
Speaker 5:  So every time a new Stylist Gadget comes out, I'm like, is this,
Speaker 5:  is this it? Is this the thing that will enable me to like circle stuff? Mm.
Speaker 5:  That's all I want. And in particular, circle David's copy in a red pen.
Speaker 5:  The answer for a decade now has been no. We've tried almost every style
Speaker 5:  of gat in this way and they don't work. Google just released an update to
Speaker 5:  Android at M WC Ooh, where Google Docs
Speaker 5:  on an Android tablet. It's called Project Inkwell. You can now mark
Speaker 5:  up with a pen. That's very exciting. The problem is that
Speaker 5:  this requires you to have an Android tablet. It also
Speaker 5:  requires David to file a copy to me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's,
Speaker 5:  You know, challenging problem. We're getting there. I'm just, I'm just thrilled
Speaker 5:  about this. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're getting an Android tablet. We're gonna demo this on the show. It's
Speaker 5:  going to happen.
Speaker 2:  I'm excited about it.
Speaker 5:  I can't look, I can't see Liam right now. I imagine he's vigorously agreeing
Speaker 5:  with me that we're gonna do a demo
Speaker 2:  With me. That's, that's, that is what's happening.
Speaker 5:  He's circling things live on The. Vergecast. That's all I want. This is my
Speaker 5:  dream.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna do it. I would say based on the history of
Speaker 2:  Google Docs being good at things, I would not get your hopes super high.
Speaker 2:  But I believe in this dream for you and I want you to add it.
Speaker 5:  If, you could just add up the number of things that have to be good for this
Speaker 5:  to go. Well, Android tablets, conceptually
Speaker 2:  The Google Docs app
Speaker 5:  On the Android tablet. Android tablet stylus.
Speaker 5:  Actually some of the Samsung stylists are pretty good. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They're getting,
Speaker 5:  They're getting there. But does the Spen support Google Docs markup
Speaker 5:  on
Speaker 2:  Android? It's okay. You just import it into Samsung's proprietary document
Speaker 2:  viewer and then export it
Speaker 5:  Out. It's such a small dream. Just give it to me. Just figure it out. Take
Speaker 5:  all that energy. Shut down Gemini. Put all those engineers on a circle problem.
Speaker 5:  Be like, we'll do the Hamilton conundrum another
Speaker 2:  Day. Said maybe now that the Apple car's gone. Everybody's working on generative
Speaker 2:  AI highlights. This could be you. What's your other one?
Speaker 5:  Like it's TikTok. We gotta talk about TikTok News. We,
Speaker 2:  We should talk
Speaker 5:  About TikTok. So they're in Big Fight. Believe tomorrow is, you're listening
Speaker 5:  to this is the Drop Dead deadline. Mm. So
Speaker 5:  Universal Music Group, which has Taylor Swift usher, everybody you can think
Speaker 5:  of Justin Bieber. I believe I looked at David very knowingly. I was like
Speaker 5:  your favorite.
Speaker 2:  I can, I can confirm you started Harry Styles. Many others.
Speaker 5:  David, the lead of one of David's stories this week was Justin Bieber. So,
Speaker 5:  oh,
Speaker 2:  It was good stuff.
Speaker 5:  With a photo of Justin Biebers. I wanna point out what I'm here for. We've
Speaker 5:  put a lot of the beeb
Speaker 2:  I spent on The Verge
Speaker 5:  Com this week. Spent
Speaker 2:  90 full minutes on Getty Images, looking at pictures of Justin Bieber in
Speaker 2:  public. It's the best thing I did
Speaker 5:  All week. It's a good story. Anyway, universal Own had all the biggest artists.
Speaker 5:  So you can think of, you know, a fight with TikTok over music
Speaker 5:  licensing. They say TikTok is a bully. They don't wanna pay the higher rates.
Speaker 5:  There was a first date that date came, the music went away.
Speaker 5:  The poor woman on TikTok who has all the jobs, her, her sound is gone.
Speaker 5:  Oh no. And so she's just making sad, like increasingly sad tiktoks about
Speaker 5:  her sound being gone.
Speaker 2:  Oh, that's awful.
Speaker 5:  There's like a lot of this happening on the platform. Yeah. And tomorrow,
Speaker 5:  I believe That the, the time that you are currently
Speaker 5:  listening to this Friday, that's what it's called. There you go.
Speaker 5:  Is the drop dead date when the rest of it goes. And TikTok has already started
Speaker 5:  putting, pulling not just Universal's like own
Speaker 5:  music, but anybody who has a publishing deal with Universal, some of the
Speaker 5:  songwriters that are associated with Universal. Right. So even more music
Speaker 5:  is coming off the platform, which I think TikTok thinks it has the leverage,
Speaker 2:  Which is wild. I mean, one of the stats that I read, and I think a lot of
Speaker 2:  this is really fuzzy, so Who knows, but one of the stats that I read is,
Speaker 2:  I think it was something like 30% of the songs,
Speaker 2:  but 80% of the videos with music Yeah. Would suddenly go silent. Like
Speaker 2:  that's a huge number. That's just
Speaker 5:  Of TikTok. Yeah. If. you take Taylor Swift off of TikTok, you've, that's
Speaker 5:  not great. Yeah. And I think what TikTok has learned is like, we
Speaker 5:  seem to be fine. And I, I don't know if that's true. There are no
Speaker 5:  numbers. I I I, we were trying to do some more reporting on it, but
Speaker 2:  It, one thing I've seen that's been really interesting the last few days
Speaker 2:  has been a bunch of up and coming artists who now can't
Speaker 2:  promote their own songs on TikTok. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Basically like a having to figure out a new thing to do and b kind of
Speaker 2:  pleading with their audience, like, keep watching
Speaker 2:  my stuff, follow me. Like it so that it stays on your for you page. Because
Speaker 2:  if I can't put my song on it and you're not following me, the algorithm is
Speaker 2:  not gonna serve stuff. And this is the thing artists have said for forever
Speaker 2:  is that like, when they just make a thing where they talk, it doesn't do
Speaker 2:  as well. So they do covers of, well-known songs so that they get put into
Speaker 2:  that part of the algorithm. Or they do their own songs that people like,
Speaker 2:  so they get served to their fans. But if it's just them talking to camera,
Speaker 2:  that doesn't do as well. Like, just historically, that is a thing I, I've
Speaker 2:  seen a bunch of artists say on TikTok and now it's like, if you're an up
Speaker 2:  and coming artist, the place where people find you is TikTok and
Speaker 2:  So I think it, it's, it's just creating this Interesting, and
Speaker 5:  That's tiktoks leverage, right? That's what they're basically saying. Right.
Speaker 2:  Universal. But then Universal's leverage is Taylor Swift. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 2:  most of the rest of the music people want to listen to and do stuff. But
Speaker 2:  it's like that that spectrum is going to affect the people in so many messy
Speaker 2:  ways. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 12:  Also though, like not having music on so many tiktoks makes
Speaker 12:  TikTok like kind of unusable.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's totally been my experience now. Like it's, it's like one out
Speaker 2:  of every two videos is just awkwardly quiet. And it turned out, watching
Speaker 2:  people do TikTok dances with no music is
Speaker 2:  uncomfortable. Like it's not a
Speaker 12:  Good sign. And it takes you a couple seconds to register that. Like there's
Speaker 12:  no music. It's not that like your volume is
Speaker 2:  Too
Speaker 5:  Low. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's weird. I totally agree.
Speaker 5:  I'm surprised that, you know, YouTube has a much healthier relationship with
Speaker 5:  the universal, like, universal is like, we're very mad about fake Drake and
Speaker 5:  ai and YouTube was like, we made some stuff for you. Like we have a council
Speaker 5:  about ai. Like, I'm surprised that YouTube is not doing more to promote
Speaker 5:  shorts in this moment and to say like, all these creators come over here
Speaker 5:  because that, that is right now their competitive advantage is they have
Speaker 5:  access to all this music. Yeah. They've
Speaker 2:  Been kind of quietly saying things like, you know, we
Speaker 2:  continue to be a good partner to the music industry and stuff like that.
Speaker 2:  but it is weird that like Lyor Cohen who runs YouTube music is not out there
Speaker 2:  being like, you want music? We have all the music. Like, this is, you're
Speaker 2:  kind of right. This is sort of YouTube's best shot.
Speaker 5:  It's Instagram has the correct deals with the industry. Pull people. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're not, they're not pushing it. It's, I I think Universal is basically
Speaker 5:  like, all right, like we just won't be on TikTok. That'll be the end of that.
Speaker 5:  And like, we have to figure out a new way to promote artists. But guess what
Speaker 5:  we do? We're a record label.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's the, there have been ways before that's
Speaker 5:  Historically how we provide value to the artist. But we'll see. I tomorrow
Speaker 5:  I think will be an interesting day. 'cause I, I think it either gets solved
Speaker 5:  or it, if they pull out even more, I think it actually drags on for quite
Speaker 5:  a bit longer.
Speaker 2:  Think you're probably right. Alright.
Speaker 5:  Do you have another one or should you just read?
Speaker 2:  We should just get outta here. We
Speaker 5:  Should get outta here. You don't wanna talk about Wendy's dynamic search
Speaker 5:  pricing? No. They said they weren't gonna it. All right. We've gone over
Speaker 5:  as always, Lauren, thank you so much for joining over our test. Yeah, thanks
Speaker 5:  for having me. Really fun. We'll have to have you back soon. Would love to.
Speaker 5:  Whenever Larry Toms issues his decision.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be a mega chill policy here, so we Oh yeah. We probably won't
Speaker 2:  have much to talk about it. I don't think
Speaker 5:  It'll be great. All right. That's it, Alex. We'll be back next week. That's
Speaker 5:  for Chest Rock Roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.