# Transcript
ID: c90515d0-b651-4ed7-81de-1cb5e4d78749
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6521533430875191771/-8275225816555240808/s93290-US-4823s-1729589866.mp3
Description: The Verge's Victoria Song joins the show to talk about her year of testing smart rings, and which of the many new options is the one you should buy. Then Chris Welch takes us through his testing of the new hearing health features for Apple's AirPods, including the surprisingly intense hearing test you can take right on your phone. Finally, Andrew Webster helps us answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline: why doesn't Apple buy Nintendo, and what would happen if it did?
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of decades
Speaker 1:  of listening to music. Too loud in your headphones. I'm your friend David Pierce
Speaker 1:  and I am sitting here at my computer doing what I call a feeds
Speaker 1:  reboot. I think I've talked about this on the show before, but basically
Speaker 1:  once a year I try to go through and just take all
Speaker 1:  the stuff out of every single feed or thing that I subscribe
Speaker 1:  to on the internet and I define that super loosely, So I. Try to go through
Speaker 1:  all the people I follow on every social platform I go through, all the
Speaker 1:  email newsletters I subscribe to, I go through all the email newsletters
Speaker 1:  I never subscribe to but am somehow on the list for all the channels I follow
Speaker 1:  on YouTube, all the podcasts I subscribe to. Anything that just puts
Speaker 1:  an ongoing list of stuff in front of me at any given time.
Speaker 1:  Once a year I try to go through it all, look at every single source that
Speaker 1:  stuff is coming from and get rid of all the stuff I don't want anymore. Over
Speaker 1:  the course of a year, you just become like a different person with different
Speaker 1:  interests and a lot of the sources you care about get better or worse
Speaker 1:  or more relevant or less relevant. And once a year to just go
Speaker 1:  through the whole list is really helpful. It's super boring
Speaker 1:  frankly, and kind of tedious because most of these platforms don't make it
Speaker 1:  easy to go through and sort of systematically unfollow things.
Speaker 1:  But it's so helpful. I cannot recommend it enough. I try to like put on
Speaker 1:  a movie I've seen before or just a bunch of episodes of the office in a row
Speaker 1:  or when the weather's nice, I'll go like sit at a coffee shop and just over
Speaker 1:  the course of an afternoon burn through all of the feeds that I have.
Speaker 1:  I find this actually most useful in an RSS reader where there's tons
Speaker 1:  of things that like change a bunch or publish too much or publish
Speaker 1:  not enough or go outta business or whatever. And going through and doing
Speaker 1:  a full reset of all the stuff that is being pushed at me is so helpful.
Speaker 1:  Highly recommend it. Again, not a lot of fun, but totally worth it
Speaker 1:  Anyway. One thing you should not unsubscribe to by the way, is The
Speaker 1:  Vergecast. This is a very good podcast. I hope we're doing our best
Speaker 1:  and we have a super fun show coming up today actually, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 1:  two things. First, we're gonna talk about smart rings because I think smart
Speaker 1:  rings are really interesting and this has been in a certain way kind of the
Speaker 1:  year of the Smart Ring. We've gotten a bunch of new entrants, we've gotten
Speaker 1:  new models from some of the companies that have been doing this a while.
Speaker 1:  Vong has tested everything there is to test and has some thoughts, so we're
Speaker 1:  gonna talk about it. We're also gonna talk about the hearing health features
Speaker 1:  on the new AirPods Pro two, which I think are actually pretty
Speaker 1:  cool and exciting, but are also big promises
Speaker 1:  from a company like Apple promising that your AirPods can act as a hearing
Speaker 1:  aid and really make a difference in how you hear and operate in the
Speaker 1:  world. If that stuff works, it's awesome and there should be more like it,
Speaker 1:  but we're gonna see if it works. Chris Welch has been testing it. He knows
Speaker 1:  the answer. We also have a really fun question on The Vergecast hotline.
Speaker 1:  So much stuff to do. But. first I have to finish this
Speaker 1:  feeds reboot. I normally do it in the summer, but this year just couldn't
Speaker 1:  make myself sit down and do it. And now I'm doing it. I'm in it. I'm getting
Speaker 1:  it done. It's gonna be awesome. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. All right, my podcasts have been pruned.
Speaker 1:  The RSS reader is just humming. Everything
Speaker 1:  is great. Let's get into it. So the first thing we're gonna talk about today
Speaker 1:  is smart rings. I don't wear a smart ring,
Speaker 1:  but I'm fascinated by them because for years now they have
Speaker 1:  been this really interesting device kind of trying to figure out what it's
Speaker 1:  for. You wear it on your finger, which gives it access to some really interesting
Speaker 1:  biometric data. You also typically wear it all the time because it's a
Speaker 1:  ring and it's unobtrusive and you just can wear it all the time. So in theory,
Speaker 1:  it has access to all this interesting information about you and the ability
Speaker 1:  to do all kinds of interesting stuff. But it's a tiny gadget
Speaker 1:  with a tiny battery and not that much literal physical room to
Speaker 1:  do stuff. So how do you make a smart ring that's good. And what does it even
Speaker 1:  mean to make one? That's good. Like I said, I don't
Speaker 1:  wear a smart ring, but V song does. She actually wore six, like for
Speaker 1:  months to do a test to see what the best one is. And I wanted to have her
Speaker 1:  on both to see what she learned and whether she figured out
Speaker 1:  what a smart ring is really for. So let's just get into it. V.
Speaker 1:  Hello.
Speaker 4:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  Gadgets.
Speaker 4:  So many gadgets.
Speaker 1:  We just, we talk about watches, we talk about rings, we talk about things
Speaker 1:  on your face. This is just what we do. You wear things and look ridiculous
Speaker 1:  in public and then I ask you about it. This is, this is our lives. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is, you know, it's a burden I'm willing to take. So no one else
Speaker 4:  has to look stupid.
Speaker 1:  It's beautiful. We appreciate it. So the, the thing I mostly want to talk
Speaker 1:  about, I confess, is the new Aura ring a device I have been
Speaker 1:  fascinated by for a very long time, and both think is very interesting and
Speaker 1:  not nearly as interesting as it should be. But we're gonna get to that
Speaker 1:  first, I think I wanna talk about this, this battle royale of smart rings
Speaker 1:  that you did and put yourself through some true like
Speaker 1:  a summer's worth of pain in order to pull up. So
Speaker 1:  first, just like lay the stakes of this experiment for me. 'cause I think
Speaker 1:  to some extent, like most people, even most people listening to this have
Speaker 1:  never given one second of thought to a smart ring in their whole lives. So
Speaker 1:  I'm very curious like how you go through the process of picking the best
Speaker 1:  one and wearing six of them at a time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, So I decided that I was gonna wear six smart rings
Speaker 4:  all at the same time for about, I wanna say
Speaker 4:  two, about two and a half, three months earlier the summer. Which
Speaker 1:  Six fingers by the way?
Speaker 4:  No, no pinky, no thumb. Okay. Because those are, you know, two
Speaker 4:  extremes. So just the middle three.
Speaker 1:  So you did like, you did a brass knuckles
Speaker 4:  Basically? I did, I did. I was a smart ring mafia wife. I love this for
Speaker 4:  you. Okay. For, for a solid three months. Ended up with six ring
Speaker 4:  pants over the summer, despite all my best efforts at
Speaker 4:  sunscreen, it just happened.
Speaker 1:  You must look like you had some like unknowable disease just
Speaker 1:  to have six ring tans.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, they've, they've somewhat faded now because the experiment is
Speaker 4:  over. I declared a winner, but yeah, so you know,
Speaker 4:  it, this idea actually popped into my head a
Speaker 4:  few months before the summer because I knew that the Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 4:  ring was coming and that in order to review that
Speaker 4:  I needed to know about the entire landscape. But, you
Speaker 4:  know, I didn't wanna subject all of our readers to a bunch
Speaker 4:  of little smart ring reviews as I was testing stuff. So
Speaker 4:  what I ended up doing was taking a look at the market, what was currently
Speaker 4:  available was coming out and I decided
Speaker 4:  let's do this gauntlet where I test all of them at the same time
Speaker 4:  and tell you which is the best at being a smart ring.
Speaker 1:  Can I tell you what's interesting about that to me, by the way, and this
Speaker 1:  is, we're we're just, I'm just diving into the results before I even let
Speaker 1:  you finish your question. But the thing that was so striking to me was that
Speaker 1:  a, there were six of these, which I would not have guessed, that there were
Speaker 1:  like six actual viable competitors here and
Speaker 1:  how much the same all six of these are
Speaker 1:  in sort of what they are and what they are trying to be like,
Speaker 1:  God help you having to review this six times in a row. It's like,
Speaker 1:  it's like I feel for the people who have to like review the, the
Speaker 1:  $500 Android phones because they're just all the same
Speaker 1:  and, and at some point it's really helpful to be like, okay, these are basically
Speaker 1:  all the same. Let's run through the like narrow ways in which they are different.
Speaker 1:  But even just reading through the thing, I was surprised at how few
Speaker 1:  sort of differences in ideas these six things had.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So when Smart Rings first were a thing like 10 years ago or so,
Speaker 4:  there were a lot of ideas as to what a smart ring could be.
Speaker 4:  You had something like Ringly and Motive
Speaker 4:  Ringly was just a big fashion thing that didn't do too much.
Speaker 4:  Very unobtrusive, but just really there for people who wanted something fashionable
Speaker 4:  that could also track stuff. And then you had Motive, which had some really
Speaker 4:  big ideas about two factor authentication in a Smart Ring
Speaker 4:  and Oh that's right, fitness tracking on top of that, you know, at
Speaker 4:  some point before they shuttered they were like, we're gonna be able to authenticate
Speaker 4:  you based on your your gate. So there was a lot of weird, interesting ideas.
Speaker 4:  But the one ring that survived that first iteration of
Speaker 4:  Smart Rings was the Aura Ring. And so this second class batch
Speaker 4:  of that had came after it. In many ways they're just trying to
Speaker 4:  do what the Aura Ring got successful at
Speaker 4:  with a Twist, right? So that's what I came up
Speaker 4:  against with a lot of these competitors. I too was surprised
Speaker 4:  at CES this year when I went, I went, oh my God, why are there like
Speaker 4:  a half a dozen smart rings out there? I guess
Speaker 4:  this popped up and has been a thing. Okay,
Speaker 4:  cool. I guess. And then, you know, the really big impetus was Samsung coming
Speaker 4:  out in February going like, Hey, we're getting in on Smart
Speaker 4:  Rings. And So I found myself in a situation where it was, okay,
Speaker 4:  we, we gotta do a deep dive into this and see, because
Speaker 4:  Samsung's big Samsung, Samsung, if they were successful in
Speaker 4:  Smart Rings, you know, that had an opportunity to get other
Speaker 4:  big tech to maybe copy them. So
Speaker 4:  that, that was the whole thought process behind it. And it was, it
Speaker 4:  was real fun to just go through all of them and go like, oh,
Speaker 4:  you have ideas, but they are not even a quarter baked.
Speaker 4:  Forget half baked, you are y you know, If, you watch Great
Speaker 4:  British Bake off. And Paul Hollywood goes and he goes, oh this is
Speaker 4:  underdone. That there were some, there were some
Speaker 4:  rings that were, oh this is, this is extremely underdone.
Speaker 4:  It was the circular ring slim that was my least favorite of the bunch. It
Speaker 4:  just did not do what was supposed to do. It felt really cheap on the
Speaker 4:  finger. They have since reached out to me since I wrote this and they're
Speaker 4:  like, we addressed some of the issues and
Speaker 1:  Which is the story we hear all the time. All the time. And is often not
Speaker 1:  the case.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Often not the case. But like one of the things they said they
Speaker 4:  addressed was the fact that this is, this was the only smart ring that had
Speaker 4:  a haptic motor in it. So I had high hopes because it, it's a
Speaker 4:  smart ring that has ideas about what the smart part of a smart ring should
Speaker 4:  be. That haptic alarm was just the nightmare.
Speaker 4:  'cause you had to tap above a very imperceptible, hard to see logo.
Speaker 4:  And I just ended up smacking my hand most mornings being very frustrated
Speaker 4:  why this thing wouldn't stop buzzing. They said, you can just tap the ring
Speaker 4:  anywhere now and it's fine. And we'll see. We'll see. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I confessed that is one use case I think could be very cool. I, I honestly
Speaker 1:  like the whole reason I wear the Apple watch to bed is
Speaker 1:  to use it as an alarm. I just think it's a nicer thing to wake up to, especially
Speaker 1:  when you sleep next to someone than having like a big loud alarm. So the
Speaker 1:  idea of being able to do that on a ring and not have to wear the watch. Super
Speaker 1:  interesting and exciting to me. Also, neither of the options
Speaker 1:  you just described sound like good, useful, reliable ones. So
Speaker 1:  remains to be seen. Also, we've already talked too much about the circular
Speaker 1:  stem, but notably neither circular nor slim, that's all I'm
Speaker 4:  Gonna say. Notably, no, and it's, it was the least comfortable
Speaker 4:  of all of them. It felt 3D printed and that just was kind of
Speaker 4:  ha not cool. I, I was on Reddit and in some of the circular
Speaker 4:  forums and there, there were a lot of angry people on there just because
Speaker 4:  there's just a, a bunch of really cool ideas, but
Speaker 4:  very underdone in terms of execution. So that was very easy to
Speaker 4:  eliminate as like straight off from the get go. It was like, no,
Speaker 4:  you, sorry, you are not the best.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The next one, I think you probably had a harder time getting rid of
Speaker 1:  if, knowing the little bit I knew about this research process, I'm guessing
Speaker 1:  this was a harder one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I really have enjoyed the EV ring. I've
Speaker 4:  been talking to the company behind it ano for years because they just
Speaker 4:  were really gung-ho about the FDA clearance process. So that kind of sets
Speaker 4:  them apart in terms of accuracy. They had a very
Speaker 4:  interesting idea in terms of design. It has an open gap at the top, which
Speaker 4:  I, I will say one of the most frustrating things about smart
Speaker 4:  rings is sizing. Smart watches have bands.
Speaker 4:  You can adjust them. It's very easy to adjust them. Smart
Speaker 4:  rings less so because it's on your finger. They're not adjustable.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of tech inside, so you can't get them resized. You just have
Speaker 4:  to get the right size that fits you. And what
Speaker 4:  most people don't realize is that you bloat you have, you
Speaker 4:  have a lot of pasta one night or the temperature rises, your fingers
Speaker 4:  swell. So, you know, it can be very hard to get these rings off,
Speaker 4:  especially, you know, they're, you're supposed to wear smart rings on
Speaker 4:  your index finger, that's gonna be the most accurate. But, you know, maybe
Speaker 4:  that's just not in the cards for you. Maybe you want the to wear be
Speaker 4:  worn on the middle finger or the ring finger. So, you know,
Speaker 4:  just it can, it can change the size that you need. Right. And
Speaker 4:  you could gain weight. You could lose weight. That will also change how a
Speaker 4:  ring fits on you. Not so much of an issue with the ring because
Speaker 4:  of that open gap design is always very easy to take off. It's very comfortable
Speaker 4:  to wear. I thought that was really clever. It looked
Speaker 4:  so nice. I it was so pretty. But it's, it's a first
Speaker 4:  gen product and it had some very first gen
Speaker 4:  quirks and again, this, this is gonna be a theme with some of the, the
Speaker 4:  rings on this list, they have gone and they said we have addressed
Speaker 4:  some of the feedback since the first run.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, we will see how, how that, how that goes going on. But,
Speaker 4:  you know, I really loved the hardware design, but
Speaker 4:  it's not just the hardware that matters. If you're using it as a fitness
Speaker 4:  tracker, the, the software, how that data is presented to you
Speaker 4:  also matters. and there was just some quirks here that I'm hoping will get
Speaker 4:  smoothed over in a second iteration.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, agreed. You, I think my, my only gripe with this
Speaker 1:  part of your piece was that I think you,
Speaker 1:  if anything undersold how much better looking this thing is than every other
Speaker 1:  one of the competition. Like it really is. Yeah. You, you could put the six
Speaker 1:  of them next to each other and it would be the other five in one bucket and
Speaker 1:  then this one on its own, right? Like it is, it is, yeah. A full like order
Speaker 1:  of magnitude more stylish and attractive than the others.
Speaker 1:  So like kudos that doesn't get you anywhere.
Speaker 1:  Like, you know that, that and a nickel will buy you a Coke, but
Speaker 1:  it, it's, that's a cool, interesting start. Right? And you ran
Speaker 1:  into one of my favorite things about first gen products, which is
Speaker 1:  my pet theory forever has been that If you make a product and it's hard to
Speaker 1:  update the firmware. Your product probably sucks. It's just, it's a real,
Speaker 1:  like the, the tiny details that matter, right?
Speaker 1:  Like If, you haven't fixed that. There are probably other things that you
Speaker 1:  haven't paid attention to and this is one of those
Speaker 1:  things, but it gives me great hope that there are a lot of things that Evie
Speaker 1:  can go get right that are easier than making nice looking hardware. And
Speaker 1:  if it does those things that could be very compelling.
Speaker 4:  I I have a, I have a bit of faith in the company because I've talked to their
Speaker 4:  CEOA bunch of times and this is a dude who is very well versed in the
Speaker 4:  medical space and what it takes to make a FDA cleared
Speaker 4:  product. So I, I I generally give that a lot of credit because
Speaker 4:  it takes a certain level of dedication and resources to
Speaker 4:  go that route to begin with. So, you know, I I
Speaker 4:  wanted to give them a little more, you know, cut them some slack, but you
Speaker 4:  know, th this is a battle royale, we can't be too nice. So they
Speaker 4:  unfortunately were kicked out second. Yeah, fair. And yeah.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're gonna skip over the next one, which is the ring con because
Speaker 1:  you barely even talked about it's fine. You're like, fine, this thing is
Speaker 1:  thoroughly fine, who cares? Moving on. So this thing is fine. Who cares?
Speaker 1:  Moving on. The next one was the Galaxy Ring. I will say,
Speaker 1:  I would've guessed probably those first three would've been the first three
Speaker 1:  you would've gotten rid of. This was the first one that surprised me that
Speaker 1:  it went here. Tell me why. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  The hardware's great. I think it actually has the best hardware. It's the
Speaker 4:  slimmest, it's the most comfortable to wear besides the EV ring. But you,
Speaker 4:  you know what, you know what I'm saying? Yeah. And at the time it
Speaker 4:  had the largest size range. It no longer does, but
Speaker 4:  it just doesn't stand alone. The thing about the
Speaker 4:  Galaxy ring on its own is that it
Speaker 4:  doesn't do a whole lot. It's a fitness tracker. It, it,
Speaker 4:  it's an okay fitness tracker. The battery life will
Speaker 4:  be better If, you get it with a Galaxy Watch because it does like some smart
Speaker 4:  sensor trade off as to like, which one's gonna be more accurate. And that
Speaker 4:  bore out in my testing, which
Speaker 1:  Is super cool by the way, like as a, it's very cool as an ecosystem play.
Speaker 1:  I actually think that's really clever. But it does, like if
Speaker 1:  you're, if you're narrowing it down to only people who have Samsung phones
Speaker 1:  and narrowing it down again to only people who have Galaxy watches, you've
Speaker 1:  like, the number of people who get the best version of this product is just
Speaker 1:  very small.
Speaker 4:  It's very small. And then If, you have the newest
Speaker 1:  And you've already spent a ton of money. Like
Speaker 4:  If, you have the newest right. Smart, ah, Samsung Galaxy Flip
Speaker 4:  six or the fold six, you know, you can also use it as
Speaker 4:  a pinchy pinch, gesture control for certain things on the phone. And that's
Speaker 4:  something they're interested in expanding. Very cool idea. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Awesome. In terms of ecosystem play, If you, you know,
Speaker 4:  can stomach ecosystems as, as a thing that we're being locked into,
Speaker 4:  but okay, so you're gonna buy the, the fold six,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna buy a Galaxy Watch on top of that and you're gonna buy a
Speaker 4:  smart ring. There's no discount bundle for getting all three of those things
Speaker 4:  together. You are spending over $2,000 at this point, close
Speaker 4:  to $3,000. It doesn't matter if there's no
Speaker 4:  subscription because you've just paid Samsung $3,000
Speaker 4:  to get the full benefit range of this Samsung
Speaker 4:  Galaxy ring. And then also it is very much tied to
Speaker 4:  the Android ecosystem only. So, you know,
Speaker 4:  I'm sure I, I got so many angry Samsung people
Speaker 4:  by eliminating it this early. And don't get me wrong, it's a great
Speaker 4:  little ring. I love the little charging case. I think the hardware is really
Speaker 4:  excellent, but you shouldn't have to pay $3,000
Speaker 4:  to get the full range of what it can do.
Speaker 4:  It's full to unlock its full potential. Like in some ways weighing
Speaker 4:  that cost versus a subscription. Yeah. They don't have to charge
Speaker 4:  you a subscription if you're willing to pay $3,000 to get everything.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think it, to me, it's just a totally different way of thinking
Speaker 1:  about a smart ring and it, it's not necessarily wrong, it's just really different,
Speaker 1:  right? Like this is a thing you buy after you have bought those
Speaker 1:  other devices. The the Ring is not the entry point
Speaker 1:  into Samsung's ecosystem. You're not gonna go buy these other devices because
Speaker 1:  you want the Galaxy Ring and If, you already have those other devices
Speaker 1:  kick ass. I think there's a, there's a decent chance this is the best choice.
Speaker 1:  If, if you're like, I'm coming to this shootout, yes, I already own these
Speaker 1:  two devices. I think the galaxy ring probably wins or at least comes close.
Speaker 1:  But that's not most people and that's not most people. And you're not, and
Speaker 1:  you, you're not. And you shouldn't make those other choices just to get a
Speaker 1:  smart ring.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's also not, most people looking for a smart ring,
Speaker 4:  like the people looking for a smart ring is very kind of,
Speaker 4:  they're a defined set of people. I would say A lot of them are people
Speaker 4:  who just don't like smartwatches, So, I. Immediately you're, you're
Speaker 4:  kind of losing that benefit of like using it with a smartwatch.
Speaker 4:  And a lot of times they, you know, this is an interesting tip that, that
Speaker 4:  Aura told me, but their user base is majority female now. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  So they started out as a company where, you know, it was a majority men and
Speaker 4:  now they're majority women. So I think a lot of women who just
Speaker 4:  don't wanna wear these bulky smart watches who don't, who want
Speaker 4:  something a little more sleek, a little more understated. They, they're the
Speaker 4:  ones who are really kind of pushing the smart ring as, as a form factor forward.
Speaker 4:  Like If, you look at smart ring ads on social media
Speaker 4:  'cause Lord knows I get served a zillion smart ring ads on my cursed
Speaker 4:  algorithm. It's all women. It's all women really kind of pushing the Oura
Speaker 4:  Ring forward. So, you know, I think in terms of people
Speaker 4:  looking for that, Samsung's great, but
Speaker 4:  you know, the ecosystem play is kind of their greatest strength and their
Speaker 4:  greatest weakness at the same time. It's very interesting to see how that'll
Speaker 4:  play out. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I, I totally agree. So that leaves us with two, speaking of the AA ring,
Speaker 1:  we have the, the ultra human ring air stupid name and we have the
Speaker 1:  Ora Ring three. Which one came in second place?
Speaker 4:  It was the ultra human ring Air it, is it 'cause
Speaker 1:  Of the stupid name?
Speaker 4:  No it's not. 'cause it's the stupid name. Okay. It's because it's like way
Speaker 4:  too focused on training. Mm.
Speaker 1:  And it's like whoopy that way. Is it?
Speaker 4:  It's very
Speaker 1:  Whoopy. It's like super intense. Okay.
Speaker 4:  It's very whoopy. It's like if Garmin made a smart ring, I feel like
Speaker 4:  it would be very close to the ultra human ring and that's gonna be a plus
Speaker 4:  for some people. Yeah. But for others I think it's
Speaker 4:  just kind of too cluttered. It's too much.
Speaker 4:  It's, I thought it was really interesting because they, you know, they'll
Speaker 4:  tell you here's your caffeine window and here are the drinks that you can
Speaker 4:  drink during the day. Here's like a little like
Speaker 4:  widget plugin that you can use If, you want sun exposure and just
Speaker 4:  very hyper-focused on optimizing. And I
Speaker 4:  believe there are a ton of people who would love that. I, I enjoyed it quite
Speaker 4:  a bit. I, I liked it a lot but I also felt that
Speaker 4:  it was just a little hyper-focused on that aspect
Speaker 4:  of it versus the Oura Ring, which is a little more holistic.
Speaker 4:  So If, you look at something that's really specialized
Speaker 4:  versus something that is for everybody, I think something
Speaker 4:  that's for everybody generally wins out. Which, yeah, at the end of the day,
Speaker 4:  that's why I picked the Oura Ring over the Ultra
Speaker 4:  Human Ring air. Even though that name is a
Speaker 4:  mouthful. It was, it was quite a nice ring. I really liked it. What pained
Speaker 4:  me actually about those two being the winners is that those two are the ones
Speaker 4:  that use docs for charging. And I really like
Speaker 4:  a charging case for a smart ring. So agreed. It pains me that we have
Speaker 4:  to give doc supremacy, but it just boils down to the ring
Speaker 4:  itself of
Speaker 1:  The two. The only one of those two that I've had is the oral ring and the
Speaker 1:  number of times that it's Little Doc has just slid off my bedside
Speaker 1:  table and fallen onto the ground because it's not heavy enough drives me
Speaker 1:  nuts. It's,
Speaker 4:  It's not great.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But I agree the charging is like, you know, do better everybody. But
Speaker 1:  that's not, it's not the the be all end all of this whole thing and the,
Speaker 1:  the battery's on all of them last long enough that like, it's, it's mostly
Speaker 1:  fine. So that means the Aura Ring three was the winner. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Kind of a boring outcome. I'm not gonna lie to you. That's
Speaker 4:  Not very boring.
Speaker 1:  It's like, it, it's, it was like Aura versus a bunch of Aura
Speaker 1:  imitators. I was and Aura
Speaker 4:  One I was rooting just like If. you can just imagine me as Tyra Banks with
Speaker 4:  six ring tanks. I was rooting for all of you to Deone
Speaker 4:  Aura to be quite frank. I did not want, I did not want it to
Speaker 4:  be the winner. and there was, there was a point where I was like, should
Speaker 4:  I give it to the ultra human? And just really my instinct was
Speaker 4:  that, you know, it's a little too training focused. If it had been a bit
Speaker 4:  more holistic then I would've happily
Speaker 4:  given it to the ultra human ring air. What a also
Speaker 4:  the name is just, I'm
Speaker 1:  You, it's,
Speaker 4:  It's really tripping me out.
Speaker 1:  Terrible. But I'll say one of the things that really struck me about this
Speaker 1:  is, I think this is where Aura having been in this
Speaker 1:  game this long has been really useful because a lot of the things you just
Speaker 1:  said about ultra human were true of aura in previous
Speaker 1:  generations. That it was really good at generating a lot of numbers and not
Speaker 1:  that good at making any sense of it or helping you in any sort of
Speaker 1:  meaningful way unless you like really wanted to be somebody who was super
Speaker 1:  intense about your sleep. And over time they've just gotten better at this.
Speaker 1:  Like they, they they do more like wellness content. It's much more of
Speaker 1:  like a thoughtful thing for how to live your life as opposed to
Speaker 1:  just like a sleep score. And yeah, I think a a that's to aura's
Speaker 1:  credit and B, that is just a thing that takes time. And so Aura has just
Speaker 1:  been at this for so long now that I think it has figured out how to turn
Speaker 1:  all of that data into something that makes sense to lots of people instead
Speaker 1:  of just the like the hustle bro body hackers who
Speaker 1:  are served by some of these other devices.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like one point I'm gonna make is that we are now on an Oura Ring
Speaker 4:  Gen four or Oura Ring four. They removed the gen from the name.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And that drives my OCD Crazy. But so we're on the fourth
Speaker 4:  generation of Aura Ring. Most of these other rings are on their first
Speaker 4:  maybe second Right. Or like, and when we talk maybe second
Speaker 4:  literally just announced maybe second version of of the rings.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 1:  Announced it after you said the first one was bad. Yes. They said well we
Speaker 4:  Have another one basically. Yeah. The honestly, yes. So,
Speaker 4:  so you know the, it's very hard to kind of
Speaker 4:  discount experience in all of this. Sinking was a big
Speaker 4:  issue for some of these competitors. Yes. They, it took a while. Like
Speaker 4:  again with the circular I, I rage quit several times 'cause
Speaker 4:  it just would not sink. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Aura good at firmware updates now
Speaker 4:  Good at firmware updates now it does not take a lot to sink. Yeah. An
Speaker 4:  aura ring when you open the app, you're like, ooh, it's shiny and polished.
Speaker 4:  There's no like finickiness with it. Right. All the other ones, there's,
Speaker 4:  there's a bit of, there's a little bit of a lack of polish. It's very either
Speaker 4:  basic and some people just won't care about that and that's fine.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying you can tell there's a difference when you open up the app
Speaker 4:  and it's smooth and there's no jitteriness or there's no
Speaker 4:  crashing or you know, it doesn't take forever to find a connection with
Speaker 4:  the ring. Even though they're all just using Bluetooth, it's not that hard.
Speaker 4:  So, you know, there's just a, a degree of polish
Speaker 4:  there that I can very confidently say after spending several
Speaker 4:  mornings waiting for all of these things to sink
Speaker 4:  that I can say that the aura was the best at it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that makes a lot of sense. So the aura wins and then
Speaker 1:  immediately just to flex on 'em, they drop a new
Speaker 1:  version, they drop gen four, right? The Aura three one, this,
Speaker 1:  this shootout and then they drop to the four. What's new in the four?
Speaker 4:  So the four goes to an all titanium design. And
Speaker 4:  for most people what you're gonna notice is that the inside of the ring is
Speaker 4:  flat. There's no like sensor bump. The, the old ring had
Speaker 4:  three little bumps on the inside and that was there for a reason. The inside
Speaker 4:  was epoxy. And epoxy is a type of resin where
Speaker 4:  it diffuses light in a specific way. It can get a, a little bit
Speaker 4:  messy. So you really want the sensors to have good skin contact
Speaker 4:  in that case to kind of mitigate that kind of factor. Also
Speaker 4:  rings will rotate during the day. Ideally you want the sensors to be on the
Speaker 4:  underside of your ring because that's gonna get the best signal pathway
Speaker 4:  to your blood and all that nonsense. So
Speaker 4:  what this new ring does is that it recesses the sensors so
Speaker 4:  that it's more comfortable, you know, when I'm bloated this is a lot easier
Speaker 4:  and less painful to take off than the, the gen three was. I do appreciate
Speaker 4:  that.
Speaker 4:  And they have a new sensor algorithm which, you know, it just
Speaker 4:  basically more than doubles the number of signal pathways that can be used.
Speaker 4:  So if the ring is moving around on your finger,
Speaker 4:  it's not gonna matter quite as much for accuracy and
Speaker 4:  data collection. So it's, it's so minute. It's very
Speaker 4:  cool in terms of like an engineering perspective. Oh it also improves battery
Speaker 4:  life. Okay. So it's very cool from like a Ooh that's really
Speaker 4:  nerdy. That's awesome. I love this for the engineers. But
Speaker 4:  in terms of actually wearing it, not,
Speaker 4:  not a huge difference. Yeah, not a huge difference.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's fair. But I think the, there, there was a bunch of
Speaker 1:  software like between the beginning of the three and the beginning of the
Speaker 1:  four also. Oh gosh. That is like
Speaker 4:  So much
Speaker 1:  The three, and again I think this is very much to aura's credit. Like the
Speaker 1:  three is a much better device than it was when it shipped, which is not always
Speaker 1:  true of these devices. And the four gets all
Speaker 1:  of that. And then a little more like the one I was excited about was the,
Speaker 1:  the sort of expanded activity trekking. Yes. Because for me,
Speaker 1:  my problem with the Ora rings for a while and granted it's been, I,
Speaker 1:  I think the last one I wore was like the very beginning of the three
Speaker 1:  was that it eventually got to a point where it was only sort of sporadically
Speaker 1:  good at everything except sleep. Which it was very good at. But I didn't
Speaker 1:  care. Like I, I just, I have gotten to a point where sleep tracking just
Speaker 1:  does nothing for me. I, I know when I sleep well and I know when I don't,
Speaker 1:  I, that's pretty much all I got but there was a lot of the like
Speaker 1:  standalone activity tracking that it wasn't very good at even then. And I
Speaker 1:  think now it seems like the, the three and especially now
Speaker 1:  the four are, are pretty good at that actually that like
Speaker 1:  as activity trackers they're pretty good.
Speaker 4:  They've expanded the automatic activity detection, which was a big thing
Speaker 4:  because like on a smartwatch it is so easy to manually start
Speaker 4:  a activity. Yeah. On a smart ring you have to take out your phone, you have
Speaker 4:  to open up the app, you have to do the thing which is
Speaker 1:  Like non-starter honestly it's,
Speaker 4:  It's a non-starter for a lot of people. But now they've expanded it to 40
Speaker 4:  activities and it's not just the Aura Ring four that's gonna
Speaker 4:  get that they've really not gate kept any of these software updates. Like
Speaker 4:  it might Well that all goes back. Yeah it goes, it goes all back. So it might
Speaker 4:  take a bit to roll out to the three but you know, I asked
Speaker 4:  Aura and nothing is really gate kept software wise.
Speaker 4:  It's just that this is like got the new sensing algorithm so it's more
Speaker 4:  accurate. That's the only thing that's really true of the four versus the
Speaker 4:  three. So not a huge incentive to upgrade for people unless their batteries
Speaker 4:  are shot.
Speaker 4:  But the automatic activity detection is, you
Speaker 4:  know, I don't track my walks on smart watches
Speaker 4:  for a number of reasons but you know, it was actually quite good
Speaker 4:  at picking up when I had done the walks. It includes GPS maps,
Speaker 4:  it includes the heart rate. So it's like oh my little activity
Speaker 4:  was, it was still counted. Yeah. And I didn't have to worry about
Speaker 4:  duplicates because I do track all of my runs on a watch and all of my strength
Speaker 4:  sessions on a watch and those, it just imported from
Speaker 4:  the health API so it was very clean, it was a very clean experience.
Speaker 4:  I have yet to get housework counted in
Speaker 4:  the Oura Ring. So apparently I'm not cleaning.
Speaker 1:  You have to clean more
Speaker 4:  Aggressively. I'm not cleaning with vigor. Yeah. Yeah. So we'll, we'll
Speaker 4:  have to see. I would love to hear from people if it's catching their basketball
Speaker 4:  sessions or whatever, but I'm boring. I mostly
Speaker 4:  run walk and do strength training. So I.
Speaker 4:  I'd love to hear from other people how that's worked out for them.
Speaker 1:  Well I barely do that so you've got me on that. But the reason Aura
Speaker 1:  is very happy to bring all of these new features back to their old rings
Speaker 1:  is because of the way Aura makes money, which I would say caused a great
Speaker 1:  amount of consternation in our comments and in your email inbox
Speaker 1:  after you published three years, is this the battle royale in particular,
Speaker 1:  which is the subscription fee?
Speaker 1:  I should probably just lay my cards on the table here and say I don't think
Speaker 1:  this is a problem and a $6 a month subscription fee for something like this
Speaker 1:  is fine. It's fine. If, you don't wanna have it. Don't have it.
Speaker 1:  Like this is not, I think if you're, if if Apple started to suddenly
Speaker 1:  magically charge you another $6 a month to have an iPhone, I would have an
Speaker 1:  issue with it because that is like a, a thing. Everyone needs to live modern
Speaker 1:  life. A smart ring is not that thing. $6 a month to
Speaker 1:  make your $350 ring actually continue to be very
Speaker 1:  good for as long as Aura has done it I think is fine. I'm gonna get a lot
Speaker 1:  of angry people. That's just where I'm at. You,
Speaker 4:  You are going to get a lot of angry people. I have some sympathy because
Speaker 4:  what basically, you know, Ora did a Marquez where
Speaker 4:  they had a, that's that's what they did. That's what they did
Speaker 4:  with the Gen three. Even though they did it before Marquez did it.
Speaker 1:  Marquez just catching strays on the first cast. Jeez.
Speaker 4:  No I, I mean like I think this is just like kind of a really easy recent
Speaker 4:  example to explain why people are mad.
Speaker 1:  Did Aura Release WA wallpapers app? Is that No. Oh okay. I see
Speaker 4:  What you're talking about. So you know the, the Gen two had no subscription.
Speaker 4:  They introduced it with the gen three Fair. So you had a thing that did not
Speaker 4:  have a subscription that you've then added a subscription to. And that
Speaker 4:  is why Aura has been catching strays and has
Speaker 4:  made people super angry about this for so long. That
Speaker 1:  Is fair. It didn't use to require charging for charging something that didn't
Speaker 1:  use to cost money sucks. I do, I do agree with that. Yeah. I'm sensitive
Speaker 1:  to that
Speaker 4:  Argument. Yeah. So I, I fully understand where people are coming from
Speaker 4:  as to like why they were mad that Aura has a subscription
Speaker 4:  to begin with. On the other hand, I have to
Speaker 4:  say that one time hardware sales does not
Speaker 4:  keep the lights on for most companies real and it really doesn't. When
Speaker 4:  you have a company like Aura who is investing quite a lot into research and
Speaker 4:  development and science that's stuff is
Speaker 4:  expensive to have peer reviewed studies on
Speaker 4:  your device, you know, just submitting to a journal, a peer reviewed
Speaker 4:  journal that's like $25,000. That's a lot of money. And
Speaker 4:  that's why you see a lot of dubious claims in the health tech
Speaker 4:  space about algorithms, about all of this stuff. They
Speaker 4:  are, they don't have to do this really, they don't have to test their
Speaker 4:  algorithm against Polysomnography, which is the clinical gold standard. They
Speaker 4:  don't have to do any of this research. None of it is required
Speaker 4:  to just sell you a consumer grade device. They're choosing to do it
Speaker 4:  and it is expensive to do this So
Speaker 4:  I I in that sense you are paying for that. You are paying for the science,
Speaker 4:  you are paying for that degree of research.
Speaker 1:  Is that a good trade? I mean Oro, Oro has won our contest and you just gave
Speaker 1:  it a nine. Like is that, is that the right trade off for Aura to be making
Speaker 1:  over time?
Speaker 4:  It is, it is a gambit that they are taking, I don't know if it's the right
Speaker 4:  one. Okay. They are betting that people are willing to pay for the best and
Speaker 4:  so long as they are the best. Okay, sure. Go for
Speaker 4:  it. I do think it is worth noting that all of
Speaker 4:  their competitors make a very big point about not having a subscription.
Speaker 4:  Right. And Samsung can afford to do that. Samsung is big.
Speaker 4:  They have other revenue streams. They don't need to
Speaker 4:  charge a subscription for the Galaxy ring, which is pricey.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Because you have to spend $2,000 on a phone to get there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. To get everything you're gonna have to spend on all that hardware.
Speaker 4:  For some people they're not gonna think too hard about that because they
Speaker 4:  already have it or whatnot. Sure. Et cetera, et cetera. Sure. Love that.
Speaker 4:  But for some of the other competitors like Ring Con, which we completely
Speaker 4:  glossed over 'cause it's fine, you know, it's, it's it's, they can undercut
Speaker 4:  Aura in terms of price and they can deliver a decent
Speaker 4:  fitness tracking experience and some people are
Speaker 4:  just gonna be super happy with that and they're gonna be fine with that.
Speaker 4:  And that's, that's great. I just
Speaker 1:  Think If, you want a decent fitness tracking experience,
Speaker 1:  download an app on your phone. Like I I I need that. I'm, I'm sort of serious,
Speaker 1:  right? Like you, you, you would be surprised not you v
Speaker 1:  but most people I think would be surprised at the sophistication
Speaker 1:  that you can get by downloading an app on your phone and then holding your
Speaker 1:  phone in your hand. It's not
Speaker 1:  remotely within range of these dedicated devices, but like If, you just want
Speaker 1:  a thing that does a relative job of counting your steps and telling you how
Speaker 1:  you slept. Those are apps on your phone. They exist. Yeah. Download those
Speaker 1:  things. I think the people who want this dedicated hardware
Speaker 1:  mostly want the best things and should, and this is like, it's, it's why
Speaker 1:  ultra human and whoop and some of these companies are going so hard. It's
Speaker 1:  why Garmin continues to go as hard as it does because these are, this is
Speaker 1:  the customer. And I think to some extent the thing that Apple
Speaker 1:  did with smartwatches was like pull that down towards
Speaker 1:  everyday people in a way nobody had before and, and had like taught Google
Speaker 1:  and Samsung in a lot of ways how to make watches that appeal to regular people
Speaker 1:  but also do some of those other things. And rings for me are still
Speaker 1:  very much in the like, unless you're serious about this, you don't even
Speaker 1:  consider buying one phase.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're just very, I really feel like it appeals
Speaker 4:  the most actually to wellness influencers and like that
Speaker 4:  type of person who just does not want a bulky smartwatch.
Speaker 4:  They don't want smart, they're, you know, it is definitely not
Speaker 4:  the average Vergecast listener. But there I have been to parties where
Speaker 4:  this very well dressed, well-heeled woman comes up to
Speaker 4:  me and she's like, oh I see you have an Aura ring. I love my aura ring because
Speaker 4:  I wanna wear this designer watch that is not a smart watch. I don't want
Speaker 4:  an Apple watch, I don't want this. And I've just been sitting there going
Speaker 4:  like, oh, okay. Yeah. How, how much is that
Speaker 4:  Air one salad that you're eating? Yeah. Like exactly. You know, I
Speaker 1:  Mean I buy that entirely Right. Like that. Yeah. And I think that is a really
Speaker 1:  good case for smart rings, but I think for most people If you don't wanna
Speaker 1:  wear a smartwatch and you don't care deeply
Speaker 1:  about the fitness side of things. Like, my point is there's no use for a
Speaker 1:  casual smart ring user at this moment. For most things.
Speaker 4:  For most things it's, it's truly just people who do not care
Speaker 4:  about, like, it's gonna seem foreign to techies I think. But they're just
Speaker 4:  truly normal people who do not care about anything a
Speaker 4:  smartwatch has to offer. Because if we compare a smart ring and a smartwatch,
Speaker 4:  which are generally similarly priced value for value, the
Speaker 4:  smartwatch is gonna give you more of everything and
Speaker 4:  is in my opinion, a kind of ave better value proposition
Speaker 4:  for a lot of people. But there are just people who do not care about that.
Speaker 4:  And it's, it's why I get so many people just
Speaker 4:  messaging me and DMing me and being like, I don't understand the whole point
Speaker 4:  of a smart ring and I get it. I get what they're, where they're coming from.
Speaker 4:  But I've also talked to these other people who just are like, I don't get
Speaker 4:  the point of a smartwatch. Right. So it's, you're just serving two
Speaker 4:  very different audiences in in that respect. And
Speaker 4:  you know, it's the Kim Kardashians who is an Oura Ring user. It is be
Speaker 4:  Gwyneth Paltrows, the Jennifer Aniston, all of these people who are
Speaker 4:  just, it's a more discreet thing. So you're really just paying for the
Speaker 4:  discretion. You're paying for the form factor.
Speaker 4:  And we'll have to see because the, the thing about
Speaker 4:  other companies and if Apple comes out with a smart ring,
Speaker 4:  I think Aura is cooked. I think they're potentially cooked, maybe
Speaker 4:  not right away, but you know, 'cause the first Apple Watch wasn't anything
Speaker 4:  super amazing. It was just, oh, Apple's here. But like
Speaker 4:  if Apple was like, oh the Apple rang for oh
Speaker 1:  And I mean if Apple could take the decade of stuff it has learned
Speaker 1:  about health and fitness and just pull it out of the watch and into this
Speaker 1:  different form factor, like I think there's reason to believe that thing
Speaker 1:  could get much better, much faster
Speaker 4:  Than, much better, much faster. And you know, if they kind of take some
Speaker 4:  of what Samsung's doing and pull it into the ecosystem, oh all
Speaker 4:  of a sudden we got the smart part of the smart Ring. 'cause right now we're
Speaker 4:  just having a basic fitness tracker in a different form factor that is slightly
Speaker 4:  more comfortable for people to wear. Especially for this one specific
Speaker 4:  use case which is sleep tracking. Right. And Aura does that really well,
Speaker 4:  but Aura doesn't make phones, aura doesn't, it's, it's a very like
Speaker 4:  one trick pony kind of situation and they have to partner with other companies
Speaker 4:  in order to kind of expand beyond that. So,
Speaker 4:  ah, did this, is this, is this subscription
Speaker 4:  plan gonna play out long term? I say in my review, I'm not sure
Speaker 4:  as so long as they're the best at this niche category. Yeah sure. I think
Speaker 4:  it could, it could work for them but other
Speaker 4:  people are coming. I think it's very telling that Samsung came
Speaker 4:  out and knocked it out of the park with the hardware in its first go.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The software is what needs work with Samsung and you know,
Speaker 4:  not gatekeeping it to very expensive phones and watches to get the best
Speaker 4:  out of it.
Speaker 1:  Which to be clear is exactly what Apple would and will do if it ever
Speaker 1:  launches this
Speaker 4:  One. Yeah. But you know the, the Apple fans, they're really
Speaker 4:  invested. I have already,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They got the money.
Speaker 4:  I have already heard from readers who are like, if Apple came out with the
Speaker 4:  Smart Ring, I would get it, but I can't be bothered with this Oura Ring and
Speaker 4:  its subscription and I'm like duly noted. Duly noted.
Speaker 1:  It's good to be Apple. It really, really, really is
Speaker 4:  Is good be it's
Speaker 1:  Very good to be Apple. Yeah. Alright v we gotta go. Thank you so much.
Speaker 1:  Here's hoping you don't have to do this again next year because Apple launches
Speaker 1:  a ring but also If. you do. We'll be back. I
Speaker 4:  Probably will. I already have a, a straggler smart ring that I have to
Speaker 4:  review so we'll see.
Speaker 1:  All right, well we'll see you for the next one.
Speaker 4:  Alright,
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. So when Apple announced all of its
Speaker 1:  new stuff in September, one of the biggest announcements was
Speaker 1:  about the AirPods Pro two, but it wasn't new
Speaker 1:  headphones, it was just a software update for the headphones that brought
Speaker 1:  among other things some new hearing health features and
Speaker 1:  particularly an hearing aid mode that could actually be a really
Speaker 1:  big deal for people with hearing loss. We didn't get to try it at first,
Speaker 1:  but Chris Welch has gotten to try the new features now they're coming out
Speaker 1:  soon. I think there's something very exciting going on here
Speaker 1:  if all of this actually works the way that Apple claims that it does. Chris
Speaker 1:  luckily knows the answer. Let's get into it. Chris Welch, welcome back.
Speaker 1:  Hello. It's a pleasure to be
Speaker 5:  Here as always.
Speaker 1:  This is, we've gotten to do this so much recently. It's just, it's like headphone
Speaker 1:  season in a, in a truly crazy way right now.
Speaker 5:  It is. Now we're here for a headphone reason, but something a bit different
Speaker 5:  than usual.
Speaker 1:  That's true. It's like headphones adjacent, I would say. Yes. Yes. So
Speaker 1:  this is a strange way to ask an initial question, but what exactly have you
Speaker 1:  been testing on the AirPods?
Speaker 5:  So I've been testing a suite of new hearing health features for the AirPods
Speaker 5:  Pro. Apple announced to these at their event a few months ago
Speaker 5:  and now they're rolling out with iOS 18.1 and some new
Speaker 5:  firmware for the Air Budds the week of October 28th. And so everyone
Speaker 5:  will be able to use their AirPods as hearing protection as hearing
Speaker 5:  aids and there'll be, there's hearing tests. You can test
Speaker 5:  your hearing because no one ever goes to the hearing doctor. I haven't been
Speaker 5:  in years. Yeah. So there's a lot to cover. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I am going to ask you to reveal some personal information about yourself.
Speaker 1:  Of course. I hope you're ready for that. I'm ready. But the, the reason I
Speaker 1:  ask that question that way is it seems like my initial
Speaker 1:  impression of this was that there was going to be like a, a hearing aid mode
Speaker 1:  on the AirPods, right. That you would like go into settings and turn it on
Speaker 1:  and then it would do a bunch of different stuff or it would be sort of an
Speaker 1:  accessibility feature. Yeah. And what it actually seems like is Apple has
Speaker 1:  baked this kind of hearing awareness
Speaker 1:  both of your own hearing and of the world into kind of how the whole
Speaker 1:  thing works. Like it's much more holistic Yeah. Than I expected. Has that
Speaker 1:  been, has that been your impression too? Mostly,
Speaker 5:  I mean there is a hearing aid mode like that is a separate mode that you
Speaker 5:  turn on or off. Okay. But the rest of like hearing protection is always on
Speaker 5:  by default in all modes now. So like it was there before, like they had,
Speaker 5:  I think it was called loud noise reduction, but this is much broader. It's
Speaker 5:  like people like wore their AirPods to concerts before and Apples never really
Speaker 5:  like said Sure, that's great. They didn't tell you not to, but they, you
Speaker 5:  know, weren't like thrilled about it. But now you actually can use your AirPods
Speaker 5:  at concerts and like they've tuned the EQ so you hear stuff better.
Speaker 5:  And so that's there and that's gonna be a huge deal for a lot of people who
Speaker 5:  like don't wear earplugs at concerts. Please wear earplugs at concerts.
Speaker 5:  And so that's there. Yeah. It's like a lot of it's just on by default and
Speaker 5:  it's just gonna be there from now on. Okay.
Speaker 1:  So the very beginning of this process is you take the hearing test right?
Speaker 1:  That's the like the first thing that happens. Yeah. Tell me about this hearing
Speaker 1:  test.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, it was very like emotional, very nerve wracking.
Speaker 5:  'cause I haven't seen the audiologist since probably 2018 pre covid
Speaker 5:  easily. So it's been a long, long time. And like, I don't listen to like
Speaker 5:  metal. I like sad bastard, singer, songwriters, you know, that kind of genre.
Speaker 5:  So like, thankfully I'm sure that's saved me a bit over the years, but like
Speaker 5:  I grew up with like a Sony Diskman at my hip and like then so many iPods
Speaker 5:  and iPhones and so like I was nervous taking it. And so it's like
Speaker 5:  five minutes and you hear like a series of beeps, these three tone beeps
Speaker 5:  just beep, beep, beep, beep, beep, beep and like all sorts of frequencies.
Speaker 5:  And it lasts about five minutes first to do your left here,
Speaker 5:  then you're right here.
Speaker 5:  And the test is different for each, like you hear it tones like different
Speaker 5:  times for both ears. So it's so you can't game it or like
Speaker 5:  that kind of thing. But yeah, it's just very intense. Like I had several
Speaker 5:  people here at the office take it and they were all like, yeah, it's just
Speaker 5:  very, you know, it's a lot also like hearing
Speaker 5:  loss is super common. Like 1.5 billion people in the world have some level
Speaker 5:  of hearing loss and so like, it's nothing to be ashamed of or like stigmatized
Speaker 5:  and so it's just, you know, part of life. But like taking that test for the
Speaker 5:  first time is definitely like a thing.
Speaker 1:  So it, the test is like, it, it plays these tones and it's, I'm sort of
Speaker 1:  imagining the, the thing that you do, I've done this
Speaker 1:  once that I can think of where you actually sit in the doctor's office with
Speaker 1:  a giant pair of headphones and and they're like, raise your hand when you
Speaker 1:  hear the tone. Yeah. Raise the, the hand on the side that it's on.
Speaker 1:  It's kind of a, it sounds like it's sort of a smartphone ized version of
Speaker 1:  that.
Speaker 5:  Tap the screen whenever you hear a tone essentially. Okay. Yeah. Okay. Yes.
Speaker 5:  So you tap the screen and like some noises are like super faint so you've
Speaker 5:  gotta like pay super close attention. It's like that thing where like you
Speaker 5:  think you heard something but you're not sure they've like accounted for
Speaker 5:  all that and like the testing. And so yeah, it takes about five minutes.
Speaker 5:  It's a long five minutes, then you get your results charted out and there
Speaker 5:  are five tiers of hearing loss. There's little to know which I fell in somehow,
Speaker 5:  which is congrat amazing to me. Congrat. Yeah, thank you. There's moderate,
Speaker 5:  sorry, there's mild, moderate, severe and profound is the last one.
Speaker 5:  And so those are the five levels. And so the hearing aid functionality is
Speaker 5:  for anyone who has mild to moderate hearing loss. So If you have like more
Speaker 5:  than that then you're still gonna have to go see like a professional and
Speaker 5:  get like that tier of hearing aid versus this. But it's still like a
Speaker 5:  big deal for so many people who don't wanna spend thousands of dollars.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, the test itself is, it's kind of fun.
Speaker 1:  I am sort of terrified just at the prospect thinking about this now because
Speaker 1:  I'm sort of in the position that you are. And I think about this with vision
Speaker 1:  too. Like I have, I have 2020 vision. I don't wear glasses. I'm very proud
Speaker 1:  of that fact. I am 100% sure that if I go to an
Speaker 1:  eye doctor, they are going to make me wear glasses. And so I'm never gonna
Speaker 1:  do it. I don't even have problems with my vision. It's just one of those
Speaker 1:  things that like, I, I bet it could be better and I don't even know. But
Speaker 1:  the prospect of that scares me. And I think what's interesting about hearing
Speaker 1:  is that we all sort of understand the massive scale
Speaker 1:  of vision issues, right? That like you, we understand prescription
Speaker 1:  levels and they go all the way up and down and you can, you can go all the
Speaker 1:  way from like barely needing glasses to being totally blind. Like yeah, that
Speaker 1:  spectrum we all understand. We don't talk about that with hearing at all.
Speaker 1:  And I think there is like, I don't know, decades at this point
Speaker 1:  of people warning you about wearing headphones and listening to music Too
Speaker 1:  loud. And I can still hear my parents being like, turn the music down.
Speaker 1:  You're gonna, you're gonna go deaf. Yeah. But I don't think I've ever
Speaker 1:  had someone quantify my hearing for me. So. I. I am
Speaker 1:  curious like what was that, what does it feel like when you, you take the
Speaker 1:  test it process and as you get the audio audiogram being like
Speaker 1:  you're mostly okay, like what is that? Yeah, a strangely
Speaker 1:  like gratifying feeling.
Speaker 5:  Very strange And like for some reason like my left ear a bit worse off than
Speaker 5:  my right. So that had me wondering like where in life like does my left ear
Speaker 5:  exposed to like much more sound than my right And like I couldn't pinpoint
Speaker 5:  like any phase of life where that would've been the case. But it's driving
Speaker 5:  with the window. That's it is that's what it is.
Speaker 1:  It's just the wind coming by could very
Speaker 5:  Well be just crushing your ears
Speaker 1:  Honestly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. So that was my main takeaway. But I could see this going like
Speaker 5:  viral on TikTok and like having like a moment which would be good for like
Speaker 5:  awareness. I think, you know, it is like private obviously it's health information
Speaker 5:  so not everyone is gonna be comfortable sharing. But I think, you know, it
Speaker 5:  could have a moment on like social media of just people like raising awareness
Speaker 5:  and sharing their results and you know, I'm sure like the iPod generation
Speaker 5:  is gonna have a reckoning of some sort, but yeah, it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  something.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So just to go back to one of the things you said a minute ago, the
Speaker 1:  the, there are the five different scales of, of hearing loss
Speaker 1:  and you said the AirPods are only designed for the first
Speaker 1:  three basically, right? Yeah. Little to no mild and moderate. Like that's,
Speaker 1:  and for the rest that is you, you require something
Speaker 5:  Different. Still have to see a doctor and Okay. Have like a professional
Speaker 5:  hearing aid equipped. Yeah, this is like more, this is like apple's counters,
Speaker 5:  like all the, all these new like over the counter hearing aids, this is their
Speaker 5:  take on that. And so yeah, it's gonna be like a super, super powerful thing.
Speaker 5:  Like we talk about like ecosystem lock-in and like this is like a whole new,
Speaker 5:  whole new level of that If. you think about it like your hearing aid is like
Speaker 5:  an Apple device now. And so like what are the ads you're ever gonna like
Speaker 5:  leave the iPhone at that point.
Speaker 5:  Like on the whole I think it's a very good thing. I think there are some
Speaker 5:  concerns about like smaller companies, like why would you bother making your
Speaker 5:  own hearing aid and trying to compete against Apple, like the biggest tech
Speaker 5:  company in the world, like once they come into this space. But on the whole
Speaker 5:  people are gonna save a ton of money, which is I think a huge deal. Totally.
Speaker 1:  So once it's set up and once it's tuned to you specifically,
Speaker 1:  what does it do? Like it it's, it's easy to say, you know, it just,
Speaker 1:  it makes everything louder so that you can hear it. But I have to imagine
Speaker 1:  it's more complicated than that. Like what are, what are the actual features
Speaker 1:  inside of this hearing it stuff
Speaker 5:  You can tune like how loud it is you can tune like how sharp the sound is
Speaker 5:  and how crisp like there are a lot of the customization options once you
Speaker 5:  actually have your results. And so like that's important. If you wanna make
Speaker 5:  it sound right and yeah, so Apple says it
Speaker 5:  takes like a few days to adjust to how it sounds like for me it barely did
Speaker 5:  anything because I have little to no hearing loss. So I didn't really notice
Speaker 5:  much of anything, but I say like that can still help people who like need
Speaker 5:  certain frequencies boosted and So I just haven't noticed it myself but,
Speaker 5:  but it's there. If you want it. Battery life is about six hours with the
Speaker 5:  hearing aid mode turned on, which is about the same as the Air pods itself.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, that's pretty nice. And yeah, I
Speaker 5:  mean I don't know, not sure what else there is to say about like, I haven't
Speaker 5:  tried it myself. I'm sure there are gonna be like a deep dives about like
Speaker 5:  how well it works versus like over the counter options. Was there a
Speaker 1:  Little part of you as a reviewer who was who wish that I wish I didn't have
Speaker 1:  worse ears. So I could actually do this to myself?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, in some way, but for now I'm just glad that I should concerts and still
Speaker 5:  still have mostly good hearing intact. So yeah,
Speaker 1:  I think it nets out. It nets out. Okay. Yeah, the concerts one I think is,
Speaker 1:  is interesting 'cause there do seem to be sort of two sides of
Speaker 1:  what a device like this does to your, your hearing, right? On the one hand
Speaker 1:  it's enhanced things you want to hear. And I think to me the, the
Speaker 1:  best sort of existing thing I've heard a bunch of people mention is like
Speaker 1:  the the voice isolation feature that you can get on calls and stuff that
Speaker 1:  it's just, that's a, that's a certain bit of processing just designed to
Speaker 1:  make it easier to hear the thing that you want to hear and it's like take
Speaker 1:  that idea and sort of expand it across all the audio
Speaker 1:  on your phone and that is one version of what it's trying to do. Does that,
Speaker 1:  does that seem about right to you? Having used it now? Yeah. Okay. But then
Speaker 1:  the flip side is all the, all the hearing protection stuff, right, which
Speaker 1:  is like the, these things are designed to protect your ears from getting
Speaker 1:  worse. And that strikes me as something that, that
Speaker 1:  may actually be just as interesting to just as many people, even people like
Speaker 1:  you who aren't photographing concerts all the time. Right.
Speaker 1:  I, I realized in just reading about this that I have no idea how that would
Speaker 1:  work. Like what, what is, what is it doing in the hearing protection mode?
Speaker 5:  Just avoids loud sounds beyond like a certain threshold I think, I'm not
Speaker 5:  sure what the number is offhand, but like once things are like over that
Speaker 5:  level, it'll just kinda like down, you know, just bring things back to a
Speaker 5:  safer level. And so that works in like all modes, like noise cancellation
Speaker 5:  mode, transparency mode, and also at the adaptive audio mode. And so
Speaker 5:  like each of those, like you'll hear like certain amounts of like a concert
Speaker 5:  like, like noise cancellation mode, you're still not gonna hear like much
Speaker 5:  of anything. So just still trying to like cancel out everything. So like
Speaker 5:  that's not the most enjoyable concert experience I would say, but you can
Speaker 5:  use that transparency mode here pretty much everything. It's still gonna
Speaker 5:  be fairly loud in your ears, but it's gonna be like a much safer level of
Speaker 5:  loudness versus If you didn't have them in at all. And so that makes all
Speaker 5:  the difference. Got
Speaker 1:  It. So it's, it's basically there to just say it is
Speaker 1:  going to sort of brutally suppress the worst noises, right?
Speaker 1:  No matter the cost. Like forget the smoothing it out, trying to make it sound
Speaker 1:  natural thing. Like we are going to just, just demolish any of these
Speaker 1:  really loud damaging sounds.
Speaker 5:  I mean just tuned to makes some things sound like natural and crisp and like
Speaker 5:  detailed. Okay. So like you don't lose much by having it on. Like I was at
Speaker 5:  this open mic night a few nights ago and didn't feel like I was like really
Speaker 5:  missing out on much in terms of like frequency range or anything like that.
Speaker 5:  So like I was impressed. I haven't used it like a big arena show yet, hopefully
Speaker 5:  this week and he'll get a chance to do that. But yeah, I don't know, it's
Speaker 5:  like a, it's just strange to have them in all the time now.
Speaker 5:  Like for these tests that I've been doing, I think that's like a whole different
Speaker 5:  thing to talk about. Like people are gonna be wearing air pods all the time
Speaker 5:  now, which is kind of unusual versus where we've been before.
Speaker 1:  I wonder about that though. I mean I, and I'm I'm, I'm still sort of
Speaker 1:  struck by you just saying so casually. Lots of people wear AirPods at
Speaker 1:  concerts and like at first I was just like, oh yeah, sure, of course. And
Speaker 1:  I'm like, wait, why on earth would you wear AirPods at concerts? But
Speaker 1:  to some extent I think we have really normalized the idea of
Speaker 1:  wearing AirPods all the time. Yeah. I think we, you can argue about whether
Speaker 1:  that's a good thing or a bad thing. I think by and large it's act it actually
Speaker 1:  sucks because like the social cues are a problem. Like right.
Speaker 5:  If people think it's rude, but now you really can't have that like assumption.
Speaker 5:  Like usually when I have my AirPods in people probably assume like I have
Speaker 5:  like half, they have like half my attention. Whereas now like someone could
Speaker 5:  be using it as a hearing aid and like you could have their full attention,
Speaker 5:  right? And so it's not, you can't just assume like what someone is using
Speaker 5:  them for. I think that's gonna be the big legacy change here.
Speaker 1:  Totally. So yeah. What, how, how do you see that playing out? Like is this
Speaker 1:  just going to push the, I'm wearing headphones from the minute I wake up
Speaker 1:  till the minute I go to sleep thing to kind of the, the nth
Speaker 1:  degree forever. Like for me it's always what do I do when
Speaker 1:  I'm wearing headphones and I walk into Starbucks? Right. Right. And I, I
Speaker 1:  think about like if I'm wearing over the ear headphones, this is the thing
Speaker 1:  I've thought about too much. If I'm wearing over the ear headphones, I will
Speaker 1:  take them off. You take them off around my neck because I'm wor like, you
Speaker 1:  should assume I'm wearing noise canceling headphones and legitimately cannot
Speaker 1:  hear you. Yeah. If I'm wearing AirPods I'll usually just
Speaker 1:  take one out. Okay. And sometimes even like take one out
Speaker 1:  while the person is looking at me as a way of being like, hello,
Speaker 1:  I have, I am now paying attention to you. Yeah. But again, like you're saying,
Speaker 1:  there are now going to be people who have an actual medical purpose to be
Speaker 1:  wearing these things in order to be able to hear people better. Right. And
Speaker 1:  if I'm the person behind the counter at Starbucks, that's just, it's gonna
Speaker 1:  be tricky to figure out what to do about that.
Speaker 1:  But it also just seems like maybe the only correct assumption is just gonna
Speaker 1:  be just talk to the people and hope to God they're not playing really loud
Speaker 1:  music and I don't, I don't know. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think it's gonna take time obviously. I think it's gonna like just
Speaker 5:  kind of like have that thought of like people are being rude or like trying
Speaker 5:  to ignore you kind of fade away. I mean that'll still be the case in certain,
Speaker 5:  like I put my AirPods in to avoid people at times. So like that's gonna keep
Speaker 5:  going I'm sure. But like there's just like that assumption of like why someone
Speaker 5:  has their AirPod air AirPods in or earbuds in, it's gonna have to change
Speaker 5:  over time. It's gonna be a while I think. And I think like this is gonna
Speaker 5:  put a lot of pressure on Samsung and Google, Google's like roll out their
Speaker 5:  own like versions of these features and like once that happens then, you
Speaker 5:  know, and then it's really on. And so, but yeah, it's been like a
Speaker 5:  surreal experience. Like the test is very intense. The hearing protection
Speaker 5:  stuff is a lot of fun. It's good I think for everybody 'cause you don't realize
Speaker 5:  like how loud daily life is. Like I'm down in the subway hearing like screeching
Speaker 5:  trains go by sometimes and I'm just like covering my ears when I have nothing
Speaker 5:  else available to me. So stuff like that is, yeah,
Speaker 1:  You, you never go back once you wear something that is, is really good at
Speaker 1:  doing that kind of work. Yeah. Like it, it, it ruins a lot of things for
Speaker 1:  you. But to that point actually, I, I'm curious how
Speaker 1:  you're feeling as a, as a headphone guy about all of this because
Speaker 1:  the, I think the, the stuff that Apple is doing for hearing health I
Speaker 1:  think is like unequivocally a good thing, right? Yeah. Like the, the question
Speaker 1:  is how well it works and for how many people And, and that's gonna be tricky
Speaker 1:  because people are complicated and ears are different and everybody's hearing
Speaker 1:  is different, but whatever I think that is mostly agreed
Speaker 1:  upon a good thing to be working on. But we're also in this phase and I think
Speaker 1:  Apple is out in front of this, of
Speaker 1:  trying to perfect every sound in every instance all the
Speaker 1:  time. Right? And like the, the AirPods Pro two are probably
Speaker 1:  the best example of this, right? There's the, there's a gaming mode, there's
Speaker 1:  a, there's stuff dedicated to just Siri working well. There's voice
Speaker 1:  isolation,
Speaker 5:  Spatial audio, head tracking. Yeah
Speaker 1:  There's spatial audio head tracking. Like God help us if the
Speaker 1:  head nod thing ever starts to take off like that, that sounds like a nightmare
Speaker 1:  but I just think we're, we're headed to this place where step one is like
Speaker 1:  build a nice pair of headphones and then step two is like
Speaker 1:  try and process it perfectly and for
Speaker 1:  every imaginable situation. And I just wonder if that's the right road
Speaker 1:  to be going down with all of this stuff. Like we're headed towards such a
Speaker 1:  weird everything is ar audio
Speaker 1:  universe. Yeah. And I what does that make you feel as a, as a music guy?
Speaker 5:  I think I feel much better about like these use cases versus like the other
Speaker 5:  stuff we've seen previously. Like we've made a lot of noise about like, you
Speaker 5:  know, giving up the headphone jack and like the pho you buy like the decides
Speaker 5:  what earbuds you get basically. Yeah. And like that's where we're at now.
Speaker 5:  So to see like health benefits like that's where I'm like okay this is the
Speaker 5:  payoff to like where we've been going for all these years and that's great
Speaker 5:  but like, although like head nods and like those gimmicks are, you know,
Speaker 5:  they are what they are, you know, people are gonna use them or they won't.
Speaker 5:  But like this is like the argument where it's like okay this is worth like
Speaker 5:  giving up that phone jack going wireless only 'cause we're these are not
Speaker 5:  like just earbuds anymore obviously. And so that's good I think for the whole
Speaker 5:  industry. But as far as like, you know, just music is still there, you know,
Speaker 5:  I love my music. I can just settle in and and you know and just vibe. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that's not gonna change anytime soon but they do do so much more now
Speaker 5:  and so yeah, just a lot to think about to process and so
Speaker 5:  this is like a huge moment obviously, but gonna see the same from Samsung
Speaker 5:  and, and those companies I'm sure 'cause like how could they not, you know,
Speaker 5:  try and copy this.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It does seem like pretty clearly the next thing for all of these
Speaker 1:  companies. Yeah. And again I think it's mostly a good thing and I do think
Speaker 1:  one thing it seems Apple has done well and I wanna hear more about your experience
Speaker 1:  of this is kind of after that initial setup, it doesn't
Speaker 1:  seem like you have to do all that much. Like you, you take the test and it
Speaker 1:  learns about your ears and yeah, I expected there to be tons of, you know,
Speaker 1:  buttons and knobs and you're constantly having it going in and, and like
Speaker 1:  the, the voice isolation is another one for me. It has always driven me crazy
Speaker 1:  that that's not just on like it's, it just makes your calls sound
Speaker 1:  better. Yeah. Just turn the thing on. I don't understand what the problem
Speaker 1:  is. Yeah. But Apple has always sort of hidden it underneath a setting and
Speaker 1:  my assumption would be that a lot of this would be hidden underneath a setting
Speaker 1:  but it sounds increasingly like it's not and that once
Speaker 1:  you take the test and it understands your ears, it just kind of happens.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah it's pretty true. So like there's the hearing aid mode, there's also
Speaker 5:  this media assist half of it to where it tunes like your music and your phone
Speaker 5:  calls and videos based off like all your data from your hearing test. So
Speaker 5:  all those things sound clear as well. So that's nice. So yeah, it's like
Speaker 5:  a very comprehensive, all encompassing feature that's just kind of there,
Speaker 5:  just always there in the background, just working and so yeah, there's not
Speaker 5:  much to do. Like you can turn it all, some of it off hearing aid obviously
Speaker 5:  can turn on or off, but the hearing protection is just there, which
Speaker 5:  should be the case obviously. And so yeah, there's not much to like do or
Speaker 5:  tinker with or get wrong or mess up yourself, which I think is super important.
Speaker 5:  Especially 'cause like, you know, there're gonna be older people using these
Speaker 5:  features who like don't wanna have to like dig through settings, many use
Speaker 5:  to, you know, tinker with stuff and so that's a big deal. Yeah. I don't know,
Speaker 5:  it's just there, it's simple, you know, it is very Apple. We say that a lot.
Speaker 5:  It just works. This mostly has just worked Say Mary,
Speaker 5:  curious to see like how it compares to like other options on the market,
Speaker 5:  like people's steep dives and like hearing aid functionality and, and all
Speaker 5:  that. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  What do you, what have you heard anything from the, the kind of hearing aid
Speaker 1:  community so far?
Speaker 5:  Not much. I've been trying to chat folks up but I guess, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  a busy bunch these audiologists so That's true. So hopefully pretty soon
Speaker 5:  I'll be able to stay with somebody and get some context but it seems like
Speaker 5:  people are pretty optimistic and hopeful that this is gonna be at least,
Speaker 5:  you know, push the whole industry forward towards like making all this, you
Speaker 5:  know, more affordable and that whole trend. So
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean we've been waiting for a few years now since
Speaker 1:  that bill passed for this kind of over the counter
Speaker 1:  hearing aid revolution that we were expecting and I think
Speaker 1:  years ago people were expecting ultimately this, right? Yeah. Like, and
Speaker 1:  which I think is actually very cool. Apple sort of delivered the thing people
Speaker 1:  have been asking for, which is give me something that looks like a pair of
Speaker 1:  headphones that doesn't scream medical device but
Speaker 1:  gives me some of the help that I need. And I think I, I'm
Speaker 1:  gonna be fascinated to see how Apple communicates that line between here
Speaker 1:  is who they're for and here is who they're not that like
Speaker 1:  even where you fall on the audiogram test, if it's gonna like throw up
Speaker 1:  a thing that's like go see a doctor immediately about your hearing or if
Speaker 1:  it's just more gentle about it, like we can help but only so much. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's pretty gentle. My experience, like the test is very like low stress.
Speaker 5:  It's like this is all normal, hearing loss is normal, these are your results,
Speaker 1:  Everything's fine. But we did call 9 1 1 on your behalf just now. Yeah. Talk
Speaker 1:  to
Speaker 5:  A doctor If you have any questions? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But, and it makes me wonder if this is going to be the
Speaker 1:  beginning of that movement that we've been seeing because I think
Speaker 1:  there is one version of the outcome here that says Apple is
Speaker 1:  actually way ahead of some of these other companies and health stuff and
Speaker 1:  has been working on this a lot longer and has a lot more of the expertise
Speaker 1:  and a lot more of the, you know, corporate lock in to make some of this stuff
Speaker 1:  work. And I think there's truth to some of that, but also Google
Speaker 1:  and Samsung ought to be able to do this kind of thing
Speaker 1:  pretty well pretty quickly. Yeah. Is there any
Speaker 1:  reason you think Apple might have some insurmountable lead here or is this
Speaker 1:  just gonna become the next feature of, of all of these headphones? I
Speaker 5:  Think they'll be the next feature in time. I think Apple got a head start
Speaker 5:  is 'cause they've like focused on this vertical integration of like all their
Speaker 5:  hardware for so, so long that like they've had to jump on like these features.
Speaker 5:  But I'm sure in time like Samsung and Google, I'm not sure how like other
Speaker 5:  companies would get involved like Zen Heiser and Sony, like what are they
Speaker 5:  gonna do? Right? Like being just like third party Sony has something over
Speaker 5:  the counter hearing aids, but like that's not quite the same thing as like
Speaker 5:  that's the thing that's tied to your phone, like knows what you're listening
Speaker 5:  to and like how to make that sound better at all times.
Speaker 5:  Say it's curious, like, I'm curious if Apple's gonna like run ads about these
Speaker 5:  features like on tv, like that'll be fascinating. But I think there's just
Speaker 5:  gonna be like a big push of like awareness hearing health. 'cause that's,
Speaker 5:  you know, very easy to take for granted until, you know, you
Speaker 5:  start losing some of it over time. Totally. Thankfully I'm still in good
Speaker 5:  shape. I've got random bouts of tinnitus. Tinnitus. Well however that's
Speaker 5:  pronounced random bouts of that like once or twice a month where I hear just
Speaker 5:  a little like ringing in my ears. But if that's the worst that I've had through
Speaker 5:  40 years so far, then I'll, I'll take that. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  That's not so bad. You gotta, you could just print out and frame the, the
Speaker 1:  audiogram results there. That's pretty good. Yeah. Before I let you go, anything
Speaker 1:  else in the, the software update here? I mean Apple
Speaker 1:  basically announced these things like they were a brand new product.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Despite it just being a software update to a set of existing headphones.
Speaker 1:  You've been using the software update for a while now. Anything else to
Speaker 1:  report?
Speaker 5:  I mean that's the reason that I would update to iOS 18.1. You know, If, you
Speaker 5:  don't care about all the AI stuff and Apple Intelligence, this is a great
Speaker 5:  reason to like get all these new features. You can't do it on iOS 18.0 or
Speaker 5:  like any previous version. So you have to update If, you want all these AirPods
Speaker 5:  features. So If, you don't care about the ai AI stuff, which I do like the
Speaker 5:  summarized notifications on iOS 18.1. They're, they're pretty handy.
Speaker 5:  But as far as like other like AirPods stuff, you know, the head nods are
Speaker 5:  there, they work fairly well. Do
Speaker 1:  You use them beyond?
Speaker 5:  I've tried them. I turned them off pretty quickly. They worked, you know,
Speaker 5:  I'm sure, I'm sure there are people who love like all these like very niche
Speaker 5:  features and so, you know, people like love having Siri, like read their
Speaker 5:  notifications out loud. I would never want that to, to be my situation.
Speaker 1:  No. To me it's just the, the penalty for having the
Speaker 1:  nod and head shake on and get it wrong is that like I answer a
Speaker 1:  phone call that I don't want to in the
Speaker 5:  Wrong. That you very clearly like shook your head vigorously not to answer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Exactly. Like that is, I know enough about this technology
Speaker 1:  to know that that stuff is imperfect. Yeah. And the just the penalty for
Speaker 1:  being wrong once terrifies me. Like even now when I'm, I'm in the car
Speaker 1:  or whatever and it's like, so and so is calling. Would you like to answer?
Speaker 1:  I I have, I never have said the word no more clearly than I do Yeah. In
Speaker 1:  those moments. Yeah. And still I'm afraid that something is gonna go wrong.
Speaker 1:  So I think making that stuff even simpler seems like a
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 1:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com. We love all of your questions and we try to answer at least one
Speaker 1:  on the show every week. I've been promising a full hotline episode for
Speaker 1:  a while and I, that is coming. We just, there's too much going on.
Speaker 1:  If they could just stop with the news for a minute, I'd love to do a hotline
Speaker 1:  episode, but I think that's coming. I'm very excited about it. So get all
Speaker 1:  your questions in all of your weird tech mysteries, all of the things you
Speaker 1:  want us to just ruminate endlessly on. And we'll get to them all this week.
Speaker 1:  We have a very fun question about video games.
Speaker 6:  Hi Vergecast, my name is Brian, I'm in North Carolina, nearish, epic and
Speaker 6:  limited run games. For context, I've had this question ever since you had
Speaker 6:  RI tested on the show about Delta and emulation on iOS,
Speaker 6:  it came up again at the tail end of your origins of podcasting episode.
Speaker 6:  Apple had a gaming problem. Why don't they just buy Nintendo?
Speaker 6:  I know they have enough liquid capital sitting around that they could purchase
Speaker 6:  the entirety of that company like you. Or I could go buy a switch.
Speaker 6:  So what's stopping them? Is it Lena Khan? Does that matter?
Speaker 6:  If the company isn't American, is it that they don't actually
Speaker 6:  care about games? Would Nintendo say no to a
Speaker 6:  Scrooge McDuck sized pile of Apple cash? So that's
Speaker 6:  my question. Why doesn't Apple solve its problem with gaming by eating
Speaker 6:  Nintendo? What stops it from doing that? And just for fun,
Speaker 6:  what would the world look like if it did? Thanks for talking about this.
Speaker 6:  I've been sitting with this in my head for literal months and I'm more than
Speaker 6:  happy for it to sit in your heads. Instead, I need to go do other things
Speaker 6:  now. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 1:  All right. I have brought the verges foremost Nintendo expert, Andrew Webster
Speaker 1:  here to help me with this. Andrew. Hello. Hello. So. I caught you
Speaker 1:  in the middle of writing a piece. Would you just briefly describe the piece
Speaker 1:  that you've, you're, you're working on? Because I think it's a useful setup
Speaker 1:  for what we're doing here.
Speaker 7:  Oh, well now I have to write it, but the, the working headline is,
Speaker 7:  I have given up on guessing what Nintendo is going to do,
Speaker 7:  which is a conclusion I've come to after covering them for like, I dunno,
Speaker 7:  15 years or so,
Speaker 1:  So I. I wanna separate, separate this into two pieces. There is the, why
Speaker 1:  does an Apple buy a Nintendo piece of it? and there is the, what
Speaker 1:  would the world look like if Nintendo were owned by Apple? And I feel like
Speaker 1:  in the first case the answer seems very straightforward, which is that
Speaker 1:  anyone would, seems like they would wanna buy Nintendo, right? Like ev
Speaker 1:  everyone given the opportunity would, including Apple I assume
Speaker 1:  would leap to buy Nintendo. You think that's true?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think the, what's stopping them is obviously Nintendo.
Speaker 7:  Nintendo has Scrooge McDuck piles already and they just keep getting
Speaker 7:  more and more.
Speaker 7:  So there's not really any reason for them to sell. And I do think
Speaker 7:  that that point about Apple not caring about gaming is very true.
Speaker 7:  I'm like, in addition to being the verges foremost Nintendo expert,
Speaker 7:  I'm also our only Apple arcade expert. And it is a great service. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That it is just nobody knows about because
Speaker 7:  Apple does not care. And I also don't think Apple thinks it
Speaker 7:  has a gaming problem because it makes a lot
Speaker 7:  of money from games and not the kind of games that Nintendo
Speaker 7:  makes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think the question of like, would Apple be interested in making
Speaker 1:  the next Zelda game is actually really interesting. I think Apple is very
Speaker 1:  happy running a store in which it gets cuts of the
Speaker 1:  work that other people do. And if we've learned one thing about the gaming
Speaker 1:  industry in the last couple of years, it's that you spend an awful lot of
Speaker 1:  money making things that may or may not work. And I guess the
Speaker 1:  appeal of Nintendo is that mostly it makes things that work, its hit rate
Speaker 1:  has gotta be better than anybody's, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I mean they tried this, I am one of the few
Speaker 7:  people who will say Super Mario Run was an excellent game fair and it was
Speaker 7:  downloaded, I don't know, 200 million times, but not enough people bought
Speaker 7:  it for Nintendo to consider that success. So like you've
Speaker 7:  already had Shiro Miyamoto make a game for the iPhone and
Speaker 7:  they never followed it up. So, and you know, apple
Speaker 7:  Arcade already has a very good sell to clone So I think Apple's pretty happy.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So before we pivot to the what would it look like thing I just
Speaker 1:  wanna, I went back after we got this question and found
Speaker 1:  from last summer, summer of 2023, there were all those emails
Speaker 1:  from 2020 that leaked out in the Microsoft case
Speaker 1:  and one of them was from Phil Spencer to a couple of folks on his team about
Speaker 1:  Nintendo. And I think he, he pretty neatly I think sums up
Speaker 1:  everyone's feelings about Nintendo in general. And he says, I totally agree
Speaker 1:  that Nintendo is the prime asset for us in gaming. And today gaming is our
Speaker 1:  most likely path to consumer relevance. This is, they're talking about Xbox,
Speaker 1:  obviously I've had numerous conversations with the LT of Nintendo about tighter
Speaker 1:  collaboration and feel like if any US company would have a chance with Nintendo,
Speaker 1:  we are probably in the best position. This is the best part. The unfortunate
Speaker 1:  or fortunate for Nintendo situation is that Nintendo is sitting on a big
Speaker 1:  pile of cash. They have a board of directors that until recently has not
Speaker 1:  pushed for further increases in market growth or stock appreciation. And
Speaker 1:  his basic thing is like, I don't know what to give Nintendo. They don't want
Speaker 1:  our money, they don't want our resources. They're very happy being Nintendo.
Speaker 1:  And I feel like that is why no one has bought Nintendo because Nintendo is
Speaker 1:  super happy being Nintendo.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We think of Nintendo as this playful company. You know, me
Speaker 7:  and Boto is like happy go lucky guy, but they're a
Speaker 7:  ruthless corporation that extracts as much money from everything as they
Speaker 7:  can. Yeah. Good luck finding Zelda on sale ever.
Speaker 1:  Right, right. I mean, what the switch is eight years old now. Yeah. And still
Speaker 1:  doing just fine. Like Nintendo knows exactly what it's doing
Speaker 1:  and Yeah, I I I like to the would they accept
Speaker 1:  any offer? I'm sure there's a number, everybody always has a number, but
Speaker 1:  at some point Nintendo's market cap I think I was looking at this morning
Speaker 1:  is like $62 billion and that's a, that's a big number
Speaker 1:  and at some point I'm sure there is a number, but I bet that number is substantially
Speaker 1:  higher than anybody thinks it is for what it would take to actually get that
Speaker 1:  done. But since you brought up Apple Arcade, I just, I just
Speaker 1:  want to fantasize for a minute here. Let's, let's say Apple decides to write
Speaker 1:  a check for, you know, all of the cash. It has $250 billion
Speaker 1:  and it owns Nintendo. And do you think Apple would do with Nintendo
Speaker 7:  That is like, I've been thinking about this and I feel like there's two avenues,
Speaker 7:  one of which is good and will not be successful and one of which is bad and
Speaker 7:  we will make a ton of money.
Speaker 1:  That sounds right.
Speaker 7:  The one is the Apple arcade route, which is like, yeah you can play like
Speaker 7:  Mario three and the Mario Wonder and like all these games
Speaker 7:  on your phone and Nintendo has access to the hardware
Speaker 7:  in a way that they do when they make their own hardware
Speaker 7:  and can make things that are perfectly suited for it. Again, Mario one is
Speaker 7:  good. It's a game designed for a touchscreen. They know what they're doing.
Speaker 7:  That's like
Speaker 1:  A dream scenario by the way. That's
Speaker 7:  A dream scenario.
Speaker 1:  A lot of like you get to emulate all the games on your Apple devices, it
Speaker 1:  becomes this like incredible place for Nintendo to put everything it's ever
Speaker 1:  made, including all the new stuff like that. Sounds awesome.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that's what people say they want, but not enough people most likely
Speaker 7:  would actually pay the money for it. Yeah. And what's more likely to happen
Speaker 7:  is, so Mario Run, I keep bringing it up,
Speaker 7:  it was generally a failure for them, but they have had several
Speaker 7:  successful mobile games which are, there's Am Crossing one, there's
Speaker 7:  Fire Emblem one, and they are just filled with all of the free to play
Speaker 7:  bullshit that everyone hates, but they make so much money they're still running
Speaker 7:  and even though Nintendo has forgotten about
Speaker 7:  mobile gaming, they don't turn those switches off because they get money
Speaker 7:  and that is how Apple makes it money from gaming.
Speaker 7:  So I think the dire scenario is, you know, loot boxes
Speaker 7:  and animal crossing
Speaker 1:  Right. Or loot boxes in tiers of the kingdom. Right. That's exactly the,
Speaker 1:  that's that's where this starts to get really dark. Yeah. Which of course
Speaker 1:  ruins tears of the kingdom in a lot of, and so it's like maybe there is something
Speaker 1:  about the way that Nintendo works right now that is the reason it's able
Speaker 1:  to do the things that it does. Like maybe it stick it inside of a corporation
Speaker 1:  that is much more worried about maximizing growth and it changes all of the
Speaker 1:  incentives here. Yeah. Like maybe the way we have it is actually the correct
Speaker 1:  way to have it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Mario Wonder exists when I was talking to the
Speaker 7:  directors because they were like, we're not gonna have a deadline, we're
Speaker 7:  just gonna let people come up with ideas and when it's ready, it's ready.
Speaker 7:  And then it was, you know, the best Mario in a decade. So
Speaker 7:  that's how it happens.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. So do you, do you think there is
Speaker 1:  a world in which this ever happens in, in the time that
Speaker 1:  we're doing this? Like Nintendo's been around forever, we've given
Speaker 1:  up guessing what's gonna happen with Nintendo. Is this just
Speaker 1:  Nintendo's after you're making alarm clocks, not worrying about like live
Speaker 1:  service games, you know what I mean? Like is this Yeah, is this just Nintendo
Speaker 1:  forever, do you think?
Speaker 7:  If, you can turn it around after the Weu. I think like you're safe. They're,
Speaker 7:  they don't have to worry about it. Yeah, they're Nintendo. Fair enough.
Speaker 1:  All right, before I let you go, do you know anything about the Switch Two,
Speaker 1:  can you blink twice? If, you know what's going on with the Switch two?
Speaker 7:  I got nothing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, fair enough. Alright Andrew, thank you. Appreciate
Speaker 1:  Media podcast network. Eli, and I'll be back on Friday to talk about
Speaker 1:  more gadgets, more AI stuff, continuing
Speaker 1:  craziness at open AI and lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 1:  roll