# Transcript
ID: cbe34ed9-5675-42ef-ae7e-accf80d6e8d5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8738651179393976956/9204521294220976189/s93290-US-5351s-1725040067.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss Telegram CEO being charged in a French criminal investigation over content moderation, Yelp suing Google for antitrust violations, a week in AI-generated nonsense, and more.
Telegram says CEO has ‘nothing to hide’ after being arrested in France
French authorities arrest Telegram’s CEO
Why the Telegram CEO’s arrest is such a big deal
Telegram CEO charged in French criminal investigation
Telegram CEO Pavel Durov faces court questioning in France.
French prosecutors explain why they arrested Telegram CEO Pavel Durov
How Pavel Durov, Telegram’s Founder, Went From Russia’s Mark Zuckerberg to Wanted Man
Can Tech Executives Be Held Responsible for What Happens on Their Platforms?
How Telegram played itself
Yelp sues Google for antitrust violations
TikTok must face a lawsuit for recommending the viral ‘blackout challenge’
California State Assembly passes sweeping AI safety bill
Mark Zuckerberg responds to GOP pressure, says Biden pushed to ‘censor’ covid post
Google Gemini will let you create AI-generated people again
xAI’s new Grok image generator floods X with controversial AI fakes
X’s Grok directs to government site after sharing false election info
Smart home company Brilliant has found a buyer
ESPN ‘Where to Watch’ feature helps find where to stream sporting events
Plaud’s NotePin is an AI wearable for summarizing meetings and taking voice notes
The maker of the Palma has a new cheaper e-reader
The Dyson Airwrap i.d. is a smarter hair curler
Snapchat finally launched an iPad app
Instagram adds what photos have always needed: words
Apple’s iPhone 16 launch event is set for September
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (45 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  and I I don't know that those are the right decisions.
Speaker 4:  Well, you can't read. We should say that upfront. Neli famously
Speaker 4:  illiterate.
Speaker 3:  I hate reading. Hi, I'm your friend Neli. I I I love reading
Speaker 3:  and I think you should do more of it. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 4:  Hi
Speaker 3:  Alex. Cranz is here. I'm
Speaker 5:  Just thinking about reading Rainbow now.
Speaker 3:  You know, it's, it's fun when you have a small child, you're like in reading
Speaker 3:  again. That's a real thing. And which, what Max wants to read with me most
Speaker 3:  is Calvin and Hobbes, which is, I love it. The
Speaker 4:  Dream that rules.
Speaker 3:  Have you ever tried to read Calvin and Hobbes out loud to another
Speaker 3:  person who doesn't understand the jokes from the literal
Speaker 3:  1980s? She's like, what's a telephone?
Speaker 4:  Kavanaugh Hobbs is definitely a cartoon for adults. Like it is not,
Speaker 4:  yeah. The jokes in it and, and like the messages in it I find like deep
Speaker 4:  and important and profound now. And I'm like very old
Speaker 4:  and it, how, I don't know how to explain any of that to a child.
Speaker 3:  Try, try. I just, if you have a kid and you're like, here's what we can do,
Speaker 3:  we can read comic books together. We were at, I already own all these books
Speaker 3:  and we were at an estate sale like down the street from our house and we
Speaker 3:  bought the full collection again 'cause it was so cheap. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  this is what money's for. Like this is how you make it to buy all the Calvin
Speaker 3:  Hobbs books whenever they're available to you. Yeah. And so she was excited
Speaker 3:  'cause we bought all these what appeared to her to be comic books. I encourage
Speaker 3:  you, if you have children, to try and just try to read any comic strip. Like
Speaker 3:  first of all, that's bananas. True. And then these are like the multilayers,
Speaker 3:  like I'm giggling and she's like, I don't, is the, is the tiger alive?
Speaker 3:  I don't understand.
Speaker 5:  Get her in on Kathy's. See
Speaker 3:  She looked at me. Let's see
Speaker 5:  How she feels about Kathy.
Speaker 3:  Oh man.
Speaker 3:  She looked at me very seriously the other day and she goes, my line never
Speaker 3:  comes alive. And I was like, well, you're a grown up kid. You're in first
Speaker 3:  grade now. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Working taxes your imagination, max. How about that?
Speaker 3:  Alright. There's a lot going on this week. It's kind of a, we're two weeks
Speaker 3:  out from the iPhone event. It's, I keep joking. It's like summer's over.
Speaker 3:  That's where we are. Yep. I candidly have just like
Speaker 3:  end of summer whatever, like that's my brain. Like
Speaker 3:  what if I, what if I just shut it down for a couple weeks before we ramp
Speaker 3:  up into the gadget season? But there's still a lot of news a ton and all
Speaker 3:  of it is like policy news, like the, the, the legal systems of the world
Speaker 3:  just keep generating PDFs for me to read on a Bos Palmer,
Speaker 4:  I mean literally it's just everyone trying to
Speaker 4:  do the work that they have to do so that they can have a long weekend over
Speaker 4:  Labor Day. Like I'm, I'm convinced that's, this is the same thing that happens
Speaker 4:  like right before Thanksgiving. It's just a bunch of people who are like,
Speaker 4:  I need a minute. Let me, let me file all my paperwork. Let me get
Speaker 4:  all the work done. Let me push publish on the thing and then get out. Like,
Speaker 4:  nothing is going to happen on Friday. Nothing. Everybody's on vacation. They're
Speaker 4:  like, I did it already four day weekend. Let And
Speaker 3:  You're listening to this on a Friday, so get ready. Yeah. We're gonna recapitulate
Speaker 3:  everyone else you've
Speaker 4:  Done work any work today. Stop it.
Speaker 5:  I I do think like the, the theory falls a little short when we
Speaker 5:  consider France. 'cause they don't do Labor Day the same Labor day. I mean
Speaker 3:  Every day in France is Labor Day.
Speaker 5:  That's true.
Speaker 3:  They're like, were you counting on the buses today? Strike.
Speaker 3:  That's not how French people talk. Can I just talk about the, the Boots Bomber
Speaker 3:  for one more second. So governments around the world generate PDFs and it
Speaker 3:  is our job to read them a broad in broad strokes. That's how I think of
Speaker 3:  the virtual policy teams coverage. Yes. David made everybody
Speaker 3:  buy a b Palmer. Right. He came to your house and it with threat of violence
Speaker 3:  made you buy an EIN Android phone. He
Speaker 5:  Just knocked on my door. But it was, it was polite.
Speaker 3:  But it happened. It, yeah,
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 3:  Happened. The ver the other function of The Verge besides responding to
Speaker 3:  government PDFs is making people buy stupid gadgets.
Speaker 3:  I'm very confident in this dynamic. Like this is how it should be. So I.
Speaker 3:  I buy a BWA and I'm like, this is how I'm gonna do PDFs 'cause so much of
Speaker 3:  my job is reading PDFs. But then you need another piece of software. 'cause
Speaker 3:  it's not good at anything by itself. No, because it's just a low end
Speaker 3:  Android phone with an e this way. So then you gotta get Read Wise Reader
Speaker 3:  and it feels like those two companies should just
Speaker 3:  put it together. Like those are the 200% things. It's not actually
Speaker 3:  the B Palmer that people want it's read wise reader on an eing screen.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent could not agree more. And and like
Speaker 4:  every time Alex and I both go through this, every time we talk to a company
Speaker 4:  that makes e-readers, we say, when are you gonna make a decent app for reading
Speaker 4:  things? And every time we talk to a company that makes a reading app, it's
Speaker 4:  like, why don't you make hardware? And at some point somebody's gonna
Speaker 4:  do it and it's gonna be great because you are exactly correct. Didn't
Speaker 5:  Amazon kind of do it
Speaker 3:  Right? This is a no, what I'm arguing for is lockin, but I'm just
Speaker 4:  Pointing out I software that's the the word good is so, so, so important
Speaker 4:  in that That's true. That's true. Read wise reader, good software. There's
Speaker 4:  good software out there. Omnivore free app, good software.
Speaker 4:  Make a, make a thing for it. I mean Omni
Speaker 3:  Or, or work together with the company that's making the thing like if you
Speaker 3:  buy the books, but you would not know that Read Wise Reader exists and is
Speaker 3:  the thing that unlocks the hardware. Right. Right. I feel like they could
Speaker 3:  just close that loop Anyway, read Wise Reader, the thing that you do to it
Speaker 3:  is you upload the PDF and it basically ocr it into a format
Speaker 3:  that looks good on an ING screen, which is great. Only that takes
Speaker 3:  time. And I have no attention span and no patience. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  screw it. I'm just reading this PDF on my iPad and that has happened like
Speaker 3:  five times in a row.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Kevin Wynn, our features editor is, is constantly dealing with this
Speaker 4:  'cause we're always getting like galley of books and stuff and
Speaker 4:  every time I get like a PDF of a book that's about to be released that I
Speaker 4:  have to read for whatever reason, I first try to upload it into my Kindle
Speaker 4:  where it doesn't work and looks bad. Then I try to put it in read wise where
Speaker 4:  it doesn't work and looks bad. And then I end up reading it like in Dropbox
Speaker 4:  on my iPad and I'm like, how is this the best possible solution
Speaker 4:  here? And yet it
Speaker 3:  Is. and it, every time it's, I I've come this close from
Speaker 3:  going from Books Palmer to, to buying an iPad mini like pilots around the,
Speaker 3:  the world. By the way, people now just send us creep shots of pilots
Speaker 3:  with iPads.
Speaker 4:  It's the best.
Speaker 3:  It's my favorite. Yeah. Very unexpected outcome of hosting a podcast about
Speaker 3:  technology. But pilot, you look, all the pilots look great.
Speaker 3:  Everyone looks happy with their iPad. Okay, let's talk about some actual
Speaker 3:  technique. So we, we gotta talk about Telegram. There's a bunch of other
Speaker 3:  legal stuff that happened this week and then we got a a, a true lightning
Speaker 3:  round where we're gonna try to get through 'em all to wrap this thing up.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yep. But we should start with Telegram, which is, I would say
Speaker 3:  not only news of the week, but the ongoing news of of time to
Speaker 3:  come. Yeah. Because the idea that's that social or messaging
Speaker 3:  platform owners face criminal liability for what happens on their platforms.
Speaker 3:  It might feel new and shocking 'cause the French government arrested this
Speaker 3:  guy, but it's also been building for a very, very long time
Speaker 3:  that some amount of responsibility for what happens on our platform will
Speaker 3:  be imposed. And ev government, our government has wanted to do this. Right.
Speaker 3:  I mean Congress is like Jack Dorsey, we're gonna yell at you for a while.
Speaker 3:  This one I think is particularly shocking 'cause of just the facts of what
Speaker 3:  Telegram is. The fact that Paval Duro, the CEO landed
Speaker 3:  in France on a private jet and the French authorities immediately arrested
Speaker 3:  him. Why land your plane where the people are gonna arrest you? His sort
Speaker 3:  of unrepentant attitude about what's going on the platform. David, catch
Speaker 3:  us up on the basics.
Speaker 4:  Sure. So basically last Sunday, Paval Duro,
Speaker 4:  the CEO of Telegram was arrested, like you said, after landing. The
Speaker 4:  PJ in France
Speaker 3:  Just don't land your PJ there.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, it's an odd move. You're
Speaker 3:  Connecting
Speaker 4:  Don't call it No, just don't land. The PJ is
Speaker 4:  is a good, we can make shirts that say just don't land the PJ that could
Speaker 4:  work,
Speaker 3:  Stay in the sky Pavo.
Speaker 4:  And all we knew at the time was that he was arrested. I believe the
Speaker 4:  French authorities said like in conjunction with an investigation into
Speaker 4:  crimes. It was very vague. But he, he was arrested and over
Speaker 4:  the next several days it, it came out that essentially what
Speaker 4:  was happening is that he was being arrested based on
Speaker 4:  criminal activity that was happening on Telegram. He, he was not as
Speaker 4:  far as I understand, being accused of doing the crimes, but of, of what the
Speaker 4:  French government ended up calling complicity in the, the criminal
Speaker 4:  activity that was happening on Telegram. He has since been charged with a
Speaker 4:  bunch of things, most of which are complicity for things like money
Speaker 4:  laundering and child abuse, child sexual abuse material, all
Speaker 4:  sorts of other internet crimes. And the, the overarching theme seems to be
Speaker 4:  a, a lot of this bad stuff was happening in relative plain sight
Speaker 4:  on Telegram. And b Telegram
Speaker 4:  not only knew it was hosting this stuff and allowed
Speaker 4:  it, but actively resisted working with governments
Speaker 4:  to help. Yes. I think, again, this is the very beginning of what I
Speaker 4:  think is gonna be a very long story, but I think in terms of like the basics
Speaker 4:  of what we know, I think that's kind of where we are at this moment. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Am I missing anything? No,
Speaker 3:  Those are the basics. Obviously none of us are experts in French law. If
Speaker 3:  you are an expert bull Sure. French law, you know, hit us up. We would love
Speaker 3:  to talk to you.
Speaker 3:  But the, the piece of that puzzle that are really important here that I think
Speaker 3:  we can understand and talk about credibly are one, how Telegram
Speaker 3:  works. Because a lot of people want to impute how other
Speaker 3:  platform works onto Telegram and they're actually really different. So
Speaker 3:  it's a very common misconception that Telegram is encrypted and it is just
Speaker 3:  not, it's not even like Secret Chats
Speaker 3:  one-to-one chats You can push a button and make them encrypted, but that
Speaker 3:  is not the default. Right. Telegram groups are not encrypted. Like
Speaker 3:  there's nothing inherently secure about Telegram. Like I will tell you,
Speaker 3:  I know a lot of activists who know, who know that there
Speaker 3:  is CSAM on iMessage that there is is bad stuff on
Speaker 3:  signal. And the defense is these are end-to-end encrypted.
Speaker 3:  No one can see the data except the participants. So Apple knows it's there.
Speaker 3:  Everybody, people have told them, they've actually built some tools to try
Speaker 3:  to detect it and gotten yelled at Yeah. For essentially breaking the encryption.
Speaker 3:  We've, we've talked about that straight at length, but fundamentally it can't
Speaker 3:  see it. So it has this out like these companies have these outs,
Speaker 3:  like people are using, doing bad things on our platforms, but we can't see
Speaker 3:  it. So we don't know. And you should find other ways to catch them. Right?
Speaker 3:  And this is a lot of the argument about end-to-end encryption is
Speaker 3:  the cops wanna see the bad stuff and they want the companies to build them
Speaker 3:  back doors to give the bad stuff to them. And So, I think there's a
Speaker 3:  temptation to assume Telegram is operating the same way and it
Speaker 3:  is not. Right. And I think that is actually the first most important thing
Speaker 3:  is all this stuff is just happening out in the wide open in Telegram
Speaker 3:  in these huge channels, in these unencrypted chats.
Speaker 3:  Telegram can see almost everything that happens unless you press secret chat,
Speaker 3:  which no one is pressing and it only happens between people anyway. And so
Speaker 3:  it is a very unusual service in the sense that it,
Speaker 3:  it knows te it has the technical ability to know what is happening on service.
Speaker 3:  And lots of people can see what's happening on service, which
Speaker 5:  Have y'all used Telegram a whole lot
Speaker 4:  In bits and pieces
Speaker 3:  Today? Today felt like the wrong day to start.
Speaker 5:  I would say no. I like, I remember using it. I, I used it when I
Speaker 5:  went to Taipei at one point just 'cause it was easy to communicate with my
Speaker 5:  friends. And when I got back Covid hit was living in New York and
Speaker 5:  so all the protests and stuff were happening. So there was a ton of organizing
Speaker 5:  happening on Telegram most miserable experience I've ever
Speaker 5:  had using a chat program. Just awful. Because it is just like,
Speaker 5:  it's a chat room. It's just, okay, you're now in a chat room and you're gonna
Speaker 5:  go to bed and wake up to 200 new messages in a chat room
Speaker 5:  and you have no
Speaker 4:  Control over that. It actually, you make a good point. Let me just quickly
Speaker 4:  like explain the rough structure of Telegram because like you're saying,
Speaker 4:  Eli it is, it is actually instructive for what's
Speaker 3:  Happening here. It tells you a lot about the story.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. So there are, there are basically three levels of
Speaker 4:  Telegram which exists, I would say somewhere in the, like if you imagine
Speaker 4:  the overlapping Venn diagram of like WhatsApp and
Speaker 4:  Discord and like WeChat. Like Telegram
Speaker 4:  is somewhere in the middle of those three things. So all the way at the top
Speaker 4:  you have public channels, right? Which is basically like the
Speaker 4:  equivalent of an Instagram feed, right? You, you post something,
Speaker 4:  lots of people can see it. It's a, it's essentially just a public, like
Speaker 4:  one-way feed the middle thing, which I think is probably telegrams
Speaker 4:  like most, I don't know if not most used and sort of most
Speaker 4:  unique thing is the group chats. And the group chats can have, I think the
Speaker 4:  number is up to 200,000 people in them, which is a crazy number,
Speaker 4:  but is is a huge part of the reason that Telegram has been used for things
Speaker 4:  like political organizing and for huge, like government communications.
Speaker 4:  It's because You can have that many people literally in a space together.
Speaker 4:  It becomes abject chaos. But it can be really useful. And then
Speaker 4:  at the bottom of that is one-to-one chat. So You can go all
Speaker 4:  the way from, you and I are texting each other to
Speaker 4:  like one to millions inside of Telegram.
Speaker 4:  And there's also like, there's, there's app stuff going on in there. There
Speaker 4:  are all kinds of like plug iny things You can do inside of Telegram. It has
Speaker 4:  some of that like WeChat operating system dynamic
Speaker 4:  to it. But most of what
Speaker 5:  Happens truly terrible emojis.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's not a good looking app in the same way that WeChat is not a good
Speaker 4:  looking app, but like it does a lot. Yeah. And so it's, it's very useful
Speaker 4:  for those reasons. And so the reason
Speaker 4:  most people use it, and for our purposes, I think the reason it's particularly
Speaker 4:  interesting right now because of what's going on with POV is
Speaker 4:  really probably the top two things, right? The thing where one person can
Speaker 4:  communicate with a lot of people very quickly and the sort of giant
Speaker 4:  teaming group chats of up to 200,000 people, right? So like there's nothing
Speaker 4:  else that works quite that same way on
Speaker 3:  The internet. And to be clear, if you have a one to 200,000 person
Speaker 3:  group chat, not, it doesn't matter if that's encrypted definitionally, that
Speaker 3:  thing is leaking, right? Yeah. It's, it, it, it, you're not trying to keep
Speaker 3:  that secret. Like that's not the point of talking to 200,000 people. So
Speaker 3:  there's all these arguments for why it would and would not be encrypted.
Speaker 3:  But I I think the first thing to just be very clear on is it's
Speaker 3:  not like the other platforms that are used for political organizing. It's
Speaker 3:  not like the other platforms that are encrypted or claim to be encrypted.
Speaker 3:  It is inherently this broadcast medium. And then the other piece, which is
Speaker 3:  tremendously relevant to all of this is that it has
Speaker 3:  no, the has no content moderation, which is not like a technical
Speaker 3:  decision that is a policy decision. They've just decided
Speaker 3:  this is gonna be fine, it's a free for all. We don't care. We support free
Speaker 3:  speech and the policy decision's a flow from that get all the way to like,
Speaker 3:  how do we treat governments and also just implicate things like ISIS lives
Speaker 3:  on Telegram. This is just gonna be the app that ISIS uses and people have
Speaker 3:  known this for a long time. We are going to accept an enormous
Speaker 3:  amount of pornography, including some of the worst pornography, including
Speaker 3:  some child sexual abuse material, perhaps lots of child sexual abuse material.
Speaker 3:  And everyone can just see it and researchers can just file a report after
Speaker 3:  report about this, the prevalence of this material on Telegram and the
Speaker 3:  company is gonna do nothing about it. And then that brings you to the actual
Speaker 3:  policy decisions, which is the way they've structured the data on
Speaker 3:  Telegram means that if a government wants to issue a warrant or a subpoena,
Speaker 3:  they actually have to issue like 20 right? In countries across the world
Speaker 3:  in order to get the data and prove the case against the bad people. And telegrams
Speaker 3:  are very proud of this. And all platforms have, you know, kind of like their
Speaker 3:  transparency reports or you know, in other
Speaker 3:  times, like they've had what's called canaries where they, they
Speaker 3:  say they have a sentence on their website, it's like, we've never done this.
Speaker 3:  And then they silently change it, they get rid of that sentence so people
Speaker 3:  know it happened, but even they haven't disclosed anything. Oh wow. Telegrams
Speaker 3:  one is like, we've just never given up any data. Everyone can see all the
Speaker 3:  bad things on our platforms. They wanna catch the bad people and we have
Speaker 3:  made it so you cannot, you can't do it. Right? Like it's so hard to do it.
Speaker 3:  No government has ever managed to do this. And I think that is the
Speaker 3:  liability. Again, I don't really know French law,
Speaker 3:  but I, I know how our government thinks about it. I know how researchers
Speaker 3:  think about it. You know, academics think about it. And once you get to,
Speaker 3:  you know it's happening and you won't even help the cops stop it.
Speaker 3:  You end up with maybe you're responsible for yourself and that is,
Speaker 3:  that's a lot of steps. You gotta get through a lot of steps. I
Speaker 3:  don't think there's any networks in the United States that are anywhere close
Speaker 3:  to that, even though the usual morons are screaming
Speaker 3:  about free speech on Telegram. That's just not how it works here. Like no
Speaker 3:  one is that stupid, but here it feels like there
Speaker 3:  was an such an active effort to frustrate authorities from
Speaker 3:  prosecuting just straightforwardly criminal behavior. The
Speaker 3:  dude landed his PJ in France and got arrested. Yeah, I think we gotta find
Speaker 3:  out the case. We gotta figure again, not an expert in French law. Like there's,
Speaker 3:  there's a whole bunch of stuff, but the, you know, the crimes are
Speaker 3:  happening and you won't even help us stop it. That's where you, you
Speaker 3:  get that collapse of liability too. We're just gonna arrest the CE of the
Speaker 3:  social network. Well,
Speaker 4:  And it goes back to the questions of encryption too, because I think you,
Speaker 4:  you look at something like iMessage, right? Where Apple's
Speaker 4:  stance, right or wrong believe it or don't believe it is privacy is
Speaker 4:  more important than everything else. We can't see it and neither can you,
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We don't even know it's happening. Right? You believe it's happening,
Speaker 3:  but there's no way for us to know it's happening. Right?
Speaker 4:  Agree or disagree. That is a stance, that is a whole stance. What
Speaker 4:  Telegram has said is, is the opposite, right? Like all the things you're
Speaker 4:  saying about we can see it and we're doing nothing about it. They've like
Speaker 4:  touted this as part of the point over the years. And one of the things that
Speaker 4:  Paval Durra has said many to times is like, You can't build a,
Speaker 4:  a private, secure, safe place for people to talk except for
Speaker 4:  terrorists. And like, again, bunch of really interesting arguments behind
Speaker 4:  that sentence, but it's not encrypted. And this is the thing that it comes
Speaker 4:  back to, right? Is it would be a different argument if Telegram were an encrypted
Speaker 4:  app on which all of this stuff was kind of loosely known to be happening,
Speaker 4:  but you couldn't see it. But like You can see it. It's just, it's just
Speaker 4:  there, there have been all these researchers in the last few days who are,
Speaker 4:  are coming out and saying like, the the new Defy
Speaker 4:  AI apps is one that you see a lot on on Telegram and
Speaker 4:  Willow Remus at the Washington Post Twitter. Great story about researcher
Speaker 4:  who was like, I just went and found a bunch of 'em just right there. They're
Speaker 4:  just sitting there. It's not like a secret. This stuff is known. And so
Speaker 4:  it seems like that disconnect between, it's just sitting right there.
Speaker 4:  The the evidence is that is in front of us. Like all I have to do is look
Speaker 4:  with my eyes and it's right there. And yet you are willingly
Speaker 4:  obfuscating my ability to do anything about it. That is, I feel like
Speaker 4:  the bridge that I've never seen another company cross this way. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well I think there's the, the one example is like kim.com, right? Where he
Speaker 5:  was kind of egregiously ignoring the fact that his,
Speaker 5:  his mega upload site was full of pirated stuff.
Speaker 5:  And then one day they came, the New Zealand authorities came and said, yeah,
Speaker 5:  you can't do that anymore. And now he's being extradited like on his
Speaker 5:  extradition tour every couple of years gets sent to a new country to be
Speaker 5:  extradited, So, I. Think there's like examples of this before.
Speaker 5:  And Pavel, I like, why did this guy come to France?
Speaker 5:  'cause hadn't he said
Speaker 3:  Before, this is the biggest question I have on this. Why land the plane in
Speaker 3:  France? Like
Speaker 5:  Did, he'd said before like, I'm not gonna go to places where they wanna arrest
Speaker 5:  me for this stuff and they hate what I'm doing. France.
Speaker 5:  Like, did he miss the Olympics?
Speaker 3:  Maybe he thought they were just distracted. Like they're coming off the Olympics.
Speaker 3:  He's like, I'm gonna stop and get a baguette and a cigarette, you know, and
Speaker 3:  see how it goes. Two things about kim.com. One, we had the,
Speaker 3:  the best headline in virtual history kim.com mega uploaded to the
Speaker 3:  United States. Oh yeah, it's very good on copyright charges, which people
Speaker 3:  thought was a body shaming joke. And we're like, no, that's the name of the
Speaker 3:  company.
Speaker 3:  I'm sorry I, it was just very funny. That whole sequence of events was very
Speaker 3:  funny. Two copyright law, the only one where we
Speaker 3:  just accept the speech regulation. It is wild to me. You're like, you
Speaker 3:  hired a bunch of Disney movies, jail, the entire international community
Speaker 3:  is gonna put you in jail all together at the same time. Yeah. Everyone's
Speaker 3:  like, huh, that's not a pro. Like Elon Musk is not like justice for kim.com
Speaker 3:  right? Right. And then it's like we're talking about ISIS and, and CS a
Speaker 3:  and censorship. We're, we're having a free competition. And it's like, what
Speaker 3:  are you talking about? So there's just a huge disconnect in how we perceive
Speaker 3:  speech regulations. Even in this case where tub are facing criminal
Speaker 3:  prosecution around the world for, you know, for violating our speech norms.
Speaker 3:  One just happens to be Disney or like Hollywood and that seems to be fine.
Speaker 3:  So that's just weird. Like just on its face, Alex. I agree there's a weirdness
Speaker 3:  there. But the other piece of the puzzle is that even United States where
Speaker 3:  we have strong prohibitions against speech regulations in the First Amendment
Speaker 3:  and things like Section two 30, which insulate
Speaker 3:  platform owners for the speech that happens on our platforms, we make a
Speaker 3:  big exception for criminal behavior on your platform. It's like part of
Speaker 3:  section two 30 is no effect on criminal prosecution.
Speaker 3:  Like it's the heading. It's like you don't get insulated from
Speaker 3:  crimes, right? If the people are doing crimes in your platforms and we
Speaker 3:  can connect it to you, we're going to, you are the crimes that's you
Speaker 3:  fossa and cesta. The, the the, the exception to to two 30
Speaker 3:  that made basically made talking about sex
Speaker 3:  work illegal on these platforms. It was an anti-trafficking law, but it
Speaker 3:  landed with basically sex workers can't do business on platforms anymore.
Speaker 3:  That is a criminal, that's a criminal statute. We're like, you, this is illegal
Speaker 3:  now you'll be responsible for this, you'll be liable for this. And the platforms
Speaker 3:  all took it down and most people are sort of fine with that. There's a
Speaker 3:  large controversy brewing about that that we don't have time to talk about.
Speaker 3:  But that was the tradeoff that was made in that policy here. I think
Speaker 3:  there's just a deep confusion about a
Speaker 3:  French law. No, no one knows, says French law and B like how much do
Speaker 3:  you have to know? When do you have to know it? Is Mark Zuckerberg gonna go
Speaker 3:  to jail? 'cause all of this stuff exists on meta platforms, but
Speaker 3:  they actively try to shut it down. They work with law enforcement. So I was
Speaker 3:  like you in jail if you do slightly less than meta, do you go to
Speaker 3:  jail? If you're Elon Musk, do you go to jail? Right? Like, I, I don't think
Speaker 3:  we understand the gradation. And then on top of that, every country
Speaker 3:  on the planet right now is grappling with how to regulate social media and
Speaker 3:  the bad things that happen on social media. And they're all gonna come to
Speaker 3:  different wildly different answers. And I think all these platform
Speaker 3:  owners are kind of like, okay, this is the tip of the spear. Like this is
Speaker 3:  the beginning of the end, even though
Speaker 3:  it's so out of bounds, even though it's so far few, like no one else is doing
Speaker 3:  a Telegram is doing it this way.
Speaker 5:  Do you guys consider Telegram social media? I always considered it like a
Speaker 5:  chat platform.
Speaker 3:  What is a photo?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I basically wanted to just do that at you. What is a social
Speaker 5:  media
Speaker 4:  Platform? Like it's it's instagramy enough in the
Speaker 4:  way that people use it in some ways that I think, I think it
Speaker 4:  counts. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I'm all the way at like, anything where You can post Yeah.
Speaker 3:  To like, and that post might go to people you don't know is
Speaker 3:  a social media platform. Yeah. Right. And that's a, that's a very
Speaker 3:  loose, so You can, You can find exceptions to that one all over the place.
Speaker 3:  But that's kind of my, my broad definition.
Speaker 5:  Can you post, I I like that. Well
Speaker 3:  Can you post and, and can the person on the other, like, do you have to know
Speaker 3:  the person on the other, other end of it? So like by this definition, like
Speaker 3:  Discord is a social media platform, right? Twitch is a social media platform.
Speaker 3:  Twitch is obviously, it's in my mind obviously a social, YouTube is a social
Speaker 3:  media platform. Yeah. By this definition. Yeah. So I. Think there's, that's
Speaker 3:  a, that's a broad one, but this basic idea of like if you run
Speaker 3:  a platform or, or someone can talk to a lot of strangers, what
Speaker 3:  responsibility do you as a platform owner have? And pretty much the only
Speaker 3:  responsibility we've decided any of these companies truly have
Speaker 3:  is making sure there's not copyright ment. Like is making sure
Speaker 3:  that Hollywood and the music industry are protected. That is pretty much
Speaker 3:  it. Right? And then there's a, there's a litany of, of
Speaker 3:  really bad things that they've decided that they will keep off on their own.
Speaker 3:  And that is it, that's the answer. Like across the world, like that's the
Speaker 3:  baseline answer is copyright infringement and then, and then there's TikTok,
Speaker 3:  which is like, what if we did it anyway?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But like I would just point out that that always is where
Speaker 3:  these arguments break down. If you're okay with
Speaker 3:  sending Kim come to jail for copyright infringement, you,
Speaker 3:  you, you might have to reconsider how you feel about the other stuff or you
Speaker 3:  might have to reconsider feel about copyright infringement. I just think
Speaker 3:  this stuff is so openly horrible that actively
Speaker 3:  thwarting the authorities
Speaker 3:  should probably light you in some hot water.
Speaker 4:  But I think the, the question of who, who is you in that
Speaker 4:  sentence, right? I think is is doing a lot of work in this question because
Speaker 4:  like what what we see most of the time is companies get in
Speaker 4:  trouble, right? Like companies get fined or
Speaker 4:  everybody, like the government sends things to lawyers and,
Speaker 4:  and it's all this sort of entity to entity thing. And So I think the fact
Speaker 4:  that it was like a a a dude who got arrested for it
Speaker 4:  is so unusual. I mean it's like if, if somebody did a bad tweet and
Speaker 4:  Jack Dorsey got arrested, like back in the day, instead of him going
Speaker 4:  to
Speaker 3:  Do, you know how different our lives would've been if Dorsey could have been
Speaker 3:  arrested for bad tweets?
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean. And I think it, it's it's,
Speaker 3:  We live in a utopia.
Speaker 4:  I I think if you, if you like there's that kidding
Speaker 4:  the jails would just be full of Jack Dorsey,
Speaker 3:  But,
Speaker 4:  But I think
Speaker 5:  He'd be on this extradition tour.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. Just send him around the world from jail to jail around the
Speaker 3:  world.
Speaker 4:  And I think if you, if you cast this out and in a certain way that it goes
Speaker 4:  like, you know, we talk about chilling effects of laws all the time. Like
Speaker 4:  yeah, how are you gonna feel right now if you're a CEO of a company that
Speaker 4:  is dealing with any of this, you're like, oh my God. Suddenly not only is
Speaker 4:  my company at risk, but literally I personally could go to jail man. Which
Speaker 4:  I guarantee you is not something most people are thinking about. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  My access to high quality wine and cheese is at risk today.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 3:  We cannot go to France.
Speaker 5:  I was like, who are tho who are those CEOs? It's like Mark Zuckerberg. What?
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk? They're
Speaker 3:  Fine. Well it's, it's a lot of them, right? Like, you know, what
Speaker 4:  If Andy Jassy could go to jail
Speaker 3:  That something
Speaker 4:  Happened on Twich,
Speaker 3:  But well all of like, yes you
Speaker 5:  Should for Amazon Kindle app you
Speaker 3:  Should likes should go to jail for what happens on YouTube is like a
Speaker 3:  pretty weird jump, right? Yeah. At the same time, all of
Speaker 3:  those companies actively cooperate with law enforcement all the time.
Speaker 3:  For sure. In ways, in ways good and bad. I think on our lightning round list
Speaker 3:  is like Mark Zuckerberg sending a letter to Jim Jordan in Congress
Speaker 3:  this week saying, I, we caved to the Biden administration too much. I think
Speaker 3:  that letter is like political theater, but like, that's what I mean by active
Speaker 3:  cooperation. The governor on both sides, he's saying we cooperated with the
Speaker 3:  Biden administration and now he's cooperating with Jim Jordan saying we cooperated
Speaker 3:  with the Biden administration. Like the, the big companies
Speaker 3:  in this country at least are actively engaged with various governments
Speaker 3:  around the world in various ways. And I think that insulates them
Speaker 3:  from Mark Zuckerberg getting arrested in France. Here you just have this
Speaker 3:  other thing. It is so different like architecturally and how the
Speaker 3:  app works user experience wise and you know, the the one to
Speaker 3:  200,000 kind of opportunities you have moderation wise. And that
Speaker 3:  they do literally nothing with the worst content anyone can possibly imagine.
Speaker 3:  And then policy wise in that they have structured it to
Speaker 3:  make it impossible for the authorities to even arrest the people they can
Speaker 3:  see with their own eyes, right? Yeah. And all of that and
Speaker 4:  Kinda is the middle finger to them in the process, right?
Speaker 3:  And you just, you just like stack all that up. You're like, that is a lot
Speaker 3:  of decisions that land you in French jail.
Speaker 5:  I I wonder how it's gonna affect Elon 'cause he'd really been trying to take
Speaker 5:  the same path with x that Davs been doing of just being like
Speaker 5:  the free speech absolution. Is that how you say it?
Speaker 3:  Oh, I, I completely disagree with that. I mean, I understand the argument.
Speaker 3:  That's what he wants us all would think, but
Speaker 5:  He's just a full, he always like, ah, it's, it's all about free speech. And
Speaker 5:  he fundamentally is very different in how he actually does that. 'cause he's
Speaker 5:  always like, oh, you want me to take that down? Done. But
Speaker 3:  Like, yeah, I mean his, his definition of free speech and we can You can
Speaker 3:  go look at the tweet is if
Speaker 3:  people want speech regulations, they should pass laws and that's how democracy
Speaker 3:  is supposed to work. And I will follow with the law. And you're like, you're,
Speaker 3:  that's the weirdest definition of free speech that exists because you're
Speaker 3:  asking for government speech regulations, right.
Speaker 4:  And what they have followed historically has been draconian speech laws
Speaker 4:  in other countries.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right? Like India has draconian speech laws X complies with them, right?
Speaker 3:  Brazil has new draconian speech laws and he doesn't like the government,
Speaker 3:  so he won't, it's like, it's this weird balance of like,
Speaker 3:  actually I'll do whatever I want, but like if I don't want to get
Speaker 3:  into a fight with the government or I like the government there, I'll do
Speaker 3:  what they say, which is just not a position. Right. That is just pure
Speaker 3:  opportunism. Yeah. And I think the noise around
Speaker 3:  dur of getting arrested in France is like useful for him and his
Speaker 3:  ongoing quest to be perceived as a free speech martyr. But I,
Speaker 3:  if you look at his posts lately, You can tell he is like in an
Speaker 3:  intellectual spiral because his position has no center,
Speaker 3:  right? There's no, there's actually no ideological commitment to anything.
Speaker 3:  So if you're like, I would wish to deify the government, but I might get
Speaker 3:  arrested also, some of this stuff is horrible. Also, I'm still like, I'm
Speaker 3:  suing advertisers for antitrust. There's nothing there.
Speaker 3:  Like there, there's literally no center, there's no intellectual center to
Speaker 3:  that position. And You can kind of see him be like, oh crap, this is what
Speaker 3:  free speech might actually mean. I don't wanna, I don't wanna over
Speaker 3:  intellectualize Elon's, you know, ketamine musings or
Speaker 3:  whatever the fuck it is. But it's like You can, You can see it's starting
Speaker 3:  like the pressure welcome to hell is basically what I'm saying. Like yeah,
Speaker 3:  yeah. The internal contradictions of owning a platform like X and all of
Speaker 3:  the demands that are placed on that. Right. I think it's it's starting to
Speaker 3:  wear on 'em a little bit. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, and I think we should probably move on from this, but the,
Speaker 4:  the thing that keeps coming up to me as I, I read these stories and talk
Speaker 4:  to people about this, there's been a ton of good reporting on this by the
Speaker 4:  way. Good, good week for the journalists out there is
Speaker 4:  how much that the, the sort of legal push against
Speaker 4:  the tech industry is still going along the lines of we have to protect the
Speaker 4:  children. Like so much of this is about the CS a m stuff
Speaker 4:  that's happening on Telegram and the laws that have been passed recently.
Speaker 4:  I think it was, I think it was Britain that re that passed a law
Speaker 4:  last year that explicitly allows the executives
Speaker 4:  of tech companies to be held personally responsible for
Speaker 4:  CS a m stuff and child safety stuff on their platform in general if they're
Speaker 4:  told about it and don't do anything about it. Like that's, that's now a law
Speaker 4:  that exists. And, and this idea of we have to protect
Speaker 4:  children being like the most bipartisan thing you'll find anywhere on
Speaker 4:  any line of poli political reasoning.
Speaker 4:  That's how we're getting towards all of this. And it's just, it's just fascinating
Speaker 4:  that that continues to be the thing that is like, the deeper this goes, the
Speaker 4:  more it's about child safety.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's always the argument for censorship or like, that's always
Speaker 5:  like the first line of arguments for censorship is we must think of the children.
Speaker 3:  Well no, it's Hollywood first and then child safety. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's it's be
Speaker 3:  Right. Like it's never, it's never not Mickey Mouse first.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Mickey Mouse and then child safety almost always. Like, there's a great
Speaker 5:  Simpsons episode about that exact thing and then all of the big fights in
Speaker 5:  the the nineties over TV ratings and stuff like that where you
Speaker 5:  had like Clinton Yeah. And then all these Republicans getting together being
Speaker 5:  like, won't anyone think of these babies?
Speaker 4:  Right. You can get anything done if You can convince people. It's about keeping
Speaker 4:  children safe.
Speaker 3:  Right. And I, I agree with you and you know, tipper Gore
Speaker 3:  put the explicit lyrics label on all the CDs and
Speaker 3:  Gore, tipper Gore, very weird. Tipper Gore versus
Speaker 3:  NWA. Just imagine how far we've come.
Speaker 3:  It's super weird. But the the reason that you do
Speaker 3:  that is if You can make the counter argument seem morally
Speaker 3:  indefensible you, you win. Right? Right. And but here I just
Speaker 3:  wanna come back to it is really there. It it, oh yeah. The the, the
Speaker 3:  CS a m is there, it's very bad. And so like sometimes
Speaker 3:  you just have to say it's there and it's bad and you have to do something
Speaker 3:  about it. Right. And I that's, I if you've listened to this show or
Speaker 3:  decoder or list read us for years, like the free speech debate online
Speaker 3:  has raged and we have struggled with it and we've done endless episodes about
Speaker 3:  it, but like, you need an ideological center. Right. That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 3:  and it's real, it's there like ISIS is there, like you don't
Speaker 3:  have to overthink it, you just have to make it go away and hold the people
Speaker 3:  responsible for it accountable. And I think here it's like, well that's an
Speaker 3:  easy line. There are lots of gray areas and lots of much harder lines. That
Speaker 3:  one feels pretty easy to me. Yeah. Alright, we should wrap it up. I promise
Speaker 3:  we'll talk about doing other more fun crimes the next session we'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 3:  I was gonna are these,
Speaker 11:  They're they're less
Speaker 3:  Bummer crimes. I don't they're more fun crimes. I would say that
Speaker 3:  not about whimsical crimes in episode. The, the, the grok
Speaker 3:  AI being so out of control that You can just make like
Speaker 3:  Hillary Clinton do. GTA is legitimately very funny
Speaker 3:  to me. Okay, yeah, fair enough. I'll give you that. Like I
Speaker 3:  have a lot of deep reservations about deep fakes and what is a photo and
Speaker 3:  lies on the internet. And then I'm like, it's also hilarious to have Elon
Speaker 3:  Moscow on an ayahuasca journey at the end of it, have his deep fake character
Speaker 3:  say, I'm starting in soup kitchen, which is a real video I watched today.
Speaker 3:  s like, oh
Speaker 3:  you,
Speaker 3:  it's all very good with an Elon voice too. Yes.
Speaker 3:  All of it's great. Don't look at it, respect the truth.
Speaker 3:  Photography is sast.
Speaker 3:  I laughed. I did law. Let's start with the, the big one, David, you, you
Speaker 3:  said this is the story of segment two. It's Yelp sues Google for antitrust
Speaker 3:  violations.
Speaker 4:  So, okay. Did you guys think that Yelp had already sued
Speaker 4:  Google?
Speaker 3:  Because
Speaker 4:  I definitely thought Yelp sued Google like a long time ago. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yelp at this point is a front for suing Google, right? Is that not
Speaker 3:  how it
Speaker 4:  Basically, it's, I think everyone who works at Yelp is just lawyers now.
Speaker 4:  Yes. But anyway, so very recently, earlier this summer, a couple weeks
Speaker 4:  ago Google lost its antitrust search
Speaker 4:  trial. We're still in the remedies phase and then there will be appeals and
Speaker 4:  then God only knows. But for now it lost. And so Yelp
Speaker 4:  clearly emboldened by that fact filed a suit of its own
Speaker 4:  that basically brings up something that got thrown out
Speaker 4:  of the last case against Google, which I find really interesting. And
Speaker 4:  essentially the argument is that Google prioritizes
Speaker 4:  its own stuff in Google search results and thus
Speaker 4:  Deprioritizes Yelp and TripAdvisor and other companies like it and has
Speaker 4:  thus killed them.
Speaker 4:  This is an argument we've been hearing forever. This is an argument Yelp
Speaker 4:  has been making loudly forever. Literally. I assumed Yelp had already
Speaker 4:  sued Google. Apparently it hadn't. And now
Speaker 4:  what Yelp seems to be thinking like Jeremy Stoppelman, the CEO said
Speaker 4:  in as many words, the wins on antitrust have shifted dramatically. So
Speaker 4:  this company clearly senses this is the moment to finally
Speaker 4:  pick the fight. It's been wanting to pick for many years, which I think is
Speaker 4:  very odd given that that particular fight has been
Speaker 4:  thrown out of court in the same search trial that Google just
Speaker 4:  lost. So I'm confused, but also I think it's fascinating. And
Speaker 4:  yet again, like Google is just up against it, man.
Speaker 4:  Like the, the epic stuff is happening. The search stuff is happening. This
Speaker 4:  is happen. Like it's just, it just keeps happening for Google.
Speaker 3:  There's an ad tech trial. Yeah. I I say that like people know it is Google
Speaker 3:  has yet another antitrust trial coming up over its ad tech stack,
Speaker 3:  which is the money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, wasn't this like Google strategy? They would spend
Speaker 5:  20 years fucking around and then now
Speaker 5:  they're in their find out phase and that's why they have all the lawyers
Speaker 5:  that they pay a lot of money to.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean there's something I I I agree with Jeremy Stoppelman and
Speaker 3:  the winds of antitrust have definitely changed. I actually can point to a
Speaker 3:  very, very odd example of this. Luther Lowe,
Speaker 3:  who is Yelp's old policy person recently left
Speaker 3:  Yelp. He's doing all this stuff. He, I think he's a Y Combinator now, and
Speaker 3:  they did like a meet and greet in dc you know, like a little thing.
Speaker 3:  And JD Vance before he was vice presidential candidate, showed up at the
Speaker 3:  meet and greet with all the startups, talk about how he used to be an ad
Speaker 3:  tech and he thought big tech was censoring everyone. And the woke mob was
Speaker 3:  outta control. And then in the middle of all that nonsense, he was like,
Speaker 3:  I think Lena Khan's doing a good job. Yes. Weird. Like weird, right?
Speaker 3:  Like that's how much the wind of antitrust has changed. He's like, the only
Speaker 3:  person that Biden administration is doing a good job is Lena Khan because
Speaker 3:  we should break up. And, and, and really his point was like, because this
Speaker 3:  woke will, should is outta control. And like maybe that doesn't all put together
Speaker 3:  like that puzzle, you put all the pieces together, you're like, that doesn't
Speaker 3:  look like anything. But he still said it, right? Like that's the, you got
Speaker 3:  the spirit. That's where mindset, the mindset is, is these companies have
Speaker 3:  too much control and we should take that control away from them and do something
Speaker 3:  else. What the something else is. I think all of us are very
Speaker 3:  curious to find out. It's clearly going to be something else. But you look
Speaker 3:  at Google, which is just taking it on the chin lately,
Speaker 3:  right? In the search case, in the epic case, they lost there's, and that
Speaker 3:  the judge in that case has been very loud like, you did it, I'm gonna do
Speaker 3:  something about it. Yeah. And then the ad tech case, which I, you know, I,
Speaker 3:  we don't know what's gonna happen. Every trial is kind of a coin flip, but
Speaker 3:  we're gonna get a documents about Google's money in that case. Like it's
Speaker 3:  gonna, some stuff is gonna come out because it's gonna be the business side
Speaker 3:  of Google talking about the money. Yeah. And I, I think Google's image is
Speaker 3:  very cuddly as though the money just appears from nowhere. And that's not
Speaker 3:  true.
Speaker 4:  And that's also the trial. Let's not forget that Google wrote a, just without
Speaker 4:  any questions, just wrote a check for the maximum possible this, oh my God.
Speaker 3:  God, I forgot
Speaker 4:  To avoid having a jury trial like innocent,
Speaker 4:  you know, innocent until proving guilty. But let's a tough look. Can we just
Speaker 3:  Sit on for one second? This is a real thing. We have a picture of the check
Speaker 3:  on the website. I believe they just wrote a check to the
Speaker 3:  Department of Justice for the maximum, like a cashier's check. Yeah. I believe
Speaker 3:  it's drawn on Wells Fargo and they're like, here's all of the money
Speaker 3:  we could possibly owe you. We would like to settle the case like out of the
Speaker 3:  blue. Yeah, it's incredible
Speaker 4:  Just to not have a jury trial
Speaker 5:  And I mean, it's at Wells Fargo, so it'll take about what, 12 years before
Speaker 5:  it gets cashed
Speaker 3:  The blockchain. I gotta double check solves this Alex,
Speaker 5:  Oh, sorry, it's sorry.
Speaker 3:  Have you heard of Lightning? Okay, so back to Yelp.
Speaker 3:  I think the winds have changed is an opportunity
Speaker 3:  for maybe not to, you know, win like epic, right? Yelp doesn't have
Speaker 3:  a Fortnite in the background to fund all this stuff,
Speaker 3:  but I think maybe to claw out a settlement outta Google Yeah. To, to somehow
Speaker 3:  put some pressure on Google to open up and make this go away to appease the
Speaker 3:  Europeans in some way. Whatever you think of Google's relationship, the internet,
Speaker 3:  it is changing. And I think that as we've said a million times, that means
Speaker 3:  the Internet's gonna change.
Speaker 4:  So you think Yelp wants to be, to Google what, like
Speaker 4:  the Delta emulator folks have been to Apple? Yes. Which is just,
Speaker 4:  just sort of the one in there, just like prying it open slightly
Speaker 4:  and they're in a position of weakness and gonna have to start to make policy
Speaker 4:  changes that are good for you, but also good for everybody. And so Yelp is
Speaker 4:  like, we don't, we don't wanna break up Google, we just, we just think this
Speaker 4:  is a chance to like extract some of what we want from the company because
Speaker 4:  they're gonna decide it's easier to do that.
Speaker 5:  It's kind of necessary for Yelp at this point because
Speaker 5:  they have been struggling for a while, right? Like they, they, they have
Speaker 5:  resorted to basically bullying restaurants and stuff and making sure that
Speaker 5:  they're on their, their platform and everything. Here's
Speaker 3:  What we can do. We can shake down millions of local restaurants or we can
Speaker 3:  get a check from Google, which is Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean it kind of feels like what it's for you, y'all,
Speaker 4:  There's so many companies You can describe with that sentence. Good god.
Speaker 3:  Well, so there was somebody who was on thread say, who posted that? I, I've
Speaker 3:  been more cantankerous lately. Can I, can I just describe my Joker
Speaker 3:  moment broadly? Yes. Because I love that these companies are
Speaker 3:  having these fights. I love that the Internet's gonna be potentially more
Speaker 3:  open. I love that. At least we're in the season of change. All that's great.
Speaker 3:  I do not for one second believe any of this is truly idealistic, right? I
Speaker 3:  think this is a version of capitalism at play where a lot of
Speaker 3:  very self-interested parties are looking out for their own self-interest
Speaker 3:  and they're colliding in weird ways. Great. The reason I say it that way
Speaker 3:  is because a long time ago I used to cover net neutrality like every other
Speaker 3:  day. And the big player in net neutrality was Netflix,
Speaker 3:  if you'll recall. They, Netflix and Reddit
Speaker 3:  were like out in front, like black out the internet, fight for net neutrality.
Speaker 3:  We don't let Comcast throttle us disclosure, Comcast is an investor in this
Speaker 3:  company and boy did they not like my net neutrality coverage,
Speaker 3:  just putting it all out there. And then one year
Speaker 3:  Reed Hastings on stage of the code conference, So I believe Peter Kafka.
Speaker 3:  And Peter said, you, you've been really quiet about net neutrality lately.
Speaker 3:  And Reid Hastings looked at him and said, yeah, we're so big it doesn't matter
Speaker 3:  anymore. And I turned into the joker.
Speaker 4:  That's honest. Wow.
Speaker 3:  And like, fine. Right? Like fine. And
Speaker 3:  So I like the idea that Yelp is a idealistic freedom fighter or even Delta,
Speaker 3:  even though it's a smaller company, I do think they're pressing their regulatory
Speaker 3:  advantage to open up these platforms. Oh yeah. But I don't think that like
Speaker 3:  they're the, they're gonna get theirs, right? And then yeah, all bets are
Speaker 3:  off. And I, I, I think all of this change is like, who's gonna get theirs
Speaker 3:  at the end of this? And so like, we're gonna shake down a bunch of restaurants
Speaker 3:  or shake down Google is kind of the best, in my mind, like the best way to
Speaker 3:  understand it. Like everyone's just trying to get paid whether or not the
Speaker 3:  legal system can shift the money around in a more equitable way. At the end
Speaker 3:  of all this totally remains to be seen. I don't, I truly
Speaker 3:  do not know.
Speaker 4:  In a funny way, what you're arguing for is capitalism working as intended.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That might be everyone
Speaker 4:  Fighting for money is what it should be. What we've landed on is nobody can
Speaker 4:  fight for money because Google took it all. Like Yeah, that's that's true.
Speaker 3:  Capitalism has never been tried. David, I think that's what I'm trying to
Speaker 3:  tell
Speaker 4:  You. Yeah. What if it was just a street fight
Speaker 4:  for money? Let's find out. Is
Speaker 5:  Postmodern capitalism just Google opening its wallet?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You have
Speaker 5:  Like, sorry,
Speaker 3:  You come all the way. That's the horseshoe theory of internet capitalism
Speaker 3:  is Google is the planned economy directors handing money to people.
Speaker 3:  I'm not saying that's not what everybody wants. Okay. So that's Google. We'll
Speaker 3:  see what happens with Yelp and Google. But You can see, like, as we keep
Speaker 3:  saying whatever happens to Google is the internet. Yeah. And You can just
Speaker 3:  see the internet sort of like fracturing around around that already. This
Speaker 3:  other one I think is really interesting. It's a weird ruling.
Speaker 3:  TikTok has to face a lawsuit for recommending the blackout challenge.
Speaker 3:  And this is a very, very sad story. There is a, a 10-year-old who
Speaker 3:  died doing the blackout challenge. The parents sued
Speaker 3:  TikTok. You know, one of those cases where it's like
Speaker 3:  TikTok didn't make the blackout challenge videos. They didn't,
Speaker 3:  they're they're not telling you to do it. Right? The people are
Speaker 3:  seeing the content on the platform, they're taking the action. A
Speaker 3:  horrible, extremely depressing thing happened. And now we're gonna try to
Speaker 3:  hold TikTok liable. And throughout most of this, we
Speaker 3:  are not holding platforms liable for what the recommendation algorithms do,
Speaker 3:  except we just had a Supreme Court ruling which said
Speaker 3:  maybe we should like, more or less, maybe we should. So one of the weirdest
Speaker 3:  things about this case is that it's, it's like a, it's like
Speaker 3:  a puzzle the Supreme Court put itself in, so the,
Speaker 3:  there were content moderation laws passed in Texas and Florida. They went
Speaker 3:  up to the Supreme Court. The Supreme Court baseless said, nah, these are,
Speaker 3:  these are weird. You're just obviously conservative states being mad at Facebook,
Speaker 3:  but you didn't think about what would happen to other platforms, right. Or
Speaker 3:  smaller platforms. You have to go think about this before you, you met this,
Speaker 3:  like go back and figure it out. The one thing the Supreme Court was very
Speaker 3:  clear about was that it is protected first party
Speaker 3:  speech when they curate other people's content.
Speaker 3:  Right? So section two 30 says you Facebook are
Speaker 3:  not responsible for what people post on the platform for. Mostly
Speaker 3:  that's their speech, not your speech. The way you moderate that speech
Speaker 3:  and presented to other people is your speech. So that's
Speaker 3:  protected by the First Amendment. You cannot, the government cannot set content
Speaker 3:  moderation rules because the content moderation itself is speech
Speaker 3:  Right, right. Okay. That feels right. Generally that feels right. That's
Speaker 3:  how you get a marketed different platforms. That's how you end up with a
Speaker 3:  truth social and, and x and then whatever kindergarten
Speaker 3:  subreddit rules you wanna participate in, right? Like that's how you get
Speaker 3:  the whole range of expression. The marketing can sort of decide how much
Speaker 3:  content moderation they want. The court, the third circuit
Speaker 3:  evaluating TikTok case says, well give quote, given the Supreme
Speaker 3:  Court's observation that platforms engage in protected first party speech
Speaker 3:  on the First Amendment. When they curate compilations of other people's content
Speaker 3:  via their expressive algorithms, it follows that doing so
Speaker 3:  amounts to first Sparty speech under section two 30. So the
Speaker 3:  algorithm is your speech. That means you're liable for your speech. So if
Speaker 3:  you recommend a bunch of blackout challenge videos, that's your speech, right?
Speaker 3:  That's a choice you've made. Now you're liable for your speech. And it's
Speaker 3:  calling that curation, which is really fascinating. So this is just like
Speaker 3:  a long, a long chain of reasoning that ends with, okay, some of
Speaker 3:  this belongs to you, so the government can tell you what to do, but it belongs
Speaker 3:  to you. So now other people can get mad at you for it. And that, I don't
Speaker 3:  know how that's gonna shake out. I don't know if TikTok is the right plaintiff
Speaker 3:  for that. They're TikTok after all. We just talked about Save the Children
Speaker 3:  is a theme. Yeah. They, their TikTok versus the United States government
Speaker 3:  versus China. That's all in the mix there. Whether or not TikTok can like
Speaker 3:  mount a challenge to this
Speaker 3:  kind of a huge precedent to say these algorithms are not only your speech
Speaker 3:  and can be protected from laws and can be protected from
Speaker 3:  government interference, but also now other people can sue you for your algorithms
Speaker 3:  do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, that like breaks the internet, right?
Speaker 5:  Like, 'cause it doesn't just break TikTok, which arguably should be broken
Speaker 5:  because I hate its algorithm right now, but it, it breaks, it
Speaker 5:  breaks Facebook, it breaks Google because Google is using an
Speaker 5:  algorithm to res to recommend search results.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You're showing me bad stuff is now legally actionable is whoa,
Speaker 3:  off we go. You know, and like, yeah, fine. But we
Speaker 3:  we're, I don't think we're ready for that world either. So the other side
Speaker 3:  of the coin, the non-Google side of the coin also sort of up for grabs because
Speaker 3:  of what's happening in the legal system, which just, I again, say this to
Speaker 3:  you. I'm trying to have the end of summer here. I, I'm trying to drink a
Speaker 3:  pina colada and the PDFs just keep coming nonstop.
Speaker 4:  Killing
Speaker 3:  Me. All right, let's do one more PDF and then we gotta get outta here. The
Speaker 3:  p the pinot is a Wait, this one is, is a tough one 'cause
Speaker 3:  it's not actually the law yet. And I actually don't know if Gavin Newsom's
Speaker 3:  gonna sign this bill, but the California State Assembly passed an AI safety
Speaker 3:  bill. What's going on in here, David?
Speaker 4:  So it's called the Safe and Secure Innovation for Frontier Artificial
Speaker 4:  Intelligence Models Act, which just rolls off the tongue.
Speaker 3:  Is that spell anything or
Speaker 4:  Is that It's S-S-I-F-A-I-M-A. Si.
Speaker 4:  Noma. No. All good laws are acronyms.
Speaker 4:  Everyone needs to remember this. If your law is not a acronym, it's not a
Speaker 4:  good law. It's just, it's so important to me.
Speaker 3:  Just get the ai Ask Chad G to make a name, man. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Right. Can you like the, the insane things people have done.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 5:  Think the people writing this bill weren't fans of ai, though. That's true.
Speaker 5:  They, they weren't gonna ask Chad GT do it this
Speaker 4:  Law. They should have found a way to make it spell out artificial with all
Speaker 4:  the letters and it would've been amazing. But a last, it is mostly
Speaker 4:  just called SB 10 47. It's an AI
Speaker 4:  safety bill that I would say concerns itself as we've been talking
Speaker 4:  about in part with who is responsible for bad things that happen
Speaker 4:  downstream of AI models. and it changes
Speaker 4:  the way that companies need to test and train these things. It changes the
Speaker 4:  way that they need to talk to the government. Like it's, it's kind of a
Speaker 4:  sweeping like here's how we want to oversee and think
Speaker 4:  about AI models. There's been a lot of backing
Speaker 4:  and forthing open AI kind of came out against it. Anthropic
Speaker 4:  was like, we love it. Let's change some stuff. There have been
Speaker 4:  a bunch of politicians who are against it, a bunch of politicians who are
Speaker 4:  for it. I agree. It seems very debatable
Speaker 4:  whether Gavin Newsom will sign this thing as it currently stands,
Speaker 4:  but it, it, it does still feel like a moment that it passed
Speaker 4:  out of the assembly the way that it has.
Speaker 5:  If he signs it. Does that just mean like Google open ai, a lot of these companies
Speaker 5:  relocate like,
Speaker 3:  Well, California's still a huge market. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Well that, but also one of the things a lot of the companies have said
Speaker 4:  essentially is why are you making a law
Speaker 4:  to make us do what we've already promised to do? Which is essentially make
Speaker 4:  sure our AI is not going to destroy the world. And I would argue that's a
Speaker 4:  very funny line of reasoning to be like we said we're gonna be cool. Why
Speaker 4:  are you gonna make me be cool? Is, is is an odd stance.
Speaker 4:  But my sense is, and again, all of this could change,
Speaker 4:  especially as the, the law, you know, continues to change and depending on
Speaker 4:  how it gets implemented is that a lot of these companies are gonna not like
Speaker 4:  it, but we'll figure out a way to play along. I don't think this is the sort
Speaker 4:  of thing that is like gonna run anybody out of California. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Philanthropic sent a letter basically supporting it.
Speaker 3:  And to your point, they're like, yeah, but then you read the letter and
Speaker 3:  you're like, we should definitely do something. Here's just a line from Philanthropics
Speaker 3:  letter. We believe SB 10 47, particularly after recent amendments,
Speaker 3:  likely presents a feasible compliance burden for companies like ours
Speaker 3:  in light of the importance of averting catastrophic misuse.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Cool. Yeah. There's a real chance we might destroy the world.
Speaker 3:  So let's do a feasible compliance burden.
Speaker 3:  Whoops. Yeah. I don't know how this plays, you know, the Biden had the AI
Speaker 3:  order that just came out. A bunch of companies said they were gonna join
Speaker 3:  the, the AI model board that make sure their safety testing
Speaker 3:  and releases results. This one feels like
Speaker 3:  in particular, Gavin Newsom has to make a decision and then he that
Speaker 3:  will decide whether a bunch of similar
Speaker 3:  state laws get passed all around the country. 'cause once California does
Speaker 3:  it, it's, it's like fine, like York will do it tomorrow. Right? Right. Because
Speaker 3:  now you're not making him do anything. Like, you're just like off to the
Speaker 3:  races. And then the, and then Alex, your point in the question is like, whether
Speaker 3:  Texas does or doesn't do it, and it doesn't matter because all the researchers
Speaker 3:  are in California anyway, right? Like, and you have to sell to the California
Speaker 3:  market and then there you go. So I, I'm very
Speaker 3:  confused about this one in the sense that what you really need is a federal
Speaker 3:  law. And that doesn't seem likely. And it's also
Speaker 3:  election season and who knows what's gonna happen. But it also seems
Speaker 3:  like Newsom kind of doesn't wanna sign it. Like he hasn't said anything.
Speaker 3:  Like usually when you're the governor of the big state with the
Speaker 3:  first in the nation AI safety bill, you're, you're like pounding the pavement.
Speaker 3:  And here he, he literally has not said anything to anyone Well,
Speaker 5:  Like affects, who gives him money for his presidential
Speaker 5:  campaign in four years.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, yeah, it's true.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I also think like we're in a moment right now where
Speaker 4:  all of the money on planet Earth is being thrown at ai
Speaker 4:  and there are a lot of very powerful, very rich people
Speaker 4:  wants there to be rules until there are rules.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back in the break. I disclosed to David
Speaker 3:  what company I was thinking of and Liam immediately said he bought something
Speaker 3:  and now David is writing profile. It's happening, it's
Speaker 4:  Gonna happen. But
Speaker 3:  I'm I'm not telling you who, it's just immediate. It was incredible. If You
Speaker 3:  can guess, if you send us an email and you guess maybe something that'll
Speaker 3:  happen to you,
Speaker 4:  We'll ship you. Whatever Liam bought from me.
Speaker 19:  No.
Speaker 3:  All right. Okay. We're doing it this way. We're doing true lightning round
Speaker 3:  unsponsored. No one can tell us what to do because they haven't paid us any
Speaker 3:  money. I'm, what I'm suggesting here is you could pay us money. I dunno how
Speaker 3:  that works and I probably still won't do it. You say, but you know,
Speaker 3:  live a life of possibility. True.
Speaker 4:  Like I have one Vergecast listener slash startup executive
Speaker 4:  who I will not name who asked me very seriously recently,
Speaker 4:  if we actually want people to sponsor the lightning round or if we enjoy
Speaker 4:  this bit so much that we actually don't want people. And I was like, no.
Speaker 4:  To be very clear, I like money more than I like bits. We, we will take.
Speaker 4:  Please sponsor the lightning round.
Speaker 3:  Can I do an aside about the Influencer Con? I've been thinking a lot about
Speaker 3:  journals, whereas influencers are the whole thing. Here's the problem that
Speaker 3:  we have. When you give other people money,
Speaker 3:  they do what you say. People come to our sales team and they're like, will
Speaker 3:  they do what we say? And we're kinda like, no, no, just
Speaker 3:  like flat. No. There's a real problem with journalism as a whole right now,
Speaker 3:  fighting an uphill fight, but there's always a chance, huh?
Speaker 4:  Hmm. I do think our enthusiasm for a sponsor of the lightning round
Speaker 4:  might make it the greatest ROI in the history of the version.
Speaker 4:  Like we will talk about whoever that sponsor is forever.
Speaker 4:  Unless they suck, in which case we will see tattoo.
Speaker 3:  See, you never know. Go Life's the game of chance. Roll the dice.
Speaker 3:  People sponsor the lightning round. All right, true. Lightning round. I'm
Speaker 3:  gonna read a headline. We're all gonna react to it. We're gonna move on.
Speaker 3:  Right? Good. This is the idea. Yeah. Okay, here we go. Google
Speaker 3:  Gemini will let you create AI generated people. again,
Speaker 4:  Remember the diverse Nazis? No. Yeah. Those are the days we're back.
Speaker 4:  Google says they fixed it.
Speaker 3:  I would say you guys only white Nazis. Now you but you, you all talked at
Speaker 3:  length about what is a photo last week with Reimagine the Pixel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I had a bit of a freak out that I still am getting a lot of notes from
Speaker 4:  people about and I feel very good about as time goes on. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I feel, I feel by the way, yes, we're gonna defend the sanctity of photography
Speaker 3:  here in The Verge.
Speaker 3:  I feel nothing about this.
Speaker 3:  My only question is, it feels like Google's attitude about this has slightly
Speaker 3:  shifted, right? Like they diverse Nazis were a thing and they,
Speaker 3:  they killed it because now they're like, actually they killed it because
Speaker 3:  a bunch of people were like, we should be able to make diverse Nazis were
Speaker 3:  weird
Speaker 3:  and they took it down. 'cause like we don't want, I we, I don't dunno how
Speaker 3:  Gemini is gonna work now, but reimagine, they're just like, yeah, let it
Speaker 3:  ride. Right? Like it's more or less their attitude towards it. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Well, well I just, it feels like something has shifted there. I'm not sure
Speaker 3:  what with Google,
Speaker 4:  Was it six months ago that the Gemini thing first happened? Yeah, it was
Speaker 4:  like earlier this year. Wild. How much this has shifted
Speaker 4:  in six months. Because I totally agree with
Speaker 3:  You. There's more safety rules there. Like Reimagine is not supposed to add
Speaker 3:  a bunch of drugs to like, I don't think that's what they want, but you can't
Speaker 4:  Add people at all
Speaker 3:  And you can't add people. It, it won't touch people. We don't know how this
Speaker 3:  one's gonna work. So there's some shift I'm saying is there's a shift. It's
Speaker 3:  not the next thing we're gonna talk about, which is just a free for all.
Speaker 3:  But there's some little shift inside of Google that says, okay, the market
Speaker 3:  is willing to accept a little bit more crazy. And like here we are seeing
Speaker 3:  free for all X AI's new gr image generator floods X with
Speaker 3:  controversial AI fix. That is a very soft headline
Speaker 4:  Again. Wait, that's okay. Here little, little quick.
Speaker 3:  That's we're almost like a little too nice.
Speaker 4:  No. Little, little quick. How the internet works thing. That's actually the
Speaker 4:  SEO optimized headline that goes to Google. Can I read you the headline that's
Speaker 4:  on our website? Ah,
Speaker 3:  This makes more sense. Yes.
Speaker 4:  X's new AI image generator will make anything from Taylor Swift and Lingerie
Speaker 4:  to Kamala Harris with a gun. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  We should, I don't know. That's what Google wants. Kamala Harris with a gun
Speaker 3:  is all anybody's searching nowadays. So let alone the other thing,
Speaker 3:  it's bananas like again, I've watched
Speaker 3:  hilarious videos of like Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton in an arm
Speaker 3:  standoff on X and it and the underlying technology is called
Speaker 3:  Flux, which is an open source AI system. So even if X added the controls,
Speaker 3:  they've now sort of like opened everyone's eyes to flux,
Speaker 3:  which is open source. You can just do whatever you want with.
Speaker 4:  And Flux is bio icon's. Very good.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. You can just go watch the thing. It's just very funny that
Speaker 3:  grok like Elon Musk, Elon Musk, I mean he wants to be a famous person,
Speaker 3:  right? He released his own completely out of control deepfake
Speaker 3:  tool on his own platform and the number of DeepFakes of him
Speaker 3:  are out of control.
Speaker 4:  What was the one you were saying you were seeing before?
Speaker 3:  It's Elon Musk. It's a long video. Okay. Where Elon Musk
Speaker 3:  narrates his ayahuasca journey. There's a, there's like a
Speaker 3:  nightmare dream sequence in the middle of it. And at the end of it
Speaker 3:  he commits to do like giving away free food to everyone like soup kitchens.
Speaker 3:  And also says he's gonna build a public transport system and it is per is
Speaker 3:  perfect.
Speaker 3:  Like it is a perfect Elon Musk troll.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's amazing.
Speaker 3:  Robot Elon Musk ways I deep fakes should be illegal. Like
Speaker 3:  speaking of laws that are coming, like a lot of people agree that deep fakes
Speaker 3:  should be legal, especially non-consensual pornography, deep fakes. This
Speaker 3:  is gonna be a weird fight. It's gonna be a weird fight. A bunch of Scarlet
Speaker 3:  Johansen does not want her voice being used by open ai, right? Like she's
Speaker 3:  filed that complaint. I don't know. I I do not know how these are gonna go
Speaker 3:  because it feels like we just let the cat out of the bag talk about feasible
Speaker 3:  compliance. Here we go. Like we have a picture of Mickey Mouse smoking a
Speaker 3:  cigarette on The Verge dot com. It's so good.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Next one. Smart home company Brilliant has found a buyer. David, did you
Speaker 3:  ever have a brilliant
Speaker 4:  I did briefly. Wow. I knew it. I had, I had one of the earliest,
Speaker 4:  earliest ones I met with their founders, like before they even launched the
Speaker 4:  product and they gave me a, a prototype of one. I put it in my wall and
Speaker 4:  then I had a, I had a balcony at my apartment and it turned on the
Speaker 4:  balcony light permanently. It just, it wouldn't turn it off.
Speaker 4:  Just, and that was, that was my experience with the first brilliant, brilliant
Speaker 4:  stuff. Actually got very good there. They made a most
Speaker 4:  of their business like going into apartment buildings and stuff, but just
Speaker 4:  never really made it work.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is the what if you had an iPod touching your wall that controlled
Speaker 3:  all your smart home stuff, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly. And,
Speaker 3:  And Jen Tooey, our brilliant smart home reviewer, reported they were
Speaker 3:  going outta business, which they kind of denied and then they went outta
Speaker 3:  business. But rescued, rescued by those white Knights of American
Speaker 3:  capitalism, private equity,
Speaker 4:  Our people, we love them. The company's now called Rescued Us. The company
Speaker 4:  is now called Brilliant NextGen. Good. Which is just brutal.
Speaker 4:  and it seems like what we know so far is that people who
Speaker 4:  had brilliant stuff, their stuff is going to continue to work.
Speaker 4:  What happens after that? I don't know the,
Speaker 4:  the new leadership did say they're gonna stop selling direct to
Speaker 4:  consumer stuff anywhere other than their website, which I think is a pretty
Speaker 4:  strong signal that they are going further and further
Speaker 4:  into the like selling into new construction business. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Which makes a certain amount of sense. A lot of these companies, like Amazon
Speaker 4:  has focused a lot on that with Alexa stuff. There's been this big race to
Speaker 4:  be this sort of default choice for professional builders.
Speaker 3:  I know that when I was still in the rental market, what I looked for in an
Speaker 3:  apartment was a 6-year-old unsupported iPod touch built right into the wall.
Speaker 4:  It's the dream
Speaker 3:  So I was like same get these, get these non iPod touch apartments outta
Speaker 3:  my face.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I think it's, this company has always been, I would say more
Speaker 4:  sort of B2B than like a thing a regular person would consider buying. Like
Speaker 4:  you go to Home Depot and you're gonna buy a Lutron, not this, right? Like
Speaker 4:  I think that's pretty clear.
Speaker 4:  But it'll be interesting to see if they can get it righted or
Speaker 4:  if this just becomes kind of a slow death for a smart home company.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I feel like if you have one of these in your wall, you're, you're run at
Speaker 3:  the clock on that cloud service continuing to work. I kind
Speaker 4:  Of think that's right.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. All right. ESPN Where to Watch feature
Speaker 3:  fines were to stream sporting events. They basically made TV guide but for
Speaker 3:  streaming
Speaker 4:  That has ever happened to me in my entire house. This is pretty funny. I
Speaker 4:  spent like a lot of yesterday trying to find the catch in this and I think
Speaker 4:  there's like a big galaxy brain strategy, but also this is just like a good
Speaker 4:  nice thing for the internet. ESPN released a thing that just gives you a
Speaker 4:  list of all the games that are being played, which is like a thing that every
Speaker 4:  sports app has, right? Except for Apple Sports, which doesn't, but You
Speaker 4:  can go and You can see where all the games are, what the score is, whatever.
Speaker 4:  And now it just has a TV guide thing where You can, it'll say it's playing
Speaker 4:  on MLB TV or it's playing on TNT or this MLS game is on
Speaker 4:  Apple TV plus like, it just tells you where to stream sports, which
Speaker 4:  seems like it a thing that should not be complicated or need to exist or
Speaker 4:  a
Speaker 3:  Picture of a pirate ship and a Reddit logo Anywhere in this s
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's just one that says parentheses. It's a Russian website against
Speaker 3:  Like half of these
Speaker 3:  You'll be extradited. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  But I like ESPN did this whole big media day on
Speaker 4:  Wednesday this week and essentially
Speaker 4:  made clear that it is making this pivot from being a cable channel to like
Speaker 4:  a sports lifestyle brand. That was how Sarah Fisher and Axios
Speaker 4:  explained it and I think that was really right. They're about to launch a
Speaker 4:  streaming service that shows you all the ESPN stuff like ESPN, the cable
Speaker 4:  channel's gonna be a streaming service. They're part of venue sports. ESPN's
Speaker 4:  whole thing is they're just like, we want you to come to ESPN when you wanna
Speaker 4:  watch sports, even if you go somewhere else because they have the rights.
Speaker 4:  If you open the ES ESPN app first we win. Right? 'cause that's how you bet.
Speaker 4:  That's how you get into fantasy all this stuff. And so ESPN is like deep
Speaker 4:  in the weeds of like, how do we become a destination for
Speaker 4:  all things sports all the time? And this is both a very good idea in
Speaker 4:  that vein and also just like a useful page that I'm going to load every single
Speaker 4:  day for the rest of my life.
Speaker 5:  I have a question. Question. Was this originally supposed to be a venue launch
Speaker 5:  party or something? Because wasn't venue like supposed to launch around?
Speaker 5:  That's around now. Really good point. Before FUBU killed it, it was
Speaker 3:  Fu they slowed it down. They sued him another them another antitrust lawsuit
Speaker 3:  in the background of Yeah, the entire internet economy may maybe, but
Speaker 3:  venue was supposed to have everything in it. Venues the the opposite strategy.
Speaker 3:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Right, right. But
Speaker 3:  Then really ESPN is trying to send you to every other service and venue is
Speaker 3:  like, we're gonna buy everything and fu Bo's dead. And Fuo was like, yeah
Speaker 3:  but ESPN, hold on a minute.
Speaker 5:  ESPN was gonna be a part of this. So then you know, you'd go and you'd look
Speaker 5:  and be like, oh, what should I watch? Oh, it's all on venue. I sure should
Speaker 5:  subscribe to venue. It's a TV
Speaker 3:  Guide. But the answer is one channel. Just
Speaker 5:  Just one channel every time.
Speaker 3:  That's, I could see it,
Speaker 4:  But you know what's so telling about the sports industry is it wouldn't have
Speaker 4:  been that way. The thing that is ostensibly the streaming service for all
Speaker 4:  the sports is not actually the streaming service for all the sports. This
Speaker 4:  is why it's so terrible. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be like 60% I think.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which is fine. And I think venue, if it eventually launches will be
Speaker 4:  a useful thing that I'm sure I will give too much money to. But like the
Speaker 4:  fact that You can go on here and it will tell you the game is on Prime
Speaker 4:  video or that the game is on Apple TV plus is like a genuine
Speaker 4:  user interface victory. And I also think it makes a lot of
Speaker 4:  sense for ESPN as like a big,
Speaker 3:  How low our standards have fallen. This is what I mean. TV guide,
Speaker 3:  literally it's TV guide even looks like TV guide. We're moving on David.
Speaker 3:  I feel like that you're gonna try to convince some people to buy this thing
Speaker 3:  and I'm telling you already immediately saying you wanna see it.
Speaker 4:  I have it. It's right here. You have it. The claw, this thing is called the
Speaker 4:  clawed note pin. Yeah. And it's, we're just in this
Speaker 4:  phase of everybody launching little tiny voice recorders that
Speaker 4:  then use chat GPT to summarize whatever they hear. Like
Speaker 4:  they all have bigger ideas, but that's essentially what it is. This one
Speaker 4:  is just cool 'cause it's like a little, it's a little guy, it's a wearable.
Speaker 4:  It comes with a lanyard and a clip
Speaker 4:  and something else. Oh, and a thing You can wear on your wrist. So the idea
Speaker 4:  is like, it's a, it's a wearable. You, you tap it, you talk to it, it
Speaker 4:  summarizes your notes. Is that anything?
Speaker 4:  I don't know.
Speaker 4:  But this is like, this is the thing, right? Like Microsoft Recall is a version
Speaker 4:  of this, the Limitless thing which we've talked about is a version of this.
Speaker 4:  This idea of like, how do we make it easy for you to input all of
Speaker 4:  your stuff into an AI system and then it will make something out of that
Speaker 4:  for you is like a, the big new
Speaker 4:  product question for a lot of these companies. I don't know if any of it
Speaker 4:  amounts to anything. I have just been sitting here like yelling thoughts
Speaker 4:  into this thing all day and it just keeps transcribing them being like, you
Speaker 4:  need to remember that your meeting is in an hour. I'm like, is this useful?
Speaker 4:  Like what did we get from this?
Speaker 3:  This is like, what were those journals of the pens and the the, the Notebooks
Speaker 3:  had Oh, the live Scribe Dots. Yeah. And I wanted to be a live
Speaker 3:  a live scribe person. So bad. Same. So bad. And now it's a little
Speaker 3:  chat PT AI bubble device. I look forward to your review. I
Speaker 3:  encourage everyone to wait for the inevitable in the review.
Speaker 4:  The good news is this is a thing AI can actually do, which
Speaker 4:  like summarize a bunch like voice to text to
Speaker 4:  summarization. AI is good at all of those steps, unlike
Speaker 4:  so many other things. Like I watched a very funny video of somebody reviewing
Speaker 4:  the, the Brilliant Frame ar gla ai glasses. Oh my gosh. And I
Speaker 4:  got such flashbacks to doing the review of the humane AI pin where you're
Speaker 4:  just sitting there asking it really basic questions. He was sitting there
Speaker 4:  holding up like a, I forget what it was, a drink of some
Speaker 4:  kind, I think. and it kept being like, that's a bag of potato chips. And
Speaker 4:  he's like, no, it's not. And it's just like, oh yeah, this is where AI is.
Speaker 4:  But summarizing texts on point. All right,
Speaker 3:  I look again. Well I look forward to your review And. if you don't have the
Speaker 3:  chart of wearable bullshit in the review, here's what I'm saying. The
Speaker 3:  maker of the B Palmer has a new cheaper e-reader.
Speaker 5:  Don't get it.
Speaker 3:  You don't get it. Oh wait, you're saying not to get it.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so it's $150. It's the books six Go and
Speaker 5:  it's their new small low budget cheap e-reader that also runs
Speaker 5:  Android. So you think, oh, these are all good things. Oh, it's cheaper than
Speaker 5:  the book's Palmer. But I get a wider screen. That sounds great. Then you
Speaker 5:  look at how much Ram it has and then you look at how much Ram the books
Speaker 5:  Palmer has. Oh my
Speaker 4:  God. It's only two gigs of Ram,
Speaker 5:  Only two gigs of Ram. Don't, don't, you're right. Like I've had a couple
Speaker 5:  of books products where they, where they skimp on the ram and you feel
Speaker 5:  it. It's real, real rough. Yeah. So,
Speaker 4:  And that's the sort of thing that like on a Kindle, you don't really have
Speaker 4:  to worry about Ram 'cause it's kind of only doing one thing. Yeah. But like
Speaker 4:  you're gonna accidentally have three apps open at the same time on this thing
Speaker 4:  and it is just going to set itself on fire.
Speaker 5:  Yep. So don't don't Oh man. Like resist the urge. I know
Speaker 5:  books put more ram in. Like it's not that you're not Apple, it's cheap.
Speaker 3:  I mean at this point we are just directly controlling books this business.
Speaker 3:  Right.
Speaker 5:  I'm trying, I'm trying.
Speaker 3:  We'll tell you what to do. All right. Speaking of Ram,
Speaker 3:  that makes no sense. Sure. The Dyson Air Wrap
Speaker 3:  ID is a new smarter hair curler, So, I. Put this on here because one is,
Speaker 3:  Alex has mentioned to us many, many times the Dyson Supersonic, that's
Speaker 3:  the hair dryer and the air wrap. Legitimate gadgets. Like insane
Speaker 3:  gadgets in the classic Dyson mold of, we made a fan
Speaker 3:  what can have a fan. And remember when they got all the way to the car and
Speaker 3:  they're like, no fan. You
Speaker 5:  Know, they stopped. They stopped fans. They, they got to, they, they're do
Speaker 5:  a like a hair serum now. Ooh. And I was like, where is the fan in this hair
Speaker 5:  serum? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I'm calling it right now. Dyson. You're way out your lane. Yeah. It's fans
Speaker 3:  only.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  I really wanted the car to have a fan. Anyway, tell me about it.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so this is the new air wrap. They've released a couple of different
Speaker 5:  additions at this point. This one's got a couple of different
Speaker 5:  extensions. One that's like just is gonna suck your hair slightly
Speaker 5:  differently. I probably should explain what an air rep does after saying
Speaker 5:  that. It sucks
Speaker 4:  Your hair. I don't understand.
Speaker 5:  The air basically sucks your hair. You go
Speaker 3:  In one of two directions,
Speaker 5:  It sucks your hair in one of two directions and, and then you like You
Speaker 5:  can put hot air on it or cold air on it. Yeah. And it's magic
Speaker 5:  And. if you have ever tried to curl your hair or have thought about it,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's horrible. And, and this makes it easier. It's for those of us
Speaker 5:  who don't wanna worry about having hot metal our faces.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So I'm gonna ask you this question about this one. Yeah. The addition
Speaker 3:  to this one is that it has Bluetooth, it's
Speaker 5:  Got an app.
Speaker 3:  What, what
Speaker 5:  The, the, I think the app could probably be
Speaker 5:  like, you could just not get this and turn on use YouTube or
Speaker 5:  TikTok. I would give you the same thing, but yeah, it's supposed
Speaker 5:  to kind of guide you through Sure. Doing the hair and making sure you're
Speaker 5:  holding it for long enough. 'cause a lot of people would just do it once
Speaker 5:  and be like, it looks good. Is
Speaker 3:  This like the smart oven theory where you like you have a QR code of a
Speaker 3:  hairstyle and then it just like does the settings for you? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're, yeah, it kinda walks you through it. I haven't gotten to play with
Speaker 5:  this app obviously, but that's kind of the idea. It's just supposed to help
Speaker 5:  you make things a little easier through some Bluetooth in,
Speaker 5:  so yeah. More gadget. But honestly the, the
Speaker 5:  extensions for it are the cool part. They're doing like one for curly hair
Speaker 5:  and one for straighter hair. So curly hair people get like more diffusers
Speaker 5:  and stuff, which is very exciting.
Speaker 4:  And it's just as stupidly expensive as the air wrap Yeah. Was
Speaker 5:  Already so, and it's worth it. So
Speaker 4:  Whatever. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Somebody in your life is gonna ask for one and get it bought.
Speaker 3:  I bought one for Becky because Alex has been so high on these things for
Speaker 3:  so long and for in the spirit of no one knows how to use it.
Speaker 3:  I bought without the Bluetooth, the Bluetooth one was that yet also, also
Speaker 3:  if I bought Becky a Bluetooth device, she'd be like, no, no thank you. I'm
Speaker 3:  never, I'm never using this functionality. But for like a week, both Becky
Speaker 3:  and Max looked like, like full Texas cheerleaders. Like it's
Speaker 5:  Great. Just big hair Awesome. Every day. That's awesome. Yeah. And then that's
Speaker 5:  how you know somebody gets one. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And then the the weird thing is our air purifiers like light up every time
Speaker 3:  we use it. And someone told me it's because of the hot air, like the hair
Speaker 3:  products you use, it like lights up the air purifiers.
Speaker 5:  That makes sense. Your hairspray Yeah. Is you're not, don't breathe that
Speaker 5:  stuff. I mean it smells great, but don't huff it.
Speaker 3:  Here's what I'm saying. Dyson, find more things to put fans in. That's
Speaker 3:  your lane. And I, I fully support it.
Speaker 3:  Get to a car, get to a hovercraft car. This is what I'm, I'm
Speaker 3:  trying to, this is why your first car failed. It wasn't floating on a bed
Speaker 3:  of perfectly produced air. The next car, they
Speaker 5:  Got this, I believe in them. Do you think they were such great hair?
Speaker 3:  Do you think they were like Electric Motors are kind of like fans, right?
Speaker 3:  Yes. They're fans without blades and they're like, we'll do Electric Motors
Speaker 3:  at scale. Yes. I'm Di James Dyson. Sir James Dyson.
Speaker 3:  Come on the show. I have only one question for you. It's not worth a full
Speaker 3:  decoder. Did you think electric Cars were fans without Blades? Yes or no
Speaker 3:  sir.
Speaker 5:  Just a yes or no.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna get James Dyson on the show and we're gonna play. Can you put
Speaker 4:  a fan in that?
Speaker 3:  We're gonna do that for
Speaker 4:  One full hour of the first cast and it's gonna be incredible. And I honestly
Speaker 4:  believe he would say yes to doing that with us
Speaker 3:  On the first cast. Most things. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is my new goal. Can you put a fan in that with James Dyson
Speaker 3:  Gauntlet Throne?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 3:  Snapchat finally launched an iPad app.
Speaker 5:  Good,
Speaker 3:  Right? Huh? Little
Speaker 5:  Like the 13 year olds, they're like, they can use their
Speaker 5:  iPads now.
Speaker 3:  That's great. I feel like this belongs in our Is this anything Hall of Fame?
Speaker 4:  Snapchat for
Speaker 3:  IPad? Yeah. Right. It's like, it's a bunch of weird i AI gadgets and it's
Speaker 3:  like Snapchat, iPad. Like is this anything
Speaker 3:  what people is Instagram?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And they're never gonna get it
Speaker 4:  And Snap is like, it, it, it clearly wants you to use
Speaker 4:  it to like watch Snap originals and stories and stuff.
Speaker 4:  I don't think this is gonna be like a super kick ass messaging
Speaker 4:  system. Snapchat for the iPad. Not so sure.
Speaker 3:  All right. It's for the speaking of Instagram. Another classic all time headline
Speaker 3:  on The Verge dot com. Instagram adds what? photos have always needed
Speaker 3:  words.
Speaker 3:  It's good. I mean, yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  Good. I look get a lot of photos and think what if it just had a letter on
Speaker 5:  it?
Speaker 3:  Basically You can now put text in the ins on photos in the Instagram editor,
Speaker 3:  which is fine. 'cause you could already do that. And obviously real,
Speaker 4:  I was gonna say everyone has figured out how to do this anyway,
Speaker 3:  But the, the fact that Instagram is slowly becoming Canva because Instagram
Speaker 3:  is slowly becoming Craigslist very real.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's okay. So I. The reason I put this in here is I was gonna ask,
Speaker 4:  are we headed towards a world in which threads and Instagram
Speaker 4:  are just the same thing? Instagram is gonna get texty and Threads is
Speaker 4:  gonna get Photo Z and they're just gonna be the same. But what you're saying
Speaker 4:  is Threads is gonna become Instagram because Instagram is becoming Craigslist.
Speaker 5:  No threads isn't gonna become Instagram. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think they know that the point of threads is extremely leading questions
Speaker 3:  about nothing and they're just gonna keep leaning right into I I
Speaker 3:  come up with lists of questions to ask threads like every day. That's like,
Speaker 3:  I was walking down the street and I saw a guy wearing headphones. Has anyone
Speaker 3:  seen one of these before? It's like
Speaker 3:  all day long. You can, like I could be the most popular
Speaker 3:  person on threads tomorrow. You can just do it all day long. You
Speaker 3:  just like look at things like, has anyone ever seen this before? I saw one
Speaker 3:  today. Today person posted. They were on an airplane and you know, sometimes
Speaker 3:  their airplane you're boarding and there's condensation coming off the plane
Speaker 3:  and I don't know who they were just like, I've never seen this on a plane
Speaker 3:  before and I fly all the time. My plane
Speaker 4:  Is wet
Speaker 3:  In all of just like millions of replies of people being like, you've never
Speaker 3:  been on a plane before. Wow.
Speaker 5:  That's great. Yeah, a lot of people are asking, she was, she was asking if
Speaker 5:  she was gonna die and people were like, no, no.
Speaker 3:  But I'm just telling you the fact that like millions of people will fall
Speaker 3:  for the worst engagement bait on threads means we've learned nothing.
Speaker 3:  You know how like we just did the, like you're here because you, you think
Speaker 3:  people are smarter than Photoshop, you know, and everyone's like, we are,
Speaker 3:  you know this. I'm like, I wanna show you this picture of condensation on
Speaker 3:  a plane and millions of people bringing, we know nothing, one of our biggest
Speaker 3:  tech companies algorithms to its knees over the dumbest
Speaker 3:  engagement bait in the world.
Speaker 4:  It is fun just as like an intellectual exercise to look around and just think
Speaker 4:  like, what engagement bait question could I ask
Speaker 3:  You can just post a picture of anything. Be like, what is
Speaker 4:  This? Yeah, yeah. Like my water has bubbles in it. How did that happen?
Speaker 3:  This is what we're doing from now on. Just, I'm just get ready.
Speaker 3:  It's coming. Anyway, my my point is I think they know they
Speaker 3:  want that thing, they want a bunch of calm tweets during NBA games, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like you, that's not actually like a visual communication moment, but
Speaker 3:  it's a place for people to engage and they just want the engagement and they
Speaker 3:  can put the ads there. Whether or not that's photos or not, I think they're
Speaker 3:  happy with what they've got. I'm just saying Instagram is becoming a marketing
Speaker 3:  platform. It already was a marketing platform and increasingly what they're
Speaker 3:  marketing is small business services. So being able to just put the picture
Speaker 3:  on your yoga studio with the text. It's like yoga class. Like they're just
Speaker 3:  gonna do it. And that I think that they're, that's why I was like, it's Canva.
Speaker 3:  'cause that's what Canva does for people. Great. Cool. Soon it will just
Speaker 3:  be ai like generate me a photo of a yoga studio. It'll be fine.
Speaker 3:  Alright, last one. We've gone this whole time without talking about it
Speaker 3:  and we're just gonna talk about it for one second in the slide around. 'cause
Speaker 3:  I'm confident next week we'll have a full preview. Apple's iPhone 16 launch
Speaker 3:  event is September 9th.
Speaker 5:  It sure is
Speaker 4:  Glow time, right? That's the, that's that's the
Speaker 3:  Tagline's. That's gotta be for the Siri, right? The the Siri Effect.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Which I'm excited about. Okay. I have, I
Speaker 4:  I, I see this going one of two ways and I'm curious which you guys think
Speaker 4:  it is.
Speaker 4:  One, this is just another AI show. There's gonna be some new
Speaker 4:  hardware they're gonna, but all they're gonna talk about is how like the
Speaker 4:  new whatever chip inside of the iPhone 16
Speaker 4:  gives you more AI stuff.
Speaker 4:  Or this is going to be like a massive
Speaker 4:  new hardware rev. We're gonna get the camera buttons, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  get new designs, new colors, all kinds of stuff. Like
Speaker 4:  I could see this being either incredibly boring or incredibly huge cool,
Speaker 4:  exciting new iPhone year. And I kind of feel like it's nothing between, and
Speaker 4:  it all seems to me it depends on how exciting Apple really thinks Apple
Speaker 4:  Intelligence is. I think
Speaker 5:  It'll be between, 'cause that's, they, they threaded that needle at WW
Speaker 5:  DC where they took all the really cool stuff that was gonna happen and they're
Speaker 5:  like, this is happening ai, so we're gonna be like button
Speaker 5:  cool new phones AI for the rest of the show.
Speaker 4:  That is true. Like WW DC was actually like very good
Speaker 4:  and totally overshadowed by the weirdness of Apple Intelligence.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I I think, you know, they've gotta talk about it. It's the thing
Speaker 3:  that's coming next year and this phone will be the bleeding edge of it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think the real question is whether
Speaker 3:  they bring those features to the base model phone, for lack of a
Speaker 3:  better word, right? Does the iPhone 16 get Apple Intelligence or just the
Speaker 3:  16 Pro? Because only the 15 Pro is getting it right. If the 16 is
Speaker 3:  getting it, the regular 16, that's the big upgrade cycle and they're gonna
Speaker 3:  reintroduce all of the features. Mm. Because that's,
Speaker 3:  they know that general consumers do not pay attention to wwe C Right.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's the tech audience. That's developers. Apple releases new
Speaker 3:  iPhone. It's gonna have the features coming later this Syria be able to tell
Speaker 3:  Siri to do whatever You can tell Siri to do. That's your Good Morning America.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We've seen some rumors. I think that, that it was gonna come for the 16,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 3:  I, I assume so. Yeah. But I'm just saying like, that's my guess. That like
Speaker 3:  this is, that's how they balance that out. Yeah. I'm excited for a bunch
Speaker 3:  of other stuff. I think we're also expecting new watches, new watches,
Speaker 3:  new Air pods,
Speaker 4:  New headphones, potentially new Air Pods
Speaker 3:  M four Mac mini maybe Right? Is in the mix that
Speaker 4:  Yep. Is it weird that
Speaker 4:  want it so bad to give
Speaker 5:  It to you. If, if, if that is here