# Transcript
ID: e3b715cd-6ac0-4bb4-ab99-b78a20020bed
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6817165437699178245/3609268237265293724/s93290-US-1776s-1714902325.mp3
Description: We’re kicking off our “Five Senses of Gaming” miniseries today, starting with “touch.” The Verge’s William Poor explores a controller crisis in the Nintendo 64 speedrunning community, and follows one speedrunner’s quest to recreate a mythical controller he lost.
Further reading/viewing:
How Sticks Are Sabotaging Speedrunners (Stick Crisis History)
abney317 on Twitch
The Quest to Beat abney317
Mariokart64.com
More on Beck Abney’s controller problems
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (9 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  For listening to this podcast,
Speaker 3:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Mushy Bowls, I'm your
Speaker 3:  friend David Pierce and this is the first in a new series of
Speaker 3:  episodes sponsored by Visible Wireless all about gaming. For the
Speaker 3:  next four Sundays we are going to tell you about all kinds of different stories
Speaker 3:  in gaming. We did a series last fall, we had a ton of fun. We're doing it
Speaker 3:  again but this time we're doing it slightly differently. We're gonna tell
Speaker 3:  you stories about the five senses of the gaming world and if you're saying
Speaker 3:  David, there are five senses and you just said four Sundays, that's true.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna have to stick around to see how we figure it out. Our friends
Speaker 3:  from Polygon are gonna join us to help explain. We have some really fun
Speaker 3:  wild stories about how the Five Senses show up all over the
Speaker 3:  video game world. The first one we're doing is all about touch and our touch
Speaker 3:  story comes from a very specific corner of the gaming world. Speed running.
Speaker 3:  These are those like incredibly dedicated gamers who just try to beat
Speaker 3:  games in as little time as possible. They play it over and over faster
Speaker 3:  and faster, always trying to get time down, either by exploiting
Speaker 3:  glitches and shortcuts in the game or just spending hours and hours and hours
Speaker 3:  finding the exact optimal path through a game. If you've
Speaker 3:  never watched a speed run, pick your favorite game and just poke around on
Speaker 3:  YouTube, you'll probably find someone playing it in ways that you seriously
Speaker 3:  didn't think were possible and people who are really good at speed running
Speaker 3:  can often do it blindfolded, which is just a whole other thing that I don't
Speaker 3:  even understand. Our producer will pour poked around the Nintendo
Speaker 3:  64 speedrunning community and he discovered that all is not well there
Speaker 3:  and is very not well for one speedrunner in particular. I'll
Speaker 3:  let will take it from here.
Speaker 5:  I am a big fan of Nintendo 64 and so I was delighted
Speaker 5:  to discover just how popular my favorite games are for Speed Runners.
Speaker 5:  I've been watching these incredible videos of people flying through
Speaker 5:  Mario 64, Zelda, Mario Kart, finding
Speaker 5:  all these shortcuts and hacks that I had no idea about when I was
Speaker 5:  playing these games back in the day. But the more I learned about the
Speaker 5:  N 64 community, the more I heard about this problem that they've been
Speaker 5:  dealing with for years. I found this really dramatic YouTube
Speaker 5:  video that lays it all out.
Speaker 6:  Back in 2003, the Nintendo 64 was
Speaker 6:  discontinued never to be manufactured again.
Speaker 6:  But what nobody understood at the time is that Nintendo had just set
Speaker 6:  off a ticking time bomb. Something that years
Speaker 6:  later would threaten the entire existence of speed running on the N
Speaker 6:  64.
Speaker 5:  The issue is when you play lots of these games competitively, you
Speaker 5:  end up beating the crap outta your controller. You're playing for hours
Speaker 5:  every day and you're going really hard. So you're wearing down a
Speaker 5:  bunch of little plastic parts that were just never built for it in an N
Speaker 5:  64 controller. It's the joysticks that eventually give out.
Speaker 5:  I actually remember this happening. My brothers and I used to fight over
Speaker 5:  which controller we got to use 'cause the joystick on one of them just kind
Speaker 5:  of flopped around. So it's a super common thing, but if
Speaker 5:  you're a speedrunner, a bad controller can cost you a lot of
Speaker 5:  time and precision. So everyone wants nice pristine hardware to
Speaker 5:  play with. The problem is Nintendo hasn't
Speaker 5:  made original N 64 controllers for 20 years
Speaker 5:  and all that time speed runners have been burning through joysticks at
Speaker 5:  a fast enough clip that the world is running out of them.
Speaker 6:  So under this major threat of having to go outside
Speaker 6:  speed runners have been waging a desperate war trying to
Speaker 6:  halt this problem before time runs out.
Speaker 5:  N 64 controllers are now real commodities on
Speaker 5:  eBay. An unopened genuine Nintendo controller can go for
Speaker 5:  more than $500. There are third party controllers out there but
Speaker 5:  they're just not as good. So lots of speed runners end up
Speaker 5:  playing what they call the eBay lottery. They buy a used
Speaker 5:  Nintendo made controller and just hope the joystick is okay
Speaker 8:  And this looks in pretty good shape. Sticks stick is actually pretty
Speaker 8:  tight. Stick on this one is also, it's a little loose but it's not
Speaker 8:  too bad.
Speaker 5:  There's even a cottage industry of people building new joystick parts.
Speaker 5:  Some are 3D printed, really nice ones are made of steel, but
Speaker 5:  those go in and outta stock. There's a secondary market. It's a whole thing.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, the story that I'm here to tell, it's set in the
Speaker 5:  world of that controller shortage but it's not that story.
Speaker 5:  It's about this one very accomplished. Mario Kart 64
Speaker 5:  speedrunner who has a very different, much lonelier
Speaker 5:  problem.
Speaker 5:  Just to start off, how'd you get into speed running and when
Speaker 9:  I started playing Mario Kart 64 in
Speaker 9:  I guess like late 2013, I had owned
Speaker 9:  the game when it originally came out, but it probably never touched it again
Speaker 9:  after the Game Cube came out. But I just randomly had the N
Speaker 9:  64 round one day and was just messing around with
Speaker 9:  Mario Kart on it.
Speaker 5:  This is the humble beginning of Beck Abney or Abney
Speaker 5:  3 1 7 online today he's a a 30-year-old software
Speaker 5:  engineer and Mario Kar legend. But back in 2013
Speaker 5:  he was just a guy dusting off an old game system for fun.
Speaker 9:  Then I think I was looking up how to do mini turbos or something online and
Speaker 9:  accidentally found the, the time trial rankings and thought, oh hey this
Speaker 9:  looks fun. I'll, I'll just submit some times.
Speaker 5:  The psych he found was Mario kart 60 four.com home of
Speaker 5:  that game's speedrunning community. Basically a group of gamers
Speaker 5:  dedicated to completing each of the game 16 courses in as
Speaker 5:  little time as possible. Mario Kart 64 was released back in
Speaker 5:  1996, so by the time Beck wandered in, they'd been at
Speaker 5:  it for more than 15 years.
Speaker 9:  The website has times from people who submitted, you know, right when
Speaker 9:  the game came out. So the community has existed for a really long time and
Speaker 9:  when I joined and long after I joined, it was just kind of you
Speaker 9:  send an email in with whatever your times are, you know,
Speaker 9:  you may or may not provide proof, you know, before I joined people were
Speaker 9:  mailing in VHS tapes and things like that
Speaker 5:  And Beck thought I can get into this.
Speaker 9:  I'll drive some times today and see, see where it ends up. I think I was
Speaker 9:  maybe 350th or 360 somewhere in the
Speaker 9:  mid three hundreds when I first joined, which today would be
Speaker 9:  maybe equivalent to 500 something 'cause
Speaker 9:  we've had so many more people join in the last 10 years. Now, 10 years
Speaker 9:  later I'm still still playing.
Speaker 5:  He didn't stay in the mid three hundreds for long though. He started playing
Speaker 5:  for hours a day or grinding as speed runners would call it
Speaker 5:  and it was showing. So what put you on the map in
Speaker 5:  speed running? What were your first records?
Speaker 9:  When I first was playing, I went up the ranks really
Speaker 9:  quickly so I was really high ranked in non shortcut
Speaker 9:  and shortcut. A lot of people don't really play both a
Speaker 9:  ton, usually one's more focused on the other, but I was kind of doing
Speaker 9:  everything.
Speaker 5:  So some context here, it's pretty easy to cheat in Mario Kart
Speaker 5:  on some tracks. You can hop over guardrails and land way further ahead
Speaker 5:  in the course in other spots you can glitch the game out by crashing
Speaker 5:  into just the right out of bounds wall and you get warped to the finish
Speaker 5:  line. Over the years discovering new shortcuts has become a
Speaker 5:  sport unto itself. So today the community divides records
Speaker 5:  up into these two buckets, runs that use shortcuts and runs
Speaker 5:  that don't. Anyway, Beck was making waves in both
Speaker 5:  categories but he really made a name for himself in shortcuts.
Speaker 9:  My first record eventually was the new Chaco Mountain
Speaker 9:  shortcut was discovered in 2014.
Speaker 5:  It's a pretty absurd hack. You launch yourself straight at a wall right
Speaker 5:  at the start of the race and then fall backwards across the finish line,
Speaker 5:  but somehow the game thinks you've driven a full lap.
Speaker 9:  I was the first person to hit it about six months after it was
Speaker 9:  discovered to get like a five second lap. It was just kind of automatic world
Speaker 9:  record just for hitting it. It was like a ten second world record improvement
Speaker 9:  and then I would improve the the three lap record a few months
Speaker 9:  later as well and that record kept going down
Speaker 5:  Again. Being competitive in any game means grinding,
Speaker 5:  playing for hours and hours and hours. Shaving off a
Speaker 5:  second here a second there. I've watched Beck play, he live streams
Speaker 5:  on Twitch and it is oddly mesmerizing.
Speaker 10:  Hello
Speaker 10:  race again.
Speaker 5:  Lots of speed. Runners go pretty big in their streams, especially when they
Speaker 5:  hit records.
Speaker 11:  Bouncer police.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Hey let's go.
Speaker 12:  Whoa
Speaker 5:  Dad. By comparison, Beck is pretty understated. Here he
Speaker 5:  is hitting that Chaco Mountain shortcut on all three laps,
Speaker 5:  which meant finishing the whole race in less than 18 seconds. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  the non shortcut record for reference is a minute 55.
Speaker 11:  Oh my god.
Speaker 5:  He just smiles, shakes his head and chuckles to himself
Speaker 13:  And he's a pretty Ute run.
Speaker 5:  Shortcuts are really weird to watch because the glitches are often very
Speaker 5:  hard to trigger. So it's a lot of trying, failing,
Speaker 5:  resetting and trying again and again. But there's something about
Speaker 5:  Beck that is clearly tuned to that kind of zen state and
Speaker 5:  it's worked for him. So long sessions, lots of attempts.
Speaker 5:  What is your rising through the ranks here? What is your end goal?
Speaker 5:  What? What do you have your sights on?
Speaker 9:  I just kept trying to improve. There's a lot of good goals in this game that
Speaker 9:  they have that kind of keep people playing a lot. I think I got up to number
Speaker 9:  two in non shortcut and eventually I was
Speaker 9:  grinding to become shortcut champ and I became number one in the
Speaker 9:  shortcut category.
Speaker 5:  His specialty was playing through all 16 courses using all
Speaker 5:  the known shortcuts. He was so dominant that a YouTuber named
Speaker 5:  Summoning Salt made an hour long video just about the quest to beat
Speaker 5:  him
Speaker 11:  And then there's Abney making a joke of the
Speaker 11:  competition. Nobody could catch up to him without new
Speaker 11:  strategies
Speaker 5:  But the competition was heating up 20 years after the release of
Speaker 5:  Mario Kart 64, the game was more popular than ever to speed
Speaker 5:  run Beck fell back to third place in non shortcut driving,
Speaker 5:  but he fought to stay competitive and he kept improving.
Speaker 9:  I was better at driving in 2019 than I was in 2016
Speaker 9:  even though I dropped back to third place 'cause I was playing
Speaker 9:  shortcut and I was doing the full game runs and streaming a lot and playing
Speaker 9:  a lot of different categories. It I definitely improved until, you know,
Speaker 9:  2019 and then I had a lot of controller issues
Speaker 5:  In 2019. Everything changed for Beck and not for the
Speaker 5:  better. That's the year the N 64 controller crisis caught up
Speaker 5:  with him. The joystick failures, the parts shortage, all
Speaker 5:  of it, but in a way that no one could have anticipated.
Speaker 5:  That's after the break.
Speaker 1:  Verizon as low as $25 a month every month. Taxes and fees
Speaker 1:  included. Use promo code VERGE 20 to receive $20 off your first
Speaker 1:  month. For listening to this podcast.
Speaker 5:  Welcome back to recap. The year is 2019.
Speaker 5:  Beck Abney is a Mario Kart speed running phenomenon but the
Speaker 5:  more he plays, the more he notices that something is off.
Speaker 5:  How did you find yourself in your own very lonely predicament
Speaker 5:  around controllers?
Speaker 9:  You know, that day when I just randomly decided to start playing it, we had
Speaker 9:  three controllers and I just was picked them all
Speaker 9:  and my old gray controller happened to be in the best condition.
Speaker 9:  I was like, oh this one's good, I'll just use this one. And I just kept using
Speaker 9:  that same controller for the next couple years and
Speaker 9:  as it slowly wore down, I never really noticed it.
Speaker 9:  I just kind of got used to it and I kept improving my times
Speaker 9:  so I didn't think much of it. I kept improving and the controller just
Speaker 9:  kept getting more and more destroyed from me playing Mario Kart and then
Speaker 9:  eventually that controller got worn down so much that I couldn't
Speaker 9:  turn properly with it anymore.
Speaker 7:  Here we go.
Speaker 5:  If speed running in general is stressful for controllers, Mario
Speaker 5:  Kart is torture. You're constantly wrenching the joystick back
Speaker 5:  and forth to get these little speed boosts and if you're really grinding
Speaker 5:  a new controller can flake out in a matter of weeks.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So what is the, what are the parts that are degrading and failing?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, there's like a little bowl on the inside that
Speaker 9:  kind of pushes up against the bottom of the analog stick
Speaker 9:  and it sort of is just like a little curved plastic bowl and the
Speaker 9:  analog stick just will dig into this plastic. It's just
Speaker 9:  plastic on plastic and If. you open up one of these controllers
Speaker 9:  that's like old and used, it will just be full of plastic
Speaker 9:  dust from the bowl being just shaved down.
Speaker 5:  There are ways to extend the life of these parts. Some speed
Speaker 5:  runners open up their controllers and lubricate all the places where plastic
Speaker 5:  grinds on plastic, but eventually those little sticks and bowls will
Speaker 5:  be toast. This is the crux of the joystick shortage
Speaker 5:  and it was the backdrop as Beck went looking for a new controller,
Speaker 9:  I was like, okay, I need a different controller now I guess. And then when
Speaker 9:  I tried to, you know, use a perfect condition one I bought a bunch on eBay,
Speaker 9:  they were a little bit easier to find back then I was like, oh I, I can't
Speaker 9:  drive very well with with this one.
Speaker 5:  The problem bizarrely was that the new controller was
Speaker 5:  too nice. He'd gotten really good at playing with a half
Speaker 5:  broken controller. What is the best language that you
Speaker 5:  have to describe what it is you're feeling for
Speaker 5:  with the con the the perfect controller
Speaker 9:  In the past I've described it as, and if people have used a lot of N
Speaker 9:  64 controllers or bad ones will kind of know what I mean is
Speaker 9:  like it's mushy. Like the analog stick as
Speaker 9:  you're pushing it like a, a perfect one will feel like the same
Speaker 9:  when you're pushing it, you know, halfway versus all the way like it feels
Speaker 9:  like one fluid motion where like the I guess
Speaker 9:  ones that I'm using will be kind of harder to push as you
Speaker 9:  get closer to the edge. It like stops me before I even get there really?
Speaker 9:  But it's like kind of a weird squishy feeling for it.
Speaker 5:  Beck opened up his old controller and he saw that, yep, the little plastic
Speaker 5:  bowl was worn down. He realized that that was the source of the mus.
Speaker 5:  So as a test he put that old part into a new controller
Speaker 5:  and it worked. He had a new controller that felt like an old
Speaker 5:  mushy one. So for a while Abni 3 1 7 was back.
Speaker 5:  But then that controller failed
Speaker 9:  And that same process happened maybe two or three more times where
Speaker 9:  I kind of was like, oh well I know the solution now I'll just, I just have
Speaker 9:  to swap out everything except the bowl. Keep the super worn down bowl
Speaker 9:  and swap out all the other parts. And I was doing that and I was getting
Speaker 9:  world records at that point too.
Speaker 5:  The intensity was ramping up. He was driving faster,
Speaker 5:  grinding harder and destroying his controllers along the way.
Speaker 9:  I remember specifically getting a rainbow road non
Speaker 9:  shortcut world record. My controller broke and literally the, the
Speaker 9:  analog stick actually snapped in half off the
Speaker 9:  controller.
Speaker 5:  Beck and his squishy bowl were riding high but it was never
Speaker 5:  going to last forever
Speaker 9:  And then eventually it was worn down too much.
Speaker 5:  He put the old bowl and yet another new controller but it was
Speaker 5:  too far gone.
Speaker 9:  There's no going back. At that point
Speaker 5:  The perfect controller was well and truly dead and it was
Speaker 5:  the worst possible time for this kind of setback. Beck felt like he was
Speaker 5:  this close to being at the top of his game, which would be the
Speaker 5:  top of pretty much anyone's game. But now he was being held
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 9:  It got to the point where I was reaching closer and closer kind of to my
Speaker 9:  top potential of driving maybe. And I was more and more
Speaker 9:  picky over time and every time I'd have to swap controllers I'd be like,
Speaker 9:  oh well this one's not quite as good as the one I was just using.
Speaker 5:  So it feels like you are like with your own sort of
Speaker 5:  aptitude for the game hitting a ceiling where
Speaker 5:  whatever tiny difference the controller makes yeah. Is for you. The difference
Speaker 5:  between improving or not improving.
Speaker 9:  It's like I might be able to improve in the game more but I'm not able
Speaker 9:  to even get to where I was
Speaker 5:  But Beck wasn't finished. If there was one thing he knew how to do,
Speaker 5:  Welcome back. So Beck Abney was in a bind.
Speaker 5:  His ideal controller no longer existed and competitors
Speaker 5:  were eating away at his hard won records at this point his
Speaker 5:  options were one throw in the towel, two
Speaker 5:  spend years retraining himself on a good controller or
Speaker 5:  three somehow reverse engineer his old messed up
Speaker 5:  joystick. For Beck there was only one way forward. So
Speaker 5:  talk to me about what hoops you have jumped through to try to
Speaker 5:  recreate this mythical controller.
Speaker 9:  I mean originally it was like let me just buy a hundred controllers on eBay
Speaker 9:  and just go crazy and see if I get lucky. So I literally just have like
Speaker 9:  an absurd amount of controllers and it's possible I could mix and
Speaker 9:  match something and it actually would work. I never really had any luck with
Speaker 9:  that.
Speaker 5:  So next Beck tried designing custom parts that
Speaker 5:  mimicked his old controller. He used a 3D printing service to build
Speaker 5:  them
Speaker 9:  Shout outs to Yasmin in my discord who has, who had modeled some of
Speaker 9:  these for me. Took some existing 3D models that other people
Speaker 9:  had made and basically artificially like shaved down the bowl
Speaker 9:  to make it kind of worn down as if someone had actually
Speaker 9:  used it a bunch. But I'm just 3D printing it, you know, out of the box
Speaker 9:  just in bad condition. On purpose
Speaker 5:  For the record modifying controllers is allowed in Mario Kart speed running.
Speaker 5:  You just can't add new functionality to it.
Speaker 9:  We did like a ton of different ones. So like 0.1 millimeters cut out
Speaker 9:  0.2 and then like all the way to like 1.5 millimeters
Speaker 9:  carved out and I 3D printed 'em all and I tested 'em all and one or
Speaker 9:  two of them I was like, oh this is kind of close.
Speaker 5:  It felt familiar. Yeah, with that encouragement he started
Speaker 5:  iterating on other parts like the joystick and the springs,
Speaker 9:  Now let's print it in a bunch of different materials. Maybe the different
Speaker 9:  materials will feel different and they do very different.
Speaker 9:  Actually
Speaker 5:  Beck showed me this spreadsheet he's been using to keep track of all the
Speaker 5:  permutations to date he's tested 33 distinct
Speaker 5:  combinations of bowl and stick and springs. He's got
Speaker 5:  comments on all of them. Most are some variation on me but
Speaker 5:  a couple feel promising. He even set a world record with one of them.
Speaker 9:  It's basically just guess and check. Just kind of spend a bunch of money,
Speaker 9:  three printing random iterations and hope something
Speaker 9:  magically works for me.
Speaker 5:  Is this as frustrating as it sounds as you're telling me this, it
Speaker 5:  sounds incredibly frustrating.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's pretty annoying. I mean I'm lucky that I have like a fairly
Speaker 9:  popular stream and other stuff I can play and it's still
Speaker 9:  still fun but unfortunately, I guess 'cause it's like I
Speaker 9:  probably could have competed more. I think there were records that I was
Speaker 9:  close to getting that I didn't have. I was at one point really close
Speaker 9:  on like the Luigi Raceway three lap non shortcut record
Speaker 9:  and then I had controller problems and, and they kind of ran
Speaker 9:  away far ahead of me after that and it, it's like I have no idea if I
Speaker 9:  would be able to drive the time, like their times are way beyond
Speaker 9:  what I was doing five years ago. So I have no idea if I could get there now.
Speaker 5:  Do you, you feel the irony of of everyone else hunting for pristine
Speaker 5:  joysticks while you are hunting for Yeah. These half broken ones
Speaker 5:  Kind
Speaker 9:  Of, yeah. Yeah. It's funny 'cause I, yeah and I have some of those like steel
Speaker 9:  stick controllers and stuff that people want. I use them for some
Speaker 9:  shortcut stuff, but yeah, it's like hard for me to create
Speaker 9:  my perfect garbage controller that I want
Speaker 9:  and I, I don't have that controller. I can't like 3D scan
Speaker 9:  the parts and just replicate 'em or something.
Speaker 5:  The really galling part is that some other players prefer crappy
Speaker 5:  controllers too. One of his biggest rivals does, but Beck
Speaker 5:  says that somehow it's easier for them to get used to new
Speaker 5:  parts.
Speaker 9:  He'll be like, oh I can't use this one anymore. And he'll do like a whole
Speaker 9:  controller testing stream just testing other stuff and they'll be like, oh
Speaker 9:  this one's fine now.
Speaker 5:  Whereas try as he might beck just can't seem to
Speaker 5:  warm up to anything else. It's such a bummer that as
Speaker 5:  we talked, I started trying to work the problem myself.
Speaker 5:  Like what If you tr Okay, have you tried getting controllers
Speaker 5:  from other Mario Kart 64 players
Speaker 9:  And that was the, the genius idea was to take the
Speaker 9:  person who likes the perfect controller. Now they, they're done with it,
Speaker 9:  pass it on to the person who likes the, the slightly worse controller
Speaker 9:  and have like the big chain of people passing down controllers.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god,
Speaker 9:  That was a thought. I have had people send me controllers
Speaker 9:  before and someone sent me one who was like pretty,
Speaker 9:  pretty high ranked and plays a lot. They sent me one, it was like,
Speaker 9:  it was kind of mushy like I had described, but it like wasn't
Speaker 9:  quite right and it's also, I admittedly probably
Speaker 9:  play the game like way more so I would be waiting on their
Speaker 9:  controllers if they, you know, I'm like, hurry up and wear down your so
Speaker 9:  I can, I could play again kind of thing.
Speaker 5:  So for now, that's where things stand. Beck has another batch
Speaker 5:  of 3D printed parts arriving in the mail soon he'll try those
Speaker 5:  out and see if he gets lucky. In the meantime, he's working on a few
Speaker 5:  shortcut records on individual courses. One of his Franken
Speaker 5:  controllers works okay for that kind of race. So you're still, you're still
Speaker 5:  committed. Yeah. You're still, for
Speaker 9:  Now at least,
Speaker 5:  You're still here to defend your Honor. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Haven't completely given up 'cause of the controllers yet.
Speaker 5:  Gotcha. Is do you, do you have your dark moments where you're like, this
Speaker 5:  is not worth it?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, yeah. If I didn't have like my stream and a lot
Speaker 9:  of people watching and stuff, I probably just like wouldn't even play honestly.
Speaker 9:  I just, I, I would maybe do shortcut time trials to just keep
Speaker 9:  my number one rank there, but it's just
Speaker 9:  like honestly a lot more trouble than it's worth a lot of the time. Like
Speaker 9:  spending all the money trying to print random stuff for none of it to work
Speaker 9:  is just a a lot. But to the being
Speaker 9:  able to have something fun to stream or whatever at least keeps me motivated
Speaker 9:  to some degree. I would at least
Speaker 5:  Accepting your current situation and what you've got to work with.
Speaker 5:  What do you have your sights on now?
Speaker 9:  The last few days I've been playing Yoshi Valley shortcut
Speaker 9:  three lap in Time trials.
Speaker 5:  Yoshi Valley is another one of those runs with a really weird glitch.
Speaker 5:  You start the race and immediately veer off the course, leap over a fence
Speaker 5:  and go flying into a canyon. Perfecting that
Speaker 5:  shortcut means grinding out a super precise set of button presses
Speaker 5:  for hours on end, joystick to the left, brake plus
Speaker 5:  gas to turn, accelerate leap and sail into
Speaker 5:  oblivion
Speaker 9:  Just launching off the side of the track and slamming into a wall
Speaker 9:  over and over,
Speaker 5:  Which happens to be a pretty good metaphor for Beck's situation right now.
Speaker 5:  He's doggedly testing new parts and new combinations
Speaker 5:  attempt after attempt to rebuild the perfect controller,
Speaker 5:  but more often than not he hits a wall the same wall
Speaker 5:  over and over and over again.
Speaker 3:  All right, thank you Will. That is it for The Vergecast. Today I am going
Speaker 3:  to go hug my N 64 controller tighter than ever. Thank you as always
Speaker 3:  for listening. This is episode one, as I said of our gaming series.
Speaker 3:  Every Sunday this month we are going to have different stories from the worlds
Speaker 3:  of gaming. All about the five senses. There's also lots more on the
Speaker 3:  gaming world to read at The Verge dot com. It's a cool website, we like it
Speaker 3:  a lot and actually there's a lot happening in the gaming world right now,
Speaker 3:  so go check it out. We'll put some links in the show notes, but as always,
Speaker 3:  The Verge dot com, it's a website. It's right there. This show is produced
Speaker 3:  by Andrew Marino, BM James and Will pour The Vergecast is VERGE production
Speaker 3:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday to talk
Speaker 3:  about AI voice notes, the Delta game emulator. And we'll take a question
Speaker 3:  from The Vergecast hotline. See you then. Rock and roll