# Transcript
ID: 69b5431e-3933-49a2-be9b-d484ef07311d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-935122414570873265/6300503462373667690/s93290-US-3186s-1709466099.mp3
Description: The Verge’s Jennifer Pattison Tuohy has as smart a kitchen as any reasonable person possibly could; she has smart appliances, a smart sink, a smart fridge, and more voice assistants than anyone could ever talk to. And for a few days, she tried to let her kitchen do the work: telling her what to cook, getting everything set up just right, and even taking some of the cooking and cleaning load off her shoulders. Jen kept a diary during her adventures, and then joined The Vergecast to tell the tale. The fun, frustrating, exciting, harrowing tale.
Links:
The Thermomix
The Samsung Food app
The Fresco app
The GE Profile Smart Smoker
The Smart Instapot Pro
The Traeger Smart Wood Pellet Grill
The Typhur Smart Air Fryer
Tovala Smart Countertop Oven
My favorite smart oven is toast
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (3 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Welcome To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Android
Speaker 3:  Fridges. I'm your friend David Pierce and I'm here with Jen Pattison
Speaker 3:  Tui. Hi Jen Welcome back.
Speaker 4:  Hi David. Great to be back as always.
Speaker 3:  This is part two of our Smart Home series, If. you missed last week's episode.
Speaker 3:  Go back and listen to it. We got deep in our feelings about the Smart Kitchen.
Speaker 3:  It was very fun For this episode, Jen, we gave you a very specific,
Speaker 3:  and I suspect very arduous task, which is to basically
Speaker 3:  explore the state of the art of the smart kitchen. You have kind of
Speaker 3:  acquired as smart a kitchen as probably any reasonable person could be expected
Speaker 3:  to have at this point in time. And we asked you to
Speaker 3:  basically demonstrate over the course of a few days exactly how
Speaker 3:  smart you could make your kitchen and your life. And we asked you to keep
Speaker 3:  a voice memos diary of the whole experience and we're gonna play a
Speaker 3:  few clips of what we have here, right? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So basically the idea was, okay, I'm going to
Speaker 4:  really put my Smart Kitchen to the test. As I mentioned, I had bought a few
Speaker 4:  new appliances in the last couple years, but even myself as a Smart Home
Speaker 4:  Review, I haven't really dove into all of the features that they have. you
Speaker 4:  know, I haven't had to test them for work. So, I think it's a very common
Speaker 4:  issue in the Smart kitchen. People get smart devices and actually never
Speaker 4:  connect them or do any of the features that they have. So I was like,
Speaker 4:  I'm really gonna like dive into the, the features of the stuff that I bought
Speaker 4:  for myself. And then I'm also gonna explore how
Speaker 4:  those devices and other smart kitchen devices that I've tested
Speaker 4:  work together. Because this was sort of something we talked about a lot in
Speaker 4:  the last episode that a big problem with the smart home in general is that
Speaker 4:  interoperability, you sort of feel siloed. A lot of devices feel very sort
Speaker 4:  of siloed. So that was kind of the overall theme, like put my smart kitchen
Speaker 4:  to the test. But I also wanted to use, based on chatting with Ben
Speaker 4:  and Nick and the founder of Fresco and the Whisk app, now
Speaker 4:  Samsung Food really puts it to the test how technology can
Speaker 4:  help us cook in terms of using recipes, guided cooking,
Speaker 4:  make, make me a better chef in my kitchen because that sort of seemed
Speaker 4:  to be a theme that has emerged in the Smart kitchen. That it's not so much
Speaker 4:  that the kitchen's gonna cook for you, but the kitchen is gonna help you
Speaker 4:  cook better. So that was, that was kind of one of the things I was really
Speaker 4:  excited to try. Tried a few dishes I've never tried before. I
Speaker 4:  also wanted to see if the Smart Kitchen could save me time because convenience
Speaker 4:  is sort of one of the big selling points of the smart home. Yep. That was
Speaker 4:  sort of the framing for my sort of five to seven days of, of,
Speaker 4:  of using my smart kitchen to, to its fullest extent.
Speaker 3:  So one of the things I've been thinking a lot about since we talked to Nick
Speaker 3:  and Ben for last week's episode is this idea of
Speaker 3:  cooking and kind of the role of the Smart kitchen being kind of
Speaker 3:  on a longer timeline than we think about, right? Like we talk about the smart
Speaker 3:  kitchen as I'm standing in the kitchen making something,
Speaker 3:  I have a recipe in my hand and I need to go from recipe and raw ingredients
Speaker 3:  to made thing. But actually the way they were thinking about it and the
Speaker 3:  way I think I'm curious to hear how it affected you is the timeline of that
Speaker 3:  is much longer, right? It's like it's, it's grocery shopping, which is actually
Speaker 3:  about meal planning, which is actually about recipe discovery, which is actually
Speaker 3:  about health questions. And then on the other side it's, it's prep, it's
Speaker 3:  cleanup, it's dish washing, it's all this different stuff. So actually there
Speaker 3:  is this gigantic spectrum of like time and activities.
Speaker 3:  Did your smart kitchen hit that whole spectrum? Like how, how broad a
Speaker 3:  look at this did you feel like you could take going in?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, I definitely started sort of from the beginning with the meal planning,
Speaker 4:  which is something I have tried to do for many months, many
Speaker 4:  years. Same. you know, I have two kids. I have a husband who
Speaker 4:  insists on a full hot meal. We, we, I don't get away with cereal
Speaker 4:  for dinner. That was sort of very quat of the experiment for me was
Speaker 4:  can this be better than it was before because I have never successfully managed
Speaker 4:  to meal plan. It's time consuming and
Speaker 4:  tiresome and can be kind of expensive upfront. you know, in the end
Speaker 4:  it probably saves you money because you don't end up buying takeout. But
Speaker 4:  it's a chore for sure. And I really wanted to see Samsung
Speaker 4:  food in particular. That's sort of something that this app touts that it
Speaker 4:  can help you with putting it all into one place because there are lots of
Speaker 4:  great tools out there for meal planning, digital tools, paper tools.
Speaker 4:  I've seen very fancy notebooks you can buy for $50 in stationary stores
Speaker 4:  where you plan out your meal.
Speaker 3:  I mean, I'm definitely gonna end up buying one of those and then never using
Speaker 3:  it. That feels like me. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You know when you spend more time planning than you actually doing. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I've just not, I, I've never found a good solution for me So I as
Speaker 4:  a smart home reviewer. I was hoping that this would be the solution. I just,
Speaker 4:  you know, spoiler alert it worked but it still took a lot of time.
Speaker 3:  I, I would assume by the way that the beginning of this process would
Speaker 3:  involve the first smart gadget in our array here, which would be the fridge.
Speaker 3:  That's the idea behind the smart fridge, right? Is that it can help you
Speaker 3:  with some knowledge of what's in the fridge and what you buy and what you
Speaker 3:  eat and what's going bad and whatever actually help you make that
Speaker 3:  meal plan. Right? That's kind of the dream. Was that the beginning of your
Speaker 3:  test?
Speaker 4:  That was where I started standing in front of my giant tablet in the fridge,
Speaker 4:  in my kitchen. And that did not go that well.
Speaker 4:  I hate to say Okay, there were tools there that were better than the last
Speaker 4:  time I had tried this because when I first got the fridge it did have some
Speaker 4:  of these capabilities to tell you what was in them. And those have been
Speaker 4:  upgraded over the years, which is a good thing about a lot of these smart
Speaker 4:  kitchen appliances. As I mentioned, I started this about two years ago.
Speaker 4:  I got a lot of smart appliances, although I've had my fridge for longer and
Speaker 4:  I, over those two years more features have come. I can now voice control
Speaker 4:  my oven to an extent and the smart fridge
Speaker 4:  can now recognize more foods, but it it, it didn't do it very well.
Speaker 4:  Looking here it thinks my hummus is a salmon filet.
Speaker 4:  It thinks my salmon filet is meat and it
Speaker 4:  seems to think my sour cream pot is a sandwich
Speaker 4:  and the whipped cream is a sports drink,
Speaker 4:  so, Hmm. Not entirely accurate. So it would've just been quicker for me to
Speaker 4:  dictate a note into Siri of what was in my fridge rather than using the,
Speaker 4:  the food app. And, but the pieces and parts are there. So
Speaker 4:  I could add using voice using Bixby, which was a new experience for me
Speaker 4:  'cause I've never used Bixby before. And that Samsung's voice assistant that's
Speaker 4:  built into my fridge and I was able to add all the food that was in my
Speaker 4:  pantry to the food list so that I would have this master list. you
Speaker 4:  know, that's kind of the ultimate goal that I would love the smart kitchen
Speaker 4:  to be able to do for me is keep track of what food I have. If I went and
Speaker 4:  bought that fancy Asian sauce for my one dish that I made
Speaker 4:  two months ago, well can you suggest another recipe that I could use for
Speaker 4:  it? 'cause you know what I have in my pantry and make use of
Speaker 4:  the food that's in your house rather than having to go buy it. And I
Speaker 4:  was really hoping that once I put all of my food into the food
Speaker 4:  list, which wasn't too laborious but certainly isn't something I'd want to
Speaker 4:  do regularly, it would spit out a meal plan sort of using
Speaker 4:  the food that I had. And it didn't do that. There were portions where
Speaker 4:  I could go and sort of look in a section where my food was and say,
Speaker 4:  okay, suggest recipes for me and then I could add those to my favorites and
Speaker 4:  then I could go add those to my meal plan. But you know, that's a lot of
Speaker 4:  steps. So that was a bit of a, that was a bit of a, a downside. And then
Speaker 4:  the other thing that I really think it should do, and I did talk to Nick
Speaker 4:  about this during the process and I said, is this something you're gonna
Speaker 4:  bring to Samsung food? So I. I abandoned my Amazon
Speaker 4:  a shopping list, which is what I normally use. And I used the Samsung food
Speaker 4:  shopping list and then I ordered all the food through The Samsung Food
Speaker 4:  app that connects to Instacart. And I said, okay, now
Speaker 4:  shouldn't all of the food I just bought suddenly now be in my
Speaker 4:  food list? Right. So I don't have to manually input. It seems logical.
Speaker 4:  No, it doesn't do that. So I.
Speaker 4:  That was when I gave up on the food list. I'm like, I'm not doing this again.
Speaker 3:  It is one of those things I think with both recipe
Speaker 3:  collection and that sort of grocery shopping
Speaker 3:  creation side of things this whole industry is, is you can see all of the
Speaker 3:  pieces. Yeah. And no one is actually putting any of them together. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like I use this really lovely recipes app called, I think it's
Speaker 3:  Mila, MELA. And it's beautiful. It does a really good job of
Speaker 3:  parsing recipes and putting it in and it does an awful job of just
Speaker 3:  being like, Hey, remember this thing that you've cooked 10 times? Why are
Speaker 3:  you saving another blueberry muffins recipe? You already have one that you
Speaker 3:  seem to like very much. And also remember how you've made blueberry muffins
Speaker 3:  11 sundaes in a row. Here's the blueberry muffins recipe. Like there, there's
Speaker 3:  just all these little pieces of it that feel like it's actually not
Speaker 3:  more intelligence we need. It's just putting all of these little pieces together,
Speaker 3:  which I guess to some extent is the story of the smart kitchen. Yes. Like
Speaker 3:  it's all in there. Yes. It's just a matter of making it sort of make
Speaker 3:  sense as a whole.
Speaker 4:  We have the ingredients, we just don't have the finished product.
Speaker 3:  Oh boy. There's a metaphor for you. This just became the most meta episode
Speaker 3:  of the verse cast we've ever done. I love it. Okay, so
Speaker 3:  that was the beginning of the process. Yes. But you, you acquired food. Yes.
Speaker 3:  You had ingredients in your house. What was day one's experience?
Speaker 3:  What did you do the first time?
Speaker 4:  So for some reason meal plans like to try and start you on a Monday and I
Speaker 4:  was like, no, no, no, no. I need the weekend for this. So. I started, I started
Speaker 4:  on a Saturday and it was actually a holiday weekend. So you know, I had plenty
Speaker 4:  of time and as I've mentioned before, I really enjoy cooking. So you know,
Speaker 4:  this was fun for me to do and to sort of test out all of these gadgets that
Speaker 4:  I hadn't really spent a lot of time with outside of work. And yeah,
Speaker 4:  it was, the first day was, was really kind of fun because I was making dishes
Speaker 4:  I'd never really made myself before because I'm not very good at them and
Speaker 4:  things that my family really enjoys. Like one of the first things I did on
Speaker 4:  Sunday morning was make biscuits and gravy, which is my husband's favorite
Speaker 4:  dish. I'm gonna try and make it from scratch using
Speaker 4:  my Thermomix mix. I did not think my Thermomix mix could make biscuits and
Speaker 4:  gravy, but apparently it can. And it tells me it will only take me 20 minutes
Speaker 4:  of prep time and then 20 minutes of cooking. That seems pretty fast for
Speaker 4:  Sunday morning breakfast, Therma Mix, my favorite, still my favorite smart
Speaker 4:  kitchen gadget. I have to say even that it's siloed in its own little ecosystem,
Speaker 4:  but it can't bake. So, I got to use my oven for that purpose. And that was
Speaker 4:  where I ran into some issues with voice control because this is another
Speaker 4:  area where the smart kitchen feels like it should work. Well
Speaker 4:  voice control is a natural interface you would think for a kitchen
Speaker 4:  where your hands are often busy and you're not holding your phone
Speaker 4:  and it's still tricky. There's difficult nomenclature.
Speaker 4:  I really struggled to get my oven to preheat using
Speaker 4:  voice commands.
Speaker 4:  And this also leads to another issue with the smart kitchen safety.
Speaker 4:  There are so many sort of checks and balances put in by manufacturers
Speaker 4:  I assume, who want to make sure that I don't maim myself or kill myself or
Speaker 4:  burn my house down. Which is fair enough. Seems
Speaker 3:  Reasonable. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But still causes friction and that's the one thing you don't want in the
Speaker 4:  cooking process is friction. So the voice control, I feel
Speaker 4:  ultimately I, and this might be a bit pie in the sky and you, you can, you'll
Speaker 4:  probably shoot it down, but I think voice control would work better in the
Speaker 4:  kitchen if it was in each appliance as opposed to a
Speaker 4:  universal control that's trying to understand what you are addressing.
Speaker 4:  So if I could talk to my oven and say preheat to,
Speaker 4:  as opposed to having to ask Alexa to do it for me. And then
Speaker 4:  it had this really annoying thing where it would If, you asked to preheat
Speaker 4:  it automatically does it at 350 degrees. It, it didn't let me set
Speaker 4:  what I wanted it to be. And then when I said, okay, don't do that, then
Speaker 4:  I want you to bake at 350 or 375 degrees, which
Speaker 4:  is what I wanted. It does it. And it said okay, I will set the oven for an
Speaker 4:  hour. I didn't tell it to set the oven for an hour. I didn't think about
Speaker 4:  the fact that I told it to set the oven for an hour. Two hours later when
Speaker 4:  I went to go get my food, it was only half cooked because the Oven had turned
Speaker 4:  off and an hour. Oh geez. So yeah, not, not a
Speaker 4:  good experience.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I do agree with you by the way, one of my most closely held
Speaker 3:  theories about voice assistance is that every device
Speaker 3:  should have its own and you should address the device, not
Speaker 3:  address an assistant. Yes. About a device. Yes. I just think that
Speaker 3:  paradigm just doesn't make sense in a way that I want, I wanna look at my
Speaker 3:  TV and say, Hey TV play ESPN and I wanna look at my Oven and
Speaker 3:  say, hey Oven preheat to three 50. That's just, that just
Speaker 3:  intuitively makes more sense than saying it does, you know, Hey
Speaker 3:  tell my GE smart oven to pre, like that's, that's nothing. You've lost me
Speaker 3:  at that point. Yes it is one of those things that that bar for all of
Speaker 3:  this is, it has to be easier than walking over to it and pushing the buttons.
Speaker 3:  And that's a really, really, really, really, really high bar to clear. But
Speaker 3:  if I can look at it from across the kitchen and say preheat to three 50,
Speaker 3:  that does it. As long as it works.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  But it doesn't.
Speaker 4:  I have used individual devices with built-in voice control and they have
Speaker 4:  never been good. you know, that's the, that's the hard part here is you're
Speaker 4:  asking a oven manufacturer to come up with a good voice assistant
Speaker 4:  and I, I've used it in like robot vacuums and a few other devices and
Speaker 4:  it's, it's just, you know, Amazon and Google and
Speaker 4:  Apple to some extent have nailed a good experience
Speaker 4:  that not always perfect, but it's a lot better than you're gonna find most
Speaker 4:  other places. Although I know Amazon does have this system where you can,
Speaker 4:  developers can come to them and ask them to help them make like the Hey Disney
Speaker 4:  is one of those examples. So I could see a future where this becomes possible.
Speaker 4:  And yes, I agree that would've, that would've made the voice experience work
Speaker 4:  in my kitchen. And today it is not a good experience.
Speaker 3:  So I, I'm curious at the beginning of this process, how much
Speaker 3:  you had to force yourself to like do the smart
Speaker 3:  thing in the kitchen, like quote unquote smart thing in the kitchen, right?
Speaker 3:  Because we asked you basically go way out of your way to use the
Speaker 3:  smartness of these appliances. Did it occur to you at the beginning how many
Speaker 3:  times you had to stop and be like, okay, I have to not do this the way I
Speaker 3:  would normally do this even with the same appliance in order to do the
Speaker 3:  most technology forward part of
Speaker 4:  This? Yes, a lot. I had to do that a lot and it was frustrating
Speaker 4:  because this is another issue that I've felt was a problem with the
Speaker 4:  smart kitchen is that the app control of appliances is largely
Speaker 4:  pointless. And when it is useful it does
Speaker 4:  add extra steps. There are two examples. So I have
Speaker 4:  two smart Countertop ovens that I've tested. There's the Valla and
Speaker 4:  the Typhur. The Typhur is an Air Fryer, it's like a dome air
Speaker 4:  Fryer and it is the best air Fryer I have ever used. It's
Speaker 4:  awesome. But the app makes no sense. There's just no
Speaker 4:  point to me in using the app. The only thing it can do is
Speaker 4:  send the settings for a recipe I find in its own app,
Speaker 4:  which is limited and that's somewhat useful. But the control panel
Speaker 4:  is very simple and easy and it's just as easy to hit the buttons. And So
Speaker 4:  I had kind of, I've had this Typhur for about three weeks and I've been testing
Speaker 4:  it and I never use the app and I, for this process I was
Speaker 4:  like okay, I've got to make sure to use the app. And I was like, it wouldn't
Speaker 4:  let me preheat, preheat, Oven to bake 400
Speaker 4:  degrees.
Speaker 5:  Sorry, I couldn't find anything to do that. To get started you'll
Speaker 5:  need a smart kitchen appliance.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But I have a smart kitchen appliance. All right nomenclature,
Speaker 4:  I'm probably saying it wrong. How about just
Speaker 4:  tell my oven to preheat.
Speaker 5:  Okay, bake at 350 degrees Fahrenheit for one hour.
Speaker 4:  I had to preheat on the device, then go back to the app, choose
Speaker 4:  the recipe and send those settings Once it finished preheating
Speaker 4:  and it was like this is not useful. And then with the
Speaker 4:  valla, all you can do is send the settings. I can't add cooking
Speaker 4:  time. Like the Valla is a great little lunchtime cooking
Speaker 4:  machine. 'cause you know, If, you just want to reheat dinner for lunch. I
Speaker 4:  don't wanna heat up my entire Thermador range, So, I just use this little
Speaker 4:  Countertop oven. But sometimes it takes longer and
Speaker 4:  I'm like, oh I wanna add an extra five minutes for my desk and I'd love to
Speaker 4:  be able to just press five minutes on the app. But no, you have to go back
Speaker 4:  to the device and press the button. And it's like, what is the smart
Speaker 4:  element here? There isn't really, and I get, again, this probably goes back
Speaker 4:  to the safety issue, unattended appliances that can reach
Speaker 4:  over 450 degrees. You know, they wanna make sure that you really meant to
Speaker 4:  do that. And I get that. But yeah, that was frustrating. The
Speaker 4:  only benefit I find there with the app is for
Speaker 4:  a more complicated device. So the Instapot for example, which
Speaker 4:  I have, I was testing the Instapot Pro Plus, which is
Speaker 4:  Instant Pot's first sort of truly smart device. And it
Speaker 4:  works with Fresco, the smart home, the smart kitchen platform.
Speaker 4:  And in its app you, once you choose the recipe,
Speaker 4:  it will send the precise settings to the Instapot. And if you've
Speaker 4:  used an Instapot, especially one like this, that that has a big screen with
Speaker 4:  all sorts of complicated settings on, it's, it was so much easy. I had
Speaker 4:  no idea what I was doing. I was like so nice to be able to just press the
Speaker 4:  button and they all showed up. Especially as the Instapot, it's kind of a
Speaker 4:  scary device. 'cause when it stops, it lets off all the steam, which I think
Speaker 4:  we have a clip of that too.
Speaker 4:  I was really scared of the Instapot. I put it like in the middle of the counter,
Speaker 4:  like in the middle of my kitchen. I didn't want it near anything that might
Speaker 4:  explode.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I'm so hung up on this idea of not being able to
Speaker 3:  preheat stuff remotely. Because I think to some extent
Speaker 3:  one of the challenges for the smart kitchen is that you're, you're in your
Speaker 3:  kitchen typically when you're cooking. one of the reasons I think things
Speaker 3:  like meal planning and grocery shopping for you is interesting
Speaker 3:  is that that is stuff that can theoretically be done without you and that
Speaker 3:  you're actually kind of happy to do remotely. But the odds of you wanting
Speaker 3:  to make dinner without ever setting foot in your kitchen is both
Speaker 3:  implausible and just kind of not realistic. Right? But the idea that I should
Speaker 3:  be able to walk into my kitchen and my oven is preheated. Yeah. Seems
Speaker 3:  like the simplest, most useful thing to do.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like I made dinner last night and my, my Grill is
Speaker 3:  downstairs in our back patio and our kitchen is upstairs and all
Speaker 3:  I want in the whole world is to be able to point my phone at my Grill and
Speaker 3:  say, Grill turn on while I'm standing in my kitchen
Speaker 3:  prepping stuff. Yeah. And you just can't do that. No. And part of
Speaker 3:  it is because of these totally valid and maybe slightly overbearing safety
Speaker 3:  things, but all reasons aside, that's the lowest
Speaker 3:  hanging fruit I can think of in the smart kitchen. And we still can't get
Speaker 4:  It. We can't, no, I have So, I have tested the smart Traeger
Speaker 4:  Smoker, outdoor Smoker and you can control the entire thing from the
Speaker 4:  app change settings as it goes, which is great. But to
Speaker 4:  actually start it, you have to go press the button. It will not let you do
Speaker 4:  it. And the, the Thermador oven, so when I first got the Thermador,
Speaker 4:  the only remote control option was by turning a dial
Speaker 4:  to remote control. Then you could use your smartphone
Speaker 4:  from anywhere. So I could preheat from anywhere. But I had, I would've had
Speaker 4:  to have remembered to turn the dial to remote control before I left the house.
Speaker 4:  Which is not something that's top of my list of things to do. And there
Speaker 4:  has been an update I discovered during this testing that it
Speaker 4:  should allow me to enable permanent remote start through the app.
Speaker 4:  I spent a good half an hour and I couldn't get it to work. It just, wouldn't
Speaker 4:  it, it just wouldn't let me do it. I, I don't know, maybe this is something
Speaker 4:  that's coming soon and they just didn't make that clear enough in the app.
Speaker 4:  But So I, I was actually at watching my son play tennis
Speaker 4:  and it was on the match was going long and I knew I had, I had a
Speaker 4:  chicken enchilada ready to cook. I was going to start cooking chicken enchiladas
Speaker 4:  when I got home. I knew it was gonna be a long process. So I was like, okay,
Speaker 4:  I'll preheat the oven from the app while I'm watching tennis
Speaker 4:  and no luck. So you know, I had to do the fallback, which was text my husband
Speaker 4:  and tell him to get off the couch and go preheat
Speaker 3:  The ice. There's the smart kitchen right there. That works too. Now you're
Speaker 3:  talking. Okay, so what else did you make over the course of this experiment?
Speaker 3:  I won't, I won't make you go day by day, but did you have any particularly
Speaker 3:  telling experiences? What else did you make? Oh
Speaker 4:  Gosh, I made, so for the, the long holiday weekend I did a Saturday morning
Speaker 4:  for tartar. That was kind of fun because what I did there was I
Speaker 4:  used, so Samsung food has this feature where you can take a picture
Speaker 4:  of ingredients and it will suggest recipes for you. So
Speaker 4:  I, I mean it's limited usefulness I suppose because you know, you could just
Speaker 4:  Google, okay I have eggs, I have pork, I have,
Speaker 4:  but it was kind of fun,
Speaker 3:  Which is a great way to cook by the way. I've actually had a lot of fun being
Speaker 3:  like, I have half a pound of ground Turkey, this
Speaker 3:  Korean barbecue sauce that I forgot about and bok
Speaker 3:  choy, what can I make? What can I make? And, and you just sort of make whatever
Speaker 3:  comes up. It's actually a pretty fun way to kind of empty the fridge of all
Speaker 3:  the strange stuff you have.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that was, you know, that was what I did with this. I, I So I do
Speaker 4:  a CSA and I live in the south and I often get a lot of random
Speaker 4:  vegetables that I have no idea what to do with. Although unfortunately Samsung
Speaker 4:  food did not know what to do with most of them either because they were a
Speaker 4:  bit random. but it gave me inspiration I would say, as opposed
Speaker 4:  to effectively giving me a good dish. I, I had
Speaker 4:  pork, I had ground pork, I had eggs, I just got from my chickens and I
Speaker 4:  had some vegetables and some potatoes and it thought it was mince beef,
Speaker 4:  not pork, you know, it didn't get everything right. but it did come up with
Speaker 4:  an idea of the frittata using the potatoes and the eggs. So I ended up
Speaker 4:  doing nice frittata, which is something I used to cook all the time and I'd
Speaker 4:  sort of forgotten about. So that was nice kind of getting the inspiration.
Speaker 4:  And then what else did I do? So on the big sort of holiday lunch
Speaker 4:  I had planned to do a smoked pork butt. So
Speaker 4:  I've been testing the GE profile, indoor smart Smoker,
Speaker 4:  which again is connected, but connectivity is
Speaker 4:  relatively limited. Doesn't really do a lot for me, but it is a really
Speaker 4:  interesting piece of tech being able to use a Smoker indoors. I mean, I'm
Speaker 4:  lucky enough to have a backyard where I can use a Smoker, but I know I've,
Speaker 4:  I've heard a lot of people that were very excited about the prospect of being
Speaker 4:  able to, you know, smoke some, smoke some butt indoors.
Speaker 3:  There are a lot of people with like smokers on fire escapes.
Speaker 3:  Yes. And all kinds of deeply dangerous things going on just in
Speaker 3:  the name of the flavor.
Speaker 4:  This is also an example of a, a smart appliance that I was hoping would help
Speaker 4:  me cook better because barbecue is an art
Speaker 4:  and you know, again, live in the south I'm familiar like there's a lot of
Speaker 4:  barbecue places around here and I love me some brisket and some good
Speaker 4:  pulled pork. And I did try brisket, I did try pulled pork
Speaker 4:  smoked butt and none of it worked out very well. Oh no.
Speaker 3:  What, how come, what happened? I don't
Speaker 4:  Know. I put it in there for the 10 hours that it told me to
Speaker 4:  and in the end it just came out kind of rubbery and
Speaker 4:  overcooked. So I, I, you know, there could have been user error but
Speaker 4:  I think one of the things I was frustrated with, with this device compared
Speaker 4:  to say the Traeger, which I've used before, the outdoor one
Speaker 4:  is the Traeger will automatically adjust the time and the temperature
Speaker 4:  based on the probe. Whereas this device, it would just, you, you had
Speaker 4:  to monitor it and adjust it yourself. And I think, I think
Speaker 4:  that was probably where the user error came in at some point that I didn't,
Speaker 4:  didn't top up the pellets fast enough or, and
Speaker 4:  it's so it stopped smoking and just started cooking, which probably overcooked
Speaker 4:  it. I see. But yeah, that was unfortunately wasn't a huge success. But then
Speaker 4:  I did salvage it and this was kind of fun. So the next day I decided to
Speaker 4:  make faux ramen where you put like all fun things in
Speaker 4:  noodle soup and I'd never made that before and my husband loves it
Speaker 4:  and So I sliced the top of the pork butt off and turned it
Speaker 4:  into pork belly to put in my ramen. So you know, I did things that I hadn't,
Speaker 4:  I would never have thought about doing before because you know, I gave myself
Speaker 4:  the time and the tools because making chocolate MOUs is not an easy
Speaker 4:  process. If, you aren't used to hand whisking
Speaker 4:  egg whites and heating chocolate at really high temperatures and that I could
Speaker 4:  use a Therma mix for. So a lot of the devices that I had,
Speaker 4:  like the Therma mix, the GE profile, smart mix stand
Speaker 4:  mixer, the Air Fryer and the Instapot, it did enable
Speaker 4:  me to do things that I would not have been able to do before. But this goes
Speaker 4:  back to that issue that we've talked about in the past is these are great
Speaker 4:  individual smart gadgets to have in your kitchen.
Speaker 4:  Smart. Not just because they're connected to wifi, but because they are adding
Speaker 4:  something to the process. They're making the process easier so
Speaker 4:  you can create more fun foods at home and have more joy
Speaker 4:  out of your cooking. But they were all really quite siloed in their own
Speaker 4:  ecosystems. And as soon as I get out of The Thermomix world or out of the
Speaker 4:  Instapot world, I have to start all over with another app or another
Speaker 4:  voice control or, and so that, that interoperability was something that
Speaker 4:  I still came up against for ev you know, at every step of the way
Speaker 4:  that isn't, there is no real solution yet to that, but individual
Speaker 4:  devices in the smart kitchen are fun. If, you have enough
Speaker 4:  counter space.
Speaker 3:  That is a perfect segue. We need to take a break really fast, but then we're
Speaker 3:  gonna come back and we're gonna talk about some of the takeaways and what
Speaker 3:  we can all learn and smarten up in our kitchens about this. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 7:  Fox Creative, this is advertiser content from
Speaker 7:  Kohler.
Speaker 6:  I think when we think of design we're like beautiful poster,
Speaker 6:  gorgeous graphics. But I also think design has like
Speaker 6:  a place in making sure that people feel the best that they can be.
Speaker 6:  Hi, I'm Laura Rado. I'm a group creative director of Vox Creative.
Speaker 6:  During my nine to five and my five to nine, I've always got
Speaker 6:  good design on the brain. It's
Speaker 6:  metaphorically and physically glowing. It's like the
Speaker 6:  Aurora Borealis, which is exactly why I was
Speaker 6:  so excited to meet the new me 2.0 Kohler's
Speaker 6:  smartest toilet. On first introduction,
Speaker 6:  it legit just waved a hand at me, not actual waved a
Speaker 6:  hand, but the lid moved up and greeted me
Speaker 6:  for the use. But right now we're in a showroom. So I can't
Speaker 6:  actually use it. Functions like this. A hands-free greeting
Speaker 6:  and form combined in the newie to elevate the everyday.
Speaker 6:  It's a sculpture that begs for someone to like
Speaker 6:  rest their body on it and walk away feeling really comfortable.
Speaker 6:  A temperature controlled bidet, the heated seat, automatic self
Speaker 6:  cleaning cycles, access to smart home functions thanks to a built in
Speaker 6:  Alexa. The Numis got it all for everyone.
Speaker 6:  The bottom has this really beautiful green glow and it's almost as if
Speaker 6:  they knew that was my special color because If, you go into my bathroom at
Speaker 6:  home, the entire bathroom is a mint green.
Speaker 6:  It's like the new me knew that I was showing up. And what's really
Speaker 6:  cool about this is that there is this like circular sphere
Speaker 6:  metal piece that like allows for you to change the color on the bottom.
Speaker 6:  So if I'm not in my mint green era, which I'm often am,
Speaker 6:  I can be in another era. My like calming blue, my
Speaker 6:  like rosy pink, like whatever I need to feel.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's like the Sistine Chapel of Toilets
Speaker 6:  experience a fully connected oasis of clean and comfort
Speaker 6:  with the new me 2.0. Learn
Speaker 6:  more@kohler.com.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we're back. So Jen, you've been through this whole experience, it
Speaker 3:  sounds like it has been mostly interesting. I was gonna say
Speaker 3:  mostly good, but I'm not even sure that's true. but it has certainly been
Speaker 3:  interesting. Let's talk about some takeaways from all of this because I think
Speaker 3:  there are a lot of people who are looking around at their kitchen trying
Speaker 3:  to figure out what is useful to invest time and money
Speaker 3:  and energy into figurine out. What apps should I download on my phone? Let's
Speaker 3:  help the people out here a little bit. So the first thing is,
Speaker 3:  is smartening up your kitchen as much as possible? A good idea?
Speaker 3:  Is this a goal people should have for their lives at this moment in time
Speaker 3:  to try and get a very smart kitchen?
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. Because things don't all work together,
Speaker 4:  it can create chaos. If, you have too many smart devices,
Speaker 4:  too many smart cooks in the kitchen spoil the broth. Your oatmeal
Speaker 4:  timer is done, your oatmeal timer is done. Okay. It's mild chaos
Speaker 4:  in here because my oatmeal timer is apparently
Speaker 4:  done, my robot vacuum decided to start vacuuming because it's Monday morning
Speaker 4:  and at some point my oven turned itself off and
Speaker 4:  I don't know why.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so if in theory we're gonna pick just
Speaker 3:  one device to start with, I have a feeling I know the answer to this question
Speaker 3:  based on the many ways you have recommended The Thermomix in the past. but
Speaker 3:  it does feel like the place to start is pick one or two of these kind of
Speaker 3:  multipurpose, do lots of things, ideally interact with an
Speaker 3:  app or each other or whatever, but start sort of appliance by appliance
Speaker 3:  rather than thinking about your kitchen holistically.
Speaker 3:  Where would you tell most people to start?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think it's, we're still a ways from the point where our holistic
Speaker 4:  kitchen works well together. So, you know, I would If you if you're going
Speaker 4:  out and buying new kitchen equipment, if you're gonna remodel your kitchen,
Speaker 4:  I would definitely get an oven that has wifi connectivity because we know
Speaker 4:  we're gonna have better capabilities in The future. And you can turn it off
Speaker 4:  until you want it. you know, you don't have to connect it to the internet.
Speaker 4:  But in terms of today, If, you want to get a gadget that's
Speaker 4:  going to improve your cooking experience. The
Speaker 4:  Thermomix is a great device. It is very expensive though. I will caveat
Speaker 4:  with that. It's
Speaker 3:  Like $1,500 or something, right?
Speaker 4:  But it does a lot. It's like seven things in one. And
Speaker 4:  one of the great things about, and this is sort of what I feel like is a
Speaker 4:  sort of goal for all smart kitchen appliances, is that it
Speaker 4:  does make the cooking process easier and it helps you do things
Speaker 4:  that you wouldn't necessarily be able to have done before because of,
Speaker 4:  and it keeps it all in one device. So cleanup is minimal. This
Speaker 4:  is an area we have not fixed. My kitchen is a mess right
Speaker 4:  now, in fact, would you come and help me clean up?
Speaker 3:  No, no thanks.
Speaker 4:  Because yeah, chaos rains when you do a lot of cooking in your house
Speaker 4:  and yes, we have the dishwasher but someone still has to load it and unload
Speaker 4:  it and yeah, I I, I did not find a solution to keeping my kitchen clean other
Speaker 4:  than running my robot vacuum cleaner, which got in my way a lot. But yes,
Speaker 4:  and as as a single device, The Thermomix actually has guided
Speaker 4:  cooking. This was the one area I did find has improved
Speaker 4:  significantly in my testing this last week is guided
Speaker 4:  cooking has become a lot better. I used to use smart
Speaker 4:  displays to try and do some guided cooking like Amazon's and
Speaker 4:  Google's have these functions built in.
Speaker 3:  And that's mostly, you just kind of like load the thing and sort of swipe
Speaker 3:  from step to step in the recipe, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. And it can also sometimes read out the steps for you
Speaker 4:  and my fridge can read out the steps for me, but it does it really fast really,
Speaker 4:  really quickly. And it's not very pleasant experience. But
Speaker 4:  The Thermomix has a built-in screen with the guided steps. So
Speaker 4:  as you go along you're just following the guided steps. And that
Speaker 4:  I find I found a very, very useful in my experimenting and The
Speaker 4:  Fresco app is probably the one that I found that had the best guided cooking
Speaker 4:  experience.
Speaker 4:  Okay, so that is the in-app timer on
Speaker 4:  The. Fresco app is showing the step
Speaker 4:  by step with the ingredients for each step, which is
Speaker 4:  key because you know when you're reading recipe and it says
Speaker 4:  add the flour and you're like, well how much flour was it? And then you scroll
Speaker 4:  all the way back up and find the amount this has the amount with the ingredient
Speaker 4:  and the step plus a little button for starting a timer for
Speaker 4:  the amount of time the recipe called for that step, which is
Speaker 4:  kind of ingenious. And I'm surprised no one's done this before. So, so far
Speaker 4:  this is pretty good.
Speaker 3:  What about the flip side? Is there a gadget that you are desperate to get
Speaker 3:  rid of and stop having on your counter either because it's bad or because
Speaker 3:  it's just been sort of useless to you in real life?
Speaker 4:  I need to cut down on my counter clutter and at this stage what I would really
Speaker 4:  like, and this is maybe a future bit too far in The future,
Speaker 4:  but I want my oven to do everything that the
Speaker 4:  Typhur and The Thermomix and the
Speaker 4:  Tovala and the Instapot does. I'm like, could there not be a way that
Speaker 4:  these capabilities could all be in the biggest,
Speaker 4:  most powerful, most expensive? Because
Speaker 3:  As you have pointed out to me before, all these air fryers are just fancy
Speaker 3:  convection ovens, which is a thing that your oven can theoretically do
Speaker 3:  well. And actually to that point, one of the things I I meant to ask you
Speaker 3:  about earlier is you and I have both had these years long obsessions with
Speaker 3:  these allin one little ovens that are like the size of a toaster
Speaker 3:  Oven, but are super smart. So they've had the ones that have the cameras
Speaker 3:  that you put it in and it knows you're making chocolate chip cookies and
Speaker 3:  it'll just bake the chocolate chip cookies for you. That feels like magic
Speaker 3:  to me, right? Like make that the size of my oven and that's
Speaker 3:  what I want. I want to open it up, I wanna put it in and I wanna have the
Speaker 3:  Oven know what to do. Yes. And that seems like
Speaker 3:  where we should be headed. But you haven't once mentioned one of
Speaker 3:  these little mini all in one smart ovens. No. And it does sort of feel like
Speaker 3:  a dying thing.
Speaker 4:  Literally. I mean the June is literally dead, which is very sad. That's
Speaker 3:  Right. Just recently, right?
Speaker 4:  Just recently like unofficially confirmed that they're not gonna make
Speaker 4:  another one and you can't buy one. And when I remodeled my kitchen, I didn't
Speaker 4:  have the space, but my ideal had been to do built-ins and to
Speaker 4:  build in two dune ovens. That was what? Oh, that's funny. But
Speaker 4:  you can't do that. They're not June oven never made that capability. It has
Speaker 4:  to be a Countertop oven. There is no smart builtin oven that I
Speaker 4:  was able to buy when I remodeled my kitchen. I know Samsung now has one and
Speaker 4:  I think there's actually this last week at the kitchen and bath
Speaker 4:  industry show, I think there was quite a lot being shown off in this space.
Speaker 4:  But those are also a level above price wise and
Speaker 4:  feature wise. But yeah, I, that's, I could imagine, you know, a big
Speaker 4:  range with like four compartments that could do all these different
Speaker 4:  things, have these different functions. And also I want my stove top to,
Speaker 4:  to be smart, I want my stove top to be able to tell me when the water's boiled
Speaker 4:  over and turn itself off. And you know, there's so many features that
Speaker 4:  I feel like we could just put all into one big
Speaker 4:  appliance in our kitchen and not have to have all of these small
Speaker 4:  Countertop pieces as as much fun as they are and useful as they are. We just
Speaker 4:  don't have the space for them. All the outlets. I run out of outlets very
Speaker 4:  quickly.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Oh no, I, I absolutely feel that I have, I bought a milk frother
Speaker 3:  and which is a ridiculous thing to own. And I pay for said
Speaker 3:  ridiculousness every time I wanna use it because I have to unplug, unplug
Speaker 3:  something some other appliance in order to plug in the milk frother. That
Speaker 3:  is
Speaker 4:  Actually the my favorite smart kitchen device that we haven't even talked
Speaker 4:  about is my, I do have a smart coffee maker and that again, is a space that
Speaker 4:  hasn't really taken off. There was one Bosch showed one off at CES this
Speaker 4:  year that you could, could actually, the first time you could use voice control
Speaker 4:  on a Countertop coffee maker. So you could say, Hey, Amazon's a
Speaker 4:  make me an espresso. And you know, that is the dream. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  you've been able to do it with the really, really expensive fancy built-in
Speaker 4:  ones. But I have a GE profile little
Speaker 4:  espresso maker and it, it's smart in that I can customize my
Speaker 4:  cup but I can't talk to it. And this would be a great device
Speaker 4:  for our built-in voice assistant. I think one day, one day I can walk
Speaker 4:  into the kitchen and just be like, geez, make me a coffee.
Speaker 3:  It's the dream. And that is another one that is kind of a little
Speaker 3:  tiny closed ecosystem. Yeah. And you could see how it would work. And I think
Speaker 3:  I, I know a lot of folks who bought the very sort of simple timer coffee
Speaker 3:  maker and it's like you put the beans in at night and you say at six 30 Yeah,
Speaker 3:  broom me some coffee. And that is, that's a thing you can do and it actually
Speaker 3:  works pretty well and I think it's very cool. If, you
Speaker 4:  Remember to set it well, right?
Speaker 3:  It's, it's like turning your oven to remote control, right? You have to,
Speaker 3:  you have to do that one bit of thing. But again, it's the same thing as meal
Speaker 3:  planning. Jen, just that one added tiny bit of
Speaker 3:  proactivity in my life and I would be a better, happier person. Well
Speaker 4:  That, that really gets to the heart of my kind of overall takeaway here was
Speaker 4:  that while I found that like the meal planning was easier and helped
Speaker 4:  expand my repertoire and kind of it break me out the cooking route that
Speaker 4:  you mentioned and you know, I spent a lot more time cooking
Speaker 4:  and I, you know, I felt good about cooking for my family as opposed to buying
Speaker 4:  pizza. I didn't feel it was sustainable though. Like when I went
Speaker 4:  to the next weekend, so to sit down and meal
Speaker 4:  plan again, I was like, whew, this is a lot of work.
Speaker 4:  And then So, what I came down to at the end is that right now
Speaker 4:  I'm the connective tissue of my smart kitchen. I'm the, the diff i I'm
Speaker 4:  the connection between the apps, the voice control, the appliances, the grocery
Speaker 4:  store. I need something to come in and, and help
Speaker 4:  fill some of those roles. You know, ultimately, you know, the Rosie the
Speaker 4:  robot, I know we're a few years away from that or the robotic arms to do
Speaker 4:  some of the work. But I also feel like, and this is something that Ben and
Speaker 4:  Nick talked to a bit in our last interview with them, is that this is probably
Speaker 4:  where generative AI is really gonna come in and kind of move the needle
Speaker 4:  on the smart kitchen in terms of helping pull all those pieces and parts
Speaker 4:  together and taking some of that mental load away from you. And then combined
Speaker 4:  with the interoperability, we're beginning to see between appliances
Speaker 4:  with the home connectivity alliance matter and what Fresco's doing with
Speaker 4:  its app. And I know I say this all the time, but we are so close.
Speaker 3:  Don't say matter, Chad, don't do it. Don't do it.
Speaker 4:  We are close. Oh, we're close. We're, we're a lot closer than we were 10
Speaker 4:  years ago. I just feel like we didn't take as much, there hasn't been as
Speaker 4:  much movement in the last decade as I had genuinely
Speaker 4:  hoped there would be. I put off redoing my smart kitchen, my kitchen
Speaker 4:  as long as I possibly could.
Speaker 3:  Is there anything that came outta this that you learned that you're like,
Speaker 3:  okay, I will actually pull this back into my real life as a real
Speaker 3:  person? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I, I do think I will keep, I will keep using the The Samsung Food
Speaker 4:  app. I did actually find that useful and I actually used my
Speaker 4:  smart fridges screen much more in the last week than I have in the
Speaker 4:  entire five years that I've had it. Okay. So using the
Speaker 4:  screen here on my fridge has actually been very
Speaker 4:  handy for cooking this recipe. I can see the entirety
Speaker 4:  of the ingredients on one screen and it stays on
Speaker 4:  unlike my phone or iPad, which keeps locking itself. So, I have to keep
Speaker 4:  pressing, putting my code in or trying to get my face in the right angle.
Speaker 4:  I will, my next recipe, I'm gonna try one of the smart displays because
Speaker 4:  for memory those will stay fixed while you're following a
Speaker 4:  recipe and they can call out the steps to you. Whereas for the fridge
Speaker 4:  I had to keep coming back and checking. But it worked pretty well. It
Speaker 4:  was useful on that big screen. And it does make me think, and this is
Speaker 4:  something that Ben discussed last week, that ultimately we do need a
Speaker 4:  central kitchen interface. Maybe that's one of those things that
Speaker 4:  could replace the, the connective tissue that I mentioned about a,
Speaker 4:  a, a central sort of dashboard for your smart kitchen. Once we have the
Speaker 4:  interoperability and once we have maybe some, the generative AI
Speaker 4:  being able to help with a lot of these tasks, having one central dashboard
Speaker 4:  where you can control all of your appliances. Read your recipes. Yes.
Speaker 4:  What watch TikTok when you're waiting for that timer to finish. I do feel
Speaker 4:  like that is something we are, we are gonna need. I felt like we moved away
Speaker 4:  from it because everyone was like, this is a bad idea but
Speaker 4:  I don't see another solution yet. So
Speaker 3:  Here's my question about that though is, is that a screen
Speaker 3:  built into one of your appliances and in that case I think the fridge is
Speaker 3:  very natural, right? Like one thing you and I agree on is that the TV as
Speaker 3:  a center of a smart home is a really interesting, powerful thing because
Speaker 3:  it's this giant screen in the middle of your home that can
Speaker 3:  do a lot of stuff and I think the kitchen, that's the fridge, right? That
Speaker 3:  is the thing. It is, it is always within arms reach as you're in the kitchen.
Speaker 3:  Unless you have a weird kitchen, it's just huge. It's right there. It makes
Speaker 3:  a lot of sense that the fridge would be the thing. And yet I wanna upgrade
Speaker 3:  most of my screens a lot more often than I wanna upgrade my kitchen. So my
Speaker 3:  question is, is that some appliance maker who will build that thing or
Speaker 3:  is that an iPad or a Pixel tablet? I mean Google made the pixel
Speaker 3:  tablet like pretty clearly as a smart home thing and you just reviewed
Speaker 3:  Amazon's Echo hub, which is very much after the same thing. Like is this
Speaker 3:  a whole category of device that a kitchen maker
Speaker 3:  needs to figure out? Or is this just a tablet that understands my kitchen?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, I actually, when I was reviewing the Echo Hub, I did try and put
Speaker 4:  it on the wall in my kitchen because it did feel like it would be a, a great
Speaker 4:  device to have in the kitchen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Stick a magnet on that thing. Yeah, put it right on the fridge. I love
Speaker 3:  it. So
Speaker 4:  Samsung's in a unique position because it's an electronics company and an
Speaker 4:  appliance manufacturer. So it kind of had it, it was in a good position
Speaker 4:  to do this and they've done a good job with it and they've iterated.
Speaker 4:  But I agree that the idea of having
Speaker 4:  one screen that you rely on to run your entire kitchen in your appliance
Speaker 4:  is kind of a scary one. But on the flip side would be
Speaker 4:  small screens in every appliance, which is actually what Samsung's doing
Speaker 4:  and they showed at CES and that that those screens all communicate with each
Speaker 4:  other. So you're not dealing with a nude interface every time you
Speaker 4:  move around the kitchen. So you can, but you do have to have all smart things
Speaker 4:  appliances or or Samsung appliances.
Speaker 3:  I kind of hate that outcome. Yeah. I'm not gonna lie. Yeah. This idea of
Speaker 3:  everything has its own little screen and touch universe is not what I'm after.
Speaker 4:  I don't know that an iPad is a solution either I don't, you know,
Speaker 4:  something that's portable is gonna walk out of the kitchen,
Speaker 3:  Right, true. Or it's battery dies or whatever.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think something that is permanently in the kitchen
Speaker 4:  but that is upgradable and swappable is where we will probably get
Speaker 4:  to rather than it being in appliances. Because once you have interoperability
Speaker 4:  once matter and the Home Connectivity Alliance brings everything
Speaker 4:  hopefully to a point where all your appliances can talk to each other,
Speaker 4:  then you don't need a proprietary tablet in your fridge. You can
Speaker 4:  use any device and I think we might start to see people kind of fill this
Speaker 4:  niche and come up with dedicated sort of kitchen smart home
Speaker 4:  control panels. And that's what I felt like I needed actually this this
Speaker 4:  last week was just that extra interface where everything, all,
Speaker 4:  everything was worked together in one space and I didn't have to kind of
Speaker 4:  run around and deal with lots of different appliances.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And especially if I can have that thing without worrying about
Speaker 3:  getting flour and olive oil all over my very expensive iPad.
Speaker 3:  Now we're now we're talking, I'm into that. What about the software side
Speaker 3:  of this before we go, we should talk about this. You mentioned, so Samsung
Speaker 3:  food as an app that you have used and liked. I think one of the
Speaker 3:  challenges of the Smart Kitchen is that it demands, you have a
Speaker 3:  home screen full of apps to control all of your individual things.
Speaker 3:  But did you find anything that A, either does a good job of putting
Speaker 3:  that stuff together or B just feels like awesome smart Kitchen
Speaker 3:  software that everybody should know about?
Speaker 4:  So this, I did enjoy The Samsung Food app. I did not enjoy the ads. Lots
Speaker 4:  of ads you can pay to get rid of them. I do feel like the
Speaker 4:  Fresco's Kitchen os is probably our best experience I had and
Speaker 4:  I had two experiences with that one. We talked about the guided recipe, which
Speaker 4:  was, which was really useful. And that works with any recipe that
Speaker 4:  it, that you can import into The Fresco app and then it sort of strips it
Speaker 4:  and does the whole process of turning it into a guided recipe for you,
Speaker 4:  which was useful. But what Fresco does with its kitchen
Speaker 4:  os is it uses its interface in appliance
Speaker 4:  manufacturers apps. And in my two to
Speaker 4:  five years of testing smart kitchen appliances, I have yet to come across
Speaker 4:  a Smart Appliance kitchen, a smart kitchen appliances app
Speaker 4:  that is any good. They are all useless,
Speaker 4:  they're badly laid out, they don't have good interfaces, they're
Speaker 4:  hard to understand. And so what Fresco's doing with its kitchen os is trying
Speaker 4:  to make that a uniform experience no matter what device
Speaker 4:  you're using. It uses the same interface. And that's a huge
Speaker 4:  step forward I think in the smart kitchen because as it is, most of our
Speaker 4:  appliances have confusing interfaces. Like I still haven't figured out how
Speaker 4:  to use 80% of what my microwave can do because I don't know, I,
Speaker 4:  the the touch panel, it's not touch panel. It's, it's a beep beep beep panel
Speaker 4:  and it's not intuitive. So yeah, I I really, I was impressed.
Speaker 4:  I used the Kitchen os interface in the Instapot app
Speaker 4:  and it was, it was, it definitely gave me a feeling of like, okay,
Speaker 4:  someone has solved this, let's just hope more manufacturers
Speaker 4:  will use this and put it into their apps rather than trying to come
Speaker 4:  up and reinvent the wheel every time. Because that's where we end up with
Speaker 4:  it's complicated and confusing and I just don't wanna use an app anymore.
Speaker 4:  I just gonna go press the button on the device and probably set it
Speaker 4:  wrong and burn my toast.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I, I like the idea of thinking about how do we make
Speaker 3:  it so that you are less the connective tissue of the smart kitchen
Speaker 3:  because the individual things are getting smarter and I think, I mean this
Speaker 3:  is why I'm, I'm glad we had Ben on last week to talk about kind of what it
Speaker 3:  means to unify all this stuff across systems and
Speaker 3:  they're very bullish on AI as the solution and we'll see about that.
Speaker 3:  I have a lot of feelings about generative AI as the solution to everything,
Speaker 3:  but yeah, I, I have really come to believe that relying on appliance
Speaker 3:  manufacturers to build great software is just not going to work. Nope. And
Speaker 3:  that's okay. Their job is not to build great software. Their job is to build
Speaker 3:  washing machines Yes. And blenders and that's good
Speaker 3:  and fine. Yes. And what we need is the layer that comes in and
Speaker 3:  I feel like we've spent the last decade getting a lot of versions of that
Speaker 3:  layer that haven't really worked. And whether it's Matter or Kitchen
Speaker 3:  os or something else, it does feel like everyone at least knows
Speaker 3:  that's the thing now. And that's where we unlock a lot of what
Speaker 3:  comes next in the Smart kitchen
Speaker 4:  For sure. We just need to bring it all together and the Smart Fridge needs
Speaker 4:  to move beyond just Samsung too. Like they've done a great job here.
Speaker 4:  It didn't start out well, but it's getting better and you
Speaker 4:  got, you know, they've persevered. LG just kind of stopped
Speaker 4:  with smart fridges and Well, cool. And GE,
Speaker 4:  I you know, we, I just haven't seen much innovation in this sort of smart
Speaker 4:  kitchen space for cooking. And there's been a lot of innovation in technology,
Speaker 4:  just not in making it a seamless experience the way
Speaker 4:  we've been talking about it. And, you know, we need a fridge that can tell
Speaker 4:  us what food we have and what's gonna exp when it's gonna expire, what you
Speaker 4:  need to buy. Because, you know, that doesn't, that's not just about convenience,
Speaker 4:  but it solves a huge issue around food waste. And as we talked about healthy
Speaker 4:  eating, there's just so, there's so much potential there. And I
Speaker 4:  just feel like the other appliance manufacturers do kind of need to step
Speaker 4:  up here. 'cause not everyone's gonna buy the Samsung Smart Fridge.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We, we talk a lot on this show about like the increasingly boring
Speaker 3:  state of smartphones. Like phones are becoming appliances. Like let's,
Speaker 3:  let's make appliances, gadgets again. you know what I mean? Yes.
Speaker 4:  Let's, I like it.
Speaker 3:  I want Tim Cook to be on stage in three years being like, we've done it,
Speaker 3:  we've made the Apple Fridge. And everybody's like, oh my God. Like, that's,
Speaker 3:  that's what we're going for. Jen. These are the rules. All right.
Speaker 3:  We gotta get outta here. Jen, this has been a pleasure. Thank you for going
Speaker 3:  through this insane process for our pleasure. I
Speaker 3:  I, I apologize to you and your family.
Speaker 4:  Oh, they loved it. They got to eat all the food.
Speaker 3:  They got ramen, they got pork belly every, everybody wins. Alright,
Speaker 3:  well as always, it's a pleasure to have you here. Thank you for doing this
Speaker 3:  with us.
Speaker 4:  Thanks so much, David. It's been fun an experience.
Speaker 3:  That's it for The Vergecast today. And that is it for our miniseries about
Speaker 3:  the Smart Kitchen. If, you didn't catch the first episode. Please do. It's
Speaker 3:  a couple episodes back in the feed. We had a ton of fun. It's a really great
Speaker 3:  episode. Thanks so much to Jen for doing this with us. And thanks to everybody
Speaker 3:  who has helped us make this and participated and dealt with all of Jen's
Speaker 3:  troubleshooting over the last couple of weeks in the Smart Kitchen. There
Speaker 3:  is tons more on all of our Smart Home coverage. Smart Home Week is
Speaker 3:  happening on The Verge dot com. Tons of great stories, tons of good stuff
Speaker 3:  going on. We'll put some Links in the show notes, but also check the website.
Speaker 3:  Lots of good stuff coming. As always, If you have thoughts or questions or
Speaker 3:  feelings or gadgets that you think Jen should try and incorporate into her
Speaker 3:  life and we can make her life very complicated as a result. Always get in
Speaker 3:  touch. Email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline. Eight six six
Speaker 3:  VERGE one one. we love hearing from you. This series has been fun. I think
Speaker 3:  we're gonna do more like it in The future, so keep your ideas coming. This
Speaker 3:  show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Will pour The. Vergecast
Speaker 3:  is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We will be
Speaker 3:  back with regularly scheduled programming on Tuesday and Friday, and we have
Speaker 3:  a big show coming up at South by Southwest. Lots of fun stuff coming up.
Speaker 3:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll.