# Transcript
ID: 9dafd27c-1fbc-473d-9230-158bf36bbdb0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6155755077619046190/255370180714847303/s93290-US-5684s-1722623394.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Allison Johnson, and Victoria Song discuss Apple iOS 18.1 beta. upcoming Pixel 9 rumors, Olympics coverage, AI deepfake regulation, and more.
Speaker 3:  for good reason I think. So we're just gonna see what happens. Thank you
Speaker 3:  too for, for joining me.
Speaker 2:  We're here for the ride. I'm here for Saturday Samsung
Speaker 2:  as the, as the local Korean gadget reviewer on staff.
Speaker 2:  I am so here for Saturday Samsung.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna get to what the Saturday Samsung is This I would say,
Speaker 3:  you know, up until now it's been, there's stuff Samsung will give you a free
Speaker 3:  TV if you buy a TV is a real idea generated by Saturday
Speaker 3:  Samsung. This week's is, I think bananas in a different
Speaker 3:  way, but we'll, we'll come to it. There's a bunch of other stuff going on.
Speaker 3:  The iOS 18.1 developer beta with Apple Intelligence, some
Speaker 3:  Apple Intelligence features hit Allison, you played with that V you
Speaker 3:  reviewed the Galaxy Watch Ultra, or as I call it the Apple Watch Ultra.
Speaker 3:  There's some other gadget news. There's a Pixel nine event coming up.
Speaker 3:  We caused an entire furious news cycle about subscription
Speaker 3:  mice. I'm sorry. And then because we have been devices,
Speaker 3:  I am trying a new style of lightning round. Still unsponsored,
Speaker 3:  but it's, you know, get honest, David, David, David and Liam are not around
Speaker 3:  to put me in a box. So we're gonna, we're gonna try something new.
Speaker 2:  Chaos.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's chaos. Chaos. I wanna start with, we should just call it
Speaker 3:  the cast run, although I think, so one of the topics is a little serious,
Speaker 3:  so I dunno if we, oh, we'll get there. We're, we're gonna get there. We're
Speaker 3:  doing it live. Everybody.
Speaker 3:  Let's start with, there's big news in the week just outside of tech. It's
Speaker 3:  the Olympics. It feels like the
Speaker 3:  experience of watching consuming the Olympics is very
Speaker 3:  different this year than in years past. Every other year we run a story that's
Speaker 3:  like streaming the Olympics sucks. We haven't really had to run that story
Speaker 3:  this year. It's
Speaker 2:  'cause it's on TikTok baby. I have not streamed
Speaker 2:  a single second of the Olympics. I'm telling you, I have not streamed a single
Speaker 2:  second of the Olympics. Normally I am all over the gymnastics, but everything
Speaker 2:  I know about the Olympics has just come through doom, doom. Scrolling my
Speaker 2:  TikTok feed and just going like, oh actually that's kind of really
Speaker 2:  wholesome. I really love chocolate muffin guy and yeah,
Speaker 2:  can't remember his name.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Explaining Chocolate muffin guy. This is a foreign
Speaker 4:  concept to me.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's just this Norwegian athlete who has discovered the chocolate
Speaker 2:  muffin from the Olympic Village cafeteria
Speaker 2:  and he gets increasingly weird with this chocolate muffin. It just like
Speaker 2:  appears in his bedroom and he's in a thong and you're like, what is happening?
Speaker 2:  But, oh, that's what I'm saying. She really loves
Speaker 2:  this chocolate muffin.
Speaker 3:  You know what's happening. That's true.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Jim trying TikTok is a weird way to feel about America right
Speaker 3:  now. This is hard to know how much American pride you have, depending on
Speaker 3:  what TikTok scroll you're in. Like at this moment it's like I have
Speaker 3:  immense pride in our gymnasts who've crushed it. Once again.
Speaker 3:  Oh no, he's talking again. I have immense pride in this. Like it's
Speaker 3:  what is happening. That's a lot. We have an entire story about
Speaker 3:  the Olympics in TikTok. Mia wrote it. I actually wanted the title
Speaker 3:  to be the Influencer Olympics,
Speaker 3:  but I think that's what people think. That's Coachella.
Speaker 2:  So
Speaker 3:  Both
Speaker 2:  Are fair, but it's true.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I thought, I thought it was good pun. But it is true that the athletes
Speaker 3:  are young by and large, very young. Except for the 51-year-old Turkish man
Speaker 3:  who got a silver medal in shooting with no equipment whatsoever. Great photo.
Speaker 3:  But it's true that the athletes are by and large, very young. The US
Speaker 3:  women's gymnastics team, literally after winning gold was caught on camera
Speaker 3:  talking about what TikTok they wanted to make. Oh yeah. Which is
Speaker 3:  incredible. Aw. And so you just have this like very native
Speaker 3:  population to this format in this platform in particular.
Speaker 3:  And then there's just the universe of piracy that happens on TikTok. Like
Speaker 3:  if you wanna watch clips of cool sporting events, the TikTok community
Speaker 3:  has you covered. And tiktoks lawyers also apparently have you covered
Speaker 3:  because they don't seem to care about it. And that's like one really
Speaker 3:  interesting way of consuming this, right? You're getting kind of the raw
Speaker 3:  feed by people who are on the ground who speak in the language of video speaking,
Speaker 3:  the language of social video. And then you're getting a bunch of clips of
Speaker 3:  cool stuff curated by a community that does not care about
Speaker 3:  NBC's exclusive rights to stream
Speaker 2:  Pick on TikTok. What I'll say is the commentary on TikTok is much
Speaker 2:  funnier because you just have people filming their screen while
Speaker 2:  they're watching it. Like the, the men's gymnast pommel horse guy, I, I don't
Speaker 2:  know any of these athletes names. I know them by their memes on TikTok. But
Speaker 2:  just like I was watching these two women watching Paul Pommel Horse Guy and
Speaker 2:  they're like, yes, yes Peter Parker. Yes, you better
Speaker 2:  work. You better work. And just having this very sassy
Speaker 2:  commentary about this man doing the pommel horse. And I was just
Speaker 2:  like, this is, I am watching them watch their TV
Speaker 2:  screen and they're just better than like the NBC
Speaker 2:  commentary people who are just like, oh yes, he's on the pommel horse. And
Speaker 2:  he did the skill. Oh so serious. USA so
Speaker 2:  serious. It's like, it's like watching it with your friends except my, my
Speaker 2:  husband doesn't give a crap about the Olympics, so I'm just like, same like
Speaker 2:  yeah, pommel horse guy You can get it. Clark Kent of
Speaker 2:  Pommel horse.
Speaker 3:  So I often say that almost every experience I have with TikTok
Speaker 3:  should be a PhD in media studies. What you are describing as a PhD
Speaker 3:  in media studies, right? Like the layers of abstraction away from the thing
Speaker 3:  itself happening and then the entertainment that random strangers in the
Speaker 3:  internet are providing you. The all of that is just very different. and it
Speaker 3:  feels new this time in a way that two years ago,
Speaker 3:  basic three years ago at the last Olympics,
Speaker 3:  it was it two years ago or three years ago? The last Olympics were freshman
Speaker 2:  Three. They were in 2021 because of, you know,
Speaker 4:  Covid Oh, events. Yeah. Yeah. That's what the Olympics just
Speaker 4:  has always felt to me. Like this big serious important
Speaker 4:  thing And like that's kind of part of the appeal. But there's something great
Speaker 4:  about like yeah, having it kind of distributed among
Speaker 4:  like, you know, from people on the ground and having more fun
Speaker 4:  with it. Like it doesn't have to be this like big booming voice of like
Speaker 4:  NBC will deliver you the Olympics and that is how you will watch them.
Speaker 3:  Right? If you put 18,000 teenagers in the middle of France with cell phones,
Speaker 3:  like something funny is gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. That's it. That, that seems correct.
Speaker 2:  You just learn more about different sports. 'cause I don't care about rugby.
Speaker 2:  I love alone Amar, she's hilarious on TikTok. She's just all
Speaker 2:  over my entire feed. Yesterday was just lesbians crying
Speaker 2:  that alone a Marv was not a lesbian because they were just like
Speaker 2:  in love with the women's rugby team. And I was like, and that'll be it
Speaker 3:  For chaos Forecast everybody.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna end it here. No, I mean, but that right. The idea that different
Speaker 3:  communities, different groups can view the thing
Speaker 3:  together in a different way as a community is new. Like that just is a new
Speaker 3:  thing that even like sports Twitter doesn't accomplish,
Speaker 3:  right? It's, it's the native video communication
Speaker 3:  ability of particularly the younger generation that like is interesting and
Speaker 3:  new. And that's one thing that's different about these Olympics. The
Speaker 3:  other thing that's different is that actually NBC and Peacock are doing a
Speaker 3:  good job. I must disclose that NBC is a minority
Speaker 3:  investor in Vox mania apparent company. They're owned by Comcast. I've
Speaker 3:  rarely said anything good about Comcast, so I must disclose, I'm saying something
Speaker 3:  nice about Comcast NBC. That's the first time I believe in history
Speaker 3:  that that has happened. But they are doing a good job. It is actually like
Speaker 3:  refreshing and interesting to see a big
Speaker 3:  legacy broadcaster just go for it with her app.
Speaker 3:  And it's not saying there's not problems there. Random ad breaks in the
Speaker 3:  middle of stuff. There's infinite complaints about just how overwhelming
Speaker 3:  it is. But it's like ev they had, they had every idea
Speaker 3:  and executed every idea. So if you want to just watch
Speaker 3:  highlights of the sports You can just watch highlights of the sports. If
Speaker 3:  you wanna watch the traditional gauzy 1980 style
Speaker 3:  primetime broadcast with completely unnecessary human interest
Speaker 3:  interludes about how the gymnasts grew up, knowing they would be gymnasts.
Speaker 3:  Those stories are always the same. It's like when they were four, they're
Speaker 3:  like, I'm gonna jump on stuff every, every four years. You can get that story
Speaker 3:  from NBC if you want, but that's available to you. They have the Gold Zone,
Speaker 3:  which is basically NFL red zone for the Olympics that they're doing 10 hours
Speaker 3:  a day. And inside of the app when you're watching stuff, You can just be
Speaker 3:  like, I just wanna keep watching this thing that we're whipping around to,
Speaker 3:  which is fascinating. They have multi-view, which is the more standard,
Speaker 3:  just like, here's four feeds at once. They have Al Michaels doing
Speaker 3:  AI powered highlights that You can just listen
Speaker 4:  To. Oh, okay. Which
Speaker 3:  Is super weird. Like it's just weird to have Robot
Speaker 3:  Al Michaels being like the gymnast trumped over stuff again. But they,
Speaker 3:  it's like all the ideas. I had someone in my mentions, 'cause I, I was
Speaker 3:  posting on threads and they're like, all of this is stuff that a normal company
Speaker 3:  would like de-scope to hit the deadline. And N BBC just
Speaker 3:  like did it all. And then on top of it they're like, do all of, it's like
Speaker 3:  pretty good, like Gold Zone is actually really funny. Do you, there's like
Speaker 3:  very funny NFL trauma inside of Gold Zone.
Speaker 3:  So you know, there's Red Zone where, where you like whip around all the games
Speaker 3:  on Sundays and there there used to be two Red Zones. There was the one on
Speaker 3:  DirecTV and there was the one that the NFL did Google bought the
Speaker 3:  rights to Sunday ticket. They took the NFL Red Zone and they shut down the
Speaker 3:  DirecTV red zone. So Scott Hanson, who does the NFL Red Zone
Speaker 3:  is like gonna do it with Google. Now, NBC realized they can't just
Speaker 3:  have Scott Hanson 10 hours a day, 16 days
Speaker 3:  in a row. So they hire Scott Hanson and the guy who used to do the
Speaker 3:  DirecTV Red Zone to do Gold Zone. So they're like back together. Not his
Speaker 3:  rivals, but his friends like all, it's like hilarious that they did
Speaker 3:  that. This
Speaker 4:  This is a PhD. This is a PhD.
Speaker 3:  But they had to do it like somebody at N BBC had to be like, all right, let's
Speaker 3:  like, let's do a red zone for Olympics. How will we do that? We should just
Speaker 3:  get all the red zone guys.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And like go get some contracts together, like make it happen. and it all
Speaker 3:  is kind of working like it's working better than if
Speaker 3:  I suggested to you NBC was gonna make an app full of
Speaker 3:  Olympics content, your expectations would be very low.
Speaker 3:  And it's called Peacock. But they're actually doing, they're doing good.
Speaker 4:  I love that. I'm an Olympic lover. Yeah, I love that. You know, are you
Speaker 3:  Watching a peacock or are you, are you like full TikTok?
Speaker 4:  So I am, I have to put an asterisk that like I'm a Winter Olympics
Speaker 4:  girl. Mm. And I, I don't know what it is this year, but I've been like
Speaker 4:  shouted down by the Summer Olympics people about how the Winter Olympics
Speaker 4:  is not the real Olympics. And I, I think I just like got tired of it. So
Speaker 4:  I I've kind of been missing out on, on this year's games.
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 2:  Can't, there's, there's Snoop Dogg, like between
Speaker 4:  Everything I'm getting NBC and
Speaker 2:  Decision to have Snoop do and Flava Flav here. I'm like, this
Speaker 3:  Is what I mean by NBC just went like somewhat NBC is like, I'm, is there
Speaker 3:  a Snoop Dogg budget? And they're like, yes. In addition to that there's Flava
Speaker 3:  Flav budget. Like they just like went for it. It's great.
Speaker 3:  I would, you should click around them people, it's like actually like fairly
Speaker 3:  entertaining just as a tech experience to be like, oh,
Speaker 3:  they like tried this out. Like what if this was all happening? You can
Speaker 3:  kind of see there's news this week that venue sports, which is the big mashup
Speaker 3:  of Disney and Fox and everything
Speaker 3:  ESPN, they're gonna price it like $43 a month, which is
Speaker 3:  crazy. and it's like, what would you get that
Speaker 2:  That's Peloton money.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Only you sit around. So it actually might be worth $50 a month,
Speaker 3:  but it's kind of like, oh, this is the bar. Like if you want to be anywhere
Speaker 3:  close to that much money, you've gotta deliver a a user experience
Speaker 3:  that is at least this good. Because if it's just a, well, if it's just like
Speaker 3:  a minimum viable product list of things, like no, no one's
Speaker 3:  gonna pay the money. All right. So that's, that's the Olympics. It's going
Speaker 3:  on. I'm curious how people are watching it. Send us a note, you know, there's,
Speaker 3:  there's more time left in it. One thing I'll say is it doesn't seem like
Speaker 3:  the action is on Twitter the way it is with other live sports. Yeah, it is
Speaker 3:  on TikTok and that I'm, there's something happened in there that I think
Speaker 3:  is just fascinating. All right. We should talk about IO S 18.
Speaker 3:  Allison, you got to play, you played with iOS 18.1, which is the developer
Speaker 3:  beta, not the public beta yet, but I think that is getting pretty blurry
Speaker 3:  in that everyone is playing with it. I mean, no one was gonna stay away from
Speaker 3:  Apple Intelligence. Well you played with it. What do you think?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it's interesting. I think my kind of big takeaway
Speaker 4:  is like, well you get, you get the like visuals of the new Siri,
Speaker 4:  the like glowing border and You can type to talk to Siri.
Speaker 4:  And there's a couple things that are new about Siri that like, it
Speaker 4:  follows context better like between questions, which like
Speaker 4:  Google Assistant has been doing for a little while now. But,
Speaker 4:  so that's kinda like setting the stage and there's these other
Speaker 4:  little things throughout the UI that are like,
Speaker 4:  when and if it all gets put together like that is,
Speaker 4:  that could be really cool. But right now it's just kind of like
Speaker 4:  Siri lights up and then You can rewrite an email and
Speaker 4:  you'll get email summaries in your inbox. and it was just especially
Speaker 4:  funny like when you open the mail
Speaker 4:  app instead of the, like each, you know, email has
Speaker 4:  the first couple lines of the actual email copy. There's just a little summary
Speaker 4:  now and that makes a lot of sense for like a long email. But
Speaker 4:  most of my emails are garbage like promo stuff. So it
Speaker 4:  just summarizes the promotional stuff and it's like
Speaker 4:  lunchbox is ship free and I'm like,
Speaker 3:  Hmm.
Speaker 4:  Didn't need a summary of that, but thank you.
Speaker 3:  That is very much like what's happening with gr and trending topics
Speaker 3:  on Twitter now.
Speaker 4:  Oh no. Where
Speaker 3:  Like the AI just doesn't know that some things are jokes and so the, the
Speaker 3:  trending topics are like when I turn black in
Speaker 3:  relation to like people tweeting about Trump talking about Kamala Harris
Speaker 3:  and it's like, no that's not, that's not right. That's not, that's not what
Speaker 3:  people mean. That's just
Speaker 4:  A joke. Yeah, you didn't get it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  AI is just so sincere about stuff that it just like, it's
Speaker 4:  funny. We have to laugh about it
Speaker 3:  I guess. So are those the only features that are out yet? It's the summarizing
Speaker 3:  emails and rewriting,
Speaker 4:  Summarizing.
Speaker 3:  I've seen a lot of pictures of people intentionally writing very mean
Speaker 3:  notes and trying to get the AI to make them nicer, which is fascinating.
Speaker 4:  Oh, the one I did, you know, at the end of Willy
Speaker 4:  Wonka when Gene Wilder does that like fizzy lifting drink thing,
Speaker 4:  like you stole fizzy lifting drinks. Yeah. I put that into a note and
Speaker 4:  rewrite it like friendly and it was like, hey, just just so
Speaker 4:  you know, you can't be stealing fizzy lifting drinks.
Speaker 4:  That's just as far as I got without very amusing to me
Speaker 4:  personally.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's, there's little bits and bobs here and there that are
Speaker 4:  escaping me at the moment. It's in the emails. No photos in
Speaker 4:  the photos app. You can use like natural language search. So You can
Speaker 4:  be like, you know, you could search for like food before or
Speaker 4:  someone that you've tagged in your photos, but
Speaker 4:  You can be like this person wearing glasses or food we ate in
Speaker 4:  Iceland and it's like pretty good and it comes up with that
Speaker 4:  stuff. So just getting a step closer to like,
Speaker 4:  I just search for my license plate 'cause I can never
Speaker 4:  remember.
Speaker 2:  So like I have this one picture of a chicken that I saw while walking down
Speaker 2:  a street in Brooklyn. So would I just be able and I can never, like
Speaker 2:  no one believes me when I told 'em I ran into a chicken on a sidewalk in
Speaker 2:  Brooklyn. I
Speaker 3:  Don't believe you now
Speaker 2:  I only
Speaker 4:  Have have to see it, only have
Speaker 2:  One photo of it. So would I be able to go to like the photos app and be like,
Speaker 2:  find me the photo of the chicken walking on a sidewalker for in Brooklyn?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. With my foot in there.
Speaker 4:  I think that's the most important use case of ai like
Speaker 4:  at all.
Speaker 3:  Or it will just generate that photo for you and you'll be able to
Speaker 4:  Lie to us. Yeah, You can put a chicken on the sidewalk and then tell people
Speaker 4:  that you saw it and be a liar.
Speaker 3:  So when we saw WWC of iOS 18 was AI
Speaker 3:  everywhere and every app in every corner, it's just gonna make the
Speaker 3:  phone better. And then that was like a one
Speaker 3:  set of ideas. And then the other idea was, and then Siri will become your
Speaker 3:  all-knowing assistant. Is that the experience of 18.1
Speaker 3:  in the beta right now?
Speaker 4:  Not yet. It's like, yeah, it's just little Easter eggs kind of
Speaker 4:  threw out and then the, the thing that is missing from Siri is like
Speaker 4:  the, the big stuff where it's like it under the ai, the the
Speaker 4:  intelligence and the AI I think. Yeah, no the like
Speaker 4:  it'll understand what's on your screen and You can ask for it. You know,
Speaker 4:  You can be like, email this photo to my mom and it'll just go
Speaker 4:  do it for you. Like that is the stuff that's coming. And then the the
Speaker 4:  third party app stuff, 'cause developers are gonna be able to hook into
Speaker 4:  it and, and let you do series stuff in their apps
Speaker 4:  and that's the, the AI dream on our phones.
Speaker 4:  And that's still the like no, it's coming 'cause people
Speaker 4:  have to develop it
Speaker 3:  Is the Well they changed the user experience of of Siri, right? So now when
Speaker 3:  you open it, it like flashes the thing You can, like You can type to it
Speaker 3:  now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You double the tap. You've always
Speaker 2:  Been able to
Speaker 4:  This, I learned this and I didn't know it. V what's the,
Speaker 4:  how do you do this?
Speaker 2:  Oh it's, it's, it's an accessibility feature where You can type to Siri.
Speaker 2:  So You can do it even if you don't have the beta. I just think it looks a
Speaker 2:  lot prettier in the beta because yeah, this is another example of them
Speaker 2:  going like, oh, accessibility features. Actually they work for everybody.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Why don't we just like shine them up and make them useful.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. Make it glow.
Speaker 3:  It is, it is actually really interesting how many accessibility features
Speaker 3:  have just made their way into the main Apple Pinch, pinch operating systems.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Andy Pinch there. There's other ones but tap to type to series
Speaker 3:  the big one with 18.1 because it, it's
Speaker 3:  the thing that takes Siri from being timers and music player
Speaker 3:  to chat bot to assistant to intelligent agent
Speaker 3:  that is taking action across all of your apps. And I, it seems like
Speaker 3:  they've added the stuff but they haven't added any of the backend to make
Speaker 3:  it go yet.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like I'm asking it questions and it's still just Googling stuff
Speaker 4:  for me. I'm like oh. Oh okay. Well I could have typed this into a Google
Speaker 4:  search bar instead of a Siri text box but,
Speaker 3:  And it seems they've added AI call recording and transcription, which is
Speaker 3:  the feature that I want the most.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Because if you're a reporter, not because I'm constantly spying on everyone.
Speaker 3:  I'm Richard Nixon everyone. I'm constantly recording everyone. No, I mean
Speaker 3:  we're reporters and like AI call recording and transcript are legitimately
Speaker 3:  useful in our jobs and it's been, we've just been doing, either
Speaker 3:  people are using their Android phones in our office, which lots of people
Speaker 3:  do or there's a set of weird third party stuff. But being able to just use
Speaker 3:  my iPhone, which is my main phone would be really great. So that's
Speaker 3:  here now. Has it worked yet? Have you tried it out?
Speaker 4:  I have not. 'cause I didn't put my sim card in that phone because of
Speaker 4:  eim 'cause of nightmares. But I did try out,
Speaker 4:  so like the voice memos app, we'll do
Speaker 4:  transcriptions now and that's not an Apple Intelligence feature. Like the
Speaker 4:  recording a call I think is Apple Intelligence could be wrong.
Speaker 4:  But the transcription is good. Like I put, I am a
Speaker 4:  Pixel recorder stand. I always have a Pixel phone at
Speaker 4:  a press event, you know, like it is just in my bag
Speaker 4:  and I put it next to the iPhone and it was really good.
Speaker 4:  It was like up there with the Pixel. So I am
Speaker 4:  personally excited about that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah I think that that's the one, it's always a grab bag
Speaker 3:  of which feature is the one that hits and I just know that that feature
Speaker 3:  for at least our little community of reporters is gonna hit the hardest.
Speaker 3:  Oh
Speaker 4:  They're gonna love it. See people
Speaker 2:  Excited. I'm so excited. Yeah. Can't wait to cancel my Otter subscription.
Speaker 3:  Oh no. Yeah, I mean like talk about startups getting wiped out. There's like
Speaker 3:  two or three that are gonna go away as soon as it sense.
Speaker 3:  It seems like the rest of the feature is not coming for a while. Right. Like
Speaker 3:  Mark Erman at Bloomberg said some of these might not come until late
Speaker 3:  25 or even 26.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think the last thing, I'm so confused on the
Speaker 4:  timeline, but it, the last thing I read I think was that like they would
Speaker 4:  all come to developer betas by the end of the year, but then as far as
Speaker 4:  like being in the public beta, that's 2025.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just a really long staggered kind of
Speaker 4:  rollout it sounds like.
Speaker 3:  And that kinda makes sense. The like the danger with the Siri that can do
Speaker 3:  stuff on your behalf is quite, quite high. I think you have to make sure
Speaker 3:  it works. We're also just not sure how
Speaker 3:  any of the Apple private cloud
Speaker 3:  stuff is going to work. Like right now, is it clear that all this stuff is
Speaker 3:  happening on the phone or in the cloud or where or is it all we all, we know
Speaker 3:  it's all happening on the phone
Speaker 4:  There. So there's a like privacy report You can
Speaker 4:  pull down now that will show you like ev and I think a lot of
Speaker 4:  this is in the cloud. Like it can't, I wouldn't say that for
Speaker 4:  sure, but You can, You can pull this privacy report that shows you
Speaker 4:  everything over like a certain time period that Apple Intelligence has done
Speaker 4:  on your phone. And I guess it's encrypted 'cause it's just like
Speaker 4:  gobbledy like I downloaded it, I was like, well this
Speaker 4:  is secure as hell. 'cause I don't know what any of this is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Still kind of unclear.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean I am just like the fundamental architecture of this thing is
Speaker 3:  very new and what happens on your phone versus in the cloud,
Speaker 3:  there's some stuff that Apple's been very clear that Apple happens on your
Speaker 3:  phone like emoji and some of the photo stuff happens on your phone. Some
Speaker 3:  of the other stuff we just, I'm assuming a lot of the Siri stuff is gonna
Speaker 3:  go to the cloud 'cause Siri goes to the cloud right now. So it,
Speaker 3:  it just seems like this rollout's gonna be a lot slower and more
Speaker 3:  deliberate than anyone anticipated based on wwc
Speaker 3:  and it might roll all the way. I mean late 2025 is
Speaker 3:  very close to when we would expect iOS 19 to be coming
Speaker 3:  out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm sort of curious how that will all play, but for now it seems like
Speaker 3:  they've sprinkled in some AI in the places where you would expect it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's all, it does seem pretty safe. It's like, okay, we've been able
Speaker 4:  to, it is kind of the table stake stuff of like, write me an email
Speaker 4:  that's friendly or professional or summarize this for me and
Speaker 4:  like that's all kind of, they're kind of laying the groundwork with that
Speaker 4:  stuff.
Speaker 3:  And then we're gonna get 18.0 first and then 18.1 second. So
Speaker 3:  this is pretty far away it seems
Speaker 4:  Like. Yeah, it's always Alright,
Speaker 3:  Well the, the AI overlords are coming whether we
Speaker 3:  like it or not. All right, so that's iOS 18.1. That's it's interesting. That's
Speaker 3:  out now and they're actually dual tracking it, right? There's iOS 18 in the
Speaker 3:  public betas and 18.1 in the developer betas. And you get the
Speaker 3:  feeling they wanted people to be talking about the AI stuff because the
Speaker 3:  Pixel line event is coming very soon and we know exactly what Google's
Speaker 3:  gonna talk about Pixel line event, but we gotta take a break. Let's do that.
Speaker 3:  Come back and let's talk about the Pixel line event. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  part is You can find meta ai right in the apps you already have
Speaker 1:  Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook, and Messenger.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm good with this. We've gotten to the same place with the phone design,
Speaker 4:  but Google's like, I think it's like Samsung and Google
Speaker 4:  are like, how do we make this not an iPhone? And the answer is like a weird
Speaker 4:  camera situation. Yes. and it kinda looks like Google's really
Speaker 4:  leaning into the weird camera situation and I don't know how
Speaker 4:  I still feel about it.
Speaker 3:  I think these are the rivian headlights of phone cameras.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Oh, do you know what I'm saying? Yeah. Like You can love them. You can hate
Speaker 3:  'em. They're not changing them. They're, it's, you know, and You can try
Speaker 3:  to convince me that they look like snake eyes.
Speaker 3:  They don't, you
Speaker 4:  Know. No,
Speaker 3:  Just like You can try to convince me this phone doesn't have a weird forehead.
Speaker 3:  It does.
Speaker 2:  It does. It does. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Super does. But it's true. The, the, the colors are more vibrant,
Speaker 3:  which is getting away from what Apple is doing, or at least that's what the
Speaker 3:  leaks indicate. So we're expecting a new Pixel nine, a Pixel nine Pro
Speaker 3:  a Pixel nine pro fold, my God, these names
Speaker 3:  and then watch, right? Oh, Pixel Buds Pro two
Speaker 3:  and a Pixel watch three. So that's a pretty complete
Speaker 3:  refresh of the Pixel line. It feels like the fold
Speaker 3:  should be where the action is, but I, I just
Speaker 3:  can't tell how much Google cares about these devices.
Speaker 4:  That's the question, isn't it?
Speaker 4:  It's so they moved the, like the fold was on the
Speaker 4:  product cycle with like it was at IO
Speaker 4:  last time around. Right? And then they've like scooched it, so it's more
Speaker 4:  part of the like, main
Speaker 4:  refresh cycle, which kind of makes sense is like, is this a flagship
Speaker 4:  phone? It's like the most expensive phone you guys sell, but it's a cycle
Speaker 4:  behind, you know, with the like camera hardware and whatnot.
Speaker 4:  So I think it makes sense moving the fold
Speaker 4:  into this position. But
Speaker 4:  it's, it's a lot of phones. I don't know, do we need this many
Speaker 4:  phones?
Speaker 2:  Like how do you think it'll compare to, 'cause you know, Samsung you said
Speaker 2:  like their foldables are just basically coasting at this point. So
Speaker 2:  are we at a point where like the Pixel fold is something that is like
Speaker 2:  yay competition? Or is it just
Speaker 2:  it's here?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm still of the mind that the one plus open
Speaker 4:  got it. Right. Like that is how a foldable like a book
Speaker 4:  style foldable should be shaped. And then Samsung
Speaker 4:  is just committed to this like remote control shaped thing
Speaker 4:  every year. They're like, it's a few millimeter, like this screen is a few
Speaker 4:  millimeters wider and it still feels like a remote control to use.
Speaker 4:  So I'm curious how different this new Pixel fold
Speaker 4:  is. 'cause there's a lot of rumors that it's like thinner and lighter.
Speaker 4:  'cause boy was the previous one heavy. But
Speaker 4:  I do like that that like wider aspect ratio for the
Speaker 4:  cover screen. I don't think it needs to be like, quite as wide
Speaker 4:  as the, the first generation Pixel fold. So
Speaker 4:  we'll see.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then the, the, the point of all this is going to
Speaker 3:  be the software, right? The, this is pretty iterative
Speaker 3:  hardware across the board. Some minor camera tweaks, a
Speaker 3:  wacky camera bump. But if you're not paying close attention,
Speaker 3:  I, it's, I think it's gonna be fairly hard to distinguish the hardware from
Speaker 3:  the previous generation. It's the software that's the game. So
Speaker 3:  You can see they're adding Gemini sort of to the first layer of
Speaker 3:  the interface. We've got this new thing called Pixel screenshots, which is
Speaker 3:  basically just Microsoft Recall, which everyone is scared about only manual.
Speaker 3:  So instead of constantly taking screenshots, you have to manually take a
Speaker 3:  screenshot. Very good, a very good differentiation. But I, I'm kind
Speaker 3:  of into it, right? You take a screenshot and you're like, what is this? Or
Speaker 3:  like save it for later there's a chicken walking down the street just like
Speaker 3:  hold onto that for me. Yeah. And then of course there's circle
Speaker 3:  the search, which Google's adding to basically everything at this point.
Speaker 3:  I will, I will coily say that a friend of mine
Speaker 3:  just put like circle the search me in the face the other day. You might imagine
Speaker 3:  who that friend is who was showing me an Android feature
Speaker 3:  and he dunked on me with circle the search, which was pretty funny. But like,
Speaker 3:  this is them saying, okay, there's a new way to think about how this phone
Speaker 3:  works, right? There's AI geminis like right here.
Speaker 3:  And then You can just point at things or tell the phone to look at things
Speaker 3:  and it will generate information for you, which is a very Google approach
Speaker 3:  to it. The question is whether that's enough
Speaker 3:  to make people switch, not even from the iPhone, from their Samsung
Speaker 3:  phones, which obviously are dominant. And of course because it's Google
Speaker 3:  whether they'll stay committed to any of those ideas for more than 20 minutes.
Speaker 3:  And I, I just don't know,
Speaker 4:  It's just a confusing time. I think even just circle to search.
Speaker 4:  Like, and I use it on the, the Samsung phones I've been testing
Speaker 4:  and the Google phones obviously. But like, there's
Speaker 4:  just kind of a lot of different ways to get at circle to
Speaker 4:  search. And you're like, so is this replacing these, like
Speaker 4:  Google lens is still a thing. I can translate something, but like
Speaker 4:  did I need to circle to search that they, they just have a lot of ideas.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like, do you open up Gemini and like take a screenshot of something
Speaker 4:  or a picture of the insider your refrigerator or, I don't know,
Speaker 4:  there's just a lot of like input methods where
Speaker 4:  it just sort of could feel overwhelming. But it's a
Speaker 4:  like, seems like there in that position
Speaker 4:  that we're kind of talking about with smarter Siri where it's like, okay,
Speaker 4:  like you've made the promises, this is gonna make our lives easier,
Speaker 4:  blah blah blah. Right now it's just a bunch of like, You
Speaker 4:  can switch the faces in these photos or you know,
Speaker 4:  put a rain cloud in the sky behind you and like that
Speaker 4:  was all nice and everything. But like, let's see. Something like, can they
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The, the screenshot thing. Sure. That, that would be cool. I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  take a screenshot of a recipe and I have literally
Speaker 4:  have the same like spaghetti and meatball recipe from America's
Speaker 4:  test kitchen bookmarked in my Google photos as a like
Speaker 4:  favorite as if it's a photo of my child. Like I just look at it
Speaker 4:  that often. I'm like too cheap to pay for
Speaker 4:  America's test kitchen and can't commit to writing it down.
Speaker 4:  So I don't know. I think there's a, there's a real use case for
Speaker 4:  help me find this thing in a screenshot.
Speaker 3:  I feel like, you know, I work with both of you very closely in the audience
Speaker 3:  might not know what it's like to work with you, but I bookmarked, I
Speaker 3:  favorited a, a screenshot of a recipe that I make all the time versus there's
Speaker 3:  a photo of a chicken that I can never find is kind of exactly the difference.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's just
Speaker 4:  A little bit. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 3:  It. It tells a whole story.
Speaker 4:  I'm just making my spaghetti and meatballs and bees like where's that chicken?
Speaker 2:  I think about the Brooklyn chicken all the time. It's been so long.
Speaker 2:  I'm not sure this chicken is alive anymore. I may have the only record
Speaker 2:  of this sidewalk walking chicken. Like it's important to me that this chicken
Speaker 2:  lives in my memory.
Speaker 3:  Please send us a note and describe how your photo storage
Speaker 3:  approaches describe your personality. 'cause I think there's, there's a lot
Speaker 3:  in there. It's a rich zone to unpack
Speaker 4:  On a scale of like one to chicken
Speaker 3:  On a scale of, I'm just scrolling for a photo of a chicken endlessly. I swear
Speaker 3:  it's here. Speaking of photos, Allison, you've been
Speaker 3:  covering what can only be described as the, what is a photo apocalypse
Speaker 3:  somewhat closely. You just wrote a piece about the Samsung like sketch
Speaker 3:  A B and they'll put a b in the, the photo for you. It
Speaker 3:  seems like the Pixel nine is just gonna continue moving
Speaker 3:  inextricably down this path with this feature called Add Me that
Speaker 3:  will just add you to photos that you're not in.
Speaker 4:  Yep. That's what it sounds like.
Speaker 3:  I mean, it's only from a leak. It's it's only from a leak.
Speaker 3:  It was in a YouTube video that got removed. It was like an ad and
Speaker 3:  it got, was leaked to YouTube and it got removed. But it just feels
Speaker 3:  like Google has to start communicating about
Speaker 3:  how it will keep our information environment somewhat pure
Speaker 3:  as it adds these features that just
Speaker 3:  polluted more than ever.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, they were really like tiptoeing up to the line I feel like last
Speaker 4:  year. and it was like, well this is just something that people have been
Speaker 4:  doing in Photoshop for a long time and now more people have the tools.
Speaker 4:  And then I feel like Samsung kicked the door down with sketch to image.
Speaker 4:  It was like, put a chicken in your photo, put a blimp, like
Speaker 4:  whatever you wanna do, You can have it. And then, yeah, I feel like the,
Speaker 4:  the flood gates are open and I don't know how like, how
Speaker 4:  aggressive Google will be, like the Add Me to the photo
Speaker 4:  thing. It seems like there could be guardrails on it
Speaker 4:  or it could just be like pure chaos and
Speaker 4:  it's an election year and what could go wrong.
Speaker 2:  So, so many things could go wrong. But I also like, it just reminds me of
Speaker 2:  this one family portrait I have. So like my family's half split in
Speaker 2:  the US versus Korea. And so we all went to Korea to get this family portrait
Speaker 2:  except for one cousin who couldn't go because he was a dual citizen
Speaker 2:  and his military service time was coming up. 'cause all Korean men have to
Speaker 2:  do military service before they're 30 and he's just like, I'm just not gonna
Speaker 2:  do it. So he had to get photoshopped into the family
Speaker 2:  photo. Oh no. And. if you look at it from a distance, you
Speaker 2:  can't tell that he's been photoshopped in. But if you look up close, you're
Speaker 2:  like, well, lighting on his hair is wrong. Yeah. It's coming from a different
Speaker 2:  angle. You can really, like, You can just, he's just textually
Speaker 2:  not the same as everybody else. Yeah. So.
Speaker 4:  Oh no.
Speaker 2:  You can tell. You can tell. And it's just like this huge family portrait
Speaker 2:  and Steve who's like been photoshopped in, so like,
Speaker 2:  did it work? I don't know. Not really. 'cause we can all tell he is
Speaker 2:  not there. So it's sort of like, I don't know. I feel like my auntie stay
Speaker 2:  safe out
Speaker 3:  There. Kids,
Speaker 2:  My auntie would love to have him in this sort of situation,
Speaker 2:  but I also, you know, having aunties with the power to just
Speaker 2:  add you into anything that seems also
Speaker 3:  Dangerous. Well, so it's not, it's not like an AI Add Me feature, at least
Speaker 3:  from the ad that we see. It's like a compositing feature,
Speaker 3:  like a very manual compositing feature where you take a photo
Speaker 3:  with a, and there's, you leave space for literally yourself in the photo
Speaker 3:  and then someone else holds the camera and it, it shows
Speaker 3:  you the old photo and you like go stand where you would
Speaker 3:  have been. And then you take a photo and it stitches all the photos together.
Speaker 3:  So it's, it's very manual and its way, I'm sure there's AI in the
Speaker 3:  background to handle the stitching and alignment and
Speaker 3:  probably the textures and colors and and lighting give
Speaker 4:  You too many fingers. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But the idea that it's gonna, it's not like deep faking you to put you in
Speaker 3:  the photo. It's taking another photo of you in the, in the same space
Speaker 3:  and then like making a composite. This is, which is still weird.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's one of those features that like as a parent now,
Speaker 4:  I'm like, oh, I completely get that like best
Speaker 4:  take where it's like you try and take a picture where there's more than
Speaker 4:  two toddlers in it, like forget it, then nobody's gonna
Speaker 4:  have a good time. But then it's like, oh, you have all this data and You
Speaker 4:  can just kinda like ai it together into one photo That looks right
Speaker 4:  though. Like you get to be in the photo even though you took the
Speaker 4:  photo thing. I'm like, yeah, I am. I'm following along with that.
Speaker 4:  I get that. So
Speaker 2:  It's basically, so you never have to ask someone, oh hey, do you mind taking
Speaker 2:  a photo of us because it's just letting
Speaker 3:  Us No, you have to ask them that. But in a much more
Speaker 3:  complicated and ethically challenged
Speaker 2:  Way. No, I mean like it's in your group. It's in your group. So
Speaker 3:  Like, it would be in your group. So like, yeah, like you, you two would take
Speaker 3:  a photo and then I would, I would take the photo of you two
Speaker 3:  and then I would hand one of you the phone and I would go stand next to where
Speaker 3:  you had been standing and you would take another photo and the Pixel
Speaker 3:  would composite those photos together. So it looked like all three of us
Speaker 3:  are standing there.
Speaker 2:  I hate, I hate talking to strangers and asking them to take a group photo
Speaker 2:  for me and my group. So this is, this is really gonna help me not grow
Speaker 2:  as a person and not talk to strangers more is basically,
Speaker 3:  Oh see, I love being asked that question because then everyone's like, oh,
Speaker 3:  you know what you're doing. Which is great.
Speaker 4:  I know. Oh, people don't know what they're getting into. I'm like,
Speaker 4:  so you've got the Pixel phone, tell me about your
Speaker 4:  choices here. They're like, who's this lady?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The second someone hands you a phone and you turn it to landscape, you're
Speaker 3:  like, oh my God, we gotta play here. Ready? What
Speaker 4:  Whatcha doing? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  But I even that's weird. Like even the thing I'm describing where it's pretty
Speaker 3:  manual, right? It's not just AI deepp picking you, but you have to, you're
Speaker 3:  making a composite photo.
Speaker 3:  What is a photo? Like it's not a moment in time that that moment quite
Speaker 3:  literally never happened and we're all gonna, we're gonna pass it off as
Speaker 3:  a photo. And I've been thinking about this parent's thing because Allison,
Speaker 3:  every time you write about it, you, you put it in there. Like the experience
Speaker 3:  of being a parent is just trying to is is like,
Speaker 3:  I would like a statistical average of this moment in time that makes me feel
Speaker 3:  good. Right? Yeah. Is like the goal of of like kid photography.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The reality is too scary.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like if I could just round off the edges and be like, this felt great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like at several moments throughout this day,
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 3:  Like that would be fine. I don't actually need a Pixel perfect
Speaker 3:  recreation of this moment in time. Yeah. And it's, it's kind of weird. Like
Speaker 3:  that is sort of the goal. And I, I understand in particular my parents want
Speaker 3:  that, but it's right next to, are you showing
Speaker 3:  somebody an image of a thing that actually happened or are you just creating
Speaker 3:  an illustration? And is that illustration like in the age of
Speaker 3:  influencers Instagram, is that in, is that illustration going to lead to
Speaker 3:  all kinds of weird outcomes that what people's expectations of their own
Speaker 3:  experiences should be like? 'cause they don't know they're looking at something
Speaker 3:  fake in the entire ecosystem.
Speaker 3:  We, we talked about this show in the context of like the, the tr the images
Speaker 3:  of the Trump assassination attempt, the entire ecosystem of
Speaker 3:  validating these images, saying what's real, what's not, which ones are ai,
Speaker 3:  which ones aren't, is just not ready. Like it it
Speaker 3:  that we've talked about it a lot. There are initiatives and alliances and
Speaker 3:  there's labels on meta platforms that are being applied seemingly,
Speaker 3:  randomly. But none of it works. Like no one trusts any of it.
Speaker 3:  And I just like, we are just barreling towards this future of completely
Speaker 3:  synthetic images coming off these phones and I just don't, it
Speaker 3:  doesn't seem like any of the companies give a shit.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I feel like there's this just shared understanding
Speaker 4:  we have, especially with a phone camera. It's like you just pointed at
Speaker 4:  a thing, you were there, you took a picture, it happened, you put it on,
Speaker 4:  you see it on Instagram. It's like we just have this shared understanding
Speaker 4:  of like, yes, that was a thing that happened. Exactly. You know, like
Speaker 4:  more or less as we saw it, there's, we, we all understand
Speaker 4:  that people pose for photos with big hats on
Speaker 4:  in front of gorgeous landscapes or whatever. But yeah, we're, we're
Speaker 4:  just like coming straight at that moment of like, okay,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna have to start asking some different questions when you're scrolling
Speaker 4:  through Instagram or just like shifting your mindset. And it's not even
Speaker 4:  like when I did the, the sketch to image,
Speaker 4:  I did, you know, mess with a bunch of photos, added cats and pirate
Speaker 4:  chips and like nonsense to them. And I posted a bunch to my
Speaker 4:  Instagram like grid and a post and I went through the
Speaker 4:  requirements they have for like, when you need to add an
Speaker 4:  AI tag and it didn't even meet them. It was
Speaker 4:  like you You can, you know, it was like something about it
Speaker 4:  was my like my own personal photo and I wasn't
Speaker 4:  the way it had manipulated it. It was like, and it's kind of up to you, you
Speaker 4:  know, put a tag on there or don't whatever. Like, okay,
Speaker 4:  That's fine.
Speaker 4:  It's all fine.
Speaker 3:  Well see, the other thing I've noticed a lot of is even just
Speaker 3:  the basic AI features in phones now, they're
Speaker 3:  overcorrecting and over sharpening. And this is beyond like, it looks bad.
Speaker 3:  It's like if you zoom in too far on a lot of modern smartphone
Speaker 3:  photos now you will see that the text is all
Speaker 3:  ai wonky and like signs in the background. 'cause AI has tried to
Speaker 3:  de-noise and sharpen and you've gotten some weird stuff, like really small
Speaker 3:  faces far away. And a lot of smartphone photos now look incredibly
Speaker 3:  distorted and demonic. 'cause there's like three pixels and
Speaker 3:  it's like, well what if I put a face here and it's like, I don't really know
Speaker 3:  what a face looks like yet. So here's a face, a vaguely face shaped DNO
Speaker 3:  thing. I think Samsung phones are, are more egregious with this than
Speaker 3:  iPhones, but they're all doing it to varying degrees and that is
Speaker 3:  already confusing people. Yeah. Like they're like, these photos are AI
Speaker 3:  generated and it's like, you're not wrong, but you're also not right.
Speaker 3:  Like that moment in time did happen and then,
Speaker 3:  you know, a smartphone interpreted this demon face instead
Speaker 3:  of just not having information there.
Speaker 4:  It's weird when it kind of come like comes to the surface where,
Speaker 4:  what was the, the photo of the lady trying on a wedding dress
Speaker 4:  where Yeah, yeah. In the mirror. She's like making two different poses. Oh
Speaker 4:  yeah. And like
Speaker 3:  Everybody
Speaker 4:  Lost their minds and it turned out to be like it was accidentally in panorama
Speaker 4:  mode or something like that. But just even that is like,
Speaker 4:  you know, this stuff has been going on behind the scenes and just sort of
Speaker 4:  like doing everything it can with that data to make a photo that it think
Speaker 4:  it thinks you will like, and then when it kind of goes sideways
Speaker 4:  and is obvious, then it's a real weird moment of like, no.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, actually your phone's been doing this. Like, you just,
Speaker 4:  it just didn't look like a demon until right this moment.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I I think there's gonna be some moment
Speaker 3:  where
Speaker 3:  the industry, probably not the industry or governments, the eu,
Speaker 3:  they, they tend, they, they're always doing stuff. They're gonna say,
Speaker 3:  if you enable these features, you have to like hard watermark these photos
Speaker 3:  as being partially generated by ai. 'cause if we don't get all the
Speaker 3:  way there, then we're, we're gonna end up in this
Speaker 3:  extremely weird moment where only
Speaker 3:  professionals with like cryptographic
Speaker 3:  signatures in their DSLRs uploading directly to Getty are the
Speaker 3:  source of any truth. And I don't think that's, that doesn't seem
Speaker 3:  sustainable. Right? Like only if you buy this one like a camera
Speaker 3:  and you have a contract with Reuters, can your photos be trusted
Speaker 3:  like
Speaker 4:  $10,000 camera?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I, it just doesn't seem, that doesn't seem like what anybody wants.
Speaker 3:  I I'm, I'm hopeful that like consumers correct this
Speaker 3:  first, but I suspect that some government
Speaker 3:  somewhere is gonna have to make a rule and people are gonna have to comply
Speaker 3:  because we're just headed every time. And I'm, I know the Google people
Speaker 3:  are gonna yell at me. 'cause every time I'm like, the what is a photo apocalypse
Speaker 3:  is here because of some Google feature. They're like, no, this is just what
Speaker 3:  people want. And I'm like, but people also want sugar.
Speaker 4:  Like we want a
Speaker 3:  Lot of things. But I love cigarettes.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  Like, what do you want me to do?
Speaker 2:  It always does feel like they have the best case scenario in mind and that
Speaker 2:  humans are not goblins who do horrible things to
Speaker 2:  each other. Sometimes they're like, oh no, everyone will use it in the way
Speaker 2:  that we intend. Which is the nice way. Yeah. And it's just like,
Speaker 2:  no.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Look
Speaker 2:  Around. You only need one one jerk. You only need one jerk to ruin everything.
Speaker 3:  Look around. All right. Other reviews. V you reviewed the Galax watch Ultra
Speaker 3:  this week. What's
Speaker 2:  Yes, yes. What
Speaker 3:  Kind of, what kind of Apple watch? Is it a good one or a bad watch? It's,
Speaker 2:  It's an Apple Watch Ultra that Sure, that sure is what it is. But like, I,
Speaker 2:  well actually what it really is is that like if you took the Apple Watch
Speaker 2:  Ultra and drew it from memory, that's the Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra
Speaker 2:  or if you like, took the Apple font, it it's, it's
Speaker 2:  like the Apple Watch Ultra too, but like in an Android font is
Speaker 2:  just basically what you're doing with this. It's, there's just, I was writing
Speaker 2:  the review and then I was like, you know what, it's actually just expedient
Speaker 2:  if I tell you what's different and bullet point, everything that is the same
Speaker 2:  because there's too many things that are the same. And then I started doing
Speaker 2:  the major things that are the same and then I was like, oh, but then there's
Speaker 2:  this and then there's this, and then there's like all these tiny little features
Speaker 2:  that only a psycho like me would know and remember are on
Speaker 2:  each of the watches are there like, oh, You can run against your last race
Speaker 2:  performance if you're a runner. Yeah, apple did that and watch it West Nine
Speaker 2:  and now he's here on the Samsung and like, why is it here on the Samsung?
Speaker 2:  Because, I don't know, it was on Apple. They have an orange shortcut
Speaker 2:  button button that is a quick button on Samsung and the action button
Speaker 2:  on the Apple watch. They, it's the same thing just in a
Speaker 2:  different font. And that's, that's like you could sum up the watch as that.
Speaker 2:  And also it's, it's a squirkle and I don't like it. I don't,
Speaker 2:  I I was had mixed feelings about the Squirkle going in. And then after two
Speaker 2:  weeks of wear, I don't like the squirkle, it is just too
Speaker 2:  chunky on my wrist. I can fit three chopsticks into the gap
Speaker 2:  between the, the the watch and the and
Speaker 2:  my wrist. And it's just a chunker. It's a very
Speaker 2:  chunky, it's a very chunky boy. And so orange, like
Speaker 2:  the Apple Watch Ultra was orange. This is so
Speaker 2:  Radioactively biohazard orange. It's a little upsetting how orange
Speaker 2:  it is. It's, it's, I don't have it on me right now, but it looks like a
Speaker 2:  Halloween watch. I actually ended up appreciating the regular
Speaker 2:  Galaxy Watch seven, which I am wearing right now a whole lot more
Speaker 2:  because I was like, oh, it doesn't hurt me to wear it 'cause it's just
Speaker 2:  too big. It's too big for my wrist. And like the Apple Watch Ultra is also
Speaker 2:  big for my wrist. I can stick a bunch of stuff in here. There's like a gap.
Speaker 2:  But something about it being a square just made it a lot harder for
Speaker 2:  me to wear. When I was testing the sleep apnea feature, it was just like,
Speaker 2:  Nope, we can't get readings from you. So I actually had to wear the other
Speaker 2:  one to get the readings and test that feature out. So it was,
Speaker 2:  it makes it sound bad, but it's actually a really great Android watch. I
Speaker 2:  would say it's like one of the best Android watches that are available. I
Speaker 2:  just, there's a little part of me that hurts
Speaker 2:  that Samsung decided to make an Apple watch in order to create
Speaker 2:  this excellent Android watch. It just felt wrong. It felt wrong to
Speaker 2:  me. 'cause I truly do love how weird and unique the Samsung smart watches
Speaker 2:  have been with their rotating bezels and just
Speaker 2:  Samsung being weird about how it does health stuff.
Speaker 2:  The ages metric is just completely bonkers. Yes. I don't understand
Speaker 2:  why it's there.
Speaker 3:  I was definitely gonna ask you about this, by the way. You said age and that
Speaker 3:  stands for Advanced Glycation end products. Yes. Have they
Speaker 3:  yet told you what that means?
Speaker 2:  So You can, there's, there's a whole like informational
Speaker 2:  section that You can read in the app, in the Samsung Health app about what
Speaker 2:  it is. And it's basically measuring compounds when
Speaker 2:  fats and sugars in your blood oxidize. How
Speaker 2:  is it doing this? Samsung won't say, it just says there's a new three in
Speaker 2:  one active biosensor with more LED colors and whatnot.
Speaker 2:  And there's a little spectrum and it goes from low to high
Speaker 2:  and it, if you're low, I guess you're
Speaker 2:  metabolically younger than your age. And if you're high, I guess you're
Speaker 2:  not your metabolic page.
Speaker 3:  You're measur this through the skin.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Are they they're not like pricking you, the watch isn't like taking your
Speaker 3:  blood.
Speaker 2:  No, everything is noninvasive.
Speaker 3:  Okay. And there's not like a, there's not like a chemical sense. It's not
Speaker 3:  like in your sweat, they're just doing the thing that everyone does. They're
Speaker 2:  Just shining light into your skin. And based on like how it reflects back,
Speaker 2:  they're just telling you things that have not been FDA cleared.
Speaker 2:  It's very experimental. Like I did not know what
Speaker 2:  this, this actual feature was. So you know, when I was getting briefed on
Speaker 2:  it and I went up to Samsung and I'm like, so what is this? And they were
Speaker 2:  basically like, well we have this new sensor, so we thought why not
Speaker 2:  throw this also in here? This
Speaker 3:  Is the, that's the most Samsung answer of all time.
Speaker 2:  Oh no. And, and I was like, oh, okay. So like how, how do you intend
Speaker 2:  people to use it? And they're like, actually we dunno. Like we're just kind
Speaker 2:  of, we just kind of wanna see how people use it. And so a lot of the new
Speaker 2:  features are quote unquote AI powered and you're getting these AI insights
Speaker 2:  and they're telling me things that I don't know what to do with. Because
Speaker 2:  on the one hand the watch was like, Hey, you have not been
Speaker 2:  consistent with your sleep little lady, you should work on that. And then
Speaker 2:  I refreshed the app and it's like, great job staying consistent with your
Speaker 2:  sleep schedule. And I was just like, so which is it? Which is it? Which is
Speaker 2:  it? I had one night where I didn't like have my sleep schedule completely
Speaker 2:  perfect. So I guess that's what it was. Reacting. That's not helpful. And
Speaker 2:  then the ages metric, they're like, well if you wanna improve your score,
Speaker 2:  I'm smack dab in the middle. So I don't know, I guess that means I'm my age
Speaker 2:  metabolically. Who knows. Wait,
Speaker 3:  I just, wait, can I just stick with the age thing for one second? Yes. So
Speaker 3:  they have a metric called age. Yes. Which I
Speaker 3:  think most people know what a metric called age
Speaker 3:  meant to measure, which is your age.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Right. That's a well-known label for a thing.
Speaker 3:  And then it measures, first of all, let me just quote your
Speaker 3:  own review back. You V Yes, yes. Meanwhile, the age metric is baffling is
Speaker 3:  what you have written here.
Speaker 2:  Yes, it is baffling.
Speaker 3:  So then it, it's shining a light through your wrist and,
Speaker 3:  and then somehow from what it, the reflections of that light,
Speaker 3:  it is tracking how protein and fat
Speaker 3:  are oxidized by sugar and then telling you whether that's a low, medium or
Speaker 3:  high. And then they're saying that is something called age. And I just wanna
Speaker 3:  point out how deeply meaningfully confusing that is.
Speaker 2:  It's your metabolic age, right? If they label to do these things, skin
Speaker 2:  outta here,
Speaker 3:  But like, but there's no, but is,
Speaker 3:  but it's like a new metric. Is this a metric that exists in like the literature?
Speaker 2:  It is a metric that exists in research and scientists
Speaker 2:  are studying it, but in a consumer watch it means
Speaker 2:  nothing. It means absolutely nothing
Speaker 2:  in a consumer watch you. So it tells me that I am like kind
Speaker 2:  of in the medium, neither low or high in the yellow
Speaker 2:  section, so to speak. And it's like, okay, so to improve your
Speaker 2:  age's metric, here's what
Speaker 3:  You do. Doesn't know how old you are.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you do. I did put my like demographic information
Speaker 3:  In. So presumably if you're, it's, is it
Speaker 3:  at all related to your actual age? It's like if you're green, is your metabolic
Speaker 3:  age younger than your actual age?
Speaker 2:  Yes. That's basically what they're telling you. This is the idea
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 2:  So messed up. This is the idea. It's okay.
Speaker 3:  And then how did it,
Speaker 2:  It's not messed up. It means nothing. It means nothing. So
Speaker 2:  it doesn't have to be messed up. It's just baffling and it makes
Speaker 2:  no sense.
Speaker 3:  I like new, I like new metrics. Yes. I'm just, I'm just trying to understand
Speaker 3:  this one. So somewhere, someone, somewhere is like
Speaker 3:  a 25-year-old has a metabolism of X
Speaker 3:  And. if you tell us you're 25 by shining a light from a smartwatch into
Speaker 3:  your wrist,
Speaker 2:  Tell you old this, this is a new, this is kind of a new thing that they're
Speaker 2:  doing in wearables. It's not just Samsung. Like
Speaker 2:  basically the Aura recently did a thing where it's like we can tell you what
Speaker 2:  your cardiovascular age is and whether it's aligned with your physical
Speaker 2:  age or not. And so there's
Speaker 2:  just like this obsession with telling you whether you are like physically
Speaker 2:  speaking, aligned with expectations for your actual age or whether
Speaker 2:  you're quote unquote physically physiologically younger than your actual
Speaker 2:  age or
Speaker 3:  Older. I feel like there's a lot of people in Silicon Valley who are drinking
Speaker 3:  the bar at the young in order to live forever. And I'm, I'm not trying to
Speaker 3:  draw a straight line to the Galaxy Watch Ultra. I'm just saying there's a
Speaker 3:  path, perhaps a winding path.
Speaker 2:  There is, but, but it's, I do, it's,
Speaker 4:  I do not want, it's funny, a smart ring to tell me if my heart is dying
Speaker 4:  faster than I'm, well maybe you do.
Speaker 2:  Listen, listen, listen. There are, there are health
Speaker 2:  nuts who want this information. I don't necessarily think it's actually good
Speaker 2:  for their mental health to have this information, but the app was just
Speaker 2:  basically like, hey, so here's how You can improve your ages. Index a
Speaker 2:  metric that means absolutely nothing and you'll never guess what the
Speaker 2:  advice is because it's to eat healthy. Oh yeah. Sleep
Speaker 2:  well and exercise. So I'm just like, oh, thanks. It's always that
Speaker 3:  Gets
Speaker 2:  You never, it's
Speaker 3:  Always that last one.
Speaker 3:  Alright,
Speaker 3:  like all Samsung devices, this, this, all this works best if you're in the
Speaker 3:  Galaxy ecosystem, right? Yes. Yes. I'm assuming none of it works than iPhone.
Speaker 3:  it what gets worse if you have a Pixel or you have a one plus?
Speaker 2:  Well, do you, would you like to have your EKGs and E AFib
Speaker 2:  detection? You will not get that unless you have a Galaxy phone. Would you
Speaker 2:  like to know if you have sleep apnea? You will not get that unless you have
Speaker 2:  a Galaxy phone because that requires the Samsung Health
Speaker 2:  Monitor app, which is separate from Samsung Health, meaning you're just not
Speaker 2:  gonna get that. And some of the AI features are
Speaker 2:  Galaxy phone like only as well, which actually I think that's great
Speaker 2:  for you because the AI was very hit or miss for me
Speaker 2:  and all the advice it gave me, it would be like, Hey, your
Speaker 2:  ages is not ideal. Exercise more. And then
Speaker 2:  the AI was like, you're exercising a little too much, you should rest because
Speaker 2:  it's affecting your sleep. Oh my God. And also you're sleeping well
Speaker 2:  and not well at the same time. So it's like cool.
Speaker 2:  Great, thanks.
Speaker 3:  I feel like it's a big ask to be like, we're you need a new watch and a new
Speaker 3:  phone
Speaker 2:  And a new ring and all of that stuff.
Speaker 3:  So I did last week we asked
Speaker 3:  listeners to send us a note if they were all in on the Samsung ecosystem.
Speaker 3:  I would, I'm just gonna guess and say that if I asked
Speaker 3:  listeners to send us notes about why they were all in on the Apple ecosystem,
Speaker 3:  we would crash the internet, right? Like we would just get a lot I I like
Speaker 3:  say in a breath, like I don't think CarPlay is very good and emails
Speaker 3:  for days, man, all day long. People are like, how dare you.
Speaker 3:  We asked for Galaxy Ecosystem users. We got two emails.
Speaker 3:  No, just putting out there. No. So one
Speaker 3:  person, Sean, thank you Sean for emailing, they
Speaker 3:  wrote in, they're upgrading from a fold four to a fold six,
Speaker 3:  which is, you know, great they're doing it because the, the fold four broke
Speaker 3:  the warranty on the device is CED and they found a way through
Speaker 3:  the cell phone warranty to get a fold six. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  right. They like, they tried to use the licensed
Speaker 3:  Samsung repair company. You break iix
Speaker 3:  that cost money. So then they tried to use their Amex warranty, they were
Speaker 3:  denied. Then Amex called Samsung, they said no,
Speaker 3:  and then they went to cell phone insurance, which they had, and that replaced
Speaker 3:  the got to fold six. So that is one way to stay in the Samsung
Speaker 3:  ecosystem is a nightmare repair journey because you're fold, the seals
Speaker 3:  are fold for Brooke. I would not say this is the type of email we get when
Speaker 3:  we ask why people stay in the Apple ecosystem. So that's one.
Speaker 3:  We got another one. Thank you so much for emailing from Israel.
Speaker 3:  This one says you asked to hear from the Galaxy Ecosystem user. I am that
Speaker 3:  user, which is
Speaker 2:  Singular.
Speaker 3:  Truly appreciate that line they wrote to us. I'm typing this in my Galaxy
Speaker 3:  Tabs eight Ultra. I upgraded from Z fold four to Z fold six. I use the
Speaker 3:  tablet form factor much more than the phone fold factor, which means they
Speaker 3:  have both a Galaxy tablet and they are constantly using their phone and
Speaker 3:  tablet mode. This is the most Android tablet usage I've ever heard of in
Speaker 3:  my entire life. S incredible.
Speaker 2:  You're
Speaker 3:  Breaking, you're, you're, you're whatever you do, everyone's like, that's
Speaker 3:  90% of the usage. They have a Galaxy Watch five Pro, and
Speaker 3:  they're waiting on their Galaxy Watch Ultra. And then they have four TVs
Speaker 3:  including a, a Frame tv. They're washer and dryer Samsung. They have the
Speaker 3:  air dresser, the fridge, the oven, a robot vacuum, a smart things hub, a
Speaker 3:  Blu-ray player, you're my people. And then it says, and something else I'm
Speaker 3:  forgetting, I'm sure. And then
Speaker 2:  Are they Korean?
Speaker 3:  And then at the end it says, my husband uses an iPhone and an iPad.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow.
Speaker 2:  There's a case study. So like, so my
Speaker 3:  Family, so, and just say one Thank you. I love this. I just,
Speaker 3:  I'll, I'm gonna write back, but you, you've neglected to say
Speaker 3:  why you have chosen, so I would love to know wh why.
Speaker 3:  And if anyone else is out there and wants to send us a note with, with their
Speaker 3:  list and why I'm, I'm dying to read them because we know so much
Speaker 3:  about the Apple ecosystem and how people feel about it. Trust me, I, we know
Speaker 3:  so much you are not quiet. I'm dying to know how people at
Speaker 3:  other ecosystems feel about it. And it's like really interesting to get this,
Speaker 3:  these notes. So keep writing in. I'm, I'm very curious. That said, my husband
Speaker 3:  used an iPhone. iPad is very funny. Like deeply funny.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's, there's something going on. Oh,
Speaker 4:  I love it. Someone
Speaker 3:  Is very excited about RCS.
Speaker 4:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 2:  Oh, that's so good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean look it, there's a bunch of Samsung devices
Speaker 3:  in this house. Somehow I've ended up in the LG think Q ecosystem
Speaker 3:  because that's our washer and dryer and fridge. Oh boy. God only
Speaker 3:  knows why. And now I'm like, man, I better, I got an update the other, I
Speaker 3:  got a notification the other day that new songs for summer were available
Speaker 3:  for the washer and dryer. And I was like, yes, this is the dream.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. But
Speaker 2:  Wait, wait. Songs for your washer and dryer to play.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, every quarter LG sends new little icons
Speaker 3:  for the seasons and then issues new like songs.
Speaker 2:  This is why they couldn't presso on
Speaker 4:  There. They couldn't make phones anymore. They've like, we have to divert
Speaker 4:  those resources to the washer.
Speaker 3:  There's 50 engineers with Casio keyboards being like,
Speaker 3:  like, and once a quarter they send them to me and it's great. Oh my God.
Speaker 3:  I truly, I truly love.
Speaker 4:  It's incredible.
Speaker 3:  We can't wrap up the Samsung conversation without talking about
Speaker 3:  Saturday Samsung.
Speaker 2:  Saturday Samsung.
Speaker 3:  So if you don't know, this is what we have started calling Samsung's relentless
Speaker 3:  attempts to sell more products, which are all born of the
Speaker 3:  company losing some money. Sales are flat and they
Speaker 3:  issued an edict saying everyone had to come to work six days a week until
Speaker 3:  they recovered
Speaker 3:  crazy. And it's, it's their corporate employees, which means a bunch of suits
Speaker 3:  are sitting around Samsung headquarters on Saturday being like, we sell more
Speaker 3:  shit. They're not making any, they're the suits. They, they, they, what
Speaker 3:  are they gonna do? So that it's only weird promotions. So we have covered,
Speaker 3:  you get a free tv if you buy a tv, which is amazing, we have covered, you
Speaker 3:  get a free TV if you buy a phone also amazing. You would think it would
Speaker 3:  continue in this vein, but no. Last Saturday,
Speaker 3:  I guess burst of creativity and they
Speaker 3:  decided that the best way to market the Galaxy Z flip
Speaker 3:  in America
Speaker 3:  would be to say that the z flip, it's a folding phone.
Speaker 3:  A little flippy guy is ideal for busy police officers
Speaker 3:  to wear his body cam.
Speaker 2:  That's so Samsung. It's very good. Oh, Samsung.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's so bad. Like the, I have put a
Speaker 4:  folding phone on my shirt. I think I am safe to
Speaker 4:  say I'm one of the few people who's tried that outside of these police officers.
Speaker 4:  It's a dumb idea. Like it's just not a good idea that
Speaker 2:  It just doesn't seem secure. Also, like where
Speaker 2:  are they? Don't they wear vests?
Speaker 2:  This, this doesn't look like
Speaker 3:  They, well they, they worked so they didn't just like issue them like T-Mobile
Speaker 3:  phones.
Speaker 3:  They partnered, there's a, there's a post on Samsung's website. It's titled
Speaker 3:  Samsung Technology is helping police authority protect the public safety,
Speaker 3:  which is a lot. They partnered with a company
Speaker 3:  called Visual Labs, which is quote, a leading body camera solution provider
Speaker 3:  capitalism. And then two police departments in Missouri did a pilot
Speaker 3:  program with all of this. They have a customized Z flip
Speaker 3:  that has like slightly different buttons. The the
Speaker 3:  phones can be set to automatically begin recording when the
Speaker 3:  phone detects a pursuit or if you're
Speaker 2:  In the car
Speaker 3:  When the emergency lights are turned on. And then the video footage is sent
Speaker 3:  to the Visual Labs cloud.
Speaker 2:  Okay, this is all very good looking at this. It's all very good looking at
Speaker 2:  this. That's ridiculous. It's so
Speaker 4:  Bad.
Speaker 2:  That is so why
Speaker 3:  Well get ready V because 25 more police departments are gonna start wearing
Speaker 3:  he flip as body cams. Oh
Speaker 4:  Lord. Oh, oh. And
Speaker 3:  I was wrong. It, there's a partnership with T-Mobile. So they are T-Mobile
Speaker 3:  phones.
Speaker 4:  Like what do you, what do you need the rest of the phone on your person
Speaker 4:  for like, you just need a camera and some,
Speaker 3:  I just like the idea that people are gonna like flip it open and then like
Speaker 3:  make a TikTok and like
Speaker 4:  Close Yeah, yeah. They're gonna start doing some dances and Yeah,
Speaker 4:  no, I, oh good lord it's not. Okay.
Speaker 3:  There is a, there's a, this whole, this whole press release is great, but
Speaker 3:  there's just like other benefits which are basically like this phone has
Speaker 3:  a camera in it. So one of the benefits is in addition to their uses body-worn
Speaker 3:  cameras Z flip devices can help improve evidence gathering and transparency.
Speaker 3:  No, but clearly documenting details of arrests and other interactions.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely not there,
Speaker 4:  There's literally a feature on this,
Speaker 2:  The camera
Speaker 4:  That's just draw stuff that wasn't there.
Speaker 4:  Body cameras do not have that. This is such a
Speaker 3:  Bad idea.
Speaker 4:  Draw,
Speaker 2:  Draw in the, the drugs. Just
Speaker 3:  Put the cocaine here.
Speaker 2:  Put the cocaine here in the dash.
Speaker 3:  Yes. The Galaxy Z Flip a quote, the Galaxy Z flip additionally functions
Speaker 3:  as a digital camera needed for taking pictures of crime
Speaker 3:  all of the headlines and then we'll like figure out what's going on. The
Speaker 3:  first one though is just one headline and it's our fault.
Speaker 3:  Logitech's new CEO Hanukkah. Faber was on decoder this week.
Speaker 3:  She's the new co. She just started like late last year. We had the old co
Speaker 3:  bracken Daryl on several times.
Speaker 3:  I like I, one of my ideas with decoder is there's more than five companies
Speaker 3:  in the world and so we should talk to all the companies and pay attention
Speaker 3:  to them. That generally goes well. And Log is one of these companies, I think
Speaker 3:  it's Undercovered, right? Like they're just around you don't think about
Speaker 3:  them very much. and it turned out under Brack and Daryl,
Speaker 3:  like how worked was bonkers. Like he's like, I have 23
Speaker 3:  direct reports. Everyone's just allowed to do whatever they want. I buy companies,
Speaker 3:  I leave 'em alone. There's no overlap. It's like everyone have a good time,
Speaker 3:  which is how you end up with em buying like 50 headphone companies and
Speaker 3:  they're all just kinda like doing their thing. They're like, I wonder if
Speaker 3:  they have a strategy. The answer was they do. Which is ev leave Everybody
Speaker 3:  Alone, which worked just to whatever extent Bracken
Speaker 3:  Leaves Lodge Tech, he now works for,
Speaker 3:  I think it's called VF Brands. They own Vans and Supreme and the North Face.
Speaker 3:  So the guy who ran Log Check is now the CEO of Supreme. Incredible.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna see how that goes. We're gonna, I'm gonna try to get him back
Speaker 3:  to be like so Supreme, that sort of thing. And they have a new co Hanukkah
Speaker 3:  who came from like Unilever and Proctor and Gamble. She has this
Speaker 3:  background in consumer goods and like marketing really interesting. And I,
Speaker 3:  you know, I was like, are you gonna change this wacky corporate structure?
Speaker 3:  And that was what I thought decoder was gonna be bad. Truly. That's what
Speaker 3:  I thought we were gonna talk. And then we did talk about that for a while.
Speaker 3:  And then she's like, I wanna build a forever mouse. And
Speaker 3:  this keeps happening to me on decoder where I'm like, what? Explain.
Speaker 3:  And she's like, I wanna be able a really beautiful mouse. It's like very
Speaker 3:  heavy, very premium. And we'll just do software updates forever and that
Speaker 3:  will be your forever mouse. Like you'll just have it forever. And I'm
Speaker 3:  thinking, well I've had this mouse forever,
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 3:  It
Speaker 2:  Same,
Speaker 3:  Right? It's like 10 years old.
Speaker 2:  Are people replacing mice? No. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So very confused. Very confused. And I You can hear if you
Speaker 3:  listen to it, the transcript reads one way, but you actually go and listen
Speaker 3:  to Coder. It's very You can, I'm just laughing like, I'm like, what are you
Speaker 3:  talking about? I'm like, there's only two ways to monetize hardware over
Speaker 3:  time. It is subscriptions or it is ads. And she's like,
Speaker 3:  yep, those are the two ways. I'm like, so you're gonna do a subscription
Speaker 3:  mouse? And she's like, I am and I encourage you to go listen to this because
Speaker 3:  I'm just like losing my mind like
Speaker 2:  Laughing. What am I subscribing to with a subscription mouse? Right?
Speaker 3:  So we it's AI suffer.
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 2:  what is AI software for my mouse? Yeah. Whatcha you gonna
Speaker 2:  change the DPI based on what I'm doing?
Speaker 3:  No, no, no, no, no. It's not even, it's not even that. It like you were like
Speaker 3:  that. Here's an idea. No, no, it's worse than that. They're, they're putting
Speaker 3:  the buttons on the mouse so that when you see a field, like any text
Speaker 3:  field on your computer, the mouse will do the
Speaker 3:  prompting for you.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely not. They,
Speaker 3:  So they've already rolled this out in Options Pro in options Plus.
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 3:  This is like a thing, this is a thing in in Logic Mice today for like newer
Speaker 3:  mice. Why older mice are not allowed to have the software? I didn't even
Speaker 3:  get to 'cause I was just what? Right? Like You can listen to me like
Speaker 3:  dewire my brain in this conversation.
Speaker 3:  So I, I was like, so I'm asked and she's like, yeah, this is how our video
Speaker 3:  conferencing software works. And I was like, but it's,
Speaker 3:  that's a service. This is a mouse. And she's like, yeah, a mouse. I put like
Speaker 3:  a beautiful, and I believe she said Diamond and crusted mouse. So that was
Speaker 3:  decoder. These things happen to and decoder all the time. My god, I, what
Speaker 3:  I was not expecting was the idea of the
Speaker 3:  subscription Mouse has just like, it's a news cycle
Speaker 3:  and it was just like the new see riffing, but now there's a full news cycle
Speaker 3:  launch tech doing subscription wise. Oh no. And I will tell you
Speaker 3:  not since like HP was like subscription printers. Have people been this unhappy
Speaker 3:  about any idea that I've ever heard.
Speaker 4:  I mean
Speaker 3:  There, there are YouTubers for making YouTube videos about it. I've seen
Speaker 3:  tiktoks about it's like crazy. It's like, it is. It's living its own little
Speaker 3:  life.
Speaker 4:  People are throwing away their Logitech mice like
Speaker 2:  No, no, we're not throwing away. This is really gonna be my forever
Speaker 2:  Logitech mouse now. I'm never giving it up. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I will say the mouse to my other computer there is easily 15 years old.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like you just get one out of the box.
Speaker 3:  It's kind of gross. You don't, I'm not saying it's not a little gross,
Speaker 4:  They get disgusting, but like you're just in an office, you find one out
Speaker 4:  of a box. Someone put it there 10 years ago,
Speaker 2:  You don't see my thumb sweat. It's You can see my thumb sweat on this mouth.
Speaker 3:  You stop. It's a radio show stop showing people your thumb sweat.
Speaker 4:  It's just,
Speaker 2:  You know,
Speaker 3:  Describe it for the audio listener.
Speaker 3:  I will tell you, I rarely,
Speaker 3:  rarely get deeply surprised by what happens on decoder.
Speaker 3:  It's mostly shit about org charts as the listeners know. And then every now
Speaker 3:  and again these, these past couple months, the Zoom CEO came on and was like,
Speaker 3:  we're building AI clones of everyone to put in Zoom meetings. And
Speaker 3:  again, I just encourage you, You can just listen to me try to try to
Speaker 3:  respond to that in real time. And look, I'll take the heat on decoder. People
Speaker 3:  are like, you're too nice, whatever. Like, I'm always trying to be better.
Speaker 3:  I'm always trying to ask harder questions. Just imagine what it's like
Speaker 3:  in real time to be faced with someone being like, the future of Zoom
Speaker 3:  is AI clones and meetings and you have to like
Speaker 3:  acknowledge that like not die
Speaker 3:  and then formulate a series of follow up questions that make any sense that
Speaker 3:  like tell a little story. It's, it's harder than it looks is all I'm trying
Speaker 3:  to say. And they're serious and you have to keep 'em there, right? They're
Speaker 3:  dead and you have to Right. And you have to keep 'em talking.
Speaker 3:  and it is just, it is just much more challenging in subscription mice. You
Speaker 3:  can hear me just, what are you talking about?
Speaker 4:  Record Scratch. Yeah. God.
Speaker 3:  So I was not intending to cause a full news cycle about mice.
Speaker 3:  It was truly not my intent, but I hope that here we are. It doesn't do
Speaker 3:  subscription mice. I, I tried very hard to be like, I don't think
Speaker 3:  that's a good idea.
Speaker 4:  Please don't.
Speaker 3:  But you know, logic has this really interesting problem. Like it is interesting
Speaker 3:  to think of their big problem, which is if you believe that AI
Speaker 3:  is gonna be important and we've talked about it in this episode,
Speaker 3:  it might be that you just talk to your phone a bunch more, right? and it
Speaker 3:  just like does stuff for you. It might be that natural interfaces,
Speaker 3:  natural language interfaces using the cameras interface. All this stuff starts
Speaker 3:  to take over from traditional PCs more and more and more. This has been the
Speaker 3:  dream for a long time. There's a, I, you know, there's a reason that Google
Speaker 3:  and Microsoft, everybody else calls AI a a platform shift. And if
Speaker 3:  that happens, like my sales go down, right?
Speaker 3:  Like we, if we use desktop computers left and we talk to our phones more
Speaker 3:  or whatever, maybe the say like PC sales will go down and
Speaker 3:  then my sales go down and then we just like if you're Logitech, you're like,
Speaker 3:  well how do I preserve the revenue? And, and you're like gold plated diamond
Speaker 3:  and crusted subscription nights and like maybe that's not the right solution,
Speaker 3:  But You can see the pressure. It's like, it was, it was a good conversation
Speaker 3:  that I was not expecting just that little bit to, to resonate as much as
Speaker 3:  it does. That said we have to find the brother laser printers of mice.
Speaker 3:  Oh, oh my gosh. The other thing there were tiktoks about subscription mice
Speaker 3:  and that put me into like people complaining about subscriptions TikTok.
Speaker 3:  And then I got to one where a very nice like young woman was like
Speaker 3:  bitching about her. A very nice woman. It got me to one
Speaker 3:  where I think an influencer, she was just complaining about her subscription
Speaker 3:  printer and all the comments are like, buy a brother laser printer. And I
Speaker 3:  was like,
Speaker 3:  I did it. Like The Verge has accomplished its goal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. One thing we stand for. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Buy one piece of heart. It lasts forever. And I think The Verge stands
Speaker 3:  for that. Yeah. All right, so that's lightning round one. It feels like we're
Speaker 3:  on a consensus that we're not gonna do AI powered subscription mice.
Speaker 4:  No. Don't like it. Don't want it. No, absolutely not. The
Speaker 3:  Idea that your mouse is the one that creates the prompt for open ai
Speaker 3:  s like it's bold. You know, it's,
Speaker 4:  It's an idea that sounds like a mouse wrote it.
Speaker 3:  If you're a diehard options plus ecosystem person,
Speaker 3:  write us a note. Alright, so, okay, here's, here's the other two where I'm
Speaker 3:  just gonna read a bunch of headlines for lightning Round. The first, very
Speaker 3:  much related to what we've been talking about with photos, there's just a
Speaker 3:  bunch of deep fake news this week. Everyone knows it's a problem. We
Speaker 3:  know we gotta stop it. And then some people are like, screw it, we're doing
Speaker 3:  it anyway. And by some people, I mean Elon Musk who posted a deep fake
Speaker 3:  video of Kamala Harris that violates X's own policies
Speaker 3:  about deep fake that were implemented under his ownership.
Speaker 3:  This isn't like there was an old rule that he disagrees with and he is bulldozing
Speaker 3:  it. He made a rule about D fakes 'cause everyone knows this problem. And
Speaker 3:  then he posted this ad with Harris, it's like Harris's campaign
Speaker 3:  ad with the Beyonce song, but they replaced the voiceover
Speaker 3:  with her saying Biden is too old.
Speaker 3:  Okay. You know, like in many ways this is like, this is just
Speaker 3:  standard political parody. Like if I hired a Kamala Harris impersonator to
Speaker 3:  do this, would it be a problem? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I don't know. But if you already have the rule that's like, don't do this,
Speaker 3:  you should not. Yeah, you should not as the owner of the platform do it.
Speaker 3:  So he doesn't care. He doesn't give a shit. But that's where we are, right?
Speaker 3:  It's like already happening. There's already these like weird moments occurring
Speaker 3:  because of just bad faith actors on both sides. On in
Speaker 3:  particular one side. But it's already happening. Then
Speaker 3:  here's the rest of the headlines. Microsoft wants Congress to
Speaker 3:  outlaw, AI generated DeepFakes Google tweaks, search
Speaker 3:  to hide explicit DeepFakes. So if Google
Speaker 3:  drans your website or knocks your website for having DeepFakes on it, especially,
Speaker 3:  especially explicit ones search won't show them to people anymore. They're
Speaker 3:  just gonna go away from search
Speaker 3:  Congress want to, wants to carve out intimate DAID
Speaker 3:  fakes, which is basically what you, what there's a, there's a language conversation
Speaker 3:  here about what you should call these. So you might call these like AI revenge
Speaker 3:  porn.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 3:  Revenge porn is like a very loaded word for a lot of reasons. So now we're
Speaker 3:  gonna try AI intimate AI deep fakes. So
Speaker 3:  you carve that out from section two 30, right? So that means right now if
Speaker 3:  you post stuff to a platform like Facebook or X or Instagram or whatever,
Speaker 3:  those platforms are not liable for what you post. That's section two 30.
Speaker 3:  It makes the internet go round. And they're saying no, actually if you allow
Speaker 3:  intimate AI deep fakes, you are now liable for them. Like you as, and that
Speaker 3:  basically means you have to moderate them. So that's one idea. And then
Speaker 3:  the copyright office
Speaker 3:  just issued a huge report on AI and copyright, which they've been working
Speaker 3:  on for quite some time. And their first chapter of this report was about
Speaker 3:  DeepFakes. And they're, they're You can read. It's very long. It's very good.
Speaker 3:  It's very easy to read. We will, we'll link to it in the show notes here.
Speaker 3:  But they're basically like, yeah, copyright law can't do this. We need a
Speaker 3:  new law. This is a disaster. Here's how we think the new law should work.
Speaker 3:  So we're just at this moment where everyone is seeing the problem very clearly.
Speaker 3:  And then lastly, in the Senate, the no fakes
Speaker 3:  act has been introduced. It's not close to passing, but
Speaker 3:  yet another bill to ban de fakes. It's to regulate d fakes. So we're at this
Speaker 3:  point now where everybody sees the problem, right? Google is a
Speaker 3:  platform, is doing some stuff to stop it. Microsoft as a company is
Speaker 3:  asking Congress to outlaw it. The government is like, we don't have the
Speaker 3:  laws to do it. Some parts of the governments are saying we need to do it.
Speaker 3:  It feels like this is the first big AI regulation that's gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  It feels like that's also the first one that has to happen.
Speaker 2:  Deep fakes, bad deep fakes bad. So yeah, I, yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's like the Spider-Man pointing at Spider-Man meme. And we're like, what?
Speaker 4:  What's going on? Who's in charge here? Like Elon Musk is
Speaker 4:  making rules about deep fakes and then not following those rules, not following
Speaker 4:  them. The government is like, yeah, we don't know.
Speaker 3:  I agree. Defect's bad. Especially the, the ones that are being used to harass
Speaker 3:  people and intimidate people and bully people. Like those are,
Speaker 3:  I think, fully bad And. if you read that copyright office report, they're
Speaker 3:  like, a lot of our law right now is set up to protect famous people like
Speaker 3:  that patchwork of state likeness laws and publicity laws
Speaker 3:  are all basically like if you're a celebrity and Samsung
Speaker 3:  uses you to sell refrigerators, you can't do that.
Speaker 3:  And I say that because that is a real case that happened in our justice system
Speaker 3:  where Samsung made a robot that looked like Vanna White to solve refrigerators
Speaker 3:  and Vanna White sued Samsung and won Oh my God. Because the robot looked
Speaker 3:  too much like Vanna White real case. Real, this is a real thing that happened.
Speaker 3:  Oh my god. And that's like all of, all of our law right now is set up to
Speaker 3:  deal with that problem, which is wonderful. But it's all for famous. Like
Speaker 3:  you have to be famous enough so that people can be confused about, but
Speaker 3:  it, regular people have no protection. 'cause none of them are famous.
Speaker 3:  So the copyright office is saying, no, this problem is gonna affect regular
Speaker 3:  people. It's gonna affect teenage girls in schools. It already is. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  affect teenage boys in schools. It's gonna affect everybody. It's if you
Speaker 3:  don't like your teacher and You can fake that. Like all of this bullying
Speaker 3:  that can happen with DeepFakes is real. It's happening now and we don't have
Speaker 3:  the laws to stop it. So then you say we could stop it. But that brings you
Speaker 3:  all the way back around to, well what if I just hire a Trump impersonator
Speaker 3:  to look at a camera and be like, I'm bad. You know? Like
Speaker 3:  that is straightforwardly like political speech. It should be protected.
Speaker 3:  The line there is really blurry and I think we're, we're
Speaker 3:  in for maybe a pendulum swing pretty far in the direction of all of
Speaker 3:  that is not allowed. And then over time we're gonna have to swing it back
Speaker 3:  to, well you should probably be allowed to hire the Elvis impersonator, right?
Speaker 3:  He's dead
Speaker 3:  right. But should the, should the Taylor Swift impersonator at the one casino
Speaker 3:  be allowed to act like Taylor Swift? Like probably where, how
Speaker 3:  are you gonna draw that line? It's pretty unclear right now.
Speaker 2:  Well what do SNL do at that point? 'cause then their whole thing is
Speaker 2:  just like, man, I don't envy the people at the
Speaker 2:  copyright office or anywhere just trying to like proactively
Speaker 2:  think about how to deal with this. 'cause it's, it's a lot easier when it's
Speaker 2:  reactionary when you're like, oh, bad thing happened. We need to do something.
Speaker 2:  But then to actually think of it in a proactive manner and be like, how are
Speaker 2:  people going to use this? Well, I don't know. We're only as good
Speaker 2:  as the, we're only as good as the most unhinged teenage
Speaker 2:  boy in the classroom. Just thinking up of the most
Speaker 2:  crazy way to use these things. Like
Speaker 3:  I was that boy and don't allow me to have access to
Speaker 3:  computers. That was a real mistake the whole time.
Speaker 3:  Allison, you, I mean you, we talk about photos and cameras and device makers
Speaker 3:  all the time. You know, Google is changing search to hide explicit
Speaker 3:  DeepFakes. Microsoft wants regulations. Do you see that expressed in the
Speaker 3:  products that they're making at all? It's like, it's funny that they're kind
Speaker 3:  of like asking for someone to make rules on what they can and can't do.
Speaker 3:  And if they don't have the rules, they won't stop themselves.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's a weird thing of like, they're all sort of
Speaker 4:  like, well we definitely agree that, you know, fake
Speaker 4:  bad stuff is bad, so but here,
Speaker 4:  draw a chicken into your photo or you know, it's sort of like
Speaker 4:  there's no agreement between like, and we're going to
Speaker 4:  slow down and wait till we've figured this out. Or you know,
Speaker 4:  like have some kind of
Speaker 4:  industry standard that these things are like
Speaker 4:  abiding by. It's just sort of like, well we're just gonna run as fast
Speaker 4:  as we can over here. And then like, eh, some people will figure out
Speaker 4:  the laws,
Speaker 2:  Right? See Allison and I told you the blurry bumblebee, it absolutely
Speaker 2:  can destroy the fabric of our society. You said it wouldn't shoot,
Speaker 2:  but it can,
Speaker 4:  It all started with the Bumblebee.
Speaker 3:  Well it's like the, I'll just accuse the no fakes act, which I, I think by
Speaker 3:  the time you listen to this should be in the Senate.
Speaker 3:  This is basically a reaction to open AI and Scarlet Cha Hansen,
Speaker 3:  you know, the New Voice is out with open ai. It's actually really impressive
Speaker 3:  in like very cool ways. But obviously they made a voice that sounded a lot
Speaker 3:  like Scar Johansen. She's really mad. She might sue them a whole kerfuffle.
Speaker 3:  That's a great time for politicians to act, be like a kerfuffle. Here's some
Speaker 3:  stuff that I'm doing. So they had a discussion graph last year. They
Speaker 3:  updated it, they have it this year. And now
Speaker 3:  the goal is to give people a federal property, right?
Speaker 3:  To approve the use of their voice appearance or likeness and ex and
Speaker 3:  create liability to people who use their voice appearance
Speaker 3:  or likeness without permission. Okay. That's like a lot.
Speaker 3:  But again, SNL exists again. Like
Speaker 3:  Trump impersonators exist.
Speaker 3:  I sometimes do a British accent. I don't know if I sound like a British person
Speaker 3:  who's real. Like there's, there's, I I think we're probably in for a moment
Speaker 3:  where the pendulum swings way, way too far. And that might be
Speaker 3:  fine, but I, we just need to like be alert for it. 'cause that pendulum swing
Speaker 3:  too far might be appropriate given how damaging deep fakes can be, especially
Speaker 3:  for younger people, especially in these non-consensual intimate ways.
Speaker 3:  But it's also like, oh man, like you might go, you might just dial impersonation
Speaker 3:  along the way and we just like, dunno the answer yet. But there's a lot of
Speaker 3:  that action happening it seems to the company. So that's lightning round
Speaker 3:  one. Lightning round two sort of related to this last week,
Speaker 3:  last week, David, I'm just gonna call David after this. He titled the episode
Speaker 3:  the End of Google as we know it. And I was like, bro,
Speaker 3:  you just mean search generally. I was like, yeah, I'm going on vacation.
Speaker 3:  He changed it.
Speaker 3:  So we changed it. But we, we were, we're, we're basically at a moment and
Speaker 3:  that was the, the real thesis of last week's episode is that the entire like
Speaker 3:  web and search market is changing and we keyed that off of
Speaker 3:  Reddit getting Google to pay it for, to index the site and then
Speaker 3:  blocking everybody else. So there are some backlash to that, right? That's
Speaker 3:  the closing of the open web. So suddenly the only way to search
Speaker 3:  Reddit with a search engine is Google. Weird. That's a weird new outcome
Speaker 3:  that we didn't have before. Microsoft has, you know, been blocked. Perplexity
Speaker 3:  is blocked. Reddit, CEO, Steve Offman talked to our own Alex Heath this week.
Speaker 3:  He's like, everybody needs to pay me.
Speaker 3:  He's like bing, anthropic, perplexity. We've all been at after them.
Speaker 3:  And then the big quote is, it's a real pain in the ass to block these companies.
Speaker 3:  So he just wants money and this looks like the future, right? We just want
Speaker 3:  money. If you want to, if you wanna build an AI powered search engine at
Speaker 3:  crawler site. Similarly perplexity, which has gotten itself into
Speaker 3:  a lot of trouble, especially showing paywall the content without paying
Speaker 3:  anyone. They're just scraping sites and a lot of trouble about scraping
Speaker 3:  sites even though it's blocked, which they keep saying like, you don't know
Speaker 3:  how the web works. And I'm always like, tell me, tell me how you think
Speaker 3:  it works. And they won't say, but Perplexity has started cutting checks
Speaker 3:  to publishers
Speaker 3:  Time Dr. Spiegel, which big German publisher and Fortune are in the first
Speaker 3:  batch. I assume there will be more. I feel like I need to disclose, OpenAI
Speaker 3:  pays our company, Vox Media for its search, GPT product.
Speaker 3:  You can just put that on the list, right? OpenAI is paying the Atlantic and
Speaker 3:  a bunch of other publishers as well. New York Times is suing OpenAI because
Speaker 3:  it wants more money than it's presumably been offered. So like this thing
Speaker 3:  that's like, you've gotta pay search engines have to
Speaker 3:  pay to index our content on the open web is not just
Speaker 3:  like a blip. It's the thing that's happening. Like it is
Speaker 3:  the change that is happening across the industry. Everybody wants to get
Speaker 3:  paid, especially from the new breed of search engines. 'cause everybody made
Speaker 3:  the mistake with Google where they didn't ask for money and now Google's
Speaker 3:  like, we're doing AI anyway and no one can turn Google off.
Speaker 3:  Right next to that we, I mentioned circle to searches everywhere.
Speaker 3:  Desktop Chrome is getting something that looks a lot like circle to search.
Speaker 3:  So you see Google's building AI search ish experiences right into the
Speaker 3:  browser. And then Chrome is also getting an AI product
Speaker 3:  comparison mode where if you have a bunch of products open in tabs, Chrome
Speaker 3:  will just synthesize the tabs and build a comparison for you, which is legitimately
Speaker 3:  very cool. And at least you get to have to load the webpage. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Which is like
Speaker 4:  A good step. We love that. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But you see the, the web is just fully changing like
Speaker 3:  a, whatever you think AI is doing to productivity or workers
Speaker 3:  or whatever right now, at this moment, how we think
Speaker 3:  about the web and in particular search on the web, it's already,
Speaker 3:  it's the past is passed. Like it's gone. It's in the rear view mirror. We
Speaker 3:  might only be a little bit far away from it, but it's not coming back
Speaker 3:  like we are. We're just in a mode where you're gonna sign up to use a search
Speaker 3:  engine and maybe it will have a different set of sources than the next
Speaker 3:  search engine based on the deals they have made. Which is gonna be really
Speaker 3:  weird.
Speaker 4:  It's just strikes me every time, you know, Reddit comes
Speaker 4:  up, is that like we're racing to have, you know, Google
Speaker 4:  wants to answer your question without you clicking on anything you
Speaker 4:  chatbots wanna answer your question or like robots can answer your
Speaker 4:  question. But then also like Reddit is incredibly
Speaker 4:  valuable and it's just people talking to people. Like that's the thing that,
Speaker 4:  you know, we wanna get to in search now where I'm like,
Speaker 4:  you know, I have a question about my plant or whatever. It's like, I
Speaker 4:  don't want the AI generated answer. I don't want
Speaker 4:  whatever blurb, like I want to read an answer from a
Speaker 4:  person. And it's just strange to me that that's at the center of this. Like,
Speaker 4:  what if you could just talk to robots? It's like,
Speaker 4:  but the robots need to listen to a person who knows the answer.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, and Reddit is itself being polluted with AI generated text.
Speaker 3:  So that's the next turn. And then on top of it all the new information
Speaker 3:  is a bunch of kids talking to TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. And like,
Speaker 3:  And we found, we found out this week that TikTok is one of the biggest customers
Speaker 3:  of open ai because they're using all that for the recognition algorithms
Speaker 3:  and sorting and tr like, and you're like, oh, this is a weird little circle
Speaker 3:  where it's, there are gonna be more silos on the internet than ever before
Speaker 3:  because the open web did not make enough of the people
Speaker 3:  who make the original content enough money.
Speaker 3:  And so like no one wants to repeat that. So now it's like you gotta
Speaker 3:  pay us. And like, whether that actually comes back to individual redditors
Speaker 3:  who are contributing remains to be seen. But Reddit itself, Steve Huff's
Speaker 3:  like, yeah, I'm just gonna block you. Like I got my money from Google and
Speaker 3:  now everyone else is blocked unless they pay up. And I think You can do it
Speaker 3:  'cause he just needs Google. Like Google's gonna send Reddit a lot of traffic
Speaker 3:  and that's fine. You can block Bing and be like, pay up or you're dead.
Speaker 3:  And I think eventually they're all gonna end up paying because if you have
Speaker 3:  an AI search product that can't look at Reddit, I think a lot of people are
Speaker 3:  like, well where's the good stuff? And you're gonna, you're just gonna end
Speaker 3:  up in a weird loop. We've been covering this a lot. Like we over a
Speaker 3:  year now, we, we covered sort of the end of the SEO industry and what that
Speaker 3:  did to the web and all this stuff. 'cause we wanted to mark like, this is
Speaker 3:  what it looks like now. And I didn't, I honestly did
Speaker 3:  not expect it to feel as different as fast as it feels today.
Speaker 3:  Like the, the end of the search era that we knew is I think just
Speaker 3:  firmly here. And You can see even this week it's just like, here's six more
Speaker 3:  headlines that are just like, here's how it's changing.
Speaker 4:  I keep thinking about a friend who she was buying a new mattress
Speaker 4:  and she's like, I just asked Claude. Yeah, Claude did it for me, Claude.
Speaker 4:  I was like, yeah, which is the, oh, which one? It's not
Speaker 4:  Perplexity. It's Anthropic. It's Anthropic. Yeah. Oh
Speaker 2:  God.
Speaker 4:  And it was just like, my eyes get wider. I'm like, put the little
Speaker 4:  mattress review.com that it was scraping. You know, I don't know. That's
Speaker 4:  a whole minefield too. No,
Speaker 2:  My husband does it. My husband is like an avid chat GPT as
Speaker 2:  a search engine user before it even had this project. And
Speaker 2:  like he's been using Gemini and all the other stuff. And he'll be like, oh
Speaker 2:  yeah, I just asked that. This is how I built some code for this and this
Speaker 2:  is how I like, 'cause he just, Google just doesn't give him the answers that
Speaker 2:  he needs anymore. And so like, I've just been watching them just completely
Speaker 2:  shift how they use the internet over the last year. And I'm just doing the
Speaker 2:  same things that I have always done. And I just am like, hmm,
Speaker 2:  this, this, this feels like getting left behind. Maybe I should try
Speaker 2:  using it. Maybe I should try using it more in the ways that they
Speaker 2:  do. But I just run into the same problem as you do Alison, where I'm just
Speaker 2:  like, I just, I don't like the source that they pull from in these, in
Speaker 2:  these things. So I'm just like, oh, that's, I don't trust rando blog
Speaker 2:  site.com. Give me the other
Speaker 3:  Ones. Hey, I started ran blog site.com all by myself. 10 years all
Speaker 2:  Are ran. Blog site do com
Speaker 4:  Respect your elders.
Speaker 3:  Hey, that was my first website.
Speaker 3:  You know, I've been using chacha for Olympics trivia. 'cause I assume that
Speaker 3:  the, you know, like, it's like what's this cable on the fencer is like,
Speaker 3:  that answer's been the same for a long time, right? Yeah. And so you just
Speaker 3:  like, I have chat mapped the action button on my iPhone 15 pro
Speaker 3:  and it works like it just delivers an answer to you and you're like, I didn't
Speaker 3:  even know. That's right. Right. It's, it's like close enough. Yeah. and
Speaker 4:  It stakes are low.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's like, it's part of the scoring system. I hope that's true. You
Speaker 3:  know? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You're not like judging the fencing like
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  The judges are not using that.
Speaker 3:  Actually we have a big feature we on this week about AI being used to judge
Speaker 3:  gymnastics. You should read that. It's very good. I mentioned that because
Speaker 3:  we are way over.
Speaker 7:  Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you. Give us a call at eight six six
Speaker 7:  VERGE one. One The. Vergecast is a production of The Verge and Vox Media
Speaker 7:  Podcast Network. Our show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 7:  That's it. We'll see you next week.