# Transcript
ID: ef534cff-be75-4ee3-85eb-fc8ec305b9eb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1630694376660347931/4192419842202868508/s93290-US-6640s-1728037707.mp3
Description: Nilay, Alex, and David discuss Microsoft's new Copilot announcements, and the friendlier face the company is trying to put on its chatbot. They also wonder: what, exactly, is an AI companion supposed to do for you, and how is it supposed to do it? They then dive into OpenAI's huge funding round, before exploring all the new gadgets of the week and some deep drama in the WordPress universe. Finally, it's time for a lightning round of news about Dish and DirecTV, Progressive Web Apps, and Nintendo's fight against emulation. We also send off Alex, our sadly departing co-host, with cake and Plex servers.
Speaker 7:  David Pierce is
Speaker 9:  Here. Hi. I, for many months just
Speaker 9:  wore gray t-shirts on every episode of The Vergecast and I legitimately do
Speaker 9:  own many gray t-shirts. I'm like the old Mark Zuckerberg who just
Speaker 9:  opens a closet and I have like 15 identical things and that's what I wear
Speaker 9:  every day. Dude knew what he was doing. I envy you. This new thing he's doing.
Speaker 9:  Wrong idea. Go back to the gray t-shirts
Speaker 7:  Mark. Yeah. Every day he's gotta pick a new Latin phrase. Yeah, yeah. That's
Speaker 7:  a lot. No one needs
Speaker 9:  That.
Speaker 8:  It's just gonna be like I'm tired in
Speaker 7:  Latin. The very end. He's like, I've been defeated Latin.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. By the way, also the flagship podcast of our game Cube, the Hena Cube.
Speaker 7:  Thanks to my friend Gabe who really thought I was gonna send that back to
Speaker 7:  him. Oh, poor Gabe.
Speaker 9:  The now multi podcast, multi-platform, potentially
Speaker 9:  award-winning podcast adjacent.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Game Cube because they redesigned the studio and we put our game cube
Speaker 7:  in the corner and then all the other Vox Media podcasts are in here and they
Speaker 7:  don't take it down.
Speaker 8:  So now every podcast is sponsored by Heineken. It's fine.
Speaker 7:  I'm sure Megan Rapinoe and Sue Bird don't have thoughts about that at all.
Speaker 7:  Nope. Anyway, please watch the rest of the shows on Vox Media podcast network
Speaker 7:  of which the Vergecast remains the flagship. Alright, there's a lot.
Speaker 7:  Let's not edit that out. But If, you work at Vox Media. Just pretend you
Speaker 7:  edited that out in your mind. There's a lot to talk about this week. A lot.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Some controversies. I think we might break a little news on
Speaker 7:  this show.
Speaker 7:  AI announcements, funding deals and then we got a lightning round,
Speaker 7:  which remains unsponsored. Sure, that's your fault
Speaker 7:  because some of you control ad budgets and then there's someone here at this
Speaker 7:  company that you should talk to who is not me that you should spend that
Speaker 7:  money on. That's how it works. Here in
Speaker 8:  Or you can Venmo us.
Speaker 7:  We can Venmo. Alex directly.
Speaker 8:  Venmo me. I'll take it.
Speaker 7:  See If. you can co cop the number of sneaky ad reads Alex does throughout
Speaker 7:  the show.
Speaker 7:  All right, so I've got a rundown here. We gotta talk about copilot. There's
Speaker 7:  open ai, big funding round Gavin Newsom vetoed to major AI
Speaker 7:  safety bill. But on the rundown, David has written in bold letters.
Speaker 7:  But first. David has a question. David
Speaker 9:  Has a
Speaker 7:  Question. David, what's your question?
Speaker 9:  So you two are display nerds. I would say, I am not a display nerd. So. I.
Speaker 9:  I have a, I have a thing that I would like to present you with that
Speaker 9:  surprised me greatly. And I would like you to react and tell me how to feel
Speaker 9:  So. I bought a new iPhone. I bought a a blue iPhone 16. I decided instead
Speaker 9:  of going pro that's pretty, I was gonna go regular 'cause it's like a little
Speaker 9:  lighter. The blue is hot.
Speaker 7:  That's the one. That's the one this year. Easily
Speaker 9:  The, this is the best looking phone Apple has made in a very long time. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  I think this color is awesome. Like it's great and
Speaker 7:  Moving the camera is really did a thing there. It
Speaker 9:  Really did. It's really nice. So I bought this one, brought
Speaker 9:  it home and I think on the same day that I bought it, Federico
Speaker 9:  Vichi at max stories wrote a thing about how he had gone from a pro
Speaker 9:  to a regular iPhone. And it turns out this is like a bit of a trend, especially
Speaker 9:  because of the colors. There are a lot of people I've heard from like the,
Speaker 9:  the nerd pro users who have gone to the iPhone
Speaker 9:  16. Michael Fisher, Mr. Mobile is one of 'em. He, he made a great video about
Speaker 9:  it.
Speaker 9:  I would say in in shocking numbers, both to me and
Speaker 9:  to all of those other people. The overwhelming response from people is what?
Speaker 9:  How are you gonna live without promotion? What's wrong with you? Do you not
Speaker 9:  have eyes? How refresh rates? How do you survive? And
Speaker 9:  if I'm gonna be completely honest with you, I have not noticed. I
Speaker 9:  could not, I could not tell you the difference in my phone experience between
Speaker 9:  one and the other. But I am also not a display nerd. I have a 42
Speaker 9:  inch junkie TCL TV behind me. Don me. Stop. Say that. That will attest
Speaker 9:  to that So I I bring to you the display nerds.
Speaker 9:  How big a deal is it that I lost promotion. And all the people who are worried
Speaker 9:  about losing promotion on the iPhone, should they be worried? If
Speaker 8:  You're worried about losing promotion, then yeah, you should be worried because
Speaker 8:  you care that much. But 90% of people aren't gonna
Speaker 8:  notice the difference. We see this all the time with refresh rate stuff like
Speaker 8:  once you hit 30, most people aren't gonna notice. But
Speaker 8:  then some people are like ne will definitely notice. I can see him noticing
Speaker 8:  right now. I'm thinking like, no Kranz is wrong.
Speaker 7:  I think Kranz is moving at too low of a refresh rate right now.
Speaker 7:  IRL speed it up double.
Speaker 8:  Sorry, sorry, sorry. I just gotta, I don't know how to do a fast refresh
Speaker 8:  rate.
Speaker 7:  You know, my feeling on this is the the things you can see, you
Speaker 7:  can see and the things you can't see, you can't. And that is, is
Speaker 7:  just like pretty much that simple. And I think a lot of people are
Speaker 7:  very sensitive to motion. Like more than we That's fair.
Speaker 7:  More than we suspect. So If, you are the sort of person who
Speaker 7:  can see tearing on a screen or the jelly
Speaker 7:  effect. You're gonna really see it. You're just gonna see it.
Speaker 7:  And a lot of people can't. The jelly effect is when the screen
Speaker 7:  controller, the electronics that con controls the screen is on one side.
Speaker 7:  And so that side refreshes a little bit faster than the right side. And you
Speaker 7:  can see the thing just warp as you scroll. I can see that every time,
Speaker 7:  every time it's a curse. 99%
Speaker 7:  of people I don't think can see it and you shouldn't worry about it. And
Speaker 7:  that's why most screens have that effect. 'cause you can minimize it
Speaker 7:  to the point where it doesn't bother most people. So
Speaker 9:  You're a hundred percent confident that if I handed you two identical devices,
Speaker 9:  one at 120 hertz and one at 60, you could immediately tell the difference.
Speaker 7:  I could. So promotion makes it hard, right? 'cause it's always changing,
Speaker 7:  right? So, I don't know. I think on scroll, if I, if I started
Speaker 7:  scrolling them, I could. But if they're both playing videos
Speaker 7:  and the promotion one has fallen back to 24 and the other one is
Speaker 7:  interpolating frames to get to 60 No. On a phone, no,
Speaker 7:  but on scroll I can probably see it. Okay. It doesn't bother me. I I'm actually
Speaker 7:  not that sensitive to it. But I, what I am
Speaker 7:  sensitive to is like
Speaker 7:  all those emotion artifacts, like I, the the weird screen tearing and
Speaker 7:  all that stuff and promotion minimizes it. So yeah, I, I, I,
Speaker 7:  there, you know, there's like videos on there of like people with that weird
Speaker 7:  app that puts the frame counter in front of the display and they're like,
Speaker 7:  it's only eight. It's like, you guys are all crazy. Like who cares?
Speaker 8:  I think you're right though. If, you can see it then you can see it. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And it's, it's in, yeah, you should probably spend a little more money and
Speaker 8:  If you can't see it. Enjoy having cheaper devices.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like a lot of people own Toyotas and then
Speaker 7:  some people have Lexuses and If. you take a
Speaker 7:  real hard look at the cheapest Lexus and the most expensive Toyota,
Speaker 7:  they're the same car. You know? Yes. It's like
Speaker 7:  on the, on the finest edge of difference there. Right. And that's really
Speaker 7:  what I think for a lot of people, it promotion represents except
Speaker 7:  for the people who are like, Nope, I can see it.
Speaker 9:  I see. Okay. So it's a little bit like, like I always tell people one of
Speaker 9:  the dumbest financial decisions you can make is developing a taste for good
Speaker 9:  wine. Because If, you think $6 wine tastes good,
Speaker 9:  you're gonna live such a happy, easy, simple life of
Speaker 9:  delicious wine. And then when you discover that actually 60
Speaker 9:  and $600 wine tastes much better, you're screwed. So like
Speaker 9:  don't ever learn that. Just, just enjoy, enjoy
Speaker 9:  your crappy $6 wine and life is fine. You
Speaker 9:  like,
Speaker 8:  Oh no, you could just smoke cigarettes and then, then it'll all taste the
Speaker 8:  same. And you're fine.
Speaker 7:  So I, don't know if my mom's listening to this episode. No further comment,
Speaker 7:  mom.
Speaker 7:  I don't, I mean I, you should have some taste.
Speaker 7:  I recommend finding the things that make you happy and,
Speaker 7:  and spending money on those things. But I, chasing a display spec
Speaker 7:  If, you can't see it in motion is one of those things where I think people
Speaker 7:  can see it or they can't. I can't teach you to see motion. I can teach you
Speaker 7:  to see motion smoothing and then I will have ruined your life.
Speaker 9:  Yes. Agreed. Right?
Speaker 7:  Yes. And so that's like one of those things where, okay, now I can see it.
Speaker 7:  I just need to turn this off. Or If, you have a Roku tv, they're gonna lie
Speaker 7:  to you and not let you turn it off. Which is still an ongoing scandal.
Speaker 7:  But like the, the refresh rate of the screen is like either do you see it
Speaker 7:  or you don't? I I think it's the same with there's like ultra
Speaker 7:  crazy high refresh rates on, on, on, on monitors now.
Speaker 7:  And I asked Tom Warn like, does anyone even, can anyone see this? And he
Speaker 7:  was just very confident, like, PC gamers can. And I was like, okay,
Speaker 8:  Only some It's, it's it's,
Speaker 7:  I'm out. Like I I'm not fighting that fight. It,
Speaker 8:  It's counterstrike, right? Like, like it's the people who play the twits
Speaker 8:  twitches games. Yeah. Yeah. And they can see it because they're, they're
Speaker 8:  like, yeah, that one millisecond means I can get a headshot or not. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  No one else can because none of us are trading our brains that way. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. If if, if this, if the refresh rate is the difference between you and
Speaker 7:  a, a rewarding career in eSports, God bless you. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's not for me. I don't
Speaker 7:  Care. But yeah, I I think the promotion one on the iPhone, the, the, the
Speaker 7:  thing that you will actually see and you have a kid and I would just,
Speaker 7:  I mean it's blue and it's a beautiful phone and it's probably fine. The camera
Speaker 7:  on the pro is substantially better. Yes. Like the main camera is substantially
Speaker 7:  better on the pro, but it doesn't matter 'cause they're, they all just kind
Speaker 7:  of HDR to hell and back and fine like spend your money in a good
Speaker 7:  camera and the regular iPhone 16. Terrific compromise.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That's kind of where I'm landing. I'm like, I bought this phone
Speaker 9:  at the beginning of a year in which I'm going to try to do fewer things on
Speaker 9:  my phone, including like chase my child around. So
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna figure out new ways to take pictures.
Speaker 7:  You're gonna a flip cam and, and like a beautiful Rico
Speaker 7:  camera like for stills. There you go. I love it. I can't wait for you to
Speaker 7:  have just a full dad utility belt.
Speaker 8:  Little fanny
Speaker 7:  Pack. Just like, you know how like the, the dominant story in technology
Speaker 7:  is convergence to the phone. David has the divergence belt just 60
Speaker 7:  gadgets
Speaker 9:  Except it's definitely gonna be like a diaper bag just full of gadgets. People
Speaker 9:  will be like, do you have any snacks in there? I'll be like, no. Just cameras.
Speaker 7:  Alright, good question David. Thank you. I would
Speaker 7:  say that that was a lot of people,
Speaker 7:  the promotion fan boys, if there are, if there's such a thing as variable
Speaker 7:  refresh rate fan boys, you're out there. We appreciate you.
Speaker 9:  Oh, for sure. I think it's totally valid. And I was just, the thing that
Speaker 9:  surprised me most was that the overwhelming feedback I got and others got
Speaker 9:  was not what are you gonna do without the camera? What are you gonna do without
Speaker 9:  the extra screen size? What are you gonna do without the bigger battery?
Speaker 9:  It was promotion like overwhelmingly that was the feature people said they
Speaker 9:  couldn't live without. And I was just very surprised by that. You just have
Speaker 9:  a
Speaker 10:  Lot of counterstrike players that,
Speaker 9:  That bother you evidently. Yeah. That's awesome. And and again, God bless
Speaker 9:  all of you, but
Speaker 7:  I'm also saying the people who can see it can really see it. And I think
Speaker 7:  there's more people who can see it than you think I
Speaker 9:  Buy it. I totally do. I'm just not one of those people.
Speaker 7:  Alright, let's talk about Microsoft. They had a lot of announcements this
Speaker 7:  week. Would you call it a new version of copilot?
Speaker 7:  Not really. I,
Speaker 9:  I cleaned up I think so it's a new vibe for copilot. It's like,
Speaker 9:  yeah, it feels different in a way that I actually think is really important.
Speaker 9:  Like copilot was headed down this road of
Speaker 9:  being just a tool inside of office that was like
Speaker 9:  very businessy and very focused on helping you write emails and get
Speaker 9:  stuff done. And they made this shift now to something that like
Speaker 9:  looks and feels and wants to be very
Speaker 9:  different, which is different for Microsoft, sort
Speaker 9:  of odd strategically given like what the company is and what they've been
Speaker 9:  pushing towards. But I think it's really different. I do
Speaker 7:  So I wanna talk about what is different and new about actual copilot
Speaker 7:  the Microsoft product that has been redesigned. You know, they,
Speaker 7:  they quote unquote bought inflection by hiring all of its employees and the
Speaker 7:  CO and making the CEO of inflection the CEO of Microsoft ai, but they didn't
Speaker 7:  actually buy the company. Yeah know there's probably like one
Speaker 9:  Guy still working
Speaker 7:  There. Like the what the, the Lean con loophole. That's what they,
Speaker 7:  that's they call it down in the Silicon Valley.
Speaker 9:  You just like don't buy the domain name and you're good.
Speaker 7:  So he did all that and then, you know, this new product looks a lot like
Speaker 7:  inflection. We should come to that. I I wanna take one step back. David,
Speaker 7:  you and I have been talking about this moment in AI
Speaker 7:  kind of broadly and it feels like every company has realized the models
Speaker 7:  are whatever, they're all kind of the same and we have to build a set of
Speaker 7:  products and all of the products are the same idea. We're gonna go do stuff
Speaker 7:  for you. And it it, this feels like part of that is that,
Speaker 7:  I know you've talked to a bunch of people, you've seen a bunch of these products
Speaker 7:  Now is that just the shape of like, we have to build a product and the only
Speaker 7:  product anybody can think of is an agent
Speaker 9:  Basically. Yeah, I think we're, we're at a moment now where
Speaker 9:  these things have to be more than just novelties and the
Speaker 9:  quickest way to get there is to make them actually live out the
Speaker 9:  idea of being assistants, right? So we're seeing like Rabbit, which
Speaker 9:  did a lot of work to actually like popularize this idea earlier this year
Speaker 9:  with the large action model thing. Launched
Speaker 7:  The large action model.
Speaker 9:  A beta of a beta of a beta of a thing pretending to be the large action.
Speaker 9:  Like we can litigate that If you want to to, but, but the
Speaker 9:  idea is essentially like these are things that can go accomplish things on
Speaker 9:  your behalf, right? And those things are not just write an
Speaker 9:  email or make a deck for you. Like the thing everyone
Speaker 9:  always talks about is travel, everyone like I should say,
Speaker 9:  I need to be in San Francisco next Tuesday at a Thursday and it,
Speaker 9:  it should in theory be able to go like book my flights
Speaker 9:  and get my hotel and put together an itinerary for me and tell me fun stuff
Speaker 9:  to do while I'm there and restaurants actually try it. And like that's what
Speaker 9:  everyone is building towards. It's that and it's multimodal search. Those
Speaker 9:  are the two things. And multimodal search I think is gonna come
Speaker 9:  faster because it's a lot more achievable with the technology that we have.
Speaker 9:  But like everyone is pushing on this idea that instead of like
Speaker 9:  opening a bunch of tabs or doing a bunch of Google searches or flipping between
Speaker 9:  a bunch of apps, you should just be able to ask your AI to do something and
Speaker 9:  it will go do all of those things for you. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  But like with travel specifically, we already have TripAdvisor and stuff,
Speaker 8:  which will always put me in Bothell instead of Seattle. It's like,
Speaker 8:  you don't, you don't wanna be in Seattle proper, you wanna be in Bothell.
Speaker 8:  And I don't, I like, I just struggle to trust these things every single
Speaker 8:  time because Bothell, that's what I think of every time that
Speaker 8:  one of these things is like, we're gonna do all of these steps Yeah. For
Speaker 8:  this really finicky thing for you and we're gonna just magically know how
Speaker 8:  to do it. And I'll be like, but you've never done that before in the history
Speaker 8:  of computers. That has never successfully happened. Instead I get bled,
Speaker 7:  I have a lot to say with this. Two things. One, I interviewed Rabbit co
Speaker 7:  Jesse Lou for a decoder that's coming out on Monday. I don't want to give
Speaker 7:  too much away about that conversation except to say it was bananas
Speaker 7:  and the thing you're describing, which is
Speaker 7:  I can have the computer go use the computer for me and then that's a little
Speaker 7:  brittle. Yeah, that's that's rabbit. That's, that's the thing they wanna
Speaker 7:  build. That's the beta, the beta, the beta literally Rabbit is
Speaker 7:  best thought of as a VNC client. Right? The rabbit device is a
Speaker 7:  VNC client to a chrome browser in, in the sky. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And I can just open Chrome on
Speaker 7:  My computer. So this is the challenge. Yeah. So I, I won't spoil too much
Speaker 7:  of that, but I spend a lot of time being like, what is it, what, what is
Speaker 7:  the thing that you've made? And the answer is a VNC client
Speaker 7:  that to a chrome browser in the sky that an AI is running for you. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Which is fascinating, but that's pretty brittle. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's all of these agents are,
Speaker 7:  the answer is we built an incredible enabling technology
Speaker 7:  that lets us see and interact with the world in sort of natural language
Speaker 7:  or to David's point, multimodal and, and voice and
Speaker 7:  images. Great. So now we have this like interaction back and forth. What
Speaker 7:  are we gonna build with this is like, if I was like, I invented Bluetooth,
Speaker 7:  it's $20 a month. Like that's kind of where we are with the
Speaker 7:  AI chatbots and now everyone has skipped all the way the head to
Speaker 7:  the final vision, which is you'll talk to the computer and
Speaker 7:  everything will happen exactly as you desire. And it doesn't seem like any
Speaker 7:  of the middle steps have been filled in. And then the vision is pretty
Speaker 7:  the enabling technology, the LLM is still pretty brittle when it tries to
Speaker 7:  go use the computer for you. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So it's like, okay, doesn't seem like you guys have actually done the thing.
Speaker 8:  I I see the vision, but also where's the execution? Or am I staying in boli?
Speaker 7:  And the, the big question that I have is, is that just because they have
Speaker 7:  to pay off all the investment or because there's nothing in the middle,
Speaker 7:  like generative fill is very cool. Microsoft announced the paint, Microsoft
Speaker 7:  paint is getting generative fill. That's sick. That's awesome.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Is that worth the money that they've invested in these?
Speaker 7:  Like, I don't know. Probably not. But hey, there's an
Speaker 7:  AI agent that you can talk to that will go do things on your behalf and that
Speaker 7:  will cost a lot of money. That seems like it's worth the money.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Well, and and I think, I think the middle step is actually
Speaker 9:  the only thing that's interesting, right? Because the, the middle step is
Speaker 9:  pointless If, you think we're gonna get to God level a
Speaker 9:  GI in 2027?
Speaker 9:  I do not believe that is going to happen. And So I think
Speaker 9:  all the interesting stuff is, is in the middle and like
Speaker 9:  it's very much on both sides. There's the, there's the underlying technology
Speaker 9:  of it all, which is can basically, can the the
Speaker 9:  vnc get better and more useful and more powerful
Speaker 9:  or are we gonna build like an API ecosystem of things
Speaker 9:  so that data providers can plug into each other and this becomes powerful
Speaker 9:  over time. Like there are a bunch of ways this could go that are really
Speaker 9:  interesting. Like Delta Airlines has lots of good reasons
Speaker 9:  to want every AI service to be able to tap into all of its data
Speaker 9:  because then I will book flights. Like there's a way in which these things
Speaker 9:  can be put together that doesn't require magical ai. But the magical
Speaker 9:  AI is also like definitely continuing to improve. But then the other question
Speaker 9:  of like, do I want to just say I need to be in
Speaker 9:  San Francisco next Tuesday and everything just magically happens,
Speaker 9:  is that the right outcome? I don't think So, I really don't. And I think
Speaker 9:  the question is like, am I gonna get to a point where I trust the AI
Speaker 9:  such that I just roll up to the airport on Tuesday and I'm like, all right
Speaker 9:  chat GPT, what do we got for me? Let's go. Or
Speaker 9:  is there like a really interesting UI question in like, okay, how does it
Speaker 9:  present that data back to me? How do we make choices together? How does it
Speaker 9:  ask me questions without being annoying and how far can you go down that
Speaker 9:  road before I'm just doing as much work as it would've been to go on kayak.com
Speaker 9:  and book the flight myself. We're at the very beginning of exploring all
Speaker 9:  of that. And it's actually why I think the new copilot is really interesting
Speaker 9:  because it is a really different UI on this stuff. Yeah. Like the copilot
Speaker 9:  app now is not just a chat bot. You don't open it up and it's an empty text
Speaker 9:  box. It's like full of prompts you go on and like the, the screenshot they
Speaker 9:  have, it says good afternoon at the top and it's this in this like beautiful
Speaker 9:  sort of warm beige colors. It's like, it looks like a meditation app. It
Speaker 7:  Also looks like inflection to be very clear. Well sure. The company they
Speaker 7:  did not buy. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Right. And inflection, I think one of the reasons people have been interested
Speaker 9:  in inflection for a long time is 'cause they've been doing smart UX stuff
Speaker 9:  on top of ai, which is very hard to do when you also have to
Speaker 9:  build your own models, but makes a lot of sense to do inside of a company
Speaker 9:  like Microsoft, which has all the other resources. But anyway, you, you go
Speaker 9:  in and it says like the, the screenshot they keep sharing says Good afternoon.
Speaker 9:  And then it offers you a bunch of things to do, right? You can go to,
Speaker 9:  it says explore skills you can learn in a month. And presumably you,
Speaker 9:  you click on that and it will essentially engage the co-pilot
Speaker 9:  model in like leading you to do a bunch of things that you can
Speaker 9:  learn how to do in a month. It says tips for meditating, which is another
Speaker 9:  one that like, that quickly turns into a text conversation, but it's like
Speaker 9:  a different way into that interface. And I just think this is
Speaker 9:  really smart and clever for Microsoft to say basically like
Speaker 9:  AI is such a discovery problem in terms of like, you open this thing up and
Speaker 9:  it's a chat bot and what do I, what do I do? How do I
Speaker 9:  ask these questions? How do I talk to this? What's available to me? What's
Speaker 9:  gonna work? How, like what is the actual correct interface for this? And
Speaker 9:  Microsoft is like starting to abstract away the text box a little bit.
Speaker 9:  And I think we're starting to see bits and pieces of like what this new interface
Speaker 9:  might look like. But even this feels like the very beginning of that
Speaker 7:  So I want to just read the quote from Mustafa Soleman who was the CEO of
Speaker 7:  inflection and is now the CEO of Microsoft ai, but reminder Microsoft did
Speaker 7:  not buy inflection.
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Makes
Speaker 7:  Sense. They just hired everybody from inflection and gave them an equivalent
Speaker 7:  amount of equity in Microsoft stock as they would've had inflection had they
Speaker 7:  bought inflection but they
Speaker 8:  Didn't buy it.
Speaker 7:  Come on. That's the old con two step. Yeah. And this is how they
Speaker 7:  describe it in the bars down the valley. All right, here's a quote from
Speaker 7:  Mustafa Litman who as the CE of Microsoft ai. And again the, this
Speaker 7:  redesign of copilots first big project at Microsoft ai, we are creating an
Speaker 7:  AI companion for everyone. He says, I truly believe we can create a
Speaker 7:  calmer, more helpful and more supportive era of technology quite unlike anything
Speaker 7:  we've seen before. I should note here that Mustapha has a, a delightful British
Speaker 7:  accent. And so when he says quite unlike anything we've seen before, you
Speaker 7:  have to imagine that in the accent. Ooh,
Speaker 8:  That sounds nice. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So this is like, the notion here is that they've made you a friend,
Speaker 7:  right? Everyone has this vision of the, you know, the
Speaker 7:  great executive assistant and I, I can't tell if they're thinking of
Speaker 7:  Jarvis or Pepper pots and I think Microsoft would much rather
Speaker 7:  have you think of Jarvis given that they're pre like
Speaker 7:  being tried to bang Kevin Ru. I don't know what else to say about that. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  like friendly but not trying to bang you is the very much the vibe they're
Speaker 7:  trying to get at like not horny.
Speaker 9:  That's the dream. That's right. That's where I aspire.
Speaker 8:  They're trying to abstract it from being human-like
Speaker 8:  and thus bankable.
Speaker 7:  Well, I don't know, there's some people out there who this is true, who do
Speaker 7:  not make a connection between you and a bankable. This this
Speaker 8:  Is true. I think of a lady in the, the rollercoaster all the
Speaker 7:  Time. We had the CO of Ika on on decoder and she was like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  there, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 7:  But this notion that here's this like very calm like space
Speaker 7:  for you to be in, where you're gonna ask for help with everything from your,
Speaker 7:  your mental wellness to getting work done to booking flights
Speaker 7:  and you've got this assistant character. It's, that is what
Speaker 7:  everybody wants. My question is,
Speaker 7:  the reason ChatGPT took off and the whole industry sort of like
Speaker 7:  reorganized around itself is because the wide open text box is such a powerful
Speaker 7:  thing, right? Like, I don't know, just, just talk to it, it's gonna
Speaker 7:  talk back to me. I'm gonna ask it whatever question it's gonna answer correctly.
Speaker 7:  That is the enabling technology, right?
Speaker 9:  It it is and it isn't. Right? Like it's, it's powerful in the same way that
Speaker 9:  the command line is powerful that If you If, you know how to operate
Speaker 9:  it, you are unstoppable.
Speaker 7:  But isn't the point that you don't need to know how to operate this thing.
Speaker 7:  You just talk to it. Sure.
Speaker 9:  That's a great idea. That isn't remotely congruent
Speaker 9:  with technology. People
Speaker 8:  Have to think about what they're gonna say, right? Like I I, I've run into
Speaker 8:  this every time I try to use a chat bot, I'm like, what the hell do I use
Speaker 8:  this for? What do I, what do I need this for? And then I feel really weird
Speaker 8:  talking to it 'cause I can think of her and all these other things where,
Speaker 8:  where you've seen that happen and you're like, that person's kind of producer.
Speaker 8:  Can I, can I bang
Speaker 7:  You? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like whatcha are you doing later tonight? And co-pilot's like Please leave
Speaker 8:  me alone cramps.
Speaker 9:  Well, and I, I do think there's a big chunk of people who show up to something
Speaker 9:  like chat GPT knowing what they want right? And will do stuff, right?
Speaker 9:  Like that's, there are lots of people who work like that.
Speaker 9:  Most people don't. Most people are not sure like that
Speaker 9:  that is not baked into their brain that like, I'm tired, let me talk to a
Speaker 9:  chat bot about it. Right? And so like maybe someday we'll get there.
Speaker 9:  I think it's not crazy to imagine that that becomes a much more normal behavior
Speaker 9:  for a much larger number of people. But we're nowhere near that yet. And
Speaker 9:  so right now it's the chat bot is both very powerful and like
Speaker 9:  the ultimate Cold Start problem and So I think even you're starting to see
Speaker 9:  chat GPT and others like offer you prompts and ideas and just like
Speaker 9:  little things that it's like here's the kind of stuff I can do just to get
Speaker 9:  you over that hump of like, what am I supposed to type into this box? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Because I think the more you use it, the more you get it and the more natural
Speaker 9:  it feels. But those first few are really challenging.
Speaker 9:  But I just, I just wanna mention one thing. There was a really great piece
Speaker 9:  in The Atlantic this week about a bunch
Speaker 9:  of researchers who got a huge data set of people's transcripts with
Speaker 9:  chat GBT and basically went through it
Speaker 9:  and found people are willing and able to reveal
Speaker 9:  so much about themselves to a chat bot in this incredibly like deep
Speaker 9:  personal way. And it just keeps reinforcing this idea for me that like the
Speaker 9:  bar for people to pour their lives and souls and hearts and minds into these
Speaker 9:  things and treat them like people is so low. Like we're way past that
Speaker 9:  bar. All of these models pass whatever Turing test there is
Speaker 9:  in real life at this point, right? And, and so now the question is basically
Speaker 9:  like what products are we supposed to make out of that? And the first one
Speaker 9:  is just, it's fun to talk to, right? And that's where we are with so much
Speaker 9:  of this and like now that that, that, that doesn't get Microsoft anywhere.
Speaker 9:  It just costs Microsoft a lot of money, right? Like being fun to talk to
Speaker 9:  is not how Microsoft makes money over time. They've gotta figure out this
Speaker 9:  other stuff. And I think you're starting to see copilot pushed towards that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So what's fascinating about this is on the flip side of this, lemme
Speaker 7:  say again, So I agree with all that. What is deeply
Speaker 7:  fascinating to me is the flip side of the new copilot, which is the voice
Speaker 7:  mode, which is inherently open-ended. You just talk to it. It doesn't
Speaker 7:  wake up and say, Hey, would you like to meditate? Right? Right. You just
Speaker 7:  like, you just like push the button and start talking and then it talks back
Speaker 7:  to you and you can interrupt it like all the new multimodal voice modes can
Speaker 7:  do. And that it seems like you don't have to prompt people.
Speaker 7:  Like they will just start talking to the AI and AI will just talk to them.
Speaker 7:  And that feels very natural. And then the other one is copilot vision
Speaker 7:  where it can do all the things that all of them can do now, which is like
Speaker 7:  look at the web for you and like do searches. And that also doesn't have
Speaker 7:  prompting. It's just the text box where we're like, we need to show people
Speaker 7:  what they can type. Everything else is kind of wide open. And I think that's
Speaker 7:  really, I think that split is just gonna keep going. It's just gonna keep
Speaker 7:  getting wider and wider and wider. Where, when you want
Speaker 7:  to do it in or when you want to interact with a computer in ways that feel
Speaker 7:  more human like talking, we don't think we need to prompt you 'cause you're
Speaker 7:  just gonna start talking and then mice and keyboards and typing still feel
Speaker 7:  like computer stuff and people still need instructions or
Speaker 7:  training wheels or whatever metaphor you want to use to like get up and running.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I, I totally agree. It's, it's why everybody is pushing toward both
Speaker 9:  voice and vision, right? Like the camera is very much the same way.
Speaker 9:  Like in the way that sitting down at a text box to
Speaker 9:  accomplish a goal is not a thing that comes naturally for a lot of people
Speaker 9:  taking a picture of a thing Super is, that's just
Speaker 9:  the world now. And so the, like Google just rolled out
Speaker 9:  the, the Gemini search with a video in lens, which I think
Speaker 9:  is gonna be very successful. Everybody's doing this multimodal search.
Speaker 9:  Part of copilot is now that it has the same voice mode and it will do the
Speaker 9:  the video search stuff and like those I totally agree. Those are the things
Speaker 9:  that are gonna like immediately click in people's brains. And I
Speaker 9:  wrote this feature for Wired when I was there like in 2016 being
Speaker 9:  like, the voice revolution is coming. And for years I looked at that piece
Speaker 9:  being like, boy did I whiff on that one because it was like the thesis
Speaker 9:  then was that it was, it was Alexa and it was sir and it was Google assistant.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It was like this is going to change how we interact with our computers
Speaker 9:  and Yeah, like, like Microsoft. I wasn't wrong. I was just way too
Speaker 9:  early.
Speaker 7:  Well the enabling technology wasn't there. I wanna keep coming back to this
Speaker 7:  point. Yeah. Everybody had this idea and then the first problem everybody
Speaker 7:  had was the computers can actually understand what you are saying.
Speaker 7:  And even if they do set a timer for five minutes, that gets
Speaker 7:  filtered into some pretty static algorithms.
Speaker 7:  Like I will set a timer, or in the case of Siri only one at a time,
Speaker 7:  God help us two timers, it took them like five years. Or I can play some
Speaker 7:  music or I can go do a Google search or I can look at Wolf from Alpha, like
Speaker 7:  these very pre-planned routes. And now
Speaker 7:  you have an enabling technology, which is, I can just understand anything
Speaker 7:  you're saying and I can go look at stuff and with a
Speaker 7:  multimodal search, find it, understand it and spit it back out to you. Natural
Speaker 7:  language. That is a very powerful set of enabling technology. Like you just,
Speaker 7:  everybody had the right ideas, but the the literally the core bits and bobs
Speaker 7:  weren't there. I knew when I was a child that cell phones would exist. I
Speaker 7:  could not make an LCD screen like that. That is the thing, right?
Speaker 7:  It just in the middle is all of the, I think the word everyone uses
Speaker 7:  is age agentic like an agent. Oh
Speaker 7:  it's good. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I was like, what does that even mean? Now it makes,
Speaker 7:  The first time I heard it, I was like, what age? Agentic? Okay, you are gonna
Speaker 7:  hear it a lot.
Speaker 9:  That sounds like a consulting firm.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Sounds like the name you come up with. We should start a, when you
Speaker 7:  Consulting
Speaker 8:  Firm, A
Speaker 7:  Consulting firm, we would make so much more money than whenever it's unsponsored
Speaker 7:  lightning around
Speaker 9:  Or like a, like a medication of like that doesn't,
Speaker 9:  you're not sure if it works. It's like it's long. Ask your doctor about agent
Speaker 9:  today. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yikes. Ask your doctor
Speaker 9:  If you're ready for age agentic.
Speaker 7:  Well if you're AI curious, The, Vergecast and age
Speaker 7:  agentic are here for you. Okay. So you've got all these ideas
Speaker 7:  which are okay now I can understand you can go do stuff for you and in the
Speaker 7:  middle, the actually doing stuff for you, unclear how those tasks
Speaker 7:  will be accomplished. Is it a bunch of APIs? Will Delta provide
Speaker 7:  a bunch of flight booking APIs to all AI products?
Speaker 7:  Delta
Speaker 8:  Can't even manage to get their flight attendants. You see to the planes
Speaker 7:  On time. Delta and Microsoft, their software. Very tense relationship right
Speaker 7:  now. I would point out is everyone just gonna allow AI bots to,
Speaker 7:  to set up VNC clients in the cloud and click around on their websites
Speaker 7:  that is very slow and very brittle
Speaker 8:  And computationally like expensive,
Speaker 7:  Probably computationally expensive, right? Being like, they could be rendering
Speaker 7:  them in black and white. I don't know. There's probably some way, you know,
Speaker 7:  who knows? But that is such a hack,
Speaker 7:  like a pure hack to say the way the AI agents are gonna
Speaker 7:  work is we're gonna light up Chrome on
Speaker 7:  AWS on a Linux instance for every
Speaker 7:  individual user. Take your credentials to the cloud and then
Speaker 7:  click around and websites to accomplish the tasks for you.
Speaker 7:  Because what you really wanna do is speak to your phone. Maybe you could
Speaker 7:  do it locally, right? Apple's gonna do it with intents in Siri. So
Speaker 7:  you talk to Siri, presumably whenever Apple Intelligence ships a bunch
Speaker 7:  of app developers will have had to allow Siri to
Speaker 7:  access their services. And Siri locally will fire
Speaker 7:  off a bunch of API calls and do stuff on your phone. The middle part
Speaker 7:  is totally up for grabs. I don't know if anybody has an answer. I don't know
Speaker 7:  if anybody has a fallback that is better than we're gonna light up a Chrome
Speaker 7:  instance in the sky. And I don't know if anybody has a solution for
Speaker 7:  what happens when Kayak or DoorDash or Delta,
Speaker 7:  like don't have the ability to show you their user interface. They will like
Speaker 7:  If, you run DoorDash and suddenly people can order stuff
Speaker 7:  without ever looking at the DoorDash interface. You don't actually run much
Speaker 7:  of a company anymore. All of your revenue opportunities go away. 'cause you're,
Speaker 7:  you're built in advertising the thing where they try to get you to order
Speaker 7:  more stuff the second you've ordered something. I'm convinced this is DoorDash
Speaker 7:  ISS entire
Speaker 8:  Yeah. They're always like, don't you want a soda with this soda? You're already
Speaker 8:  ordered.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They're like double dash, like the counter comes up and you're like,
Speaker 7:  that's just more stuff. But that's the business. Uber is like, would you
Speaker 7:  like Uber Eats If? you just If you
Speaker 7:  commoditize all of those services and the things that AI can do,
Speaker 7:  those companies are gonna be like, actually no. Like Uber
Speaker 7:  and Lyft want to be different companies, not just
Speaker 7:  commodity providers of taxis to AI services, dumb pipes. You create a
Speaker 7:  lot of dumb pipes. Yeah. You commoditize a lot of businesses right away.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I just don't know that middle part is where I think all of these
Speaker 7:  companies are gonna run into the reality of well, everybody else doesn't
Speaker 7:  wanna be a commodity for your ai. Yeah. And I truly right
Speaker 7:  now it seems like the fallback answer is, well, we're just gonna click around
Speaker 7:  on your website. Like what are you gonna do not have a website? And it,
Speaker 7:  lately it seems like the answer is not have a website.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Or like a terms of service battle about you have to be a human to use our
Speaker 7:  website. Well
Speaker 8:  It also seems like in, in the conversations I've had with folks that part
Speaker 8:  of this is also, they don't necessarily wanna do that. They just want it
Speaker 8:  to be like this companion you talk to, it doesn't
Speaker 8:  necessarily, it's not your executive assistant. It's not ordering you flights
Speaker 8:  or anything like that. It's there to help with math. It's there to like do
Speaker 7:  Notoriously bad at
Speaker 8:  Very basic things. And then I think you, you, with all of it, you
Speaker 8:  still run into this cultural cons. Like, like
Speaker 8:  culturally, are we prepared for this? Are we prepared to make these things
Speaker 8:  our friends? And I don't think people are.
Speaker 7:  Well, so the new copilot, because it has open ai Yeah. Oh
Speaker 7:  one in it has a feature called Think Deeper, which
Speaker 7:  allows it to supply step by step answers to complex questions.
Speaker 7:  Like, should I move to New York or San Francisco? Ooh. Which is definitely
Speaker 7:  something you just wanna ask.
Speaker 8:  That's what I wanna ask a computer.
Speaker 7:  That is,
Speaker 8:  That is the thing like, right? Like it's, it's trying to replicate
Speaker 8:  friends and, and I don't know how to tell it.
Speaker 8:  Computers are not friends. They're computers. They, they
Speaker 8:  don't have souls, they don't have the ability to reason.
Speaker 7:  But this is what David is saying. Yeah. Once you let people talk to a computer,
Speaker 7:  they just start talking to
Speaker 8:  A computer. Right? Because they, they, yeah. They like to talk once you let
Speaker 8:  somebody on the internet, they love to put everything on the internet, right?
Speaker 8:  Like, like there's no, we, we all love to just, not everyone, but a
Speaker 8:  lot of people just love to put themselves out there in all these forms. And
Speaker 8:  generally speaking, culturally, we think it's weird when someone talks to
Speaker 8:  a computer over and over again, we see in TV and film that's like the,
Speaker 8:  the example of that person is cut off from everything they know. That person
Speaker 8:  is profoundly lonely. I think of, was it Mr. Robot where the woman would
Speaker 8:  every episode have a conversation with Alexa and, and it was meant to show
Speaker 8:  you how sad, empathetic she was. And now we're like, actually that
Speaker 8:  isn't sad, empathetic. It's cool with co-pilot,
Speaker 7:  We should do a remix of Mr. Robot as a co-pilot ad.
Speaker 8:  Yes. A hundred percent
Speaker 7:  Percent would want's a very good idea. I actually don't know. I want, I I
Speaker 7:  don't know if the answer, well, I know the answer to that question is should
Speaker 7:  he move to New York, San Francisco? It's obviously New York, just putting
Speaker 7:  that out there straight out better food, everything.
Speaker 9:  No, that's true. Yeah. I was gonna fight that for a minute. It's true.
Speaker 7:  It's just so true. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Sorry to everyone in San Francisco.
Speaker 7:  Sorry, in particular, Connie Robinson, our reporter ar reporter in San Francisco,
Speaker 7:  who loves reporter, but I'm right, it's New York.
Speaker 7:  But the, the idea that you can have some like big life decision and you're
Speaker 7:  asking a computer in a low stakes way to like help you think through it.
Speaker 7:  Fine. Does that make you better? Talking to other people,
Speaker 7:  unclear that, like, that's what the replica people will say is people practice
Speaker 7:  having social interactions with their robots and then they go off into the
Speaker 7:  world and they're confident.
Speaker 9:  Hmm. I I'm really of the mind that we should
Speaker 9:  spend more time wondering if actually those two things have nothing to do
Speaker 9:  with each other. Right. Because I think the, the like alarmist side of that
Speaker 9:  argument is people are talking to computers and
Speaker 9:  thus not talking to other people. And you hear the stories about like
Speaker 9:  the, the women in Asia who are dating men who are
Speaker 9:  ais instead of men in the world. And there's like this big moral crisis about
Speaker 9:  it. And like, there's probably lots of interesting research being done on
Speaker 9:  those fronts, but I think to me, the question of is it a good and
Speaker 9:  healthy thing to have a relationship like this with a computer
Speaker 9:  is interesting and important in its own right.
Speaker 7:  Can I read you the quote from that directly responds to you? Yeah, sure.
Speaker 7:  We are not creating Reminder, beautiful accent
Speaker 7:  musical
Speaker 9:  Did not get acquired by Microsoft, did
Speaker 7:  Not get acquired by Microsoft quote. We are not creating a static tool
Speaker 7:  so much as establishing a dynamic emergent and evolving interaction.
Speaker 7:  It will accompany you to that doctor's appointment, taking notes and following
Speaker 7:  up at the right time. It'll share the load of planning and preparing for
Speaker 7:  your child's birthday party. And it will be there at the end of the day to
Speaker 7:  help you think through a tricky life decision.
Speaker 7:  This is just a friend what he's, what what he is describing as a friend
Speaker 7:  who's gonna come do all the, and and then you can just take advantage of
Speaker 7:  the friend, like plan this birthday party. And I, that is a huge
Speaker 7:  vision and again, I'm just pointing out, okay, planning and
Speaker 7:  preparing for your child's birthday party requires doing a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 7:  And how it does this stuff is not a technical
Speaker 7:  problem. It is a legal problem and it is a set of business problems.
Speaker 7:  And I don't know if anybody actually has the answers to those problems right
Speaker 7:  now. Like, can this robot go use a website on my behalf?
Speaker 7:  Well, I can, someone can just write a terms of service agreement that prohibits
Speaker 7:  that. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And now, now we have to have a lot and Microsoft can pay the money. They,
Speaker 7:  they got money, but like they, some, it's gonna get fought out before this
Speaker 7:  vision happens. And I think there's, as always with the tech
Speaker 7:  industry, they're like, huh. Permission.
Speaker 8:  It's still really weird that a couple of years ago Google fired a dude
Speaker 8:  and part of the reason they fired him, not the entire reason, part of it
Speaker 8:  was that he insisted the AI was like
Speaker 8:  human enough now. Oh yeah. And then now we're back. Now we've gone all the
Speaker 8:  way around to look at how human our AI is.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. It's a feature, not a bug now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And that's just, that's a weird turn that I'm, I'm having trouble
Speaker 8:  baking along with all of the tech companies. They did it and I'm like, hello?
Speaker 8:  I'm still back here. Like, it's kind of weird.
Speaker 7:  Google's like, you've planned too many birthday parties. Get outta here.
Speaker 9:  Can I just say, by the way, tech companies stop using children
Speaker 9:  in your marketing for AI chat? It's just a bad idea. Yeah. Like
Speaker 9:  stop having them write letters to Olympians
Speaker 9:  with it. Stop having your, their birthday parties planned with
Speaker 9:  ai. Like, please, please leave children out of it. It's just not a
Speaker 9:  good look. It makes everything feel very dystopian and bad. Can we? Let's
Speaker 9:  just not do that. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Also, most parents of young children right now are deep in a
Speaker 7:  extraordinarily controversial discussion about whether the kid should have
Speaker 7:  phones at all. Yeah. Just what you do. Yeah. Also, if you're gonna spend
Speaker 7:  your time doing anything, it's planning your kid's birthday party all of
Speaker 7:  the rest of the time she get freed up so you can do that thing.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 8:  Well, yeah, but they can't do that because all of that other stuff is business
Speaker 8:  stuff and, and you get into what is legal at your company Gonna say, if you're
Speaker 8:  using this to plan all of your, your meetings, they might have problems.
Speaker 8:  You, you know, like, like you run into that thing of, okay, this has to be
Speaker 8:  in the personal space because we're not yet ready to put this
Speaker 7:  In the space and who can't sue us kids.
Speaker 8:  Yep. Kids can't Sue get more money. Little kids
Speaker 8:  loser.
Speaker 9:  What would be a good ad for AI is me sending my stupid
Speaker 9:  AI note taker to all of my meetings so that I can go plan my kids' birthday
Speaker 9:  party. What if I'm outside with my children while my AI is in a meeting?
Speaker 9:  Now I'm in on ai. I
Speaker 7:  Just wanna point out that Eric Han, the CEO of Zoom, came onto coder
Speaker 7:  and said, soon all meetings will be AI avatars talking to each other.
Speaker 7:  And you will have thousands of AI avatars going to thousands of meetings.
Speaker 9:  Somebody posted something on Threads the other day, I don't know if it was
Speaker 9:  true or not, but they posted a screenshot of a Google meet with several people
Speaker 9:  in a meeting and all of them had just sent their AI note.
Speaker 7:  That's the scene from the, the greatest movie of all time.
Speaker 7:  Real genius with Al Kilmer, where in the eighties everybody puts
Speaker 7:  their boombox in record, the lecture, then the, the professor comes and plays
Speaker 7:  the lecture out of the boombox.
Speaker 7:  This is one of the most underrated movies of all time. This is Val Comer's
Speaker 7:  greatest performance, real genius. Go watch this movie. Everything you need
Speaker 7:  to know about my personality comes from this movie. I'm just letting you
Speaker 7:  know
Speaker 9:  This sounds like a special episode we need to do. I'm sort of serious.
Speaker 7:  We just wash real genius. Yeah. An incredible final scene. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Speaking of AI companies that don't ask anyone for permission to do anything
Speaker 7:  open AI just raised $6.6 billion to build God,
Speaker 7:  that seems fine. That's cheap. Yeah. Everyone works there
Speaker 7:  still, right? Yeah. There are now more founders of OpenAI who work at philanthropic
Speaker 7:  than work at OpenAI. This is a real stat, it's
Speaker 9:  Pretty fantastic.
Speaker 7:  Who knows if they're gonna do that Money? Sam Hellman has consolidated evermore
Speaker 7:  power. I think one of the big questions here with all this Microsoft news
Speaker 7:  is it feels like Microsoft is pulling farther and farther away from OpenAI.
Speaker 7:  I mean
Speaker 9:  For Microsoft, this is just, it's just a really great way to get a
Speaker 9:  lot of computing money. I forget who the author was, but somebody at the
Speaker 9:  information wrote a very good story basically being like, here's why all
Speaker 9:  these investors would do this. And you just go down the list and it's like,
Speaker 9:  oh, Nvidia is in this because Nvidia is actually just giving open AI money
Speaker 9:  that it will get back. Yep. Because for all of its technology, Microsoft
Speaker 9:  same Thrive is like in too deep now. They, they've just,
Speaker 9:  they've pinned their whole thing. Yeah. It's
Speaker 7:  A big VC
Speaker 9:  Firm being Yeah. On like being bros with founders and with Sam Altman in
Speaker 9:  particular. You, you could make a case that this is
Speaker 9:  not the like vast bet that open AI's the
Speaker 9:  greatest company in the history of ever that it appears to be on its face.
Speaker 9:  But it also is, it puts OpenAI in a pretty wild position, which is I think
Speaker 9:  the, the money hinges on the company becoming a for-profit company within
Speaker 9:  two years, which is a big deal that we've kind of known was coming.
Speaker 9:  The thing I thought was the wildest was that
Speaker 9:  OpenAI apparently asked all of its investors not to
Speaker 9:  invest in other basically similar companies, not to
Speaker 9:  invest in, in OpenAI competitors. Which is just a wild thing to be able to
Speaker 9:  ask your investors. Like, I watched Silicon Valley, I know that you're supposed
Speaker 9:  to have multiple plays in every sec in every sector of the market. And
Speaker 9:  so for AI to just be like, no, you, you can't touch anybody else. If you
Speaker 9:  aren't part of this is pretty nuts. Also, SoftBank is in
Speaker 9:  this Ooh. Which is not great.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's
Speaker 9:  Usually it's not what you want. Like money is good, but the vibes are bad.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  All this also hinges on, we would, I've I've mentioned the phrase
Speaker 7:  enabling technology a bunch of times. There's a difference between the engineering
Speaker 7:  you need to make the technology and then the product work you need to make
Speaker 7:  the products. Yeah. And all the syns on open AI going from a research
Speaker 7:  and engineering company to a products company. And right now they have
Speaker 7:  but one product which is ChatGPT or
Speaker 9:  There being some vast leap left to do
Speaker 9:  in the engineering side. Like, but
Speaker 7:  All those people have left.
Speaker 9:  Well, right. But I mean, but, but open AI's case is God, right? Like they,
Speaker 9:  they, if, if OpenAI is right about that, there
Speaker 9:  are several gigantic leaps left here and there
Speaker 9:  are an increasing number of people out there who say maybe there aren't,
Speaker 9:  and maybe it doesn't matter that maybe the technology now is good enough
Speaker 9:  to do most of the plausible stuff that we want to do. And actually, to your
Speaker 9:  point, all the interesting stuff left is product, right? Like we've, we've
Speaker 9:  built the internet now what are we gonna do with it? It's like that's one
Speaker 9:  moment we're in. There's another moment that we're in that says all of this
Speaker 9:  is about to get a hundred thousand times better at like a foundational level
Speaker 9:  and that will change everything all over again. And I hear an increasing
Speaker 9:  number of people who don't believe that second thing is true, but that's
Speaker 9:  open AI's entire pitch for why it's worth all of this money.
Speaker 7:  And that pitch comes down to we will run an even larger
Speaker 7:  model. We'll train an even larger model with an even larger amount of data,
Speaker 8:  Which they are running out of data. So they're made their own,
Speaker 7:  They're gonna make synthetic data to do it, which is great. And then they'll
Speaker 7:  use all of the power in Saudi Arabia to build the data center. Like
Speaker 7:  legitimately, this is how they're talking to, this is how they spend their
Speaker 7:  money. And that's just a big bet. You gotta do a lot of things.
Speaker 7:  I believe that people at TSMC refer to Sam Altman as a podcast, bro. They
Speaker 7:  heard his, they heard his ideas to build 36 more chip fabs to make him chips.
Speaker 7:  Like that's just a big idea. And maybe he'll get the money and maybe he'll
Speaker 7:  do it. Who knows? It's just in the meantime, while you're busy building 36
Speaker 7:  fabs to build the world's largest data center to train the world's largest
Speaker 7:  model on synthetic data that your current models have produced,
Speaker 7:  everyone else is gonna go build products. And like maybe that's fine. You
Speaker 7:  know, like I, I just, there's a weirdness here, you know,
Speaker 7:  we're covering it, we're all over it. But I would just zoom out
Speaker 7:  of like the day-to-Day, Sam Altman drama and you're like, what are the products?
Speaker 8:  There's also, there's the third one, which is that AI
Speaker 8:  is a bubble and, and it's about to pop, right?
Speaker 8:  Like, like that a lot of this stuff is, is just built on
Speaker 8:  dreams and ambition and there's nothing actually to back it up because If,
Speaker 8:  you don't have those products. If, you don't build God in the next five years,
Speaker 8:  shareholders are gonna be like, yo, where's God? Yep. I gave you a billion
Speaker 8:  dollars.
Speaker 7:  This is, look, I'm a capitalist. Yeah. I don't, I often do capitalist critiques,
Speaker 7:  but I would say, shareholders will get mad. If, you don't build God in the
Speaker 7:  next five years is the perfect summation of where we are in technology
Speaker 7:  capital.
Speaker 8:  It's like what?
Speaker 7:  That's, there's a very VERGE cast sentence right there and I just want everyone
Speaker 7:  to hold onto it as tightly as they can.
Speaker 1:  Well
Speaker 9:  We have the total of the show because that's good.
Speaker 7:  Alright, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 7:  gadgets and I might mention real genius three or four more times, we'll be
Speaker 7:  right back.
Speaker 7:  We're back with the Real Genius Radio Hour.
Speaker 7:  That movie is great actually to be, to be a hundred percent
Speaker 7:  on the nose. That movie is about a, a group of scientists
Speaker 7:  to invent a laser that gets productized
Speaker 7:  into a weapon. And at 1.1 of the main characters says
Speaker 7:  that's for the engineers to figure out. It's a real
Speaker 7:  thing. Woof.
Speaker 7:  It is great. It's truly one of the finest movies all the time,
Speaker 8:  Apparently, to prepare for it. They did a lot of research into the CIA and
Speaker 8:  Lasers. Really found it in.
Speaker 7:  They didn't do that much research months.
Speaker 8:  Wikipedia says months of
Speaker 7:  Research, like this is a movie in which the breakthrough is about kelberg.
Speaker 7:  Screaming Ice is nice. Like,
Speaker 8:  Oh, excuse me. The director did the research, not the writers.
Speaker 7:  It's not that much research. They did a lot of research into like MIT and
Speaker 7:  Caltech Secret Societies. Okay. This movie is great. It's a, it's a
Speaker 7:  tremendous eighties movie and you have to watch it like five times to catch
Speaker 7:  all the, the jokes. It's great. Alright. Lot of gadget
Speaker 7:  stuff going on. Should we start with the, the meta glasses?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. This is like Eli's dream came true when it's horrible and we have to
Speaker 9:  talk about it.
Speaker 7:  So, so many people have pinged me with this story.
Speaker 7:  An email on threads. Just I you in Slack in the comments of
Speaker 7:  unrelated stories On Slack. On Slack, a group of college
Speaker 7:  I believe at Harvard, they took the meta ray bands and they just hacked it
Speaker 7:  together. So with the meta raybans, you can just stream live to Instagram.
Speaker 7:  So they set up a private Instagram account. They started streaming live from
Speaker 7:  the meta ray bands. And then they set up facial recognition
Speaker 7:  watching their computers live stream to just tell them who they
Speaker 7:  were looking at. And you should watch this video, it's great. They, you know,
Speaker 7:  it's like everyone's a video editor. And now, so the video's edited all snappy.
Speaker 7:  There's like moments of discovery and despair. It's like the whole thing's
Speaker 7:  great, but like dude's on the subway and he's just looking at someone
Speaker 7:  and it tells him who they are because
Speaker 7:  they've done facial recognition and then he walks up to them
Speaker 7:  and he is like, Hey, are you this person that, or did I meet you at this
Speaker 7:  place? And everyone falls for it. And it is, maybe it put on like
Speaker 7:  maybe this only worked half the time. It's a video, right? We, we don't know.
Speaker 7:  But the proof of concept is there. Like that
Speaker 7:  chain of things all exist. Streaming live, Instagram exists
Speaker 7:  worldwide. Facial recognition systems exist, text messaging
Speaker 7:  exists. You can make this product today out of the things that exist. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  You can go do this and it is terrifying. It is a hundred percent the product
Speaker 7:  I want. I wanna be very clear about this. I've said this so many times in
Speaker 7:  the show that If, you could give me ar glasses that just
Speaker 7:  tell me who people are. Tell me people's names. That is a killer app for
Speaker 7:  this product. It always has been. It always will be. And the cost of it,
Speaker 7:  which I have said every single time I have said this is a killer app, is
Speaker 7:  that you need to build a worldwide facial recognition database. And that
Speaker 7:  is terrifying. And the second someone built even this hack
Speaker 7:  together prototype, it's obviously terrifying.
Speaker 9:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. By the way meta, we asked them about it and they just sent a block
Speaker 7:  quote of their terms of service to us.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean it, it makes so plain that the only reason
Speaker 9:  this isn't happening is because everyone is slightly skied out by it. Except
Speaker 9:  for you. Apparently
Speaker 7:  I would be the greatest politician in American history if I could just remember
Speaker 7:  people's names. I I, I do not want to shy away from that is my claim.
Speaker 7:  I will stick to it. It is unprovable, but I know in my heart that it is true.
Speaker 7:  I feel
Speaker 8:  Like everyone should have this when they have to go to like CES or something
Speaker 8:  like that. Like really big events. I would be totally fine with that. You
Speaker 8:  wearing it on the street? No. Stop.
Speaker 7:  I don't even like wearing the NFC tag built into the badges at c
Speaker 8:  Sip
Speaker 7:  It out.
Speaker 8:  No, I wanna know who everyone is at CES. I wanna be like, okay, I did meet
Speaker 8:  you five years ago and I'm so sorry, I forgot. That seems great.
Speaker 9:  This has made me think so much about the UX of all of this. Like, like what
Speaker 9:  If, you could wear these glasses but it wouldn't show you somebody's names
Speaker 9:  unless the glasses had seen them before. So in theory, your first
Speaker 9:  encounter with somebody wouldn't just tell you their name, but if this was
Speaker 9:  a person you knew somehow you had a picture of them in your Google photos
Speaker 9:  or you were friends with them on some social network, like again a series
Speaker 9:  of very queryable databases, then it could be like, oh you know this person.
Speaker 9:  Like does that get less sketchy?
Speaker 8:  No, because then your spouse puts on your glasses and finds out you've been
Speaker 8:  having an affair for five years. I just went straight there. Ooh. Right.
Speaker 8:  That's gonna happen. 'cause you put 'em on and then it's like, that's interest.
Speaker 8:  Wait, why doesn't recognize this person? Oh 'cause they were binging them.
Speaker 8:  Well
Speaker 7:  You look at your phone, it's like he's been banging the assistant this whole
Speaker 7:  time.
Speaker 8:  No,
Speaker 7:  Not co-pilot.
Speaker 7:  Just hearts all
Speaker 8:  Around your phone. It'd be rules.
Speaker 7:  Look, I, someone's gonna actually do this whether, whether or not it's
Speaker 7:  this hacky product or another one of these companies,
Speaker 7:  once the display technology is available, some will instantly
Speaker 7:  build a product like this. I
Speaker 8:  Mean, meta could go build this right now, but then we would
Speaker 8:  not be making, talking about his shirts as much. We'd be talking about that.
Speaker 7:  Well, I don't So the UX of this, as David is saying is the thing. Yeah, because
Speaker 7:  you need the glasses and it's to show you the name over the person. Well
Speaker 7:  no, I think if it's just saying the name, no, this is why it's a hack. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Right now it's like texting you the name.
Speaker 8:  I mean I'd still, I'd be fine with that.
Speaker 7:  I, but I I think as like as a consumer product, that's a little
Speaker 7:  challenging. Yeah. Right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah. Or on my watch it just pops up on your watch and you're like,
Speaker 8:  Phil, it's a next speech. Yeah. Like I think that'd be great.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna start doing this to people. Just call it everyone Phil. Be like,
Speaker 7:  so you're Phil. Yes. What we do, I'm saying once the
Speaker 7:  right meta could build this with Orion presumably. 'cause they have the display
Speaker 7:  technology, but that's vaporware. Yes. I'm saying once
Speaker 7:  on some timeline, once the display technology to put images on glasses that
Speaker 7:  let you just see the real world exists.
Speaker 7:  This technology, this thing is inevitable.
Speaker 9:  No AirPods solves this problem. Like did either of you watch Veep?
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 9:  You know how Gary and Veep is just forever behind her going, yeah,
Speaker 8:  No, that's what I want. This
Speaker 9:  Is, this is Senator Doyle. He,
Speaker 8:  I want, Gary
Speaker 9:  Is an idiot. This is Gary. Like call this product Gary. And it just,
Speaker 9:  whenever someone is like clearly walking towards you, it just tells you who
Speaker 9:  they are.
Speaker 8:  And it's just Tony Hale's voice in your ear. It's just
Speaker 9:  Tony Hale. Give Tony Hale millions of dollars to do this and
Speaker 9:  I will subscribe to tomorrow. A
Speaker 8:  Hundred percent.
Speaker 7:  It is funny how obvious the trade off is to everyone once they see
Speaker 7:  it. Oh yeah. Because again, for years I've been saying I would buy this product
Speaker 7:  in a heartbeat. But you have to build a worldwide facial recognition database
Speaker 7:  to do it. And everyone's like, that's fine. And then you see it, you're like,
Speaker 7:  boop,
Speaker 8:  Nevermind. Don't want that. Don't want that.
Speaker 7:  There is a worldwide facial recognition database.
Speaker 7:  It's just the internet.
Speaker 7:  Anyway. I want one If, you these college students call us. We'll, we'll do
Speaker 7:  a whole, I wanna know everything about this project and how it works. Give
Speaker 7:  us, give us a call.
Speaker 7:  Other Gadget news. Sonos announced
Speaker 7:  a plan to fix the app. We haven't covered this too much on the
Speaker 7:  word chest, I don't think in
Speaker 9:  Bits and pieces. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Chris Welsh has been covering the story top to bottom on the site. So
Speaker 7:  obviously Sonos put out the app. It was not a hit.
Speaker 8:  People hated it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's how they felt
Speaker 8:  About it. I think that, I think, I think that's, it's safe to say people
Speaker 8:  hated it.
Speaker 7:  Missing a bunch of functionality. You know, the, the, the ongoing
Speaker 7:  narrative is that they needed to rush out the headphones. I don't wanna say
Speaker 7:  conspiracy theory. Yeah. 'cause I think it, I think it is correct. They needed
Speaker 7:  to rush out the headphones. They needed to put out the new version of the
Speaker 7:  app to support the mobility of the headphones. And the
Speaker 7:  app was mentioning a bunch of functionality, very buggy missing core functionality.
Speaker 7:  You know, people
Speaker 8:  At the company were upset that they were releasing it. Yep. And so now they're
Speaker 8:  like, okay, well what if we listen more? Why
Speaker 9:  Are you guys being so nice to Sonos? This is like weird. Delic Sonos released
Speaker 9:  a horrible app that everyone hated and it has basically tanked the
Speaker 9:  company. Like it's just that simple. We
Speaker 7:  Were, yeah. They've had to have layoffs because of it. Yeah. We,
Speaker 8:  Well, but you know, like the, the reason that it happened was because they
Speaker 8:  weren't listening. No,
Speaker 9:  It's because someone almost released a horrible app that everyone hated.
Speaker 7:  Here's what I'm trying not to do. I'm trying not to just, just repeat
Speaker 7:  like Reddit conspiracy theories and, and say
Speaker 7:  only what I actually know because the Reddit conspiracy theories are in fact
Speaker 7:  out of control. Yes. And at this point the company is so tanked its reputation.
Speaker 7:  They can't do anything. Right. So what they have done is they took Eddie
Speaker 7:  Lazarus, who is their Chief legal officer and they assigned him
Speaker 7:  the project to figure out what happened. And he isn't gonna write a report.
Speaker 7:  So he did that. Eddie's been on the show before. We've talked to him
Speaker 7:  and they released their plan. The plan is
Speaker 7:  charitably fairly vague. The plan contains
Speaker 7:  things like unwavering focus on the customer experience to ensure that we
Speaker 7:  deliver the highest levels of customer experience. We'll always establish
Speaker 7:  ambitious quality benchmarks at the outset of product development. It's like,
Speaker 7:  is that the plan?
Speaker 9:  The plan is like, it, it just makes me think of the people who are like,
Speaker 9:  no one holds me to a higher standard than I hold myself. So to everyone I've
Speaker 9:  disappointed. Please know I've disappointed myself Even it's like, no,
Speaker 9:  you still did bad. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 7:  One of the other pieces of the plan is demonstrate humility when introducing
Speaker 7:  changes. In contrast, the all at once automated app release, we
Speaker 7:  should make any major changes to Sonus Apple. We release gradually. I will
Speaker 7:  just point out this is how every other company has done everything forever.
Speaker 7:  So I. I think there, yes, we should have some humility
Speaker 7:  but also just like do it Good is one of those.
Speaker 7:  It really, and the last one, which I think is oddly backfired and pissed
Speaker 7:  people off the most is the executives are foregoing their bonuses.
Speaker 8:  See, they know they did the bad. Just like David said,
Speaker 8:  no one knows more than they do.
Speaker 7:  So they're in their advisory, assembling customer advisory
Speaker 7:  board to get feedback and insights. I think people are gonna be like, finish
Speaker 7:  the app. Make app good. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  There are two real things I will say. In addition to all of those not
Speaker 9:  real things that you just said, they're, they're extending the warranty,
Speaker 9:  the manufacturer warranty on a bunch of stuff, which is good. Kudos to Sonos
Speaker 9:  for being like, okay, this is gonna take us a minute. We will keep supporting
Speaker 9:  your stuff through it. And the other one they're doing, which actually to
Speaker 9:  some extent confirms some of the conspiracy theories is they appointed, I
Speaker 9:  believe they're calling it an ombudsman to basically
Speaker 9:  help internally figure out what people think and deliver
Speaker 9:  that opinion to the people who are in charge. Because one of the stories
Speaker 9:  we've heard is that people inside of Sonos were freaking out about
Speaker 9:  how bad the app was and that they were sort of resoundingly
Speaker 9:  ignored in favor of just shipping the app. And so there were people inside
Speaker 9:  of the company who were like, this, we can't do this. This is a disaster.
Speaker 9:  Which made me think of like the, the folks at Hue who were trying the thing
Speaker 9:  before it shipped who were like, this thing sucks. And they were just like,
Speaker 9:  well ship it. And so Sonos is at least it seems
Speaker 9:  taking steps to make sure that particular thing doesn't happen again. Which
Speaker 9:  seems good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. If they listen to that person.
Speaker 7:  I think at this point Sonos is very worried that a lot of people
Speaker 7:  are realizing that Airplay two exists.
Speaker 8:  YII never use the app anymore, I just use Airplay two. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like a lot of people have realized that Airplay Two exists and can group
Speaker 7:  speakers from a variety of manufacturers together. As can Chromecast audio.
Speaker 7:  Like a lot of people have discovered that their phones have stuff in them.
Speaker 7:  They're betting on the ARC two and a
Speaker 7:  bunch of new products that are coming out. But if your app doesn't work,
Speaker 7:  it doesn't matter. Yeah. By the way, I got it wrong. Eddie Lazarus no longer
Speaker 7:  the Chief legal Officer. Chief Strategy Officer at Sono. Oh,
Speaker 8:  Congrats
Speaker 7:  On the And his strategy is making it good.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  David, what's going on with these new Chromebooks?
Speaker 9:  So
Speaker 8:  They found the G button. Our, sorry,
Speaker 7:  Cranz.
Speaker 8:  Sorry, Crans. It's, it's a, it's, it's the Gemini button.
Speaker 8:  They found the Gemini button. It's a little but
Speaker 9:  They're not calling it the Gemini button. This is the thing that throws me.
Speaker 9:  It's called the quick insert button.
Speaker 7:  Oh good.
Speaker 9:  What? It's basically, so one of, one of the hacks for years
Speaker 9:  on Chromebooks has been to reuse the caps lock
Speaker 9:  button. A lot of people do it, you can use it to like invoke
Speaker 9:  the, the menu button. A lot of people do that. You can do it for like a search.
Speaker 9:  The caps lock button is a, is a sort of endlessly mutable thing in the Chromebook
Speaker 9:  universe. And a lot of people do it. So what Google is doing now
Speaker 9:  is replacing the caps lock button, which is also sometimes the search or
Speaker 9:  launcher button with what's called the quick insert button. And
Speaker 9:  I think the idea is that it's just gonna be the like
Speaker 9:  way to do all of the help me write or turn this into
Speaker 9:  different kind of Google Doc or whatever
Speaker 9:  inside of any product. Right. The idea is to like AI your way through
Speaker 9:  the internet with this one button. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's like this little sparkle you see in Android now.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, exactly. Exactly. And
Speaker 8:  Like, but it's a little button and it's got a G on it.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And I think that's fine. It's
Speaker 8:  Fine. Yeah. I mean that's the same thing that we saw with Copilot, right?
Speaker 8:  Like it's like the copilot button. Yeah. On on on Windows. This is, this
Speaker 8:  is Google's version and it's like, yeah, they, they had to do this Windows
Speaker 8:  did it. It makes sense. Right?
Speaker 9:  I do think this is like a, a statement of AI is
Speaker 9:  important to us more than it is like an actually useful user feature.
Speaker 9:  But it is, it is something, it will remind people to use it,
Speaker 9:  which I think counts for something.
Speaker 9:  I, I don't know. I've spent a long time like waiting for Chromebooks to be
Speaker 9:  like cool, exciting, good computers and I'm kind of, I'm just over it now.
Speaker 9:  This just makes me tired. This is just like a bunch of students who are gonna
Speaker 9:  like, use AI to write their papers now and now it's easier. Great.
Speaker 8:  But isn't Samsung saying this is, this is like one of their, their thinnest
Speaker 8:  laptops ever.
Speaker 9:  Sure.
Speaker 7:  Samsung says that about every Chromebook they've ever made. Right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That's
Speaker 7:  Like they're running out of, they're running out of Chromebook. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  No room left Also they're all talking now about like 13 and
Speaker 9:  12 hours of battery life. I think were the number on the two here and they're
Speaker 9:  like 600 and $700 and then there's a Lenovo one that's
Speaker 9:  cheaper. But like these are not impressive numbers
Speaker 9:  anymore. Like we're, we're in a new phase of laptops. Y'all like
Speaker 9:  Chromebooks come come do something new and interesting
Speaker 9:  again. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Or be cheap.
Speaker 9:  The fact that Neli I bet still has not replaced his mom's Chromebook
Speaker 9:  pixel should be a real problem for everyone on the Chromebook
Speaker 9:  team at Google. And I super don't think it's,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So If, you don't know this is ancient right now. I bought my mom a
Speaker 7:  Chromebook. Do you remember the Chromebook pixel? Oh yeah. It was a thousand
Speaker 7:  dollars Chromebook. It was nice.
Speaker 9:  Still maybe the sexiest laptop of
Speaker 8:  All time. Yeah. Is it great? Is it all yellowed now?
Speaker 7:  No, it's fine. Oh that's nice. It was aluminum mostly So I bought that for
Speaker 7:  my mom and instead of that you think
Speaker 9:  You're the Pixel book Crans the one that that got weird on the Palm rest.
Speaker 9:  The Chromebook Pixel was the one that was like metal and it was a MacBook
Speaker 7:  Gorgeous. It was gorgeous squared off. It was great. It was one, it was A-U-S-P-C
Speaker 7:  computer back when that was like a thing. Not every computer,
Speaker 7:  but I was, my mom needed a new Mac and I was just like, there's too many
Speaker 7:  interface metaphors here. And I was before all the ones
Speaker 7:  that exist now on top of everything else. And I was like, she just wants
Speaker 7:  the browser. Like she doesn't give a shit. And So I bought her a Chromebook
Speaker 7:  pixel, which a thousand dollars Chromebook with an I seven in it. It's
Speaker 7:  ridiculous. She's still using it 'cause she just runs Chrome. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And she just, I dunno, she's banging around on the web all day. I would love
Speaker 7:  to get her a new one, but there's, I can't think of a reason to. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  There's
Speaker 8:  Not. And she
Speaker 7:  Hasn't complained and there's not one that is as cool looking as the Chromebook
Speaker 7:  pixel. Yeah. Because again, that was a thousand dollars computer. There's
Speaker 8:  One with a little light bar on it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. At the very top on on the hitch. Yeah. It's great. And I, I, every
Speaker 7:  now and again, I check on it and it continues to run Crumb, which is all
Speaker 7:  anyone really needs. Yeah. And I think Google just hasn't chased that idea
Speaker 7:  all the way to ground. Right? Like what most people, they,
Speaker 7:  they're just cheap and like students get them to cheat on their homework
Speaker 7:  with Now with ai, I'm spending more time with the Pixel Line Pro and
Speaker 7:  Google's just like, AI Clippy is everywhere. Every time you pick up that
Speaker 7:  phone, it's just like more AI stuff and it's just fun. Yeah. And if Google
Speaker 7:  can bring that to a Chromebook, maybe that will be fun.
Speaker 7:  But I, I don't think they think of the Chromebook the same way as think of
Speaker 7:  the Pixel. No,
Speaker 9:  I agree. Yeah. And as a, as a layer on top of stuff
Speaker 9:  Google is, is like the quick insert button where you can just like put it
Speaker 9:  anywhere kind of makes sense. Right? And you're invoking like system software
Speaker 9:  instead of just doing it inside of Google Docs. But I,
Speaker 9:  I don't know, I don't see it hard to get excited about it.
Speaker 7:  It's interesting that we didn't talk about this next one in the context of
Speaker 7:  Microsoft doing copilot because Microsoft was way ahead on AR glasses
Speaker 7:  with HoloLens. And in the same breath that they're doing this new
Speaker 7:  copilot, they're discontinuing HoloLens and everyone's idea
Speaker 7:  is that you'll have an AI assistant that's just looking at stuff with you.
Speaker 7:  But I think HoloLens just never got there.
Speaker 8:  Well also the guy who like was the big champion of HoloLens,
Speaker 7:  He was not a great guy.
Speaker 8:  He was not a great guy and left the company
Speaker 7:  And Panos, I think oversaw the whole thing and he also left. He's
Speaker 8:  Amazon. Yeah. So, so you didn't have any advocates within the company with
Speaker 8:  any real power over it. And it, it's a shame because like HoloLens figured
Speaker 8:  it a lot of it out straight off the bat and then just never did anything
Speaker 8:  besides teach us how to change Spark products.
Speaker 7:  Did they figure it out again? So they solved a display problem? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I, well I don't think the display problem, I think, I think the user interface,
Speaker 8:  I thought the user interface and it really just made sense. And we've seen
Speaker 8:  bits and pieces of that in, in stuff from Meta. We've seen bits and pieces
Speaker 8:  of that and stuff from, from Google. Yeah. We've seen
Speaker 8:  from a lot of people like the, the pinch pinchy and stuff like that. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Saw that there first. But then again, all they did with it was teach you
Speaker 8:  and I how to change spark plugs. And that's not especially useful
Speaker 7:  Still to this day. One of the coolest demos I've ever received from a tech
Speaker 7:  company, super,
Speaker 8:  Super cool. I
Speaker 7:  Actually, they set up a full garage,
Speaker 8:  Pull up YouTube.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There's also that problem. No, they set up a full garage and like walked
Speaker 7:  around and like was like, there's a spark club, there's where it goes and
Speaker 7:  screwed it in.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It was, it was sick.
Speaker 7:  And I was like, man, if I ever open up an A TV shop with a lot of extra money,
Speaker 8:  I'm
Speaker 7:  Ready. And I don't know what I'm doing.
Speaker 9:  This just makes me think that like this coming on the heels of what we were
Speaker 9:  talking about with meta last week, like it's so
Speaker 9:  clear that the only way to do this right now is
Speaker 9:  to have some stakeholder, ideally your CEO
Speaker 9:  who is so hell bent on the idea that this is the future,
Speaker 9:  that they're going to just pour money down the drain
Speaker 9:  to make it happen.
Speaker 8:  So Tim Cook,
Speaker 9:  I, I think Tim Cook is one of those people. Yeah. Like he, his, that man
Speaker 9:  has been a true believer in AR for a long time, like a
Speaker 9:  long time and has talked unusually publicly about how much he
Speaker 9:  believes in AR for a really long time. And I don't think Microsoft
Speaker 9:  has that conviction. I don't think Microsoft has that conviction about
Speaker 9:  much. Sometimes too. It's detriment.
Speaker 8:  It did have that conviction for a little bit there, right? Like, like it
Speaker 8:  did. They were like, they were like, this is gonna be the future of computing.
Speaker 8:  We're gonna do everything this way. Go get yourself one of these Acer headsets
Speaker 8:  and put it on so you can see the future. And then instead they were like,
Speaker 8:  nevermind.
Speaker 9:  Right. Well I think to your point, the people with that conviction don't
Speaker 9:  work there anymore.
Speaker 8:  Right. And, and so, and then they saw AI and they said that's shiny and that
Speaker 8:  works. That's what we're gonna chase out.
Speaker 9:  And it also makes us Azure money. Like Yeah. I just, I feel like Microsoft's
Speaker 9:  conviction is in office and in Azure and everything else. It will just
Speaker 9:  worry about later. And Microsoft has figured out a way to make a lot of money
Speaker 9:  on the AI revolution without winning the AI revolution. And
Speaker 9:  I think is gonna be fine with that. Whether that is the right call long term
Speaker 9:  or whether some next generation of Microsoft leadership is gonna
Speaker 9:  be like, dear God, why did we give up on this in the same way that I think
Speaker 9:  a lot of people feel like Microsoft botched mobile in all of
Speaker 9:  the decisions that it made and has made a lot of
Speaker 9:  wrong decisions about killing products that turned out to have been the wrong
Speaker 9:  decision over time. Who knows? But I, I think you're right that like
Speaker 9:  HoloLens got a lot of things right and there's no reason to believe that
Speaker 9:  if Microsoft hadn't really, really bought into this idea
Speaker 9:  that it could be very much in this race instead of like kind of a
Speaker 9:  joke inside of it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I don't think they solve the display problem. I just wanna be clear that
Speaker 7:  a hundred percent the thing that is the problem for all these devices is
Speaker 7:  the displays. And I think Microsoft got as far with HoloLens as they could,
Speaker 7:  realized they were not getting any farther and decided to walk and
Speaker 7:  I'll reveal this much.
Speaker 7:  I think the people who worked on HoloLens have looked at Orion and said,
Speaker 7:  met it didn't solve it either. Hmm. Just a, just a thing that I've heard
Speaker 7:  through the grapevine, all last one, and we're gonna try to
Speaker 7:  get through this one very quickly.
Speaker 9:  Oh God, I know it's, it's not
Speaker 7:  Gonna work. It's, it's very complicated. But we, we can add
Speaker 7:  some reporting to it. Like I said, we might break some news on this episode.
Speaker 7:  There's a lot of drama and open source world
Speaker 7:  about WordPress and If. you dunno, WordPress is, I don't know why you're
Speaker 7:  listening to the show. I think the people listen to VER has to know WordPress
Speaker 7:  is, but WordPress is the most dominant content management
Speaker 7:  platform on the internet. It's the thing that runs all websites. Famously
Speaker 7:  open source famously The Verge is moving to WordPress sometime
Speaker 7:  next year. I would call this a conflict of interest, but we're paying them.
Speaker 8:  Hmm.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You know, I know
Speaker 9:  That is, it's, I dunno, it's like saying Slack is a conflict of interest
Speaker 9:  because I'm forced to use Slack every day. Like it's, it's fine,
Speaker 7:  Whatever that is. Other Vox media networks already on WordPress Polygon,
Speaker 7:  notably on WordPress vox.com. On WordPress today, sometime next year, we're,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna move the back end. The front end will look larger the same. It
Speaker 7:  doesn't matter. I'm just letting you know because we disclose everything
Speaker 7:  as like at, at this point, force of habit. Lot of
Speaker 7:  drama in WordPress world. David, what is going on? Oh
Speaker 9:  God. Okay. So the very short version of this story
Speaker 9:  is that I have to explain the structure of the internet too. No. So the
Speaker 9:  very short version of the story is Matt Mullenweg, who is one of the co-creators
Speaker 9:  of, of all things WordPress and is the CEO of Automatic, which is a company
Speaker 9:  that oversees wordpress.com, which does a, provides a lot of service to WordPress.
Speaker 9:  The, the simplest way I can explain the difference here is there is wordpress.com,
Speaker 9:  which is a for-profit company that provides a lot of WordPress services and
Speaker 9:  hosts websites and does all kinds of stuff for WordPress. There's also wordpress.org,
Speaker 9:  which is the open source software that's open to everybody. It's like Google's
Speaker 9:  version of Android and open source Android, technically different things.
Speaker 9:  Super messy oversight questions over both of them. Matt
Speaker 9:  Mullenweg is the super messy oversight question over both of them.
Speaker 9:  Got, Matt Mullenweg got very mad at this company called WP Engine, which
Speaker 9:  is I think pretty neatly, a wordpress.com competitor. They provide lots of
Speaker 9:  services to WordPress people. They host
Speaker 7:  WordPress. So WordPress has software you can download and you can just like
Speaker 7:  host it yourself. Right? We can pay another company to host to manage it
Speaker 7:  for you. Right. To just run your website on. Right. And
Speaker 9:  That's WP Engine is
Speaker 7:  A big, that's what WP Engine does.
Speaker 9:  It got bought by a private equity company. Matt Mullenweg, like many people,
Speaker 9:  has strong negative feelings about private equity.
Speaker 9:  Picked a fight basically saying you're being a bad citizen of the open source
Speaker 9:  community because you're not giving stuff back to the open source community,
Speaker 9:  even though you're taking things from the open source community. This spiraled
Speaker 9:  into WP Engine, essentially calling him an an
Speaker 9:  extortionist, which led to a, a lawsuit calling him an Extortionist after
Speaker 9:  Automatic, sent them a term sheet basically demanding a chunk of
Speaker 9:  either their revenue or their employee's time dedicated back to the open
Speaker 9:  source community. And I think that's
Speaker 9:  a rough sense of where we are. These two sides are very mad at each other
Speaker 9:  about everything. Yeah. And Matt Mullenweg would tell you that he is just
Speaker 9:  being a defender of the open source community and the WordPress community
Speaker 9:  at large, WP Engine would tell you that he is trying to bully
Speaker 9:  them out of their money and or out of existence.
Speaker 7:  Right. So along the way, the only mechanism
Speaker 7:  for wordpress.com and Automatic to get money
Speaker 7:  out of WP Engine was to claim some amount of
Speaker 7:  intellectual property infringement somewhere. But you can't do that 'cause
Speaker 7:  WordPress dot, because the WordPress code is open source. So
Speaker 7:  what they're claiming is trademark infringement over the WordPress name
Speaker 9:  And WooCommerce, which is a thing that Automatic owns and is a big, it's
Speaker 9:  like a Shopify competitor inside of WordPress and it's very big and very
Speaker 9:  popular. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So they're claiming this trademark infringement and to settle it, they're
Speaker 7:  saying you can pay us some percentage of revenue, which might be huge. This
Speaker 7:  is all very messy and we've been reporting on it. Emma Roth on our
Speaker 7:  team has been an amazing job reporting on it. By the time you listen to this,
Speaker 7:  she should have a story up because she just talked to Matt Mullenweg.
Speaker 7:  Well, we were podcasting. She was doing reporting.
Speaker 7:  There's a thing here going on that it feels
Speaker 7:  like we're, we're splitting hairs that Matt is trying to split hairs between
Speaker 7:  the WordPress Foundation, which has a, like a board of directors, like
Speaker 7:  a, there's three of 'em. Matt's one of 'em that actually makes decisions
Speaker 7:  Automatic and wordpress.com, which is the company that he's the CEO of
Speaker 7:  and in the middle wordpress.org, which is just a website
Speaker 7:  that is the most important website in the entire WordPress ecosystem. Because
Speaker 7:  the other way that you can make life miserable for WP Engine
Speaker 7:  is by blocking access to the repository where all the
Speaker 7:  plugins live on WordPress, which is wordpress.org Right.
Speaker 9:  Plugins, themes, like all the, all the stuff that isn't like the very basic
Speaker 9:  infrastructure lives inside of wordpress.org.
Speaker 7:  Yep. And so If, you set up If, you If, you take open source WordPress code,
Speaker 7:  build it yourself and put up your own website and you wanna use a new theme.
Speaker 7:  It's gonna go look@wordpress.org, right? Which is where all the plugins and
Speaker 7:  themes are. Matt Mullen Wave just said to Mr os wordpress.org just
Speaker 7:  belongs to me personally. Whoa. It's just
Speaker 7:  his website. He's the one who controls the repository of all the
Speaker 7:  plugins and things. He
Speaker 13:  Made his own WordPress site.
Speaker 7:  It, it, I think it runs on WordPress. So there's the foundation which controls
Speaker 7:  the open source code and also notably has the trademark
Speaker 7:  Automatic, gave the trademark to the WordPress Foundation
Speaker 7:  of WordPress, and then WordPress Foundation licensed it back to automatic.
Speaker 7:  So there's that mess. Where to call yourself WordPress,
Speaker 7:  you need to apparently get the trademark, which is hazy. That's a new idea.
Speaker 7:  And then there's the, to use WordPress at any scale, you probably want the
Speaker 7:  repository of plugins and themes and everything, which just means Matt has
Speaker 7:  to like you because it's just his. Here's the other quote.
Speaker 7:  I happily provide wordpress.org services to literally every other host. We
Speaker 7:  serve over 30,000 requests per second. I can't say the exact numbers, like
Speaker 7:  40 times the size of WP Engine websites that pay wordpress.org for updates,
Speaker 7:  for plugin searches, for image searches, for everything they have every right
Speaker 7:  to the GPL code. And that's perhaps what my PR team is trying to explain.
Speaker 7:  They have access to all the code, but they don't have any rights to call
Speaker 7:  our services.
Speaker 7:  So he's basically saying, I can just take this away from you. Oh boy. And
Speaker 7:  that is complicated. Like in the world of open
Speaker 7:  source, the whole point of this is no one gets all the control. And he's
Speaker 7:  saying, well, I have this control and either they can pay us for the trademark,
Speaker 7:  which will help pay to fund the development, or they can walk away from
Speaker 7:  everything that I provide on my own. That's a lot of con like, I think a
Speaker 7:  lot of open source people are having a lot of feelings about this. Can
Speaker 7:  I just make the devil's advocate argument here? Hmm. The,
Speaker 7:  the thing about open source is you, other companies are supposed to be able
Speaker 7:  to take your code and do whatever they want with it. And So I
Speaker 7:  have all the feelings in the world about private equity. We did an entire
Speaker 7:  decoder about private equity being bad. And so the idea that the private
Speaker 7:  equity company is gonna come and free ride in the open source community and
Speaker 7:  provide hosting services and never contribute anything back to the code.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's problematic. It, you know, probably offends,
Speaker 7:  but the leverage points in open source are rarely
Speaker 7:  in taking things away. Right. Like that's against the
Speaker 7:  ideals of the community. Right. And I, there's something there
Speaker 7:  that needs to get sorted out here that I don't understand. Like If, you are
Speaker 7:  on the Chrome team at Google.
Speaker 7:  Lots of people are doing all kinds of wacky stuff with the open source chromium
Speaker 7:  engines, including Microsoft building browsers that compete with you.
Speaker 7:  But you, they're still open sourcing chromium because
Speaker 7:  that makes the whole ecosystem better.
Speaker 9:  I think the better analogy in this particular case might be with Android,
Speaker 9:  because you, you have on the one hand A OSP, the
Speaker 9:  the open source Android, which which anyone can take and do whatever they
Speaker 9:  want with. And lots of people do. Like, there is an overwhelming chance that
Speaker 9:  everything in your house that you think is a gadget runs on Android in
Speaker 9:  some way. Many of them are the open source Android. And then there is
Speaker 9:  what you would call like recognizable Android and Google
Speaker 9:  famously Litigiously Regulatorily
Speaker 9:  said If, you want the full experience of Android that feels
Speaker 9:  like it is to people, which means you need things like the Play store, which
Speaker 9:  means you need things like YouTube pretty popular, you need Gmail pretty
Speaker 9:  popular. Here is a long set of rules that you have to play by. And, and
Speaker 9:  it's technically you can have Android, technically it is open source, but
Speaker 9:  If, you want the thing that is functionally recognizably the Android that
Speaker 9:  people want. Here's a long set of Google rules for it. And that feels
Speaker 9:  a lot like either the threat or the reality of what's happening here is like,
Speaker 9:  sure, knock yourself out. You can have WordPress but If, you want the thing
Speaker 9:  that actually is WordPress, you have to play by my rules. And that
Speaker 9:  feels different. Yeah. If, you want
Speaker 7:  WooCommerce and all of that.
Speaker 9:  W but like literally like plugins, like the thing that makes comments
Speaker 9:  work is like, that's a, that's a separate thing.
Speaker 9:  And if you're, if you're gonna take away literally everything other than
Speaker 9:  you can have words that render on a
Speaker 9:  page and make that part of the, the,
Speaker 9:  like, if you're in my good Graces side of things, you've completely changed
Speaker 9:  the way that people are gonna feel about this.
Speaker 7:  Well, so let me make a tiny distinction here. 'cause it's a small distinction,
Speaker 7:  but it's a big one. So if you're
Speaker 7:  Motorola and you wanna make an Android phone and you're like, I can't
Speaker 7:  sell an Android phone unless I Google Maps, that means I gotta take all of
Speaker 7:  place services and sign Google's contracts and all that. At least you're
Speaker 7:  a big company, right? And there isn't anything other than Android. You can
Speaker 7:  run, like you're not calling Microsoft being like, so Windows phone, right?
Speaker 7:  But whatever. But you, you have some amount of agency 'cause you're a company
Speaker 7:  and it, you, I can either make a phone or not. In this case, WP Engine is
Speaker 7:  a reselling WordPress hosting to its customers who are now being blocked
Speaker 7:  from going to get plugins. And those customers are kind of being
Speaker 7:  punished for picking a hosting provider that competes with wordpress.com.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's where this just gets really sideways, right? They're,
Speaker 7:  they're trying to punish WP Engine and maybe they're right, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  like dueling lawsuits, who knows. But at the end of the day, it's a bunch
Speaker 7:  of WordPress customers, like people using
Speaker 17:  And there's number four.
Speaker 7:  Alright, we're back
Speaker 7:  for the lightning round. I'm
Speaker 8:  Gonna break some news on the lightning round.
Speaker 7:  The worst sponsor we've ever had in the lightning round. We
Speaker 7:  have some news Alex Sayer news.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so the news is I am leaving The Verge today
Speaker 8:  is my last, or when you're listening to this, it'll be my last day. This
Speaker 8:  is my last VERGE cast. Well that's great.
Speaker 7:  It might not be your last VERGE cast. It might
Speaker 8:  Not be the last VERGE cast, but this is the last one as co host. Yeah. And
Speaker 8:  it is, it is a i great time. I've had a wonderful
Speaker 8:  time working with you guys and, and doing really cool stuff here and
Speaker 8:  talking about my Plex server as, as humanly possible.
Speaker 8:  Subscribe now via Venmo. Yeah. Alex
Speaker 7:  Is leaving to start a subscription Flex server business. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That definitely won't end in litigation. So yeah, just
Speaker 8:  gonna take a break for a little bit and play as many video games as possible.
Speaker 8:  Hit me up if you've got recommendations, but it has been a blast.
Speaker 8:  And now we're gonna talk about a lightning round. Not
Speaker 7:  No, first we have a surprise. Oh, who am I gonna talk about? He with Alex
Speaker 7:  the surprise? Yes.
Speaker 8:  Oh hell yes. Look at this. Look at this. We got Kate.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna light the studio on fire with this. Happy. I mean, do do we have
Speaker 7:  a plan for what happens, Natalie?
Speaker 19:  Well, I I figured Alex would make a, a secret
Speaker 19:  wish for her last episode of The Verge Cast. Blow out our candles and
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Liam said Alex, you have to make a secret wish and then blow out your
Speaker 7:  candles.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 19:  And then you have to guess
Speaker 7:  What the wish is. I don't think this is what we usually do when people leave
Speaker 7:  the So,
Speaker 8:  So, so my Is
Speaker 7:  This the new tradition? I think Neil, I should have to give you his jacket
Speaker 7:  for your last VERGE cast.
Speaker 8:  I take the jacket with me. All right. Lemme blow 'em out. 'cause then I'll
Speaker 8:  tell you what my secret wish is.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God. We're gonna set off this smoke. We
Speaker 8:  Hit me a hundred percent. This is what it gets. They send us our, their
Speaker 8:  smoke. Wow. We give them ours.
Speaker 7:  My secret wish is we don't get arrested. My
Speaker 8:  Secret wish is Amazon fixes the Kindle. Hey, I, I feel
Speaker 8:  it in my heart. I feel like I'm, I'm bringing that into existence.
Speaker 7:  You're willing, we're willing. Some new willing, some new
Speaker 7:  Kindles into existence. All right. Well, Alex, it has been a delight and
Speaker 7:  a pleasure. It has. I'm glad we got to spend our last few verse chasses in
Speaker 7:  the studio together.
Speaker 8:  It is gorgeous studio Oh my
Speaker 7:  God. That we have now lit on fire. Yeah. It smells like burning birthday
Speaker 7:  cake in here so much.
Speaker 8:  It smells very, very good.
Speaker 7:  You know how usually when we sat down in here, it smells like weed. The next
Speaker 7:  people are gonna be like, what is that weed?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And it's, it's cake weed.
Speaker 7:  All right, let's do the, let's do the Latin Your end. Let's do it. Alex.
Speaker 7:  You, you, you are the person of honor. You go first. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So Nintendo is, is continuing to
Speaker 8:  find switch emulators and kill them.
Speaker 8:  In this case it was R Rio Jinx. I think that's how you say it.
Speaker 8:  Rio Jinx sounds right. And Rio Jinx, however you wanna
Speaker 8:  say that. But it was another switch. Em emulator, they actually reached
Speaker 8:  out. Nintendo apparently reached out to the developer and was like,
Speaker 8:  can you stop? And it's unclear if they reached out via legal
Speaker 8:  channels via stop and we'll give you money channels. It's, it's,
Speaker 8:  it's not really clear there, there haven't said a whole lot, but, but it
Speaker 8:  stopped a lot of theories for this. Nintendo has famously
Speaker 8:  not gone after emulators in the past and now it's gone after, this is
Speaker 8:  now two switch emulators that have been killed. And the my favorite
Speaker 8:  theory so far is that the Switch and the Switch
Speaker 8:  two have such similar, like they work so similarly
Speaker 8:  that they're trying to just head off switch to emulation by
Speaker 8:  killing the Switch one emulators, which we saw the same thing with We versus
Speaker 8:  the Weu. It uses the same thing. So like Dolphin.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So, so that's, that's like, that's
Speaker 7:  A, knowing that the Switch two is so small of a leap. Yeah. That switch
Speaker 7:  one emulators now have to be legal is, I feel like I know a lot now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So, so definitely play all of
Speaker 8:  your switch games on your pc. We're a little run better. And that, which
Speaker 8:  is what we learned this week because of emulators like this, we saw like,
Speaker 8:  oh, it actually runs better when it's not. The cake smells so good. It's,
Speaker 7:  It's, it smells so much like cake in here. It's
Speaker 8:  So much. It's like a bakery in here and rules. But, but
Speaker 8:  yeah. So it sounds like the Switch two is, you know, If, you still have your
Speaker 8:  copy of this stuff. You might be able to play some switch two games. Wow.
Speaker 8:  When it comes out. We'll see same thing happened again. Same thing happened
Speaker 8:  previously, but they didn't go after Dolphin and all of those companies.
Speaker 8:  So something's different this
Speaker 7:  Time. That is fascinating that that, that they have not pushed the switch
Speaker 7:  to that far ahead. Yeah. Or at least that's what it feels like.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And and the exact same thing. We were all like, why, why is the Weu
Speaker 8:  so similar? And they're like, well, because we want your money and we don't
Speaker 8:  wanna build a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 9:  Alex wasn't this the one that was supposed to be untouchable after all the
Speaker 9:  yuzu stuff? It was like, oh, but there's this other one. People start using
Speaker 9:  it and and they won't shut it down. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  'cause it was based in Brazil, right? Oh yeah. So, so it was based in Brazil.
Speaker 8:  So they thought they would, they, they were like, there's less litigation
Speaker 8:  I guess you can do 'cause Brazil's laws around this stuff is a little different.
Speaker 8:  Got it. But that's why Nintendo apparently reached out directly to the developer
Speaker 8:  and was like, stop and unclear if they said Stop
Speaker 8:  really, and like really seriously. Or if they said stop and then slowly pushed
Speaker 8:  over a bag of money in a little Mario suitcase. But
Speaker 8:  something happened there. Yeah. Sean's been on it. He will continue to
Speaker 8:  be on it. I'm sure he will find out the truth. And he better text me. First
Speaker 7:  We asked Sean to write a story about the state of emulation and he came back
Speaker 7:  with, I could do a multi-part feature package. And we're like, one, one story.
Speaker 7:  Let's start.
Speaker 9:  But he is not wrong. He's
Speaker 7:  Not wrong. It's, it's, there's a lot there. All right, David, what's
Speaker 7:  first
Speaker 9:  I just wanna briefly talk about a web app that I'm very excited about,
Speaker 9:  which is the, the new Google Pixel Buds web
Speaker 9:  app is a web app, an oh an app on the web that you
Speaker 9:  can download on lots of devices and use to manage your pixel
Speaker 9:  buds. You can update your firmware, you can change the multi-point
Speaker 9:  connection stuff. You can like, do all the things you would normally
Speaker 9:  do on one device, but you can do it on the web, which means you can do it
Speaker 9:  anywhere. And I'm just like, this to me was one of those moments where it
Speaker 9:  was like, oh, this is why the web is better. Right? Like this, this is an
Speaker 9:  example I will point to, to a lot of people. You can, you can update the
Speaker 9:  firmware on your Bluetooth headset through a web app. I
Speaker 9:  just wanna say that out loud. That is, that is a thing that is possible to
Speaker 9:  do. That's good. And it means you can do it anywhere. And this is very
Speaker 9:  exciting and this is how it should work everywhere.
Speaker 7:  Wait, the pixel bot stops to talk to your phone to Bluetooth, right? Through
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth, right? Yeah. So the web app can control the Bluetooth on your
Speaker 7:  phone or communicate over Bluetooth from your phone.
Speaker 8:  It's just,
Speaker 7:  It just feels like Tim Cook is standing there being like, you shall not pass
Speaker 9:  Whenever it's a progressive web app. Right? So you, you like have to sort
Speaker 9:  of, you have to like do the home screening thing. Oh sure. But it has it,
Speaker 9:  they're able to have this same kind of access. And to me it's like, this
Speaker 9:  is a thing Google has pressed on for years, right? They're like, rather than
Speaker 9:  make good native apps, especially for iOS, we're just gonna make
Speaker 9:  you use our websites. Sometimes that sucks. Like with Google Docs, which
Speaker 9:  I desperately could use a better native app on iOS, but in this case it's
Speaker 9:  like, oh, it's ridiculous that the only way to manage your
Speaker 9:  headphones is through one single device. And the fact that
Speaker 9:  you can just open up a website and do it on other devices
Speaker 9:  is a good thing. And like speaks to how powerful Progressive Web Apps can
Speaker 9:  be when they're actually like developed and worked on and
Speaker 9:  allowed to be powerful. And I just think that's very cool.
Speaker 8:  It sounds so normal that I'm like, wait, you can't already do this with a
Speaker 8:  bunch of other products.
Speaker 7:  Well, with other products historically, yeah. They have all run tiny
Speaker 7:  web servers in them. Right. So you can control my
Speaker 7:  Sony receiver through a a web browser, but
Speaker 7:  you shouldn't.
Speaker 8:  But I'm gonna,
Speaker 7:  Do you know what I mean? Like there's, there's something, there's a, there's
Speaker 7:  a full on web server, like a Apache is running on you. You you're gonna
Speaker 8:  Be like, what's happening in my house next week? And you won't
Speaker 7:  Know. Yeah. It's just like web server. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna have a great time
Speaker 7:  Plex server running on my receiver. I know what you're after Alex. Oh yeah.
Speaker 7:  Alex has botnet Plex server idea who's been pitching this to
Speaker 7:  Caesar in the country's
Speaker 8:  It's gonna rule get excited, but
Speaker 7:  Like, but but you're talking about a web app that actually just talking to
Speaker 7:  the device directly. Not some weird web server idea.
Speaker 9:  Right? And it's, it's just a, it's just a more cross-platform way of
Speaker 9:  doing the same kind of stuff. Like If, you have a pair of AirPods, right?
Speaker 9:  Like you can, you can manage the settings of your AirPods
Speaker 9:  on your phone in a way that you can't anywhere else. Like God help
Speaker 9:  you If. you want to like change the way you do stuff on your AirPods
Speaker 9:  through an Android phone. Sure. Best of luck friend o you
Speaker 9:  can, that's not how it should work. And it, this now works in other places
Speaker 9:  and like I have a, oh, I
Speaker 7:  Get it. 'cause you don't have to write an Android app and an iOS app and
Speaker 7:  a desktop app. You just Right. You
Speaker 9:  Just write web apps and it works everywhere because it actually has that
Speaker 9:  access. And like I have a, I have a pair of Bose quiet
Speaker 9:  comfort headphones that like theoretically do multi-point, but they never
Speaker 9:  ever guess correctly, which thing I want to connect to So. I. Like turn it
Speaker 9:  on and it's like connected to these two devices. And then I press play on
Speaker 9:  my phone and it's like, you didn't want that. You're trying to play from
Speaker 9:  your computer, which is closed in your backpack. So. I have to open up the
Speaker 9:  Bose app and on my phone, turn off the computer
Speaker 9:  one turn on the phone one, and then it will play in the right place. And
Speaker 9:  it's like all of this management is bad, but the idea of just being able
Speaker 9:  to like whip open a browser and do it anywhere is good. And I'm in favor.
Speaker 7:  So here's my worry about this. The web app still lives in the web, which
Speaker 7:  means when Google wants to turn it off, which
Speaker 7:  Google often wants to do, it just disappears. Whereas
Speaker 7:  at least if I have the bits on my iOS device or whatever, or my Android,
Speaker 7:  Android phone, at least they're still there. The thing I'm specifically thinking
Speaker 7:  about this week, we ran a story, juice Box If. you have EV Charger or
Speaker 7:  Juice Box. Oh yeah. That company N LX just was like f it. We're out.
Speaker 7:  Like we're just leaving North America and all of the backend infrastructure,
Speaker 7:  including the commercial chargers that they have installed is just going
Speaker 7:  dark. Oof. So the thing will still charge your car with whatever settings
Speaker 7:  you have, but If, you wanna change the amps or you want to connect it to
Speaker 7:  your electric company or whatever it's gone to. Like literally
Speaker 7:  they changed their website to just a letter that's like, we out.
Speaker 8:  Yep.
Speaker 7:  Nope. You can email this email address that we're not listening to.
Speaker 7:  And like that's the always the worry, right? Is like if you're now dependent
Speaker 7:  on Google maintaining an app on the web, let me tell you about
Speaker 7:  Google's history of maintaining apps on the web.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I should also say it only works in chromium. Of course. Yeah. So there's
Speaker 9:  a large series of browsers it won't work inside of including
Speaker 9:  the iOS ones.
Speaker 9:  It all sucks, but I think But that's better. Like it's better. I just, my
Speaker 9:  I it, it just confirms my belief that if we do it right, Progressive, Web,
Speaker 9:  Apps solve a lot of problems. Yeah. Somewhere. Dieter Bone just did a thumbs
Speaker 9:  up at his headphones hearing me say that. Dieter, I love you.
Speaker 7:  His headphones are paired to the wrong device. It's the real problem. Peter
Speaker 7:  can't hear us at all.
Speaker 9:  All right, Neela, what's yours?
Speaker 7:  I'm so sorry for this, but also You're welcome.
Speaker 7:  That's what I have.
Speaker 9:  Sometimes you introduce what you're about to talk about and I just immediately
Speaker 9:  know and I'm like, oh, I can leave for 20 minutes. Like This's fine. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  I'll
Speaker 7:  Come back. So my lightning round is a direct tv. The satellite TV company
Speaker 7:  is merging with Dish, the other satellite TV company.
Speaker 7:  It's for a dollar like the, and you, you look at the transaction price.
Speaker 7:  CNBC is like DirecTV to buy Dish for a dollar. It's actually they're taking
Speaker 7:  on $9 billion of debt. Hmm.
Speaker 8:  Sometimes If, you have one Titanic and you put it with another Titanic,
Speaker 8:  maybe it won't sink as
Speaker 7:  Fast. You're like, you've reduced the debt that I'm taking on by $1 is
Speaker 7:  what you've accomplished here. So they're acquiring this like underwater
Speaker 7:  company for a a dollar and a whole bunch of debt.
Speaker 7:  DirecTV is being further spun out of at and t by a private
Speaker 7:  equity company called TPG Management. And then they're gonna merge the
Speaker 7:  whole thing with Dish and that will be the satellite company. And then
Speaker 7:  Echo Star,
Speaker 7:  the company that currently owns Dish will be free to pursue
Speaker 7:  its dream of starting a 5G network in this country called
Speaker 7:  Genesis, which I does not exist.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 9:  This doesn't kill the possibilities for Gen five sis,
Speaker 7:  Gen five sis, it still exists. The only phone they have is the
Speaker 7:  2023 Motorola Edge Plus, which you can get in some
Speaker 7:  markets and mostly, which from at least the Reddit rolls
Speaker 7:  over to at t's network and sucks on it. Sure. That's, and I will remind
Speaker 7:  you that this all happened because T-Mobile wanted to buy Sprint
Speaker 7:  and the Trump administration didn't know how to stop it. So they
Speaker 7:  orchestrated a deal in which T-Mobile was allowed to buy Sprint. A
Speaker 7:  bunch of Sprint Spectrum went to Dish Network. So Dish Network could stand
Speaker 7:  up a 5G network using a technology called O Ran Open Radio
Speaker 7:  Access Network that would become a fourth wireless carrier and provide meaningful
Speaker 7:  competition to at t, Verizon and T-Mobile competition, which all this can
Speaker 7:  feel every day. It went great through the lower prices and better services
Speaker 7:  that we experience in our nation's wireless system.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, Verizon definitely didn't go down this week for like a lot of people
Speaker 9:  in a large chunk of time. Nope. So that's good. Didn't happen.
Speaker 7:  Thank you. Did So that's what, that's, that's today's news. That's
Speaker 7:  what's happening now. I just, the thing I wanna point out to you is
Speaker 7:  that this Merger Mania has been going on
Speaker 7:  for 25 fucking years
Speaker 7:  and Richard Lawler and I have been working together for a long time
Speaker 7:  and we have covered so many versions of these mergers
Speaker 7:  between these companies that we just like looked at each other
Speaker 7:  like, is it over? Is it just beginning?
Speaker 7:  How damaged are we? How much of my brain contains the knowledge
Speaker 7:  of who owns DirecTV? It's so much of it.
Speaker 7:  So Richard and Wes Davis and I sat down and we made a timeline.
Speaker 7:  By the time you listened to this, our poor designer, Kath Virginia,
Speaker 7:  may, may have solved how to make this timeline a chart of mergers.
Speaker 7:  I will tell you right now, it, there's too many mergers on it to make
Speaker 7:  a visually coherent timeline. Like,
Speaker 7:  she's like, can you take stuff out of the timeline? And I'm like, no. Wow.
Speaker 7:  Those are the jerseys. So let me just read
Speaker 7:  you some of what has happened here to arrive at DirecTV buying
Speaker 7:  Dish for a dollar and billions of dollars in debt.
Speaker 9:  Wait, I'm gonna, while you do this, I'm gonna keep a list of the number of
Speaker 9:  companies I forgot existed while you
Speaker 7:  Do this. Oh, I've taken some out of this. I've condensed it. I'll put
Speaker 7:  one on there. Right now. There's a whole company, the whole sideshow of a
Speaker 7:  company called Sky Terra that I just removed from this. That's one that goes
Speaker 7:  on the list. That's just number one. It's not even on my list. The,
Speaker 7:  the Sky Terra sideshow is just, I've removed it. Alright.
Speaker 7:  Our story starts in January, 2001. When a OL Time Warner is born
Speaker 7:  in October, 2001, general Motors
Speaker 7:  gm, the car company tries to sell Hughes Electronics,
Speaker 7:  which owns DirecTV to EchoStar
Speaker 7:  the company that owns Dish Network.
Speaker 7:  This is a victory for EchoStar CEO Charlie
Speaker 7:  Ergen, who beat out Rupert Murdoch, who wanted to buy
Speaker 7:  Echo, who wanted to buy Hughes the FCC blocks
Speaker 7:  Ergen from buying EchoStar. So Hughes EchoStar deal is blocked. This is
Speaker 7:  a huge defeat for Charlie Ergen and News Corp. Rupert Murdoch
Speaker 7:  swoops in in December, 2003 and wins the bid to buy Hughes
Speaker 7:  Electronics giving Rupert Murdoch control of DirecTV
Speaker 7:  March, 2004. Hughes Electronics Rebrands itself as the DirecTV group.
Speaker 7:  November, 2005, a city in Texas called Clark, Texas
Speaker 7:  changes its name to Dish Texas. What in exchange
Speaker 7:  for 10 years of free TVs and DVRs.
Speaker 9:  That's amazing.
Speaker 7:  This is a real thing that happens. Mm. In June of
Speaker 7:  2006, I graduated from law school. Lemme just put that in there because this
Speaker 7:  is when Richard and I entered the scene and start blogging every one of these
Speaker 7:  deals. At Eng Gadget. January, 2008, EchoStar officially renamed
Speaker 7:  itself to Dish Network and splits into two companies. One is Dish
Speaker 7:  Network, the provider of satellite services, and the other
Speaker 7:  is certain satellite assets which are owned by a new company called
Speaker 7:  EchoStar. What does it make any sense to you? No. EchoStar
Speaker 7:  renamed itself to Dish and splits off a company that owns a satellite. It's
Speaker 7:  called EchoStar Time Warner. In March, 2009 spins off Time
Speaker 7:  Warner Cable. December, 2009 spins off a OL. Just keep that
Speaker 7:  in mind.
Speaker 7:  June, 2011, EchoStar buys Hughes Communications, remember,
Speaker 9:  Which didn't exist anymore,
Speaker 7:  Giving EchoStar and therefore dish access to those satellites.
Speaker 7:  February, 2013, Comcast buys the remainder of NBC Universal from ge,
Speaker 7:  a General Electric, not General Motors, a process that had started two years
Speaker 7:  earlier. March, 2014, DirecTV and Dish are rumored to be in talks for
Speaker 7:  a merger, which falls through May, 2014. At and t announces
Speaker 7:  it, we'll buy DirecTV. So now we're 10 years ago. At and t has bought DirecTV.
Speaker 7:  June, 2018 at and t buys Time Warner
Speaker 7:  and Renames it Warner Media.
Speaker 7:  I'm just reminding you this started with General Motors selling Hughes
Speaker 7:  Electronics to Rupert Murdoch and we end in June, 2018 with at
Speaker 7:  and t buying Time Warner, which I will remind you resulted
Speaker 7:  in the four three Grayscale Snyder Club. I'm just putting that out there.
Speaker 7:  2020 Dish Network suggests merging with DirecTV once
Speaker 7:  again. Once again, shut down August, 2021, at and t spins off
Speaker 7:  DirecTV because the Warner Media deal was a disaster, but keeps
Speaker 7:  70% of the assets of the company April, 2022, it
Speaker 7:  spins off Warner Media, which merges with Discovery and Warner
Speaker 7:  Brothers Discovery is born January, 2024. Echo Star
Speaker 7:  once again buys Dish Network.
Speaker 7:  I don't know, man, what this happened. It's rules
Speaker 7:  October, 2024 at T will sell the rest of direct TDB to
Speaker 7:  TPG, which will then buy Dish Network and
Speaker 7:  merge the two together. Finally,
Speaker 7:  what a disaster that is. So many billions of dollars
Speaker 7:  in so many layoffs. I cannot even tell you. Every one of those deals,
Speaker 7:  thousands of peoples lost their jobs. Every one of those deals, thousands
Speaker 7:  of people lost their jobs and all of our service declined.
Speaker 7:  All the bankers got rich, all the lawyers got rich. Well, what a
Speaker 7:  disaster.
Speaker 8:  A bunch of people in Clark, Texas have free TVs
Speaker 7:  Out. The people of Clark, Texas got 10 years of free DVR.
Speaker 8:  There's only like 400 people that live
Speaker 7:  There and you can't argue that, you know, this was all because satellite
Speaker 7:  distribution went away and now there's streaming. But this all
Speaker 7:  came to nothing. Dish and EchoStar have merged and split and been
Speaker 7:  owned by different companies like eight times in that list. I think
Speaker 9:  EchoStar you just described as like four completely different entities. Yep.
Speaker 9:  Over the course of that
Speaker 7:  And somewhere in there I'd like
Speaker 9:  there's an