# Transcript
ID: 66d56b16-5d66-4ab3-b42e-6325a02e5f7c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7009124679606371689/3470904767424790036/s93290-US-5168s-1727778774.mp3
Description: The Verge's Jennifer Pattison Tuohy joins the show to discuss a bunch of updates in the smart home world, including what's new from Google Home and in iOS 18, plus some big news in the world of smart locks and video doorbells. Then, The Verge's Chris Welch comes on to test some new earbuds, and see which pair has the best sound – and the best mic. After that, a new take on the Vergecast's chaotic wearables theory.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Powered Front
Speaker 2:  Doors, which is a thing that I just learned exists. Thanks to this
Speaker 2:  episode, I'm your friend David Pierce and I am cooped up
Speaker 2:  inside and have been for several days. Obviously a lot of people in the
Speaker 2:  US have been really horribly affected by Hurricane Helene.
Speaker 2:  I hope you're all doing okay. Our thoughts are obviously with everyone dealing
Speaker 2:  with all of that where I am. It's been fine. It's just
Speaker 2:  basically been raining for four days and my kid has been outta daycare and
Speaker 2:  he's been sick and so it's just been a lot of inside
Speaker 2:  time. It's been a lot of running around in the basement. It's been a lot
Speaker 2:  of watching the same old McDonald had a farm YouTube video over and
Speaker 2:  over. It's just been a lot like you, you, you just grow to
Speaker 2:  appreciate outside more and more. I'm in a real like touch grass moment
Speaker 2:  except it's still raining so there will be no grass touching for a little
Speaker 2:  while. Even the dog over there is starting to lose it a little bit I
Speaker 2:  think. But anyway, luckily we have The Vergecast to keep us on track
Speaker 2:  and doing stuff. Today we have two things we're gonna do. First
Speaker 2:  we're gonna catch up with Jen Tuy about all things Smart Home. There's been
Speaker 2:  a lot this summer she was at EFA looking at sworn home gadgets. We have some
Speaker 2:  protocol news with Matter and Thread. We have a bunch of stuff going on with
Speaker 2:  Google and Apple and software updates everywhere and all kinds of fun stuff
Speaker 2:  to talk about. So we're just gonna kind of play round Robin and catch up
Speaker 2:  with her. Then we're gonna talk to Chris Welch about this new run of
Speaker 2:  earbuds that we have this year. Apple just released some new ones. Google
Speaker 2:  released some new ones. Samsung released some new ones. Bose released some
Speaker 2:  new ones. I'm missing some. Oh nothing. Just released some new ones that
Speaker 2:  I'm really interested in. So we're gonna talk to him about this new slate
Speaker 2:  of earbuds. But also we're gonna do a mic test because as
Speaker 2:  I continue to say and really strongly believe microphones matter,
Speaker 2:  the way we talk to ai, the way we talk to the assistants on our devices,
Speaker 2:  the way we talk to each other, microphones in these earbuds matter
Speaker 2:  a lot and they don't get talked about enough. So we're gonna do what we occasionally
Speaker 2:  do on this show, which is put some really, really bad audio into the podcast
Speaker 2:  and I'm sorry in advance, but you know, we do it for the greater good.
Speaker 2:  We also have a really fun hotline question lots to get to today. Super fun
Speaker 2:  episode. But first I have to, I have to go outside. I'm just gonna
Speaker 2:  go like stand in the rain like a 1990s rom-com
Speaker 2:  star and just like stare upwards for five minutes and then we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  to it. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Very happy to be back indoors looking at screens. Anyway, let's get to it.
Speaker 2:  First up, we're gonna talk about smart home stuff because it's been a minute
Speaker 2:  since we talked about smart home stuff. And normally I like to have the verges
Speaker 2:  Jen Tui on every once in a while just to basically, sadly
Speaker 2:  ask her why matter isn't better and why the smart home isn't fixed. And
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do a little bit of that today. But there's also been a surprising
Speaker 2:  amount of interesting smart home news that kind of points to something
Speaker 2:  bigger going on. There have been a lot of new gadgets for your front door,
Speaker 2:  which I find fascinating. Smart locks and video doorbells and that kind of
Speaker 2:  stuff. So, I. Think that whole space is really interesting. I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about that. We've seen some new software from Google and Apple that makes
Speaker 2:  it easier to administer your smart home, which I think is a really big deal.
Speaker 2:  and we have some protocol news because matter
Speaker 2:  continues to be chaos. We have to talk about the chaos that is matter.
Speaker 2:  Let's get to all of that with Jen. We're just gonna bounce through a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch of news. I'm very excited about it. Let's get into it. Jen. Hello.
Speaker 5:  Hi David. Pleasure to be back. It's been too long.
Speaker 2:  It has been too long. You're you're going through a hurricane right now.
Speaker 2:  We should just tell the people that If you suddenly disappear. And this segment
Speaker 2:  is four minutes long. It's because you're like deep in hurricane times. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Are you holding up? Okay.
Speaker 5:  Helene has been paying us a visit this morning. Thankfully we are not as
Speaker 5:  bad off as the poor people in Florida, but it's, it's been a bumpy ride so
Speaker 5:  far, so fingers crossed. We'll make it through
Speaker 2:  For sure. I find myself very curious in the middle of all this, what happens
Speaker 2:  to your smart home situation when your power goes off and then comes back
Speaker 2:  on? Like, does, is it just full insane chaos
Speaker 2:  every time the power blips in your house right now?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because everything talks to me. It's kind of
Speaker 5:  scary actually, especially when it happens in the middle of the night. 'cause
Speaker 5:  so many things will be like, you know, connection restored or
Speaker 5:  offline and, and like voices from every corner of the house.
Speaker 5:  Robots in particular, robot vacuums, you know, cameras,
Speaker 5:  security systems and lots. Yeah, it it, it gets a little chaotic and then
Speaker 5:  obviously the notifications on my phone are like, ding, ding, ding, ding,
Speaker 5:  ding, ding. You know, offline, offline, offline. You can turn those off.
Speaker 5:  But because I, obviously I'm testing these things, I always turn on all the
Speaker 5:  notifications and then I have, you know, it was, it gets
Speaker 5:  a little crazy, especially cameras. 'cause when they go offline they send
Speaker 5:  you alerts and then when they come back online, right. So this morning I
Speaker 5:  was woken up numerous times throughout the night when the power went out.
Speaker 5:  Thankfully though, smart lights have managed to fix the problem where they
Speaker 5:  all turn on automatically when the power comes back. And
Speaker 5:  that used to be a terrible issue where, you know, they would reset
Speaker 5:  to default and like all the lights in your bedroom would turn on at 2:00 AM
Speaker 5:  when the power came back on. That's no longer a problem. Thankfully.
Speaker 2:  That is really like the first act of a horror movie is, is all of that stuff
Speaker 2:  happening, all
Speaker 5:  Going crazy?
Speaker 2:  Well I'm glad it's, it seems to be settling so I'm, I'm glad, I'm glad everything's
Speaker 2:  okay. Yes,
Speaker 5:  I'm doing good.
Speaker 2:  We have some stuff to catch up on. We do. We have not done our
Speaker 2:  Jen, why isn't matter solving all of my problems check in in a while. So
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do that. But you mentioned right before we started recording
Speaker 2:  that you're working on a, a smart lock thing and
Speaker 2:  I just wanna start, I, I wanna run a theory by you and then I, I want you
Speaker 2:  to tell me what you think and then we're gonna talk about some new stuff
Speaker 2:  around it. Okay. I think you could make a pretty compelling case that
Speaker 2:  your front door is the most interesting space in the smart home
Speaker 2:  right now between what's going on with video doorbells, what's going on with
Speaker 2:  smart locks, what stuff is like mainstream and very
Speaker 2:  good and suddenly like super interesting in a way that I feel like
Speaker 2:  everything else in the smart home is like kind of cool kind of a mess. And
Speaker 2:  it's like your front door is like where cool, interesting, good smart stuff
Speaker 2:  is happening right now. What do you think? Good theory, bad theory?
Speaker 5:  No, I agree. I think the front door always sort of actually always has been
Speaker 5:  a really key part because it's something that appeals to
Speaker 5:  everyone. I mean smart lights are really fun. Robot vacuums have
Speaker 5:  large appeal but you know, they are still niche. But the
Speaker 5:  concept of just of easy access to your home, not worrying about losing
Speaker 5:  keys, being able to let people in lock, unlock your door remotely,
Speaker 5:  know who's at your front door, you know, the front door is the gateway to
Speaker 5:  your house. And having the capability to sort
Speaker 5:  of remotely monitor it, always know what's going on. Having control over
Speaker 5:  the entrance to your home is something that everyone is interested in. Even
Speaker 5:  people that live in apartments, you know, the smart entryways,
Speaker 5:  you know, 'cause smart home quite often apartment dwellers sort of get left
Speaker 5:  out a little bit, but not when it comes to smart locks and smart doorbells
Speaker 5:  there. There's lots of devices tailored to those types of
Speaker 5:  living scenarios. And it is an area that there's a lot going
Speaker 5:  on right now. There's a lot of change happening, but there's also, it's also
Speaker 5:  an area that's always had quite a lot of challenges
Speaker 5:  primarily because of power. And that's an area
Speaker 5:  we've seen more sort of innovation in. I think it will take a while. There
Speaker 5:  was the smart door that came out a couple years ago that was like wired for
Speaker 5:  power, which everyone kind of Oh yeah. Laughed about
Speaker 5:  a little bit but you know. Yeah. I think ultimately most homes, new homes
Speaker 5:  as they're built or homes as they're remodeled, wiring your door for power
Speaker 5:  is gonna make more and more sense. Both for lighting, for
Speaker 5:  powering video doorbells, for powering your door locks. 'cause
Speaker 5:  battery power in the door lock is probably one of the biggest
Speaker 5:  pain points with smart door locks. You know, most sort of
Speaker 5:  ordinary people who decide to get a smart door lock, you know when they realize
Speaker 5:  they have to start changing the batteries every three to six months. It's
Speaker 5:  like this is, this is not smart. This is a pain. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Especially if it locks you out because you know you've ignored the warnings
Speaker 5:  after the seventh or eighth time that they've sent them to you.
Speaker 5:  So we, it's interesting to find, you know, to see the solutions that are
Speaker 5:  coming around there. And then we've also got, UWB is a new,
Speaker 5:  a new technology we're seen in door locks. Apple quite recently
Speaker 5:  announced that they were adding capability for unlocking smart door
Speaker 5:  locks using UWB chip in the iPhone.
Speaker 5:  So we're starting to see sort of a real shift there that in, what's interesting
Speaker 5:  about that is the sort of the hands free notion of you know, being
Speaker 5:  able to access your home without even having to even tap your watch to
Speaker 5:  the door, let alone pull your key out because UWB
Speaker 5:  radio will automatically sense that you are there, connect to your door and
Speaker 5:  unlock it for you. So there's so much interesting going on. But you, you
Speaker 5:  need the power. And actually something I've been testing recently,
Speaker 5:  which sort of ties into all of this is wireless power. I'm testing
Speaker 5:  something called We Charge, which is a wireless power
Speaker 5:  transmitter and it can wirelessly power a door lock that I've been testing,
Speaker 5:  which is by a company called Alfred.
Speaker 2:  Wait, this has been around forever, right? Yes. I feel like I've been hearing
Speaker 2:  like science project things about wireless power for like
Speaker 2:  the entire time I have been covering technology. Is this for
Speaker 2:  real now? Like is somebody actually gonna ship this thing to me at some point?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well you can buy this right now with this door lock. Okay. It is,
Speaker 5:  it's not sort of off the shelf. You kind of have to get in touch with the
Speaker 5:  company and they can arrange for installation. So it's a little laborious.
Speaker 5:  But I was talking to the founder and he said they've actually developed a
Speaker 5:  retrofit design so that you can just plug a little
Speaker 5:  transmitter into power, put it on a shelf and then plug a
Speaker 5:  receiver into your power port of say your door locks, a lot of door locks
Speaker 5:  have power ports and then that can actually end up allowing you to
Speaker 5:  wirelessly power your door. Now wireless power I
Speaker 5:  think is maybe not the solution ultimately to all of these
Speaker 5:  issues. I think Wired is always generally
Speaker 5:  gonna be more reliable, but it requires so much more effort
Speaker 5:  for installation. So, I feel like there is, you know, there's
Speaker 5:  always maybe gonna be a middle ground, you know, especially for retrofit.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna, you know, having the options to do something other than
Speaker 5:  use, I mean, have you used, do you have a smart door lock?
Speaker 2:  I don't. It's actually the, the one and only smart home
Speaker 2:  device that I think my wife would allow me to install. But
Speaker 5:  You haven't
Speaker 2:  So I'm, I'm gonna do it. It's just like we're we're, I'm at the point where
Speaker 2:  I'm procrastinating painting the thing So, I'm not sure I'm a good like
Speaker 2:  version of, you know, being ahead of things on home projects. But it's on
Speaker 2:  the list. It's on the list.
Speaker 5:  Well and the, the battery is an issue. I mean the August
Speaker 5:  is a great smart lock for example, but when you know you have to change the
Speaker 5:  batteries every two to three months, that's too often some smart locks will
Speaker 5:  go at least a year and a year. Sounds great. But actually that's still, that's
Speaker 5:  still a lot. Yeah. I mean it's like, do you remember to change your smoke
Speaker 5:  alarm batteries every year?
Speaker 2:  I remember when it beeps at me right at two o'clock in the morning. That's,
Speaker 2:  that's when I remember to change the smoke alarm.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I mean And that if we could have wireless power
Speaker 5:  or wired for power built into our homes so that you can have, you
Speaker 5:  can power your video doorbell, you can power your door lock, you can power
Speaker 5:  some lighting around your door, maybe even your security panel. You
Speaker 5:  know, it just, I can see sort of a much easier transition
Speaker 5:  to these types of devices rather than having to constantly mess with them
Speaker 5:  and recharge or put new batteries in and
Speaker 5:  So, I go through so many batteries and I hate it. I'm like, ah,
Speaker 2:  This
Speaker 5:  E-waste. Yeah. So it's, it's an interesting space for sure.
Speaker 2:  Too many of these devices also make that part really complicated
Speaker 2:  because I, I think the, the battery life thing is really interesting to me.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think like I I, one of the, I've owned a home for three years
Speaker 2:  now and I'm still discovering all the things you're supposed to do on like
Speaker 2:  a routine basis and I just like, I have, I have furnace
Speaker 2:  air filters right? That I just am supposed to change every three months and
Speaker 2:  I more or less remember every three months. That's fine. It's every three
Speaker 2:  months. It takes 30 seconds, it's fine. But I feel like the problem with
Speaker 2:  way too many of these smart home gadgets is not just that you
Speaker 2:  have to charge it or reinstall
Speaker 2:  batteries or whatever, it's that that process is annoying and I, this has
Speaker 2:  probably gotten a lot better with these gadgets over time. But it feels like
Speaker 2:  you basically have to like unmount the thing, charge the thing,
Speaker 2:  reinstall the thing, reconnect the thing, which probably won't work the first.
Speaker 2:  So there's just, yes, there's all these little pieces that it's like if I
Speaker 2:  could just walk up to it with a double a battery, like pull a thing down,
Speaker 2:  stick the battery and put it back on, I'm good. Yeah, I'll do that three
Speaker 2:  times a year. Yeah. But that is not what the process is.
Speaker 5:  That's generally not what the process is. No and
Speaker 2:  It feels like that to me is the solve problem. Yeah, that is true. Like wireless
Speaker 2:  power is like a miracle of of chemistry that I hope we
Speaker 2:  accomplish sometime day but just like make it easier to change the batteries.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  True. That
Speaker 5:  Seems easier. That is true. There are some where you have to get like a special
Speaker 5:  tool and it's like no.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's just silliness as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Although, but speaking of wireless power, I was just at EFA in Berlin
Speaker 5:  and they, the wireless power consortium have launched the
Speaker 5:  first spec for key wireless power. That's
Speaker 5:  wireless power for kitchen appliances now. Not necessarily ovens
Speaker 5:  and fridges 'cause you don't really need that but for your countertop
Speaker 5:  gadgets. So air fryers, microwaves, blenders,
Speaker 5:  kettles so that you know, you, it's basically
Speaker 5:  induction power. You have induction coils underneath your counter,
Speaker 5:  which can be retrofit also can work with retrofitted
Speaker 5:  induction cooktops. There are some new ones coming out that
Speaker 5:  have this capability built in and your
Speaker 5:  countertop or induction cooktop can power your blender
Speaker 5:  or air fryer and you, they were showed me a demo at EFA
Speaker 5:  where you just basically put the appliance on the countertop and it
Speaker 5:  turn it on and it will blend or cook or whatever it is you need it
Speaker 5:  to do. And what's been, you know, power in the kitchen
Speaker 5:  is a challenge. There's, you know, never enough outlets, the
Speaker 5:  cord never goes far enough where you are trying to reach. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I really do think the thing where everyone has three gadgets and two
Speaker 2:  outlets is like a completely universal experience Yes. Of being a person
Speaker 2:  in the world in a kitchen. Like I can, I can tell, I can picture in
Speaker 2:  my head the Tetris I have to do every time I make coffee just
Speaker 2:  in order to have the, the grinder and the kettle
Speaker 2:  and the milk frother, which is my favorite fancy gadget of all time.
Speaker 2:  I have to just the, I know which one is which by feel. I could do all that
Speaker 2:  like in the dark now and like it's ridiculous and bad because it's three
Speaker 2:  things and two outlets and If you can solve that problem for me. I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  in I love this idea.
Speaker 5:  You a happy person. I know, me too. I have the same issue. And
Speaker 5:  I also got recently redid my kitchen and just still, even though
Speaker 5:  I asked the electrician to put in as many outlets as you could, I still
Speaker 5:  don't have enough outlets. And this, you know,
Speaker 5:  again, a lot of this feels very much in the future, but the,
Speaker 5:  there are, I can see a lot of benefit here, especially in
Speaker 5:  the way that your new, the the, obviously it does require all new
Speaker 5:  appliances, but the way that they are manufactured because they don't
Speaker 5:  need cords, which means they don't need any open
Speaker 5:  access to them. They don't have batteries in, it's not a battery charging,
Speaker 5:  it's not like g charging which powers the battery.
Speaker 5:  This is just direct power transfer. So the device
Speaker 5:  itself still kind of weighs the same, there's not a giant battery in there,
Speaker 5:  but it's completely sealed. So the gentleman I was talking to Iffa was like,
Speaker 5:  you know, manufacturers can design say your blender so that you could just
Speaker 5:  put the entire thing in the dishwasher because there's no open
Speaker 5:  ports. And that also could reduce things like wear and tear. 'cause quite
Speaker 5:  often it's the power supply that goes first on a, on a lot of these
Speaker 5:  devices and these gadgets in your kitchen. So, and it's, they also
Speaker 5:  said it's only 10% less efficient than wired power.
Speaker 5:  So it's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think the future of no wires anywhere in our house is kind of an
Speaker 5:  interesting one.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I agree. I also think I, I like, I I admire your optimism
Speaker 2:  and also I feel like I've been burned by wireless power at this point too
Speaker 2:  many times that I'll believe it when I see it. But I do think the,
Speaker 2:  the kitchen as a thing with like mostly stationary things
Speaker 2:  feels like a good use for that as opposed to like you can charge your
Speaker 2:  phone wirelessly and it's like, that's a lot harder than you think it is.
Speaker 2:  But I can just like, I can set this down and it will power, it feels more
Speaker 2:  doable. Yeah, I'm excited about that. It
Speaker 5:  Feels, it feels pretty smart.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's, that's very cool. I will say we should, we should switch gears,
Speaker 2:  but the fact that we now have key qi and we char
Speaker 2:  no this is bad everybody, you have done this wrong.
Speaker 2:  Let's, let's, let's all come together and figure out one rhyme
Speaker 2:  that we can do together for wireless power. Yes, I agree.
Speaker 2:  So you're, you're doing a big update to the the smart lock buying guide,
Speaker 2:  right? Give us a preview. What's your favorite one right now?
Speaker 5:  Still a big fan of Yale, the Yale Assure two
Speaker 5:  because it comes in so many different flavors, it kind of fits everyone's
Speaker 5:  needs. So Yale if, if you're not familiar, has these swappable
Speaker 5:  modules. So depend If you decide to change your smart home setup.
Speaker 5:  You know you've gone from Z-Wave to Apple Home or Google Home.
Speaker 5:  You can easily pop in a different module and be able to have
Speaker 5:  compatibility, which is nice. Although a lot of the locks I tested
Speaker 5:  do work sort of universally with different platforms.
Speaker 5:  But they also matter is sort of is slowly
Speaker 5:  coming into the smart lock space, which will help with compatibility.
Speaker 5:  Although I mean a lot of people who buy smart
Speaker 5:  locks, it's really just for that it's easier for me to get into my house.
Speaker 5:  I don't have to have my key. So you don't necessarily need to set it up with
Speaker 5:  your smart home platform. But that's again what I like about Yale is it gives
Speaker 5:  you multiple options. You've got fingerprint access,
Speaker 5:  you've got keypad access, you've got lock key
Speaker 5:  If, you really insist on using the key. And then also it
Speaker 5:  has the auto unlock feature. So if, which is again
Speaker 5:  this hands free concept, which I've never found work
Speaker 5:  that well for me, but that's also because I have poor cell service and poor
Speaker 5:  GPS in my neighborhood. Fair enough. And it relies on that. But it is nice
Speaker 5:  the concept of having your door automatically unlock as you walk up to it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so Yale has that feature which actually got from August,
Speaker 5:  which Yale is the sister company of August now. and we
Speaker 5:  haven't had a new lock from August for a while. So I think Yale is kind of
Speaker 5:  now the the main sort of smart lock space that
Speaker 5:  we're gonna see from what was Asa Aloy now owned by
Speaker 5:  Fortune.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  The whole smart lock space has got quite complicated. Yes. But Yale,
Speaker 5:  yeah, Yale has some really good stuff. They actually just released a new
Speaker 5:  retrofit locks which kind of replaces the original iconic
Speaker 5:  August retrofit lock, which has been my long been my number one pick for
Speaker 5:  your best retrofit lock. And just to clarify what retrofit means, there are
Speaker 5:  two types of smart locks. There's a full deadbolt replacement, which is what
Speaker 5:  most of the Yale Assure two locks are. So that replaces your entire
Speaker 5:  lock. So you're gonna have a different lock on the front and on the back
Speaker 5:  a retrofit lock just replaces the back so that you still
Speaker 5:  can use your regular key and Yale's come out with a new
Speaker 5:  retrofit lock called the Yale approach and you just replace the back portion
Speaker 5:  to add smarts to your lock. And that's really helpful for people who are
Speaker 5:  renting and can't swap out their lock. And also If, you have a nice
Speaker 5:  lock set and you don't want a kind of ugly looking smart lock
Speaker 5:  on the front of your door and fair. They've come out with a good solution.
Speaker 5:  And we're seeing this a lot now and I've tested a lot of these for the the
Speaker 5:  new update to the buying guide keypads that go with
Speaker 5:  retrofit locks so that you can still use a key
Speaker 5:  code or a fingerprint to unlock the lock
Speaker 5:  without, because that was always an issue with retrofit locks. You couldn't
Speaker 5:  actually control it from the outside other than using a key or an app.
Speaker 5:  And when you get to your front door, you don't wanna have to pull out your
Speaker 5:  phone to unlock your door
Speaker 2:  No. By then just pull out your key. It's actually simpler to have keys at
Speaker 2:  that point. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's easier to pull out your key, right? Yeah. So now, so the Yale approach
Speaker 5:  comes with a keypad that has a fingerprint reader and a keypad built
Speaker 5:  in. So you can use either of those options. And the nice thing about these
Speaker 5:  keypads is you don't have to put them like on your door or next to your door.
Speaker 5:  They have quite long range so you can kind of have it tucked away and still
Speaker 5:  have your front door look. Oh that's cool. Like a normal front door. So,
Speaker 5:  and I've seen, there's a couple other companies, a Cara has a new retrofit
Speaker 5:  lock that I've been trying and the Switch bot also has another one that all
Speaker 5:  come with these Bluetooth keypads, which I think is really kind of
Speaker 5:  a nice upgrade. And a lot of those also work with Apple
Speaker 5:  Home Key, which is new again in the retrofit space, being able to
Speaker 5:  use Home Key, which people that use it swear by, they say it's the absolute
Speaker 5:  favorite way of getting into a smart lock. 'cause you can put your home key
Speaker 5:  on your watch up to the lock. Right. Or you can use your phone,
Speaker 5:  obviously phone again, not necessarily easier than key, but
Speaker 5:  watch quite easy. So yeah, lots of great options in the lock
Speaker 5:  space right now we're seeing new smart locks come out
Speaker 5:  almost daily. It's kind of a bit overwhelming.
Speaker 2:  It really does seem like that. Well and I think part of me thinks it's, it's
Speaker 2:  because of the thing you just mentioned a minute ago is that these are not
Speaker 2:  devices that have to like have a grand vision of how do they fit into
Speaker 2:  an ecosystem and like tell you a big story about routines in your smart
Speaker 2:  life and like you can build that stuff if If you want. But this thing is
Speaker 2:  just like, it's, it makes it easier to get inside of your house, which is
Speaker 2:  just like the single most mainstream home use
Speaker 2:  case that anyone has. Everyone needs to get into their house. Yes. That is
Speaker 2:  a thing that happens when you have a house. Any kind and So I think that
Speaker 2:  stuff is, is very cool. 'cause it's like in a, in a sort of
Speaker 2:  increasingly messy idea of how everything works together. That's one thing
Speaker 2:  that just doesn't have to it it can, it can completely do its job
Speaker 2:  completely on its own. And I think as we get through this
Speaker 2:  messy matter phase, I can see why that would be very enticing to any company
Speaker 2:  that wants to build this stuff. But let's talk about Matter. You, you mentioned
Speaker 2:  where we are with some of the, the protocol stuff and I think
Speaker 2:  Google has made some big changes. Apple has made some big changes were it
Speaker 2:  feels like we've had some good momentum on the how you control
Speaker 2:  all of this stuff and how it all works together. But let's start with the
Speaker 2:  protocol stuff. There was a big threads update this summer
Speaker 5:  Thread. Don't put the S on the end. You're right. 'cause that just confuses
Speaker 5:  everyone. And everyone thinks I'm writing about Meta.
Speaker 2:  Just the one thread there, there was a big thread
Speaker 2:  with a D at the end update this summer. There's been
Speaker 2:  some ongoing matter news. Catch us up. Where are we in the, the protocol
Speaker 2:  world.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well okay, just before we jump into those protocols,
Speaker 5:  there is one protocol I should mention before we move on from Smart locks.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 2:  God, is it another wireless charging protocol? How much? Where's the wireless
Speaker 2:  power coming from this time?
Speaker 5:  No, no, no. This is a LiRo. So this is tied to matter, but this is the
Speaker 5:  new smart lock protocol.
Speaker 5:  David's just put his head down
Speaker 2:  Someday you're gonna come on the show and just make all of this stuff up
Speaker 2:  and I'm not gonna know and I'm gonna feel very stupid at the end.
Speaker 5:  But no, this ties into what we were just talking about and what we're about
Speaker 5:  to talk about. Okay. So a good segue, but Allero is the new
Speaker 5:  access control standard from the CSA, which is an organization behind
Speaker 5:  Matter, the Connectivity Standards Alliance. And this is why we're seeing
Speaker 5:  so much movement in the lock space because it's actually going to help
Speaker 5:  standardize the way we access Smart locks, not just in our homes,
Speaker 5:  but maybe even in like our businesses and apartments and
Speaker 5:  everywhere. So we're waiting for the standard to actually be
Speaker 5:  released. It's likely to involve UWB, which we've discussed
Speaker 5:  as well as an fc, which is the tap, which is what Home Key uses.
Speaker 5:  And we actually just saw our very first UWB
Speaker 5:  supporting Locke get released this last month, although, oh cool.
Speaker 5:  It won't work with a LiRo. So it's
Speaker 5:  like we're seeing a lot of cut before, so we're
Speaker 2:  Just doing this again. Yeah, we've
Speaker 5:  Seen a lot of cut before horses at the moment, but it, it's the excitement
Speaker 5:  in this space. And Apple is a huge
Speaker 5:  part of developing the Allero standard as are the big
Speaker 5:  smartphone companies. Because basically the idea here is that you'll be able
Speaker 5:  to use your phone or watch to unlock any door and no matter which
Speaker 5:  operating system you're using or which platform you're using, it's the universal
Speaker 5:  access. Just like matter is the universal standard for the smart home. This
Speaker 5:  is like a universal standard for the smart lock, which is kind of
Speaker 5:  connecting you into the smart home. So it's separate from but connected
Speaker 5:  to. So this is a space we should be watching quite closely. I
Speaker 5:  think we'll get a lot of movement around CES, especially since Apple announced
Speaker 5:  that it's supporting u WB unlocking in Apple Home. So
Speaker 5:  anyway, that was just to wrap up Smart Locks and now into Smart
Speaker 5:  Home.
Speaker 2:  No, it's good. The answer I I've always said is let's invent more protocols,
Speaker 2:  more pressure. That's that's what I, I'm glad that we're continuing on the
Speaker 2:  trend of more protocols.
Speaker 5:  I know, I know it, but what, it gives me something,
Speaker 5:  it gives me stuff to write about So.
Speaker 2:  I know it's true. If if everybody figures this out, we'll be out of jobs.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. So like it's, this is for the best. So, but yeah, the,
Speaker 2:  the talk to me about threat. Threat with a D and no s The. Thread. Just the
Speaker 2:  one one single thread.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so Thread is, as I've written about in the past,
Speaker 5:  is one of the two main wireless protocols of format.
Speaker 5:  So wifi and Thread Thread's been around for a decade or so prior to
Speaker 5:  matter, but it is, and it was originally developed Inside Nest
Speaker 5:  along with a few other companies and it is a low bandwidth, low
Speaker 5:  power protocol developed specifically for IOT devices, which
Speaker 5:  actually is a sort of a first, whilst we've got things like Z-Wave and ZigBee,
Speaker 5:  they weren't necessarily designed for the Smart Home and Thread is designed
Speaker 5:  specifically for the smart home. And so it was sort of re relaunched with
Speaker 5:  big fanfare when Matter launched a couple years ago. I was like, this is
Speaker 5:  gonna solve all our problems because
Speaker 5:  talking about battery life, this is something we've seen throughout the Smart
Speaker 5:  Home. Smart Home device is constantly running outta battery, needing to be
Speaker 5:  charged Thread is low power. So supposedly should, especially
Speaker 5:  things like smart door locks should not need to
Speaker 5:  be recharged or have their batteries replaced frequently if they use Thread.
Speaker 5:  But we've been having a lot of issues with threads since it kind of
Speaker 5:  launched into the, the broadest smart home space in the last year or
Speaker 5:  two. And just last, no, two weeks ago just around
Speaker 5:  EFA when I was at the tech show in Berlin and The Thread group
Speaker 5:  launched Thread 1.4, which is basically
Speaker 5:  their pania to all the problems that we've seen so far with
Speaker 5:  thread specifically around
Speaker 5:  interoperability, which is one of the main points of
Speaker 5:  matters that we're supposed to be solving here. The idea that anything
Speaker 5:  you buy for your smart home, your smart lock, your smart lights should all
Speaker 5:  work together no matter which phone you use or which platform you use. And
Speaker 5:  so Thread uses something called thread border routers to help
Speaker 5:  communicate from your thread device to the internet and to whichever platform
Speaker 5:  you want to use. And this wasn't necessarily
Speaker 5:  The Thread Group or The Thread protocols problem. I'm trying to
Speaker 5:  avoid saying Threads problem.
Speaker 5:  Sorry,
Speaker 2:  Thread apostrophe s Yes. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Because every border router is made by a different manufacturer. So
Speaker 5:  you have border routers from Apple, so like your Apple Home pod, your Apple
Speaker 5:  TV is a thread border router from a Amazon, your
Speaker 5:  Echo, your Echo show, 10 number of
Speaker 5:  devices from Amazon. The arrows are thread border routers. Same for
Speaker 5:  Google. But unfortunately these thread border routers didn't talk to each
Speaker 5:  other and this was causing all sorts of problems because your
Speaker 5:  devices, you'd think you'd connected your device to your smart home, but
Speaker 5:  it was on a different network from, say your smart lights might be on a different
Speaker 5:  network from your door lock. So it was, it was causing headaches and and
Speaker 5:  problems. And so this 1.4 should
Speaker 5:  they say fix that specific issue, but we have to wait,
Speaker 5:  this is the, this is the thing with these protocols, they come along promising
Speaker 5:  all these great solutions and then it's all down to the manufacturers and
Speaker 5:  the platforms to then implement them. So we're gonna have to wait for that
Speaker 5:  So I mean, I think with, you know, being optimistic, which
Speaker 5:  is definitely my preferred method Absolutely. Of approaching, we
Speaker 5:  should see some movement by around CESI think
Speaker 5:  we'll see a lot of products that are coming out with thread 1.4, but still
Speaker 5:  that's a long way away.
Speaker 2:  It is. But I will tell you here is the thing that gives me optimism is I
Speaker 2:  think the last time you and I talked, my worry was starting
Speaker 2:  to become that this was moving so slowly,
Speaker 2:  all that everyone was essentially just gonna give up on all things matter
Speaker 2:  and it would be kind of a, a thing that existed but nobody really cared about
Speaker 2:  and thus kind of languished. Yeah. And it actually doesn't seem like that's
Speaker 2:  the case. I I there, maybe I'm wrong, maybe I'm missing it, but it doesn't
Speaker 2:  seem like there has been sort of reverse momentum where everybody has just
Speaker 2:  decided to go back to doing their own things. It's just that it's moving
Speaker 2:  slower than we hoped, but it still seems to be actually moving in the right
Speaker 2:  direction, which gives me optimism about the fact that we will
Speaker 2:  get where we wanna be. It's just gonna take a lot longer than anybody hoped.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think, I think that's, that's spot on. But the problem has been
Speaker 5:  I think around expectation
Speaker 5:  and a lot of companies kind of jumped on the bandwagon with Thread and matter
Speaker 5:  and we were like, this is our solution. We're going to, you know, make
Speaker 5:  everything work with thread and matter and ship it to our customers and it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be a great experience. And specifically companies like Nano Leaf and
Speaker 5:  Eve who are quite well known in the smart home space, but not
Speaker 5:  broadly, very well known. And they were sort of seen this as their opportunity
Speaker 5:  to become more sort of household names because their products can
Speaker 5:  be so much easier to use and they've really been burned by these
Speaker 5:  things, these protocols not working in the way that it was predicted or
Speaker 5:  promised. And so we have seen a lot of companies kind of walk back
Speaker 5:  from these protocols at least Nana Leaf specifically created
Speaker 5:  its own protocol, another
Speaker 2:  One. Oh no, it did. Oh no,
Speaker 5:  Because it's like we can't rely on thread. It's not that we can't rely on
Speaker 5:  the protocol itself. It's a great protocol is what that CEO Jimmy
Speaker 5:  Chu told me. But it's the way it's implemented by the platforms. And
Speaker 5:  this all comes back down to this interoperability issue. And there's something
Speaker 5:  you and I have talked about a lot, the different manufacturers, the different
Speaker 5:  platforms playing nicely together. Apple playing nicely with Amazon, Google
Speaker 5:  playing nicely with Samsung, you know, we all worried that
Speaker 5:  that could be the issue eventually that they, you know, they all got together
Speaker 5:  to start with, but when, when they all gonna start going there separate ways
Speaker 5:  and causing issues and that's where The Thread water router issue came from.
Speaker 5:  But they've come back, they said they're gonna work on it, they should hopefully
Speaker 5:  be fixed. But yes, right now, If you went all in on
Speaker 5:  thread or If, you went all in on matter. It's not the sort of
Speaker 5:  panaya that we were hoping for, but we're getting there and people aren't
Speaker 5:  giving up. You are right. There is momentum. It's just not ready for the
Speaker 5:  the real world yet. It's not ready for the people that want a good door lock
Speaker 5:  and a good video doorbell.
Speaker 2:  And we are definitely past the point where a lot of these
Speaker 2:  companies promised us it would work by now and it doesn't. Right. But it
Speaker 2:  will. I still, I I still believe that someday it will. And speaking
Speaker 2:  of last thing we should talk about before I let you go is there's been some
Speaker 2:  big software changes on that front, right? Like you mentioned Home Key with
Speaker 2:  Apple. There's some stuff in iOS 18 that I think has been really
Speaker 2:  important to the smart home things. Google is doing a bunch of smart home
Speaker 2:  stuff right now with the, with its TV products. I have a TV
Speaker 2:  streamer right over there that you and I both really like. Yes. That feels
Speaker 2:  like it's moving in a really good direction, right? Like the, the stuff is
Speaker 2:  getting built into the devices it needs to get built into.
Speaker 5:  So yes, so the iOS 18 has an update that's specifically designed to
Speaker 5:  address this problem, this problem of, of thread and border routers
Speaker 5:  because people were buying a thread device bringing it home and it wasn't
Speaker 5:  working because they didn't have a border router. They didn't know they needed
Speaker 5:  a border router because
Speaker 2:  You shouldn't have to know that. You shouldn't, no one should have to know
Speaker 2:  about border routers.
Speaker 5:  Right. And so as you may recall, all
Speaker 5:  iPhone 15 pros and newer have
Speaker 5:  thread radios in. Right. And with iOS 18, apple
Speaker 5:  released an update that allows you to add matter devices
Speaker 5:  directly to your Apple Home app without requiring any hub,
Speaker 5:  either a home hub or an a thread border router. So wifi devices and
Speaker 5:  thread devices can connect using your phone directly. I
Speaker 5:  mean this isn't an a solution for the long term because If, you want a smart
Speaker 5:  home, you do need a hub for orchestration, but it does
Speaker 5:  solve the problem of I just bought this cool new smart light and I wanna
Speaker 5:  set it up and I don't wanna have to go buy a thread border router. And that's
Speaker 5:  also an answer to sort of why Apple decided to put thread chips
Speaker 5:  in their iPhones. They are also,
Speaker 2:  Which you kind of called you, you should take just a mini victory lab on
Speaker 2:  that one because you were, you were way out in front of that whole story.
Speaker 5:  Well it, it did make sense. It's, it's, it's confusing a bit though because
Speaker 5:  people are like, oh, well doesn't that make your phone a hub and a thread
Speaker 5:  border rack? It's like, well no it's not. But it's
Speaker 5:  like a temporary connection that you can use
Speaker 5:  If, you don't have anything else. It's like a fallback and then,
Speaker 5:  but If, you do want a thread border router that's getting easier.
Speaker 5:  There are more and more devices like you mentioned, there's the Google streamer
Speaker 5:  that just came out. This is Google's new answer to the Apple TV
Speaker 5:  and that is a smart home hub as well as a streamer.
Speaker 5:  It has thread border router and matter capabilities and
Speaker 5:  also great smart home controls, which I was my favorite thing about this
Speaker 5:  device. We said we both would tested out and reviewed it and we try
Speaker 5:  all the streamers in our house and most of my family just ends up using
Speaker 5:  the regular Samsung remote and going to the built-in os like no.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But they all love the streamer and they've all set up their own
Speaker 5:  profiles and it's like, it's been a huge success in my house. So there you
Speaker 5:  go. So, but it's great to see more devices like this that
Speaker 5:  kind of have a good use case in your home, but for, for every day. Like you
Speaker 5:  would go buy this because you want a good TV streamer, but it's also gonna
Speaker 5:  help If. you do want to use a smart home to give you a bit more
Speaker 5:  infrastructure built into your home so that when you come home with that
Speaker 5:  shiny new thread light bulb, it will work and you didn't have to worry about
Speaker 5:  it. But what what I'm most excited about right now
Speaker 5:  overall with the smart home is where we're going with generative AI
Speaker 5:  because, and this is something that Google talked about a lot
Speaker 5:  at its event at what was the last big event they had made by Google? Made
Speaker 2:  By Google I think is what they call it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Basically both Apple and Amazon we
Speaker 5:  know have kind of struggled in this space. Google says it's about to
Speaker 5:  release some really interesting updates. I'm interested to see who,
Speaker 5:  who gets their first. But where I see the most
Speaker 5:  interesting use case of generative AI in the smart home is making the smart
Speaker 5:  home easier. It's that natural language that we're being promised, being
Speaker 5:  able to just say, oh I'm, I'm a little cold and it's too dark.
Speaker 5:  And your smart home voice assistant knows that it should raise the
Speaker 5:  thermostat and turn the lights up for you. And Google has promised
Speaker 5:  with some new enhancements through
Speaker 5:  Gemini for Google Home and the Google Assistant that it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be bringing these kind of features to the smart home along with
Speaker 5:  interpretive notifications. Which is another thing I'm interested
Speaker 5:  in, like I mentioned at the beginning of this chat that my smart home,
Speaker 5:  when my smart home cameras send me notifications nonstop and
Speaker 5:  it's really annoying. So what's happening with Google Home is they're using
Speaker 5:  Gemini to sort of filter through your video
Speaker 5:  footage and only send you relevant notifications.
Speaker 5:  Like you can say, I only want to know if this person shows up at my front
Speaker 5:  door or this car shows up at my front door. Those kind of, you know,
Speaker 5:  specific notifications rather than just, oh, there was a breeze and plastic
Speaker 5:  bag flew past your
Speaker 2:  Right and then back the other way and then back the other way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wake you up at one o'clock in the morning. So
Speaker 5:  these kind of sort of quality of life make the smart home so much easier
Speaker 5:  to use. Less annoying and more
Speaker 5:  intuitive I think will really sort of push smart home
Speaker 5:  adoption because there are so many benefits. But like you said at the beginning,
Speaker 5:  just trying to unlock or figure out how to replace a battery. There are
Speaker 5:  too many parts of smart home and home automation that require
Speaker 5:  a lot of time and attention and reading and Googling and watching YouTube
Speaker 5:  videos and reading my articles, which is a good thing. But I
Speaker 5:  think we've, we're seeing both Google, Amazon and Apple and Samsung
Speaker 5:  all trying, you know, using generative AI to make
Speaker 5:  this experience a lot smoother and therefore hopefully
Speaker 5:  encourage more people to kind kind of reap the benefits of, of what
Speaker 5:  I think is is a great experience in your home when, when it all works.
Speaker 2:  I agree. I mean, and it seems like we're presumably only weeks
Speaker 2:  away from Amazon launching the, the generative
Speaker 2:  AI underpinnings of Alexa, which we've been hearing about for a long time
Speaker 2:  ago. We were at the event, was that a year ago at this point?
Speaker 2:  They were the first ones they a to promise this.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And So I. And is that the same kind of stuff that you think we're gonna see?
Speaker 2:  Like I think honestly if, if Google Assistant and Alexa both
Speaker 2:  get even kind of a pretty good version of what you just described, that
Speaker 2:  instantly upgrades like many, many millions of people's
Speaker 2:  smart home lives, which I think is very
Speaker 5:  Exciting. Very much so. Yeah. I mean Amazon promised, you know, they launched
Speaker 5:  all of this a year ago and it's taken a long time. It's not here yet.
Speaker 5:  So this is why I'm interested to see when Google's actually gonna implement
Speaker 5:  what they've promised. And Apple hasn't even mentioned the smart home,
Speaker 5:  you know, none of its Apple intelligence or Siri improvements are specifically
Speaker 5:  for the smart home. It is a difficult space you get,
Speaker 5:  you know, you get hallucinations in the smart home and it can go really,
Speaker 5:  really wrong. Yeah. And this is what, speaking to all of the companies
Speaker 5:  involved here, I hear a lot. It's like, it's complicated
Speaker 5:  and hard. So I think we're gonna see baby steps. We're
Speaker 5:  gonna see, I'm hoping we'll see something from Amazon here. I mean, it's
Speaker 5:  fall, we normally have a fall event, it's kind of later than
Speaker 5:  normal last year, I think it was this week. So, but we know
Speaker 5:  we've, there's been a lot of reporting on the struggles the company's had
Speaker 5:  to really nail this down. And every time I've spoken with an executive
Speaker 5:  at Amazon about the new Alexa, they said, well,
Speaker 5:  we are working on it. But it's very complicated.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, I think it's, it's a struggle. But when, but if and when we can
Speaker 5:  see these solutions, I, I really do think it's gonna be a game changer for
Speaker 5:  the smart home. It's gonna just make, it takes it from being something you
Speaker 5:  have to program and fiddle with to something that just
Speaker 5:  works if, if they get it right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's remains the biggest question. Yes. All right, well we're, we'll,
Speaker 2:  we'll have you back on after all this Amazon stuff happens, because I think
Speaker 2:  in a very real way with all of this stuff, the, the proof is in the pudding.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And by the pudding, I mean your house. So we, we'll come back
Speaker 2:  and we'll do this Jen. Thank you as always. Thank
Speaker 5:  You.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we are gonna come back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna do a mic test. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So if you've been listening to The Vergecast for a
Speaker 2:  long time, you know that a thing we like to do occasionally is test the
Speaker 2:  microphones on a bunch of different kinds of headphones. The last one
Speaker 2:  of these I think we did was the face gadgets, the meta
Speaker 2:  ray bands and the Vision Pro and that kind of stuff. And that I thought was
Speaker 2:  actually really interesting. The Ray Band Meta Smartt glasses might be the
Speaker 2:  best like body worn mic we've tested yet, which is
Speaker 2:  pretty cool. But this time I want to go through
Speaker 2:  all of the new headphones that have come out from kind of the major
Speaker 2:  headphone companies in the last few months. Because for people who just want
Speaker 2:  like a normal set of wireless earbuds, you're suddenly spoiled for choice,
Speaker 2:  right? There's the new Pixel Buds Pro two from Google. There's the AirPods
Speaker 2:  four from Apple Samsung has some new Galaxy Buds Pro,
Speaker 2:  nothing has the new ear open. Bose has some stuff.
Speaker 2:  There's just a lot of new options on the market. Chris Welch
Speaker 2:  has them all as he has want to do. And so we sent him to a coffee shop
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna talk a little bit about the audio quality and his feelings
Speaker 2:  about them overall. But mostly I want to test the microphones because my
Speaker 2:  running theory is that microphones really matter. I mentioned this a bit
Speaker 2:  in the intro, but right now so much of using your headphones is
Speaker 2:  using them to talk to people or to make videos or to talk to
Speaker 2:  Siri or to do this increasingly multimodal AI stuff that these
Speaker 2:  companies are talking about. Microphones matter and we don't talk about them
Speaker 2:  enough. And I think to some extent that lets these companies off the hook
Speaker 2:  from building better microphones. Like it's not impossible to be able a very
Speaker 2:  good microphone. It's just hard. And a lot of these companies care a lot
Speaker 2:  about noise cancellation. They care a lot about sound quality and I think
Speaker 2:  they should care more about Mike's. So we're gonna talk about Mike's and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna see who is doing the best job right now. Chris Welch is sitting
Speaker 2:  in a coffee shop, I assume with lots and lots of headphones
Speaker 2:  around, confusing everyone else in the coffee shop. So let's, let's do some
Speaker 2:  testing. Chris Welch. Hello.
Speaker 6:  Hello again.
Speaker 2:  Where are you right now? I feel like I'm, I'm growing to like learn the
Speaker 2:  different spots that you are when we test your buds. Where are we?
Speaker 6:  This is my Go-to coffee shop in my neighborhood that I come to
Speaker 6:  fairly often and work from. And yeah, it tends to be, you know,
Speaker 6:  pretty loud as most Brooklyn Coffee Shop are. But
Speaker 2:  Do they know you there by now? You're like the guy who shows up with a pile
Speaker 2:  of gadgets and takes a bunch of pictures. Like is that they just, they just
Speaker 2:  understand Absolutely. When you walk through the door. Yes. Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's good. I'm glad.
Speaker 2:  So we're here 'cause we're kind of at the end of this year's cycle of
Speaker 2:  new earbuds. You just published the, the Pixel Buds
Speaker 2:  Pro two review. You have a bunch of them, so we figured this is a good moment
Speaker 2:  to test them. Before we dive in, just give us the list. What are
Speaker 2:  we gonna, what are we gonna try here? What do we have?
Speaker 6:  We've got the Air Pods four, which I have right now in
Speaker 6:  my ears. That's what you're doing. Okay. To start, we've got the Samsung
Speaker 6:  Galaxy Buds three Pro, the Pixel Buds Pro two,
Speaker 6:  the new Bose Quiet comes with earbuds that just came out as well. And
Speaker 6:  the nothing opens very is funky open style
Speaker 6:  earbuds that were just announced as well. So
Speaker 2:  I'm very excited about those here. Yeah, I, I have developed an like
Speaker 2:  unnecessary attachment to an obsession with these open earbuds.
Speaker 2:  So I'm, I'm very excited to see if those are any good. And I'm glad you started
Speaker 2:  with AirPods. So this is actually good. This is a good first test because
Speaker 2:  I feel like AirPods are a useful control in a lot of
Speaker 2:  this because they're just like the one that everybody has. Yeah, they sound
Speaker 2:  fine. I described them to somebody the other day as like, the nice thing
Speaker 2:  about AirPods is that you can get them to sound like a c plus in almost
Speaker 2:  any situation. Yeah. The downside of the AirPods is you cannot get them to
Speaker 2:  sound better than a c plus in any situation. Like perfect
Speaker 2:  scenario, they're gonna sound just like this,
Speaker 6:  But that's, that's fine. I guess so, yeah. Yeah. So like, here's their
Speaker 6:  like normal mode, but on phone calls you can do like the voice isolation
Speaker 6:  feature, which usually like machine learning to make you sound even clearer.
Speaker 6:  We're not getting that unfortunately, but it does get a little bit better
Speaker 6:  on phone calls. Yeah. Because day to day
Speaker 2:  The voice isolation, you can only do, it's like phone calls and FaceTime,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Exactly. Not here, but you know, they sound fine, which is all you
Speaker 6:  really need. Like 90% of the time If, you just send, if they chat somebody,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they, they they do the job. Alright, well let's, let's, we've got enough
Speaker 2:  of this. Let's switch to the next one. Let's do, let's do Google next.
Speaker 6:  Google. That's the most
Speaker 2:  Go too. I think that's, that's a good, if I remember correctly, Google has
Speaker 2:  outperformed my expectations several times on these tests over the last
Speaker 2:  couple of years. So, I'm, I'm curious about this one. Let's just do it first.
Speaker 2:  We'll see. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Alright. I'll do it.
Speaker 2:  All right. Let's see it.
Speaker 2:  All right. Hit me.
Speaker 8:  We're back again. You said some buds Pro two,
Speaker 8:  they're smaller and lighter
Speaker 8:  and the mics have gotten mixed feedback so far.
Speaker 2:  I'm don't see, I'm gonna go decidedly lower than mixed on this one.
Speaker 8:  Really that much of a difference from the
Speaker 2:  AirPods even. Do you remember when we did a test on the ferry
Speaker 2:  in New York and it was just blindingly obvious how
Speaker 2:  hard some of them were working? Yeah. Like even, even though they were kind
Speaker 2:  of working and I could kind of hear you, you could, you could hear how hard
Speaker 2:  it was for them to get to that point. That's what I'm getting here too. It's
Speaker 2:  like the, one of the things interesting that just happened was between
Speaker 2:  recordings here, we just to let everybody in on how this works, we
Speaker 2:  use a app called Riverside and you have to stop and start recording every
Speaker 2:  time you wanna change devices. So we have to stop each time. So, I get to
Speaker 2:  hear like the natural audio coming out of your Mac. And there was
Speaker 2:  music playing that I didn't really hear on the AirPods. There was more noise
Speaker 2:  than I expected that I wasn't really hearing on the AirPods. I'm hearing
Speaker 2:  all of that now.
Speaker 8:  Interesting. There's like no cancellation whatsoever, huh?
Speaker 2:  Almost. I, I mean there's some and it's like it's coming and
Speaker 2:  going it's kind of like they're raising and lowering the volume as time goes
Speaker 2:  on. And
Speaker 2:  your voice sounds fine. It's like it's picking up more of everything.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So I'm actually like, your voice is a little richer than I was hearing
Speaker 2:  through the iPod or through the AirPods, but so is
Speaker 2:  the background noise
Speaker 8:  Not great? Yeah, but I guess that's a trade off. I'm getting smaller and
Speaker 8:  lighter. They're even further away from my mouth when I'm talking obviously.
Speaker 8:  So it's harder to kind of separate voice from
Speaker 8:  background noise. But these also have like clear calling on phone calls,
Speaker 8:  which again, you can't do on like video chats unfortunately. So like,
Speaker 8:  it should be a little bit better when you're actually talking to someone
Speaker 8:  on the phone. But if you're in a coffee shop, this is what you're trying
Speaker 8:  think you have,
Speaker 2:  You know, this makes me think of, do you ever, do you ever do the thing where
Speaker 2:  you're wearing noise canceling headphones, like over the ear noise canceling
Speaker 2:  headphones and you just kind of take 'em on and off your ears and, and you
Speaker 2:  can sort of hear it pulse the noise in and outside. It feels a little like
Speaker 2:  that as you're talking. It's like a, it, it, it's sort of constantly
Speaker 2:  picking up and letting go of the background noise in a way that is like,
Speaker 2:  it, it's, it works, but it's also like a little unnerving as I'm listening
Speaker 2:  to it. I think if I was just holding up my phone to my head, it wouldn't
Speaker 2:  really bother me. But I'm on like, pretty good headphones in a pretty good
Speaker 2:  situation here. And it is like I'm hearing stuff that I was not hearing the
Speaker 2:  AirPods. Yeah, it's really interesting. Okay, so yeah, this is,
Speaker 2:  we're we're gonna Google like a, like a gently passing grade.
Speaker 2:  I would say, this is not like a disaster. I can hear you,
Speaker 2:  but I can, I can safely already say Google is not going to win
Speaker 2:  this evaluation. They do look good though. They're, they do look very
Speaker 2:  nice. They're super small in your ears. That's, it's really nice. And they're,
Speaker 2:  they seem very comfortable from, from what I saw in your review. Very, very
Speaker 2:  comfortable. Very
Speaker 8:  Comfortable. I've still got that Mentos look, which you know, is what it
Speaker 8:  is. But yeah, you can barely see in your ears anymore, which
Speaker 2:  Is nice. Yeah, when you're head on, I can, I can basically not see them at
Speaker 2:  all. That's really cool. Alright, let's switch to the next one. Let's do,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, you pick surprise me. What are we doing?
Speaker 8:  Let's do Samsung. Get the big three out of the way. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I love it. All right, let's switch.
Speaker 2:  All right. Samsung buzz. How we doing?
Speaker 6:  These are the Buds three pro. They have stems now just like the AirPods
Speaker 6:  Pro do. So hopefully that makes them a little bit crisper. Clearer.
Speaker 6:  Oh my, that was loud. So
Speaker 2:  I didn't hear that at all. This is okay. This is the opposite of what we
Speaker 2:  just heard from Google. This is, this is actually super fun. I'm glad we
Speaker 2:  did this in this order because basically the AirPods are the
Speaker 2:  middle. Google is all the way at the end of the spectrum of like, let's make
Speaker 2:  this sound kind of as natural as possible, even if it means getting noise
Speaker 2:  in and you are just compressed to within an inch of your
Speaker 2:  life. But there is no background noise. Like it, it is interesting. It sounds
Speaker 2:  like you are in a silent room.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's super loud there. Someone's like suning dishes and stuff over
Speaker 6:  there. So If, you can't hear that. That's impressive. Do I sound like intelligible
Speaker 6:  though?
Speaker 2:  Intelligible? Yes. Okay. You almost don't sound like
Speaker 2:  yourself.
Speaker 2:  Like it, it sort of sounds like If you, If you like held up
Speaker 2:  a pillow to your mouth and then had a phone call. Like that's kind of what
Speaker 2:  you sound like right now. Okay. I can hear everything you're saying. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  but I mean, it is it, you are processed to death,
Speaker 2:  but again, I, I cannot overstate the extent to which I'm not hearing anything
Speaker 2:  but your voice right now. That's kind of wild actually. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Huh. That's fun. Yeah, and these have been pretty good so far from
Speaker 6:  my voice calls and talking to people I've heard like similar feedback to
Speaker 6:  that, that I sound processed but clear. So,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And this is, this is a, this is a fun test case because
Speaker 2:  normally with these headphones, at least my experience has been that they
Speaker 2:  process your voice less when they're having to process less background noise.
Speaker 2:  So in theory, when you're in like a perfectly quiet space Right,
Speaker 2:  they should all sound better,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But they'll sound worse in, so we tried to pick, this is a
Speaker 2:  pretty good, like normal-ish use case to like test them, but not
Speaker 2:  overly so. But yeah, this is, this is solid. I
Speaker 2:  take this over Google. Okay. 10 times outta 10. Like, it's just more
Speaker 2:  pleasant to listen to you, even though you don't sound amazing, just because
Speaker 2:  there's not that kind of roller coaster volume of
Speaker 2:  background noise.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. And there's a lot of noise in So If you can't hear any of that.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's nice. But yeah, these are these, they're great. They sound
Speaker 6:  really nice. They have lights on the stems so you can have 'em
Speaker 6:  light up when you're talking to people. You know,
Speaker 2:  These are the ones that Samsung just went full AirPods, right? Yes. Like
Speaker 2:  they just, they just did AirPods. Absolute. But like the Samsung way. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Silver. I
Speaker 2:  Don't even mean that as an insult. Like it just is what it is. That's just
Speaker 2:  what Samsung does. Yeah. Yeah. In terms of like
Speaker 2:  pleasant to listen to and wear all day, which has been your favorite of the
Speaker 2:  bunch. If you're gonna just like do your life wearing headphones, do you
Speaker 2:  have a favorite?
Speaker 6:  I'd probably say a tie between these
Speaker 6:  and the pixel boats. Honestly, those are newer. So I'm So I just kinda used
Speaker 6:  to those. These I've used a ton and yeah, they feel like AirPods Pro
Speaker 6:  and you know, they're stable, they fit well, they sound really nice. They
Speaker 6:  do all the Samsung ecosystem tricks, so, you know,
Speaker 6:  they're not super original, but at this point
Speaker 6:  they're all the same. So yeah. But yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah, I'm
Speaker 6:  Good to hear that. You can hear me very clearly. That's
Speaker 2:  I'm impressed. Yeah, like you sound very clear, but you don't sound very
Speaker 2:  good. And if I have to make that trade, I'll make that trade, you know what
Speaker 2:  I mean? Like, I'd love to have it both ways, but I will, I will pick this
Speaker 2:  over the alternative. Fair. All right, let's, let's switch, let's do,
Speaker 2:  let's do pose next. You tell
Speaker 6:  Mes next? Yeah, let's do it. All right,
Speaker 2:  Let's switch.
Speaker 2:  All right. Bose time. How we doing?
Speaker 6:  Just
Speaker 8:  Have a brand new quiet comfort
Speaker 6:  Here for those second generation. You're already laughing. That's not a good
Speaker 2:  Time. Was I just very loud in your ears? Just then you like startled as I
Speaker 2:  said something. Oh, okay. No, that was good.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Just making sure,
Speaker 8:  Make sure I can hear you too. Just came out this past wheat
Speaker 8:  and they have really good, super good noise cancellation. Multiple from
Speaker 8:  those through smaller than faster, but cheaper.
Speaker 8:  1 7 9. Same as the AirPod four. You have tips obviously,
Speaker 8:  whereas the AirPod four do not,
Speaker 8:  but so far I like to apply the best.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Sound.
Speaker 2:  I don't, I don't wanna be hyperbolic here. This is awful.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 2:  So bad. This is the first time I can't
Speaker 2:  understand some of the words that you're saying. And, and again,
Speaker 2:  I wonder if an experience, I've had So I have a pair of Bs like over
Speaker 2:  ear quiet comforts and the, the impression that I get every
Speaker 2:  time I use them is kind of what I was saying before, that the mic is, it's
Speaker 2:  never good, but it's fine when there's not a lot of
Speaker 2:  noise. But Bose seems to so aggressively prioritize
Speaker 2:  noise cancellation over audio quality that when you get
Speaker 2:  into bad sound, it will just destroy everything else in the name of noise
Speaker 2:  cancellation. So I'm guessing you're sitting there and it's like not very
Speaker 2:  loud to you and it all sounds
Speaker 6:  Not so much
Speaker 2:  It's, it's just ruining it pretty high. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's doing a decent job of suppressing the background noise. It's actually
Speaker 2:  like, it's better now than it was when we started, which is interesting.
Speaker 2:  It's like, it, it's, it took the processing a minute to like figure it out,
Speaker 2:  but it seems to have cut a bunch of the background noise. Okay. But you sound
Speaker 2:  like trash
Speaker 6:  Sounds absolute trash. It's really these important
Speaker 6:  meetings. That's good to know.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This is, this is not the one to take a zoom call in a coffee shop with
Speaker 2:  that is like, basically the, the two reasons we do this test are like,
Speaker 2:  are you the worst? If you're on a video call with these and, you know,
Speaker 2:  grand theories about how we talk to AI and all that stuff, like, I really
Speaker 2:  do believe microphones matter. This one will fail at both of those tests.
Speaker 2:  And I feel very confident about that.
Speaker 6:  Yikes. Big yikes. Okay. Well they're good at everything else
Speaker 6:  so far.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, these are good listening headphones. Like Bose Bose makes very good
Speaker 2:  headphones to listen to. Please don't call me from these
Speaker 6:  Ever again. Okay.
Speaker 2:  All right. Let's, let's get off this one as quickly as we can. Yeah. Let's,
Speaker 2:  let's go to the next one. What gonna do next?
Speaker 6:  Let's do the nothings the funky open ones. Sweet.
Speaker 2:  Love it.
Speaker 6:  Do that
Speaker 8:  Right now.
Speaker 2:  All right. Nothing. The, nothing ear open. That's what they're called,
Speaker 2:  right? How we do it.
Speaker 6:  It's, yeah. These are the first call I actually had on these period.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 2:  It's an honor.
Speaker 6:  It's one experience for us both.
Speaker 2:  I kind of like how those look in your ears. I have to say it's a little,
Speaker 2:  it's they're, they're a little more like deliberately space agey
Speaker 2:  than anything else you've tried. They've got the, the sort of ear hook
Speaker 2:  and slight Yeah. They just, they just look like you're wearing some kind
Speaker 2:  of futuristic star trekky headset. Okay. Which is not the worst
Speaker 2:  thing in the world.
Speaker 6:  Some people love this for like bike riding and that kind of, those kind of
Speaker 6:  activities. I'm not an open earbud guy, but I can see the appeal. Like I,
Speaker 6:  I can hear everything in this room right now. That's just kind of absurd.
Speaker 6:  So like, you sound pretty quiet compared to like all this right racket from
Speaker 6:  the moon, but how does the voice quality compare to Pretty
Speaker 2:  Solid? Actually, I would put this kind of right in the
Speaker 2:  AirPods range. I'm getting a little bit of the background noise. Like I can
Speaker 2:  tell you're in a coffee shop, unlike the Samsungs
Speaker 2:  where it was like truly just deathly quiet. I can,
Speaker 2:  it's clear you're somewhere, but I'm only catching kind of
Speaker 2:  bits and pieces of the background noise. Like I can tell there's a, there's
Speaker 2:  a woman talking somewhere near you. Yeah, but I'm only catching like,
Speaker 2:  snippets, like syllables of it instead of like the whole conversation.
Speaker 2:  And I can hear you pretty clearly actually this, I'm, I'm, I'm sort of impressed
Speaker 2:  by these.
Speaker 6:  See, I'm not sure where the mics are in this particular, like, there's like
Speaker 6:  a stem that runs down here, so who knows? But they're pretty funky. They're
Speaker 6:  fun, they're interesting. But it's good to know If, you're gonna make
Speaker 6:  phone calls on your bike or wherever you might be, or in these
Speaker 6:  people will be able to understand you. I'm getting so many looks at this
Speaker 6:  coffee shop, doing this call being that guy who I see
Speaker 6:  every day.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We'll, we'll, we'll only keep you a couple more minutes, I promise.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But I think the part of the reason I'm, I'm interested in these is
Speaker 2:  like, you, you, I hear from people all the time who are like, yeah, I'm trying
Speaker 2:  to do more phone calls while I'm walking. Right? It's just the like,
Speaker 2:  like I work from home now. I sit in my basement all day and I'm trying to
Speaker 2:  do more of that too. Just get out and it's like, oh, we're gonna talk for
Speaker 2:  a half hour. I'm gonna just wander around the neighborhood for a half hour.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And that's one reason that a open ear is useful. Like,
Speaker 2:  I think for this particular case in a coffee shop, open ear headphones are
Speaker 2:  actually the wrong answer. So like, for this purpose, you probably wouldn't
Speaker 2:  use these. Yeah. Even though they sound okay, but for like
Speaker 2:  general sort of day-to-Day life, like it's the same reason I like the, the
Speaker 2:  RayBan meta smart glasses, right? Like I can just sort of have a conversation
Speaker 2:  into my sunglasses in a way that sort of works. And I feel like
Speaker 2:  this is appealing to me for the same reason. And they sound pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Cool. It's not, it's not the best one, but it is, it's kind of right in that
Speaker 2:  sweet spot middle with the, the AirPods that I, I'm, I'm sort of impressed
Speaker 2:  with.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Okay. Good to know. Should I switch back to the AirPods for
Speaker 6:  the conclusion or? Yeah, let's,
Speaker 2:  Let's switch back. Now that I've heard all of them, let's go back to the
Speaker 2:  AirPods and we can, we can, we can pick a favorite here.
Speaker 6:  Alright, let's do it. All right.
Speaker 2:  All right. So we're back on the AirPods four.
Speaker 6:  We are, and these still sounds pretty serviceable.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This, it's such a boring answer, but I think of this
Speaker 2:  round, this is actually probably my favorite. I think
Speaker 2:  the, there's a little more background noise here than there was on
Speaker 2:  the nothings, but it's also a little less, I'm
Speaker 2:  realizing like a, a little bit of consistent background noise
Speaker 2:  is actually less annoying than, than
Speaker 2:  background noise. Yeah. It's like this, you just kind of have that low
Speaker 2:  tone behind you all the time. And so it's actually easier for me to pick
Speaker 2:  out your voice, whereas like the pixel buds which kept coming in and out
Speaker 2:  were like giving me a headache trying to figure out what was going on.
Speaker 2:  But I'm curious. Eric Gomez our producer. Hi, Eric is here.
Speaker 2:  Hello. You have been listening to and making all of this work. What do you
Speaker 2:  make of all of this? You're the, you're the audio expert here.
Speaker 9:  Definitely impressed by the Samsung,
Speaker 9:  but the quality is, yes, it's being squished
Speaker 9:  and compressed to death, but at least you're not picking up anything
Speaker 9:  going on in the background at all. And it's pretty, you know,
Speaker 9:  it's, it's clear enough and it's coherent enough to be able to have a good
Speaker 9:  conversation. And I'm really surprised by the pixel buts.
Speaker 9:  They're just not,
Speaker 2:  Just not impressive. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I'm really disappointed in that. You know,
Speaker 9:  I, I think Google did a good job in terms of hardware this, this round, but
Speaker 9:  I'm just a little disappointed by the quality of the mic on that, on, on
Speaker 9:  these pixel buts, So,
Speaker 2:  I do wonder, I mean, Welch, you mentioned that they're smaller
Speaker 2:  and thus just further away from your mouth. And I wonder at some point if
Speaker 2:  that just be, is like an insurmountable physics problem? Like the, the things
Speaker 2:  with stems tend to be better because they have stems. Like it just is
Speaker 2:  a, seems to be a fact.
Speaker 6:  I think So I mean, I don't wanna see everybody do stems. So that would be
Speaker 6:  boring. So I, hope they can find a way to like, you know, like use machine
Speaker 6:  learning or AI or whatnot to like find some way to fix this problems.
Speaker 6:  Maybe the pixel bullets will sound better on like phone calls with clear
Speaker 6:  call line. Like so far I haven't gotten so many complaints there, so that
Speaker 6:  might, that might make a difference versus just like, just overall audio
Speaker 6:  mode. But yeah, it's clearly that all
Speaker 6:  that Samsung and Apple are kind of the head honchos here and
Speaker 6:  the rest are kind of okay at best.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. The wi the winner for most improved is Samsung for sure. I think
Speaker 2:  the, the last time we did this, I think Samsung came in last and it was,
Speaker 2:  it was the one that was like borderline unintelligible.
Speaker 2:  And, and I think Samsung here is either in first or second place
Speaker 2:  depending on just kind of what you like, like the, the thing for
Speaker 2:  me of that sort of eerie quiet, super compressed just doesn't
Speaker 2:  sound as good as what I'm hearing now from the AirPods, which just feels
Speaker 2:  a little more natural. It's like if I were sitting across from you at a coffee
Speaker 2:  shop, that's what it would sound like. Okay. But I can also understand that
Speaker 2:  if what's clear is also, if there is one that you are gonna trust in awful
Speaker 2:  situations to keep you intelligible, it's probably the Galaxy Buds, right?
Speaker 2:  Eric? Is that, is that your takeaway here?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I I I would have to agree with
Speaker 2:  That. They're like the worst case scenario buds.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Don't, don't use 'em. Good
Speaker 6:  To know for the future, whenever I'm stranded somewhere and I carry around
Speaker 6:  like several pairs of beer buds at all times, so it's nice to know that those
Speaker 6:  are the ones.
Speaker 9:  Don't don't call 9 1 1 with those buds. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They'll be like, this is fine. You can't hear anything. Yeah. All right,
Speaker 2:  good. Well we, we've, we've done it. I just, I would love for somebody
Speaker 2:  to just like blow my mind here. That's, that's everyone's charge for next
Speaker 2:  time. It's just like, do slightly better. We're still at a point where the,
Speaker 2:  the RayBan Meadow ones are the like, best sounding ones we've tested
Speaker 6:  Maybe
Speaker 2:  In the history of this segment on The Vergecast. Still
Speaker 6:  Haven't ever tried those myself, but I want one of those nuclear colors.
Speaker 2:  They look
Speaker 6:  Awesome. Awesome. Glasses look awesome.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I have two pairs now and I don't want one of them. So you
Speaker 2:  can have one of
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  You can hit me up personally on threads or on signal. We try to answer at
Speaker 2:  least one hotline question on the show every week. And actually I think we're
Speaker 2:  due for like a full hotline episode. We've gotten a lot of fun stuff. We're
Speaker 2:  in deep gadget season right now, so we've gotten a lot of gadget questions.
Speaker 2:  We will probably get to all of those at some point in the very near future,
Speaker 2:  but for now we have a question that feels so, so very birge Casty.
Speaker 2:  Let's hear it.
Speaker 10:  Hey Birge, this is Jeff from North Carolina. I was
Speaker 10:  listening to your latest episode on Meta's New Glasses and
Speaker 10:  I'm wondering, I remember, I believe it was Sky Galloway made a
Speaker 10:  comment that any product that you're wearing on your body that makes you
Speaker 10:  less attractive will never succeed. I'm wondering If,
Speaker 10:  you think with the Vision Pro and then now the Meta Smart Glasses,
Speaker 10:  this will apply that If, you don't look cool in them. No one's gonna
Speaker 10:  buy them. Love the show. Thanks very much. Bye.
Speaker 2:  All right. There is only one person on earth who can answer this question.
Speaker 2:  The Scott Galloway of The Vergecast. I call him sometimes brutal,
Speaker 11:  Brutal
Speaker 2:  Ne left tell. Why would
Speaker 11:  She invite me here to insult me to my face?
Speaker 2:  Hey buddy,
Speaker 11:  This is my own show.
Speaker 2:  I didn't even prepare you for this. You didn't even get to listen to this
Speaker 2:  ahead of time. This was just, I, this is everything I wanted to. Hey, would
Speaker 2:  you
Speaker 11:  Like to walk into your own house? Me slapped in the face.
Speaker 11:  Amazing.
Speaker 2:  So I. Love this question for two reasons. One, because I think it's a good
Speaker 2:  question and two, because it, it threatens the very core of
Speaker 2:  Neli Patel's theory of wearable bullshit, which is just this, this
Speaker 2:  just says, actually it doesn't even matter if it doesn't make you look cool.
Speaker 2:  It's out So I want, I want to know your thoughts on, on this particular take
Speaker 2:  with these devices.
Speaker 11:  Well, you'll recall that the, the matrix of wearable bullshit has a
Speaker 11:  minus 100 face penalty. Right? Which
Speaker 11:  is basically what we're talking about here because you can put all
Speaker 11:  kinds of stuff on your body that makes you look uncool. People wear
Speaker 11:  fanny packs all day long. Fair first walking around. They're not even wearing
Speaker 11:  'em on their Fannie from what I'm told.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they're slings now. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  It's, it's watches. Incredibly subjective fashion choices, true
Speaker 11:  clothing itself, shoes, the, the way people talk about shoes in this
Speaker 11:  world.
Speaker 11:  All, all kinds of ideas about things you put on your body. It's really just,
Speaker 11:  do you have it on your face that sets people a flame,
Speaker 11:  right? That's the thing we're talking about here. Is it on your face? Is
Speaker 11:  it in your way? And the, the matrix of wearable
Speaker 11:  bullshit is fids versus utility. And then
Speaker 11:  there's just like this like big penalty for face somewhere in there
Speaker 11:  that brings you way below the line. And then you have to offer vastly more
Speaker 11:  utility to get back above the line so that people wear it every day. Regular
Speaker 11:  glasses
Speaker 11:  on your face, they take the penalty, but they're pretty useful to most people.
Speaker 11:  True. So they, they come back up and now we've, you know, over decades
Speaker 11:  we've turned glasses into fashion accessories. Well, okay, so that's
Speaker 11:  made this choice
Speaker 2:  That, that's the thing that I keep thinking about, thinking about this. 'cause
Speaker 2:  there, there's basically two ways to look at this. One is these things
Speaker 2:  will never be cool and the only way they're ever going to work
Speaker 2:  is if we make them so phenomenally useful that it doesn't matter.
Speaker 2:  Right. And I feel like, I don't know, like wired headphones is probably a
Speaker 2:  good example of that, right? Like, I don't know that a, a pair of ear
Speaker 2:  EarPods is like cool, but they're like simple and they're useful and we all
Speaker 2:  just kind of gut over it, right? That that crossed the threshold with
Speaker 2:  utility, not with cool. The other option is that in some way
Speaker 2:  someone figures out how to make these things actually objectively
Speaker 2:  cool and then, and then it flips, right? Like in glasses,
Speaker 2:  some people like how they look in glasses better than how they look without
Speaker 2:  glasses. Like that's a real thing. We have made them a fashion object and
Speaker 2:  that seems like a much harder road for any kind of technology,
Speaker 2:  but is maybe the actually most effective way to get there. It's just make
Speaker 2:  them objectively cool. Figure out how to make it like iconically awesome
Speaker 2:  to have ski goggles on your face and then none of the rest of it even
Speaker 2:  matters. But,
Speaker 11:  But this is, I think what Apple tried with the Vision Pro. They tried to
Speaker 11:  make it cool and it fell on its face. 'cause it just, we can't be,
Speaker 11:  it
Speaker 2:  Just isn't.
Speaker 11:  Well ski go, there are some ski goggles. Like cool. I I've certainly seen
Speaker 11:  like sweet pictures of eighties people wearing ski
Speaker 11:  goggles. True. They look cool as hell. Have you ever seen the movie ski
Speaker 11:  school highly recommended? Anyway, my my point
Speaker 11:  is one, you should watch ski school. Two, even
Speaker 11:  the people who think they look better in glasses that don't, don't
Speaker 11:  have not created enough of a market for like clear glasses. Like there's
Speaker 11:  a little bit of interesting for clear glasses. Yeah, right? Like on prescription
Speaker 11:  or non-prescription clear glasses that you just wear as a fashion accessory
Speaker 11:  like a little bit, but it's as a signifier as part of
Speaker 11:  another outfit, right? It's supposed to be part of another vibe that you're
Speaker 11:  sending out, right? Not just, I wear these every day, all
Speaker 11:  day. Like my shoes Right?
Speaker 2:  As pure fashion statement, right? There's not much to, and
Speaker 11:  So when you just, I think for a tech product you need to vastly increase
Speaker 11:  the utility of the thing. Like AirPods, they're so useful and I care
Speaker 11:  about them so much and they provide me so much value every single day as
Speaker 11:  a product that I will overcome the fact that
Speaker 11:  they're in my ears all the time and people can see them 'cause they're white
Speaker 11:  and like regular over the ear headphones or fashion
Speaker 11:  statements in different ways, right? They look different. There's different
Speaker 11:  ways you can style 'em. There's different ways you can wear them that, remember
Speaker 11:  when Beats came out, the beats were not the best sounding headphones. Like
Speaker 11:  Jimmy Ivy and Dr. Dre had one idea for what headphones should sound like
Speaker 11:  and it was super base heavy. Right? And they were a fashion
Speaker 11:  statement at first 'cause it came in all the colors. Like they were the
Speaker 11:  first headphones to like really push that idea. And they were a phenomenon
Speaker 11:  in their time just for that. I think with smart glasses
Speaker 11:  yep. You gotta make the form factor smaller. Yep. They've gotta be,
Speaker 11:  yep. They've gotta look more like regular glasses. You've gotta solve the
Speaker 11:  battery, you've gotta bring the fids way down and the value way up.
Speaker 11:  They gotta be able to do more things and then somewhere in
Speaker 11:  there you might overcome the penalty of it being on your face. But I
Speaker 11:  still think that the core tenant holds, which is if it's really, really
Speaker 11:  useful, people get over the fids and part of FIDS is
Speaker 11:  like, is this shit on my face?
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 11:  And whether or not that you want to interpret that in the Galloway fashion
Speaker 11:  of does this make me more attractive That it's, it is up to you
Speaker 11:  to decide if that is the type of utility you desire from a a product
Speaker 2:  Fair. And I guess to be fair, like
Speaker 11:  Post Malone is out here being like, you know what? Face tattoos. That sounds
Speaker 11:  right.
Speaker 2:  Listen, some things are attractive to some people. Every
Speaker 2:  no accounting for taste. No one is attracted to Division Pro. I think is
Speaker 2:  is basically the only true statement I can make at this. Yeah. Particular
Speaker 2:  moment in time.
Speaker 2:  I, okay, so the, the a hundred point deductible is on a scale
Speaker 2:  that deduction, it's, it's an Apple. It's not like a,
Speaker 11:  It's not like a tax return,
Speaker 2:  Right? I apologize. The hundred point deduction is, is like,
Speaker 2:  it's, it's apple chart crime, it's out of nothing. But what I wonder
Speaker 2:  is, is have we, have we not hit it enough? Like
Speaker 2:  should it be a 200 point deduction? Like I am starting to think that this
Speaker 2:  thing might be harder to surmount even than I had thought.
Speaker 2:  'cause even like I look at the Orion glasses, which are smaller and much
Speaker 2:  closer to being normal glasses and then somebody puts 'em on their face and
Speaker 2:  they still look kind of stupid. Like they're cool 'cause they're cool technology,
Speaker 2:  whatever, but like in no way are they like cool looking glasses.
Speaker 2:  And that is like the bleeding edge of the bleeding edge of where we are in
Speaker 2:  terms of being able to make these things awesome. Like should we be,
Speaker 2:  should we be dinging these things harder for their face wearing
Speaker 2:  issues for the foreseeable future?
Speaker 11:  Well, I would say one of the most fiddly things about the Orion is that
Speaker 11:  you need to work at Facebook and apparently have $10,000 in order to have
Speaker 11:  one. Yeah. Ums pretty fiddly. It's very fiddly. Like whether or not it's
Speaker 11:  in your face, like doesn't matter. Like it, it's, it's a product you can't
Speaker 11:  buy. You need to grow crystal lenses in the basement of your underground
Speaker 11:  Hawaiian layer apparently to have them very fiddly. Like you're just in
Speaker 11:  the hole and then you're a little bit further in the hole. I think a better
Speaker 11:  example is the RayBan glasses that Meadow is doing where their
Speaker 11:  utility is not that high. Right? Like they
Speaker 11:  can take some photos, they can do some AI stuff. People actually like the
Speaker 11:  photos. People like listening to music on them, but they're not very
Speaker 11:  fiddly.
Speaker 2:  That is
Speaker 11:  True. They're just, they're just ray bands that have to, they're
Speaker 2:  Mostly glasses. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  And so even they can overcome the face penalty
Speaker 11:  because their fids is so low. Right. And then, and then
Speaker 11:  you get whatever utility you get out of it and they, they kind of just curve
Speaker 11:  right back up to glasses maybe a little bit under regular glasses
Speaker 11:  because they have a little more fids to them. But
Speaker 11:  they, they're, I think they're just on the same curve as regular glasses,
Speaker 11:  which also take the a hundred point face fids de deduction. Right.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna be so interested to see how the clear ones end up doing in the
Speaker 2:  real world that like limited edition one that they came out with because
Speaker 2:  my like threads algorithm is filled with people who are obsessed with
Speaker 2:  it. My threads algorithm is also filled with like nerds. And so, and
Speaker 11:  That's also owned I would point out by meta.
Speaker 2:  It is also one by meta. That's a very good point. So I think the, the question
Speaker 2:  of like, I, I have a pair here that are essentially
Speaker 2:  indistinguishable from normal Wayfairs. Like you would never look at me twice
Speaker 2:  wearing them. They just look like Wayfairs. That is a huge victory. I think
Speaker 2:  the, the clear ones look a little more like gadgets and So I think
Speaker 2:  how those sort of percolate out into the world is gonna be really
Speaker 2:  interesting because there is this like all the way at the other end of that
Speaker 2:  spectrum is Google glass, which is like the gadgets gadget of all time.
Speaker 11:  And it also offered almost no utility. Right? I just, everyone forgets this
Speaker 11:  about Google Glass. You had a little display in your face that was not very
Speaker 11:  useful at all.
Speaker 2:  No, it like told you you had a text message. Yeah. And I'm like, my phone
Speaker 2:  buzzes when that happens this far.
Speaker 11:  You were just in the hole. It was like, and it would be like turn left.
Speaker 11:  It's like when you were doing Google apps. Yeah. And it's just, none of
Speaker 11:  this is useful at all. So I, the, the, the real thing
Speaker 11:  that I think that the Raybans have accomplished is they've
Speaker 11:  gotten closer to the curve is of regular glasses.
Speaker 11:  What's really interesting is the clear ones you're talking about have the
Speaker 11:  next generation of transitions lenses in them, gen S they're called,
Speaker 11:  which are supposed to go from sunglasses to clear much faster than
Speaker 11:  before. And the idea is that that will make you wanna wear them all the
Speaker 11:  time.
Speaker 11:  I don't know, you know like, are people gonna buy these way
Speaker 11:  things that look like Wayfairs and then just like wear 'em around their
Speaker 11:  office because they're getting so much value out of wearing the meta
Speaker 11:  ray bands. And I think the answer is no. I think you're still on the same
Speaker 11:  curve as just regular sunglasses. So we'll see. I think that's the most
Speaker 11:  successful of these products because they've gotten to the
Speaker 11:  same sort of value equation as a regular set of sunglasses.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think that's right. And that's, that's a good example of, I don't
Speaker 2:  know that like your sunglasses generally make you look like cooler
Speaker 2:  and more attractive, but they are like useful and they look good.
Speaker 11:  I think historically in, in the history of culture, people have thought
Speaker 11:  sunglasses make them look cool and attractive.
Speaker 2:  No, they just like make you mysterious 'cause nobody can see what you're
Speaker 2:  looking at and that Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Sexy and dangerous.
Speaker 2:  How do you feel about your sunglasses?
Speaker 11:  I'm just saying I think this is how most people feel about sunglasses.
Speaker 2:  That's no, that's fair. So maybe, maybe we're onto something here that there's
Speaker 2:  maybe the new, the the, the whatever seventh
Speaker 2:  dimension of the, the theory of wearable bullshit.
Speaker 11:  I think I'm down to just two. It's two in the face deduction,
Speaker 2:  But there's also like a sexiness quotient.
Speaker 11:  No, I disagree. Two all too subjective. It's fids versus
Speaker 11:  utility and then face.
Speaker 2:  So do we put sexiness under utility? Is one of the utility like
Speaker 2:  a possible utility? Just it makes me look hot as a hell per
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Perceived utility. It's all, it's all in there. Which is why face
Speaker 11:  is such a wait is face, a fiddly face is utility
Speaker 11:  deduction.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I think that's right.
Speaker 11:  That
Speaker 2:  Seems, no, it's a fiddly deduction face is very fiddly.
Speaker 11:  I'm never gonna get this right.
Speaker 11:  It just depends on which axis is which. Whichever one brings you down
Speaker 11:  below that curve like hard and then you've gotta like, you've gotta
Speaker 11:  pay it off with utility. So it is a, it is a utility deduction.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 11:  Right. You put it on your face, you suddenly need to deliver vastly more
Speaker 11:  utility to get back above the curve. Right.
Speaker 2:  And one of those utilities can be sexy looking
Speaker 11:  Hot. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right. There we go. We've solved it. And as always If, you
Speaker 2:  listeners can figure out how to graph this for us. Please,
Speaker 2:  dear God, we'll let you sponsor the lightning round for free.
Speaker 11:  You
Speaker 2:  Can figure out how to
Speaker 11:  Do this. We've mentioned it before. So there's regular glasses. This is
Speaker 11:  the, the first thing to put on your chart is regular glasses, which
Speaker 11:  are quite fiddly, especially If. you need them to see
Speaker 11:  the fact that If you lose them you can no longer see is really quite fiddly.
Speaker 11:  Yes. Agreed. Like you gotta keep them clean. You can't lose 'em, you don't
Speaker 11:  want to scratch 'em. You gotta, you gotta wear 'em all the time. Very fiddly
Speaker 11:  utility off the chart. You're, you're, you're way above the curve
Speaker 11:  of success on this, on this whatever quadrant chart we're doing.
Speaker 11:  AirPods also in the chart. Good, good thing to graph right? People like
Speaker 11:  'em, but they make you look like you have AirPods in your ears. Apple watch
Speaker 11:  first gen versus the current gen, first gen. Ooh, that's a good one. So
Speaker 11:  fiddly. Yep. Not a lot of utility. So fiddly below
Speaker 11:  the curve and they, they, they evened it out to where they are now. So
Speaker 11:  like that's the chart, right? You just gotta, if you're gonna put something
Speaker 11:  on your body, it's gotta be so useful. It's worth the time and attention.
Speaker 11:  And then you've got face, face deduction,
Speaker 2:  Face deductions, the, the title of Neli,
Speaker 11:  The face penalty.
Speaker 2:  All right, we did it Neli. Thank you as always.
Speaker 11:  I'm still mad about the Scott Galloway thing. I wanna be very clear with
Speaker 11:  this.
Speaker 2:  All right, that is it for the Vergecast. Thank you to everybody who was on
Speaker 2:  the show today, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more
Speaker 2:  on everything. We talked about all of Jen's coverage of matter and thread
Speaker 2:  and the video doorbells. She actually wrote about a smart door just yesterday.
Speaker 2:  Great stuff. All that is on the website. All of Chris's reviews of
Speaker 2:  these various headphones are on the website. I think the, the
Speaker 2:  wearable theory is mostly a vergecast thing. So, you know,
Speaker 2:  keep it locked here for all of the updates on
Speaker 2:  Eli's insane wearables theory that basically doesn't make any sense. And
Speaker 2:  If you have thoughts, questions or feelings or anything else you wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about. Other headphones you want us to try other ways to put terrible audio
Speaker 2:  on The Vergecast. You can always email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com
Speaker 2:  or call the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one one. we love hearing from you.
Speaker 2:  Please keep all our questions coming. This show is produced by Liam James
Speaker 2:  Will pour and Eric Gomez