# Transcript
ID: a337eab7-b40c-4457-96f3-95a39fac1f8f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2084151803544604244/6180894079391549771/s93290-US-4530s-1706086155.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of really old computers:
03:54 - Walt Mossberg, former Verge executive editor and longtime Wall Street Journal tech columnist, joins the show to discuss forty years of the Macintosh computer.
Mossberg - The Verge
The Mac turns 40 — and keeps on moving
Steve Jobs Introduces the Macintosh
Looking back on 40 years of Macintosh
40:28 - Ali Abdaal chats about his new book "Feel Good Productivity: How to Do More of What Matters To You" and why overthinking your productivity system might not be such a good idea.
Ali Abdaal - YouTube
Feel Good Productivity
1:06:53 - David Pierce answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about laptops.
The best laptops you can get
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 3:  To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of really, really old computers.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am currently sitting in my car
Speaker 3:  out front of my house. I've developed this morning routine over the last
Speaker 3:  few weeks when it's been like bitterly cold and snowy and icy on
Speaker 3:  the east coast of the US where I live. Where instead of coming out and
Speaker 3:  being a proactive person who, you know, scrapes off my windshield and
Speaker 3:  dusts off all the snow and gets everything ready and just gets going for
Speaker 3:  the day, I instead come out, turn on the car, put all the
Speaker 3:  heat up to full blast, and then just sit here for like 15 minutes
Speaker 3:  until everything you know, melts and goes away on its own.
Speaker 3:  And then I'm safe to drive while I'm waiting. I listen to podcasts,
Speaker 3:  I drink coffee, I catch up on email. I like to convince myself
Speaker 3:  that this is like a meditative thing I do to really get ready for the day
Speaker 3:  and not just a thing that I do because I'm too lazy and too
Speaker 3:  annoying about my hands being cold, to actually just get outta the car and
Speaker 3:  get it ready. Listen, it's not a great strategy, but it's working for
Speaker 3:  me and hopefully it's not gonna be this cold much longer, so I'm going with
Speaker 3:  it. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you. today we're gonna
Speaker 3:  talk about the 40th anniversary of the original Macintosh,
Speaker 3:  which launched this week in 1984. We're gonna talk to Walt Mossberg,
Speaker 3:  who has all the stories you could possibly imagine about that computer and
Speaker 3:  what happened in the interim 40 years. Then we're gonna talk to Ali Abdaal,
Speaker 3:  who is an influencer and creator and YouTuber that you might have heard of
Speaker 3:  about a book he wrote about what it means to be a productive person
Speaker 3:  in the world. We're right at the time of the year where everybody bails on
Speaker 3:  their New Year's resolutions, and I thought it would be a fun time to talk
Speaker 3:  about how to do better and whether specifically all of the
Speaker 3:  digital tools we have can help us do better. All of that is coming up in
Speaker 3:  just a second, but first I think the snow is finally going.
Speaker 3:  So I have to run to the store and then we're gonna get to it. This is the
Speaker 3:  Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back, I'm defrosted cars defrosted. Let's do some Verge
Speaker 3:  casting. But real quick before we get started, we're working on an upcoming
Speaker 3:  segment about Boss Ware, which is the software that employers use to
Speaker 3:  monitor and evaluate their employees. That software is getting more powerful
Speaker 3:  and more invasive all the time. You have software suites that are logging
Speaker 3:  keystrokes and taking screenshots. They're calculating active and
Speaker 3:  inactive time and they can even spy on you with your devices
Speaker 3:  webcam. We're looking for people with firsthand experience with ware,
Speaker 3:  so if that's you get in touch. We wanna know how you're being tracked and
Speaker 3:  how it affects your day-to-Day work life. Also, we wanna know all of the
Speaker 3:  ways you've found to creatively, let's say work around
Speaker 3:  ware. We want to hear all your tips and tricks. You can email Vergecast at
Speaker 3:  The Verge dot com or call the Hotline eight six six Verge one one.
Speaker 3:  We'll keep you anonymous if you want, but we want to hear all of your stories.
Speaker 3:  Alright, today, first up, 40 years ago this week, in fact 40 years
Speaker 3:  ago today, if you're listening to this, on Wednesday, January 24th,
Speaker 3:  apple launched the original Macintosh. It was a big deal in
Speaker 3:  part because Apple launched it alongside one of the most epic ads of all
Speaker 3:  time. Do you remember the one with the woman hurling the hammer at the big
Speaker 3:  screen shattering it, and then you have the message about Big Brother. In
Speaker 3:  1984,
Speaker 7:  On January 24th, apple computer will introduce
Speaker 7:  Macintosh and you'll see why 1984
Speaker 7:  won't be like 1984.
Speaker 3:  Apple hyped this thing up in a big way, and as it turns out,
Speaker 3:  deservedly so. Here's Steve Jobs introducing the Macintosh at a meeting of
Speaker 3:  the Boston Computer Society.
Speaker 8:  What we need now is the third industry milestone product,
Speaker 8:  and that's what Macintosh is all about. We've been working on this thing
Speaker 8:  for over two years now, and those of us that have been really close to it,
Speaker 8:  we'll all tell you it is insanely great and you'll have a
Speaker 8:  chance to see a little bit more of it later on tonight.
Speaker 3:  You can find that whole launch on YouTube. By the way, I'll put the link
Speaker 3:  in the show notes. It's great, super fun to watch 40 years later and
Speaker 3:  40 years later, I think it's safe to say Jobs was mostly right,
Speaker 3:  the Macintosh was a game changer, and its legacy is actually
Speaker 3:  everywhere in the computers that we use now. So we figured on this
Speaker 3:  anniversary, we'd go back in history a bit and talk about what the
Speaker 3:  Macintosh meant 40 years ago and what it means now and
Speaker 3:  who better to do it with than Walt Mossberg, former Verge executive editor,
Speaker 3:  longtime Wall Street, Journal tech columnist, and probably the person
Speaker 3:  with the most impressive gadget collection you'll ever see anywhere.
Speaker 3:  Walt, Mossberg, Welcome, back to The. Vergecast. Always
Speaker 5:  Love to be here, David.
Speaker 3:  We're happy to have you. So our occasion this time is the 40th anniversary
Speaker 3:  of the Macintosh, and one of the reasons I'm very excited to talk to you
Speaker 3:  about it is obviously you've sort of seen this thing through its whole history,
Speaker 3:  but also the Macintosh came out, if I'm doing my math correctly,
Speaker 3:  six or seven years before you became a tech columnist.
Speaker 9:  That's right.
Speaker 3:  You were a computer hobbyist at the time, so it's not like you were not aware
Speaker 3:  of the Macintosh in 1984. Right. What was your experience of that launch
Speaker 3:  then?
Speaker 9:  Well, I was, I was a crazed computer hobbyist,
Speaker 9:  and it was really all, all I did outside of work. You know, at
Speaker 9:  the time I was covering Washington for the Wall Street Journal, Washington
Speaker 9:  Bureau. So my first encounter with the Mac was as a
Speaker 9:  customer, but it was little confusing. I mean, I bought a Mac,
Speaker 9:  not the first one, either the second or the third one, and I can't
Speaker 9:  remember, I loved it like any bleeding
Speaker 9:  edge person, I thought it was genius, partly because
Speaker 9:  it shipped with capabilities that on an Apple
Speaker 9:  two or a Wintel pc you had to buy cards
Speaker 9:  and put them in to get these things and the Mac had not every
Speaker 9:  one of them. Like, I don't think it had a modem, but it, it
Speaker 9:  had sound. That was really good sound. It had
Speaker 9:  a bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 3:  The thing about the Mac, I was, I was going back and trying to think, okay,
Speaker 3:  like we sort of understand the legacy of it now as
Speaker 3:  it was the first computer that, you know, to use an Apple
Speaker 3:  is just worked, right? It was the first thing you could sort of sit down
Speaker 3:  and intuitively use, which computers had just not been before.
Speaker 9:  Well, that's
Speaker 3:  Right. But I'm particularly curious for your perspective in 1984,
Speaker 3:  did it feel like that? Because part of me thinks about a lot of what we do
Speaker 3:  with new technology is unlearn old bad habits and it actually
Speaker 3:  feels bad. Like this thing we're doing with Google search right now, right?
Speaker 3:  Where we all learned how to sort of type the keywords to get what we wanted
Speaker 3:  and now it's like, oh, we have these better tools, just ask a question like
Speaker 3:  a person. And that actually feels strange, even that it's an objectively
Speaker 3:  better behavior. But I wonder coming from something like an Apple two E,
Speaker 3:  which you would learn how to use and get very good at, and it's like learning
Speaker 3:  an instrument coming to a Macintosh, even if it is sort of better,
Speaker 3:  there's gotta be a weird phase of like, what do you mean I click
Speaker 3:  on this icon to open the thing?
Speaker 9:  The weird phase for me maybe lasted 48 hours.
Speaker 9:  Okay. It was very easy to make the transition and the reason
Speaker 9:  was, although I was very proficient in Apple
Speaker 9:  Doss or whatever the, I think pro doss, whatever they
Speaker 9:  called it, it was Doss, it was like Doss from Microsoft or
Speaker 9:  using Lotus 1, 2, 3. I mean, you had to learn a ton of commands
Speaker 9:  and syntax and if you got, if you mistyped one letter,
Speaker 9:  you were screwed. I
Speaker 3:  Mean, you were writing code in a, in a very real way on it. You
Speaker 9:  Were. And you know, I became proficient at that, but
Speaker 9:  even before I started my column, which was in
Speaker 9:  1991, and which was all dedicated to
Speaker 9:  the proposition that computers were too hard to use and everything had to
Speaker 9:  get easier even before that, that's how I felt. In fact, that
Speaker 9:  bled into my decision to try to convince, successfully
Speaker 9:  convince the Wall Street Journal, let me do a computer column. Well,
Speaker 3:  And even in that first column, if I remember correctly, you mentioned the
Speaker 3:  Macintosh as an example of kind of how to do this better.
Speaker 9:  I don't remember that, but it's possible. I will tell you that in one of
Speaker 9:  my many, many meetings with Bill Gates, he said to
Speaker 9:  me, this is some years later, he said to me,
Speaker 9:  Mossberg, why don't you just headline every one of your columns by a Mac?
Speaker 9:  I swear to God and with Steve Jobs, whatever I
Speaker 9:  said about the Mac, even if it was, you know, a rave review in my
Speaker 9:  eyes, it was never good enough for him. Sure. Because I would point out some
Speaker 9:  downside of it or whatever, even if I said, this is the one to buy, but
Speaker 9:  please be aware of these five downsides, he would call me
Speaker 9:  up and complain that I'd put any downsides in. So those were
Speaker 9:  the two polls I had, which
Speaker 3:  I figured if you've got them both mad at you, you're probably doing something
Speaker 3:  right.
Speaker 9:  Probably doing something right. Yeah. So as a hobbyist and a customer,
Speaker 9:  I thought the Mac was vastly superior. I also owned a, a
Speaker 9:  Doss machine at the time. I had all these computers that I couldn't afford,
Speaker 9:  but I just fell in love with the graphical user interface and, and the Mac.
Speaker 9:  So it's fair to say that Apple helped invent the personal
Speaker 9:  computer. It was one of three companies that in 1977
Speaker 9:  brought out a sort of mass market personal computer
Speaker 9:  where you didn't have to be an engineer to use it, although really you
Speaker 9:  had to be a techie and you know, radio Shack and,
Speaker 9:  and Commodore with the others. But the Apple two sort of, once it got
Speaker 9:  was VisiCalc, it became the thing that people wanted
Speaker 9:  more than the others. So they helped invent the personal computer and
Speaker 9:  then they, with the Mac, they completely changed seven years later.
Speaker 9:  The way the personal computer is used to this day, I
Speaker 9:  don't know of another computer that's 40 years old.
Speaker 9:  I mean, it's semantics, right? There's been a million different Macs, right?
Speaker 9:  So you could say the iMac that I'm talking to you on is a
Speaker 9:  standalone computer by itself and shouldn't be counted in the 40 year
Speaker 9:  run, but it's all just iterations of the Mac and
Speaker 9:  40 years is sort of incredible.
Speaker 3:  I do think it's true that you can draw an unusually straight line
Speaker 3:  from that first Mac to the current crop of Macs. Even just
Speaker 3:  what the thing looks like. I always enjoy going back and looking at you.
Speaker 3:  You look at early versions of like Microsoft Word and Excel and some of these
Speaker 3:  things that have really endured over time and in a
Speaker 3:  surprising number of cases, it's amazing how little changes, right? And I
Speaker 3:  think part of that is like there's, there's one way to look at that, that
Speaker 3:  is like maybe a failure of imagination to keep trying and you get a thing
Speaker 3:  that works and then it's, it's hard to fight success. But also a lot of these
Speaker 3:  things just got a lot of things right the first time. And I think the Mac
Speaker 3:  was one of those things. It the basic sort of tenets of the
Speaker 3:  GUI just were there and I think they were right. And, and everyone has
Speaker 3:  tried. We've seen some people try and sort of reinvent that wheel over and
Speaker 3:  over over time. And for the most part, nothing has been better than that.
Speaker 9:  Well, I think that's right and just to, not to sound like an Apple fanboy,
Speaker 9:  but I mean I think the iPhone was the same way. It obviously
Speaker 9:  didn't have the same interface as the Mac, but the iPhone touch
Speaker 9:  interface and the, you know, the scrolling and the different things
Speaker 9:  they had are all on Android and, and you know,
Speaker 9:  they've borrowed back some things from Android, but largely
Speaker 9:  what Apple sat down for the iPhone is the way
Speaker 9:  all phones work. And what Apple sat down for the Mac is the way all
Speaker 9:  computer, all computers, PCs work. but it wasn't that
Speaker 9:  it didn't have flaws, it cost way too much.
Speaker 3:  Right. I was just gonna ask what columnist Walt would've said about it in
Speaker 3:  1984, and I'm guessing price would've been where you started.
Speaker 9:  I would've said that they got this revolutionary UI or ux
Speaker 9:  correct. but it was out of range for most people
Speaker 9:  and it was outrageous. And I will tell you that when
Speaker 9:  many years later, 2007, we had
Speaker 9:  famously, as you know, Cher and I had Gates and
Speaker 9:  Jobs on stage together in a joint interview. And
Speaker 9:  part of that interview was telling the story of the Mac. one of the things
Speaker 9:  that Gate said in that joint interview, he and Jobs were going back and
Speaker 9:  forth. Karen and I were going back and forth with them. Gate said,
Speaker 9:  you came to me and you said this is gonna be a a, a cheap
Speaker 9:  customer priced machine, blah blah. It's gonna do this and that.
Speaker 9:  And when you delivered the machine, I was very excited 'cause the machine
Speaker 9:  really looked good and I really wanted our apps to
Speaker 9:  work on it. But every time we had a meeting, the price went up
Speaker 9:  and the price went up and the price went up. And you know,
Speaker 9:  it's not like Microsoft sold its big
Speaker 9:  apps at a or or Windows itself at a bargain
Speaker 9:  basement price. Sure. But they couldn't compete with Apple on
Speaker 9:  overcharging. I mean, as we are making this
Speaker 9:  podcast, the Apple Vision Pro is coming out at
Speaker 9:  $3,500. Yeah. And we all know that's gonna come
Speaker 9:  down in price and, you know, maybe lose some features
Speaker 9:  or whatever and it's gonna not sell very many at
Speaker 9:  $3,500. But that's what they did and that's what they did with the
Speaker 9:  Mac. I think it was partly, 'cause Steve Jobs was a
Speaker 9:  perfectionist. His idea of what was a customer friendly price
Speaker 9:  wasn't really a customer friendly price.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I, I agree. They, there have definitely been more on the, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  make a good thing and you'll pay for it. Which has turned out to work pretty
Speaker 3:  well for them over time, I would say. Why do you think the Mac name has
Speaker 3:  stuck around this long? I, I was just looking back over it. It's, you know,
Speaker 3:  you, we've had several CEOs. Steve Jobs left, Steve Jobs came back,
Speaker 3:  the devices themselves have changed. There have been a million new things.
Speaker 3:  And it's like the only constant at Apple for 40 years is that something
Speaker 3:  is called the Mac.
Speaker 9:  Yes. Originally they used the full name Macintosh.
Speaker 9:  Right. And don don't know how many years that lasted, but
Speaker 9:  everybody just called it a Mac anyway, everybody who
Speaker 9:  bought it or referred to it or wrote about it, called it a Mac.
Speaker 3:  Even back then, like, you'd be hanging out with your hobbyist friends and
Speaker 3:  you'd be like, oh look, I have a Mac. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Okay. Nobody said, I mean, you know, maybe for the first six months people
Speaker 9:  said Macintosh and then everybody started calling it a Mac. And so then
Speaker 9:  Apple called it a Mac. And I don't know when the first
Speaker 9:  of, well probably during jobs as exile, when there was
Speaker 9:  a parade of horribly incompetent CEOs
Speaker 9:  and product managers and no real
Speaker 9:  leaps of improvement in the Mac, they might've
Speaker 9:  started calling it the Mac. Then they certainly started calling it the Mac
Speaker 9:  with the iMac, which came out in 1998. And that was jobs in his
Speaker 9:  second coming. But when jobs came back to Apple,
Speaker 9:  he started calling my house and maybe some other journalists, I'm not
Speaker 9:  gonna say it was only me. And we'd have these hour and a half conversations
Speaker 9:  and we talk a lot about the Mac and he and about Apple
Speaker 9:  as a company and so forth. But when I went, I, I never forget, I went
Speaker 9:  to meet with him around that time around not long after he took over.
Speaker 9:  And he said that he was horrified when he got there to find
Speaker 9:  out how many Mac models there were. This shouldn't have happened. There were
Speaker 9:  like Quadras and Performas and I can't
Speaker 9:  remember the other names, but I think most of 'em amended with an A for some
Speaker 9:  reason there were there, there were just different Mac names and it was very
Speaker 9:  hard for consumers to figure out the difference between them. And
Speaker 9:  they have different, they had different sales teams, they had different PR
Speaker 9:  campaigns. It was just ridiculous. They all
Speaker 9:  still were too expensive. They all still were better
Speaker 9:  than Wintel computers, I thought. But they were getting
Speaker 9:  worse because it's getting more complicated and all, all this stuff.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That was when Apple was started to license the idea out to other companies,
Speaker 3:  right? They were gonna let other companies make Macintoshes. That
Speaker 9:  Was the other thing. He was furious. He was fucking furious
Speaker 9:  about it. He said to me, I can't believe they licensed
Speaker 9:  the oss. And then he went to a whole discourse
Speaker 9:  about how you have to make a choice. You can be a company that
Speaker 9:  licenses, like we now know Google licenses Android, or you could be
Speaker 9:  a company that does vertical integration and sells the whole thing.
Speaker 9:  And or as he liked to say, the whole banana, that was his phrase. But
Speaker 9:  you can't do both really successfully. So he canceled
Speaker 9:  all those licenses and then he did for me, what I think he did
Speaker 9:  for many people was he turned to the whiteboard in the room
Speaker 9:  we were in, which I think was his conference room. And he drew
Speaker 9:  a four squares with a marker and he, and one
Speaker 9:  was called consumer and one was called pro. And in
Speaker 9:  the upper left hand box he wrote consumer desktop.
Speaker 9:  And underneath that he wrote consumer laptop. In the upper right hand box
Speaker 9:  he wrote pro desktop and pro
Speaker 9:  laptop. He said, that's all I want, that's all I'm gonna make.
Speaker 9:  Which was true for quite a while. Now I think
Speaker 9:  less
Speaker 3:  True now.
Speaker 9:  Less true. Now, can I tell you just another random anecdote about the
Speaker 3:  Mac? Please go.
Speaker 9:  Okay. So he comes in, he saves the company, he saves the
Speaker 9:  Mac. I mean the iMac was genuinely another revolutionary
Speaker 9:  step. Yeah. Revolutionary because it had every
Speaker 9:  capability you wanted in it.
Speaker 3:  Part of what I think is so interesting about that is that there are kind
Speaker 3:  of those two distinct eras of the Mac, right? And I
Speaker 3:  think, I think the iMac launch is a perfect sort of middle moment
Speaker 3:  of the story. Because without it, like not only would Apple maybe have
Speaker 3:  died, the Mac would've maybe gone away too. But then that was like
Speaker 3:  Steve Jobs coming back in and, and sort of reaching back to 1984 and being
Speaker 3:  like, no, this is, I am going to redraw the line back to that thing
Speaker 3:  from this new device that we're making. Which is kind of a, just from a
Speaker 3:  like business leader perspective, sort of remarkable in
Speaker 3:  retrospect. And then from there it just, it has continued on in that
Speaker 3:  same way for a really long time.
Speaker 9:  Well, I would call the first iMac the funny rounded one
Speaker 9:  that you could, it was either translucent or in one case
Speaker 9:  transparent, had all these colors. I
Speaker 3:  Love that thing. You're
Speaker 9:  Right. That you could think of it as the middle, but I would call it the
Speaker 9:  second true second generation of the Mac. Okay. I mean the Mac
Speaker 9:  had a number of smaller generations. Like I mentioned at one point
Speaker 9:  they put a hard disc in it and then they branched it out
Speaker 9:  into all these crazy models. But the iMac was really,
Speaker 9:  here's what the Mac is now given the internet given
Speaker 9:  1998, whatever, you know? Yeah. And you know,
Speaker 9:  they did rip mix burn, they did all billboards that said that
Speaker 9:  they did all those things. But then they did the, after the iMac, they did
Speaker 9:  the I book, which was also very colorful, but
Speaker 9:  it was shaped as many people noted, like a toilet seat.
Speaker 9:  It was David,
Speaker 3:  I was, you're not wrong, it was
Speaker 9:  My wife got one and just loved it. She did not
Speaker 9:  get Doss or Windows. She had a Windows machine.
Speaker 9:  She struggled with it. She refused to buy a, a
Speaker 9:  laptop because she didn't wanna struggle with that. And then I convinced
Speaker 9:  her to buy this iBook and she didn't want to give it up. Even when it
Speaker 9:  was long past its sell by date. I mean, you know,
Speaker 9:  she just didn't wanna give it up.
Speaker 3:  So I'm hearing you say that I'm struck by how experimental
Speaker 3:  all of that stuff was. There was such a long time where Apple just tried
Speaker 3:  so many things and some of them were great and some of them were super weird.
Speaker 3:  And I mean, especially in the iMac line, like good God, they tried every
Speaker 3:  imaginable shape of computer you could make there for a while it felt like,
Speaker 9:  Hey, the cube was beautiful. It was beautiful.
Speaker 3:  It was, it was Everybody fell for the cube. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Until it cracked. And until you figured out that you
Speaker 9:  were getting an underpowered computer for a grossly high price.
Speaker 9:  But
Speaker 3:  Hey, it was beautiful. I'll, I'll give you that. but it seems like now
Speaker 3:  there's just much less of that. And on the one hand, I, I actually think
Speaker 3:  Max in general, they're obviously better than ever, but I think even
Speaker 3:  comparatively better than ever, like we're at a point now where the MacBook
Speaker 3:  is so dramatically better than anything you can buy for Windows right now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I'm gonna get a bunch of angry emails for saying that, but I think
Speaker 3:  it's true. And yet it feels like we've spent the last decade or so
Speaker 3:  on this phase of just sort of gentle refinement of a bunch of ideas, right?
Speaker 3:  And even the new stuff like a Mac Studio is just a slightly different sized
Speaker 3:  box for a thing that already existed. Are we just done with the experimenting
Speaker 3:  phase? Like is the next 40 years of Mac, 40 years of gentle
Speaker 3:  refinement?
Speaker 9:  Well, couple of things about that.
Speaker 3:  This is a lead into a question about the Vision Pro by the way. So we're
Speaker 3:  gonna get there too.
Speaker 9:  One is Apple is no longer led by a product guy,
Speaker 9:  no longer led by a product guy. There's a lot of good things about Tim Cook.
Speaker 9:  I personally like Tim Cook. I've met with him not
Speaker 9:  as much as I met with jobs over the years, but I have had some
Speaker 9:  one-on-ones with him. He's a smart guy and he's obviously
Speaker 9:  on the financial side. I mean the company has never done better.
Speaker 9:  Steve in maybe 40 hours of meetings with Steve
Speaker 9:  Jobs. He never mentioned the stock. He never, and by the way,
Speaker 9:  he boycotted all the analysts quarterly phone calls he never
Speaker 9:  appeared on. Oh,
Speaker 3:  Interesting. Okay.
Speaker 9:  With one exception, they had a scandal one year.
Speaker 9:  He considered it a fake scandal, but it was called Antennagate.
Speaker 3:  I was about to guess that's what it was.
Speaker 9:  This was on the iPhone, not the Mac, but they put the antenna on the outside
Speaker 9:  and if you grabbed it in a certain way, you attenuated the signal,
Speaker 3:  The you're holding it wrong. Scandal. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  And so he made rubber bumpers and you could get one for free and all that.
Speaker 9:  And for that quarter he appeared on the analyst call, but otherwise
Speaker 9:  he didn't. So Tim is kind of interested in
Speaker 9:  that and operations, which was his job. He
Speaker 9:  was handpicked by Steve as his successor, but he wasn't
Speaker 9:  a product guy. And this leads me to tell you a story when you talk about
Speaker 9:  the Mac sort of stagnating, even after Steve
Speaker 9:  came back and got rid of all the extra models and the licensing and all that,
Speaker 9:  their biggest seller, and in my opinion, I've written this many times,
Speaker 9:  I'll be happy to say it right here. So I can share the hate mail with you.
Speaker 9:  The MacBook Air was the best laptop ever made,
Speaker 9:  at least starting with the 2010 redesign. The one
Speaker 9:  that he introduced by pulling it out of an envelope. The original one
Speaker 9:  was fabulously thin. Nobody could believe a computer be that thin,
Speaker 9:  but it was, it had some performance issues.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Another one in that vein of spectacular idea,
Speaker 3:  overpriced and kind of underpowered.
Speaker 9:  But it did well enough that they invested and in 2010 they
Speaker 9:  made the one we're all familiar with until very recently with the
Speaker 9:  tapered edge. So I wrote four or five times
Speaker 9:  over 20 years. I wrote, this is the best laptop
Speaker 9:  ever built. And the fact is, it was their best selling product.
Speaker 9:  There were some years where it was the best selling PC individual
Speaker 9:  model of pc. Obviously they never outsold win the Windows
Speaker 9:  PCs. Sure. But individual model of PC was the best seller.
Speaker 9:  And for 20 years, the Windows guys tried to chase it and then
Speaker 9:  they got crazy. Right. They started trying once
Speaker 9:  it would fold and become a tablet and it was always like an inch and a half
Speaker 9:  thick and all this crazy stuff. I once on
Speaker 9:  stage at the very first D conference was, was in
Speaker 9:  2003. So two years after the iPod came
Speaker 9:  out, it was just an interview I had with, I don't even think Kara was there,
Speaker 9:  it was just me and Jobs. And I said, you know, you've done
Speaker 9:  all this stuff. You've invented the I the iMac
Speaker 9:  and you're still at five or
Speaker 9:  7% or whatever it was of the market. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  I said, how are you ever gonna move the needle on that? He said,
Speaker 9:  well, we're moving the needle little bit by little bit. But he said, we're
Speaker 9:  never gonna outsell windows in computers. But he said, I
Speaker 9:  love the iPod. And I said, why? He said, because I'm really tired of
Speaker 9:  being 5% of the market.
Speaker 9:  And the iPod was like 85% of the market, or
Speaker 9:  75 whatever at the time. So he, that revealed to me
Speaker 9:  that it really bothered him that his baby,
Speaker 9:  his invention, the m, he could blame all
Speaker 9:  the bo, what he called the bozos who were there when he was off
Speaker 9:  doing another failed company next. He could blame all of
Speaker 9:  them. That was a 12 year gap. But nevertheless, the M
Speaker 9:  Mac just just never, never made it.
Speaker 3:  And yeah, and in some ways it's, it's now more successful than it
Speaker 3:  ever has been.
Speaker 9:  Oh, it ab absolutely is. It's very successful.
Speaker 3:  There's seemingly real runway on this idea left I
Speaker 3:  think is kind of wild and is really the most remarkable thing about the Maxima
Speaker 3:  is that it doesn't feel like an old idea even that at this point in tech.
Speaker 3:  It's a really old idea. Well
Speaker 9:  They re just redesigned the MacBook Air. Yeah. Radically. I'm
Speaker 9:  not sure I like it. I like, I like the other one better. Yeah. But I'll just
Speaker 9:  tell you one more story before you get to the Vision Pro. Tim is a guy.
Speaker 9:  Who knows what he doesn't know. He knew he wasn't a product guy.
Speaker 9:  So he, he gave even more power to Johnny.
Speaker 9:  Ive their great designer. Eventually he gave him software,
Speaker 9:  not just hardware, he gave him everything. Right. And here's the difference,
Speaker 9:  Johnny Ive was a great designer and he had, sure, he had some
Speaker 9:  great designers under him. They probably still have a great design shot.
Speaker 9:  Steve Jobs was his editor. Steve Jobs would pull him
Speaker 9:  away from his crazier instincts. Steve Jobs would say no
Speaker 9:  to some things and yes to other things. Tim Cook didn't
Speaker 9:  do that. Right. I don't think does that to this day because he knows what
Speaker 9:  he doesn't know. And Johnny, ive decided
Speaker 9:  I can't, I have no proof for what I'm saying, except I have a very high level
Speaker 9:  source who told me this story. That's my, but it's a one source
Speaker 9:  story. This is
Speaker 3:  Good, good journalistic rigor on your part here. I like this.
Speaker 9:  No, I'm make it clear to you that it's not full journalistic rigor. Sure.
Speaker 9:  But this person really knew, really super knew
Speaker 9:  the products. What he said was, after Cook had given
Speaker 9:  Johnny all his power and Johnny no longer had an editor who
Speaker 9:  went to a lunch with him every day, which was what jobs did,
Speaker 9:  he decided they didn't need to be an he and a pro. He
Speaker 9:  decided he could do the pro and make it as light and
Speaker 9:  as thin or thinner than the MacBook Air and
Speaker 9:  it would be a higher price machine. So that would be better for their bottom
Speaker 9:  line. And people would buy it even if they didn't need the
Speaker 9:  extra power it gave. And so he could have one laptop that
Speaker 9:  would do everything. And you might say, well that kind of even jobs in
Speaker 9:  his four square thing had two laptops, a consumer and a pro.
Speaker 9:  But Johnny wanted to have one laptop. And
Speaker 9:  there was a big war between the design team
Speaker 9:  and its acolytes. In other words, the Johnny I've led team
Speaker 9:  and the engineering and product manager side of the company,
Speaker 9:  which desperately wanted new improved versions of the
Speaker 9:  air. 'cause the air was the, their bestselling product,
Speaker 9:  probably the bestselling laptop in the world, the thing everyone was chasing.
Speaker 9:  And they did not wanna leave it on a hill to die. But that's what they thought
Speaker 9:  was happening. Hmm. And they, this battle kept up for a while and
Speaker 9:  finally the product guys and the engineers
Speaker 9:  managed to yank, yank it back. And they brought out a new
Speaker 9:  MacBook Air with very minimal changes. but it was a new model.
Speaker 9:  It had, I think more storage faster,
Speaker 9:  you know, whatever. Basically
Speaker 3:  Like a spec bump of a laptop.
Speaker 9:  Correct. Yeah. And I remember that they introduced it at the Brooklyn
Speaker 9:  Academy of Music and this source of mine pulled me aside and
Speaker 9:  said we finally won. Mm. And then it was
Speaker 9:  the first, I think it was the first machine or one of the first machines
Speaker 9:  to get Apple Silicon So I still have, still have an M1
Speaker 9:  MacBook Air, you being a professional
Speaker 9:  computer writer, probably have an M three Pro or something. But
Speaker 9:  believe it
Speaker 3:  Or not, as a testament to how good this stuff has been, I'm still very happily
Speaker 3:  on an M1 MacBook Air. I upgraded basically every minute
Speaker 3:  I could new computers until I got to Apple Silicon. And I've been happy with
Speaker 3:  the M1 for, what, three years now? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Me too. Well good, good for you. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But wait, what I really wanna know is you very famously bought two
Speaker 3:  MacBook errors. Yeah. Before all of the MacBook
Speaker 3:  Air stuff got weird with the butterfly keyboards and all the nonsense they
Speaker 3:  were doing to those computers on the idea that, you know, when my computer
Speaker 3:  runs out, I'll still have one that I like. That's right. Have, have you been
Speaker 3:  able to safely get rid of the backup MacBook Air? Has Apple won
Speaker 3:  you back with Apple silicon that now you can buy the new ones instead
Speaker 9:  Of the backup? MacBook Air to my wife
Speaker 9:  Chagrin is still, I think in the basement wrapped up in
Speaker 9:  plastic, in the box, in the plastic thing.
Speaker 9:  You know,
Speaker 3:  Just in case.
Speaker 9:  Just in case. But I love my M1 MacBook Air.
Speaker 9:  It's what I use all the time. When I'm, when I'm using
Speaker 9:  a Mac or any computer, I'll be honest with you, I, I
Speaker 9:  probably do 75% of my computing on an iPad or an iPhone
Speaker 9:  now. But when I need to use a computer, like right now, this is an
Speaker 9:  iMac, it's an M1 iMac and it's, it's fine.
Speaker 9:  And the MacBook Air is fine and these are Macs and
Speaker 9:  the Mac has been better than fine for its
Speaker 9:  whole life.
Speaker 3:  So, okay. Before, before I let you go here, let's talk about the Vision Pro
Speaker 3:  just for a minute. Because the big question now is like, is this
Speaker 3:  the beginning of a new 40 year cycle? Are we, are you and I
Speaker 3:  gonna podcast in 2064, about
Speaker 3:  how incredible the moment that the Vision Pro came out was and how the world
Speaker 3:  will never be the same? There are some things that, there's a new
Speaker 3:  interface idea, there's a thing that is probably overpriced and
Speaker 3:  underpowered, but seems to have some interesting ideas. What do you think
Speaker 3:  about where we are at the Vision Pro right now?
Speaker 9:  Well, I think they think that you're right that this
Speaker 9:  will be like a, a new Mac or a new iPhone and last I don Dunno
Speaker 9:  how long the iPhone will last, but 17 years for phone seems like a long time
Speaker 9:  Still pretty
Speaker 3:  Good. Yeah. That's
Speaker 9:  What I think They think they're embarked on and they're very realistic.
Speaker 9:  They knew, they know this. I, I, we don't have the numbers yet, but they
Speaker 9:  know that this one is gonna sell less than a million in its first
Speaker 9:  year and all of that. They don't expect millions of people to go
Speaker 9:  out and buy a $3,500 thing, which you
Speaker 9:  with a battery that lasts two hours and is separate from the
Speaker 9:  device and you know, all the other things. On the other hand, they
Speaker 9:  think what they like to call spatial computing is a real thing
Speaker 9:  and has a lot of potential even that every major
Speaker 9:  possible developer has refused to build something for it. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  that was actually true on the Mac too, by the way. Microsoft and
Speaker 9:  Adobe were the only ones that built anything for it. And then
Speaker 9:  Apple's in-house stuff at the beginning, So
Speaker 9:  I think that's what they think. What do I think? I think it
Speaker 9:  depends on how smart and fast
Speaker 9:  they are at getting the price down without too
Speaker 9:  much sacrifice and features and also at
Speaker 9:  getting the size of it down. And those two things may not
Speaker 9:  run in tandem. There may be a cheaper version of
Speaker 9:  what we have now. This big thing you wear in your face with very poor
Speaker 9:  battery life and at the same time, maybe a year later
Speaker 9:  they'll start, start to shrink the size of it until
Speaker 9:  eventually they, in their dreams and this is their dream.
Speaker 9:  I know that, I know for a hundred percent fact that this is Tim
Speaker 9:  Cook's dream that it gets to be these, it gets to be
Speaker 9:  like this. Don't ask me how you can pack a battery and all
Speaker 9:  that power into this and there's no cord going down and all that, but
Speaker 9:  you know, electricity still can't be carried over wifi or
Speaker 9:  Bluetooth and all that. I think that's their ultimate goal.
Speaker 9:  I don't know if they can ever reach that goal, but it
Speaker 9:  also could be that society kind of gets used to things not being worn in
Speaker 9:  your face. As long as they're not as huge as this and
Speaker 9:  they may be able to go half the size of this and be okay,
Speaker 9:  I don don't know. I certainly would not be willing to say it's a 40
Speaker 9:  year product. But you're not ruling out that they're onto something. I
Speaker 9:  don't think it's a one year product because they have a lot of money and
Speaker 9:  they already have a roadmap. It's more than a roadmap.
Speaker 9:  They're already designing the next one to be less money.
Speaker 9:  They have a roadmap for the next three after that. So
Speaker 9:  it could be a, if it's a failure, it could be a four or five year, three
Speaker 9:  or four year product. If it's not a failure and they're selling a
Speaker 9:  plausible amount and the margin is good and all of that, and they're not
Speaker 9:  losing money on it, they'll never break out sales on it. I'm
Speaker 9:  sure unless a miracle happens and they sell a million in the
Speaker 9:  first month, then there will be a press release a hundred
Speaker 9:  percent. There'll be a press release. I agree that and the stock will shoot
Speaker 9:  up. But you know, this is a new area. Meta
Speaker 9:  is involved in it in certain ways. You know, it's,
Speaker 9:  it's worth watching. You guys have covered it very well. My
Speaker 9:  impression so far from everybody, including NELI
Speaker 9:  in the first look is technically
Speaker 9:  it's genius. They've technically done a genius job,
Speaker 9:  but in terms of the price and the overall
Speaker 9:  design, it's not something people will wanna buy.
Speaker 3:  I I think you're right. And I think, again, thinking about like a, the 40
Speaker 3:  year legacy of, of something like the Mac, I think the iPhone is
Speaker 3:  sort of a clear before and after moment, right? I think the, the day the
Speaker 3:  iPhone came out, there was this thing that happened and everybody's like,
Speaker 3:  oh, this is it. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  But they still had to cut the price on it by a hundred bucks.
Speaker 3:  Sure. I no, I I totally think that's right. That was another example of right,
Speaker 3:  kind of overpriced and underpowered, but it was obvious there was something
Speaker 3:  there
Speaker 9:  Obvious, instantly obvious.
Speaker 3:  This one, it's a little less obvious and So I think the, the
Speaker 3:  question of the next couple of years. Like, I think you're right that evaluating
Speaker 3:  the idea of the Vision Pro on this object
Speaker 3:  is actually not the right way to think about it. So I'm trying to think about
Speaker 3:  sort of the five year run before we see the five year run, if that makes
Speaker 3:  sense. And I, I think it's, there are reasons to think we might look back
Speaker 3:  on this as the beginning of something cool, overpriced and
Speaker 3:  underpowered, but on the right track. But at least to me it doesn't
Speaker 3:  scream this is the right idea to me. The way the iPhone did,
Speaker 9:  I mean look, he, the iPhone and the Mac actually
Speaker 9:  both had to have price reductions. And in the case of the
Speaker 9:  iPhone, we'll all remember that, you know, it started out without
Speaker 9:  copy and Paste started out with a bunch of stuff that was
Speaker 9:  missing. So it might've been the third version of the iPhone or the
Speaker 9:  one where they got off edge. I, which I think was the third, was the three
Speaker 9:  gss in some ways that was the first full fledged iPhone. And you know, then,
Speaker 9:  then the hockey stick began, saw a chart just yesterday,
Speaker 9:  but it was like an Apple chart. It was, it was not from Apple, but it was
Speaker 9:  like an Apple chart in that it didn't have very many numbers for the
Speaker 9:  x and Y axis
Speaker 3:  Just had lines going up. You, you couldn't really
Speaker 9:  Tell they were nice. It was a colored chart, you know, it said
Speaker 9:  yellow as the Mac and green as everything else. don don't
Speaker 9:  know. But so they've about tripled what their share was early.
Speaker 9:  And I assume, I mean it's a, if the Mac
Speaker 9:  was taken out of Apple, I think it's a $30 billion
Speaker 9:  business. Am I right? Something like that.
Speaker 3:  That sounds right. Yeah. If it was
Speaker 9:  Taken out of Apple, it would be a Fortune 500 company
Speaker 9:  all by itself. Same is true of course of the iPhone,
Speaker 9:  but the Mac, which was long considered, you know, like
Speaker 9:  almost dying and it was the last thing and all that, it would be
Speaker 9:  a Fortune 500 company.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Not bad for being 40 years old. Not
Speaker 9:  Bad for being 40 years old.
Speaker 3:  All right, well I'm putting 2064 on the calendar for our 40 year
Speaker 3:  Vision Pro retrospective and between now and then we're, we're gonna have
Speaker 3:  to have lots of reasons to have you back on. Thank you for doing this. This
Speaker 3:  was super
Speaker 9:  Fun. I I'd love to do it.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk about
Speaker 3:  getting things done, being productive, being a person on the
Speaker 3:  internet and why overthinking your productivity system might not be such
Speaker 3:  a good idea. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. If you've been listening to this show for a while
Speaker 3:  or if you subscribe to my newsletter called Installer Shameless Self-promotion,
Speaker 3:  you know, I'm like way over my head deep into productivity
Speaker 3:  software. I've used all the to-do apps, all the notes apps, all the calendars,
Speaker 3:  everything imaginable that claims it'll help me get
Speaker 3:  more done and make my life better. And you can't spend
Speaker 3:  much time in that corner of the internet without encountering this guy
Speaker 3:  full name Ali Abdaal
Speaker 12:  And I guess doctor turned entrepreneur and author. I dunno, maybe
Speaker 12:  that
Speaker 3:  Ali is right. He does do a lot of things. His YouTube channel is how I discovered
Speaker 3:  him and I'm a big fan. Hey
Speaker 12:  Friends, Welcome back to the channel in this video I wanna talk through
Speaker 12:  seven habits that I try my best to do every day. And that saved me around
Speaker 12:  three hours every single day.
Speaker 3:  Most recently, Ali wrote a book called Feel Good Productivity How to Do,
Speaker 3:  More of What Matters To You. The book came out just this week and it's great
Speaker 3:  and you should totally buy it and read it, but it is not at all what I expected.
Speaker 3:  I expected the book to be all about cool tools and sick hacks and
Speaker 3:  tips and tricks and systems for how to get more stuff done. After all, this
Speaker 3:  is the guy who makes videos about his super complicated calendar system
Speaker 3:  and the six AI tools he uses to increase productivity and how
Speaker 3:  to build your ultimate productivity system. He's done that kind of video
Speaker 3:  a few times and it always does gangbusters numbers and in fact, Feel Good
Speaker 3:  Productivity is almost the opposite of that. It's kind of a book about what
Speaker 3:  makes this human as much as it is about how to be productive.
Speaker 3:  And I got really curious about that combination of things and
Speaker 3:  whether all the tools and apps and systems are even solving the right
Speaker 3:  problems for us. I also figured this was a good time. We're three weeks into
Speaker 3:  January, it's the beginning of a new year. This is, I think statistically
Speaker 3:  right about the time most people ditch their New Year's resolutions. So it
Speaker 3:  seemed like a fun time to talk about what it means to actually be productive
Speaker 3:  and what it really takes. So I asked Ali to come on and tell me about writing
Speaker 3:  the book, his productivity journey and a whole bunch more. We started with
Speaker 3:  one of the books Recurring themes, which is ironically the book itself.
Speaker 3:  one of the things I like about the book is how much time in the book you
Speaker 3:  spend talking about the process of writing the book, which is a delightfully
Speaker 3:  like Meta thing to do in a productivity book. It's like you, you could have
Speaker 3:  kind of written the whole book about writing the whole book and it would've,
Speaker 3:  it still would've sort of tracked, but I, I could feel it in the process
Speaker 3:  of reading the book that it was like you took this thing
Speaker 3:  seriously in a pretty unusual way that it was like, I wanna make a
Speaker 3:  thing that lasts in a way that I think we're just not incentivized to do
Speaker 3:  that on the internet most
Speaker 12:  Of the time. No, exactly. Like everything on the internet is very, is very
Speaker 12:  femoral. Yeah. Throughout the whole process I was like, ah, I wanna, I wanna
Speaker 12:  take this seriously, but not too seriously to the point that it becomes
Speaker 12:  paralyzing, but Right. Sincerely enough that, you know, I'm, I'm showing
Speaker 12:  up and putting in my best effort.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, sincerely, not seriously one of the good lessons of the book. Exactly.
Speaker 3:  I like that very much. Hang on. So part of the reason I wanted to talk to
Speaker 3:  you about this is I feel like if I were to like boil the central thesis of
Speaker 3:  your book down, it's that an underrated way to be productive is to make
Speaker 3:  things more fun.
Speaker 12:  That's literally it.
Speaker 3:  There's a lot more to it and that's obviously like a massive generalization
Speaker 3:  of what you're saying, but I think that's like not a totally wrong takeaway
Speaker 3:  from the book. Is that fair? That
Speaker 12:  Is literally the, the thesis that we started the book with and the title
Speaker 12:  initially was called Make It Fun. Oh
Speaker 3:  There you go.
Speaker 12:  Okay. Or like Fun, productive as Unproductive, fun, productive. It was like
Speaker 12:  we played around with so many different titles. Eventually we kind of
Speaker 12:  realized that the word fun doesn't quite capture it and really like a lot
Speaker 12:  of the science around it was this idea of feeling good and positive emotions.
Speaker 12:  Hmm. And positive Emotions is not necessarily the same as fun, but to be
Speaker 12:  honest it's close enough that I kind of equate them. And the way I think
Speaker 12:  of it is, if you wanna be productive of anything, make it more fun and you'll
Speaker 12:  probably be more productive at the thing and you'll also be happier along
Speaker 12:  the way, which is win-win all round.
Speaker 3:  Totally. So the thing that kept jumping out to me as I was reading it is
Speaker 3:  so much of it is about framing and mindset and kind of the way that you talk
Speaker 3:  to yourself and the way that you talk to other people and the way that you
Speaker 3:  approach things and the process rather than kind of obsessing
Speaker 3:  over just like raw data of how much you accomplish as
Speaker 3:  sort of the end in itself. Which intellectually to me makes total sense,
Speaker 3:  right? Like I, I believe every word in the book and it feels right. And yet
Speaker 3:  I am a person who has spent an alarming amount of my life, like testing
Speaker 3:  productivity tools, believing that I will find the right productivity
Speaker 3:  tool that will solve all of my problems and magically work. And I
Speaker 3:  kind of got to the end of your book and was like, okay, the correct answer
Speaker 3:  here is to throw all of my technology into the ocean and
Speaker 3:  rethink the way that I do everything. And you're also a guy who has spent
Speaker 3:  an alarming amount of time testing Productivity tools. So like Square, square,
Speaker 3:  those two things for me, those two sides of your brain.
Speaker 12:  Absolutely. So people have like various hot takes on this. Some people are
Speaker 12:  like, you know, the tool really matters because the tool facilitates the
Speaker 12:  productivity. Some people are like the tool doesn't matter at all because
Speaker 12:  the tool is just a tool and any tool will do, whether it's Notion or Evernote
Speaker 12:  or Google Keep or whatever the hell new apps city in Rome, et cetera, et
Speaker 12:  cetera, et cetera. My approach has always been that the tool that I will
Speaker 12:  use is the one that feels good to use. This is why I still use Notion because
Speaker 12:  Notion have done an amazing job of making it feel good to use Notion. The
Speaker 12:  emojis, the font and the cover images between them make
Speaker 12:  it a delight to use notion. The reason I use things three as my to-do list
Speaker 12:  app is because the animations are delightful compared to Todoist, which
Speaker 12:  is just a bit more like Todoist has more features teams and cross
Speaker 12:  platform is all handy, but things is just so nice. And when we find
Speaker 12:  things that are nice to you, that's why people buy Apple products. They're
Speaker 12:  just nice, something nice about them. Like when, for me, when an app feels
Speaker 12:  good to use, I'm more likely to use it and therefore like that will make
Speaker 12:  me more productive. Totally. I dunno if you found this at all, like what's
Speaker 12:  your take on the sort of the design aesthetics niceness of, of something?
Speaker 3:  Oh no, I've, I've found that exactly. one of the notes I wrote down reading
Speaker 3:  the book was, I bet Ali loves people who design the hell outta their notion
Speaker 3:  pages. Oh yeah, I think I'm right about that. But like it's, it's funny you
Speaker 3:  mention things because it's one of those apps that is like objectively
Speaker 3:  not what I need just in terms of like how my brain works and how I sort of
Speaker 3:  run my days. It doesn't do it and yet every three months I try to force my
Speaker 3:  life into things again because it's a lovely app with really nice animations,
Speaker 3:  it never crashes. It makes total sense. All the icons are beautiful.
Speaker 3:  Like it, it feels really good and So I try to make myself use it. even that
Speaker 3:  I know for sure it's never gonna work. I just like, I want to use it. And
Speaker 3:  I think there's something to that. But I also think in this space it's
Speaker 3:  very hard for any digital tool to do the
Speaker 3:  kind of thing that you're talking about. Early on in the book you talk a
Speaker 3:  bunch about sort of making games out of everything and it's like how do we,
Speaker 3:  how do we gamify things? And we went through this whole phase on the internet
Speaker 3:  of like, how do we gamify everything? And sometimes It works and sometimes
Speaker 3:  it's like disastrous because you try to gamify things that shouldn't be
Speaker 3:  gamified and it gets really ugly and and problematic. But I think also
Speaker 3:  it's very hard for these digital tools to be
Speaker 3:  whimsical and fun and still useful. And So
Speaker 3:  I think we've gotten to this point where with so many things where we've
Speaker 3:  like leaned into like obsidian is like pure
Speaker 3:  raw utility, right? Like yeah, there's nothing delightful about it,
Speaker 3:  but it is like, holy God, if you wanna get things done, will it help you
Speaker 3:  get things done in a certain way? And I guess notions may be an interesting
Speaker 3:  outlier there and I wonder if that's part of why it's been so successful.
Speaker 3:  But part of what I wonder is like the principles that you talk about in this
Speaker 3:  book, like can those exist in the kinds of like productivity apps?
Speaker 3:  You and I spend too much time thinking about.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. And I think some apps have tried it like, fabulous. Did you come across
Speaker 12:  that habit tracker fabulous.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 12:  It was like a to-do list, but you would like build different habits into
Speaker 12:  it. It's like you'd start off with a drink my water first thing in the morning
Speaker 12:  and then like do my morning routine. And that was so full on on
Speaker 12:  the design and cute animations and stuff all the way, but to the point that
Speaker 12:  it was almost unusable because everything then took ages to be like a nice
Speaker 12:  little delightful animation. So, I dunno, like a notion is an exception
Speaker 12:  in that they somehow cracked the, the niceness thing. But for other apps
Speaker 12:  it's really hard. Wonderlist back in the day was quite delightful. And then
Speaker 12:  yeah, it it sort of died.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, RIP Wonderlist was a good example.
Speaker 12:  Inbox by Gmail was quite delightful. And then, and then it died. Well
Speaker 3:  That's the thing, right? And I think the path a lot of these end up on is,
Speaker 3:  and I've, I'd love following to-do list apps because they all go through
Speaker 3:  the same thing where it's like everybody has sort of one thing, one idea
Speaker 3:  or one mechanic or one sort of feature that makes them unusual and then people
Speaker 3:  start to use it and they say, well, but I also need this feature and I need
Speaker 3:  recurring tasks. And what if you had calendar integration and I really wanna
Speaker 3:  take notes and I do my things this way, I need a priority system. And all
Speaker 3:  of a sudden you've just built this like awful voltron of an app that does
Speaker 3:  everything and is a mess in the same way that almost every other
Speaker 3:  productivity app is a mess. And then that's when I get to the point where
Speaker 3:  I'm like, okay, I need out, this is too much. This is making me feel bad.
Speaker 3:  I'm like spending my life managing this system rather than actually accomplishing
Speaker 3:  anything. And then I go find another app and go through exactly the same
Speaker 3:  process.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Th this is like my life for the last 10 years, every few months.
Speaker 3:  Do you feel like writing this book has changed the way you think about all
Speaker 3:  of that stuff? Like do you approach new productivity apps and
Speaker 3:  stuff differently? I went back through your YouTube channel and tried to
Speaker 3:  see if I could pinpoint like when you were working hard on the book based
Speaker 3:  on how much you were talking about Productivity tools and I feel like I can
Speaker 3:  sort of invent a narrative there, but I am curious like, did you have that
Speaker 3:  experience? Like do you find yourself switching less or caring less or trying
Speaker 3:  new things less because you're like, actually the the tool matters a little
Speaker 3:  less than maybe I've thought over the years. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  I've really come to that realization over time that the tool is almost meaningless
Speaker 12:  other than the fact that someone nicer to use than others. We're actually
Speaker 12:  working on a sort of productivity course to release in 2024 with like
Speaker 12:  a community and a coaching program behind it. And that
Speaker 12:  has involved diving into a bunch of research around like goal setting and
Speaker 12:  things like that. And a big goal for this course, which is why
Speaker 12:  I'm, I'm thinking a lot about this stuff, is for it to be platform agnostic.
Speaker 12:  Mm. I've come up with a bit of a, I'm, you know, be, I'd be curious to get
Speaker 12:  your take on this a little sort of frame framework for productivity, which
Speaker 12:  is, which is not in the book, but you know, who cares about talking about
Speaker 12:  the book, which sort of stands for it's GPS goal plan
Speaker 12:  system. That's what all the productivity boils down to have a goal that
Speaker 12:  gives you a sort of destination to go towards, make a plan of how you're
Speaker 12:  gonna get there, and then have a system that encourages you to actually
Speaker 12:  follow the plan and then you adjust accordingly. Goal plan system GPS,
Speaker 12:  and I've been kind of doing sort of informal productivity coaching for like
Speaker 12:  friends and my team and stuff. And it always comes down to that if, if someone
Speaker 12:  wants to be more productive, should have a goal, should have a plan, should
Speaker 12:  have a system. And if someone is struggling with their productivity, it
Speaker 12:  is almost always a problem with either the goal or the plan or the system.
Speaker 12:  I'm trying to figure out a way of like presenting that in a way that, in
Speaker 12:  a way that does, it's not like do this in notion or do this in OneNote or
Speaker 12:  it's like do this in whatever you want used to p pen and paper use post-it
Speaker 12:  notes use notion for like hair. The point is if you have a goal, you have
Speaker 12:  a plan on a system, there's no way you're not gonna be productive.
Speaker 3:  The great challenge I have had with like Capital P
Speaker 3:  productivity internet people over the years has been that I think everything
Speaker 3:  you just said is absolutely true and makes for terrible content, which is
Speaker 3:  the challenge, right? And I think I, I was talking to somebody not that long
Speaker 3:  ago about why Notion grew this huge community and I think
Speaker 3:  it's partly, it's a very successful app because it's a very good app and
Speaker 3:  also it is a very fun thing to tinker with and make
Speaker 3:  beautiful things with that you can share on the internet, right? Like notion
Speaker 3:  allows for better YouTube videos than a text file.
Speaker 3:  And that has nothing to do with whether or not it's a better app, but it,
Speaker 3:  it is a better thing to make content about and I think so is
Speaker 3:  really elaborate systems. So is, you know, coming up with things that you
Speaker 3:  can sell courses about. And I think I'm as guilty of this as anybody, like
Speaker 3:  I've spent a lot of time writing about and covering apps that
Speaker 3:  purport to solve everything when in reality, like I find myself sending a
Speaker 3:  lot of people this blog post, I forget the guy who wrote it, but he's like,
Speaker 3:  my productivity system is a single text file. And he's like, I have a 15,000
Speaker 3:  word long text file that is just, I write down all the things I have to
Speaker 3:  do that day and then I do them. And it's like, oh shit, maybe it's that simple.
Speaker 3:  But I, I do wonder like we're, we're in this place now where trying to
Speaker 3:  make, you know, quote unquote content about this stuff
Speaker 3:  feels almost disingenuous. If the goal is just know where you're going
Speaker 3:  and figure out how to get there, like that's so much simpler and so much
Speaker 3:  less sort of visually compelling in a certain way.
Speaker 12:  I know, you know, one person who I've really been vibing with his stuff
Speaker 12:  recently, Ramit Seti has been doing a whole new new thing on YouTube.
Speaker 12:  He actually took my course on how to do YouTube and I connected with his
Speaker 12:  team and stuff and now he's crushing it on YouTube. But one thing that he's
Speaker 12:  doing, he's, he's doing just like long form conversations with people who
Speaker 12:  are struggling with their finances and they're just like sharing their screen
Speaker 12:  and going through their numbers and it's all the same simple stuff. Like
Speaker 12:  don't spend more than you earn and like put stuff in investment
Speaker 12:  accounts and like don't spend so much on a car payment for your truck that
Speaker 12:  you can't afford. Basic stuff like that. That was in his book I'll Teach
Speaker 12:  You To Be Rich. But there's something a about watching him coach a
Speaker 12:  real couple through these problems and seeing how they deal with it. That's,
Speaker 12:  I'm, I'm just hooked on this content even that I know exactly what the system
Speaker 12:  is from the book and you know, I'm fairly familiar with personal finance,
Speaker 12:  he's just really cool watching him like coach people through it. And so
Speaker 12:  I'm thinking, hmm, maybe there's something there instead of, you know, for
Speaker 12:  me when when I think of the future of my content, instead of it being like
Speaker 12:  let me try and invent some new productivity system that looks good on a
Speaker 12:  fricking YouTube video, more like, hey, let's just get someone on a call
Speaker 12:  and coach them through how to set goals, how to make a plan and how to build
Speaker 12:  a system. And it will converge on the same things. It will converge on
Speaker 12:  figure out roughly what you wanna do with your life. Turn it into a few
Speaker 12:  goals for the year. Let's break them down, let's put it in the calendar
Speaker 12:  and let's review it every now and then. But actually the process of doing
Speaker 12:  that requires a lot of coaching for some people and needs emotions get
Speaker 12:  in the way like fear gets in the way. There's like so much cool stuff but
Speaker 12:  I think the cool stuff is in the human emotion behind it rather than in
Speaker 12:  the how pretty is my notion page.
Speaker 3:  Yeah and there's something too like I don't mean to denigrate people who
Speaker 3:  have pretty notion pages. Like there is something too, like you said, if
Speaker 3:  you're a pretty good notion page makes you use notion more like that's a
Speaker 3:  victory, right? Like that is a thing that is successful and my problem is,
Speaker 3:  the reason I switched productivity apps all the time I discovered is that
Speaker 3:  I just get bored with them. And so I've actually come to take the inevitable
Speaker 3:  switching, I literally just did this yesterday, like took all of my notes
Speaker 3:  out of one app and put them in another app, which is an unbelievable waste
Speaker 3:  of time. Like it's just such a bad use of time and energy. But every
Speaker 3:  single time I like the system gets a little different. It's essentially a
Speaker 3:  way to like look at all my notes again. I get to sort of move stuff around,
Speaker 3:  I take some things out, I put some new things in and I've come to see that
Speaker 3:  as like I'm switching apps but also sort of reviewing everything that
Speaker 3:  I have and whatever it takes to get there is a win. But I, I think that's
Speaker 3:  right that it all of this is in some ways simpler and in some ways
Speaker 3:  more complex than it is made out to be. And and it's an interesting thing
Speaker 3:  for you as a person who people like look to for advice to be like, here are
Speaker 3:  ways you can do this, but ultimately like this is about your feelings. It's
Speaker 3:  just a very funny kind of line to have to walk as someone who is
Speaker 3:  trying to guide people and especially for you like a mass audience of millions
Speaker 3:  of people through that process.
Speaker 12:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  You're like an internet therapist in a lot of ways. I
Speaker 12:  Know exactly. Like I, I genuinely never thought the conclusion for any of
Speaker 12:  this would be, it's about your feelings. But the three years of research
Speaker 12:  around the book made me really realize, oh crap, it really is just about
Speaker 12:  the feelings. And if you can deal with the feelings then honestly productivity's
Speaker 12:  as simple as I write down what I need to do and then I do it. It's just
Speaker 12:  that the feelings get in the way of that.
Speaker 3:  One of the things that you mentioned with the CEO coach and I think is is
Speaker 3:  true about a bunch of stuff in your book is how valuable a lot of this stuff
Speaker 3:  is to do in person. Whether it's like giving feedback or
Speaker 3:  the, you talk about kinda the random acts of kindness that you can do or
Speaker 3:  receive and how meaningful that can be in productivity and all this stuff.
Speaker 3:  And I think my experience has been that that is sort of obviously true that
Speaker 3:  a lot of things that matter and are meaningful happen
Speaker 3:  when you're in a room with somebody. But that's also just increasingly not
Speaker 3:  the world we live in. Like you and I are doing this podcast, we're thousands
Speaker 3:  of miles away from each other, this is the world we live in. Can this stuff
Speaker 3:  work in a sort of digital space? Like I keep coming back to the idea that
Speaker 3:  like I agree with so many of the ideals in your book and I think they run
Speaker 3:  into what it means to be a person in the world in
Speaker 3:  2023 and 2024 in these really complicated
Speaker 3:  ways. Like can we get that stuff through digital tools?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I think we can definitely get some of it. one of my favorite things
Speaker 12:  to do is to work in an environment where there are other people working,
Speaker 12:  which is why right now I'm in a WeWork rather than in my hotel room. 'cause
Speaker 12:  I find it very depressing just working in a hotel room. But during, during
Speaker 12:  the pandemic when all of these coworking spaces were closed, I found this
Speaker 12:  writer's group that would just meet on Zoom four times a day for like an
Speaker 12:  hour and it was so nice. It was like, I think it's still going a London
Speaker 12:  writer's salon and it's just sick. Like, you know, it's like a zoom call
Speaker 12:  with a few hundred writers. They spent five minutes at the start giving
Speaker 12:  you a motivational quote five minutes at the end. Everyone's like posting
Speaker 12:  in the chat what they accomplished. There genuinely is a feeling of community
Speaker 12:  in being on a Zoom call with a couple hundred people and like all working
Speaker 12:  on the same general thing. So I think that definitely works. I think similarly,
Speaker 12:  you know, our team has just gone remote because they've decided to travel
Speaker 12:  the world previously we were in person and so we've been trying to figure
Speaker 12:  out like, okay, how do we apply these principles of like how do we make
Speaker 12:  work feel good in a remote world? Even like, like simple stuff. Like we
Speaker 12:  have a, we have a channel on Slack now for like nice comments that we say
Speaker 12:  to each other or nice comments that we post from you know, people in our
Speaker 12:  audience and emails that we get. And we didn't really have that before because
Speaker 12:  we were in person. But now the fact that there is a Slack channel dedicated
Speaker 12:  for pleasantries and feedback and nice things, it's kind of cute
Speaker 12:  and we've got this like matter app on Slack that gives you points and you
Speaker 12:  can redeem them for a Starbucks gift card and it's just, you know this something
Speaker 12:  about that. That's kind of nice.
Speaker 3:  Does that stuff work for you as a person? It
Speaker 12:  Really does, yeah. Honestly I love it. I love that shit. Like I used to
Speaker 12:  be skeptical of motivational quotes and I used to be skeptical of affirmations
Speaker 12:  and stuff but I think as I've gotten older I've realized the value
Speaker 12:  of reminders. You know, even something like, you know back in
Speaker 12:  the day when I had a computer monitor I used to have a post-it note, what
Speaker 12:  would this look like if it were fun just written on it. And
Speaker 12:  I think in the past I would've sort of scoffed that thinking like, the fuck,
Speaker 12:  like how would that be helpful? And it's actually a really helpful reminder
Speaker 12:  if you ask yourself what would this look like if it were fun? It's like,
Speaker 12:  oh I'd probably take it a bit less seriously 'cause it's not that deep.
Speaker 12:  Hmm. Haven't got any music in the background. Lemme put on concerning habits
Speaker 12:  from Lord of the Rings. 'cause that'll always like, you know, cracks me
Speaker 12:  up. It's a vibe. Oh I haven't said hello to some someone in my team in a
Speaker 12:  while. Lemme just go say hello and sort of give 'em a little massage in
Speaker 12:  a non weird way. I haven't said a nice message to someone on the team today
Speaker 12:  'cause you know, as A-C-E-O-I should do that. So lemme just do that. And
Speaker 12:  it's like, great, now I'm getting back into my work. but it feels more fun.
Speaker 12:  So I love, I love little reminders like that. I'm a sucker for emotion,
Speaker 12:  motivational quotes.
Speaker 3:  The part of the book that resonated with me the most actually was the part
Speaker 3:  at the very beginning where you're like, look, everybody talks about discipline
Speaker 3:  and everybody talks about this idea that sometimes you don't wanna do things
Speaker 3:  and you should just do them anyway. And that's all well and good, but also
Speaker 3:  like screw that. Like that's sometimes you have to do things
Speaker 3:  you don't wanna do. Like sure that's life, but what if there were fewer of
Speaker 3:  those things? Like that's what this book is about. And I was like, that's
Speaker 3:  such like, thank you for that because there's so many and so much of the
Speaker 3:  like hustle culture of the internet is like 24 hours a day just
Speaker 3:  get it done. No excuses play like a champ and it's just like, it's just boring
Speaker 3:  and I'm tired and I don't want to like leave me alone. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  And
Speaker 3:  I think I'm guessing that was intentional because if you've read all the
Speaker 3:  productivity books that it seems you have read, you've heard that message
Speaker 3:  more times than most, which is just like, shut up, do the work and like buy
Speaker 3:  this supplement and you'll win. Mm. And I think that is
Speaker 3:  a bleak world to live in and I feel like your version of the world is
Speaker 3:  significantly less bleak on purpose.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I think I've, I've benefited a lot from, you know, as partly through
Speaker 12:  the journey of having this YouTube channel. I just happen to connect with
Speaker 12:  loads of people who are like really rich and really like, sort of business
Speaker 12:  successful. Like deca millionaires, a hundred millionaires. I've,
Speaker 12:  hmm, only I've met two billionaires and I love asking them for advice because
Speaker 12:  I'm always like, okay, this is cool, cool shit. I I I get to hang out with
Speaker 12:  people who are like way further ahead of me in their careers and also stupidly
Speaker 12:  rich and like let me just ask them for life advice. And basically all of
Speaker 12:  them sacrifice to their health and relationships and wellbeing for the sake
Speaker 12:  of growing their business. Yep. And literally all of them regret doing that.
Speaker 12:  And they're always like, bro, you know, if there's one thing you do, trust
Speaker 12:  me, like rec recognize when enough is enough, don't sacrifice your family
Speaker 12:  and your health and your wellbeing for the sake of growing your business
Speaker 12:  because it's not actually gonna make you happy. Even that you think it will
Speaker 12:  to have some balance. Man I wish someone had told me about this before.
Speaker 12:  Have some balance. Do all this stuff, enjoy the journey. The journey is
Speaker 12:  the destination, the the goal's not gonna make you happy. The journey makes
Speaker 12:  you happy. And I've just been hearing that. So I've been reading books about
Speaker 12:  it, reading all the, the stuff about it and hearing it enough times from
Speaker 12:  people to, I think I really have absorbed it into my heart. So my
Speaker 12:  whole thing these days is like, no achievement is actually gonna make you
Speaker 12:  happy. The thing that's gonna make you happy and feel content is having
Speaker 12:  that balanced life where you're enjoying the journey. So why not start now
Speaker 12:  rather than when you hit some arbitrary income milestone or whatever the
Speaker 12:  thing might be.
Speaker 3:  So, and speaking of that, actually one of the things you mentioned in the
Speaker 3:  book that I've been thinking about ever since is this idea of like adding
Speaker 3:  friction deliberately to your life. And as somebody who covers software,
Speaker 3:  this is a thing I've been thinking a lot about, like, especially in this
Speaker 3:  age of social media and stuff, right? Like we spent a whole generation
Speaker 3:  removing friction from everything, right? We made it really easy to connect
Speaker 3:  with people, we made it really easy for people to track everything. We made
Speaker 3:  it really easy to do everything online and we like kind of broke society
Speaker 3:  in the process. And now I, the more people I talk to, the more they're
Speaker 3:  like, well what if we made shopping a little harder? Like what if, what if
Speaker 3:  shipping was slower? Like maybe, maybe that would suck, but also be better.
Speaker 3:  But I think we've hit a point where that's really, it's just hard to put
Speaker 3:  the toothpaste back in the tube in that front. And I think the people who
Speaker 3:  do things like you described in the book, like buy feature phones on purpose
Speaker 3:  are like, there's a world in which they're like smart forward thinkers and
Speaker 3:  there's a world in which they're like borderline insane people. I guess I
Speaker 3:  wonder like for you, you as somebody who, who is both sort of writing about
Speaker 3:  this for an audience and trying to live it yourself, do you have a good sense
Speaker 3:  of the balance there of like we have, we have so many tools that make it
Speaker 3:  easy to do so many things. Smartphones are so good for so many purposes.
Speaker 3:  There's all these upsides to all these things. Like the friction that the,
Speaker 3:  the avoidance of friction that helped you get a giant audience is also
Speaker 3:  the avoidance of friction that is a problem for a lot of people
Speaker 3:  trying to like successfully live their lives. Do you have a sense of kind
Speaker 3:  of how to walk that line the right way?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I think I struggle with this like everyone else, the thing that I
Speaker 12:  think I I always bring it back down to is intentionality. So I
Speaker 12:  have no qualms about spending time on social media 'cause I also do it for
Speaker 12:  a job. But one thing I found enormously helpful is just getting rid of all
Speaker 12:  of all social media apps from my home screen. 'cause before I would just
Speaker 12:  sort of swipe, swipe open up Twitter and scroll and
Speaker 12:  almost do that on autopilot with that, even thinking about it. Now the way
Speaker 12:  I open up Twitter is I scroll down on my phone, I type in Twitter, I realize
Speaker 12:  it's not called Twitter anymore and I type in X and then I go on the thing.
Speaker 12:  And that's enough friction for me to be like, I have to intentionally decide
Speaker 12:  to go on Twitter. For me to actually go on Twitter. It's not just to click
Speaker 12:  on my phone. The things that are clicks on my phone are Kindle Audible,
Speaker 12:  UAC day one, a new app that I've just released called Voice Pal, which is
Speaker 12:  like voice notes for steroids and like my workout tracker. So it's like
Speaker 12:  the only things I have access to at my fingertips are things that I would
Speaker 12:  like to spend more time on and that I think are good for my body and my
Speaker 12:  mind and my soul. Everything else I have to actively seek out. And
Speaker 12:  that is a good thing. That means, you know, I still watch YouTube videos
Speaker 12:  but I watch them when I have decided I wanted to watch a YouTube video.
Speaker 12:  Hmm. And I think one of the issues that so many people have is that, you
Speaker 12:  know, if you are for example, drained of energy, you just find yourself
Speaker 12:  scrolling through TikTok or Instagram or whatever and when was the last
Speaker 12:  time you got off a scrolling session and thought, wow, I, I feel so energy
Speaker 12:  energized as a result of that never. Whereas going for a walk or
Speaker 12:  don don't know playing the guitar is a, you know, there's to towards
Speaker 12:  the end of the book, like generally creative things or things that like
Speaker 12:  help us flex our sense of autonomy or things that help us sort of separate
Speaker 12:  from work. These are really the things that recharge our energy and we all
Speaker 12:  know that. It's just we don't do it because it's, it's too easy to look
Speaker 12:  at the notification and like click on the thing and then now we're scrolling
Speaker 12:  before. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well and that brings me back to, I hate to keep harping on the, like, can
Speaker 3:  we do any of this online stuff? But it's telling to me that like you, you
Speaker 3:  had a a section in the book where it was like the two columns, right? Like
Speaker 3:  the things I do when I'm tired and the things that are actually restorative
Speaker 3:  and it's like the things you do when you're tired are look at screens and
Speaker 3:  the things that are restorative are basically like don't look at screens
Speaker 3:  and
Speaker 12:  Yeah, pretty
Speaker 3:  Much. And, and to some extent I think maybe the answer is just what we need
Speaker 3:  is more balance. I think that's absolutely right. That like the, the
Speaker 3:  touch grass joke on the internet is like it's right, right? Like we should
Speaker 3:  all spend a lot less time looking at screens. Like that is objectively true.
Speaker 3:  But I also wonder in this like phase that
Speaker 3:  we're in, where like can we solve technology with more technology? Is
Speaker 3:  there a sort of digital answer to this? And I think, like I talk to a lot
Speaker 3:  of people who do art on the iPad and that I think is like a perfectly
Speaker 3:  valid restorative use of screens, right? Like you're still looking at a screen,
Speaker 3:  but it is like a fundamentally creative activity. I've been learning how
Speaker 3:  to play guitar using an app called Musician. I think that counts no Nice.
Speaker 3:  But I do wonder like do you have versions of those things? Like are there,
Speaker 3:  are there things you can do still looking at your phone or a computer or
Speaker 3:  a screen of some kind that recharge you in that same way?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So I, Don I don Dunno if this is just me, but one thing I love doing
Speaker 12:  is listening to a Lord of the Rings ambience type
Speaker 12:  soundtracks on YouTube. Okay. While working, 'cause I was doing some
Speaker 12:  research for the book and there, there seems to be this weird thing where
Speaker 12:  hearing the sounds of nature has this weirdly energizing effect on
Speaker 12:  us. So you can obviously walking through nature is like the best, but you
Speaker 12:  can even just listen to Birds song or listen to like the sound of waves
Speaker 12:  of something and that taps into something in our brain. No one quite knows
Speaker 12:  what it is, but it seems to be quite energizing. Hmm. And so people have
Speaker 12:  put these like playlists together, like three hour long videos on YouTube
Speaker 12:  where it's like Harry Potter music or Lord the Ring's music, but with the
Speaker 12:  sounds of rain or the sounds of birds. I just love that shit. It's, it's
Speaker 12:  so nice and it's like anything becomes more fun and more energizing when
Speaker 12:  doing it with that sort of soundtrack in the background. So that's a way
Speaker 12:  in which I try and recharge while also also looking at a screen. One thing
Speaker 12:  someone should do, some someone needs to make an app that lets you listen
Speaker 12:  to podcasts, but with background music, you know like with some like meditation
Speaker 12:  apps like Waking Up by Sam Harris, it's like you can listen to the lectures
Speaker 12:  with some background music and the background music makes it so much more
Speaker 12:  immersive. That's pretty, I need someone to make this
Speaker 3:  App, like listen to this podcast in the rainforest. It's like
Speaker 3:  I would do that. I would listen to that.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, rainforest or Epic or like classical or whatever, like lo-fi
Speaker 12:  and just makes the podcast more engaging.
Speaker 3:  That's a problem AI could solve. Figure out how to score the the beats of
Speaker 3:  a of a podcast like that. It could do it. Oh
Speaker 12:  That would be cool. That's a good idea.
Speaker 3:  Ali, I think we just started a company. This is very exciting
Speaker 12:  For us. I think we did. Yeah, we've got a registered domain soon.
Speaker 3:  All right Ali, thank you again everybody. Bye. Ali's book, Feel
Speaker 3:  Good. Productivity How to Do, More of What, Matters, To You. Great book.
Speaker 3:  Highly recommend it. We have to take one more break and then we're gonna
Speaker 3:  come back and answer a question on the birch cast. Hotline, we'll be right
Speaker 5:  for more details.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is 8 6 6
Speaker 3:  Verge one one and the email is Vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all
Speaker 3:  of your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show every week.
Speaker 3:  We have some super fun things coming in. Thank you to everybody who writes
Speaker 3:  and calls. It's my favorite thing about the first cast this week we have
Speaker 3:  a question from Erland from Norway, which seems relevant to what we've been
Speaker 3:  talking about today. Erland sent us an email that says I need to get a new
Speaker 3:  Mac. My last one is from 2014. It is a MacBook Pro, but now
Speaker 3:  I'm thinking of a Mac Mini to have at home and maybe later a MacBook Air
Speaker 3:  for travel, or should I just get a MacBook Pro? Again, I'm a hobby
Speaker 3:  photographer and videographer, but mostly I use it for presentations for
Speaker 3:  my job as a teacher. So that's the question. I have gone back and forth on
Speaker 3:  this question a thousand times, both in my life dealing with
Speaker 3:  my own setup and also just in general trying
Speaker 3:  to think through the best way to use a computer. Basically it's like should
Speaker 3:  you have a workstation at home and then a thing you take with you? Or should
Speaker 3:  you just have one computer that you kind of dock in and out of various
Speaker 3:  setups as you need it? I will say personally, I'm in a one computer
Speaker 3:  at home and one computer on the road phase. I'm actually on a Mac Mini right
Speaker 3:  now as I record this and I have a MacBook Air that goes with me whenever
Speaker 3:  I leave the house, which is increasingly rarely, but that's for another day.
Speaker 3:  So I think for most people though, if this is what you're
Speaker 3:  debating this specific thing, I think the answer is the MacBook Pro and I
Speaker 3:  went through just to spec it out real quick and see what the cost would be.
Speaker 3:  So you have a 13 inch MacBook Air, just the M
Speaker 3:  2 256 gigs, the base model MacBook Air for
Speaker 3:  1090 $9. I desperately want to upgrade your RAM here for
Speaker 3:  $200 more, but we'll leave it alone for now. And then you have the
Speaker 3:  eight gigabytes, 2 56 gigabytes M two base model
Speaker 3:  Mac Mini for $599. So you're at like
Speaker 3:  1700 bucks all in between these two machines, two great
Speaker 3:  machines. They do a pretty good job of talking to each other. one of the
Speaker 3:  things you run the risk of with having two separate machines is you have
Speaker 3:  stuff on one device that's not on another device, but things like iCloud
Speaker 3:  Drive make that easier. I personally am just religious about uploading
Speaker 3:  stuff to Google Drive so that it's everywhere. It's a relatively easily solved
Speaker 3:  problem, but it is a thing that can happen. Or you can get a
Speaker 3:  base 14 inch M three MacBook Pro.
Speaker 3:  Again, base model, I wanna spend $200 to upgrade your ram, but you can just
Speaker 3:  get the stock base model for 1599. So for
Speaker 3:  all intents and purposes, the price is not that different, but it's a little
Speaker 3:  bit cheaper to just get the pro and I think that's the answer.
Speaker 3:  It's the newer computer, it's gonna last you longer. It has the better
Speaker 3:  processor. It has Apple's latest stuff. I think the PRO is
Speaker 3:  probably the single most versatile computer that Apple makes.
Speaker 3:  The M1, even MacBook Air and especially the
Speaker 3:  M two MacBook Air are gonna be plenty for all of the sort of standard presentation
Speaker 3:  stuff. But you'll notice the difference when you're doing things like editing
Speaker 3:  photos, and especially dealing with video. The speed increase you'll get
Speaker 3:  on the pro is meaningful. It's not gonna totally change your life, but it
Speaker 3:  is noticeable. And then on top of that, the MacBook Pro
Speaker 3:  gets just outrageous battery life. It's not super heavy, it's
Speaker 3:  noticeably heavier than the air, but it's not like gonna weigh down your
Speaker 3:  backpack in a super brutal way. And I think if
Speaker 3:  the question is should I get an error or should I get a pro, most people
Speaker 3:  I would tell to get just an error. But if you're debating, do I get an error
Speaker 3:  and then a mini, I think the pro actually overlaps
Speaker 3:  what's good about both of those computers in a pretty good way. So I
Speaker 3:  think if I were in your position, I would just get a 14 inch MacBook Pro,
Speaker 3:  spec it out as much as you can, and plan for that thing to last you an awfully
Speaker 3:  long time. You got 10 years outta your last MacBook Pro. I wouldn't be surprised
Speaker 3:  if you get just as long out of this one. So that's what I do. But Erland,
Speaker 3:  tell me what you decide and how it goes. And also if you have thoughts on
Speaker 3:  this setup question, let me know. Call the Hotline, send us emails. This
Speaker 3:  is a thing I think a lot of people go through and I'd love to know what you
Speaker 3:  think. Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks
Speaker 3:  to everybody who came on the show, and thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 3:  There's lots more on everything we talked about from the Mac anniversary
Speaker 3:  to productivity stuff all over The Verge dot com. We'll put some links in
Speaker 3:  the show notes to Ali's stuff and Walt's stuff and everything else, but also
Speaker 3:  read The Verge dot com. It's cool website. As always, if you have thoughts,
Speaker 3:  questions, feelings, or other old Macs you wanna see if you can stump me
Speaker 3:  with, you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the
Speaker 3:  Hotline. It's six six Verge one one. We love hearing from you. Send us all
Speaker 3:  your thoughts and feelings and questions and ideas. We do a Hotline question
Speaker 3:  every week and we're gonna start to do even more of them, so keep 'em coming.
Speaker 3:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Wil Poor The. Vergecast
Speaker 3:  is a VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network, NELI, Alex.
Speaker 3:  And I'll be back on Friday to talk about Ford's weird new ideas
Speaker 3:  about Android, Elon Musk and Mr. Beast, what's going on in the
Speaker 3:  streaming wars and a whole bunch of other stuff. We'll see you then. Rock
Speaker 3:  and roll.
Speaker 5:  Introducing Kia's first, all electric SUV, the 2024
Speaker 5:  Kia EV nine. Remarkably luxurious and relentlessly capable.
Speaker 5:  The Kia E nine has something for everyone. Impressive. Zero to 60
Speaker 5:  speed off-Road agility, a spacious three row cabin, even available
Speaker 5:  mood lighting. Get premium comfort and rugged capability all
Speaker 5:  in one sleek, spacious package. The all new, all-electric
Speaker 5:  three row Kia EV nine electric like you've never seen.
Speaker 5:  The 2024 Kia E nine is available now. Inventory limited. Check the dealer
Speaker 5:  for availability and visit kia.com/e nine for more details.