# Transcript
ID: ab35b237-d180-46f0-b1a8-fe390ecc44b9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2121630302733687244/-3272677348282785756/s93290-US-5951s-1713518145.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss third-party iPhone app stores, game emulators, Google Android and hardware team restructuring, the latest TikTok news, and more.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome. To Vergecast flagship podcast. Mini
Speaker 4:  LED technology.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That if there's one thing the show is actually about.
Speaker 5:  It's displays.
Speaker 4:  It's displays. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Classic audio subject.
Speaker 5:  It's David's favorite subject.
Speaker 4:  If you're gonna talk displays. Yeah, you want to do it in a
Speaker 4:  radio show?
Speaker 6:  That sounds right. Yeah. Because the power, I'm gonna make a TV show. That's
Speaker 6:  just sound next. It's gonna be sick.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I feel like that that's been done quite
Speaker 6:  A lot. I also feel like Netflix just green lit that for me just now.
Speaker 6:  Congratulations.
Speaker 4:  Just sound with David
Speaker 4:  Pierce. It's pretty good. It's just you listing sounds you like.
Speaker 5:  I was seeing him like in a little, little robe sitting at like a fireplace
Speaker 5:  behind him and be like, and now here's another sound.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah, right. He's
Speaker 5:  In PR voice. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  He's like babies laughing.
Speaker 4:  I feel like I have to disclose it on the EP of a Netflix show.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. We got to this right away. You can even said your name and you've
Speaker 6:  already disclosed
Speaker 5:  This is great. That was Neli.
Speaker 4:  I'm Neli. The Netflix show is called The future. It's great. You should go
Speaker 4:  watch it. This is Alex Cranz. Hey,
Speaker 5:  What's up?
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 4:  All I got. David, David Pierce, host of Just Sounds, David
Speaker 4:  Pierce is
Speaker 6:  Here. It's an honor to be here. Oh
Speaker 5:  My God, I love your work.
Speaker 4:  It's good. Yeah. you know that when you plug a USB device
Speaker 4:  in to, to Windows and it's like, do do, it's a good one.
Speaker 4:  That's episode three. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just, I'm just offering my, you know, you had a brainstorm. It's a spinoff
Speaker 4:  for The Vergecast. All right. There's actually quite a lot of news this week.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We've gotta talk about what's happening to the iPhone. Emulators have
Speaker 4:  hit various app stores around the world, which is actually really interesting.
Speaker 4:  Google has reshuffled its Android team, which we should talk about.
Speaker 4:  Meta launched its big AI push to compete with chat GBT.
Speaker 4:  It is true that Sony announced the next generation of its million LED TVs
Speaker 4:  that will be a full hour in the middle of the show today. Then we got a couple
Speaker 4:  of letting rounds and David's gonna do something he calls Headline Blitz
Speaker 4:  with David Pierce. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Speed
Speaker 6:  Round. I'm just, I'm gonna, it's the just sounds, but it's me screaming
Speaker 6:  headlines at you about TikTok. It's gonna be incredible.
Speaker 4:  I also, I just want to, I'm gonna try to summon some
Speaker 4:  energy in the world. It appears not today,
Speaker 4:  but there might be a lightning round sponsor in The future. So If, you could,
Speaker 4:  everyone listening could just
Speaker 5:  Send us the good vibes.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna make it happen. Yeah, it's a, it's a guy named Steve.
Speaker 4:  He, he gave me 20 bucks.
Speaker 5:  I love Steve. Thanks for the 20.
Speaker 4:  It's not Steve. Sorry Steve. Okay, let's talk about emulators on the app
Speaker 4:  store. This is a big deal. So If, you've been listening to Vergecast. you
Speaker 4:  know,
Speaker 4:  the Europeans did some regulating as they want to do.
Speaker 4:  They basically said you have to allow other app stores in Europe on iOS devices.
Speaker 4:  Those other app stores started appearing. One launched this week, alt Store
Speaker 4:  pal. What's the first thing these alternative app stores want
Speaker 4:  to allow game emulators. It's the thing people want. There's been a little
Speaker 4:  bit of back and forth about which emulators are going up first, which
Speaker 4:  ones aren't. Apple responds to this by saying, you know what?
Speaker 4:  We are going to allow emulators in our app store now because we
Speaker 4:  don't want people installing these other app stores. That means emulators
Speaker 4:  have come to the i Apple Run io s App Store, the first good one
Speaker 4:  called Delta is out. It's been 10 years in the making basically RI test out.
Speaker 4:  The developer isn't cranking away on it in various ways, gray
Speaker 4:  area ways for 10 years. It's here. People are playing it and they're loving
Speaker 4:  it. It's good. David, you've been tracking this all very closely. What's,
Speaker 4:  what's the vibe?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'm just looking to see if this app is still the number one app in
Speaker 6:  the app store. It is in fact still the number one app in the app store. So
Speaker 6:  it was like two weeks ago. As you're hearing this, on Friday, I think two
Speaker 6:  weeks to the day since Apple did what it likes to do in these cases, which
Speaker 6:  is just sort of update a support page without really telling anybody. But
Speaker 6:  there are people watching these things. And basically over the last
Speaker 6:  five days really we got The first, Apple
Speaker 6:  emulator, which showed up in the app store and then fairly quickly
Speaker 6:  was revealed to be a clone of the old version
Speaker 6:  of Delta, which was an app called gba four io
Speaker 6:  s spelled just like it sounds really pulls off the tongue and
Speaker 6:  it event it quickly got pulled from the app store and then another one came
Speaker 6:  out, I think it was called Bii. It was out for a minute and
Speaker 6:  then the developer pulled it out of what the developer said was fear,
Speaker 6:  which we should come back to, which I think is fascinating. And then like
Speaker 6:  you said, Delta came out, we've talked to RI on this show before. He was
Speaker 6:  on the show last fall talking about emulators. He's been working on this
Speaker 6:  forever. And at one point a few years ago, thought he
Speaker 6:  was gonna be in the app store and then that got ripped away and has come
Speaker 6:  up with, I would say, increasingly creative ways, If, you want to do some
Speaker 6:  work to get this thing out. As soon as the announcement came out
Speaker 6:  that third party app stores were gonna be allowed, he announced he's been
Speaker 6:  working on one. Like this was always the plan. And then I think it seems
Speaker 6:  like basically just out of nowhere, apple was
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, you're cool. You can do this. And he was like, sick. I've been
Speaker 6:  building this for 10 years. Here it is. and it is like, I mean, it is a
Speaker 6:  remarkably good app for what it does.
Speaker 6:  We can talk about the legality of ROMs and emulation. We should talk about
Speaker 6:  all of that. I did a decoder episode with Sean Hollister on all of this like
Speaker 6:  two weeks ago. It was very good, but it, it's, it's just so funny.
Speaker 6:  This is like a version 10 app that just showed up on the app store
Speaker 6:  all at once. Like, I think I can say this without getting me or ri in
Speaker 6:  trouble. This thing has been in test flight for a very long time because
Speaker 6:  there's a lot less review on test flight. You can
Speaker 6:  just test apps in beta. Some people can have them. I have had it.
Speaker 6:  It's like it's out there and now all of a sudden he was able to just flip
Speaker 6:  the switch and it is the number one app in the app store. So much pent up
Speaker 6:  demand for something like this. It's fascinating.
Speaker 4:  So we should talk about the legality of it. Alex, I know you've been tracking
Speaker 4:  a lot of that stuff over time. There's a war on emulators
Speaker 4:  generally occurring.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Nintendo is, Nintendo for the longest time was
Speaker 5:  like, you know what you do you, because the emulator audience I think was
Speaker 5:  fairly small and I think they have been kind of probably dreading
Speaker 5:  and looking at this moment and knowing it was gonna happen at some point.
Speaker 5:  'cause you can get 'em on Android and, and, and, and go to town,
Speaker 5:  but iOS, but
Speaker 6:  It takes some work.
Speaker 5:  Like it's, yeah, it takes some work and, and iOS is like, there's some impact
Speaker 5:  there. And If, you can just automatically download this and then get your
Speaker 5:  ROMs. That means you're not gonna pay Nintendo for kind
Speaker 5:  of a similar version of it on your switch. Right. Like why would you do that
Speaker 5:  when you can just have it on your iPhone?
Speaker 4:  I mean, so the, the answer for the longest time is, and why doesn't Nintendo
Speaker 4:  make a Game Boy advance emulator and sell Ros?
Speaker 4:  And the answer to that has been they don't want to pay 30% to
Speaker 4:  Apple. And
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's kind of like, I think the, the the more accurate, like,
Speaker 5:  like emotionally, their response is, you know, that meme of, of
Speaker 5:  your beloved,
Speaker 4:  The meme of my beloved
Speaker 5:  Singer, this
Speaker 4:  Singer Mariah Carey.
Speaker 6:  Mariah
Speaker 5:  Carey. Okay. you know that one of Mariah, that's what I think of
Speaker 4:  The meme of my beloved sounds like a very, very inexpensive Netflix
Speaker 4:  show.
Speaker 4:  That's just a couple guys in an iPhone and
Speaker 5:  One Yeah, that's like a, a freebie show. Yeah. Right. That's on freebie.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry.
Speaker 5:  But you know that the Mariah Carey meme where she's like, I don't know her
Speaker 5:  and puts the glasses down. Yeah. That's kind of been Nintendo looking at
Speaker 5:  the iPhone for the last, like, last 15 years. Fair enough.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. but don don't know her go away. Well,
Speaker 4:  But, but If, you put Nintendo games on the iPhone, you, you just reduce the
Speaker 4:  value of Nintendo's hardware. Right, right, right. Like that's the thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That has been the problem. And
Speaker 5:  That, that, that is the thing that's, that's what Nintendo is most focused
Speaker 5:  on, is they, they they've got a really good business of focusing on the hardware
Speaker 5:  and they, they've opened up right? They they've done some more development.
Speaker 5:  Super Mario, is it Super Mario Run? I believe they've got some, some good
Speaker 5:  games on there and and they've even recently as like, I believe late
Speaker 5:  last year were kind of like, yeah, we're gonna start exploring more stuff
Speaker 5:  on
Speaker 5:  iOS. But they've, for the longest time they've not been a fan of it. And
Speaker 5:  they've recently started going after these companies again,
Speaker 4:  Companies in like little groups. Yeah. So Jason
Speaker 4:  Citron, the CEO of Discord is on decoder next week. Look out for that
Speaker 4:  Discord just got what amounts to a cease and desist like legal orders
Speaker 4:  saying delete these channels, these servers that are hosting
Speaker 4:  emulator groups and they just wiped them out. Yep. And it's actually, when
Speaker 4:  we talked about it, you know, he's like, the lawyers won't let me say,
Speaker 4:  but basically he's like, we don't have a choice. And no one really knows
Speaker 4:  how they ended up and not a choice. So you're just in this weird moment
Speaker 4:  where this stuff has been tolerated because the distribution is
Speaker 4:  zero or handful of people in test flight who know Riley.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or illegal in a way that's like, fine,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of arguments that it should be legal, but it's been
Speaker 4:  tolerated. Yeah. Now it's in the store like apple's, like,
Speaker 4:  screw it. The last thing we can allow is the rise of
Speaker 4:  successful alternative app stores because there's demand for
Speaker 4:  these emulators. We have to allow it in our store to keep people away from
Speaker 4:  the alternative app stores. and it, it feels like this whole conversation
Speaker 4:  is gonna come to some kind of head.
Speaker 6:  I totally agree. And I think this is sort of a truism of
Speaker 6:  gaming in general that has held true over time. That people who wanna play
Speaker 6:  games will jump through a surprising number of hoops in order
Speaker 6:  to play games. Right. It's why all of the cutting edge PC hardware is
Speaker 6:  given to gamers first because they're the ones who will pay for it and do
Speaker 6:  the work to adopt it. It's why Apple allowed game streaming for the same
Speaker 6:  reason people will go out of their way to do whatever they have to do in
Speaker 6:  order to play games. And so Apple has started to pull this stuff back, but
Speaker 6:  I just keep thinking about when we did an episode on emulators on this show
Speaker 6:  last year, Chris Plant, the editor in chief of Polygon, basically said when
Speaker 6:  I asked when are we just gonna get Spotify for old video games? Why can't
Speaker 6:  I pay 20 bucks a month to play all of these ROMs perfectly legally? And he
Speaker 6:  just looks me dead in the face and goes, no one actually wants that. And,
Speaker 6:  and hi, his point was just that this group of people is so small and
Speaker 6:  so irrelevant to the rest of the gaming industry that it's actually
Speaker 6:  not worth the effort to care about them for Nintendo for
Speaker 6:  anybody else. That it's like you leave them alone because odds are they're
Speaker 6:  also buying your new games. And so that's great. You don't wanna piss them
Speaker 6:  off, but it's just kind of a live and let live thing because it
Speaker 6:  doesn't mean anything to anybody else. I think the fact that Delta is so
Speaker 6:  successful and the fact that this has become such a big thing is going to
Speaker 6:  be a really interesting moment in that story because
Speaker 6:  this is the first time ever it looks like there is actual, honest to God
Speaker 6:  mainstream demand for something like this. Because If, you just download
Speaker 6:  Delta, there's nothing there. It's just an app with nothing to do. You have
Speaker 6:  to fill it with stuff and that stuff has to come from somewhere. And that
Speaker 6:  stuff mostly comes from places that are not you dumping
Speaker 6:  ROMs that are yours from your Game Boy cartridges, which
Speaker 6:  no one knows how to do and no one is going to know how to do. And you can
Speaker 6:  just go on Google and search for Ros and they're all right there. So like,
Speaker 6:  this stuff is just out of the shadows in a way it never has been
Speaker 4:  Before. I feel like notable Plex owner, Alex Cranz has a response. For You
Speaker 4:  David. I I
Speaker 5:  Do. It is a lot easier. If, you wanna back up your carts now
Speaker 5:  versus 20 years ago. That's true. There's a lot of different ways to
Speaker 5:  do it. I think you can technically do it with some of the analog
Speaker 5:  consoles and, and there's a whole bunch of little tools and stuff. And to
Speaker 5:  be clear, Nintendo doesn't care as much about the NES games and the super
Speaker 5:  Nintendo games. Like when they went after Yuzu, that was because Yuzu was
Speaker 5:  doing much more like it was doing the switch. Yeah. The thing actually out
Speaker 5:  right now that you can hide
Speaker 6:  Including tears of the Kingdom. Yeah. Like before other people were playing
Speaker 6:  tears of the Kingdom. People on Yuzu were able to play tears of the Kingdom.
Speaker 5:  And this next part I say as someone who owns the Super
Speaker 5:  Nintendo version of the analog Loves a Retro game.
Speaker 5:  Have you played a retro game lately?
Speaker 4:  I, so I'm watching Fallout and I was like, I should play fall at one. And
Speaker 4:  then I looked at it and I was like, I'm not gonna play fall at one.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, it's, it's like watching old movies, you, it takes a very particular
Speaker 5:  kind of person to be like, yes.
Speaker 6:  You know where they really work though is on the iPhone. Yes.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 6:  All the games that look like crap on your 60 inch 4K TV
Speaker 6:  look great in a little square on your iPhone. It is the
Speaker 6:  perfect place for this kind of thing.
Speaker 5:  But it's, it's it in some ways. Right. but
Speaker 6:  Don don't know this. I just know this hypothetically based on Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Hypothetically,
Speaker 6:  You know, the internet and all of the carts that I have legally
Speaker 6:  downloaded.
Speaker 4:  This is great. Yeah. I feel like the fact that I am one
Speaker 4:  in, in charge of this operation two, a fucking copyright
Speaker 4:  lawyer and three deeply aware of the situation is all bad.
Speaker 4:  Like, I'm going to jail when I leave here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're actually, actually sitting out there. But just for neli, David
Speaker 5:  and I get off
Speaker 4:  The Nintendo police are here. They're like, Nintendo don't,
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry,
Speaker 4:  I, I couldn't apologize more deeply if I wanted to.
Speaker 5:  Here's a,
Speaker 4:  So let's set aside the legality, right, because it, it is actually a weird
Speaker 4:  gray area. There's a lot of parallels to Napster and ripping
Speaker 4:  MP threes and it's a lot. Yeah. The law has changed.
Speaker 4:  Maybe we'll come back and do a whole thing on the legality of, of that. Let's
Speaker 4:  set that aside. One huge problem Apple has here is it
Speaker 4:  traditionally has not allowed emulation of any kind. and now it is
Speaker 4:  allowing it, which means an entire library of software
Speaker 4:  that people like better than Apple software is available and proving a
Speaker 4:  very important point, right? Like Nintendo
Speaker 4:  games are better than the games that Apple has had heartedly supported
Speaker 4:  for 10 years. Yeah. And they are running in emulation.
Speaker 4:  They're not sw they're not coded in Swift. The
Speaker 4:  controls are better, they're more portable, it's better. They like the whole
Speaker 4:  thing is showing a vision of what the iPhone
Speaker 4:  could have been the whole time if Apple would just let go.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And I, I feel like that's actually the bigger problem for Apple in
Speaker 4:  office. Like the next emulator that comes out is going to just
Speaker 4:  be Windows 95. Right.
Speaker 6:  But it can't, that breaks the rules. This is like the, the
Speaker 6:  parsing Apple's review guidelines is so funny here because you can just
Speaker 6:  tell the number of meetings they had to make sure what you just said is
Speaker 6:  impossible. Lemme just read you two sentences. It says additionally,
Speaker 6:  retro game console emulator apps can offer to download games.
Speaker 6:  So much going on in that sentence, the following sentence, you are
Speaker 6:  responsible for all such software offered in your app, including ensuring
Speaker 6:  that such software complies with these guidelines and all applicable laws,
Speaker 6:  which applicable laws, who's to say, but the, the, the phrase
Speaker 6:  retro game console emulator apps you
Speaker 6:  is so specific and so lawyered to
Speaker 6:  absolute death. What is, what, what counts as retro?
Speaker 6:  Who's to say Apple can do whatever it wants? What counts as a console? A
Speaker 6:  PC probably doesn't like it is so narrowly tailored
Speaker 6:  to just let Apple do whatever it wants in nothing else. In the funniest
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 5:  I just think this is gonna somehow end up with all the Nintendo
Speaker 5:  emulators getting kicked off because Nintendo raises a stink and we're just
Speaker 5:  left with like Atari links
Speaker 4:  There. But there can't be a universe. By the way, Atari links emulators
Speaker 4:  rule. I had California games on my Atari links. That shit was awesome. You
Speaker 5:  Had Atari
Speaker 4:  Links. Oh yeah, I did not notably have a game gear. No,
Speaker 4:  I had the other thing That's a bummer. I'm so sorry. I had the
Speaker 4:  ostracized at links.
Speaker 5:  You're the one that I could only find it like the Offbrand toy
Speaker 4:  Story. It wasn't great. I really wanted the TV tuner attachment. We, we we're
Speaker 4:  gonna come to TV tuners later. The show Curious We'll back. It's all thematically
Speaker 4:  linked.
Speaker 4:  I'm just thinking about my entire links. It had the little cartridges that
Speaker 4:  were like very thin. It was so cute. The Xbox 360 is a retro game console
Speaker 4:  at this point in time. Is
Speaker 6:  It?
Speaker 4:  Yes, of course it is. Maybe it's two generations ago. It's 20 years old.
Speaker 5:  I think part of this is gonna be these companies who are actively selling
Speaker 5:  it, right? Like, like Microsoft is pretty active in supporting old games,
Speaker 5:  right? They they they're very backwards compatible. Nintendo's actually pretty
Speaker 5:  backwards compatible Sony way less so. So, so I think
Speaker 5:  there's a real potential of seeing like a PS
Speaker 4:  One game. If, you are Microsoft. Yeah. You have a 20-year-old
Speaker 4:  console. Why aren't you putting that emulator on the store tomorrow?
Speaker 4:  Well some with the ability to download games for three bucks and you're giving
Speaker 4:  30 a buck to Apple and who cares? That is free money.
Speaker 5:  Some consoles are harder to, to emulate than others. Right? Like, like the
Speaker 5:  Nintendo consoles, most of them are really easy. N 64. Yeah. Super
Speaker 5:  hard. Even on an iPhone today it is really hard to get in N
Speaker 5:  64 games playing properly. And I think Xbox might be the same.
Speaker 5:  I need to double check this, but I'm pretty sure that the Xbox 360, you don't
Speaker 5:  see as big a robust emulator community around it
Speaker 5:  as you do like Sony games. And part of that is, again, you can just go buy
Speaker 5:  those games. Like If, you have an Xbox, any kind of Xbox you can just go
Speaker 5:  and play Saints Row to or whatever.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Sony is an interesting example because Sony has done a really good
Speaker 6:  job over the years of making its current
Speaker 6:  consoles. And I confess, I don't have a PS five, so I don't know how true
Speaker 6:  this still is now, but for a long time there were a lot
Speaker 6:  of PS one and PS two games that you could play on a PS three and a PS four.
Speaker 6:  Like they've done a good job of keeping that stuff available and making it
Speaker 6:  part of its cloud services and all this stuff. So I think
Speaker 6:  if I'm Sony, I can sort of see it in both directions where one, it's like,
Speaker 6:  okay, this is helping me sell PlayStations, so I I want to do that. But on
Speaker 6:  the other hand, I kind of agree that if Sony was just like, Hey, for
Speaker 6:  whatever, 10 bucks a month, you can play every PS one game on your iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Like I'd sign up for that in a heartbeat and it's just sitting there for
Speaker 6:  them.
Speaker 4:  It is true that some of this stuff is hard, but have you heard of the staggering
Speaker 4:  power of the Aeries trip?
Speaker 5:  I, so as you guys were talking, I was looking this up and apparently there's
Speaker 5:  only really like one emulator for right now for Xbox 360. It's only for pc.
Speaker 5:  It's called Xenia, which love the name. And on Reddit there
Speaker 5:  is discussions. It, people are really weird about it. They're, they're
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, it sucks or it's fine. But it's apparently like one of the only
Speaker 5:  ones.
Speaker 4:  No, there's one called Zemo.
Speaker 5:  Oh there's also Zemo.
Speaker 4:  Zemo is for the Mac. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  How did you forget about Zemo? I'm
Speaker 4:  So sorry. We're we're all just Googling weird. We're just
Speaker 5:  Googling this
Speaker 4:  Furiously now. The now the point is Microsoft is very capable of making the
Speaker 4:  products. Sony is very capable of making the product. It is free to them.
Speaker 4:  'cause they already own the library. The demand is obvious
Speaker 4:  and the thing it's just gonna prove out is Apple's
Speaker 4:  way of doing things has unnecessarily restricted user experiences
Speaker 4:  on the Amazon.
Speaker 5:  That's a good point. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And I, I, that is the danger because once that
Speaker 4:  falls away and people are like, wait, this is better than when
Speaker 4:  Apple is in tight control of this ecosystem, which is what we hear. By the
Speaker 4:  way, when we talk about antitrust and control, we get an awful lot
Speaker 4:  of notes from people who are like, this is what I'm paying for, for Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  to push all the buttons on my phone for me.
Speaker 6:  Well, and I would point out that one of the really hard things about regulating
Speaker 6:  that is proving the other way because a big part of what like the DOJ
Speaker 6:  in this case is saying is that it would be better if it wasn't like this.
Speaker 6:  And that's so, so, so hard to prove. And this
Speaker 6:  to your point, is going to be a very real way in which it is going to get
Speaker 6:  a lot better very quickly because it changed.
Speaker 4:  And I believe, I don't know, but I believe that's why the emulator rule
Speaker 4:  is global and not just in Europe where Apple is
Speaker 4:  required, like legally required to allow other app stores which would just
Speaker 4:  go ahead and do this. They know they can see the outsized
Speaker 4:  demand for emulators If. you allow other app stores with more
Speaker 4:  permissive rules, people will flock to those app stores. They'll get the
Speaker 4:  demand. They'll be like, in Europe, we get game emulators, why don't we get
Speaker 4:  them here? Well I guess we need rules to allow other app stores in the United
Speaker 4:  and they're not. Right. I think they'd rather soon be in a lawsuit with Nintendo
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Than have any political capital to open up the app model
Speaker 4:  in
Speaker 5:  The United States. And that'd be a wild lawsuit, right? Because a lot of
Speaker 5:  these games
Speaker 5:  were made in a copyright was super weird in the eighties around
Speaker 5:  video games, if I remember correctly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It remains super weird.
Speaker 5:  I would say it's not, it is not, it's not easily sorted. So this would be
Speaker 5:  a fight for Nintendo regardless.
Speaker 4:  It Well it depends on who you're suing, what you're suing them for. Like
Speaker 4:  again, the the the things that you would map it to
Speaker 4:  are still Napster and Grokster. Yeah. In the
Speaker 4:  Supreme Court and the appeals courts in those cases, like invented theories
Speaker 4:  of liability. Like with Grokster it was like
Speaker 4:  you are enabling copyright infringement. you know, it's happening. You're
Speaker 4:  marketing the thing for cop infringement. Now you are liable for copier infringement
Speaker 4:  even though you've done none yourself. Yeah. That's a, that's a bunch of
Speaker 4:  steps down there. You gotta get all the way there.
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure that you're gonna do that against a single developer. I'm not
Speaker 4:  sure you can prove that case against Apple by allowing these emulators on
Speaker 4:  your store, you know, this, you're marketing the iPhone to do this copyright
Speaker 4:  infringement. There's a lot of road. That's a lot of steps.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Yeah. It's also Apple is like the, the second sentence of
Speaker 6:  that thing in the guidelines that I read is Apple pretty clearly foisting
Speaker 6:  that responsibility on whoever is shipping the emulator. They're like, oh,
Speaker 6:  if people use software in here that isn't yours to own, that's your problem.
Speaker 6:  We, we told you not to. You've broken our terms of service. Well
Speaker 5:  That's why they pulled the the one app too, right? Like the, the was GBA
Speaker 5:  four iOS.
Speaker 4:  No, that is very confusing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I agree.
Speaker 4:  So IGBA comes out, that's the first emulator hit any of these stores.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so not GBA
Speaker 4:  Fours. Right. But then RI tweets, hey this is a fork of GBA four iOS
Speaker 4:  the thing that I made long ago
Speaker 5:  That I definitely never had on my phone at any
Speaker 4:  Point. Right. And, and well his point was Apple makes all this noise about
Speaker 4:  how the app store is controlled and safe and here's just a bootleg of my
Speaker 4:  decade old project that they let slide through while my real project
Speaker 4:  is waiting sitting in review. Yeah. So he is like very irritated about this.
Speaker 4:  Apple pulls the app and then in a classic sort of Apple
Speaker 4:  way, there's no public explanation given of what they're doing. There's nothing
Speaker 4:  we can link to. There's Mac rumors saying Apple has told us on background
Speaker 4:  that they've pulled it for these two reasons, one of which is copyright.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's so important in this context to remember
Speaker 6:  that Apple's review process is insane. Like, like in all
Speaker 6:  seriousness, like anyone who claims that Apple's app review
Speaker 6:  process is consistent and has rules and
Speaker 6:  make sense is just out of their mind. Right? And like we see this all
Speaker 6:  the time. It's so easy for bad apps to get through while people
Speaker 6:  get their apps hung up on absolute tiny
Speaker 6:  technicalities that don't actually have anything to do with anything. It's,
Speaker 6:  it's lunacy. And so I think what happened in this case is
Speaker 6:  once it became obvious that this app was just a rip of Riley's app,
Speaker 6:  it's very popular. This is a new thing. It makes sense from Apple's perspective
Speaker 6:  to say you've violated the rules by borrowing someone
Speaker 6:  else's app. I think there's even the rules borrowed in scare quotes in
Speaker 6:  Apple's guidelines that they can't borrow your work.
Speaker 6:  Which is a very funny way to say. And so I think in this case it was, it's
Speaker 6:  pretty easy and protected for Apple to say you just boosted somebody else's
Speaker 6:  app, you can't have this.
Speaker 5:  Well yeah and it, it was like, it basically had wiped some of the licenses
Speaker 5:  that the original was developed with
Speaker 4:  Classic
Speaker 5:  Off off of it and
Speaker 4:  Classic bad faith move.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And like filled it with ads, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So it was just all around like, no, this is garbage. Yeah. And the guy
Speaker 5:  apologized.
Speaker 6:  This is the thing that we see in the app store all the time. Do you remember
Speaker 6:  the, when Flappy Bird came out and all of a sudden there were 40,000 flappy
Speaker 6:  birds that all had a million ads or chat GPT when it came out and was first
Speaker 6:  really popular, you could search for chat GPT and there were a billion things
Speaker 6:  that kind of looked like chat GPT and were called chat GPT, but just had
Speaker 6:  ads and would like steal your family from you. Like
Speaker 6:  Apple is bad at this and and just continues
Speaker 6:  to pretend that it is like in a firm hold of everything that happens on
Speaker 6:  the app store and it just is not. Nope.
Speaker 4:  So that's emulators here in the United States around the
Speaker 4:  world because Apple knows if it allows emulators in alternative app
Speaker 4:  stores in Europe, people want them here. It's bad. So it's allowed them here.
Speaker 6:  Wait, can I ask a legal question though? This is the thing I've been wondering
Speaker 6:  about the last couple of days is this has been going on the, this idea that
Speaker 6:  we now see what better looks like and that could be bad for Apple.
Speaker 6:  I've been trying to figure out in my head if I'm Apple, am I
Speaker 6:  more worried about, okay, this sort of prove the point that the iPhone gets
Speaker 6:  better if we allow this one thing now it becomes more legally dicey. They're
Speaker 6:  gonna say, well now we have to allow all these other things because we've
Speaker 6:  proven the point that it gets better when we do. Or does Apple say
Speaker 6:  we've thrown you a bone or two, let's all shake hands and move on.
Speaker 6:  Does that make sense? I'm trying to figure out like which is the winning
Speaker 6:  strategy there.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna ask some AI generation program to generate Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  and Jonathan Cantor and Tim who was saying, we've thrown you a bone or two
Speaker 4:  now let's shake hands and like it'll blow up. Like we're gonna blow up a
Speaker 4:  data center With that prompted it is an unimaginable situation. Okay.
Speaker 4:  I I think the danger for Apple is they will get forced into allowing
Speaker 4:  more and more things. This has long been the danger. This is why
Speaker 4:  they have fought it for so long. We don't know what kinds of things
Speaker 4:  will happen in the European market because other kinds of app stores are
Speaker 4:  gonna let other kinds of things happen. So there's only one app store in
Speaker 4:  Europe right now. It's by Riley Test out. It is called Alt
Speaker 4:  Store Pal. It's gonna launch with Delta obviously. And
Speaker 4:  this clipboard manager app clip, which is a type of app that is
Speaker 4:  forbidden by Apple in the regular app store because a clipboard manager can
Speaker 4:  see all the things that you are copying and pasting and da da da da. Totally
Speaker 4:  normal. That clipboard managers on desktop computers, apple is not allowed
Speaker 4:  on the phone. So here we go. Here's this one other kind of thing you can
Speaker 4:  do in the iPhone that you couldn't do before. Is that gonna be enough to,
Speaker 4:  to turn the tide of regulation around? I don't know, emulators obviously
Speaker 4:  were Yeah. Right. Yeah. So there, there's only one store right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. There's only one store and then and there's no porn or gambling.
Speaker 5:  And I feel like we, we made a bet. I think I may have lost a bet
Speaker 4:  Somewhere. How quickly porn. Well I think Riley's been working on this store
Speaker 4:  Yeah. For a long time. He,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And he didn't wanna put porn.
Speaker 6:  Give it, give it a minute. Kranz. I, I absolutely do not believe you have
Speaker 6:  lost this bet yet.
Speaker 5:  Okay. It's coming.
Speaker 4:  The second the Vision os app store opens
Speaker 4:  the floodgates. Wrong phrase.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry boy.
Speaker 5:  Don't cut any of that.
Speaker 4:  There's only one. The the point is there's only one store we don't know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But the second, there's another compelling thing
Speaker 4:  that you can accomplish with an app from another store that is
Speaker 4:  compelling enough for anyone, any significant set of people to go download
Speaker 4:  that store and get that app. Apple will allow that thing. It,
Speaker 4:  it seems inevitable that that is the, the just the how the
Speaker 4:  flow of innovation is gonna go now. you know, we always joke that like, just
Speaker 4:  the hint of competition makes these companies behave just like
Speaker 4:  the, a whisper of competition here. You have both like
Speaker 4:  mandated competition because of the regulators. There's now other app stores
Speaker 4:  and there's gonna be way more than a whisper of competition. There's gonna
Speaker 4:  be just people trying stuff. 'cause it's a land grab in
Speaker 4:  Europe for iPhone customers again, which is cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And that pipeline of cool apps
Speaker 6:  come out that Apple doesn't allow to, apple allows it
Speaker 6:  so that people don't go through the hoops of downloading an app store. Like
Speaker 6:  what it, what it seems is now obvious, and I'm so curious how far this
Speaker 6:  will go, is that it is more important to Apple to keep you in the app
Speaker 6:  store than to keep its rules about the App store. Oh yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  Apple will bend massively as long as you
Speaker 6:  stay in the app store and it's gonna be so interesting to see how
Speaker 6:  far that extends. Like I I I am on record with like
Speaker 6:  the Apple sports stuff to say that betting and gambling is coming
Speaker 6:  to Apple platforms in a way that people do not yet see.
Speaker 6:  And I think this like porn I think is probably a pretty bright line
Speaker 6:  for Apple that it, it won't cross for a variety of reasons, but like
Speaker 6:  there will be popular betting apps that do things that Apple's
Speaker 6:  apps won't let you do. And like how far will it go
Speaker 6:  to keep as much in the app store as it possibly can is going to be a big
Speaker 6:  question over the next year or so.
Speaker 5:  Oh see, I I think the port is gonna happen as well. I think they're
Speaker 5:  gonna do like in the App store. Yeah. I think they're gonna be like, oh,
Speaker 5:  you can age gate it and then use Face ID to access your PornHub
Speaker 5:  account
Speaker 6:  And they'll tell a security story about
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah, yeah. They're gonna do a whole security story about it.
Speaker 4:  This is No, I disagree. Okay. Yeah. And I,
Speaker 5:  Because you'll just see too much porn on the, the subway. No.
Speaker 4:  Although here two things. One, as I was riding the subway into work this
Speaker 4:  morning, a woman was watching a horror movie with full
Speaker 4:  speakers, no headphones. Oh, cool. And there was just a lot of deep breathing
Speaker 4:  and then screaming, just horror movie. And for
Speaker 4:  a while it was just deep breathing. So everyone was looking around the subway
Speaker 4:  car, incredible breach of subway etiquette all the way around.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, should I just give her my AirPods? Yeah. Like this might
Speaker 4:  be worth the 200 bucks right now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I honestly believe that If, you are listening to something on full speaker.
Speaker 6:  Everyone else within earshot is now firmly within their right
Speaker 6:  to come over and press pause or rewind or we're all watching this
Speaker 6:  together now. Like you
Speaker 4:  Just sit down next to the
Speaker 6:  Person. Yeah. We're all watching this together. And I can be like, co can
Speaker 6:  we just go back 10 minutes? I missed the part that was happening. You should
Speaker 6:  be able to sit down next to 'em and be like, we're watching this together.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Do the double tap to go back 10 seconds. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  Don't do that. But If, you do let us know how it goes.
Speaker 5:  Probably not.
Speaker 4:  Well, I'm guessing not. Well. Okay. That was a side note. Here
Speaker 4:  is why I think Apple won't just like, let porn happen. Okay.
Speaker 4:  There was nothing to watch the other night. And I I did it. I watched Argyle
Speaker 4:  welcome. It was bad. It was bad. It's real bad. Did his
Speaker 5:  Hair ever move? Did he ever fix his hair?
Speaker 4:  It's not, I don't want to say anything about this movie. What I wanna say
Speaker 4:  is, throughout the entire period that I was watching Argyle,
Speaker 4:  I was trying to imagine Tim Cook watching Argyle.
Speaker 5:  Is that just like, if Tim Cook wouldn't do this, it won't appear on the app
Speaker 5:  store.
Speaker 4:  I I think that is as good of a content understanding for Apple as
Speaker 4:  anything and you're like, this is about as far as as he's gonna go.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like he, he had to sit there
Speaker 4:  and then he had to tell Matthew Vaughan that that was a good movie. Mm. Right.
Speaker 4:  Like they, there was a, there was obviously a screening. This is a big Apple
Speaker 4:  movie from the Twisted Mind of Matthew Vaughn. Yeah. UA Lippa in
Speaker 4:  the thing. And then they all got up and the lights came on and in, you know,
Speaker 4:  apple Park and Tim was like,
Speaker 5:  Right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just, there's like a part of me that says like that there's a
Speaker 4:  boundary on Apple's behavior. And I don't know exactly what it is about
Speaker 4:  the image of Tim Cook watching Argyle. That makes me confident. The boundary
Speaker 4:  will never get to porn. Yeah. But If, you just sit there. I
Speaker 4:  don't watch Argo. I don't, I can't stress this enough. This is not a good
Speaker 4:  use of your time. No, it's awful. It is just not a good use of your time.
Speaker 4:  But If, you watch it and you imagine him cook watching it and being like,
Speaker 4:  this is what I paid for. Mm. Yeah. Then, then there's a part of your brain
Speaker 4:  that's like when the, the whatever Apple product marketing
Speaker 4:  manager comes to him and says, all right, here's how we're gonna solve for
Speaker 4:  the porn revenue. Yeah. Like that person will just like get Ed on site.
Speaker 4:  Like, he's like, my brain can't process this.
Speaker 5:  He's just got a little spring in his office that he
Speaker 4:  It's a beautiful Johnny. I, yeah. Liquid metal. Like,
Speaker 5:  It's gorgeous. It looks kinda like the Webby Award.
Speaker 4:  The design is obvious and it's minimalism, but it's just a box
Speaker 4:  on a spring. It's like, all right, that's enough. Talk about Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook and pornography in the same sort of mental space. We're sorry,
Speaker 4:  we're not David, you're, I know you're covering it. Are there more app stores
Speaker 4:  in the mix here?
Speaker 6:  I think so. So the, the first phase of this, there's been a
Speaker 6:  handful of folks saying it's coming, right? And a lot of it is gaming. Epic
Speaker 6:  has been loudly talking about doing this. The folks behind the, the
Speaker 6:  Set app thing, which is like a subscription to a bunch of Mac
Speaker 6:  apps. They've said they're working on some stuff. So I think we're gonna
Speaker 6:  get more of these and there's gonna be a set of them that are like very
Speaker 6:  professional and very legit and are sort of big businesses
Speaker 6:  unto themselves. And then there's just gonna be this crazy
Speaker 6:  minefield of new ideas. And I think those are gonna
Speaker 6:  take a while from what I can tell. It's like it's hard work to build one
Speaker 6:  of these things. And I think in Riley's case, he's been running alt
Speaker 6:  store for a while and so there were, there was a bunch of paperwork and stuff
Speaker 6:  to do to get this working. There was the, you have to get like a million
Speaker 6:  dollar line of credit or something to open one of these app stores. Cool.
Speaker 6:  But he was able to, from what I understand, jump through these hoops
Speaker 6:  relatively quickly if this is just a
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Because Tim Sweeney was like, here's a million dollar line of credit.
Speaker 4:  I need this to start happening
Speaker 6:  Basically. Right. And then if you're, if you're the, the MPA
Speaker 6:  folks who have been running set for a while, or you're epic, like you have
Speaker 6:  the resources to do this, but If, you wanna just spin up an app
Speaker 6:  store from nothing, it's actually pretty hard work. Yeah. And so I think
Speaker 6:  that my guess is like this fall and maybe even into
Speaker 6:  next year is when the like truly weird stuff is gonna start
Speaker 6:  to happen. But it is going to happen.
Speaker 4:  My question is, what is the next set of emulators? Like, just to stay focused
Speaker 4:  on emulators. Maybe Apple's not gonna allow Windows five.
Speaker 5:  It's T links 95.
Speaker 4:  It's definitely Ari Links, but like maybe Apple isn't gonna allow Windows
Speaker 4:  emulation in this app store at the gate. But you can see
Speaker 4:  maybe Alt store is gonna allow Windows 95 emulation and
Speaker 4:  we're all gonna be playing leisure suit Larry, on our iPads. Right. Like
Speaker 4:  it's interest. Yeah. You can see Commodore 64 mean is the Commodore
Speaker 4:  64 retro game console? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I guess it was. Yeah, it was. I believe there was one briefly on the
Speaker 5:  store.
Speaker 4:  There you go. I mean, oh yeah, that's right. What is the definition of a
Speaker 4:  retro game console? Right? We could do another half hour on the birch chest,
Speaker 4:  I'm confident, but as that starts to open and the library
Speaker 4:  of acceptable software starts to expand, which Apple has
Speaker 4:  never allowed, they've wanted everyone to stay inside of their user interface
Speaker 4:  and for good reason. I don't think these are bad things that Apple wanted.
Speaker 4:  Right. They didn't want a bunch of weird flash ports in the iPhone in the
Speaker 4:  beginning. They, they made very serious rules about how apps should look
Speaker 4:  and feel so that the user experience would be great. I think
Speaker 4:  that that the time limit on needing to do that has long since expired.
Speaker 4:  So now it's like, what, what else is gonna be allowed here? And you can see
Speaker 4:  that emulation of various kinds of other computers are gonna
Speaker 4:  very quickly open the door to floods of other cool software,
Speaker 4:  which all, most of which by the way won't be monetized by like weird micropayments
Speaker 4:  and hat. Yeah. 'cause it's just old software.
Speaker 5:  I'm curious, one that I think will be kind of interesting is Scum vm. So
Speaker 5:  Scum v Scum VM is a
Speaker 4:  Lot of, oh, what was that Game? Monkey Island.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Monkey Island Point and Click Games all made by Lucas Arts. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is now owned by Disney. And, and Scum VM is
Speaker 5:  kind of like independently maintained by other people. And I'm like, oh,
Speaker 5:  that's a really, that's one you always see anytime a system starts allowing
Speaker 5:  emulators, the PSP, the the Vita. Like
Speaker 5:  even the the Steam deck, that's one of the first ones you see. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  is it gonna, is it gonna pop up soon? Are we gonna get scu vm? Are we gonna
Speaker 5:  be able to play the dig in Monkey Island on this thing? Or is Disney gonna
Speaker 5:  come around and say, Hey,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we'll see. I'm look, I it's gonna be what? There's a part of me
Speaker 4:  that, the thing I'm looking forward to most is some sort of
Speaker 4:  retro windows or Mac emulator. Yeah. That just lets me run a
Speaker 4:  non-creative cloud version of Photoshop on an iPad.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  Close coming. That's coming, right? It's a, it's coming. Wes Davis, our weekend
Speaker 4:  editor post on Threads a video of him playing,
Speaker 5:  It was the Kirby, the Canvas Kirby game. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. On an iPad. The ds Yeah. For the Nintendo Ds. But he was playing it
Speaker 4:  with a stylus on iPad and it's like, that's better than any idea. And Apple's
Speaker 4:  had for an iPad game. Yeah. I was
Speaker 5:  Like, that's, that's cool as hell. I love that.
Speaker 4:  That's not great. I'm excited for it all Little chaos
Speaker 4:  is good for this market. Yeah. All right. I want you all to go, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  take a break. You all go Just watch the Argy trailer.
Speaker 6:  Don't, don't do that. Why would you tell people to do that? Go
Speaker 6:  do anything with your life other than watch the Argyle trailer.
Speaker 4:  I've never watched a movie where I've, I've like openly wished the Apple
Speaker 4:  TV had a two x button. I'm just like, because I can't
Speaker 4:  stop in the middle. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  You don't just like walk out of the room like, I'm just gonna go do laundry
Speaker 4:  Now. No, I gotta know what happened. It's just like a curse. This is why
Speaker 4:  I watch so
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. For me, it was the scene where she started ice skating.
Speaker 5:  Wait, who? Who I haven't seen it yet. No, this is spoilers. No,
Speaker 6:  We cannot do this. Listen, sometimes I would
Speaker 6:  say The Verge cast is known for long diversions down strange rabbit
Speaker 6:  holes. This is just like objective cruelty to our audience.
Speaker 4:  I'm just, you know that famous story where Tim Cook looks at his lieutenant
Speaker 4:  and he is like, why are you still here? Yeah. I literally imagined him standing
Speaker 4:  up in the Steve Jobs theater when that happened in the movie and being
Speaker 4:  like, why are you all still here?
Speaker 5:  Matthew Vaughn just crying, running, weeping from the room.
Speaker 4:  It's not good.
Speaker 4:  I have so much to say about how bad this movie is. I can't, all right,
Speaker 5:  That's, that's a, that's a Tuesday episode.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  No that, do that on decoder. Get that out. Here's a full,
Speaker 4:  We're gonna get Matthew Vaughn on decoder and be like, all right, so the
Speaker 4:  big reveal of
Speaker 6:  The smoothie. How do you make decisions? And let's change that.
Speaker 4:  Whew. All right.
Speaker 4:  All right. Speaking of decoder, oh, there's an org chart change of
Speaker 4:  Google. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That's a, that's that was a good segue. I love that.
Speaker 4:  I pulled that one off. I was rehearsing that one. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I loved that.
Speaker 4:  I looked in the mirror this morning, I'm like, we're gonna get this right
Speaker 4:  today. Just nail it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So Google, Google's getting a whole reorg, like, or it's not just Google,
Speaker 5:  it's Android, right? Because David, you, you actually spoke with Rick.
Speaker 5:  You, you got the whole the whole thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So the place to start is that Google is a famously
Speaker 6:  well run company with an org structure that makes sense to
Speaker 6:  everyone and is is structured in
Speaker 6:  order to make everyone produce good work. Are you right? We all agree on
Speaker 6:  that as sort of the premise Yeah. Of all of this. No, Google is just
Speaker 6:  abject chaos all the time. And this is like in large
Speaker 6:  part, deliberate like the, from the beginning Google's whole thing has been
Speaker 6:  like hire really good people and just sort of like turn them loose and it's
Speaker 6:  just like a loose construction of smart people who make things. And
Speaker 6:  that's fine as far as it goes. That's how you get Gmail, which was somebody's
Speaker 6:  20% project, 20 plus years ago. Now it's also
Speaker 6:  how you get 400,000 messaging apps and all of the weird
Speaker 6:  things that Google has built and killed over the years. But
Speaker 6:  basically the, the thing that I have come to understand over the last couple
Speaker 6:  of days of talking to people, including this new team at Google, which is
Speaker 6:  basically a combination of Google's hardware team,
Speaker 6:  which was run by Rick Oslow and its Android team,
Speaker 6:  which was run by roi, Lockheimer. roi, also ran
Speaker 6:  Chrome, Chrome os, Google Photos, Google One
Speaker 6:  and smattering of other stuff. But it basically oversaw like a lot of
Speaker 6:  the most popular platforms where people actually interact with Google
Speaker 6:  stuff. All of that is now being smooshed into one team under
Speaker 6:  Rick Oslo. It's called the Platforms and Devices team.
Speaker 6:  And the idea very much is to make all of that into
Speaker 6:  one team so that they can run faster with ai. Like the whole story
Speaker 6:  over and over is just ai. We have to do things faster.
Speaker 6:  We have to make our moves more quickly. We have to be able to pivot faster.
Speaker 6:  We have to be able to build new stuff faster. We need to have hardware, software,
Speaker 6:  and AI altogether. We need to have full stack everything like
Speaker 6:  Google. I think as we've seen over the last, what, 18 months
Speaker 6:  now, got caught sort of off guard by
Speaker 6:  the speed with which AI took over the world. Like Google built so much of
Speaker 6:  this foundational technology and yet didn't beat
Speaker 6:  chat. GPT to market like that is a failing of that company
Speaker 6:  and they are now racing to keep up. And I think sort of
Speaker 6:  smushing the hardware and software together, particularly on phones
Speaker 6:  is a, a pretty huge shift in trying to make that go faster.
Speaker 4:  So I have a number of questions here.
Speaker 4:  One, I think Google was initially, Alex is just laughing.
Speaker 5:  I'm just laughing. I was like the speed with your, I've got some questions.
Speaker 4:  I just Yeah, I'm reading this. I mean, it's an org chart. Yeah. I,
Speaker 4:  I have a number of ideas about this org chart change, but the core one is
Speaker 4:  what you just said, which is Google was caught off guard by t it's failing
Speaker 4:  the company. We're, it's, it's been a year now.
Speaker 4:  LLMs are not as good as people said they were gonna be. Like the humane,
Speaker 4:  like even If, you imagine a version of the Humane pin where
Speaker 4:  the hardware was perfect and it was fast. It's still like that's the wrong
Speaker 4:  bridge.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They, they just, there's no way for them to fix that problem. Right. And
Speaker 4:  we have not seen any meaningful improvements on
Speaker 4:  hallucination for any of these models really? So you're like, yeah, they
Speaker 4:  were caught off guard and then they were really worried that Google search
Speaker 4:  would go away. Satya Nadella is out there being like, I'm makeup
Speaker 4:  dance. I would, it is true that Google started
Speaker 4:  dancing. They, they
Speaker 5:  Did a little tippy tap dance,
Speaker 6:  But Sya Nadella didn't do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, right. It's like, but that wasn't, Bing has not been the
Speaker 4:  beneficiary of said dancing in any way, shape, or form. Nope. Google, I would
Speaker 4:  say dancing without rhyme or reason. Not a lot of
Speaker 4:  rhythm in the, the dancing happening in Mountain View. Agreed.
Speaker 4:  And so it's like if If you believe that that is the thing that set them into
Speaker 4:  action, that's the thing they're talking about. Like to what end,
Speaker 6:  I don't know if I'm being completely honest and I feel like this is the strange
Speaker 6:  moment we've come to in ai. Like you had Drew Houseton on
Speaker 6:  decoder this week, I think, and he repeated the line
Speaker 6:  that Sundar Phai and others have said that AI is as important as fire. Like
Speaker 6:  people just say that unironically, that that this is the
Speaker 6:  most important thing that has ever happened to society. Like literally that's
Speaker 6:  a thing people say out loud. And
Speaker 6:  is it like, is there any actual evidence of that so far?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I, I would say yeah, Liz,
Speaker 5:  Liz and I fire
Speaker 6:  Alex. Yeah. Fire also electricity. I would say there's ample evidence. It's
Speaker 6:  not crypto like I think, no, I
Speaker 5:  Think we're there. Yeah. I think, I think Liz and I have talked about this
Speaker 5:  a lot. She gets like weird 2:00 AM texts from me just being like, do you
Speaker 5:  think that like AI is the biggest thing since
Speaker 4:  If Liz Internet Liz is not responding to these texts with AI generator responses?
Speaker 4:  I don't know what we're
Speaker 5:  Doing here. No. She's always fully in the conversation with me.
Speaker 5:  It's really nice that she returns my calls. Thank you, Liz. But I, I do think
Speaker 5:  that like AI is artificial intelligence as a whole, not necessarily
Speaker 5:  just generative AI is a pretty big moment, right? Like, like
Speaker 5:  there's a form of automation that is, that is enormous and,
Speaker 5:  and it covers a whole lot of different industries. And that kind of big
Speaker 5:  C change is very rare. and it is as big as the internet. It is as big
Speaker 5:  as when we started automating, you know, machinery and stuff like that. Like
Speaker 5:  it's a big moment, but it happens in fits and spurts and,
Speaker 5:  and, and stuff. And right now we're kind of, in a moment,
Speaker 5:  it's a technical term,
Speaker 6:  Right? It's only obvious which things qualify in
Speaker 6:  retrospect, right? Like If, you, if you're running one of these companies,
Speaker 6:  you look at what the internet did 25 years ago and you look at what
Speaker 6:  Mobile did 15 years ago and you say, okay, a whole generation
Speaker 6:  of companies died at the hands of these changes and the world
Speaker 6:  changed because of these changes. Like If, you believe that AI is the next
Speaker 6:  one. You kind of have to bet everything right now,
Speaker 6:  even before it's ready because If you don't, you'll, you'll
Speaker 6:  get left behind by the companies that do. That's one
Speaker 6:  side of the bet. The other side of the bet is that at this moment
Speaker 6:  there is nothing about AI and chatbots
Speaker 6:  and this thing that is that important yet. And,
Speaker 6:  and, and so we're in this place where it's, it's still, I think the, like
Speaker 6:  we got that incredible pop of like Oh my God. I cannot believe this thing
Speaker 6:  is as good as it is when chat GPT launched. And there
Speaker 6:  has not been a moment that has surpassed that since then.
Speaker 6:  Maybe I'm wrong. I, I, I would be curious to know if there are folks who
Speaker 6:  feel like we've hit higher highs than that in terms of like,
Speaker 6:  remarkable achievements in ai, but to me it feels like we're still riding
Speaker 6:  that one single high. But If you believe that
Speaker 6:  it is going to be as big and fast and powerful as so many of these
Speaker 6:  people do. You don't have a choice but to bet everything on it, because otherwise
Speaker 6:  you're just dooming your self and your company and your employees to death.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And f fine. I I think all of the big
Speaker 4:  high point moments in AI since then, or at least the ones
Speaker 4:  that have like made the news broadly, like broken into mainstream news,
Speaker 4:  not just this show have been bad. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They've been failures. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  They've been failures.
Speaker 6:  They've been swaggy popes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like, you know, weird, weird woke
Speaker 4:  mind virus controversies. Like fake ones, like just like
Speaker 4:  all over the place. Like barred, just getting dates wrong all over the
Speaker 4:  like. Yeah. The thing that is notable about these systems right now is that
Speaker 4:  they don't know anything. Yep. Right. We're gonna talk about Meta's AI launch
Speaker 4:  this week. I generated a bunch of images of stuff and
Speaker 4:  it just like, doesn't know how clothes move. Yeah. Yeah. It's like, and it's
Speaker 4:  like, oh, this isn't that useful. And that's like,
Speaker 4:  so I just wanna stay there for one second. Like, you're making this bet
Speaker 4:  because you're like, we have to accelerate our, our AI moment.
Speaker 4:  It's still unclear like what that moment looks like in the end. And maybe
Speaker 4:  that the whole point is like, move faster, figure out what's right and what's
Speaker 4:  wrong. Oslo gave you the example of the Pixel camera.
Speaker 4:  Okay, I get it.
Speaker 5:  But they've been doing AI stuff with the Pixel camera
Speaker 4:  For a long, but this is his example. Yeah. And he is like, we're gonna do
Speaker 4:  that, but faster. It,
Speaker 5:  It felt a little to me, and, and David maybe correct me if I'm wrong, it
Speaker 5:  felt a little like Silicon Valley in particular is very hyped on
Speaker 5:  ai, right? Like, like there the conversation is what are you doing with ai?
Speaker 5:  If you're not doing something, you're stupid. And a lot of this felt like
Speaker 5:  almost an response to those people being like, yes, we also care about
Speaker 5:  ai. We're at the big, we're we're big. This is our performative moment to
Speaker 5:  tell you that we genuinely believe in this.
Speaker 5:  But it was really for that audience, not necessarily
Speaker 5:  for the,
Speaker 6:  I think that's half right. Like, I think that's exactly right. I think the
Speaker 6:  other audience is investors, right? Yeah. To right now, If, you
Speaker 6:  want to continue to run the company that you run. You have to tell an
Speaker 6:  AI story. You just do. Like, that's, that is where we are. It's,
Speaker 6:  it's what everybody was doing with Mobile 10 years ago
Speaker 6:  is like, If, you didn't have a mobile strategy. What are you doing now?
Speaker 6:  That that thing is ai, right? Like it's, mark Zuckerberg is the perfect example
Speaker 6:  of this. Like, mark doesn't talk about the Metaverse anymore 'cause nobody
Speaker 6:  wants to hear about the Metaverse and they sell shares in Meta when they
Speaker 6:  do. And so now they're telling an AI story and in a lot of ways, the
Speaker 6:  AI story and the Metaverse story actually run together. But they talk about
Speaker 6:  it differently because that is how you win. And you get people excited and
Speaker 6:  you convince them that you are marching towards something huge. So I think
Speaker 6:  you're right. They're, they're telling that sort of same story to two audiences,
Speaker 6:  because without them, they don't have the runway and talent they need to
Speaker 6:  get there at all.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So this was, but the first question,
Speaker 5:  Okay, sorry.
Speaker 4:  Is this the right goal, right? Yes. That's just the first one. And I think
Speaker 4:  the answer is probably yes. Like you have, it has to be the right answer.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We have to show movement towards this goal. We have to unify
Speaker 4:  Google's famously messy teams, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Google
Speaker 4:  now has Google DeepMind, which itself is a merger of Google
Speaker 4:  Brain and DeepMind, the CEO of that
Speaker 4:  Saba, who's been on decoder. And I asked him, how will this merger work?
Speaker 4:  And he is like, it'll be fine. Recently suddenly comments
Speaker 4:  suggesting he's not so happy with it. So, right. So now you've got
Speaker 4:  Google Research in DeepMind. We'll see how that's going.
Speaker 4:  And then you've got this new group, which
Speaker 4:  you know it from a thousand yards. If, you squint and you're hammered is
Speaker 4:  like, oh, this is, they're doing an Apple. Yeah. They're doing hardware and
Speaker 4:  software and services all under one roof to make better
Speaker 4:  complete products. They're
Speaker 5:  Gonna vertically integrate everything. Right? When the FTC is like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  stop
Speaker 6:  That. That's perfect tactic.
Speaker 4:  I mean, you do have to be hammered Yeah. To, to make that claim. Like, I
Speaker 4:  don't, but you see it, right? It's like If, you squint, you're like, oh,
Speaker 4:  okay. Then they'll do all the products over here.
Speaker 4:  They still have a Samsung to deal with. Like if Google's like, now the Pixel
Speaker 4:  rules, 'cause we made the software custom for the Pixel. Do you want some
Speaker 4:  of this Samsung also? You just announced a bunch of our AI stuff in your
Speaker 4:  phones. How are they gonna manage that?
Speaker 6:  Google is very sensitive to this question. I raised this
Speaker 6:  question to Rick and Hiroshi and the, their response was essentially,
Speaker 6:  no, you're wrong. Everything is fine. The partners love us. Don't even worry
Speaker 6:  about it. I'm paraphrasing, but only, only Justin.
Speaker 6:  But I think,
Speaker 4:  I mean they gave you a quote from the CEO EO of Qualcomm for this story just
Speaker 4:  to be like, see that's like, dude, he sells ships to every, like he doesn't
Speaker 4:  care. That's right.
Speaker 6:  That's right.
Speaker 4:  Christian Haman does not care if Google and Samsung are beefing as long as
Speaker 4:  everyone's on phones. Yeah. He's good. It's
Speaker 5:  All about the power of Snapdragon.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think there, there are two things going on here. One,
Speaker 6:  I think there's an interesting thing here to
Speaker 6:  compare what Google is doing to actually what Patos Pinene did at Microsoft,
Speaker 6:  which is he was running Surface and then he was running Surface and Windows.
Speaker 6:  And the way that they came to see it was actually what we need to do is we
Speaker 6:  need to make the best Windows PCs and then give what
Speaker 6:  we make back to the ecosystem. So like the Surface team
Speaker 6:  actually pioneered a lot of things that really worked well on Windows. They
Speaker 6:  did a lot of work on the handwriting stuff. They did a lot of work on Detachables
Speaker 6:  and then essentially gave that back to partners who were then able to make
Speaker 6:  better Windows PCs as a result.
Speaker 4:  Can I tell you a story about that? Sure. I feel like I can tell the story
Speaker 4:  'cause it doesn't work there anymore. Okay. So one of my favorite CS moments,
Speaker 4:  I'm walking around a Microsoft booth with Enos and we're
Speaker 4:  we're talking about that exact concept. What, why do you make these things?
Speaker 4:  'cause the surface machines were there and the partner machines were there.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, this has gotta be weird. For You. And he was like, no, no,
Speaker 4:  no. Lemme show you something. Anos was like, no, no. Lemme show you something.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And he is like, that's my hinge. Mm. And he
Speaker 4:  was appointing at one of the partner machines. He's like, we, that's our
Speaker 4:  hinge and that's my displayed blah, blah, blah. Like, he
Speaker 4:  was like, this is all our stuff. And like what we're doing, like we are just
Speaker 4:  spending the money to innovate because the e none of these OEMs can out spend
Speaker 4:  Apple. So this is worth it to us. And I asked
Speaker 4:  him for years to give me that story like in a printable way. But
Speaker 4:  obviously none of the partners are gonna be like, that's upon us' Engine.
Speaker 4:  Right? Right.
Speaker 6:  But I think there's something to that, right? And If, you are the company
Speaker 6:  with the resources to feed the ecosystem. You can kind of
Speaker 6:  rising tide, lift all boats that situation. And if you're Google and
Speaker 6:  what you need is for AI to win broadly and for Gemini to
Speaker 6:  win, specifically doing that work on the
Speaker 6:  Pixel and then giving it to Samsung theoretically works for
Speaker 6:  everybody. I I say theoretically because I think Samsung
Speaker 6:  has a long history of not being psyched about Google's
Speaker 6:  situation internally Anyway. Ties in, I guess still
Speaker 6:  exists. I would not bet Samsung is thrilled with this change
Speaker 6:  at Google. But I, I do buy the theory that if Google manages
Speaker 6:  this correctly, it could, it could pull Android
Speaker 6:  AI as a whole along with it.
Speaker 5:  Well, and and you're talking about phones. We've been talking about phones
Speaker 5:  mainly. But it's not just gonna be the phones, right? Like it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  in the TVs and the watches and all the other places too, where Samsung
Speaker 5:  doesn't have as big a, a sharehold. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like Samsung TVs, they sell a lot of TVs mainly to Neli,
Speaker 5:  but no
Speaker 6:  Ties in Baby.
Speaker 4:  I love it. But Oh, that's a good sound. The actually the ties in startup
Speaker 4:  sound on the tv do, do, do. It is like, ooh,
Speaker 6:  Just sounds episode,
Speaker 4:  Episode four.
Speaker 5:  But, but there is all this other stuff. And, and in those cases, like
Speaker 5:  yes, this makes a lot of sense, right? Like Android, okay,
Speaker 4:  Let Android give you the counter example.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Let me just before you go off into Android tv 'cause there's nothing I want
Speaker 4:  to talk about, more about the raging success of Android tv.
Speaker 5:  It's all you think about. I know
Speaker 4:  Google bought Motorola famously.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And Andy Rubin, the founder of Android,
Speaker 4:  who worked at Google at that time, was, it is another CS story. He was walking
Speaker 4:  around Cs and he saw how hard Samsung was skinning Android
Speaker 4:  got furious, locked into a battle with Samsung
Speaker 4:  to bring them back into the fold and ruin Android less. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Touch whiz.
Speaker 4:  And the deal was Google had to sell Motorola
Speaker 4:  to Lenovo. That's what, that was the concession that Samsung
Speaker 4:  extracted to stop it.
Speaker 4:  Like it wasn't because I yelled at them about making bloop bloop sounds and
Speaker 4:  having, making everyone go to the bathroom because of touch whiz. It
Speaker 4:  was because Andy Rubin was like, what are you doing? Yeah, I will sell Motorola
Speaker 4:  and stop competing with you directly. If, you real touch whiz Beckon. That's
Speaker 4:  a lot. Right? And many things have happened since then. We've now,
Speaker 4:  it's called one ui. Like what? It's all different now. Google since then
Speaker 4:  bought the failing HTC turned that into whatever pixels we have now.
Speaker 4:  Like the relationships are different. It seems like the tensions
Speaker 4:  are different, but there is actually history of
Speaker 4:  Samsung being so irritated that Google would compete with it head up
Speaker 4:  by buying Motorola, that it started peeling people off and
Speaker 4:  Google had to make the big concession. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But at the same time, touch was sucked.
Speaker 5:  Like it was hurting Samsung, wasn't it?
Speaker 4:  You know, many people,
Speaker 5:  It was hurting me to look at it. So I just assumed
Speaker 4:  Famously someone has called this show and insisted that ladies love The Wiz.
Speaker 4:  This is a real thing that has happened on this show before. I forgot about
Speaker 4:  that. Big Papa Joe baby. We'll run the clip. We'll, we'll put the clip in
Speaker 4:  the, in the show notes. That's a real thing that has happened. Yeah. We've
Speaker 4:  been doing this show for a very long time. Yes. I don't know if
Speaker 4:  people like touch with or not. I dunno if that was a good idea. I'm just
Speaker 4:  saying that tension was there. Yeah. And part of the reason Tieszen exists
Speaker 4:  is because Samsung wanted its own operating system.
Speaker 4:  It does not want to, it wants to be in control of its future. Right.
Speaker 4:  and it has this massive dependency on Google and phones. and it did
Speaker 4:  not want that in TVs it anywhere else. It doesn't want these dependencies
Speaker 4:  where I I'm just saying, you look at this and you're like, oh, they're, you're,
Speaker 4:  you know, you do your drunk thousand yard squint Yeah. At
Speaker 4:  this org chart change. You're like, oh, they're, they're gonna walking right
Speaker 4:  back into it.
Speaker 5:  I call that the 2:00 AM Liz Text
Speaker 4:  Squint.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I think that's right. I guess I think that the thing that is
Speaker 6:  different from 10 years ago is like, where are you gonna go? Like Samsung
Speaker 6:  knows ties in is not a move at this point.
Speaker 6:  There's just no, there's no option outside of Android
Speaker 6:  If. you are a smartphone manufacturer. Samsung, if it made
Speaker 6:  Android worse or tried to go the the A OSP route and
Speaker 6:  build their own apps like it, it didn't work last time and it super wouldn't
Speaker 6:  work this time. Yeah. And the other side is If, you believe
Speaker 6:  that AI is the thing you need Google more than ever
Speaker 6:  because like Samsung has been way out in front of
Speaker 6:  promoting Gemini, it's getting a lot of these Gemini features ahead of pixels
Speaker 6:  in some cases. Like, I, I think if, if You believe in the AI
Speaker 6:  revolution, Samsung is actually sort of forced to increase its
Speaker 6:  dependency on Google, not try to get away from it.
Speaker 5:  I mean, what if they end up going with like Harmony os or whatever Huawei's
Speaker 5:  operating system is on, right? Like,
Speaker 6:  How's that, how's that going for, for them in the us?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Not great, but you like, I don't know. I I, I think I don't
Speaker 5:  wanna just immediately say they're, they're totally locked into Android.
Speaker 5:  Although they, they very much are. I think there is like options available
Speaker 5:  to them, especially as we have this,
Speaker 6:  I say this in all sincerity. Make me a list of those options. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's Harmony os they're just gonna go all in on the Chinese market.
Speaker 4:  This is why you need middleware and super apps.
Speaker 5:  You got us there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It was coming inevitably. Yeah. All right. I I'm exci
Speaker 4:  I'm hopeful for a more focused faster Google. That's what Rick
Speaker 4:  is saying he wants to do. He wants to move everything faster. He wants to
Speaker 4:  shit more things. I, I think the best thing Google could do would to
Speaker 4:  kill even more products actually right now, just do remember reduce the number
Speaker 4:  of Google products by half and then loudly announced that it will just keep
Speaker 4:  iterating those products for five years. That'd be cool. That would be a
Speaker 4:  huge change.
Speaker 6:  Do you remember in like 2011 when Larry Page came back as CEO and
Speaker 6:  he did, I think it was on an investor call,
Speaker 6:  said the, he gave the whole like more wood behind fewer arrows speech. And
Speaker 6:  then Google promptly killed a whole bunch of stuff that it had been working
Speaker 6:  on. Like this is just the Google cycle, right? They're like, they
Speaker 6:  realize, oh, we're not making enough money and or the world is changing.
Speaker 6:  The first time it was about Google Plus was like, we're gonna reorient everything
Speaker 6:  around social, which went super great and that's why we all use Google Plus
Speaker 6:  now. It's just the same thing again, right? Like Google sort of lets, its
Speaker 6:  company sprawl lets everything get weird hires, lots of people builds a million
Speaker 6:  messaging apps. And then at some point you go, oh, this is actually making
Speaker 6:  us interesting, but it's making us slow and we have to all point in one
Speaker 6:  direction now. And that's what you do when you have to point in one direction.
Speaker 6:  And for Google that one direction is very much ai. Like, they made a couple
Speaker 6:  of other little org changes today as part of this
Speaker 6:  announcement at DeepMind in Google research and elsewhere. And like Sundar
Speaker 6:  Phai in particular is very clear that the message is like, move faster and
Speaker 6:  move towards ai. Like that is Google's job for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 6:  Will it work?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Because Google is a famously well run company with a culture and structure.
Speaker 6:  That makes total sense.
Speaker 4:  All right, well Google IO is coming up next month. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's right. Yep.
Speaker 4:  And I anticipate we will, I we end up talking to all of these folks at IO
Speaker 4:  every year. So we, we will just see how it's going. We're like one month
Speaker 4:  in, did it work?
Speaker 5:  Just stare really hard. And
Speaker 6:  Then AI sued our phai. We'll say, yes it did. And then that'll be it all.
Speaker 4:  You know, I, we have Meta is competing with chat JPT on our list.
Speaker 4:  Here they are. They announced AI products. It's, they're everywhere. You
Speaker 4:  can chat with a Meta AI on literally any Meta surface. You can think of
Speaker 4:  Instagram, WhatsApp for some reason. Have you done
Speaker 5:  That?
Speaker 4:  No. I, I have gone directly to Meta dot ai. Oh. And only
Speaker 4:  asked to produce images of Jesus made of spaghetti.
Speaker 4:  The
Speaker 6:  True correct use.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Which it won't do it, it will not produce any
Speaker 4:  religious iconography. If, you ask it to produce images of a Middle Eastern
Speaker 4:  man from ancient times made of spaghetti. It will happily do that.
Speaker 6:  Oh, but it's not Jesus per se.
Speaker 4:  I, you know, you can, it's
Speaker 5:  Open to interpretation.
Speaker 4:  You can get to a, a state, you can prompt
Speaker 4:  engineer your way into something that I believe is, we can
Speaker 6:  Look more jesusy.
Speaker 4:  So the reason I, I mentioned this just to point out, this has been going
Speaker 4:  on for months now. Crazy AI generated images are
Speaker 4:  constantly going viral on Facebook. The last one, I think
Speaker 4:  our friends at Hard Fork covered it. Jesus is a crab,
Speaker 4:  just like hundreds of thousands of likes. Was there a shrimp?
Speaker 4:  There's crab and shrimp. Oh, there's crab and
Speaker 6:  And shrimp. Oh, I got deep into shrimp. Jesus. I totally miss crab. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think hard fork was shrimp. Jesus. But there's also, you know, cartonization
Speaker 4:  is like a real phenomenon and evolution where everything turns into a crab.
Speaker 4:  and it has been true of AI generated Jesus as well
Speaker 4:  on these platforms. And then the one that just killed me,
Speaker 4:  it's a quick post on this. I wrote it, you can go into it. The images
Speaker 4:  of Jesus made of spaghetti on the Lambo also made of spaghetti.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God. It was so good.
Speaker 4:  The last one I saw had 36,000 likes. Oh my God. It's
Speaker 4:  very good. And I, you know, if Meta is gonna release AI tools, we gotta see
Speaker 4:  if we can just close the loop. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And the, the answer is no, actually that spaghetti Jesus on a
Speaker 4:  Lambo is not nearly as good as the ones that are currently on Meta other
Speaker 4:  platforms. So whatever tool the spams are using a little bit
Speaker 4:  ahead of Meta's tools currently. I like
Speaker 6:  That. That's, that's good for them. Meta some work to do. Meta should always
Speaker 6:  be a little bit behind its own users. That feels right. I do think it's interesting
Speaker 6:  though that part of this also Meta released Lama three, which is the new
Speaker 6:  version of its own LLM. and it seems
Speaker 6:  in a very real way, like we have a pretty strong
Speaker 6:  sort of four party race right now between Claude from Anthropic,
Speaker 6:  GPT, whatever, Gemini, and now Llama
Speaker 6:  to be like the model. We're in this space where
Speaker 6:  it's like, it feels like computer chips from a million years ago when like
Speaker 6:  every subsequent one that comes out every two weeks is like a little bit
Speaker 6:  faster and just the, the sort of speed and success
Speaker 6:  is going up really fast. But these four companies are all like deep in it.
Speaker 6:  They have a ton of money, they're very invested. and it is, it is kind of
Speaker 6:  happening really fast.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Although I don't know that it's quite like computer chips and
Speaker 4:  that they are all bad in different
Speaker 4:  ways. Fair. Right. Like as chatbots, Molly White,
Speaker 4:  who writes Web3 is going just scrape. She just had a newsletter that she's
Speaker 4:  like, I'm kind of interested in this. Like I, I'm more positive around the
Speaker 4:  people think given how she feels or cryptocurrency will link to the newsletter
Speaker 4:  as well. But she's like, I asked it to write this newsletter and she has
Speaker 4:  all the results of all the four. And she's like, the thing about them is
Speaker 4:  I told it to write like me. and it just is scolding you. Like they, they
Speaker 4:  write like angry school teachers I think was her phrase. And it's like, that's
Speaker 4:  the thing. Like it, they can generate
Speaker 4:  copy.
Speaker 4:  Is there a reliable way for anyone to say whether the copy
Speaker 4:  is generated is getting better or worse even within a single model?
Speaker 4:  Or,
Speaker 5:  I mean, is it between them as a critic and an editor? Yes,
Speaker 5:  but don don't wanna read it all.
Speaker 4:  But you look at like four columns of like middling work and you're like,
Speaker 4:  aren't I gonna rank these? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're
Speaker 4:  All garbage. All of you get D minuses. Like get outta here.
Speaker 6:  Well, in that way it's actually kind of an interesting parallel to the computer
Speaker 6:  chips thing because we're in the, we're in the phase where they're all passing
Speaker 6:  benchmark tests with increasingly impressive scores that don't mean much
Speaker 6:  to real people yet. Yeah. And the question is like, is anyone
Speaker 6:  actually going to make real use of the sort of raw capability of this stuff
Speaker 6:  that means anything to anybody? And so far I, the answer
Speaker 6:  is largely not really. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But I do think one interesting piece of the Meta puzzle at
Speaker 4:  least is it has massive distribution and is 0% afraid of
Speaker 4:  using it. Yeah. Yep. Like If, you use a Meta product. Boy
Speaker 4:  is there AI next to you now it's just happening. It's just here it is.
Speaker 4:  Just talking to you. Am Meta's AI showed up in a Facebook group for people
Speaker 4:  with gifted and disabled children made up a child It had and said it was
Speaker 4:  very happy in the New York City public schools. Oh no. Yeah. That's
Speaker 4:  just a thing. And someone said, is this Black Mirror and AI responded? No,
Speaker 4:  it's not. It's just me. Meta ai That's a, it was like a story
Speaker 4:  in 4 0 4, which we also link many links. Links to everyone. I'm
Speaker 4:  just saying the most notable stuff about this air. And I was like, when it's
Speaker 4:  going it's a little sideways. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, I mean they've, they've gotten really, really good at making machines
Speaker 5:  that are impressive at confidently lying.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that's
Speaker 4:  The goal. I mean, they've always been the goal. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  Just go put a little suit on it and have it run for office. Like it's got
Speaker 5:  it down
Speaker 4:  Finally. Yeah. Finally a president. I can get you behind. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Llama three.
Speaker 4:  It's like, I'm shrimp. Jesus.
Speaker 4:  I'm proud to be an American.
Speaker 4:  That's enough. AI talk. Let's talk about the real thing.
Speaker 4:  Mini LED televisions.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we got the tv.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's been heavy man. Sorry David. Policy updates. There's been
Speaker 4:  Europeans AI stands for awesome interpolation.
Speaker 4:  All right. So Sony, this is like the most important story of the year.
Speaker 5:  I'm with you for now. Until next week.
Speaker 4:  I'm telling you there's a revolution in TVs happening.
Speaker 4:  Just lock in.
Speaker 5:  All the TV makers are like Neil. I gets it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because I do. So at CSS last year we saw
Speaker 4:  a bunch of mini led D televisions. I confidently predicted that many LEDs
Speaker 4:  would bring prices down and people would start buying bigger TVs.
Speaker 4:  There's a little bit of data's worth, there's a little bit of data about
Speaker 4:  some other thing that I'll talk about in a second. Sony has started skipping
Speaker 4:  cs. They've done it for years. They announced their TVs this year. Sony
Speaker 4:  slowly pulling back for mullets, which is really
Speaker 4:  interesting. So the oled, I have the A 95 L
Speaker 4:  QD OLED ola, very bright, very colorful. They're just
Speaker 4:  sticking around. No updates to the flagship OLED in the SO line.
Speaker 5:  Wow.
Speaker 4:  All of the flagship TVs are mini LED TVs. They're the
Speaker 4:  bravia nines.
Speaker 4:  Sony won't tell you how many backlight zones they have. They'll just tell
Speaker 4:  you increasing percentages. Incredible chart. They're just like
Speaker 4:  325% and more dimming zones.
Speaker 5:  Just more,
Speaker 4:  Just more.
Speaker 5:  Don't worry about it. It's just a lot.
Speaker 4:  So I've seen, and that's three 25% more than last year's X 95 L which
Speaker 4:  I've seen, which is a beautiful TV that only if you're paying attention to,
Speaker 4:  do you see any blooming? Now it's brighter. There's
Speaker 4:  325% more zones. I'm anticipating that there will be no
Speaker 4:  blooming or it'll be even harder to see. Which means you can now
Speaker 4:  get gigantic super bright
Speaker 4:  LED bright TV with the black levels of OLED without the burning
Speaker 4:  problems.
Speaker 5:  How much is that
Speaker 4:  Cost? And, and it's better for gaming 'cause it's faster refresh of
Speaker 4:  LEDs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, i, I totally am all for that. and it was someone with a
Speaker 5:  2017 oled. Really? You cannot understand how much I'm
Speaker 5:  all for that. Oh,
Speaker 4:  It's also 50% brighter than the X 95. I'm just telling you. But how
Speaker 5:  Much is it?
Speaker 4:  They're not, they're not like a, a number. That's good.
Speaker 6:  No ne Neil tell the people, tell the people what is the cheapest one of
Speaker 6:  these cost?
Speaker 4:  The the 65 inch is 32 9 9, which is
Speaker 4:  not outta whack with top end OLEDs. Let's top
Speaker 6:  End. Let's, let's just, can I just say that? Can I just say that price number
Speaker 6:  slightly differently? Yeah. It costs
Speaker 6:  $3,299 and 99 cents.
Speaker 4:  If you're like sitting there,
Speaker 6:  32 99 is like, oh, 33 bucks. That's what a normal
Speaker 6:  TV costs now. No,
Speaker 4:  No. You're gonna have to stay on the wall for 10 years. If you're out there
Speaker 4:  cross shopping an LG G three, you're like, oh, that's interesting.
Speaker 4:  That's all I'm saying. Yeah. You're
Speaker 6:  Gonna have it on your wall for two years and then Neli Patel is gonna come
Speaker 6:  on The Vergecast in 2025 and say, listen everybody, there's
Speaker 6:  another 325% increase. Well,
Speaker 4:  So here's the problem. So the A 95 only goes up to 77 inches and
Speaker 4:  the top end braa nines are 85 inches.
Speaker 5:  That's so much tv,
Speaker 4:  Which is $5,499. I just bought this TV last
Speaker 4:  September. Like, what am I doing? It's a, this is bad.
Speaker 4:  Like I have to send her to college. Right. you know, like that's gonna be
Speaker 4:  a couple days of college by the time she's ready to go to college.
Speaker 6:  That's like some textbooks.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. A single textbook. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You get 24 hours in the storm kid. I bought a new tv.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying these TVs represent a huge
Speaker 4:  shift from Ed in this market. Yeah. This
Speaker 4:  is when it's starting to happen. And that, I think that means the rest of
Speaker 4:  the TVs are gonna get cheaper. Like these are the crazy top ends that are
Speaker 4:  supposed to compete with the high end eds. They have insane features. They,
Speaker 4:  we've we're so far from the motion smoothing debate. Generally
Speaker 4:  like regular, you know, regular people TVs, you still have to turn off motion
Speaker 4:  smoothing at the high end of the market. Now the TVs have built
Speaker 4:  in calibrated modes for the services where the services can calibrate
Speaker 4:  your TV for whatever they're streaming. So Prime video
Speaker 4:  calibrated on the new Sony Bravia Nines will know if
Speaker 4:  you're watching a movie or you're watching Monday Night Football and recalibrate
Speaker 4:  the tv For You automatically.
Speaker 5:  But that'll only work.
Speaker 4:  If. you
Speaker 5:  Use use this the smart TV function they have. Oh,
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be not talk with the details.
Speaker 4:  If. you wanna run Bravia core and stream at 80 megabits per second. You gotta
Speaker 6:  Look so tight.
Speaker 5:  You gotta, you gotta make some sacrifices.
Speaker 4:  By the way, there's some debate in the comments of Chris Welch's story about
Speaker 4:  this, about whether it's called Bravia Core or Sony Pictures core.
Speaker 4:  I just, lemme just clear it up. It's only a Bravia core and Bravia TVs
Speaker 4:  were the only place the platform supports 80 megabits per
Speaker 4:  second Purestream. Everywhere else it's Sony picture score and it doesn't
Speaker 4:  have the one feature. That's good. Mm.
Speaker 6:  So Sony Pictures is the bad one.
Speaker 4:  Sony picture score is like, what if we made a not good streaming service
Speaker 4:  with a small cat? Like what if we made a streaming service where you opened
Speaker 4:  it and it was like, Mme. Webb is the thing. We got this
Speaker 5:  Just you turn it off.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I just didn't, I didn't redeem my credits for Madam Web.
Speaker 6:  No, I will say Sony does a thing that I appreciate, which is they
Speaker 6:  just, they make the TV that is just the
Speaker 6:  DOPE TV and they're like, whatever it costs no problem. But like
Speaker 6:  this 5,501 is enormous. It has, what was it called? Like
Speaker 6:  X wide angle for the viewing angle stuff. It has amazing
Speaker 6:  speakers. It's like I just, Sony does the thing that I like where they're
Speaker 6:  like, here is the luxury version and we are just going to slowly make that
Speaker 6:  one cheaper over time. And someday in
Speaker 6:  2061, I will own this exact TV in my house
Speaker 6:  and I can't look, I can't,
Speaker 4:  It's gonna take a long time. So the, the, that's the Brav nine, the top
Speaker 4:  ends. So the flagship Sony TVs this year are mini LEDs and
Speaker 4:  my A 95, which we'll just soldier on. Yeah. Well,
Speaker 5:  I mean that, that's good though because you don't have, do you have regret
Speaker 5:  buying it? Do you have the fomo?
Speaker 4:  I don't want to say it this time
Speaker 4:  then the, the one step down, the brav eights are regular
Speaker 4:  OLEDs, not the cutie OLEDs that I have in the A 95. They've got all the same
Speaker 4:  stuff. But you can just see Sony is like their biggest
Speaker 4:  best. Their push is many LEDs. I think the resting industry will follow them.
Speaker 4:  Then there's actually cheaper many LED D TVs. They don't have all the stuff.
Speaker 5:  I think you use cheaper generously here.
Speaker 6:  It's a very relative term,
Speaker 4:  $2,300 for a 65 inch man set is like,
Speaker 4:  that is as good as the X 95 is dead on competitive with an ola. Do
Speaker 4:  you with a high end Ola? I
Speaker 5:  Think I, I need to just one in my house next to my 2017
Speaker 5:  Ola to see which is better. I gotta like get 'em next to each other. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And see if it's truly better.
Speaker 4:  All right. So I will end my, I know gushing over Sony television, which I
Speaker 4:  haven't seen. I don't know, I don't know if these are as good as I want them
Speaker 4:  to be. I don't know what 325% more dimming zones mean. I don't know if these
Speaker 4:  auto calibrated modes that require to use their weird software that
Speaker 4:  basically tries to like ransom you into enabling samba
Speaker 4:  interactive tv, which washes your every move like a hawk
Speaker 4:  to sell it to some snarling data. Bro, I, I don't know. All right. That's
Speaker 4:  all just there. I'm just saying picture quality wise, you can see what's
Speaker 4:  happening in this market. Yeah. Next to that is the fucking Frame
Speaker 4:  tv, which is like dominating the charts. And I just
Speaker 4:  wanna tell this story about the rudest text. You can sell, send me po the
Speaker 4:  rudest text I've ever received. And I feel comfortable saying this 'cause
Speaker 4:  I posted about it and Casey revealed himself.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So ca you know, Casey and I are friends. Casey, you can tell by the tone
Speaker 4:  of my voice.
Speaker 4:  And so, you know, he just got a new house. He's like, everyone's excited.
Speaker 4:  Everyone's buying stuff. I just got a new house and he is like, should I
Speaker 4:  buy a Frame tv? And he sent me this text at 1230 in the morning. Oh my. And
Speaker 4:  I, he's on the West Coast. On the East coast. And I I I believe this conversation
Speaker 4:  took another full hour. Like, I was like, I can't let this go. Something's
Speaker 4:  wrong on the internet. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You, you like, you couldn't sleep that night until you get that done.
Speaker 4:  I tried so hard to, to make this man buy an LGGI was like, you play video
Speaker 4:  games.
Speaker 4:  You do you like quality. What,
Speaker 5:  What? Why did he want the frame?
Speaker 4:  Because in the end it was revealed that all of the
Speaker 4:  people, he was asking own frame TVs, including me.
Speaker 4:  I own two. I mean, one's just in the studio, in the podcast studio in my
Speaker 4:  house. It just shows the decoder logo. That's all it does. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it is, and it does have a beautiful bezel.
Speaker 4:  It was, yeah. It yeah, it, it, sure,
Speaker 5:  Sure. I'm trying to help you here Neil. I'm trying, I'm trying.
Speaker 4:  I'm saying the Frame TV is like a 10-year-old LCD panel with a single backlight
Speaker 4:  No dimming zones. It's just a bad tv. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But people like it because this the display is Matt at
Speaker 4:  and most people don't actually watch their TVs anymore. They watch TikTok
Speaker 6:  Neli. Can I, can I float a theory at you that maybe
Speaker 6:  people don't care about 325% more dimming zones
Speaker 6:  anymore? Is it, is it possible they
Speaker 4:  Don't care about TVs anymore? I think the Frame TV is the, the Harbinger
Speaker 4:  of Doom. What's the problem? What, what is the thing all streaming services
Speaker 4:  are facing? People are saying, okay, there's gonna be a big black rectangle
Speaker 4:  in my house. I want it to look best when it's off. 'cause it's mostly off.
Speaker 5:  Wait, I just realized the Sony TV is basically like
Speaker 5:  a cool gaming PC to the, the
Speaker 5:  Frames iMac.
Speaker 4:  I've never, I don't think I've ever wanted to melt as much as I currently
Speaker 4:  wish to melt.
Speaker 5:  You have so many iMac in your house. Neli
Speaker 6:  Neli. This is why it just sounds is gonna be a huge hit on your place because
Speaker 6:  nobody watches their TV anyway. I was, it just sound while you look at TikTok,
Speaker 6:  it's
Speaker 4:  Gonna be incredible. I, but I'm saying like, I think I keep making this joke
Speaker 4:  that I could write 10,000 words about the Frame tv. It definitely could.
Speaker 4:  Maybe I just need to like rant into a camera for an hour. We can
Speaker 4:  edit it together. Yeah. But all I'm saying is you look at the market, you
Speaker 4:  look at the, the quality of TVs that are coming. Right? There's a technology
Speaker 4:  shift in the TV industry underway right now with these many identities. I
Speaker 4:  think they're gonna be really cool. And then you look at what people are
Speaker 4:  spending the money on, like what people think the best TV on the market is.
Speaker 4:  What's still priced? Ex you we're worried about these prices. Go look at
Speaker 4:  the frame when it's not on sale. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  Insane. You're buying a 20 16,
Speaker 4:  20 17 vintage, you know, edge Lit l Ct p like it's
Speaker 4:  bad. And they're charging the prices of an OLED because the display is Matt
Speaker 4:  and you can pay 50 bucks for
Speaker 4:  the art store. And people are like, that's the best TV you can buy.
Speaker 5:  And that's why Samsung will stick with Android ties
Speaker 5:  on the phone. Oh, on the phone. It's all comes back to the phone in
Speaker 5:  Android.
Speaker 4:  Why is that?
Speaker 5:  I just
Speaker 4:  Forgot because the ties and App store is killing it on the
Speaker 5:  Frame. It was a bad joke. Keep going.
Speaker 4:  Okay. We'll just cut that part anyway. I'm just saying it's like, just keep
Speaker 4:  ranting about this forever. Forever and ever and ever.
Speaker 5:  I like
Speaker 4:  It though. I I'm telling you the Frame TV is the harbinger of doom
Speaker 4:  for the streaming services.
Speaker 5:  Mm.
Speaker 4:  Because people are like, oh, we don't watch this thing. We're gonna pay a
Speaker 4:  premium.
Speaker 5:  Oh, you're saying because the TV is so crappy that when they do watch it,
Speaker 5:  they'll be like, what's the point?
Speaker 6:  People are buying a TV intentionally to not watch it is
Speaker 6:  what you're saying. Mm. The point of a TV is no longer to be watched.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's to just be there. It's like a binky. Yeah. Like if
Speaker 4:  I need a tv, I'll turn on this thing and I don't really care what it looks
Speaker 4:  like the rest of the time. It's gonna show me a picture. Is
Speaker 5:  It that many people though?
Speaker 4:  It is. I would argue the Frame TV is Samsung's most important product.
Speaker 4:  It is the product that has the most impact on the culture today.
Speaker 4:  A thousand words. 10,000 words.
Speaker 5:  I was like, I read 15,000 words. I wanna read all of these words. I need,
Speaker 4:  When am I gonna, I host two podcasts a week.
Speaker 4:  I and I, I can't even justify to the, to this group of people that we should
Speaker 4:  talk about the Frame TV that much. Everyone I need to take a week off.
Speaker 6:  I got a lot of emails asking for your 10,000 words on the
Speaker 6:  Frame tv. So I think we're, we're gonna have to just do this at some point.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We're we're, we'll carve the time out. We'll call Carve the Time out. All
Speaker 4:  Right. Let's do one more TV related just to end this segment
Speaker 4:  in place. Okay. Of hope and optimism. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Noran. Are we about to go from Neli? Crazy to Crans is crazy. Yeah. Oh no.
Speaker 5:  Well 'cause one of the things I noticed in the Sony story was that these
Speaker 5:  TVs all have a TSC 2.0 twos in em. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And this week was the big broadcasting
Speaker 5:  conference in Las Vegas, NAB. And everybody was making lots of
Speaker 5:  announcements. And the big announcement, some of the big announcements I
Speaker 5:  was excited about was from Roxy who we covered back at CES and
Speaker 5:  NBC Universal Peacock, some sort of
Speaker 5:  distantly related cousin of ours. Is that There's
Speaker 4:  No way, I'm sorry. Not there's no way. Peacock
Speaker 4:  is a distant
Speaker 5:  Comcast
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Is is a part investor in us. Okay. And
Speaker 5:  Peacock, we're distinct cousins. Sure.
Speaker 4:  I don't Mm, we don't know each other. We
Speaker 6:  Means I'm basically friends with Zoe Dechanel, so I'm
Speaker 5:  Good with that, basically. That feels fine. Yeah. Yeah, it's fine.
Speaker 4:  That's the worst disclosure we've ever, ever had.
Speaker 6:  I'm basically friends with Zoe de Chanel.
Speaker 5:  That's the new disclosure.
Speaker 5:  But, but they both announced that they were bringing new
Speaker 5:  technology to a TSC 3.0. Right now there's a couple of
Speaker 5:  channels in the country that broadcast on this spectrum that, that use
Speaker 5:  a TSC 3.0 Not a lot. And right now, If, you go and you watch shows on those
Speaker 5:  channels. It's just normal tv. There's no reason to
Speaker 5:  be excited. But coming soon because of
Speaker 5:  Roxy, you're gonna be able to pause and skip in your
Speaker 5:  local news. And then on the Today Show,
Speaker 5:  which I know everyone listening is a huge fan of,
Speaker 5:  you'll be able to do the same. That's pretty good. Through the NBC Universal
Speaker 5:  stuff. And so it's like, it's a little bit and little, little, yeah. Little
Speaker 5:  bit. Little little something happening there. And eventually it could be
Speaker 5:  something really cool. I still keep being like one of these days Peacock
Speaker 5:  is just gonna be on NBC and that'll just be the new NBC Oh,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  See. And it'll distribute over there. I got, I got you. Yeah. One day, the
Speaker 4:  thing I want to real about this story is that when Alex was writing
Speaker 16:  And I'll tell my mom, mom, I'm gonna the bathroom, I'll be back if I'm not
Speaker 16:  out in like three minutes. Dog. She's like knocking on the door going,
Speaker 16:  everything okay in there? Yeah, mom. Everything's cool, dog.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. I would say that it's when there's not quite enough
Speaker 4:  news is when our show goes the longest. Mm. I don't know why
Speaker 4:  that is, but that has been true for 10
Speaker 6:  Years. I think it's when I give you too much time to mess with the rundown.
Speaker 6:  Before we start, I'm gonna start revealing The Vergecast to you.
Speaker 4:  Four minutes before we just just live reacts. We could just do a box of me
Speaker 4:  reacting to you doing To Vergecast the whole time. It's rare that we get
Speaker 4:  a show that's so out of control that we bring up Big, Papa Joe.
Speaker 6:  Here
Speaker 4:  We are. That's a lot. All right, we're here. We gotta we gotta wrap this
Speaker 4:  thing up. We're we're just way, way over the line. I've promised it and now
Speaker 4:  it's here. David Pierce's headline blitz. David,
Speaker 4:  take it away.
Speaker 6:  I would like to just briefly catch you up on all of the things that are happening
Speaker 6:  with TikTok, because TikTok is not banned. It is still here
Speaker 6:  and it is wild, is just how I would say it. So here's what has gone on in
Speaker 6:  TikTok land just since the last time we did this show together in
Speaker 6:  the studio. TikTok Notes is an app that is coming out. It's only available
Speaker 6:  in a couple of countries, but it's just straight up Instagram. TikTok just
Speaker 6:  did Instagram and they're like, here, would you like Instagram? TikTok made
Speaker 6:  it. So that's the thing that exists. There are also now ways to
Speaker 6:  buy event tickets, like concert tickets and stuff inside of TikTok because
Speaker 6:  TikTok hasn't found enough ways to sell you stuff. They wanna sell you more
Speaker 6:  stuff. I think that is gonna work. I think like
Speaker 6:  all of this concert stuff is going to move inside of music apps in really
Speaker 6:  interesting ways. And I think TikTok is gonna do it first, and it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be really fascinating. There's been a bunch of like non-New
Speaker 6:  news about the TikTok divestment stuff. There's a new bill in the
Speaker 6:  house that is being attached to aid to foreign countries
Speaker 6:  that is partly now also a TikTok ban. So it's possible
Speaker 6:  that that is going to move to the Senate much more quickly where they're
Speaker 6:  gonna have to talk about divestment and banning. The president has said that
Speaker 6:  he's going to potentially delay a ban another six months to make
Speaker 6:  this all happen again. TikTok has said it's going to
Speaker 6:  restrict people who p keep posting problematic stuff on the
Speaker 6:  For You feed.
Speaker 6:  It also was reported this week that all of this project Texas stuff,
Speaker 6:  which I would say we have relentlessly made fun of on this show for a long
Speaker 6:  time, is basically just a bunch of nonsense. And that by dance has
Speaker 6:  access to lots of US users, TikTok, data,
Speaker 6:  Twitch and Spotify continue to do their best TikTok impressions.
Speaker 6:  Spotify is rolling out a remix thing so you can start to play with music
Speaker 6:  in the same way that you can play with sounds and speed them up on TikTok.
Speaker 6:  Twitch is doing a For You feed basically, I don't know how to say it more
Speaker 6:  than that. They just did a For You feed for Twitch, which I think is actually
Speaker 6:  very smart. The world is TikTok now. Like everybody is trying
Speaker 6:  to become TikTok and TikTok is trying to become everybody else. And maybe
Speaker 6:  it'll be banned and maybe it won't. And that's all I got.
Speaker 4:  I will say that TikTok trying to sell stuff relentlessly is just
Speaker 4:  reaching new levels of weirdness. For me personally,
Speaker 5:  I found a solution. Okay. Okay. Here's what you guys are gonna do. You're
Speaker 5:  gonna go on TikTok and you're gonna search Deep Talk
Speaker 5:  one word Deep Talk, and then you're gonna watch a bunch of those videos.
Speaker 5:  They're gonna be really weird. They're gonna be nonsensical. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  be really confused. You're gonna be like, this is just, looks like what Kranz
Speaker 5:  brain looks like on the inside. Yeah. Yeah. And you like a few of those and
Speaker 5:  then you're on Deep Talk and you're no longer on Shop Talk. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It's great.
Speaker 4:  I would, when I say all AI right now is, is my experience
Speaker 4:  with it is like weird and bad. Yeah. TikTok believes I
Speaker 4:  want to coil things that look like ropes. Mm. So much. It's
Speaker 4:  like you're gonna buy a garden hose reel, you're gonna buy an extension cord
Speaker 4:  reel. You're gonna buy a USB cord re which I don't think you should be doing
Speaker 4:  at all. It's just like, have you thought about reels? Buy
Speaker 4:  'em, just buy 'em now. and it and the the
Speaker 4:  pitches are increasingly abstract and a little threatening. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like, they're like, you will feel guilt. They, you don't get in on this hose
Speaker 4:  reel deal now.
Speaker 5:  Mine is a puppet.
Speaker 4:  It's already bad. It's already bad. Alex
Speaker 5:  Skateboarding on a leaf over water. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's all my TikTok is right now. And it's great. I'm like, I don't know
Speaker 5:  what the hell's happening here.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying there's, there are people out there right now who have bought
Speaker 4:  like up upwards of a dozen hose reels because this algorithm
Speaker 4:  is just the ruthlessly manipulated them. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I did buy something not directly from TikTok. All right. But they
Speaker 5:  should be a strainer. I went and got it on Amazon. It's great.
Speaker 4:  We'll see. Do we have a sense of the Senate bill might be moving?
Speaker 4:  Do we have a sense of it's gonna happen or not
Speaker 6:  At the moment? Not exactly, but Lauren Finer just wrote a really
Speaker 6:  good story that the, the general assumption is that because it's tied to
Speaker 6:  foreign aid, the Senate is basically gonna have no choice but to talk
Speaker 6:  about it. Like where we landed with the last bill is the Senate is just sort
Speaker 6:  of studiously pretending it doesn't exist.
Speaker 6:  That is going to be less possible now. And it's, it's, I
Speaker 6:  think it's gonna get raised one way or another. Where it goes seems to
Speaker 6:  be anyone's guess.
Speaker 4:  All right. We, we have time for I, I think two more. You, that was David's
Speaker 4:  headline Blitz. Everyone congratulate David, please sign a note you'd like
Speaker 4:  more headline Blitz in The future. You could
Speaker 6:  Sponsor the headline blitz inside of the lightning round if you'd
Speaker 4:  Like to. It's available for sponsorships at this time.
Speaker 4:  We're still, we're we're very close. Just everyone close your eyes and send
Speaker 4:  good vibes for our first Lightning round sponsor, and then we'll move on
Speaker 4:  to the headline blitz. All right. Alex, what you got? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  So Boston Dynamics, they make the, the robots. That's a good one. Yeah. They,
Speaker 5:  they, they make the robots. Earlier this week they said goodbye to Atlas
Speaker 5:  and then the very next day they said hello to New Atlas in the most
Speaker 5:  terrifying video of all time. Yeah. Where like the legs
Speaker 5:  did like some weird 360 degree hinge stuff.
Speaker 5:  The head looks like some sort of lamp. It basically looks like a video game
Speaker 5:  monster. And, and then we wrote about how it needs
Speaker 5:  to have hair.
Speaker 4:  We did, we did do that. It was a good pitch from Alex. Yeah. And I said,
Speaker 4:  just make sure it's over reported. And boy did Eve pizer over report the
Speaker 4:  story of why robots need hair.
Speaker 5:  Excellent. Just asking directly Some poor scientists. Do you think the
Speaker 5:  robot would be less creepy with fur and the robot's like No.
Speaker 4:  The scientist was like, not the robot. You don't ask the robot. What would
Speaker 4:  make it less creepy? Sorry.
Speaker 5:  Don't worry about it.
Speaker 4:  Was this written by a robot? Yeah. Give the robot's hair written by
Speaker 4:  a robot.
Speaker 4:  Sorry. You should watch the video. Our former VI reporter
Speaker 4:  James Vincent, I believe his post on the video was, it's
Speaker 4:  funny that Boston Dynamics just leaned directly into Terrifying. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just Oh yeah. Horrifying, horrifying thing. It's
Speaker 4:  Very good because it looks like a person, but it moves like a horror movie.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is probably what the person on the trainer was watching. All right.
Speaker 4:  Here's mine. I just wanna end with this because
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna say it. So this, wait, so this is mine. I just wanna end with
Speaker 4:  this. I dunno why I think this is so funny. Samsung
Speaker 4:  is requiring its executives to come to work for six days a week.
Speaker 4:  Zou, to quote, inject a sense of crisis.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They gotta get around that Google reorg. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wait, so Samsung is like, we wanna make this
Speaker 6:  worse
Speaker 4:  For everyone. Yeah. So, right. They've had disappointing financial results.
Speaker 4:  Sales are down, they fell short of expectations in
Speaker 4:  2023. It's a crisis. We need to make you feel the crisis. The
Speaker 4:  executives are now doing a six day work week until
Speaker 4:  something, and I,
Speaker 4:  you know, theoretically I'm an executive at this organization. I feel like
Speaker 4:  if I was like, I'm gonna come to work one extra day a week, but it's just
Speaker 4:  executives having ideas about how to not come to work anymore.
Speaker 4:  I feel like our staff would be like, you're gonna have the worst ideas in
Speaker 4:  the world.
Speaker 5:  Have fun by yourself.
Speaker 4:  It's like, here's what we need. Everyone have more meetings Yeah. On Saturday
Speaker 4:  about how it's a crisis. That's the, that will solve the crisis.
Speaker 4:  I cannot wait for the weird shit. Samsung is about to start doing
Speaker 4:  like just fully, they just did a buy one get one free TV deal.
Speaker 4:  That's a six day work week idea. Like fully a six day work week idea.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna start giving away toasters when you open a bank, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be incredible. They're gonna have the, the wobbly guy and the lots outside.
Speaker 4:  The Best Buy. I was
Speaker 5:  Like, is Bixby coming back?
Speaker 4:  Bixby full Bixby. Yeah. But like goth Bixby, like, get some attention.
Speaker 4:  I finally saw the video of what's her name,
Speaker 5:  Just crawling out of the water. Go, go. Jojo
Speaker 4:  Bixby. She's doing a country album. Let's see if that works. Like, can you
Speaker 4:  imagine what a bunch of executives unconstrained
Speaker 4:  by the reality of making or doing anything? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're just gonna stand over you and breathe loudly.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna start calling Whatever happens next. We just have to start calling
Speaker 4:  it Saturday Samsung. Yeah. Just as a family. Can we agree on
Speaker 5:  That? Yes, totally.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I'm hope as a, as a, as a person who is an afic of weird
Speaker 4:  Sony, I am very hopeful for the opportunity. Saturday Samsung might bring
Speaker 5:  Party speakers. Well,
Speaker 4:  Right. Where are they?
Speaker 5:  It's coming where? Where Sam is gonna ask that answer
Speaker 4:  To Ult Pro
Speaker 5:  Somewhere. It's coming.
Speaker 4:  What was that little robot we saw that could Bali?
Speaker 6:  I was just about to say, Bali is about to get a lot of shine at Saturday.
Speaker 6:  Samsung. Bali is a main character.
Speaker 5:  Let's go. B, go.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's it. We're way over time. We're just completely
Speaker 4:  over. I apologize, but I don't apologize because, well, the feedback we get
Speaker 4:  is you'd like this to be six hours long. So we'll do that next week.
Speaker 4:  Alright. That's it. That's the bridge test. Bye.
Speaker 10:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 10:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One. The Vergecast
Speaker 10:  is the production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is
Speaker 10:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 10:  week.