# Transcript
ID: a1334c2c-67b7-4238-b2f3-0f09b66b2f83
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/951762544982466456/6385100334042017214/s93290-US-5436s-1715338341.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Apple's iPad event, the evolution of the streaming business, updates on the Wisconsin Foxconn site, and much more tech news.
Apple iPad event: all the news from Apple’s ‘Let Loose’ reveal
The 7 biggest announcements from Apple’s iPad event
Here's how the latest iPad Pro compares to the new iPad Air (and prior models)
Apple adds a 13-inch iPad Air to the mix
The iPad Air is now heavier than the iPad Pro
Apple announces new iPad Pros with OLED displays and thinnest design ever
Apple announces its M4 chip
Magic Keyboard for iPad Pro M4: bigger trackpad and a function row
Hands-on with the new iPad Pro: yeah, it's really thin
You can upgrade the iPad Pro’s processor now, too
The new Apple Pencil Pro is harder to lose and better to draw with
Apple puts more ‘Pro’ in Final Cut and Logic Pro for the iPad
Apple quietly kills the old-school iPad and its headphone jack
The new iPads are ditching physical SIM cards
Goodbye to Apple’s Smart Keyboard Folio, the best iPad Pro accessory
People sure are pressed about Apple’s crushing iPad commercial
A Disney, Hulu, and Max streaming bundle is on the way
The streaming business will look “very different” in the next couple of years.
Max nears 100 million subscribers globally.
Max price hike incoming.
Disney’s streaming business gets closer to becoming profitable
ESPN is coming to the Disney Plus app
Sony is now in play to buy Paramount.
The Office is getting a Peacock spinoff about local newspapers
The new Sonos app is missing a lot of features, and people aren’t happy
Inside Microsoft’s Xbox turmoil
Microsoft says it needs games like Hi-Fi Rush the day after killing its studio
Epic v. Apple judge seems displeased over style restrictions on iOS buttons
The new Sonos app is missing a lot of features, and people aren’t happy
President Joe Biden to announce AI data center at failed Foxconn site in Wisconsin
TikTok sues the US government over ban
The Google Pixel 8A is a midrange phone that might go the distance
Google’s Pixel Tablet relaunch at $399 makes its magnetic dock optional
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (11 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Hello And Welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast of manufacturing in
Speaker 2:  southeastern Wisconsin. We're gonna go deep today on
Speaker 2:  concrete, on blue collar jobs, bringing America
Speaker 2:  back from wherever it was. And then
Speaker 5:  We, then we get a big globe,
Speaker 2:  Right? Huge tiny dome. Yeah. A dome. Excuse me, it's a dome.
Speaker 2:  What I'm talking about of course is Foxconn. In my hometown of Racine, Wisconsin,
Speaker 2:  the the literal place where I grew up, we're gonna get to
Speaker 2:  it. It's really just a victory lap for me personally
Speaker 2:  because Fox on has not done anything else. Like actually, quite notably the
Speaker 2:  news is that someone else has done stuff on that site in Wisconsin.
Speaker 2:  Neela.
Speaker 6:  Do you think you're the most famous resident of Racine, Wisconsin at this
Speaker 6:  moment in
Speaker 2:  Time? No. The most famous people from Racine, Wisconsin is the, the
Speaker 2:  bad team in the movie. A League of Their Own. Oh, that's good.
Speaker 6:  That's really good.
Speaker 2:  Easily the most famous Racine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You're never top in that
Speaker 2:  Thing. Is that what's her name? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is it Lori Petty? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Lori Petty. She goes
Speaker 2:  To the other team. I don't remember her character's name. I just know it's
Speaker 2:  Laura's Lori Petty. Yeah, she has to go. She goes to the Racine
Speaker 2:  Bells and then has to pitch against her sister Gina Davis. That's correct.
Speaker 2:  And Jeff Bridges is already dead and the bus can't go slower than 55 miles
Speaker 2:  an hour.
Speaker 2:  That's not in the movie at all. That's a straight, they're all the same straight.
Speaker 2:  That is a straight reference to Dress To Kill by Eddie Izard and If. you
Speaker 2:  get it. I love you and you are my people and you can just send me a note
Speaker 2:  and I'll send you a T-shirt. But you have to be able to tell me exactly what
Speaker 2:  it's okay. That's that whole thing. The other most famous president received
Speaker 2:  in Wisconsin is of course Sam Johnson of Johnson's Wax fame,
Speaker 2:  who did some weird stuff in a plane over Central America and built a
Speaker 2:  wax fortune that started the high school I went to Whose PBX system was
Speaker 2:  connected to the SC Johnson company. So you could pick up any phone in the
Speaker 2:  school and dial four digits and get a j, a vp.
Speaker 2:  I don't know if, I don't know why I know that information.
Speaker 5:  That was a deep Racine lawyer. Wow. Just
Speaker 6:  Was that who you would prank call in?
Speaker 2:  I got kicked outta that high school lot.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that right.
Speaker 2:  Just flatly kicked outta that school. Anyway, that's coming later in the
Speaker 2:  show. Not the Johnson wax stuff. The fox fun stuff.
Speaker 6:  That's much later in the show.
Speaker 2:  There is iPad News, like a lot of iPad news to talk to, but in a small
Speaker 2:  way we'll get to it. Kranz. The streaming
Speaker 2:  movie industry. The television industry in a moment. I of I would say
Speaker 2:  turmoil.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they, they, they realize they have to make money.
Speaker 2:  That's a problem. So we're gonna talk about that. And then we got a lightning
Speaker 2:  round, just shock waves in the lightning round,
Speaker 2:  which is unsponsored again this week. So if between now
Speaker 2:  and the lightning round, if you've got money to spend,
Speaker 6:  We have gotten some interest though. I will say If, you If, you want to throw
Speaker 6:  money at us? Let's start a bidding war because it's coming.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And we'll do it live on the air. That'll be the lightning round. Love
Speaker 2:  it. Recursive lightning round. Sponsored by the people. Wait
Speaker 5:  Dude, does that mean we get to do the bidding voice? The,
Speaker 2:  You know, you can go to classes for those. I saw a TikTok. Anyway. None of
Speaker 2:  that is important
Speaker 2:  by the way. I'm your friend Neil Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend who really wants to be one of those guys.
Speaker 2:  Auctioneer. The auctioneer for is auctioneer.
Speaker 6:  The Bo guy is like don't wanna up 30 foot That's
Speaker 2:  That's what he's No, that's a kid rock song.
Speaker 2:  David Pierce is
Speaker 6:  Here. Hi. Okay. Lovely to be here.
Speaker 2:  Alright, so this week the news is that Apple had
Speaker 2:  like a warmup event for wwc. I don't even know what else to call it. It felt
Speaker 2:  like a warmup
Speaker 5:  Cracked their knuckles.
Speaker 2:  They're like, here's some stuff, we gotta get this stuff outta the way. They
Speaker 2:  ran a 35 minute infomercial for new iPads at this point. Apple
Speaker 2:  loves the infomercial event, but they had some watch parties. David went
Speaker 2:  to one in New York. You got to sit down, watch the infomercial,
Speaker 2:  spend some time with the new hardware. But all of it, even
Speaker 2:  at the end of the event, I just want to, I feel like it's important to
Speaker 2:  contextualize this event by noting that at the end of the iPad
Speaker 2:  infomercial, Tim Cook came back on the screen and said, we
Speaker 2:  will have much more to say about the future of our platforms at WW DC
Speaker 2:  because the thing that needs to change on the iPad is iPad os.
Speaker 2:  And they announced no changes to iPad OS at this event.
Speaker 5:  Nope.
Speaker 2:  So it just, it just felt like, here's part one of the story.
Speaker 5:  You watched follow for part two.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You watched all of Mission Impossible, dead Reckoning.
Speaker 2:  Can't wait till next year. Like that's basically how that felt.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was odd, I think and, and I went in
Speaker 6:  thinking there must be something and we got to be fair little teeny tiny
Speaker 6:  bits of software, right? There was new final cut and new logic. There's a
Speaker 6:  new app called Final Cut Camera that works. So there's like tiny
Speaker 6:  bits of things that you can do, but the, the overwhelming question for the
Speaker 6:  iPad for like damn near a decade at this point has been, what am I supposed
Speaker 6:  to do with all of this power in this thing? Yeah. And we did
Speaker 6:  not get a lot of, I would say, new compelling answers to those questions.
Speaker 2:  I would say, in fact, we got none. And I want, I wanna come to that because,
Speaker 2:  you know, we have to review these things and I think there's like a, there's
Speaker 2:  a question mark at the end of this review. And the question mark is like,
Speaker 2:  what if they add a bunch of AI features in June? Right? Like, who knows?
Speaker 2:  But's actually talk about what they announced. They basically refresh the
Speaker 2:  entire lineup. Save the mini. It's actually very funny. If, you go to
Speaker 2:  apple.com right now and click on iPad. All of the iPads have the word new
Speaker 2:  under them and it feels like the, the mini should have the word old under
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 2:  They're just like the mini
Speaker 6:  Did at least get, it was like in the last 20
Speaker 6:  words that Tim Cook said in the whole thing. He said the words iPad
Speaker 6:  mini out loud. Which made me happy because that, that at least
Speaker 6:  is some acknowledgement that it exists and will continue to exist.
Speaker 6:  But it, that was it. That was the entirety of the love for the iPad mini
Speaker 6:  at this event. And that made me sad. I loved,
Speaker 5:  They just refreshed it last year. I'm trying to remember when I bought mine.
Speaker 5:  Was it last
Speaker 2:  Year? It was like two years ago. It
Speaker 6:  Was 2022 sometime. Yeah. Yeah. Oh wow.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's, and they make that product entirely as I understand it, for
Speaker 2:  pilots to strap to their legs while they fly planes. Yeah. So whatever the
Speaker 2:  mini aside deer sweet mini, the base models
Speaker 2:  refresh in so much as it a refresh is that they dropped the price,
Speaker 2:  the 3 49, which is important 'cause that's probably where it should have
Speaker 2:  been. They got rid of the ninth gen, which they were selling for 3 29. That's
Speaker 2:  one of the lightning connector and the headphone jack, no iPads. Apple is
Speaker 2:  selling right now, have a headphone jack, which I think is nightmares for
Speaker 2:  parents. I know I have a lot of dongle apologists in my mentions,
Speaker 2:  but If, you have a small child and you are ever traveling with the child
Speaker 2:  managing Bluetooth headphones for a child. It's just like no fun. Like,
Speaker 2:  and charging a thing. Like it's just easier to have the analog connector.
Speaker 2:  Please don't tell me about your SPC dongles. I don't care man. I don't care
Speaker 2:  that you're in the pocket of big dongle, which is not my problem.
Speaker 2:  Anyhow, they, that's the big refresh there and I think it's important they
Speaker 2:  brought that price down. Then the iPad Air feels
Speaker 2:  like a very subtle refresh. David, what'd they do there?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, it's, I would say subtle refresh is
Speaker 6:  basically right. The big change is that now there's a bigger one,
Speaker 6:  there's now a 13 inch version of the iPad air.
Speaker 6:  It has an M two chip. It comes in a couple of new colors,
Speaker 6:  but it is still very much an iPad air, right? Like thi, this
Speaker 6:  is I think the iPad that Apple wants most people to
Speaker 6:  buy, which is why it has the new colors, it has the,
Speaker 6:  the magic keyboard, it has the pencil. It is kind of the sort of
Speaker 6:  most mid of all of the iPads. And that is very much
Speaker 6:  what Apple wants it to be. And yeah, it's 5 9 9 for the 11
Speaker 6:  inch, 7, 9 9 for the 13 inch. And they're very much doing like a MacBook
Speaker 6:  Air MacBook Pro thing with these devices where you have the
Speaker 6:  sort of slightly less powerful, cheaper, simpler
Speaker 6:  computer into sizes. And then you have the more pro thing with all the advanced
Speaker 6:  specs for a lot more money still at the same two sizes. But
Speaker 6:  they've landed on this 11 and 13 inch thing as like the way going
Speaker 6:  forward.
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 5:  I just don't understand why anyone would buy the air
Speaker 5:  when the regular iPad exists and is got
Speaker 5:  like what? It's got the same or it's got an A 14. Okay. The iPad air has
Speaker 5:  an M two, does that really matter to 90% of people who are
Speaker 5:  using an iPad?
Speaker 6:  No. Which is, back to what you were saying Neli a minute ago,
Speaker 6:  a Apple would like you to believe that it matters and Apple would love to
Speaker 6:  tell you stories about all the power of its new chips
Speaker 6:  and why this stuff matters. And we're gonna get to the pro in a minute, which
Speaker 6:  has an even newer chip and I spent a lot of time with Apple
Speaker 6:  executives learning about the, the wonders of the new chip.
Speaker 6:  If you're just like a person who does normal iPad things in the world, I
Speaker 6:  cannot in good conscience tell you a processor upgrade in
Speaker 6:  your iPad is worth it. Yeah. And so I think that is the question. It's like,
Speaker 6:  I think Apple would very much like you to buy
Speaker 6:  the air, and I think Apple thinks the air is the
Speaker 6:  correct one for the largest number of people, but it
Speaker 6:  still feels a little like tweener ish to me
Speaker 6:  for a lot of things.
Speaker 5:  I found some differences between the air and the 10th gen iPad.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  The hover function on the new Apple pencil will work on the air.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's a bunch of pencil stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like
Speaker 2:  The, the original, the 10th gen iPad is
Speaker 2:  A-U-S-B-C
Speaker 2:  Dous pencil. Yeah. And it has the other smart keyboard or the magic
Speaker 2:  keyboard and that's it.
Speaker 5:  And it a hundred knits brighter
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  P three instead of SRGB.
Speaker 2:  Hey, that, that matters to me. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That, that does like that. And the fact that it has anti-reflective coating,
Speaker 5:  those two things do actually matter.
Speaker 2:  But it's a slightly nicer product that uses slightly newer accessories.
Speaker 6:  But again, by the time you're down this road of any of this stuff, you're
Speaker 6:  way beyond
Speaker 6:  the the average. I just need an iPad to look at while I sit on the couch
Speaker 6:  user. Right. Like to me it's like if you're even thinking about buying a
Speaker 6:  magic keyboard, buy the air or higher period. Yep. Right. Like that's, it's,
Speaker 6:  I think that's fairly simple. I think a lot of people who want iPads don't
Speaker 6:  want anything other than the pane of glass to hold in their hands.
Speaker 6:  And for most of those people, I can't think of a single reason the air
Speaker 6:  is going to be like meaningfully better for you in your life than the regular
Speaker 6:  iPad.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think this points to just the problem, which is what
Speaker 2:  is the use case for the iPad? And now again, the hardware
Speaker 2:  suggests that it is an expansive list of use
Speaker 2:  cases and to some extent it is. Right? Like
Speaker 2:  some people, I am sure produce music in Logic
Speaker 2:  exclusively in an iPad. Those people are causing themselves
Speaker 2:  an enormous amount of pain, but they're choosing to do it. And that is they're
Speaker 2:  right as Americans. Sure. Fine. Right. It's just here at
Speaker 2:  the, at the bottom of the range, the step from the 10th
Speaker 2:  gen to the air is very small hardware wise. Right. It is a nicer piece of
Speaker 2:  hardware. It's a bigger screen you can get now an even bigger screen, but
Speaker 2:  it's a very mild refresh. And basically they, they have added the
Speaker 2:  13 inch size fine. Yeah. But the
Speaker 2:  capabilities of the product are exactly the same as they were yesterday or
Speaker 2:  the day before. Yep. It's where you, it's the iPad Pro
Speaker 2:  and now the Pencil Pro where like, now
Speaker 2:  this, the purpose of this event it felt like was to simplify
Speaker 2:  this increasingly complicated lineup. And you get to the iPad Pro
Speaker 2:  and the Pencil Pro and the fact that Apple now sells I think four different
Speaker 2:  pencils and you're just like, what is going on here?
Speaker 5:  The pencils are really bad. Yeah. Like, like the, the, the chart
Speaker 5:  of which pencil works with which product and has which feature. Like no
Speaker 5:  If, you have a chart that big for a Apple product. You've, you've
Speaker 5:  messed up. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Let's get into the, well there's that. Yeah. Let's, let's talk about the
Speaker 2:  philosophy of the iPad in a second. Sorry. The iPad Pro is a piece of hardware
Speaker 2:  appears be very impressive. David, you've seen it. Tell us about it.
Speaker 6:  It's so, so good. I
Speaker 6:  we we go to a lot of these events, right? And you're like, you're constantly
Speaker 6:  being handed a thing that somebody has just spent a half hour telling you
Speaker 6:  is new and most of the time you're just like, this is, this is a
Speaker 6:  MacBook like of c It sure is. And and the iPad
Speaker 6:  is like the canonical example of that, right? Like for years and years
Speaker 6:  and years, you pick up an iPad and you're like, boy, that sure is an iPad.
Speaker 6:  I picked up the iPad Pro at this event in New York and like out loud
Speaker 6:  involuntarily just said, holy shit. Ooh. Like it is so
Speaker 6:  thin and so light and so small, especially on the 13 inch.
Speaker 6:  I I it was, it's the biggest like leap forward
Speaker 6:  in how impressive I find this hardware in a really long time.
Speaker 6:  Again, we can debate forever the value of any of this hardware, but just
Speaker 6:  the sheer like engineering feet to get this thing under a pound,
Speaker 6:  it's 5.1 millimeters thick. by the
Speaker 6:  way everybody says 5.1 millimeters thin now. And I think we've complained
Speaker 6:  about that. Yeah. That's nothing. Things are not, You can't measure
Speaker 6:  the thinness of something. Yeah. It's thickness and there's not much of it.
Speaker 6:  Which is
Speaker 2:  Steve, Steve, Steve Jobs started doing this with the, I believe the second
Speaker 2:  generation MacBook Air.
Speaker 6:  I hate it so much and everybody does this now and it drives me insane. But
Speaker 6:  that's neither here nor there.
Speaker 5:  It's 5.1 millimeters, but that's the 13
Speaker 6:  Inch. Yeah. And I, and the 11 inch I believe is is either is five three.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Okay. But the point is the, they're, they're spectacular.
Speaker 6:  Like truly as pieces of hardware, they are incredibly impressive to the point
Speaker 6:  where you're holding the thing. And like everybody who's made this joke,
Speaker 6:  Marquez Brownley, when he made a video, had the jerry rig everything guy
Speaker 6:  just sort of peek out from the corner of the video. Like it feels like you
Speaker 6:  could snap this thing in half. Whether or not you can, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  If you can, that feels like a problem. But yeah, just the, the sheer
Speaker 6:  machinery inside of this thing is really, really, really impressive.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's two pieces I think that are important to call out. One
Speaker 2:  is new processor, the M four, which is interesting just sort of
Speaker 2:  from a processor technology standpoint. Apple
Speaker 2:  didn't put an M three in this If, you read Ben Thompson's
Speaker 2:  eckery, he points out that the M three is on
Speaker 2:  a three nanometer process node from tsmc. That was a technology dead
Speaker 2:  end. Yeah. And TSMC has all but admitted it and the M
Speaker 2:  four is on the one that is sustainable and has a future. So
Speaker 2:  at TSMC was like, we made this weird dead end because we have customers who
Speaker 2:  insist on being at the, at the leading edge, there's one customer that
Speaker 2:  insists on being at the leading edge. So they made, so the M three could
Speaker 2:  be in whatever computers it was in. And the M four is the, the leap
Speaker 2:  to the good version of the three nanometer node that has like a roadmap in
Speaker 2:  front of it. So you see Apple is trying, they're putting
Speaker 2:  the stuff like the best stuff they got into this machine. And then
Speaker 2:  on top of that it has the tandem ed people have been talking about stacked
Speaker 2:  ole displaced for a very long time. It's a really simple
Speaker 2:  idea. Like, it's like deceptively simple. Obviously it's taking a long time
Speaker 2:  to pull off, but If, you run an OLED at the brightness, you wanna
Speaker 2:  run an oled, it gets hot, you risk burning. So why don't we just
Speaker 2:  take two ED displays basically combine their power source
Speaker 2:  and then we just run them each at half brightness on top of each other to
Speaker 2:  get sort like real p my ride, like linking there.
Speaker 2:  It's very clever. And then what you can do, and David, I'm very curious this
Speaker 2:  'cause I haven't seen it. I know you have If, you run 'em both at top
Speaker 2:  brightness, you get a much brighter OLA display, which is that I
Speaker 2:  think is the promise and the thing that people have been trying to work on
Speaker 2:  for a long time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It was tough to tell. I mean these, these Apple events are always lit
Speaker 6:  really bizarrely in such a way that it's really hard to sort of get in the
Speaker 6:  nitty gritty pixels of a display. But it, it was noticeably brighter.
Speaker 6:  Like I brought my 11 inch pro from last generation
Speaker 6:  with me and like just holding the two things side by side. You can, you can
Speaker 6:  tell how much brighter the ole is. I think they said it's 1600 knits at
Speaker 6:  full brightness, which is a lot. I assume we'll just shred your battery to
Speaker 6:  bits at full brightness. 'cause like you're running that
Speaker 6:  many ole pixels at full brightness. Like you're like, I'm gonna watch one
Speaker 6:  episode of something and it's just gonna shatter the battery. Well
Speaker 2:  No, but this is the, this is the idea though is that you're, you get more
Speaker 2:  efficiency maybe at the top brightness where you're running effectively both
Speaker 2:  panels all the way. But the idea is that sort of at your everyday
Speaker 2:  brightness, right? You're running both panels like
Speaker 2:  halfway.
Speaker 6:  Right? And that's also a big part of the reason that the
Speaker 6:  M four and the tandem mo that are happening simultaneously. Like the the
Speaker 6:  overwhelming thing I heard talking to folks at this event was that like we
Speaker 6:  couldn't do one of these without the other. That that, that
Speaker 6:  driving those two displays at that high resolution
Speaker 6:  and that high refresh rate is, is just a massive amount of
Speaker 6:  computational work. And doing those two things, especially in a way that
Speaker 6:  is like at all power efficient is just really hard. And that a lot
Speaker 6:  of what the M four is is explicitly about
Speaker 6:  driving the tandem ole, which I think is really interesting. And I wonder
Speaker 6:  what that says about like the next set of products that might have m
Speaker 6:  fours inside.
Speaker 2:  What kind of MacBook do you make if you've got a big tandem OLED driver
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Sitting on your chip, right? The big ass battery.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  It is just gonna be one of those like a hundred milliamp hour Oh yeah. Anchor
Speaker 2:  batteries with this, this screen that falls on it. I would take that product
Speaker 2:  if they made this twice as thick and got rid of the camera bump and was like,
Speaker 2:  the battery lasts for a week, I would be happy. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I I do agree with that. I mean, there was a very funny thing where, you know,
Speaker 6:  you, you hold this thing and it's, it's a remarkable piece of technology.
Speaker 6:  Like they built the hell outta the hardware, but then I'm like, okay, if
Speaker 6:  this thing was a little thicker so that it didn't have a camera bump, which
Speaker 6:  is the thing a lot of people pointed out was this, this could have been
Speaker 6:  the, the thickness of the camera bump and would've been about the same thickness
Speaker 6:  as the last iPad, which no one was complaining about the thickness of, by
Speaker 6:  the way. Yeah. And you'd get more battery, you might get
Speaker 6:  more power efficiency out of it. You'd get better speakers just because there's
Speaker 6:  room to move the audio around that like maybe this
Speaker 6:  constant thrust toward thinness that Apple has been on for so long is
Speaker 6:  actually not the right strategy. Yeah. And I largely agree with that, but
Speaker 6:  like, god damn, is it cool just to hold the thing when it's that thin,
Speaker 2:  This thing you are a Johnny Ipil, this thing is like Ives revenge. It kind
Speaker 2:  of, he's like, here's what happens. You pick up an iPhone six and it flops
Speaker 2:  over, but damn is it thin? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Pretty much fine. Yeah. And then there's a new
Speaker 2:  accessories, right? So there's the Apple Pencil Pro, which
Speaker 2:  adds the ability to do a barrel roll. Do a barrel roll.
Speaker 2:  You can also squeeze it. Love to, love to squeeze a pencil. When I think
Speaker 2:  about totally natural user interfaces, it's squeezing a pen. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Wait, can
Speaker 6:  I just say two things about the pencil? Yeah. One, the squeeze is actually
Speaker 6:  pretty nice. They put, they put a real like haptic engine into it. So it
Speaker 6:  feels, it feels like a, a MacBook track pad now in the sense that you get
Speaker 6:  a little bit of that response. I don't know that it adds
Speaker 6:  wildly to the experience of using it, but it does feel nice to squeeze the
Speaker 6:  thing. The other thing is Apple is very excited about the
Speaker 6:  developer possibilities for this. There there are going to be APIs that you
Speaker 6:  can just give to any app and they're gonna be able to do stuff with the squeeze.
Speaker 6:  And I just like casually threw out the example of like, oh, I can't wait
Speaker 6:  to use my pencil to change the Spotify song. And somebody just goes, Hmm,
Speaker 6:  interesting idea. And I was like, no, that was a joke. That's a bad idea.
Speaker 6:  No one should do that.
Speaker 6:  So, so there's gonna be some like deeply weird pencil gesture
Speaker 6:  support stuff going on and they're, they're gonna be able to chain
Speaker 6:  gestures on the pencil to shortcuts. So all
Speaker 6:  the shortcut nerds are really excited about this now. It's gonna get
Speaker 6:  really weird and I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. My prediction is that it does not get weird.
Speaker 2:  Like I, I love the idea of adaptive user
Speaker 2:  interfaces and I have like talked about them with a lot of people
Speaker 2:  over the years. I actually just, Dylan Field, the CEO of Figma was on stage
Speaker 2:  with me at South By, and he's like, I love the idea of adaptive user interfaces.
Speaker 2:  And we talked specifically about stylists and pencils and
Speaker 2:  like what if, as you were, you know, sketching a design in Figma, the sort
Speaker 2:  of UI was around your stylists was adapting
Speaker 2:  to what you were doing. So you could just like move seamlessly. Like this
Speaker 2:  is a dream, this is a technologist dream. The idea that
Speaker 2:  a bunch of app developers are gonna flock to the broken app
Speaker 2:  development model of the iPad and develop custom features for a pencil
Speaker 2:  that is only available at the top end of the range.
Speaker 2:  I look David, I'm very, I really want you to squeeze your way through a Spotify
Speaker 2:  playlist. I mean, there's nothing I want more for you. You're,
Speaker 6:  You're way overstating the amount of work that it's gonna be to, it's like,
Speaker 6:  it's like setting up a keyboard shortcut to do this. Like it's not hard work
Speaker 2:  To set that my set, my Netflix wouldn't put a video player on the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean fair. But also, I mean,
Speaker 6:  A, you're right. And BI would like everyone to email your favorite
Speaker 6:  shortcut to neli at The Verge
Speaker 2:  Dot com. I love, I love a shortcut. I love them. Can't get enough
Speaker 2:  of scripting my own applications to defeat the lack of cross
Speaker 2:  app interoperability on Apple's platforms. It's my favorite. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's good stuff.
Speaker 2:  I just, this is the sort of thing where Apple makes a big promise about everybody's
Speaker 2:  supporting a thing and then we wait. Yeah. And so I would just
Speaker 2:  challenge you on the scale of,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, dashboard widgets to
Speaker 2:  the touch bar. Where do we think pencil squeezing
Speaker 2:  support is gonna land
Speaker 6:  From like very bad to very bad. Is that, is that where we're at right now?
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 2:  I think about some big Apple UI idea that it had
Speaker 2:  iPhone widgets. Sure. On your lock screen live activities and then Dynamic
Speaker 2:  Island support. We've seen just a lot of support for that, especially as
Speaker 2:  it came to the mainstream phone. Very good. Okay. So that's on the, the plus
Speaker 2:  side. That's great. And then there's the touch bar
Speaker 2:  all the way over there.
Speaker 5:  The touch bar was awesome. Just nobody gave a shit.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Excited for you to use Spotify with your touch bar. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying that's the range. Yeah. Where do you put squeezing the pencil
Speaker 6:  Closer to the touch bar? I mean, I think it's just true. Like
Speaker 6:  it's not, it's not a mainstream accessory. I would actually actually like
Speaker 6:  keyboard shortcuts on the iPad are, are actually probably right in line with
Speaker 6:  the same thing. Right? It's the kind of thing that are relatively
Speaker 6:  cheap to add and relatively straightforward for users to
Speaker 6:  access once they have them. But the attach rate of those accessories is not
Speaker 6:  super high. Yep. Most apps don't really need it. Like what
Speaker 6:  you're gonna see is there's going to be this set of like apps that
Speaker 6:  use the pencil that are going to use the hell out of the pencil and you're
Speaker 6:  already all of the drawing apps. And like, I've just been talking to folks
Speaker 6:  even in the last couple of days, like folks are psyched about the barrel
Speaker 6:  roll stuff and just like the little creative abilities that you
Speaker 6:  get just with the additional tiny features in here are like a big deal.
Speaker 6:  But they're a big deal for a tiny number of features to a tiny number of
Speaker 6:  people and that's great. But I, I don't see a world in which the pencil is
Speaker 6:  ever bigger than that. So I think the idea that like Spotify is gonna care
Speaker 6:  about it is not real. If a pencil came free I would feel
Speaker 6:  differently, but it doesn't. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I do love the idea that you go to events where people are, are sort
Speaker 2:  of professionally obligated to like be kind to you and just have horrible
Speaker 2:  ideas and they're like, good idea.
Speaker 6:  It's so fun.
Speaker 2:  It's so fun.
Speaker 6:  I just pitch stupid products to people for like several hours and it's, and
Speaker 6:  they go Ha and then they keep giving me demos. It's
Speaker 2:  Great. Sets a pencil. The one I'm really curious about is
Speaker 2:  the keyboard because my favorite plane computer of all
Speaker 2:  time was a 12 inch MacBook, which was super light and thin. I tried to replace
Speaker 2:  it with the previous 11 inch iPad Pro, which just turned out to
Speaker 2:  like thick. It was just like a heavy weird, it just like wasn't
Speaker 2:  as good as a laptop in many ways because of just the way it worked. Is
Speaker 2:  the new keyboard case sort of better? It's, they announced it as being more
Speaker 2:  like a MacBook than ever, which I thought was really interesting.
Speaker 6:  The top half hasn't really changed, which I think is,
Speaker 6:  is gonna be its challenge. It's still, at least in the demos I got
Speaker 6:  and, and the time I was able to spend with it, it's still a little wobbly,
Speaker 6:  especially when you touch it. So it kind of wiggles as you move it around
Speaker 6:  the bottom, especially on the pros is aluminum. It's much
Speaker 6:  more solid. It's really smooth. It actually like, feels nice to rest your
Speaker 6:  palm on kind of MacBook Airly
Speaker 6:  and the Keys felt amazing. I've spent like 10 minutes on it so I reserved
Speaker 6:  the right to change my mind. But it, it was, it was one of those keyboards,
Speaker 6:  you just put your hands down and instantly start typing on, I
Speaker 6:  also really love Apple's normal magic keyboard. So
Speaker 6:  everyone's mileage may vary on that, but I think that's a great keyboard
Speaker 6:  and this felt to my hands just like that, which is kind
Speaker 6:  of all you'd want for this. I always thought the iPad Pros keyboard
Speaker 6:  was a little like mushy and sort of thick. Yeah. It just,
Speaker 6:  it just felt like you had to sort of smash the keys all the time. And then
Speaker 6:  I spilled like half a diet Coke on mine and so now you have to really smash
Speaker 6:  the keys. But this one, at least in the
Speaker 6:  bits that I've gotten, felt fantastic. Like I instantly
Speaker 6:  want it as just a little kitchen computer that I can just
Speaker 6:  sit and like write
Speaker 2:  Emails while I wait for my coffee to brew. Like, it felt great,
Speaker 5:  But I have a question, which do you want more this
Speaker 5:  or Microsoft Surface
Speaker 5:  device? Because I it like the whole time watching this, the whole time talking
Speaker 5:  about it, talking even about the, the stylist, I was like, this just feels
Speaker 5:  kind of like Microsoft in 2017 or 2018. Right. Like
Speaker 5:  when, when they and all the OEMs were really pushing like, yeah look it's
Speaker 5:  a touchscreen computer. And I'm like, yes. Now Apple has done
Speaker 5:  a touchscreen computer right down to talking about the processor. Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  they didn't use to do with the iPad. Like this is just a computer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There was a, this was a speeds and feeds event. Yeah. It was fascinating
Speaker 2:  on that front. It really was super
Speaker 5:  Weird.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. So it's interesting back then I think Windows
Speaker 2:  was in a weirder spot. Yeah. So they announced the surface and they're like,
Speaker 2:  but then it's Windows and Windows
Speaker 2:  is in a sideways sort of fashion come a long way.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like I would say it's in a different spot, right? Is
Speaker 2:  that spot ahead? It's more of a diagonal.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. That you
Speaker 2:  Just kinda, it's gone this way. It's, it's come a distance. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The direction I think is a, I'm
Speaker 5:  Sure it's a good
Speaker 2:  Direction and I I only say that because you can argue about what the evolution
Speaker 2:  of Windows Yeah. To contrast with the fact that the iPad
Speaker 2:  is in exactly the same place as it was. Yes. I went back
Speaker 2:  and I read my iPad air review from 2013, which in a
Speaker 2:  horrifying sequence of events, I forgot that I had written.
Speaker 5:  You're like, oh this guy's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's like, oh, smart snappy. Oh that's me. There it is.
Speaker 2:  And it is exactly the same that iPad was running iPad
Speaker 2:  OS seven. iOS seven. Yeah. In my review is like,
Speaker 2:  this thing is constantly fighting you. They have not done enough with this
Speaker 2:  software to take advantage of the larger screen. The, and it's just like
Speaker 2:  plaintiff, like why is Siri so weird on this? Like why is it, why is it just
Speaker 2:  a big iPhone? I read my iPad Pro review from 2018 when
Speaker 2:  it the first USPC one and I'm like, why is this computer fighting me? Like
Speaker 2:  why is file management on the iPad so confused? Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  all that stuff has gotten incrementally better. Yep. They've added stage
Speaker 2:  manager shortcut shortcuts. People, I'm so proud of you for
Speaker 2:  writing an alternative operating system in shortcuts on top of iPad os
Speaker 2:  that is an achieve. I, you know, that's cool as hell. That's like,
Speaker 2:  I'm a computer nerd. I'm happy you did computer nerd stuff. But the,
Speaker 2:  the ultimate problem, which is you have to fight the computer
Speaker 2:  to get it to be a computer, like remains as true for the iPad
Speaker 2:  today as it did in 2013 when I was running Iowa seven. Yeah. And this,
Speaker 2:  and I think my answer to you then, given that question is like, I'd
Speaker 2:  rather take the weird sideways windows.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Because at le at least it's gonna do everything that
Speaker 2:  I want it to do with without
Speaker 2:  some
Speaker 5:  Like, like putting on armor and just going to war with your operat.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Just like running into like the brick wall of apple's business model.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. Apple's like, we're gonna distribute all the applications to
Speaker 2:  the app store. We're gonna take 30% of all those buttons. Like, and that
Speaker 2:  will, and if we open that up on the iPad, then we're terrified that we'll
Speaker 2:  have to open it up on the iPhone. We're already being brats about opening,
Speaker 2:  opening it up on the iPhone. Like no, like we're, it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  like this, this is the future of computing. And then you're like,
Speaker 2:  is it?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it really doesn't. It feels just like they made a
Speaker 5:  hobbled surface device, like a, my to be
Speaker 5:  clear, my dream service device in 2018, but a hobbled
Speaker 5:  surface device right down to the fact that you have to choose the processor,
Speaker 5:  the storage, like the markups are high to make it functional.
Speaker 2:  So the thing we don't know weird
Speaker 5:  Thing,
Speaker 2:  The thing we don't know is like what's gonna happen in June. That's true.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  True. When a rev iPad os and that's what to me, David, I
Speaker 2:  couldn't tell if while you were at the watch parties and they had one in
Speaker 2:  New York and one in London, like maybe the vibes were different all around
Speaker 2:  the world. But for me sitting at home
Speaker 2:  watching it in the glorious still be atmos of my own home
Speaker 2:  app. Apple, by the way, did not stream this thing at any more than like eight
Speaker 2:  megabits per second. I'm just saying.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it was not in Sony Bravia Corps.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It was at 48 Kilohertz Atmos, which was great. But I mean, come on,
Speaker 2:  where's the, where's the resolution man? You're gonna show John turn whipping
Speaker 2:  around the BART holding an iPad. I want, I want the full Anyway,
Speaker 2:  I was like, man, like I can't wait until next month
Speaker 2:  when they finish this product. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like exactly. It, it just felt like, okay, you've, you've announced
Speaker 5:  this thing that we've already seen before. We've already heard the pitch
Speaker 5:  that this kind of computer is really good for creatives. Because that was
Speaker 5:  the whole pitch, right? It was like, look, this is for creatives. I was like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, I heard that from Microsoft and HP and everybody else back in
Speaker 5:  2018. I know that now.
Speaker 2:  And you've heard that from Apple about the iPad. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And like, okay, show me. And they're like, yeah, we did it. No, no, but show
Speaker 5:  me where it's actually good for creatives now where it's actually that useful
Speaker 5:  computer. All you've done is like crush a bunch of stuff with a hydraulic
Speaker 5:  crossing. Wait,
Speaker 2:  I want to come to the crushing. Yeah, well
Speaker 5:  Look into that. Yeah. Yeah. That's the
Speaker 2:  Other thing. But I'm curious, David, if that came through at the, whatever
Speaker 2:  the, when it was a wa it wasn't like a full event, but I'm curious if it
Speaker 2:  came through there. Yeah, I think
Speaker 6:  It, it was hard to tell at the event whether this was the
Speaker 6:  end of something or the beginning of something. And one
Speaker 6:  way to look at this event is that essentially Apple like finished the job
Speaker 6:  of the iPad, right? They said this over and over and over again. They're
Speaker 6:  like, this is the the magical pane of glass. Right? Yeah. Like that's the
Speaker 6:  thing they've been wanting to build for a really long time. And like they,
Speaker 6:  they built a really nice one. It has an outrageous amount of raw
Speaker 6:  horsepower. It's really light, it's really thin. The screen looks awesome.
Speaker 6:  Like you could make the case that they have been sort of working toward
Speaker 6:  this particular iPad since the beginning of the iPad. And I think like
Speaker 6:  they said over and over, this is the biggest day in the iPad since the launch
Speaker 6:  of the iPad. Which like objectively not true. But If, you wanna look at it
Speaker 6:  that way. This is the end of that journey in a certain way. Like I
Speaker 6:  genuinely don't know how much further you can push the actual
Speaker 6:  details of the hardware here than what this is now until we get to like
Speaker 6:  rollable display. It's in something that's like, this feels like an end point
Speaker 6:  in a real way. Or the flip side is this
Speaker 6:  is the thing that is going to empower all of the things that Apple's gonna
Speaker 6:  launch in June. And that was all the stuff that they were sort of intimating
Speaker 6:  with the AI stuff and talking about the features and you know, leaning on.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna have more to say about the future of the platform in June. I
Speaker 6:  don't think this running Mac os is the answer for the iPad.
Speaker 6:  And there are a lot of people who are like, the evidence is everywhere. They're
Speaker 6:  gonna have Mac Os on the iPad. Like no, they're not. It's just not gonna
Speaker 6:  happen. But if there is a next
Speaker 6:  turn for what the iPad can be and do and like a fundamental shift
Speaker 6:  in the use case, that's when this feels like the beginning of
Speaker 6:  something. Right. And now they're like, we have a different kind of hardware
Speaker 6:  with a different set of accessories and a different performance envelope
Speaker 6:  that can actually go do all of this new stuff. Yeah. And this is the story
Speaker 6:  everybody has been telling us about AI for like damn near two years now and
Speaker 6:  none of it's really been true. So I'm not ultra
Speaker 6:  confident that Apple is going to have like, massively improved the state
Speaker 6:  of the art of AI and has solved all the features for everybody in June.
Speaker 6:  But this did it, it felt very much like
Speaker 6:  this is the vessel and we're gonna fill it a month from now and if not this
Speaker 6:  will feel like the end of an era of the iPad. To me, how
Speaker 5:  Does AI fix iPad
Speaker 2:  Os Wait, I, I wanna come to, I I think that's where I wanna end. Okay. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  Sorry. I, I definitely wanna end there. Yeah. I just want to, before we get
Speaker 2:  to that, 'cause I think that's, that's the right place to end for sure. And
Speaker 2:  I think that's another hour of the show.
Speaker 2:  I just want to call out the biggest day of the iPad since the iPad
Speaker 2:  off the top of my head I can think of three more important
Speaker 2:  iPads than these that like move the needle the iPad two. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Which was a like a shock announcement and the design
Speaker 2:  direction of the iPad two was basically the iPad until
Speaker 2:  Monday. Yep. Like that ninth gen iPad
Speaker 2:  with the lightning connector, like slightly different design like, but it
Speaker 2:  was it's an iPad too. Yeah. Yep. They just flattened it a little bit. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Right. That But it's the same exact home button bezels the whole thing.
Speaker 2:  That's an iPad too. And that iPad two launch Steve
Speaker 2:  Jobs on the stage being like, I did it again. You saw the first gen iPad,
Speaker 2:  here's the second one. And this I, this is always my
Speaker 2:  test. That shit made the local news. Yeah. Right. If, you If you
Speaker 2:  wanna breakthrough on the mainstream. You need ABC seven in Chicago to be
Speaker 2:  like, I have one I a new iPad today. Like, you gotta do it, you gotta get
Speaker 2:  there. The iPad four, which
Speaker 2:  was the retina display and lightning connector, the iPad three had a retina
Speaker 2:  display, but it was way too early and it was thicker and the thing ran
Speaker 2:  so hot, the battery life was garbage. iPad four was the good one. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Huge big deal. Everybody I know who had an iPad immediately upgraded to that
Speaker 2:  iPad. And then the original iPad error where they
Speaker 2:  changed it to the boxier design and they like gave it the extra capabilities.
Speaker 2:  That was a big deal. Which is why I was reading my 2013 review
Speaker 2:  where they, they redid the form factor to make it that more square.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And a form factor change is always just a big deal. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like none of the ones you mentioned though were when they got rid of the
Speaker 5:  button.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. 'cause whatever
Speaker 5:  You don't care about the button.
Speaker 2:  I I believe that was the original iPad Pro. Yeah, I think you're right. It's
Speaker 2:  the 2018 iPad Pro. And that one I would say was not a big deal because that's
Speaker 2:  when they added the keyboard and they like got real surfacey and I'm just
Speaker 2:  using my local news test. That thing was really expensive.
Speaker 2:  It tried it, tried to make it a laptop and it, I I did it
Speaker 2:  work?
Speaker 5:  Did it go on the local news?
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying off the top of my head. Well if you're just ranking the biggest
Speaker 2:  iPads, the things that made the iPad breakthrough to the mainstream and
Speaker 2:  like cause a fuss. It's 100% the
Speaker 2:  iPad too. Yes. Like easily the most beat You're ranking the
Speaker 2:  biggest moments for the iPad Since the iPad. The iPad two is at the top of
Speaker 2:  that list. Yeah. Without question then. I think it is the iPad four
Speaker 2:  when all of the early adopters of the iPad upgraded. 'cause the hardware
Speaker 2:  had a new capability in the retina screen that was worthwhile instead of
Speaker 2:  the iPad three, which again had a retina screen but was also a tiny nuclear
Speaker 2:  reactor. And then the, the iPad error, which was the big
Speaker 2:  form factor shift that everybody upgraded to Right. And also passed the local
Speaker 2:  news test of Apple has a new iPad. It was thinner than ever before. Like
Speaker 2:  that thing
Speaker 5:  I I do wanna tell you that in fact the, the event this week did pass the
Speaker 5:  local news test
Speaker 2:  You're watching ABC seven,
Speaker 5:  ABC seven did in fact cover it. Oh, now it's covering the streaming bundle.
Speaker 2:  ABC seven in Chicago.
Speaker 5:  Just going. But, but yeah, they were just like Apple unveils
Speaker 5:  new iPad Pro with outrageously powerful AI powered chip.
Speaker 2:  All right. I'm not gonna tell you why I think about ABC seven news.
Speaker 2:  It is what my mom watches. Okay.
Speaker 5:  But no, I I'm I'm with you like local news when it hits local news. So I
Speaker 5:  I'm genuinely surprised this hit
Speaker 2:  They need something, right? Yeah. It was
Speaker 5:  A slow news week for 'em.
Speaker 2:  I just say that's my test. And I, that's to me is the God bless the
Speaker 2:  people at ABC seven News. Yeah. I'm in Chicago for New Year's every year
Speaker 2:  and they do a just a wild New Year's Eve thing. So that's why it's always
Speaker 2:  on my mind. But it is true. That's the one my, my mom watches. Oh.
Speaker 2:  But I think about that test and it's like, did this pass the test where a
Speaker 2:  whole bunch of new people are gonna pick an iPad, are gonna buy an
Speaker 2:  iPad? And I don't, I don't think this hardware is that thing.
Speaker 2:  No. Maybe at the top end of the scale, a bunch of people are gonna get an
Speaker 2:  iPad Pro 'cause they wanna do a barrel roll. I doubt I I'm that
Speaker 2:  person. I I'm not a tandem ole. Yeah. I'm in
Speaker 2:  Let's spend the money. I'm just, that's the thing I'm thinking about and
Speaker 2:  that's where I'm with David where I'm like, you gotta, you gotta reset
Speaker 2:  your expectations of what the thing is capable of. Yeah. which I think brings
Speaker 2:  me to the commercial and all this talk about
Speaker 2:  ai. Apple said a million times is the most powerful AI
Speaker 2:  computer you can get because the M four, we've been doing the neural engine
Speaker 2:  for years. Here's the the
Speaker 2:  thing in logic where you can put in a song and it does the AI and it splits
Speaker 2:  the stems into drums and guitars and vocals for you. That's cool.
Speaker 2:  Here's some final cut Pro stuff. That's cool. by the way, final cut camera
Speaker 2:  on the iPhone. They announced, they just slid by that they announced pro
Speaker 2:  camera software, right? Just for the iPhone. Just
Speaker 5:  Moved through
Speaker 2:  It. That rules like that's awesome. But you know, the thing's very
Speaker 2:  powerful. And then they're like, we're gonna have more AI features. You can
Speaker 2:  see they're gonna announce a ton of AI features at wwc. And I think what
Speaker 2:  is fascinating is maybe Apple's core
Speaker 2:  constituency hates it
Speaker 2:  and then this ad just like lit the fuse.
Speaker 5:  God, the ad was like unintentionally a flash point in what fells
Speaker 5:  like some sort of new class warfare Yeah. Between like big tech
Speaker 5:  and creatives and, and we've been seeing it in Hollywood a lot, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, like as Apple and Amazon and everybody goes and, and takes over streaming
Speaker 5:  there. Everybody's got really strong feelings about it. But to see it
Speaker 5:  happen here, to see like Hugh Grant be like, this sucks. You're
Speaker 5:  destroying the world. That was a really bad Hugh Grant impression. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Sorry. I
Speaker 2:  He's famously British. He's
Speaker 5:  Famously British. I'm, I'm, I'm I'm not. But
Speaker 2:  The opposite of British the opposite. So the ad the ad is a bunch
Speaker 2:  of stuff like beautiful old creative stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like paint and phones and
Speaker 2:  There's a, a trumpet I believe at the beginning.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Trump a metronome, a sculpture that I thought was, was
Speaker 5:  like a sculpture and then it was clay. 'cause it just smooshed all
Speaker 5:  unsatisfying in the hydraulic press. And it was like a really good
Speaker 5:  commercial. And it's the same thing they've done a billion times before where
Speaker 5:  they're just like, what if all of this stuff was in the palm of
Speaker 5:  your hand? And everybody's like, F off. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How dare you. You were And 'cause I think it was the, the, that image of
Speaker 5:  things being all crushed,
Speaker 2:  Being destroyed, like beautiful things being destroyed. Yeah. And to make
Speaker 2:  an iPad
Speaker 5:  And everybody out there in the world is, is really upset. There's a lot of
Speaker 5:  anxiety around AI in so many creative
Speaker 5:  industries. So to have that happen is like, Ooh, you'll miss the
Speaker 5:  mark on that one. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Can I just say, I think the, the like
Speaker 6:  overarching point of the idea that technology is like literally
Speaker 6:  flattening creative culture good and fair and valid and
Speaker 6:  worth fighting about the reaction to this commercial in particular is so
Speaker 6:  stupid. It's, and I just wish everyone would get over it.
Speaker 5:  It's so funny.
Speaker 6:  Like I will say there was a great, I forget who did it and I'm sorry I can't
Speaker 6:  give them credit for it, but there was somebody who literally just ran that
Speaker 6:  commercial in reverse and was like, this is actually much more compelling.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And sells the iPad much better than all of this stuff comes out of
Speaker 6:  the iPad. And I think that's very funny because it wasn't much more like
Speaker 6:  compelling. It was much version of the thing, but also
Speaker 6:  like the idea that everyone is like Apple has always loved
Speaker 6:  creatives and now it's destroying trumpets is like, come on everybody. Like
Speaker 6:  it's, nothing has changed. Apple is trying to tell you that there's lots
Speaker 6:  of things that you can do in an iPad and the fact that smooshed a trumpet
Speaker 6:  to do so is probably fine. The thing is that it's probably fine.
Speaker 6:  Things
Speaker 5:  Have changed for a lot of folks, right? Like things have changed on the other
Speaker 5:  side of it that was totally unrelated to Apple. Like Yeah. It really was
Speaker 5:  just Apple just like stepping in it without even knowing they were stepping
Speaker 5:  in it. Because out there in the world people are furious at
Speaker 5:  technology in general. And then Apple was just like, look, we did a cool
Speaker 5:  iPad. And everybody's like, you'll
Speaker 6:  Die. Yeah. I agree with that. I think, I think the, the broader story here
Speaker 6:  is real, right? Yeah. And Apple is out there talking about ai while everybody
Speaker 6:  is rightly nervous about what AI is going to mean to their creative work.
Speaker 6:  All that stuff is totally fair and valid. It just isn't about this commercial.
Speaker 2:  No, that's what I mean. I think the commercial is like, dude, in a
Speaker 2:  month Apple is gonna announce AI features across its operating systems
Speaker 2:  like huge sweeping AI features
Speaker 2:  from the reports we've read. They're gonna add the we
Speaker 2:  the AI photo editing to photos. Just imagine
Speaker 2:  the, what is a photo conversation we're gonna be having in a month when that
Speaker 2:  stuff is built in at the system level to the iPhone four
Speaker 5:  Hour
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. It's never gonna stop. We're just gonna start VERGE casting right
Speaker 2:  after the keynote ends and we're going straight onto the end of the year.
Speaker 2:  This is officially my two week notice. Liam's out. But
Speaker 2:  I mean like they want to add generative AI
Speaker 2:  capabilities to the products directly. And I think what they just
Speaker 2:  learned is even a hint of breaking
Speaker 2:  creative stuff is bad for them. Like I think the reaction they add is like
Speaker 2:  one don't destroy cool things that we like,
Speaker 2:  like I'm David, I it sounds like you're disdain for trumpets is off the
Speaker 2:  charts. Yeah. Some people think trumpets are cool, right? There's
Speaker 2:  ska bands across the world that are like, what are you doing?
Speaker 5:  David's like, no to ska
Speaker 6:  Destroy all trumpets.
Speaker 2:  There's, you know, there's like a retro arcade cons. Like it's it's just
Speaker 2:  like cool stuff stuff. People like, and they're like Smash, we're doing one
Speaker 2:  of those tiktoks with the hydraulic smashers and now here's an iPad this
Speaker 2:  like sort of soulless corporate pane of glass, right?
Speaker 2:  You take that anxiety just around this ad just around the imagery
Speaker 2:  of that ad and you hand it, you like point it at
Speaker 2:  iOS itself in a month and it's like, oh that's a powder
Speaker 2:  keg actually. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It is. And, and Apple has been, I think the extent to which
Speaker 6:  it has misread the room about how people think about Apple, I think
Speaker 6:  is what has been most telling about this. Because there was a time when
Speaker 6:  Apple really did convince creative
Speaker 6:  people that it was behind them, right? Yeah. And it was, it was making tools
Speaker 6:  even as it was disrupting the music industry and changing the way a lot of
Speaker 6:  this stuff worked. People who made things used Apple products. Like
Speaker 6:  overwhelmingly that was the case. And there was this sense that like, this
Speaker 6:  company made good products in the right way and believes in creative people
Speaker 6:  and cared about this stuff. And Steve Jobs was a Pixar investor. Like all
Speaker 6:  this stuff. And I think between the way that
Speaker 6:  Apple's business model has been sort of aired out like dirty laundry
Speaker 6:  over the last couple of years and the way we've come to understand what it
Speaker 6:  does to developers and the way that all of this stuff is just in
Speaker 6:  general getting subsumed inside of technology. Like there's the bigger
Speaker 6:  story about what technology is doing to the world and to creative people
Speaker 6:  that I think is interesting and important. But there's also a thing that
Speaker 6:  has happened where people don't look at Apple the way Apple thinks that they
Speaker 6:  do anymore. And I think to me that was the thing that was most interesting
Speaker 6:  about this was a bunch of people who otherwise would've been like, oh,
Speaker 6:  Apple's, you know, one of the good ones, they actually care about this stuff.
Speaker 6:  It's a, it's a huge tech company that actually like does the right things
Speaker 6:  the right way. That company does not get the benefit of the doubt anymore.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. No. And I don't know that that's coming back and I think it's gonna
Speaker 6:  really hurt it with AI in a really big way.
Speaker 2:  The thing that I have thought about the moment, like specific phrase
Speaker 2:  that I have been thinking about during this whole commercial kerfuffle, which
Speaker 2:  I agree is I, it's about something else. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 2:  But I have been thinking a lot about Steve Jobs introducing the iPhone
Speaker 2:  four and he held it up and he was admiring his own product in the way that
Speaker 2:  Steve Jobs was want to do. And he said it's like a beautiful old, like a
Speaker 2:  camera
Speaker 2:  And he meant it, right? Like he was like, this is,
Speaker 2:  I loved that thing and I made a thing that is like it
Speaker 2:  and this thing is actually meant to honor that thing. Right. You
Speaker 2:  could, he you just go watch it. You go watch the iPhone four introduction.
Speaker 2:  It's funny 'cause you like dunk some gizmo at the beginning. I'm sorry Alex.
Speaker 2:  It's fine. Alex wasn't there yet. I wasn't there yet. But it's like, you
Speaker 2:  know, it's like a whole thing, right? It's Steve Jobs has to
Speaker 2:  reannounce the product that has been so thoroughly leaked that it has already
Speaker 2:  been disassembled on the internet
Speaker 2:  and he like does a great job. He does. But there's this moment that
Speaker 2:  makes it work that like, makes it click where he is. Like it is like a beautiful,
Speaker 2:  like a camera. And he is just talking about a piece of design that he loves,
Speaker 2:  that represents a way of doing things that he obviously respects. And
Speaker 2:  that's, now here's his iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Contrast that to buy your mom an iPhone. Like that's, that's the journey.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, contrast that to buy your mom an iPhone. Contrast that to we're
Speaker 2:  gonna smash everything into your iPad. Yeah. Right? It's like, oh, now we're
Speaker 2:  a bulldozer. Yeah. Not a participant in this thing.
Speaker 2:  Right? We're not gonna honor the past of creativity with blah blah blah blah
Speaker 2:  blah. Yeah. We've commodified creativity. We are a bunch of accountants who
Speaker 2:  are gonna take our 30% and that is bad. Like I,
Speaker 2:  whatever it is, and I'm sure someone's gonna write to me about Apple stock
Speaker 2:  performance now. Like whatever you wanna think about that, that's great.
Speaker 2:  They're dominant. People love them, but they don't, the
Speaker 2:  benefit of the doubt where the company was led by an artist
Speaker 2:  or someone who held himself out as an artist or a patron of the arts or whatever
Speaker 2:  is gone. And I think this ad is actually a
Speaker 2:  reflection of that, right? It's just, it's an ad, it's a very expensive
Speaker 2:  ad, but it's not born out of a love of those things
Speaker 2:  because If, you truly loved those things. You would not smash them.
Speaker 2:  And like maybe that's just a metaphor, maybe it's silly, maybe it's just
Speaker 2:  a misfire. But a month from now they're gonna launch
Speaker 2:  a bunch of AI features that are trained on a bunch of creative work
Speaker 2:  and they're gonna have to answer a bunch of questions about whether or not
Speaker 2:  they paid for that training data and whether artists are gonna compensate
Speaker 2:  it. And whether If you type into GarageBand make me a beat in the style
Speaker 2:  of whoever that person gets money. And like, are you
Speaker 2:  ready for this? Because the reaction to this ad
Speaker 2:  suggests that you are not, yeah. And I, the same is true Google
Speaker 2:  next week is Google io where they're gonna announce a bunch of ai, like
Speaker 2:  it's just destined to happen. Like I, I can confidently predict
Speaker 2:  that Google is gonna announce a bunch of AI stuff at Google ai.
Speaker 5:  We are gonna talk about Gemini a lot.
Speaker 2:  They're gonna put Gemini in your face and are they ready? Are they
Speaker 2:  ready for that stuff this week? Open AI is, they're leak details of
Speaker 2:  how they're going out to publishers and the publishers are like, you already
Speaker 2:  scraped the data. This is a, this is a head fake. We, we don't trust you.
Speaker 2:  And I, I think this whole industry is kinda like on a razor's edge. Like
Speaker 2:  they don't understand that the lack of trust around AI
Speaker 2:  is gonna come to all of their products, including a relatively
Speaker 2:  innocuous iPad ad. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Agreed.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  Alright. I'm very curious now to see what Iowa 17 brings in. by the way,
Speaker 2:  David, what is the evidence real quick before we break that, that's gonna
Speaker 2:  run Mac West? 'cause that would be my dream.
Speaker 6:  I don't know, there's just a lot of, I think a lot of people who are like,
Speaker 6:  oh, the magic keyboard exists and feels more like a Mac. There's a bigger
Speaker 6:  track pad. People
Speaker 7:  Just want
Speaker 6:  It. Thus, Mac SII challenge anyone to like,
Speaker 6:  try and think about how you would touch the things in your menu bar. Like
Speaker 6:  it's just not a good idea. We should have Mac apps that work should,
Speaker 2:  There's rules. I'm done poking away over here. This is great.
Speaker 5:  I got, I'm trying to, I'm trying to scroll down so I get my menu bar.
Speaker 6:  No, I, as far as I can tell, there is no actual evidence except this thing
Speaker 6:  is stupendously powerful and when you put it in, it kind of feels like a
Speaker 6:  laptop.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right, though, that's my dream. If you're listening to me, Tim,
Speaker 2:  I will trust you again. If. you put Mac
Speaker 6:  West in, it's a bad dream. Tim, don't listen. Turn off the podcast.
Speaker 2:  Tim is in our YouTube comments. He's like, first, that's him every time.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take a break. We'll be right back. And then Alex is gonna
Speaker 2:  tell us about streaming. So buckle up. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 9:  but this year's contest comes
Speaker 5:  That's why you're listening. Don't worry. I get it.
Speaker 2:  The good news is there's not a lot of direct Zav news
Speaker 5:  There. There isn't. No, they had, they had their earnings. Disney's had their
Speaker 5:  earnings. A lot of folks had their earnings this week. And they're, they're,
Speaker 5:  they're doing okay. They're making money. And that's
Speaker 5:  because they have things like ads. Yeah. And, and they're running these companies
Speaker 5:  like businesses that have to make money now rather than just
Speaker 5:  like giving us all free content all the time, which was super sick. That's
Speaker 5:  great. And I'll miss those years, like crazy. But the big stuff was like,
Speaker 5:  Disney, Hulu and Max are all gonna, they're gonna get a bundle at some point
Speaker 5:  this summer, not your child.
Speaker 2:  You know, she walked up to the TV the other day and said, why is there an
Speaker 2:  icon? And said, max. And I, honestly, I
Speaker 2:  challenge you to explain that to a 6-year-old in a way that makes any sense.
Speaker 2:  First of
Speaker 9:  All, kudos to Max
Speaker 2:  Can read that rules.
Speaker 9:  Great. Great job, max.
Speaker 5:  That's awesome. Yeah. Did you start explaining David Zalo to her?
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 2:  Did you start, like, I just challenge you to expl, like try be like you're
Speaker 2:  six years old. You, you cannot start with, there once was a company called
Speaker 2:  Time Warner. That's
Speaker 5:  What I was hoping.
Speaker 2:  But you Right. Like that you're just like, there was a mistake.
Speaker 2:  That's a mistake. This
Speaker 5:  Is how you write a children's book for Max. Just to explain that
Speaker 2:  There was a mistake inside of that icon
Speaker 2:  rests a four three grayscale Batman movie.
Speaker 2:  And I just, I'm sorry. Okay. Like the entire
Speaker 2:  one day, I will tell you the story of the American economy and it will start
Speaker 2:  with that icon.
Speaker 5:  But for now, don't worry about it, max.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So this is where we get to Zla. Obviously Zla runs Warner Brothers
Speaker 2:  Discovery. He's been looking for money. Yeah. He's been looking for growth
Speaker 5:  And, and what better way than to partner up with other companies who
Speaker 5:  are also looking for growth and being like, if we get together, we can offer,
Speaker 5:  offer our stuff cheaper and also not have the FTC come after us
Speaker 5:  constantly for having our own little like, fiefdoms.
Speaker 2:  So they're gonna bundle this up and say, is it,
Speaker 2:  is it gonna be two different apps? Is it three? So I guess Hulu is already
Speaker 2:  in Disney Plus, right?
Speaker 5:  Hulu's already in Disney Plus. That's why it's like that gross color now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They, they're just like, they smashed the balloon to green together. So you
Speaker 2:  you, you sign up, I read the press releases. The press releases are like,
Speaker 2:  we'll release more details later. Yeah. There,
Speaker 5:  There really isn't a lot of details. It really is just like it's coming.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We don't know pricing. We don't know when we just know what's happening.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 2:  You're gonna pay some money Yeah. To someone.
Speaker 5:  Yes. They're gonna figure it out, Eli, and then like, David's very good at
Speaker 5:  this Zaz Love not Pierce.
Speaker 2:  And then you're gonna, I feel like if David Pierce was in charge with, in
Speaker 2:  charge of Warner Brother's discovery.
Speaker 6:  I was gonna say, I honestly believe, like to my bones, that I could run the
Speaker 6:  streaming industry more successfully than any of these clowns. Oh, you
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent the user interface would work.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I just let David do it. Yeah, that's what I'm
Speaker 2:  saying. You're gonna log into two apps. You're gonna have two apps on your,
Speaker 2:  on your Roku still. We don't know.
Speaker 5:  We don't know. Yeah. We, we genuinely don't know most of this stuff. We know
Speaker 5:  that it's, it's coming. We know that there, they're excited about it.
Speaker 6:  I would say by the way, that there is virtually no chance of this being
Speaker 6:  a combined app. Like just from what we've seen on the
Speaker 6:  right. Stuff alone. Like Disney, the work they had to do
Speaker 6:  to integrate the Hulu stuff with Disney Plus, and those are two companies
Speaker 6:  owned by Disney. Yeah. Just the right stuff
Speaker 6:  that wouldn't allow some things on Hulu to be in Disney Plus. So there are
Speaker 6:  things that are in Hulu, the app that are not in Hulu, the tile and Disney
Speaker 6:  Plus, like imagine adding all of a whole nother company to
Speaker 6:  that. I just don't see how that's possible. Like this is, this is good. They're
Speaker 6:  going for Unified login, which is a good idea,
Speaker 6:  is like the most ambitious thing I think comes out of
Speaker 2:  This. Yeah. But the entire idea of these roll-ups to begin with, Disney buying,
Speaker 2:  Fox buying out the rest of Hulu from Comcast
Speaker 2:  disclosure, Comcast as a stake in our parent company, Vox Media,
Speaker 2:  and also people hated Comcast so much. They rebranded their cable company
Speaker 2:  to Xfinity. That's a real story.
Speaker 2:  They don't like me very much. There's a disclosure
Speaker 2:  and then Zav just zaz in his way. Yeah. To merging Warner Brothers and
Speaker 2:  Discovery. Right. The idea there was always scale, right? Yeah. Like the,
Speaker 2:  the specific pitch for Warner Brothers discovery was we will have HBO
Speaker 2:  for your appointment Sunday night viewing. And then the rest of the time
Speaker 2:  when you're like, I don't know, what are those Property Brothers doing? You'll
Speaker 2:  just like, turn that on and watch TikTok in the background. Right? Like and
Speaker 2:  they explicitly made this, this is the idea. Like the bundle will be so big,
Speaker 2:  you'll subscribe to it, it'll be great for you,
Speaker 5:  But bundles can get bigger
Speaker 2:  And that's what the like this has run out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Basically they need other content. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  it is unrealistic to expect people to only watch Netflix. It
Speaker 5:  is unrealistic to expect people to only watch Disney Plus unless they're
Speaker 5:  like under the age of five, in which case it's super realistic. But like,
Speaker 2:  Did you see that set by the way? One out of three, one out of every three
Speaker 2:  shows in Disney Plus is a Bluey stream. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wow. Is it just Max? Just over
Speaker 2:  And Wow. It's like 30% of all Disney plus streaming is bluey. That's insane.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Oh my gosh. It's like this company is extremely
Speaker 2:  beholden to an Australian dog. Wow. I don't wanna talk about Blue at this
Speaker 2:  time.
Speaker 2:  David, your kid isn't old enough to know, but when, when it comes time
Speaker 2:  it'll be, it'll be very sad for you as well. But, so the bundles get bigger.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But why doesn't Netflix have this pressure?
Speaker 5:  Because Netflix is huge. Like, like Netflix is, is bigger than
Speaker 5:  kind of everybody else, right? Right. They have that first mover advantage.
Speaker 5:  So they can just be, they're so far ahead of everybody else when it comes
Speaker 5:  to subscribers and stuff that they can just keep doing that and they can
Speaker 5:  keep asking for more money. And also,
Speaker 5:  this is the Alex who put them higher on the Go 90 scale than
Speaker 5:  some of the other people. They've got Hubris, right? Yeah. Like they, they,
Speaker 5:  they, they still haven't worked partnered with Apple. So, so you don't really
Speaker 5:  get that. So that tight integration with like
Speaker 5:  the Apple products that you get with, with Disney Plus and Max and all these
Speaker 5:  other ones, they don't partner with everybody else as often because they
Speaker 5:  are the biggest. And oftentimes when you do that,
Speaker 5:  your hubris catches up with you eventually. So I like, I think it's a kind
Speaker 5:  of a mistake for Netflix to not try to do this, but I'm not surprised
Speaker 5:  by it because it's also the most, like, these are entertainment companies.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Netflix is a technology company.
Speaker 2:  So you made a YouTube video this week. You basically, like the cable bundle
Speaker 2:  is back's and that's what's hap that's what's happening here, right? You
Speaker 2:  got Disney, the Hulu assets, they're gonna puts
Speaker 2:  ESPN plus in the Disney plus app. That's the cable bundle.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You're, you're subsidizing all this stuff that you want that you don't
Speaker 5:  necessarily want. 'cause I know you guys love sports,
Speaker 2:  But you have to, you are just SN will be here.
Speaker 5:  I'm furious that I'm gonna have an ES, ESPN on my Disney Plus.
Speaker 2:  Well, and we don't know what the pricing will be. And then you get all the
Speaker 2:  sort of Warner Brothers assets now too, plus HBO
Speaker 5:  Depending on what the price is, right? Like you could find, it could end
Speaker 5:  up being that the price is the exact same, only the only differences
Speaker 5:  that it's just more convenient to log in. Well,
Speaker 2:  So we do have this quote from Zaz. I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  just so worried about
Speaker 5:  Zdi. There we go. Sorry, I had to do it.
Speaker 2:  I'm so tired.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  If you ever that man, like, I can't, I just walk
Speaker 2:  Away. I I won't let you as, as somebody who's responsible for this newsroom
Speaker 2:  and your friend.
Speaker 5:  He was like, no, we can't go that way.
Speaker 2:  Just can you imagine having to work with somebody every day who's
Speaker 2:  horny for David?
Speaker 2:  That's what it's like here at The. Verge. All right. Here's the quote from,
Speaker 2:  from,
Speaker 2:  It's like the New York Times is like dealing with Kevin Roos being like,
Speaker 2:  I banged 18 robots on ai and we had Alex. I'm just
Speaker 2:  like, Eile very different. Loves it. by the way, you should read the Kevin
Speaker 2:  Roo article where he did make friends with 18. It's very different AI personalities.
Speaker 2:  And even from the jump he is like, it's a little horny. He's like,
Speaker 2:  it's good. Anyway, here's a quote from David Zav. There's
Speaker 2:  a lot of irrationality in the market that's getting shaken out in terms of
Speaker 2:  money spent. Ultimately, I think the business will look very different in
Speaker 2:  two to three years. It will be much better for consumers.
Speaker 2:  A lot of ideas in that quote. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I like, basically they're just bringing TV back.
Speaker 5:  And, and in a lot of ways TV is quite convenient. Yeah. People loved it
Speaker 5:  for 50, 60 years. It, it, it worked and, and then everybody was like, we're
Speaker 5:  tired of all the ads and everything else. And that's why we got streaming
Speaker 5:  to begin with. And that's just what he's doing. Like I think he's very right
Speaker 5:  in that there are a lot of bad ideas and they are being shake, shaken out.
Speaker 5:  That's why everybody's going to advertising. That's why everybody is bundling.
Speaker 5:  That's why everybody is subsidizing sports and, and all of this other stuff.
Speaker 5:  But I don't know if it'll be better for consumers in 3D
Speaker 5:  years.
Speaker 6:  I think the, the one other thing that's worth mentioning here is it's, it's
Speaker 6:  very telling to me that what he says is in terms of the amount of money spent.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think If, you wanna talk about what's different about Netflix
Speaker 6:  versus these other companies is Netflix can afford to
Speaker 6:  exist. Whereas you have Disney, which spent way too much
Speaker 6:  money to acquire Fox. You have Warner Brothers discovery, which
Speaker 6:  took on a massive quantity of debt in order to become the company that
Speaker 6:  it is. These companies literally cannot afford to exist in
Speaker 6:  the way that they currently work. Whereas Netflix, I think it was in
Speaker 6:  20 21, 20 20 or 2021, announced basically
Speaker 6:  like, we're good. We have enough money now that we don't have to take external
Speaker 6:  financing. And that puts you in such an unbelievable position of power
Speaker 6:  to be able to just do whatever you want because you can afford your business.
Speaker 6:  And what no one else has proven other than Netflix is that this is a business
Speaker 6:  that you can afford
Speaker 2:  Or it has the margins that you grow. Right? Like Netflix is
Speaker 2:  actually, maybe the easiest way to talk about this is the Go 90 scale of
Speaker 2:  Doom streaming services. So Netflix to me, I know Alex,
Speaker 5:  I'm on the other side, but I get it
Speaker 2:  Completely thinks Netflix will fail. But by the way, disclosure are produce
Speaker 2:  Netflix show. It's called The Future of It's very good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Likely Story support 'em. Huh?
Speaker 2:  They really did rebranded Xfinity. 'cause everyone hated the Comcast brand.
Speaker 2:  So that is a true story. I heard it again recently. I put Netflix
Speaker 2:  at zero by the way. The Go 90 Scale If, you remember Go 90. It's Verizon's
Speaker 2:  failed streaming service where they thought children would join quote gangs.
Speaker 2:  No, it's a cruise. It was something they thought the kids would rotate their
Speaker 2:  phones 90 degrees to watch YouTube and they had no idea why anyone was watching
Speaker 2:  YouTube. And it immediately failed
Speaker 5:  Quibi. Before Quibi.
Speaker 2:  It was a lot.
Speaker 2:  Now to go, 90 means to die. This is ver has
Speaker 2:  lore if you're unfamiliar, so the Go 90 scale is driven streaming services
Speaker 2:  from zero to 90. You put them on a scale, zero is alive. 90
Speaker 2:  said Netflix in my mind is zero right now. It is
Speaker 2:  the one you don't quit. No one turns off a Netflix right
Speaker 5:  Now. It is a hundred percent zero. I would, I would agree with you there.
Speaker 6:  I will say Alex said it was a 40 at South by Southwest. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Few months ago. It's a 40 in my heart. And in the future it's zero.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 2:  Today because you think the hubris makes them brittle. I I understand the
Speaker 2:  argument. Yeah. But I just don't, I think Netflix is very good at
Speaker 2:  programming. Its service. Exactly. To make you never churn. They're like,
Speaker 2:  here's one more John Malaney special, like Bridger
Speaker 5:  Bridger's coming, man,
Speaker 2:  I'm so excited. It's just always, they're always doing that thing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You're like ready to quit and they got one more thing for you. Good. They
Speaker 2:  figured it out. Data,
Speaker 2:  HBO or now Max, whatever the hell it's called,
Speaker 2:  like Max is 45.
Speaker 2:  Like there it, it is, they're gonna, they hit a
Speaker 2:  hundred million subscribers globally, but they're about to hike prices again
Speaker 2:  because of what David is saying, they cannot afford to run this business.
Speaker 2:  It's programming is all over the place. Right. They have
Speaker 2:  HBO's programming, but HBO's in one of, its sort of like consistent sort
Speaker 2:  of like dry spells. I'm sure there'll be more stuff coming back, but
Speaker 2:  that's the history of HBO. It runs hot, then it runs cold.
Speaker 2:  There isn't some like consistent slate of programming. Yes.
Speaker 5:  There is those Property Brothers, people love.
Speaker 2:  Well there's that stuff, but there isn't like the, I mean that
Speaker 5:  Like we can't ignore it. It's something that maybe we don't talk about like
Speaker 5:  critically and you don't see people talking about it on threads and, and
Speaker 5:  social media and stuff. But that is a big part of their business. That's
Speaker 5:  why LOV could afford to buy Warner Brothers is because of how
Speaker 5:  big that business is for 'em. And I don't, that's not going away anytime
Speaker 5:  soon. He's really,
Speaker 2:  But that's the discovery business. That's the
Speaker 5:  Discovery business that's now in Max.
Speaker 2:  Sure. Okay. I'm just saying 45. Yeah, I know. 'cause you're not
Speaker 2:  running around trying to make a deal with Disney If, you think you're more
Speaker 2:  alive than dead. Yeah. Is just my belief.
Speaker 6:  Well, and this is why the sports race is so intense right now because I think
Speaker 6:  the, the property brothers will keep people subscribed to you. They're not
Speaker 6:  going to win you vast tens of millions of new
Speaker 6:  subscribers.
Speaker 5:  But I also wanna be wary of saying that this deal is an indication
Speaker 5:  that Disney and Max are struggling. Because I don't think, like, I think
Speaker 5:  this is as much about dealing with the fact that these are highly vertically
Speaker 5:  integrated companies and there's currently a government that doesn't like
Speaker 5:  that. And, and it's really useful to be like, no, we're partnering together.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 2:  You think that in the absence of Lena Kahn, Disney would buy Warner
Speaker 2:  Brothers discovery
Speaker 5:  If, if Lena Khan got sucked up by aliens
Speaker 5:  tomorrow and
Speaker 2:  If Trump gets elected.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and they managed to sell E-E-S-P-N so they can make all their
Speaker 5:  money. They would buy it in a heartbeat
Speaker 6:  No chance. No. With what money. I said
Speaker 5:  I I had to, I that's why I put all those, those clarifiers on there. Right.
Speaker 6:  Let's, let's add your debt to our debt and we'll give you 50 bucks and then
Speaker 6:  we'll all slowly die
Speaker 2:  Together. Wait, actually David, when you describe it like that, that does
Speaker 2:  sound like the media business.
Speaker 5:  That is,
Speaker 2:  That does, that's how it works. In fact, sound how these CEOs think. That
Speaker 2:  is basically fair. Let's let's lay off 10,000 people and have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  debt. Somehow we will get boats. And is Zach Snyder
Speaker 2:  available? Because we have a number of movies. We recut is Grayscale Squares.
Speaker 5:  Hollywood is built on debt there. They this way financing has worked in
Speaker 5:  Hollywood from the beginning is is on debt. Nothing is ever made with like
Speaker 5:  the cash they have in house. Yeah. It's made with the future.
Speaker 2:  Usually the assumption has been that the property will make money. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  A pro a problem that they're having anyway. Well, they'll be
Speaker 2:  fine. Okay, so I'm putting Max at 45. I'm putting Disney
Speaker 2:  Disney plus at 45. That's, that's, that's my go 90
Speaker 2:  scale. I I think these things are are wobbly in the middle right now?
Speaker 5:  No. Disney Disney is massive and, and like streaming is a big part
Speaker 5:  of Disney's business. Streaming is not all of Disney's business of all of
Speaker 5:  these companies. It is super positioned because it's got a ton
Speaker 5:  of very lucrative theme parks
Speaker 2:  Throughout the world. I just want to point out that technically the Max app
Speaker 2:  has already gone 90 several times as it has rebranded from
Speaker 2:  HBO to HBO Max to Max every
Speaker 5:  Other month. It goes
Speaker 2:  90. Like it's go it keeps going away in some way. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well I think the, this, this all sort of revolves around Netflix in a funny
Speaker 6:  way, which is why Netflix is so powerful in all this. Because I
Speaker 6:  think the, the case for Disney Plus going away is that Disney decides that
Speaker 6:  actually if we want our theme parks to succeed, the best way for us
Speaker 6:  to do that is to sell shows to Netflix and not put them on Disney Plus, which
Speaker 6:  I think is a not crazy Yeah. Conclusion to draw in a couple of years.
Speaker 6:  You're gonna decide it is so expensive and so wasteful for us to
Speaker 6:  run our own service. What we actually need is for people to watch our stuff.
Speaker 6:  And the way to do that is to put it in movie theaters and put it on Netflix.
Speaker 6:  And I think it's possible that that is where this goes.
Speaker 2:  We come back to this at the end of the summer if and when we
Speaker 2:  find out there whether or not there will be more bluey episodes because
Speaker 2:  it's honestly depending on that answer,
Speaker 2:  Disney Plus goes in one of two directions. If If, you just look at the scale
Speaker 2:  of how much that business is currently dependent on Bluey it, it's not
Speaker 2:  dependent on whatever horrible garbage Max watches otherwise. So
Speaker 2:  there's a show about the, the children of the villains. It's bad. All the
Speaker 2:  descendants.
Speaker 5:  Why do I know that?
Speaker 2:  I've never seen anything worse in my entire life.
Speaker 5:  I've never watched it.
Speaker 2:  It's fine. It's like very safe If. you have a 6-year-old girl, you're like,
Speaker 2:  watch this garbage. It's better than what's on YouTube kids.
Speaker 2:  But I'm saying depending on how Bluey goes, I I we should come back to that
Speaker 2:  conversation. Okay. We should take a break. I will call out by the way that
Speaker 2:  Sony is in the middle of discussions to buy Paramount.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I hope not. 'cause it's with Apollo management, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That that's just layoff city. That's what's gonna happen. Yeah. That, that's
Speaker 2:  the, all the headlines about Sony and Paramount should be like Sony discusses
Speaker 2:  laying off Paramount's employees,
Speaker 5:  But they're still also in talks with Skydance, which is owned by Larry Ellison's
Speaker 5:  son from Oracle. Yeah. And that could still happen. That's the one I'm
Speaker 5:  mainly rooting for because I hate watching companies be bought up
Speaker 5:  and broken apart.
Speaker 2:  You love CBS
Speaker 5:  Also. I love, I I'm, I is it really because I'm concerned about Star Trek?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  There's a very good episode by the way of the Town podcast where they talk
Speaker 6:  about this and basically land on If. you want good content
Speaker 6:  root for the Skydance deal. If, you want a bunch of Paramount
Speaker 6:  shareholders to make money and then all of this to go away. You should root
Speaker 6:  for Sony and Apollo.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm like slightly simplifying but not that much. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's, that's that's act that's a hundred percent correct. If. you want Star
Speaker 5:  Trek root for Skydance If. you don't care about Star Trek
Speaker 5:  and Taylor Sheridan's ranches root for Apollo
Speaker 5:  and Sony. Wait,
Speaker 2:  I I that's a, that's a bad mix of things to care about.
Speaker 2:  How do I get one but not the other?
Speaker 2:  Okay. We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back with the lightning round,
Speaker 2:  which is actually has to be lightning 'cause we are so over today,
Speaker 2:  but it's gonna be really long. We'll be right back with the front chest.
Speaker 12:  Once upon a time in America there was no such thing as all you can
Speaker 12:  eat shrimp. And then the world changed. Today
Speaker 13:  Shrimp is the most popular, the most consumed seafood in
Speaker 13:  America. The endless Shrimp Fiesta is an American
Speaker 13:  institution,
Speaker 12:  But that Shrimp Fiesta comes at a steep price. Here at Gastropod,
Speaker 12:  we found out that hidden behind the delicious shrimp on your plate is
Speaker 12:  environmental disaster and modern day slavery.
Speaker 13:  So can you have your shrimp and a clear conscience too actually
Speaker 13:  Yes. And we've got the secret to help you unlock true
Speaker 13:  lifelong shrimp happiness. Listen to the latest episode of Gastropod
Speaker 13:  wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. It's the lightning round, which really for me is what
Speaker 2:  I have taken to calling the victory lap round. But let's begin with Alex.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Not a victory lap.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This is sad
Speaker 5:  For, for mine. Yeah. No, this is a bummer. Microsoft is currently going
Speaker 5:  through it. Tom Warren had a really great piece up this week and Ash Paris,
Speaker 5:  our game reporter, had a really cool follow piece on it.
Speaker 5:  They, they've been closing studios, they've been laying people off. They
Speaker 5:  they had to bake all hands after they, they closed this one studio that
Speaker 5:  made this really popular game last year called Hi Fi Rush If. you haven't
Speaker 5:  heard about it. That's because you don't play video games enough. Hi-Fi Rush
Speaker 5:  was like a big indie darling and it was widely well
Speaker 5:  received. It did really, really well for them. And then they said
Speaker 5:  they laid off every, they they like closed the studio. Yeah. They laid everybody
Speaker 5:  off and, and they were like, yeah, we need to make more games like that.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, well
Speaker 5:  maybe. Hmm. And so there's just a lot of chaos over there and, and I
Speaker 5:  think it's the same thing we're seeing, you know, we've talked a lot about
Speaker 5:  creatives in this episode. It's that same anxiety. It's the, the same issues
Speaker 5:  that we're seeing with streaming where these people have spent a lot of money
Speaker 5:  on acquisitions and growing during the 0% interest rate days
Speaker 5:  and they, they grew a whole lot and
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  You can't grow in like infinite content has to have infinite
Speaker 5:  people watching it and paying for it.
Speaker 5:  We don't do that in this human life.
Speaker 6:  It is a remarkably similar trajectory. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  Microsoft saying, okay, we, we think this is gonna move
Speaker 6:  from a AYA thing model to a subscription model. Thus
Speaker 6:  we need a lot of content. Oh God, we need a lot of exclusive content to
Speaker 6:  okay, maybe actually there aren't as many people who want to
Speaker 6:  pay for all of this, especially given what it costs because all this stuff
Speaker 6:  is expensive. Bail, bale, bale, bale, bale. And then so you, you go
Speaker 6:  from like, we have to grow to the size of the universe in order for this
Speaker 6:  thing to work. And then you realize, oh, it's actually not possible for us
Speaker 6:  to grow to the size of the universe in the same way that everybody thought
Speaker 6:  they were gonna get a billion subscribers to streaming services. Like no,
Speaker 6:  it turns out there is kind of a local maximum to that and
Speaker 6:  people
Speaker 5:  Are finite unfortunately.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and it turns out I think Microsoft is going through the same thing
Speaker 6:  now where it's like, okay, we, if we build this unbelievable war chest of
Speaker 6:  content and people and talent, it will
Speaker 6:  work. And then all of a sudden everybody's like, oh, that's not a plan. That's
Speaker 6:  nothing. Yeah. And it all just kind of collapses. And it's really sad because
Speaker 6:  it's happening at like unbelievable scale and pace right now.
Speaker 5:  And it's also in an industry that I think was already unsustainable to begin
Speaker 5:  with, with Crunch and everything like that. Like this was an industry that's
Speaker 5:  been creaking for a decade and, and I it's it's having
Speaker 5:  a massive moment and I, it sucks for all the people involved, but like
Speaker 5:  it's happening. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I just wanna point out that Microsoft fought tooth and nail to buy Activision.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And they were like, this will grow our business. This is the thing.
Speaker 2:  And really the question we should ask with all of these deals, how many people
Speaker 2:  are you gonna lay off? How many is it? It's always some,
Speaker 6:  Wasn't it T-Mobile that said in buying Sprint that it thought the number
Speaker 6:  of jobs were gonna go up and everybody's like, ah, sick. And then they immediately
Speaker 6:  let off thousands people immediately.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like that's not true. It's never true.
Speaker 2:  And I, it just like, it's the thing like you combine two companies,
Speaker 2:  there are gonna be a lot, there's gonna be overlap. It's, it's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  I I interview a lot of executives, you can just see the wheels turning,
Speaker 2:  boy, I don't need double the back office staff. Like whatever. You can just,
Speaker 2:  and they call it efficiencies and it's really layoffs and that's just like
Speaker 2:  how it goes. And then on top of it, Microsoft was
Speaker 2:  insistent that it needed to buy Activision because it was winning
Speaker 2:  while Microsoft was losing and they bought Activision and they're like, look
Speaker 2:  at all these losers. And it's like, we, we
Speaker 2:  should start asking the questions ahead. How many people are you gonna lay
Speaker 2:  off? That's the only question, right? Like that is the policy
Speaker 2:  consequence of allowing these mergers at scale. Like really truly on the
Speaker 2:  ground, a bunch of people are gonna lose their jobs. How many is it?
Speaker 2:  And if, if they're not willing to answer that question, I honestly think
Speaker 2:  like Yeah. Don't, we should no longer give any of these companies a benefit
Speaker 2:  of the
Speaker 6:  Doubt. Yeah. You don't get to just buy
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I would point out that at and t buying Time Warner did allow Zach Snyder
Speaker 2:  to employ a number of people to make a four three gray scale Batman movie.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Nila, do you get a cut of sales of this movie? Like what, what we, what is
Speaker 6:  happening? We've officially tipped from like, this is funny to like what's
Speaker 6:  NE's angle here?
Speaker 2:  I just, I just wanna, I want to hammer it home for people
Speaker 2:  that the Trump administration getting rid of net neutrality
Speaker 2:  allowed at t to by the Time Warner and now there is a Gray Scout Batman
Speaker 2:  movie and that is a direct line of events by the way. Net neutrality did
Speaker 2:  pass. They got rid of the weird rule that would've allowed for 5G fat lane
Speaker 2:  pass lanes. We now live in a world of not child again. It's great. Sorry
Speaker 2:  Zach. Alright. Victory lap one complete victory lap
Speaker 2:  two for me.
Speaker 2:  This is, this is the whole lightning round just ne I was right about,
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry.
Speaker 2:  You'll recall that Epic Games sued Apple for
Speaker 2:  antitrust violations long ago. They mostly lost that case.
Speaker 2:  They did. They they mostly lost that case. I would say they, they might have
Speaker 2:  set the stage for the current DOJ case for other cases or they, they
Speaker 2:  made a bunch of arguments that are now being made again by the government
Speaker 2:  in different ways. They got a ball rolling, very much got a ball rolling.
Speaker 2:  The one thing they wanted in that case was
Speaker 2:  the judge applying California law because I think the judge
Speaker 2:  was unwilling to rewrite United States federal antitrust law. But the judge
Speaker 2:  interpreted California law to say Apple could no longer
Speaker 2:  prevent app developers from what's called steering. So Apple
Speaker 2:  has these things called anti steering rules where you are not even allowed
Speaker 2:  to mention that there's another website where you could buy stuff.
Speaker 2:  Anti steering rules struck down. I have the
Speaker 2:  specific quote here. Apple is permanently restrained and enjoyed from
Speaker 2:  prohibiting developers from including in their apps and their metadata buttons,
Speaker 2:  external links or other calls to action that direct customers to purchasing
Speaker 2:  mechanisms in addition to the app store. That's the rule.
Speaker 2:  Judge passes this rule
Speaker 6:  And Apple's response was to allow a app or a link rather.
Speaker 2:  Right? So the rule comes out and I wrote a piece
Speaker 2:  back then 2021 saying Apple's about to end up in a fight
Speaker 2:  over buttons and links like they're not allowed to prevent buttons and
Speaker 2:  links from going to external purchasing me mechanisms. When
Speaker 2:  courts write two nouns, they often mean
Speaker 2:  for the nouns to mean different things. So now you have buttons and you have
Speaker 2:  links that, that they necessarily mean different things. This
Speaker 2:  is just legal interpretation 1 0 1. I would say the
Speaker 2:  AstroTurf brigade attacked me. Some developers tried this, they went in
Speaker 2:  front of the court again, the judge said, I look, stop it.
Speaker 2:  Like we'll figure this out when we get there. I I, apple has to issue its
Speaker 2:  entitlements and do all this stuff and everyone thought I was wrong. This
Speaker 2:  is true. This is like a real sequence events that I'm very hot about. The
Speaker 2:  point of all this is Epic went to the judge
Speaker 2:  recently and said Apple is only allowing one external link to a
Speaker 2:  fixed webpage and you are not even allowed to say it's cheaper
Speaker 2:  on the webpage. Like all of the rules about what you're allowed to do to
Speaker 2:  get around anti steering are basically anti steering. It's such a
Speaker 6:  Punk thing. You're basically allowed to say this is a website.
Speaker 2:  Yep. And it's, it's at the very beginning of the flow, right? So If, you
Speaker 2:  have an app with other things you can buy in it. You are not even allowed
Speaker 2:  in that area of your app to put links to an external website
Speaker 2:  where you can buy stuff. It's beautiful If, you are allowed to have one link.
Speaker 2:  That link when you click on it, if you're logged into the app, can't even
Speaker 2:  pass your login info to the website.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I always think of the Kindle app as the easiest way to explain this
Speaker 6:  because it's like the, the way it should work is you should be able to go
Speaker 6:  into, I mean the way it should work is you should be able to buy Kindle stuff
Speaker 6:  from your, but there should be a link on every book that says buy this on
Speaker 6:  the web. That is explicitly against the rules. You can have one link
Speaker 6:  in one place in the app that says books
Speaker 6:  on web. That's, that's basically the entirety of what is
Speaker 6:  allowed by Apple. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Or or or sign up on web but not four 30% cheaper or not it's
Speaker 2:  cheaper on the web because Apple charges us a fee. Right. None of that's
Speaker 2:  allowed. Do they get the
Speaker 5:  Preposition? Like is the preposition allowed the on,
Speaker 2:  I mean Apple's totally in control of this. Oh by the way If, you click the
Speaker 2:  link, you get a warning screen that says you're leaving this app where Tim
Speaker 2:  Cook will protect you with sword and shield. This
Speaker 5:  Is a buff Tim Cook picture.
Speaker 2:  This is all true. So epic drags apple back into court where the, 'cause the
Speaker 2:  judge in 2121 said, I will decide if apple's in compliance with my injunction
Speaker 2:  not Apple. I'm gonna decide. So the judge, so epic
Speaker 2:  drags apple back to court. There's a, there's a hearing this week. I just
Speaker 2:  wanna read you some things that were said in this hearing to Apple
Speaker 2:  as they talk about buttons and links
Speaker 2:  and this is to an Apple executive. Is it fair to say in today's
Speaker 2:  day and age that everyone understands that
Speaker 2:  www.url.com is an external website on the worldwide web?
Speaker 2:  That's just a question like do you really think people are this stupid apple
Speaker 2:  Pete in society people make lots of purchases on the web all the time. Would
Speaker 2:  you agree with that? Yes.
Speaker 2:  And they understand that Apple trusts its users that the web is separate
Speaker 2:  and apart from different even on an iOS device, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do do people know that clicking on a link, taking you out of an app takes
Speaker 2:  you outta the app. That's where Apple is in buttons and links
Speaker 2:  and then there's the judge who interjects in the middle of a
Speaker 2:  conversation about button design because Apple has
Speaker 2:  constricted the design of buttons.
Speaker 2:  I can't imagine a logical reason why Apple would demand that of competitor
Speaker 2:  apps. What's a logical competitive reason for not
Speaker 2:  suggesting but demanding it other than to stifle
Speaker 2:  competition? I see no answer. Can you give me one
Speaker 2:  buttons and links?
Speaker 5:  Did they give
Speaker 2:  Them, it took three years? No, no. To just blah blah blah security. Oh it
Speaker 2:  took three years. But Apple is now in this fight
Speaker 2:  over the design of buttons and links in its apps because that
Speaker 2:  injunction is actually a big deal and they have not
Speaker 2:  actually provided a reason why they are constraining the
Speaker 2:  design of buttons and links in their apps. Which by the way are different.
Speaker 2:  A button is supposed just do something, a link is, takes
Speaker 2:  you somewhere else, right? So these are different in terms of construction
Speaker 2:  and I think Apple and it's hubris, all the stuff we've talked about, they've
Speaker 2:  run into the judge saying, no, no, I meant something when I issued this order
Speaker 2:  and you can't give me reasons that are not just straight anti-competitive,
Speaker 2:  malicious compliance reasons. I dunno this is gonna turn out, it's just an
Speaker 2:  evidentiary hearing right now. Maybe the judge is gonna find apple's not
Speaker 2:  in compliance. Maybe this DOJ lawsuit's gonna break it all open. I
Speaker 2:  don't know, maybe a bunch of Europeans are gonna hurl cheese at Apple until
Speaker 2:  they're stop it. Something's gonna happen. But I'm just saying right now,
Speaker 2:  three years after the epic case, apple's in a courtroom
Speaker 2:  defending its own malicious compliance because it was inevitable that
Speaker 2:  the buttons and links conversation would come back around.
Speaker 6:  And it's been interesting to watch these fights get more and more specific
Speaker 6:  over time too. And I think this is the thing that is actually
Speaker 6:  going to affect real change, right? Like we talked about this with the emulators
Speaker 6:  the other week. Yes. That as these things get whittled down from these sort
Speaker 6:  of big philosophical debates into like here is a thing about the experience
Speaker 6:  that is broken and you can't explain to me why it's broken other than
Speaker 6:  you believe you deserve all of the money. That is actually the way that Apple
Speaker 6:  is being pride open and it is happening like in these little tiny pieces
Speaker 6:  much more quickly than it's going to happen in some grand. Yeah. You're not
Speaker 6:  allowed to be like this anymore way. So I think it's like the, the death
Speaker 6:  by a thousand cuts thing is like very much underway in a really fascinating
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And this stuff takes time. Like the DOJ lawsuit, that's a decade.
Speaker 6:  Oh easily It's,
Speaker 2:  Its a decade. Like you can decide whether it is good or bad. You can have
Speaker 2:  whatever feelings about the complaint you want a decade from now. We will
Speaker 2:  see the results of that case on how the devices we use. It took
Speaker 2:  three years from the Epic case for us to be back in a courtroom saying
Speaker 2:  actually your weird link entitlement idea might be anti-competitive and that
Speaker 2:  still has to play out. So I would just, you need some patience here. But
Speaker 2:  I agree with you David. It's like it's starting in a way that Apple can no
Speaker 2:  longer defend.
Speaker 5:  I just spent a lot of this time on meta AI trying to make it
Speaker 5:  show me images of a shredded Tim Cook protecting people from
Speaker 5:  buttons and links and it wouldn't do it.
Speaker 6:  I went to
Speaker 6:  www.url.comwhileweweresittinghereanddiscoveredthaturl.com
Speaker 6:  is for sale. So that's cool.
Speaker 2:  I just think If, you have your executives on the stand and the question is,
Speaker 2:  people in society make lots of purchases on the web all the time. Would you
Speaker 2:  agree? And the answer is yes. Like
Speaker 6:  You're probably done for so good Eli, in in,
Speaker 6:  in the spirit of kindness, I would like to bequeath you my lightning round
Speaker 6:  because you have another victory lap I'd like you to take.
Speaker 2:  I do, I do. I do. I'm very excited about this one. I'll make this one quick.
Speaker 2:  'cause again, in this fixture app, nothing has happened. So we'll end
Speaker 2:  the show where we began
Speaker 6:  In Wisconsin
Speaker 2:  In south in southeastern Wisconsin where I was a child.
Speaker 5:  Were the cheese curds really
Speaker 2:  Squeaky. They're good, they're good, they're good. Everyone in Wisconsin,
Speaker 2:  they're particularly well Madison. I would say Madison is where I, where
Speaker 2:  I enjoyed the cheese curd lifestyle the most. But President
Speaker 2:  Biden was in Racine this week. He was announcing
Speaker 2:  a data center built to be built by Microsoft. So we had 2000
Speaker 2:  construction jobs and then 2000 permanent jobs to build this data center.
Speaker 2:  This is, I would just say politically opportunistic at its finest.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Microsoft had already purchased this land. They were already, they
Speaker 2:  had already announced the data center. They'd already done all the permitting,
Speaker 2:  all the stuff. Joe Biden just showed up and was like, look at the jobs
Speaker 2:  I made. Great. I'm super excited for like do politics. I'm
Speaker 2:  happy for you. The point of this is that they are building this
Speaker 2:  on the land that was supposed to be the Foxcon site and
Speaker 2:  Joe Biden's political opportunism is he's standing there and he
Speaker 2:  is like literally, I think he said something along the lines of Trump didn't
Speaker 2:  give you any jobs that I'm giving you actual jobs because it's the Foxcon
Speaker 2:  site where Trump waved a golden shovel around and promised an LCD factory
Speaker 2:  that was supposed to bring 13,000 jobs to this region. And we
Speaker 2:  at The Verge, someone famously always knew that was a lie,
Speaker 2:  reported on it quite a bit. We won an award. Josh has won an award for his
Speaker 2:  big feature on it. That feature, actually Chris Hayes read it on M-S-N-B-C
Speaker 2:  last night like just straight up. He was like, Biden announced some things.
Speaker 2:  You might remember this as Fox on and then just read some of
Speaker 2:  Josh's feature to the camera. That's awesome. To explain what had happened.
Speaker 2:  There are rules. Congratulations to Josh. He reported the hell of that story.
Speaker 2:  The victory lap I would like to take is to remind everyone and
Speaker 2:  to initiate our, our newest members of the audience. During
Speaker 2:  that period of time while we were doing all that reporting, I received a
Speaker 2:  number of hilariously threatening emails from anonymous foxcon executives
Speaker 2:  telling us, reminding us, insisting that we leave them alone.
Speaker 2:  Literally the emails would say leave us alone. And then they would try to
Speaker 2:  explain to me what Foxconn's AI plus eight K
Speaker 2:  plus 5G strategy was Galaxy brand strategy. It
Speaker 2:  was nothing. by the way Fox on has abandoned ai eight k plus 5G.
Speaker 2:  This is true. They've abandoned it. If. you go to the Fox on in Wisconsin
Speaker 2:  website now, which is literally, I believe just foxcon in Wisconsin dot com.
Speaker 2:  You can see they have a new strategy which is three plus three equals infinity.
Speaker 2:  This is true.
Speaker 6:  It's even worse.
Speaker 2:  How did they make it worse? It's a hundred percent true. Oh God. That their
Speaker 2:  new strategy is three plus three equals infinity. And then there's a lengthy
Speaker 2:  section of that website dedicated to how you can see the,
Speaker 2:  the dome that they built from the highway.
Speaker 2:  I dunno what to tell you man. They built a little dome. It's like, I keep
Speaker 2:  calling it temu Epcot like it's a little baby dome by a dome. It was supposed
Speaker 2:  to be the dot of an I. Oh, they were gonna spell
Speaker 2:  Foxcon. FII Foxconn industrial internet. They were gonna spell it in buildings
Speaker 2:  and it's a dome.
Speaker 14:  A lot of letters.
Speaker 2:  It's a lot. Well it's only three. They only got to the dot, which is the
Speaker 2:  dome. They insisted for years. This is true that the dome was a
Speaker 2:  data center. And I would have various conversations
Speaker 2:  with like data center people do like, would you ever make a data center
Speaker 2:  in the shape of a dome? Do you think that would be? And they would all be
Speaker 2:  like, no, I don't. I don't know. We wouldn't. It turns out the dome was just
Speaker 2:  like a like a party center. Yeah. It was like where corrupt Wisconsin politicians
Speaker 2:  would have drinks and take photos with
Speaker 14:  The dome. With
Speaker 2:  Their dome. The dome remains. That whole thing remains.
Speaker 2:  I know what's gonna happen there. There's some rumor, the building servers.
Speaker 2:  Microsoft is now taking all of the industrialization that was built up the
Speaker 2:  water, the power, da da da to build an AI data data center.
Speaker 2:  Alright? But I want to end here with one of the best things that has ever
Speaker 2:  happened on the show. Okay? Which is all those emails that got
Speaker 2:  about leaving people alone. I would read them on the show and then people
Speaker 2:  would make memes and songs in one
Speaker 2:  of my favorite songs, which I thought about today. As I watched Joe Biden
Speaker 2:  dunk on Trump and his golden shovel. I was like, it would rule
Speaker 2:  if Biden would just play this song that VERGE has listener Jackson
Speaker 2:  Hayes wrote for us about the factory. Liam, can we play the song
Speaker 14:  Neli? You didn't listen to me,
Speaker 14:  but that's okay because we're gonna tell you what you already knew for months.
Speaker 14:  You didn't leave us alone.
Speaker 14:  Leave us alone. You didn't leave us alone.
Speaker 14:  Leave us alone.
Speaker 14:  AI meant new generation mobility and
Speaker 14:  self driving cars. Wait, is that story we were running Jeremy? Okay.
Speaker 14:  AK means smart safety and security through
Speaker 14:  AK technology. I mean come on Neil, you should know this. 5G
Speaker 14:  means pioneering. Wait, medical solutions. Crap.
Speaker 14:  That's supposed to mean on some Health Cloud
Speaker 14:  network. Okay, you didn't leave us alone.
Speaker 14:  Leave us alone. It's catchy. It's good you didn't leave us alone.
Speaker 14:  Leave us alone.
Speaker 14:  It was just saying K and 5G.
Speaker 14:  Well I see how that was hard to believe.
Speaker 14:  You didn't leave a spot.
Speaker 2:  It's a bot.
Speaker 14:  Leave it alone. You didn't leave it slow.
Speaker 14:  Leave it alone.
Speaker 2:  Now I just want you to imagine, hey, you
Speaker 3:  Win.
Speaker 2:  Can't make that on an iPad. Well with the power of AI
Speaker 2:  technology. So thank you to Jackson, one of my all time favorite first cast
Speaker 2:  moments. I hope for listening. I just want you to imagine Joe Biden
Speaker 2:  announcing the Microsoft deal and then me like, as a reminder, busting out
Speaker 2:  his acoustic guitar. He just takes a seat.
Speaker 2:  That whole sequence just, I just wanna remind people that sequencer
Speaker 2:  reporting was like mid pandemic. This is the
Speaker 2:  weirdest time in like reporting you could do. And we were
Speaker 2:  reporting on this weird factory that didn't exist and I was getting these
Speaker 2:  crazy emails. Just leave us alone. Just leave us alone. That was awesome.
Speaker 2:  Leave us alone. Anyway, it's in, it's a data center now. There's a
Speaker 2:  little dome. You can go look at the dome. I have pictures of the dome.
Speaker 2:  It's there on the website. That's it. I think that's it. One thing we didn't
Speaker 2:  talk about, TikTok sued the government over the bill to quote unquote ban
Speaker 2:  TikTok. We wanted to take some time with that. So that will be next week's
Speaker 2:  decoder. Alex Heath and Sarah j are gonna join me. We're gonna pull that
Speaker 2:  whole complaint apart and see where the arguments are good and bad. We just
Speaker 2:  needed to take some time with it. Also, there were iPads. Come on. That's
Speaker 2:  a bcast everybody. That's it. That's The Vergecast. Rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 3:  Give