# Transcript
ID: a1859be9-8d2c-4911-936b-d8496f234a4d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8287738448897075521/-3133651659610234125/s93290-US-4067s-1711437494.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of canceled-out cricket sounds:
03:29 - David, Andru, and Will react to prototype headphones that use AI to take noise cancellation to a whole new level.
Hear how the best ANC headphones handle real world and lab tests
We sent the top ANC headphones to a lab to test their noise-canceling abilities
The University of Washington’s Semantic Hearing project
UW’s Mobile Intelligence Lab
31:30 - Michael Fisher, aka Mr. Mobile, joins the show to discuss mobile phones with physical keyboards and his latest project, “Clicks,” an iPhone case featuring an integrated keyboard.
Clicks is a BlackBerry-style iPhone keyboard case designed for creators
BlackBerry kills Ryan Seacrest's iPhone keyboard
56:30 - Andru Marino answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about the best microphone for recording your parents.
How to get great audio for podcast interviews
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (16 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Canceled out cricket sounds.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend, David Pierce, and I am sitting in my basement about to watch
Speaker 2:  Oppenheimer. Actually, I should say that differently. I'm about to finish
Speaker 2:  watching Oppenheimer. I have been watching this movie for months, but
Speaker 2:  something happens every time I sit down to watch Oppenheimer, which admittedly
Speaker 2:  is like three hours long. So life is busy. It's hard to find three hours
Speaker 2:  to watch a movie, but every single time I sit down to watch this movie,
Speaker 2:  somewhere between two and like 11 minutes later, something
Speaker 2:  happens and I have to stop watching it. It's gotten to the point where Peacock's
Speaker 2:  algorithm took it out of my continue watching
Speaker 2:  Roe in the app because I just assumed Peacock was like, there's no way he's
Speaker 2:  ever gonna finish this movie. He can't possibly care. We'll just get rid
Speaker 2:  of it. But I do care and I'm gonna finish it. And today is the day.
Speaker 2:  It's Monday morning, which is a super weird time to watch this movie, but
Speaker 2:  it's happening. I've got I think like 40 minutes left. Today's the
Speaker 2:  day, it's gonna be awesome. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for
Speaker 2:  you today. We're gonna do two things. First, we're gonna talk about active
Speaker 2:  noise cancellation. You may have seen a video that our team made last summer
Speaker 2:  about kind of the state of the art in those, like over your headphones that
Speaker 2:  tried to cancel out subway sounds or airplane sounds or whatever else.
Speaker 2:  but it turns out the tech and science underneath all of that is actually
Speaker 2:  more advanced than you might see on some of those headphones. And we have
Speaker 2:  a really fun story about it. Then we're gonna talk about keyboards, specifically
Speaker 2:  iPhone keyboards, and the cases that put physical keyboards
Speaker 2:  back on your iPhone. We're actually doing, I've realized it's kind of an
Speaker 2:  accidental mini series in the next several weeks about
Speaker 2:  keyboards, just because I think they're fascinating and we don't talk about
Speaker 2:  them enough. The ways that we talk to our devices and the tools that
Speaker 2:  we use to do that matters a lot. Like when when we switch
Speaker 2:  to voice, instead of typing on a keyboard, the way that we use our
Speaker 2:  devices changes. And when we switch from a physical keyboard
Speaker 2:  to an onscreen keyboard, the way that we use our phones changes. And
Speaker 2:  so we're gonna talk to one person who is trying to put a physical keyboard
Speaker 2:  back about how that works, what it means, and what it changes.
Speaker 2:  All that is coming up in just a second. But like I said, I have 40 minutes
Speaker 2:  of this movie to watch no one else's home. It's Oppenheimer time, baby.
Speaker 2:  This is To Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So last summer our video team made a video all
Speaker 2:  over New York City in which they carried around this crazy looking like
Speaker 2:  mannequin skull to test a bunch of headphones.
Speaker 5:  Noise canceling is hard to explain by just talking about it, so we're gonna
Speaker 5:  try to share with you how it sounds by putting a bunch of noise canceling
Speaker 5:  headphones on the KU 100.
Speaker 2:  It was all about active noise cancellation and whether different
Speaker 2:  kinds of headphones could hold up. Super fun video. one of the best things
Speaker 2:  we made last year, and I'm told that's actually only the very beginning of
Speaker 2:  the story of what ANC can do Will pour is here to help me explain. Will.
Speaker 2:  Hello?
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  Will. You made this video last summer and as far as I can
Speaker 2:  tell you have not stopped thinking about it ever since. Is that a, is that
Speaker 2:  a fair characterization of what's been going on? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Kinda. There was an interview we did at the very end of the video that is
Speaker 6:  the thing that really stuck in my brain. It was with this guy that runs an
Speaker 6:  audio testing lab where we sent all these headphones and he ranked them
Speaker 6:  for us by their ANC performance, but he also made the point
Speaker 6:  that the most noise cancellation is maybe not what people
Speaker 6:  actually want. Like maybe we don't wanna walk around in this total
Speaker 6:  vacuum of sound. And he said that in The future it'll
Speaker 6:  be about smarter noise cancellation, more user input
Speaker 6:  into what you want to hear and what you don't. So that's the idea I've been
Speaker 6:  carrying around with me.
Speaker 2:  Okay. This is a good segue to a question that I have had for a very long
Speaker 2:  time and have been too afraid to loudly ask in public, in front of people
Speaker 6:  Can't wait.
Speaker 2:  What is active noise cancellation? I know it's a thing I sort of know
Speaker 2:  roughly at a basic level, like there are noises and it cancels them.
Speaker 2:  Yes. What is, and there are other kinds of noise cancellation that I also
Speaker 2:  don't understand. So like what is ANC? What are we talking about here?
Speaker 6:  I am so glad you asked and I brought Andru along because when
Speaker 6:  we did the video I had the same question and I just immediately asked him
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 2:  Okay, good. Andru Moreno, welcome. Hello, what is ANC
Speaker 2:  Teach Will and I please?
Speaker 5:  Right. So active noise cancellation takes sound
Speaker 5:  coming from the environment and basically sends an
Speaker 5:  opposite version of that sound wave to your ear. So
Speaker 5:  when combined it basically cancels it out. This is really
Speaker 5:  easy to do with, sounds like a loud airplane engine
Speaker 5:  or subway sounds noise. That's really predictable.
Speaker 2:  So the two of you have been on this beat for a while now and
Speaker 2:  have been investigating this question of how far have we come, how far can
Speaker 2:  we go and where do we actually want to go?
Speaker 2:  Is that right?
Speaker 6:  That's right, yeah. When we started talking and thinking about smart
Speaker 6:  noise cancellation, I started looking for who's doing this right
Speaker 6:  now? And the first place I looked is Apple, because their AirPods
Speaker 6:  Pro have a bunch of these smart noise control settings they call their
Speaker 6:  features adaptive audio. And it's kind of what we're talking about.
Speaker 6:  It's not like full, let's just cancel out all the
Speaker 6:  sound. It's more, let's make some basic decisions for you
Speaker 6:  about making really loud sounds more comfortable or
Speaker 6:  dipping your music when you start talking to someone. I, I've been playing
Speaker 6:  around with those features a bunch and in practice it's not
Speaker 6:  always super clear what it's actually doing. Like there's no
Speaker 6:  fine tuning, there's no user input, you just hit the button
Speaker 6:  and it tries to magically like make a better soundscape for you.
Speaker 6:  So that's the like one place I looked and have been playing
Speaker 6:  with that is out there in the world. That's a product now that that has some
Speaker 6:  smarts. But I also played around with a really early
Speaker 6:  prototype and I have a bunch of tape that I brought to play. Awesome.
Speaker 6:  This is super early stage a device that could get
Speaker 6:  a whole lot more specific when it comes to what you
Speaker 6:  want to hear, what you don't want to hear. So, I wanna play some of this
Speaker 6:  stuff and we can talk about it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So first listen to this clip.
Speaker 6:  This is me sitting at a table alone in a room.
Speaker 6:  I'm wearing these very prototype looking headphones. They've got a lot of
Speaker 6:  extra wires and tape and circuit boards attached to them. There's a vacuum
Speaker 6:  cleaner running right next to my chair and a few feet away there's a door
Speaker 6:  and someone outside is knocking on that door. That sound that we just heard
Speaker 6:  is just coming from a microphone that's sitting on the table next to me.
Speaker 6:  So that's just what the room sounds like. But while this is happening, this
Speaker 6:  sound clip, this is what I'm hearing right now,
Speaker 6:  just the knocks.
Speaker 2:  That's amazing.
Speaker 5:  This is beyond what we have seen with noise canceling headphones
Speaker 5:  before. If, you want to just hear NOx? That is not something you
Speaker 5:  can try to get,
Speaker 6:  You can't tell your AirPods Pro. Just NOx,
Speaker 5:  Where did you find this?
Speaker 6:  So this comes from The University of Washington, specifically their mobile
Speaker 6:  intelligence lab in the CS department. It's a project that they call
Speaker 6:  Semantic Hearing. And I got this demo from a PhD student
Speaker 6:  named Malani. He's one of the people who helped build the system.
Speaker 6:  And you talk me through how it all works.
Speaker 9:  There are these noise canceling headphones. Okay. They're Bose, QC
Speaker 9:  Ultra. They're going to suppress all of the sounds. And then what we do is
Speaker 9:  we have these binaural microphones that capture
Speaker 6:  Tape tape to the outside of the,
Speaker 9:  Yeah, okay. Yeah. They capture sound from your environment. Yeah. The way
Speaker 9:  you hear it because they're on on both ears. Ears because they're outside.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And then we pass this through a mobile CPU and orange
Speaker 9:  pie. This thing processes audio in some way based on the
Speaker 9:  targets that you select. Okay. And then feeds it back to the headphones where
Speaker 9:  it's played.
Speaker 2:  So the starting point for this is a pair of headphones you actually can buy?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So the prototype starts with off the shelf bodes headphones
Speaker 6:  that use the existing ANC to just create a clean
Speaker 6:  audio slate. I see. And then the system on that orange pie
Speaker 6:  listens to the full soundscape separately and picks out just the specific
Speaker 6:  sounds that it's listening for. In this case, a door knock.
Speaker 9:  We have a program that runs on the orange pie, which
Speaker 9:  continuously just records audio that in chunks of eight millisecond. Then
Speaker 9:  it passes this to a neural network where
Speaker 9:  it's processed with the condition that this
Speaker 9:  neural network tries to extract some target class. This target
Speaker 9:  class is what you select here.
Speaker 6:  Okay. But yeah, we've got cat cricket, dog knock and rooster. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Those are the, those are the classes that you have queued up right now? Exactly.
Speaker 2:  All the most common noises in the world.
Speaker 6:  Right. Of course. Anything that you would wanna be selecting and deselecting,
Speaker 6:  there's a smartphone screen that I have access to and there are buttons for
Speaker 6:  each one of those categories. And in each one of those cases, Molik
Speaker 6:  has fed a neural network, a whole bunch of those clips, different
Speaker 6:  dog sounds and door knock sounds and everything else to train it to recognize
Speaker 6:  that specific sound. I actually asked Molik to share some of
Speaker 6:  the sounds that he used outta curiosity. I don't know what I was expecting
Speaker 6:  to learn from that, but here are the cat sounds that he used.
Speaker 10:  Oh,
Speaker 2:  Very familiar with those.
Speaker 6:  I, I had to ask him because I just pictured him sifting through and he did
Speaker 6:  this, he just sifted through hundreds and hundreds of sourced
Speaker 6:  cat sounds and cleaned them up and fed them into the system. So the AI is
Speaker 6:  trained on these categories now so that when I hit the cat button,
Speaker 6:  the system will mute every sound in the world except for cat meows.
Speaker 6:  So going back to the demo, I did that, I hit the cat button, Molik
Speaker 6:  turned the vacuum cleaner back on and he queued up a looping sound of
Speaker 6:  that really annoying cat.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Pretend like it's a regular day, lazy Sunday, you want to play with
Speaker 9:  your cat. Right. But there's a noisy vacuum cleaner in the background.
Speaker 6:  I hate it when I'm vacuuming and playing with my cat at the same time.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Transparency mode. My poor cat is trying to get my attention,
Speaker 6:  but I can't hear him so I'm gonna flip to cat mode.
Speaker 2:  Wow,
Speaker 2:  that's really impressive.
Speaker 6:  It's super impressive. The, the sound is a little odd. Like you, to me,
Speaker 6:  it sounds like the cat is meowing in a submarine, but it's super clear
Speaker 6:  and the vacuum cleaner is totally gone. And for the record, what you're hearing
Speaker 6:  right now is actually a little bit better than what it sounds like in reality
Speaker 6:  because in the room I'm wearing headphones and some of that vacuum cleaner
Speaker 6:  sound is making it through the headphones.
Speaker 5:  And this is what the headphones are outputting to your ears.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Will, you mentioned this is not for actual cats
Speaker 2:  and vacuum cleaners. What is your sense of what this is actually for? Like
Speaker 2:  what, what are the folks working on this thinking they might be able to do
Speaker 2:  with it?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean the most obvious example that comes up over and over again is,
Speaker 6:  is you're walking down the street and you want to be able to hear
Speaker 6:  a car honking at you because that is a, a thing that you, that is, that's
Speaker 6:  a safety thing. Sure. But you don't want to hear all the other annoying sounds.
Speaker 6:  Or the folks I talked to brought up industrial settings where it's really
Speaker 6:  loud and workers are wearing earplugs for safety, but they want to be able
Speaker 6:  to talk to each other or hear sounds over the intercom or whatever
Speaker 6:  else. So those are the really obvious use cases. And from playing with
Speaker 6:  this really early demo, it felt like even this early demo could
Speaker 6:  do that much, which is super impressive.
Speaker 5:  So you mentioned also like crickets and dogs and other things.
Speaker 5:  What are some other demos that you were able to test out there? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  So in theory you can train the AI
Speaker 6:  on any sound and we played through a few different
Speaker 6:  options that they had queued up. None of it was perfect. Like
Speaker 6:  there were these times where it was supposed to be muting
Speaker 6:  all voices. But my voice kind of clipped into the final mix that you can
Speaker 6:  hear. I can, we can play that.
Speaker 11:  Okay. Don't understand.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, that's funky.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So you know, rough around the edges. We went back to the barnyard and
Speaker 6:  listened to all of those other different sound clips in a lot of
Speaker 6:  different iterations just to see how good it was at toggling between
Speaker 6:  different sounds.
Speaker 9:  Now that we've done cat and vacuum cleaner. Yes. We'll move on to some other
Speaker 9:  classes. Let's do cat and cricket.
Speaker 12:  All right. Here's transparency mode.
Speaker 12:  A cat and a cricket are both trying really hard to get my attention.
Speaker 12:  That's enough. I cat
Speaker 5:  In this demo. You couldn't hear the cat at all. You just heard the crickets.
Speaker 6:  No, it was gone. Yeah. The big takeaway for me was that this system is
Speaker 6:  already really good at full isolation. It just
Speaker 6:  needs to make the sounds that you are hearing sound more natural.
Speaker 6:  Like that's just to my ear, that's where the work was. It was already
Speaker 6:  doing an unbelievable job at canceling out the stuff you didn't want.
Speaker 2:  I'm desperate to know what the like last demo he gave you was.
Speaker 2:  'cause I gotta assume he's like ramping up in difficulty here, but there's
Speaker 2:  definitely a point at which he knows this thing will fall apart. Like what?
Speaker 2:  What was the most intense demo he gave you?
Speaker 6:  Oh, we did a big finish, which was dog and a rooster and a cat.
Speaker 12:  This is the most annoying farm in the world. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Alright. Just rooster.
Speaker 6:  It's interesting those two and I can see how subjective this would all
Speaker 6:  be. It feels like those sounds are bleeding into each other a little bit
Speaker 6:  more. I wonder if they're just a little more similar than
Speaker 6:  the others
Speaker 9:  Or Yeah. Yeah, I think it could be that some sounds are similar. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  And finally we'll do dog and cat.
Speaker 12:  This is very triggering. This is why I don't like working from home. Okay,
Speaker 12:  sorry cat.
Speaker 12:  Okay. And now I'll just pay attention to the cat.
Speaker 2:  Okay. This is really impressive but I'm, I'm stuck on two things.
Speaker 2:  One is, is the idea that you will carry around
Speaker 2:  a smartphone constantly selecting the noises that you want to see. Like
Speaker 2:  should I walk around saying, oh it looks like that cat's trying to get my
Speaker 2:  attention, let me let the cat in. Or is The future some sort of
Speaker 2:  beautifully adaptive thing that understands as you're going, did you get
Speaker 2:  a sense from them kind of how they see this eventually working?
Speaker 6:  Yes, and I talked to the head of this lab all about that, but before we did
Speaker 6:  that we talked about how they're gonna get to that point.
Speaker 2:  That was my other question is how do you take this from a pair of Bose headphones
Speaker 2:  with a bunch of junk taped on it to an actual thing that humans can
Speaker 2:  buy.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, let's talk about their, their full roadmap from where they're now
Speaker 6:  to what you're describing. The first step in that process is
Speaker 6:  just getting better at doing all of these tasks. And that means
Speaker 6:  feeding their model a whole lot more data,
Speaker 2:  More cricket sounds,
Speaker 6:  So many more cricket sounds and grasshopper sounds and cicada sounds. And
Speaker 6:  just basically train it to recognize a million more categories of sounds
Speaker 6:  and to recognize all those individual sounds just a lot more accurately.
Speaker 6:  And if they can do that and do that super well, then
Speaker 6:  the possible use cases just explode.
Speaker 9:  You could totally see this being applied to different tasks. Like
Speaker 9:  say I want to not just listen to sounds but
Speaker 9:  specific people. Like I want to listen to you in a conversation. So, I can
Speaker 9:  maybe have some representation of how you sound like and then I can,
Speaker 9:  you know, just pick up your sound as we, as we speak, as we have a conversation,
Speaker 9:  even if there's lots of other people around us.
Speaker 5:  So all the current headphones right now, they do it really
Speaker 5:  well because they can predict when these sounds are coming. So when
Speaker 5:  you're in the airplane, you know these sounds are gonna be 10 seconds from
Speaker 5:  now and 10 seconds before. But a bird sound, a cat
Speaker 5:  meowing, crickets chirping, you don't know when those are coming. So how
Speaker 5:  would they be able to predict they would have to move pretty fast on
Speaker 5:  the device.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. That's the problem of what they call transient sounds.
Speaker 6:  And that's a big hurdle for existing ANC
Speaker 6:  technology. This system is really good at it, but it
Speaker 6:  needs to process the incoming audio super, super
Speaker 6:  fast. There's no time to send it to the cloud for processing. There
Speaker 6:  isn't really even time to send the incoming audio like to your
Speaker 6:  phone's processor over Bluetooth. You, you would just end up with a
Speaker 6:  lag between what you're hearing and what your eyes are actually seeing, which
Speaker 6:  is just a complete non-starter. So all of the work that we're talking about
Speaker 6:  doing has to happen onboard the headphones themselves.
Speaker 9:  If we can get this model to be much, much more efficient through lots of
Speaker 9:  just standard machine learning techniques, then we can fit like a more
Speaker 9:  capable model into this, this small device. Another way to, to
Speaker 9:  also help on the hardware side is, you know, in the
Speaker 9:  recent few years there's been lots and lots of companies that
Speaker 9:  work on designing AI chips that can do, you know, a large,
Speaker 9:  large amount of computation with very low power consumption
Speaker 9:  and those things are very promising.
Speaker 2:  So you've just made me imagine what amounts to like a pair of headphones
Speaker 2:  with A GPU attached, which I think is like literally
Speaker 2:  what he's describing and that both seems cool and like maybe we're all, this
Speaker 2:  is going but also very expensive, very big and
Speaker 2:  maybe very far away. What is the sense of how we
Speaker 2:  get from literally strapping like an Nvidia GPU to my
Speaker 2:  face to the thing he's describing, which I think ultimately it
Speaker 2:  has to look like a pair of bows headphones, right? Like we're not gonna take
Speaker 2:  anything that doesn't look like a pair of bows headphones.
Speaker 6:  This is where we'll have to see they're talking about a, a hearing
Speaker 6:  aid sized form factor. Oh wow. They want to go much, much
Speaker 6:  smaller and they think that they can do it with these
Speaker 6:  purpose-built lightweight chips that are really good at running
Speaker 6:  AI systems. So they're playing with all of the chips that are very
Speaker 6:  new and newly available and they're sort of doing all of these
Speaker 6:  different things at the same time. They're doing the software optimization,
Speaker 6:  they're feeding the model, all this more data and they're
Speaker 6:  working on the hardware too to shrink it as quickly as possible. And they
Speaker 6:  think they have the raw materials to do that pretty soon. So we
Speaker 2:  Have like an academic lab masquerading as like a full stack electronics
Speaker 2:  company here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, absolutely. That's the, that's the fun thing about this lab in particular
Speaker 6:  is they're, that's very holistic.
Speaker 5:  Oh, what about the user interface? Am I gonna be like asking Siri
Speaker 5:  every 10 seconds? Like, did you hear my cat? Is my cat meowing?
Speaker 6:  So they're thinking a lot about this because
Speaker 6:  even when I was playing with this demo, I was like, oh god, five button,
Speaker 6:  this is just five buttons in the real world you would need 5 million
Speaker 6:  buttons to actually dial in the soundscape that you want. So obviously
Speaker 6:  you need some sort of automation here. And the lab is
Speaker 6:  looking at different AI assisted ways to do this. So this whole
Speaker 6:  thing is gonna be AI onis, but I talked to the head of the
Speaker 6:  mobile intelligence lab shiam go Lakota about exactly this.
Speaker 13:  We're gonna have some systems in the next few months to a year
Speaker 13:  on trying to go away slowly from like actually having the user to like
Speaker 13:  pick different kinds of sounds to less and less
Speaker 13:  involvement of the user itself. You can imagine a system where the AI automatically
Speaker 13:  learns what you want to listen to. And I think that's something which we
Speaker 13:  are building towards. And I think by the end of the year, hopefully we can
Speaker 13:  actually have a system where AI would automatically learn what you want
Speaker 13:  to listen to.
Speaker 2:  That is ambitious. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're, they're juggling a lot of balls at the same time here. And
Speaker 6:  the, you know, the end goal that Shiam is envisioning is a system that
Speaker 6:  is using data from say your smartphone to think and
Speaker 6:  learn about where you are, what you're doing,
Speaker 6:  and start to make those decisions kind of with as much or
Speaker 6:  as little input as you want, as to what you're hearing and and what you're
Speaker 6:  not. So say, you know, again, you're living in a busy city with lots of
Speaker 6:  loud traffic, but you're inside your house.
Speaker 13:  So that's exactly the thing. Like clearly an AI can tell
Speaker 13:  depending on my motion and my IMU, whether I'm moving as much,
Speaker 13:  where am I? It knows my GGPS location so it knows that I'm in a house.
Speaker 13:  Does it really need me to listen to like the, the sounds of the
Speaker 13:  honks? Not really, but if I'm on a street, maybe it can
Speaker 13:  because I'm walking on a street or I'm in, I'm in a car, it should potentially
Speaker 13:  be like, you need to hear these honks. Although
Speaker 6:  Then I, the next place my brain goes is how to make sure
Speaker 6:  that it's doing that safely and reliably. Because there's one thing we've
Speaker 6:  watched from Tesla autopilot to, you know, chat
Speaker 6:  GPT hallucinating to whatever else. It's like there's an asterisk
Speaker 6:  on so, so many of these tasks that we just sort of let
Speaker 6:  the AI take care of and it strikes me that trusting
Speaker 6:  your headphones to decide when you need to hear a car horn or not
Speaker 6:  could be a high stakes thing.
Speaker 13:  High stake situation. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. I think that's definitely something
Speaker 13:  which has to be integrated in these systems. And it could be that certain
Speaker 13:  things, like if I'm actually in the house, that's when you remove all these
Speaker 13:  ambient sounds but it's just like hard coded saying that you cannot remove
Speaker 13:  certain things in outdoor environments where you know that it's important.
Speaker 13:  But that's an extremely important point, which is like when we deploy these
Speaker 13:  things at scale and have this thing automatically learn, you got to have
Speaker 13:  certain rules which prioritize safety over functionality. I think
Speaker 2:  The thing that's being described here is so beautiful and
Speaker 2:  smart and so non-existent in the real world that it's like, it's like
Speaker 2:  what we talk about with self-driving, right? Like if people weren't weird
Speaker 2:  and didn't make strange decisions and pedestrians and bicycles didn't exist,
Speaker 2:  self-driving cars would be awesome. So easy, so great. But the world
Speaker 2:  is a weird messy place full of edge cases.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's where we just haven't seen that whole half of
Speaker 6:  this prototype. They have proven out that they can make crickets go away.
Speaker 6:  Which
Speaker 2:  Is impressive.
Speaker 6:  Which is impressive. Yeah. And it's like you can see a roadmap to extracting
Speaker 6:  a million other sounds based on that. And then this bigger end
Speaker 6:  state of dialing in exactly what you want is the
Speaker 6:  loftier thing and there's, there's a lot of work to be done there.
Speaker 6:  But if they can figure out even some of this stuff you could
Speaker 6:  imagine, you know, them getting to a really interesting product.
Speaker 6:  Shiam is interested in smart hearing aids,
Speaker 6:  you can see how anyone with a hearing aid could use even
Speaker 6:  a portion of this technology. Anyone with a sound sensitivity?
Speaker 6:  I use noise cancellation just to turn the world down to keep my anxiety
Speaker 6:  in check. So, I would love to be able to dial in
Speaker 6:  that sound a little bit more. Shiam made the argument too that
Speaker 6:  a lot of us just live in a very noisy world and noise just
Speaker 6:  as a thing that we're all confronted with is bad for everybody
Speaker 13:  And it actually does impact your health. There are studies we say that noise
Speaker 13:  pollution affects your sleep and that ends up affecting
Speaker 13:  your lifespan. So I do think that having this kind
Speaker 13:  of a capability where people can control their environment is just not a
Speaker 13:  toy. I think it actually can have a meaningful impact on the quality of
Speaker 13:  life and sleep and a lot of things which I think are
Speaker 13:  extremely important for humans to thrive and not just survive
Speaker 6:  So, I mean wherever this specific prototype lands we are,
Speaker 6:  we're definitely leaving the fancy earplugs era of noise
Speaker 6:  cancellation and entering an era that is much more
Speaker 6:  specific and bespoke and a little bit smarter what that looks like
Speaker 6:  TBD. But I am very excited about that concept.
Speaker 2:  I am too. And I, I wonder Andru, just to come all the way back around to
Speaker 2:  this idea of what we were talking about at the very beginning with what active
Speaker 2:  noise cancellation does, it seems like knowing this kind of stuff
Speaker 2:  where you can say like not only is this an external sound and I wanna get
Speaker 2:  rid of it, but I know specifically which external sound it is. I
Speaker 2:  think even leaving aside sort of that big giant grand vision, it just feels
Speaker 2:  like that step alone does a lot.
Speaker 5:  Oh totally. I mean to be able to walk into a store
Speaker 5:  and the headphones know I am in a store and I'm gonna be
Speaker 5:  talking to someone checking out, or I have
Speaker 5:  a library of sounds that are unique to my experience that I
Speaker 5:  would like to tune out and the sounds are only at this specific coffee
Speaker 5:  shop that I go to study that's super compelling to me.
Speaker 5:  Do I want my headphones to know where I am at all times? I'm not sure.
Speaker 5:  Right. But there's a lot of awesome possibilities of
Speaker 5:  just tuning things out and tuning things in wherever
Speaker 5:  you are.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I I think the self-driving example just keeps feeling more and
Speaker 2:  more true to me as we talk about this that the first thing where it's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, my car can park itself and will
Speaker 2:  stay in its lane if I try to drift out of it because I'm not paying attention.
Speaker 2:  Right. Doable, awesome. If you extend that all the way out to all the
Speaker 2:  cars on the road will drive themselves and robot taxis will be everywhere.
Speaker 2:  Like you've sort of lost me. I it maybe it'll happen someday in The future,
Speaker 2:  but that doesn't make the first thing any less cool. And I feel like there's
Speaker 2:  a lot of that in here too, where it's like even just boil it all the way
Speaker 2:  down, this is gonna make noise cancellation better because the cats get through
Speaker 2:  my headphones now and they can stop getting through my headphones once we
Speaker 2:  get this tech.
Speaker 6:  Totally. And I think that no matter how far
Speaker 6:  into that idealized end state they get, they're very confident
Speaker 6:  that they can get a lot farther, very quickly. They have access to
Speaker 6:  these chips, the, the software is improving very quickly. So they
Speaker 6:  have a lot of ambitions for this year. They think they can get to a much,
Speaker 6:  much smaller form factor by the end of this year for example. And they have
Speaker 6:  a lot more very specific ideas for
Speaker 6:  that sort of filtration step. So yeah, it's,
Speaker 6:  you know, for me that very, very limited demo was impressive
Speaker 6:  enough and they had enough plans for this year that I'm going
Speaker 6:  be following that lab and see what they come up with next. 'cause I,
Speaker 6:  I think it's gonna be an interesting year for it.
Speaker 2:  Do you think at the end of this they're gonna try to sell me headphones?
Speaker 2:  Like what's their game plan here? Are they gonna spin out a company and try
Speaker 2:  to be a headphone player? Are they gonna try and work with some of the folks
Speaker 2:  out there? Did you get any sense of how they wanna get this out in the world?
Speaker 6:  They seemed open to that. you know, they're an academic department, they're
Speaker 6:  talking about commercialization, you know, they're like a lot of
Speaker 6:  academics, they're walking this fine line between, you know, just moving
Speaker 6:  this technology forward and experimenting with it but also like knowing that
Speaker 6:  they've got something and they feel like they are potentially
Speaker 6:  ahead of a lot of big tech companies on this. So they
Speaker 6:  are thinking in those terms and I think that's one of the
Speaker 6:  reasons they're trying to work as quickly as they are.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it does seem like this is happening fast. I feel like a Andru, you
Speaker 2:  were the one running around New York with the head on the subway
Speaker 2:  a year ago. This strikes me as something that a lot of those companies
Speaker 2:  building ANC headphones are probably also thinking about.
Speaker 2:  Like, do you think this is the next turn for a lot of those companies
Speaker 2:  and is this gonna be the next thing that makes these headphones better for
Speaker 2:  people?
Speaker 5:  I think so, and I know Bose is thinking about it a lot as the next
Speaker 5:  generation of noise cancellation. Apple is already trying to do
Speaker 5:  the adaptive things as we mentioned, but right now it's just
Speaker 5:  boosting things instead of taking things out. So if
Speaker 5:  there's a world where they can remove the, the dogs out of
Speaker 5:  Will's room while he's recording a podcast, I mean there's like
Speaker 5:  endless possibilities of there
Speaker 6:  Was a dog button on that prototype. We just need that prototype and we'll
Speaker 6:  be fine.
Speaker 2:  Well by this time next year, The Vergecast will be a listenable podcast.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be great.
Speaker 6:  Thank you. And sorry.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. If. you remember the smartphone world before the iPhone?
Speaker 2:  It was much wackier than it is today. Back then, there were lots of
Speaker 2:  ideas about how a smartphone should look and work. Some of them
Speaker 2:  twisted open, some of them slid open, some of them flipped open and a
Speaker 2:  lot of them had physical keyboards. And then the iPhone all at
Speaker 2:  once kind of upended that. Here's Steve Jobs at the original iPhone
Speaker 2:  launch in 2007 explaining what he saw as the problem with
Speaker 2:  hardware keyboards.
Speaker 15:  Here's four smartphones, right? The Motorola queue, the BlackBerry
Speaker 15:  pore, Nokia E 62. The usual suspects. What's wrong with
Speaker 15:  their user interfaces? Well, the problem with them is really sort of
Speaker 15:  in the bottom 40 there. It's, it's this stuff right here. They all
Speaker 15:  have these keyboards that are there whether you need them or not to be there.
Speaker 15:  And they all have these control buttons that are fixed in plastic
Speaker 15:  and are the same for every application. Well, every application wants a
Speaker 15:  slightly different user interface, a slightly optimized set of buttons
Speaker 15:  just for it. And what happens, If, you think of a great idea six months
Speaker 15:  from now, you can't run around and add a button to these things. They're
Speaker 15:  already shipped.
Speaker 2:  It's a good take. Right? And history proved him pretty much correct,
Speaker 2:  which is why virtually every phone on the planet now has a virtual
Speaker 2:  onscreen keyboard instead of a big physical one. Underneath
Speaker 2:  Jobs did definitely have it right, but not all right? Because there
Speaker 2:  are things I think a lot of people miss about physical keyboards. You
Speaker 2:  can type faster on physical keyboards. That's just true. There's plenty of
Speaker 2:  evidence for that. You can type without looking at your phone so much you
Speaker 2:  can type without the keyboard taking up like 40% of the screen. And
Speaker 2:  so over the years, various people have tried to bring back the keyboard
Speaker 2:  to the smartphone. Remember way back when Ryan Seacrest was out there
Speaker 2:  hawking a case called Typo that put a keyboard back underneath your iPhone.
Speaker 2:  This is how we explained it in an interview with TechCrunch.
Speaker 16:  This has changed my life. I literally was
Speaker 16:  suffocating thinking about how I was going to work every day because this
Speaker 16:  is my office, you know, the the tablet and the phone. That's how I
Speaker 16:  work. I have incoming emails from everybody that I work with and for of
Speaker 16:  my partners. And this is how I respond and can respond quickly
Speaker 16:  and be able to actually type more than two sentences.
Speaker 2:  I get it Ryan. I feel that too. But Typo didn't really work
Speaker 2:  out and none of the other projects trying to do this did either. And yet
Speaker 2:  now all these years later, there's another company trying to pull it off.
Speaker 2:  It's called Clicks and it's co-founded by a guy you might have heard of.
Speaker 17:  I'm Michael Fisher. AKA Mr. Mobile or Captain Two phones. Take your
Speaker 2:  Pick. Michael's a long time creator and phone reviewer and he knows this
Speaker 2:  space better than most, which made it frankly all the more surprising that
Speaker 2:  this is a thing he decided to do. So I brought him onto the show to figure
Speaker 2:  out whether this idea has a chance to really succeed. Why he's convinced
Speaker 2:  there's still room for a physical keyboard on your iPhone and what it takes
Speaker 2:  to make a really great tiny little keyboard. And we just started the story
Speaker 2:  at the beginning. Why would you in the year 2024 set
Speaker 2:  out to build a physical smartphone keyboard?
Speaker 17:  Oddly, the thing that was the germ of Clicks came to me. I actually, it
Speaker 17:  didn't originate from my brain. I got a call from a guy you probably are
Speaker 17:  familiar with, named CrackBerry Kevin. It's a guy who helped me build Mr.
Speaker 17:  Mobile in the first place, kind of like one of my closer friends in the
Speaker 17:  business. And he said, I gotta show you something. I will absolutely kill
Speaker 17:  you If, you show anybody else what this is. And he sends me this 3D render
Speaker 17:  and you know, you, you and I are in the same business for a lot of my day.
Speaker 17:  you know what it's like to get something in your inbox that's like, you
Speaker 17:  look at it, you take a beat and you say, oh my God, you you crazy bastards.
Speaker 17:  You actually did it. So I. Think that's what I said out loud. but
Speaker 17:  it was just a render. It wasn't even a product, it was just this very obviously
Speaker 17:  an iPhone inserted into a case with a, with a Krty keyboard that looks nothing
Speaker 17:  like it currently does. And I said in a profound demonstration
Speaker 17:  of how little business foresight I have, I said, you know, Mr. Mobil has
Speaker 17:  to have the exclusive on this. Right?
Speaker 2:  That's good. Always, always thinking one step ahead, I guess.
Speaker 17:  What an idiot. So within a week though, you know, I'm giving so much
Speaker 17:  product feedback, we're talking all the time. It's very obvious that we
Speaker 17:  should be working together on this. Turns out that's what Kevin had in mind
Speaker 17:  the whole time. So I come aboard. We finish building the company with the
Speaker 17:  guys who full credit deserve credit for the, for the initial germ of this
Speaker 17:  idea in the first place. The veterans from FX tech, the, the last company
Speaker 17:  to make a truly great Android, you know, sliding keyboard smartphone. And
Speaker 17:  that was, dude, that was
Speaker 2:  April
Speaker 17:  Of 2023.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow. That was fast. Yeah.
Speaker 17:  By January at CES we had a product that we were able to, we were ready to
Speaker 17:  ship. So it what fast is right. It was insane.
Speaker 2:  What I like about that though is that is a group of people who are maybe
Speaker 2:  most prone to being incorrectly nostalgic about
Speaker 2:  keyboards, right? You have, yeah, you have like some of the world's foremost
Speaker 2:  BlackBerry people. You have you who has just never stopped making videos
Speaker 2:  about the Palm Prix. True. And you have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  people who have like made these things in the past. So how do
Speaker 2:  you check yourself against like, boy I wish the world still existed
Speaker 2:  in which we wanted keyboards versus like, this is a thing we should do and
Speaker 2:  bring it back. So, or maybe you don't and you just soldier through and hope
Speaker 2:  other people feel the same way you do.
Speaker 17:  I think there was an element of that really. I mean we, one of the things
Speaker 17:  we knew is we had a lot of smart people on board, right? And I won't give
Speaker 17:  you the whole marketing pitch of everything, but we really do have the best
Speaker 17:  people in the roles that need to be within the company and the, the most
Speaker 17:  expertise there is. And at no point, you know, did we check ourselves all
Speaker 17:  the time? Yes. But at no point did anyone say, you know, I don't think this
Speaker 17:  is the time really what I, I had to be sold on this. 'cause I was a little,
Speaker 17:  I turned on my skepticism node for a hot second. I said, guys, is
Speaker 17:  is this it? Like no young person is going to even want a single
Speaker 17:  physical button on this thing that they're like, what? What's going on?
Speaker 17:  And it turns out that the time was right, not only for a variety of unrelated
Speaker 17:  reasons, but because you can introduce this as a new concept to somebody
Speaker 17:  like, not to name Drop Max Wach, who was like our most difficult briefing
Speaker 17:  at CES, you know, was like, he's like 20, 22 and he is just like, I think
Speaker 17:  this is ridiculous. But then you show him what happens when you are using,
Speaker 17:  you know, Instagram live and you have your entire screen there and you
Speaker 17:  go to type something and the virtual keyboard doesn't eat up 40% of it.
Speaker 17:  Or you show somebody a keyboard shortcut and you're like, wait, what did
Speaker 17:  you do? And I'm like, well, I just hit the space bar and it advanced the
Speaker 17:  screen for me. Or I hit, you know, whatever. Drop the notification shade.
Speaker 17:  That's part of the fun. All the BlackBerry people know this stuff already.
Speaker 17:  All the, you know, the people who had a palm trio like you and I maybe Yeah.
Speaker 17:  Know all these things and, and to introduce it to somebody who was not alive
Speaker 17:  when the, when the BlackBerry was a thing. It's pretty cool.
Speaker 2:  That's interesting. So we're actually like past nostalgia for a lot of people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Where it's, it's so far gone that it's actually a new thing again.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. It's a full circle. Exactly right.
Speaker 2:  But I would imagine for you as somebody who has used these things but not
Speaker 2:  built them before, part of the process is just sort of learning how
Speaker 2:  to learn a keyboard and like the vocabulary of it and yes.
Speaker 2:  What it means for a keyboard to be good or bad. 'cause I think as a user
Speaker 2:  you have this instinctive feel. But I have to imagine that at some level
Speaker 2:  there is like an objective measure of a good keyboard that you have to learn
Speaker 2:  how to reckon with in this process. There
Speaker 17:  Is, so like the first prototype of Clicks I got to use had
Speaker 17:  these domed transparent key caps. So we printed the
Speaker 17:  characters below the, the surface of the key like a palm pri, right? Yeah.
Speaker 17:  And because I'm so in forever in love with the palm pri until I die,
Speaker 17:  I loved it and I was like, oh, this looks so good and this is the the language
Speaker 17:  we should be going for. And perfect. Well it turns out though that when
Speaker 17:  you make a domed transparent key that is perfectly circular
Speaker 17:  in the design we were using. It looks great from head on and then you tilt
Speaker 17:  that phone by 20 degrees and you can't tell what the letter is
Speaker 17:  because there's interesting, but there's visual warping, right? There's
Speaker 17:  this skewing that happens. You're, is that a semicolon or a comma? I don't
Speaker 17:  know what I'm doing anymore. So very quickly we had to make little decisions
Speaker 17:  like that. Like, well let's see what flat polycarbonate keys
Speaker 17:  with, you know, satin printed top layer paint looks like. Well it turns
Speaker 17:  out that's a lot better. So there's kind of major changes early on.
Speaker 17:  What I found surprising is you and I, we've covered phones a long time.
Speaker 17:  you know how early on designs get locked in and you see people
Speaker 17:  talking about why didn't they just make this change? 'cause we were giving
Speaker 17:  'em feedback after the, after the unveiling, it's like, well, 'cause they
Speaker 17:  were been sitting in retail boxes for three months at this point. With something
Speaker 17:  like Clicks though we were making changes right up until the end at
Speaker 17:  CES. We got the final keyboard while we were at the show. The thing we showed
Speaker 17:  everybody was kind of like a second to last revision. The final keyboard
Speaker 17:  came in. It wasn't even built into the case. We're carrying around like
Speaker 17:  a, like a component with no paint on it or anything. It's just like, okay,
Speaker 17:  don't look at this, this is gross, but just close your eyes and feel it.
Speaker 17:  And everyone we showed that to, we got the final sign off on it. Kevin was
Speaker 17:  so excited. We're like, oh, that's it. Every nerd we trust has signed off
Speaker 17:  on that. So dude, I go on forever. We had like a hundred revisions. It was,
Speaker 17:  it was crazy.
Speaker 2:  I will say I am most fascinated by like the last handful because I
Speaker 2:  think I, I would assume, and please correct me if I'm wrong, but that you
Speaker 2:  get through kind of 80% of the problem fairly quickly and you, you
Speaker 2:  settle on like the rough idea of the thing that you want and then you
Speaker 2:  spend like the rest of your life until the heat death of the universe
Speaker 2:  debating like tiny millimeters of everything. But that stuff does
Speaker 2:  matter in these really like, hard to understand ways. So like the last 10
Speaker 2:  revisions I think must have been so interesting and weird to go through.
Speaker 17:  They were so wild because you're fighting, you're trying to integrate your,
Speaker 17:  your personal history without being a, you know, without being slavish to
Speaker 17:  it. Right? Hmm. So a good example is the shift in alt keys. Right up until
Speaker 17:  close to the end they were swapped and I kept trying to switch to alternate
Speaker 17:  characters and I kept messing it up and I'm like, all right, is this muscle
Speaker 17:  memory or what? And we talked about it, we kind of went back and forth,
Speaker 17:  got the whole team involved and it was like, no, we gotta swap those keys.
Speaker 17:  And once we did, everything felt right again because what do you know you
Speaker 17:  find the corner more easily. My least favorite change I think I talked
Speaker 17:  about in my video was I want that old number pad. Yeah.
Speaker 17:  I want the, you know, the, the three by three BlackBerry palm
Speaker 17:  trio kind of number pad on the keyboard. Somebody much smarter than me on
Speaker 17:  the team said, look, if we're designing the best iPhone physical keyboard,
Speaker 17:  you gotta design it like the iOS virtual keyboard. You gotta give the number
Speaker 17:  row up top. And I said, I hate that. You're right. I hate it. But
Speaker 17:  you're right. I can't say you're wrong. That's what we gotta do. So little
Speaker 17:  tiny changes like that. Have
Speaker 2:  You gone back and retested all the old physical keyboards?
Speaker 17:  It's so weird because I was using the Palm pri obviously most recently.
Speaker 17:  And I was like, I remember writing for this keyboard back in the day when
Speaker 17:  I owned it in 2009 and I pick it up now and I'm like, Ooh,
Speaker 17:  those keys barely move at all. And the Centro right. Where I was like, I
Speaker 17:  could type fine on this in 2008. Nope. Even
Speaker 2:  In 2008 I was like, this is too small with the central. I couldn't do it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 17:  But you could use the sty on the buttons though, which was great. That is
Speaker 17:  true. But other surprises in the other way. I'll get off Wabo s in a second.
Speaker 17:  But real quick, the HPV hmm. World's tiniest keyboard phone
Speaker 17:  that a lot of people made fun of. Very good keyboard for the footprint
Speaker 17:  and for me best keyboard i I ever used but did not own
Speaker 17:  Sidekick two. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 17:  They like lovely clicky travel and, and feedback and also
Speaker 17:  covered in that delightful silicone rubber that held onto your
Speaker 17:  thumbs and Oh man. Yeah. What's your, what's your favorite keyboard of
Speaker 17:  all time? If, you don't mind me asking?
Speaker 2:  I think If, you made me pick two. It would be the Trio six 50. Oh. Which
Speaker 2:  I loved to pieces. I loved that phone and the
Speaker 2:  Motorola queue, which I actually think If, you made me pick one is probably
Speaker 2:  my answer. That keyword was amazing.
Speaker 17:  I love, you know why I think the queue worked is 'cause you had this nice
Speaker 17:  interplay of of materials. Mm. They were plastic hard keys, which doesn't
Speaker 17:  sound nice, but the phone was soft touch. That's one of the things we were,
Speaker 17:  we were doing on Clicks actually pretty late, was once we had the keys locked
Speaker 17:  in, I was like, there's something still weird and missing about this. And
Speaker 17:  it turned out it's what's around back. So we ended up putting that stamp
Speaker 17:  like vegan leather back plate on there to, to make it feel, you know, to
Speaker 17:  give you the entire tactile experience. 'cause you got, you know, eight
Speaker 17:  other fingers that you gotta worry about when you're typing. Right. Right.
Speaker 17:  What do they feel? But If, you look at those keys in cross-section, you'll
Speaker 17:  notice they're domed over the top too. And that helps with, with
Speaker 17:  determining separation of keys by touch. So you'll always have an easier
Speaker 17:  time on a domed keyboard than you will on something where it's all crowded
Speaker 17:  together. Like on the bold and the bold didn't do that 'cause it was a better
Speaker 17:  typing experience. The bold did that because BlackBerry wanted a a narrower
Speaker 17:  phone. So it was, that's why you had those triangular frets in the corner.
Speaker 17:  So they're like, the science of this stuff is fascinating and
Speaker 17:  I'm so glad it's not lost to history because you can still talk to the people
Speaker 17:  who designed it. They're like, oh this is why you did this. These are smart
Speaker 17:  ideas. It's good to bring some of them back.
Speaker 2:  Tell me also about doing this in kind of the iPhone era, because I think
Speaker 2:  people have tried and failed at this in part because the iPhone, it's good
Speaker 2:  at what it does already. Yes. How do you like put those two things
Speaker 2:  together?
Speaker 17:  First of all, one frankly made our jobs a lot easier is that we
Speaker 17:  You don't have to do anything with Clicks. You don't have to install our
Speaker 17:  app If. you don't want to, you literally plug an iPhone in and the iPhone
Speaker 17:  goes, you know, which uses the lightning port or the USB port and the iPhone
Speaker 17:  says, oh that's a physical keyboard because all the hooks that it needs
Speaker 17:  are built into iOS to begin with. So you just start typing and it's like,
Speaker 17:  okay, well it turns out this product can handle it very well. And
Speaker 2:  It's not nothing that that's the case by the way. And I think, I think a
Speaker 2:  lot of people would be surprised that that's the case because there just
Speaker 2:  isn't really a reason for the iPhone to do that. but it is surprisingly
Speaker 2:  receptive to the existence of a physical keyboard.
Speaker 17:  I think in terms of like a philosophical thing, I had a little bit of
Speaker 17:  the same problem grasping it. At first it was like, gosh, what are we building?
Speaker 17:  And then somebody said something very smart and they said, look, nobody
Speaker 17:  looks twice, nobody thinks twice when you use an iPad with a magic
Speaker 17:  keyboard. And then you say, well I don't really need the keyboard right
Speaker 17:  now. So you take it off and then later you're gonna write an email and you
Speaker 17:  put the keyboard back on. Like that is the definition of normal use
Speaker 17:  case for that product. Why shouldn't the same thing be true of the phone?
Speaker 17:  And the minute somebody put it in that lens for me, I was like, oh, oh okay
Speaker 17:  good. And you know, we, we kind of hedge a little bit too because there's
Speaker 17:  a button on Clicks so you can hit to call up the virtual keyboard. So like,
Speaker 17:  you know, there are times man, where I'm walking around and I'm like, I
Speaker 17:  do not wanna type on a physical keyboard with one hand. It is annoying and
Speaker 17:  slow and I don't like it. So that's the virtual keyboard and I can swipe
Speaker 17:  around and stuff and I can use emojis and then I can put it away. So
Speaker 17:  like, it's really about the adaptability for me. Like I, you know, it's
Speaker 17:  eliminating buttons. Yeah, good call, had to do it, but it turns out
Speaker 17:  there's a lot that you miss. So why not just have buttons when you want
Speaker 17:  them? That was kind of our guiding philosophy after we figured out that
Speaker 17:  we could actually make it.
Speaker 2:  What have you seen in terms of like surprising cool stuff that you can do
Speaker 2:  on the iPhone? I mean one of, one of the things I, you know, you've mentioned
Speaker 2:  and I've seen you talk about elsewhere is just added screen real estate,
Speaker 2:  right? Like you don't realize how big your phone screen is until
Speaker 2:  you can actually see the whole thing. It's
Speaker 17:  So
Speaker 2:  Annoying. Which I think is real. I also wonder like you've been using these
Speaker 2:  things longer than just about anybody, right? Like what have you seen in
Speaker 2:  your own kind of phone usage life that is helped by a physical keyboard like
Speaker 2:  this?
Speaker 17:  Yeah. one of the, so the example that they make me do, that my colleagues
Speaker 17:  make me do on video, 'cause you're the creator, you're the influencer. Do
Speaker 17:  the, do the live Instagram streaming thing and typing while you do it. I'm
Speaker 17:  like, I don't, I don't care about that. What I care about is I'm in 85 group
Speaker 17:  chats, right? And when you're in a group chat and you're looking at all
Speaker 17:  the context of what people have said before, and then you go to respond
Speaker 17:  and then virtual keyboard pops up and then it clears half the screen stop
Speaker 17:  So I love using Clicks for that specifically, but it it, it's
Speaker 17:  kinda like an Easter egg hunt. There are all the the hot key shortcuts that
Speaker 17:  work on the magic keyboard. Oh nice. Or at least a lot of 'em work And Clicks
Speaker 17:  too. So there's that. And I go into every app and I try the old,
Speaker 17:  the old BlackBerry shortcuts. Can I hit T to go to the top? Now I can't.
Speaker 17:  What does space bar do? Oh that scrolls. Okay. Well this phone is really
Speaker 17:  tall and now with Clicks it's even taller. So how do I get to the notification
Speaker 17:  shade? Does Globe n work weirdly? Yes it does.
Speaker 17:  And what is about shift space? Oh, that goes the other way. And like just,
Speaker 17:  there are so many little old habits that I sort of forgot about
Speaker 17:  from the days of reviewing all the old Cordy phones. And again
Speaker 17:  to IOS's great credit, they didn't rip any of that stuff out. It's all just
Speaker 17:  sitting there waiting to be utilized. My favorite is Globe and you know,
Speaker 17:  Safari's got a ton of them, but I mostly just use the space bar to scroll
Speaker 17:  'cause I'm lazy.
Speaker 2:  Does it have, the thing that I love so much about the Blackberries, which
Speaker 2:  is that if you're on the home screen and you just start typing, something
Speaker 2:  happens.
Speaker 17:  So on iOS you have to do, you have to invoke spotlight like you would on
Speaker 17:  a MacBook. So you do command space and then you pop up. So
Speaker 2:  Craig Federighi, if you're listening and I know that you are, just get
Speaker 2:  rid of that. Just let me start typing and it should pop up the spotlight.
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 17:  Do you
Speaker 2:  Remember that on the BlackBerry it was the best,
Speaker 17:  It was the best.
Speaker 2:  You're like, I wanna go to my calendar. I'm just gonna pull my phone outta
Speaker 2:  my pocket and hit CAL and it's gonna take me to my calendar. But I think,
Speaker 2:  I mean that that comes back to kind of the question about, you know, all
Speaker 2:  the other affordances we've made for the ways that people use phones now,
Speaker 2:  right? Like I think the swipe typing is an interesting one and my sense is
Speaker 2:  that has kind of come and gone and just purely anecdotally, everybody I know
Speaker 2:  who uses Android knows about the swipe typing and uses it. Especially when
Speaker 2:  you're using your phone with one hand, no one I know who uses an iPhone even
Speaker 2:  knows that that's a thing you can do. And like the space bar trick to move
Speaker 2:  the cursor Yes. Is my favorite party trick because no one knows
Speaker 2:  that's a thing and you show them and it just blows their mind to pieces.
Speaker 2:  Yes. But that's the kind of stuff that all of these companies have spent
Speaker 2:  this much time working on because they didn't have physical keyboards. And
Speaker 2:  in a funny way, they're trying to solve for the problems of physical keyboards.
Speaker 2:  Right. But also like once you got rid of them, you had to figure out a better
Speaker 2:  way to move a cursor because you didn't have arrow buttons anymore. And like,
Speaker 2:  you know what's great is arrow buttons. But now we've sort of come past that
Speaker 2:  and so now you have to go back and say, okay, we have a physical keyboard.
Speaker 2:  How do we make it do some touchscreen things?
Speaker 17:  Yes. Which is
Speaker 2:  An interesting challenge.
Speaker 17:  If you're utterly insane. How do we make an individual tiny touchscreen
Speaker 17:  behind every button, which is what I want to do. I want you
Speaker 17:  remember the Samsung alias? I do,
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 17:  Yes. one of those. Let's put an e and Q screen behind it. Let's put an OLED
Speaker 17:  behind every one of these. Let's make it $500 Clicks and see if, if anybody
Speaker 17:  buys it,
Speaker 2:  It'll be great. That's the full lunacy keyboard hinge
Speaker 2:  thing that I'm, I'm, I'm very excited for.
Speaker 17:  I'm gonna make that and then I'm retire, move to Mexico.
Speaker 2:  Why start on the iPhone by the way, as opposed to starting with, you know,
Speaker 2:  galaxy phones or pixel phones or trying to do something that is sort of universally
Speaker 2:  Android. Like I've been spending some time with the backbone folks and they've
Speaker 2:  been doing some really interesting work to try to figure out how do we make
Speaker 2:  one thing that works for everybody. And I can imagine, you know, If, you
Speaker 2:  build something that works for everybody, huge increase in the total available
Speaker 2:  market, but also If, you build something for Android, you are more likely
Speaker 2:  to hit the sort of phone nerd people who care about this stuff the way that
Speaker 2:  you and I do. Why not start there?
Speaker 17:  It's really about numbers. you know, honestly the, the total addressable
Speaker 17:  market of, of iPhone users is something like 1.3 billion. Sure.
Speaker 17:  And we know that Clicks is not for everybody. It's always fun
Speaker 17:  when somebody offers up some wisdom to me on social media. Like, well, you
Speaker 17:  know, this is, I'm, no one's gonna buy this. I'm like, okay,
Speaker 17:  if one in 1000 people buy it and you're targeting a base of like,
Speaker 17:  of iPhone users, like just from a sheer numbers perspective, it's, I have
Speaker 17:  preferred Android for a long time. Sure. Partially because of the hardware
Speaker 17:  diversity of that ecosystem. Right. So, I want to build one eventually,
Speaker 17:  but again, you gotta work in stages as, as you well know, you have to
Speaker 17:  start build a great product, build a healthy business on the back of that.
Speaker 17:  And then you can do other things To your other question about like
Speaker 17:  why not make a one size fits all? One definitely considered that. I mean
Speaker 17:  we got close to announcing that it'll probably come in The
Speaker 17:  future. There were just too many compromises. It doesn't look as good.
Speaker 17:  You can't get as many cool certifications when it's not built
Speaker 17:  for a very specific type of iPhone. Right. Oh, interesting. Sure. And, and
Speaker 17:  it, I hate to keep harping on the aesthetics, but we really wanted to ship
Speaker 17:  something that wasn't this kind of klugy, I won't name, name drop any
Speaker 17:  previous efforts, but like, you know, something that just doesn't look very
Speaker 17:  good, doesn't feel like it was purpose built for the phone. You
Speaker 17:  spent what, $1,100 on,
Speaker 2:  So let's say, you know, launch goes well. Everything comes out over the next
Speaker 2:  few months. What's next for Clicks? Like I, I know I've seen you're gonna
Speaker 2:  do, your plan is to do more colors and do drops and that kind of stuff. But
Speaker 2:  I also feel like the thing that I've learned about hardware startups over
Speaker 2:  the years is that getting the first one out the door is borderline
Speaker 2:  impossible. It's a huge amount of work. You have to talk to a bunch of manufacturers
Speaker 2:  and companies that don't know you and don't care about you. But then If,
Speaker 2:  you can If you can do the thing, prove you can do it, prove you're serious,
Speaker 2:  like the world kind of opens up to you a little bit and you strike me as
Speaker 2:  somebody who has some pretty wild ideas about where all of this could go.
Speaker 2:  Do you feel like there is tons of runway left in like the footprint of
Speaker 2:  a keyboard? Do you have big ideas about other stuff you want to add in, like
Speaker 2:  tease The future a little bit For me,
Speaker 17:  This is not true what I'm about to say, but
Speaker 17:  perfect. So, but to an extent, you know, I
Speaker 17:  almost wish the beginning portion was as
Speaker 17:  harrowing as you described. But because we have so many people in the right
Speaker 17:  places, we don't have as many of those problems as we might, as we might
Speaker 17:  otherwise. So we've had to think ahead of time ahead
Speaker 17:  of when I would prefer to think about these larger conceptual questions,
Speaker 17:  these vision questions of like, at some point you have to ask yourself,
Speaker 17:  well what are we gonna do? Like you just said, are we just gonna own buttons
Speaker 17:  on, on mobile phones or are we gonna be the kind of company that asks, well
Speaker 17:  what else can click? Look, I have
Speaker 17:  giant, crazy dumb ideas in the latter category
Speaker 17:  and we have a very solid opportunity to make a, to make a pretty good business
Speaker 17:  in the former category. But I'll be honest with you, it's not clear which
Speaker 17:  direction we will go. 'cause we still do have to focus on getting,
Speaker 17:  you know, we've shipped Founder's edition that's thousands of units, but
Speaker 17:  it's not the main production run. So we're gonna take the time that we
Speaker 17:  have right now to to, to deliver the best possible Gen One product to all
Speaker 17:  the people who wanna buy 'em. And then we'll have, I'll have a better answer
Speaker 17:  for you this time next year. That's
Speaker 2:  A very good and very diplomatic answer. Thank you. And I appreciate that.
Speaker 2:  That is, that is someone who has been in a company for a while and I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  proud of you for that. Thanks man. Okay. So I won't ask you to tell me The
Speaker 2:  future, give me one huge wild idea that there's
Speaker 2:  absolutely no chance you're ever gonna build because it's impossible for
Speaker 2:  one reason or another.
Speaker 17:  You remember there was a, there was an old Kierra that ran, PAOs didn't
Speaker 17:  even have a color screen. We're talking 2001, I think it was a 7 71 something
Speaker 17:  and it had a touchscreen but it had a stowaway
Speaker 17:  detachable numeric keypad that attached via a hinge on the bottom
Speaker 17:  and If. you didn't wanna take it all the way off. You could flip it around
Speaker 17:  back so it would get outta the way. This
Speaker 2:  Is a very 2001 device you're describing. I love it. Thank
Speaker 17:  You. That's all I'm here to do is spring back the path. I wanna make one
Speaker 17:  of those for the galaxy flip five or the, or the razor. I wanna make a Clicks
Speaker 17:  that that flips around back and then flips up forward and overlaps the screen
Speaker 17:  and gives you a physical query keyboard that you can then flip away and
Speaker 17:  put around back. It would sell at least 127 units.
Speaker 17:  119 would probably fail. We will never build it. But I would like to
Speaker 17:  build it.
Speaker 2:  Why not have more mechanisms? That's right. Right. It's just like, what if
Speaker 2:  instead of a hinge, we had several hinges.
Speaker 17:  Exactly How
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one and the email is Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  Send us all your questions, all your thoughts, all your feelings, and we
Speaker 2:  try to answer at least one on the show every week. First of all, again, thank
Speaker 2:  you to everybody who is calling in about TikTok and the Apple antitrust stuff.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna get back to both of those a bunch in the next few weeks. So keep
Speaker 2:  calling. Tell us everything you think we got right? Tell us everything you
Speaker 2:  think we got wrong. Tell us all of your feelings about all of it. We wanna
Speaker 2:  hear everything. For now we have a question from Michael.
Speaker 21:  This is Michael from Madison. So my parents are getting older and I'm looking
Speaker 21:  to record them sharing family stories so we have them for
Speaker 21:  next generations and I was looking for advice
Speaker 21:  on what to buy microphone wise to record my parents
Speaker 21:  talking like Ken Burn style, like a cute couple. Any advice
Speaker 21:  on what to do would be great. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  All right. First of all, I believe strongly that everyone should make Ken
Speaker 2:  Burns documentaries about their family. This is an extremely good idea. Second
Speaker 2:  of all, Andru Marino is here to help me answer this question. Andru so much
Speaker 2:  of you on the show today, this makes me very happy.
Speaker 5:  I know what's up. You
Speaker 2:  Have come prepared with what I assume is just a large slew
Speaker 2:  of microphones. This question gets more complicated the longer I think about
Speaker 2:  it. Yeah. Which is why I'm very glad you're here. So take us through it.
Speaker 2:  What are your, what are your thoughts on this?
Speaker 5:  Okay, so I'm not sure what Michael is actually using to record
Speaker 5:  So. I have a couple options that will give a hybrid of of options
Speaker 5:  you can use. Right now I'm actually using one of the microphones,
Speaker 5:  the Road Wireless Me Road has a like a
Speaker 5:  slew of wireless microphones now. Yeah. That you could just plug
Speaker 5:  into your phone or plug into a camera or into an audio
Speaker 5:  recorder. They're super easy to use This look a little square,
Speaker 5:  you just kind of Oh, a big square.
Speaker 2:  It's a big square.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You clip onto your lapel. These
Speaker 2:  Are the ones that have like the, the receiver you plug into your phone or
Speaker 2:  computer or whatever and then the actual mic is what you put on whoever
Speaker 2:  you're talking to. Right. And then they automatically connect to each other.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. So, what I do a lot is I'll plug the
Speaker 5:  receiver into my phone and I'll record a voice memo or
Speaker 5:  with Rhodes Recorder app or like take a video and we'll
Speaker 5:  take the audio from the road wireless for the audio input.
Speaker 5:  That's a great option because you can, it's very versatile If. you want to
Speaker 5:  make video If, you want to be walking around If, you like
Speaker 5:  parents are like cooking dinner, like moving around and all that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 5:  The other one I have is the A TR 2100
Speaker 5:  XUSB mic from Audio Technica. What I like about it is
Speaker 5:  it's a USB microphone that's also an XLR
Speaker 5:  microphone. So If you wanna plug into your laptop,
Speaker 5:  into your tablet, into your phone. You can use this microphone but
Speaker 5:  also you can just use it into any mobile audio recorder that has an XLR
Speaker 5:  input or your audio interface or anything. That's a great option. We send
Speaker 5:  these mics to everyone on staff for The. Vergecast. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  This is the mic that I tell people like If, you don't wanna spend several
Speaker 2:  hundred dollars on a pro podcasting mic but you want
Speaker 2:  90% of the quality. I make people buy this mic. Like I have
Speaker 2:  recommended this mic to so many people who wanna do podcasts.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they're very cheap right now. I'm looking on B and H
Speaker 5:  and it's $49. Oh wow. Which is,
Speaker 2:  That's a really good deal.
Speaker 5:  Half the price of what they usually are.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This thing is a good deal at a hundred dollars, much less than $50.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  I should also mention that the road wireless packs range from
Speaker 5:  200 to $300. Depending what version you want to get. Those are
Speaker 5:  a little more expensive. So
Speaker 2:  Here's my question for you on this one though. I feel like there's a version
Speaker 2:  of this that is like sit with your, your two parents, right? That's what
Speaker 2:  you wanna do. You wanna, you wanna have them sit on a couch and talk to each
Speaker 2:  other. Do you give them each a mic and plug it into a recorder or do
Speaker 2:  you like set the mic on a table and kind of point it between them?
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's a good question. So I actually did this with my friends recently.
Speaker 5:  I interviewed them at their kitchen table and I had two of the
Speaker 5:  microphones, one for each person. That's the ideal situation. That's like,
Speaker 5:  I want the best recording. You can totally just put
Speaker 5:  table and have them talk into both of 'em. Like a little press
Speaker 5:  conference thing. But since they're so cheap, like
Speaker 5:  it's worth getting two maybe one for you, one for your guest
Speaker 5:  kind of thing too.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean a a hundred bucks plug these two things into your
Speaker 2:  computer. They each come with, if memory serves like a really crappy but
Speaker 2:  kind of useful little stand so you could be kinda all in for a hundred
Speaker 2:  dollars on this project and have pretty solid audio.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's actually the re another reason why I recommend it is it comes
Speaker 5:  with a stand.
Speaker 2:  It's not a good stand but it is a stand. Yes. And that comes for something.
Speaker 2:  Alright, you said you had one more, right? What's the, what's the third option?
Speaker 5:  Okay, so this is the Sennheiser MKE
Speaker 5:  600. Right now it goes for about
Speaker 5:  $350. This is more of a professional
Speaker 5:  microphone. I use this a lot for podcasting field recordings
Speaker 5:  or maybe I'm over someone's house and I'm
Speaker 5:  interviewing them. I love the crispness of this microphone.
Speaker 5:  How do you think it sounds?
Speaker 2:  It sounds really good. I, I can only see a little bit of it on your screen,
Speaker 2:  but this looks like a kind of proper shotgun mic. Yes,
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  That. Like this is the kind of thing that you stick on a boom arm and hold
Speaker 2:  over somebody's head on a film shoot like that that's, this is a much more
Speaker 2:  professional thing than either of the other two it seems.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is a great one for like indie filmmakers. Even If,
Speaker 5:  you wanna just put it on top of the camera, but I love it just on a
Speaker 5:  stand on a desk pointing right in front of the person's mouth has
Speaker 5:  just like a very detailed sound. If, you want the Ken
Speaker 5:  Burns documentary style, then this is a great choice and it's
Speaker 5:  affordable among the more professional microphones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the, the microphone world, especially in this realm of these
Speaker 2:  like shotgun boom mics can get really expensive really fast, but there's
Speaker 2:  definitely, especially for our purposes here, you hit the kind of
Speaker 2:  diminishing returns plateau pretty fast. Like just hearing you now, this
Speaker 2:  sounds really good. I don't know that you would necessarily for like human
Speaker 2:  archival purposes want something notably better than this. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I, I think so. And this is just an XLR microphone by the way. So
Speaker 5:  you would need either an audio interface or an audio recorder that has an
Speaker 5:  XLR input. Okay. Which is why I offer the others. Wait,
Speaker 2:  I want you to do one test for me here really quickly though. Yeah. Just move
Speaker 2:  around a little while you talk. Tell me sorry. 'cause this is the problem
Speaker 2:  with these shotgun mics right? Is you have to be like sort of perfectly in
Speaker 2:  front of it and it sounds amazing, but If you move sometimes they get weird.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I'm talking to the left of it right now, which is
Speaker 5:  off axis a little bit. You're gonna hear less of the clarity.
Speaker 5:  I'm going back to the center and I'm going to the right, go a little further
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  Usually when they have this shotgun mic you can go pretty far back because
Speaker 5:  it can catch your voice pretty far away.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. When you go back you get quieter but you're still very clear. But as
Speaker 2:  soon as you get off access, like it starts veering into
Speaker 2:  obviously gonna be the answer. But I feel like the lapel mic is really
Speaker 2:  useful
Speaker 5:  why I chose these.
Speaker 2:  Awesome. Well Michael, I hope that helps. Please let us know which one
Speaker 2:  you decide and we would love to hear the documentary when it's done
Speaker 2:  Andru. Thank you as always. That was awesome. No
Speaker 5:  Problem.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who came
Speaker 2:  on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on
Speaker 2:  everything we talked about, including that awesome video from our video team
Speaker 2:  about noise cancellation, all this stuff about Clicks. We'll put it all in
Speaker 2:  the show notes on The Verge dot com. But you know, read The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  It's a newsy time. There's a lot going on. Check it out. And as always If
Speaker 2:  you have thoughts, feelings, questions, or other keyboards you wanna see
Speaker 2:  brought back to life. You can always email us Vergecast The Verge dot com
Speaker 2:  or call the Hotline eight six six Verge one one. We wanna hear everything
Speaker 2:  from you. This show is produced by Andru Marino, Liam James and Will pour
Speaker 2:  The. Vergecast is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  NELI Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about probably more
Speaker 2:  antitrust stuff, more TikTok stuff and everything else going on in tech.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll.