# Transcript
ID: 1971b18c-b688-4f72-aa34-703891166e06
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6134382044359618100/-1327261820995299863/s93290-US-4182s-1712043879.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of alternate keyboard layouts:
03:36 - The Verge’s David Pierce talks to Jonas Hietala about his ultra-custom keyboard he built from the ground up to fit his specific needs.
Jonas Hietala: The T-34 keyboard layout
30:40 - The Verge’s Tom Warren explains the next phase of Microsoft with a new leader on the Windows and Surface team.
Microsoft has a new Windows and Surface chief
Microsoft’s first AI PCs are the Surface Pro 10 and Surface Laptop 6 for businesses
Rewind’s new feature brings ChatGPT to your personal information
57:32 - David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about tricks for Netflix recommendations.
How Planet Earth — and the Netflix homepage — get made
Vote for The Vergecast in the Webby's Technology Podcast category!
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of alternate keyboard
Speaker 2:  layouts. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here at my
Speaker 2:  dining room table going through what I guess I like to call just
Speaker 2:  my tech crap bag. So a bunch of years ago I started
Speaker 2:  basically buying duplicates of all of my chargers and
Speaker 2:  plugs and cords and backup headphones just to
Speaker 2:  have one thing that I can just leave in a bag in my suitcase
Speaker 2:  at all times so I don't have to unplug everything from my room when I wanna
Speaker 2:  leave, I don't have to constantly be schlepping stuff back and forth. I kind
Speaker 2:  of leave everything where it is at home, and then I have this stuff for travel.
Speaker 2:  It has saved me so much time and so much effort and so much forgetting of
Speaker 2:  stuff over the years. I cannot recommend it enough, but when I travel
Speaker 2:  a bunch in a row, it gets like this. It's kind of messy
Speaker 2:  and tangled and I don't know where anything is, and there's a bunch of stuff
Speaker 2:  that's supposed to be in here that I'm sure is not in here. So every once
Speaker 2:  in a while I have to sit down and very quietly and lovingly
Speaker 2:  coil it all back up, put it back in neatly, and then slowly destroy it
Speaker 2:  again over time. Works out great. Makes me feel good. No regrets.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today. We're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about two different things. First, starting off with our
Speaker 2:  kind of accidental keyboard series that we're doing, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk to somebody who spent two years reinventing from the
Speaker 2:  ground up, how his keyboard works and how he uses it. It's a super fun story.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna talk to Tom Warren about a surprising amount of
Speaker 2:  change happening at Microsoft right now and what that means for its plans
Speaker 2:  for AI and its plans for Surface devices and what an AI
Speaker 2:  PC is and a whole bunch of other stuff. We're also gonna do a Hotline question.
Speaker 2:  We got a lot coming up this episode. All that is coming up in just a second.
Speaker 2:  But first I just discovered that one of these cables has finally come
Speaker 2:  like fully undone and doesn't charge anymore, and so I need to
Speaker 2:  buy the replacement. This thing has lived a long life. It's time for a new
Speaker 2:  one. This is The Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 4:  your local agent today.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Here's a question. How often do you think about your
Speaker 2:  keyboard? I think for most people the answer is never. You just like have
Speaker 2:  a keyboard on your Laptop or your phone, that's your keyboard. The end at
Speaker 2:  the very top end of the spectrum I think are the mechanical keyboard people
Speaker 2:  who obsess over switches and colors and all that kind of stuff. I think as
Speaker 2:  regular computer users go, that's about as intense as it
Speaker 2:  gets. But there is a community of people online who go much,
Speaker 2:  much deeper than that. And I recently got on a call with one of them who
Speaker 2:  spent an evening in his office in Sweden talking to me about keyboards.
Speaker 5:  I'm Jonas Jonas ler. I started computer science, but I
Speaker 5:  prefer to see myself as a self-talk developer.
Speaker 2:  I found Jonas because over the last couple of years on his blog, he's been
Speaker 2:  keeping a journal of sorts about his attempt to build the perfect
Speaker 2:  keyboard because the keyboard he had, the ones that you and I use all day
Speaker 2:  without thinking much about them, wasn't working for him anymore. I mean,
Speaker 2:  it was fine in a certain sense, Jonas is a programmer and a pretty fast
Speaker 2:  typist.
Speaker 5:  I've never used these typing trainers or or websites or stuff, but I,
Speaker 5:  I think I typed in like 120 words per minute or something. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's okay, but it's not super incredible where when I started looking at
Speaker 5:  this, it was actually when I got R-S-I-R-S-I,
Speaker 2:  By the way, stands for repetitive strain injury or repetitive stress
Speaker 2:  injury. It's an umbrella term for what essentially is a lot of problems caused
Speaker 2:  by doing the same thing the same way over and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  I started feeling pain in my hand, specifically my right hand.
Speaker 5:  I had also broken my, on the top of the hand close to the the
Speaker 5:  pinky. So when I started typing, I'm like, oh, pressing like enter
Speaker 5:  and other keys with my pinky kind of hurt.
Speaker 2:  So the first thing Jonas thought was, okay, maybe I'll get an ergonomic keyboard.
Speaker 2:  One of those that's either split into or just has that kind of wavy
Speaker 2:  shape that's supposed to be less intense on your wrists and forearms.
Speaker 2:  He had actually tried these keyboards before,
Speaker 5:  Like 15 years ago or something. I was really into mechanical
Speaker 5:  keyboards, but at that time it was just, oh, pretty key caps. Oh, maybe
Speaker 5:  these switches that sound cool. Oh, look at how fast I'm typing. It
Speaker 5:  sounds like I'm typing fast with these switches. And I also
Speaker 5:  bought like an erox, I think it was one of the first
Speaker 5:  like ergonomical mechanical keyboards. And I got it. I was
Speaker 5:  super excited. I tried that out and hated it and I just put it in a box.
Speaker 5:  So when I got the RSI problems again, I'm like, oh, but I had the
Speaker 5:  solution here in a box somewhere. So I put it together and like, oh,
Speaker 5:  I theory crafted like, because it doesn't look like a regular keyboard,
Speaker 5:  right? So you have to figure out where to put your, at least your enter keys,
Speaker 5:  your space keys and some of these things. So I theory crafted them
Speaker 5:  like, oh, this will be perfect. It was so good. Put it together.
Speaker 5:  And I start typing like, oh shit, this sucks. I,
Speaker 5:  I mean I, I hate this. What? What should I do? Well of course
Speaker 5:  I bought another keyboard.
Speaker 2:  He eventually bought a keyboard called a Ferris. It looks kind of like a
Speaker 2:  normal keyboard deconstructed. It's made up of two panels of
Speaker 2:  17 keys, so 34 keys and all with a wire at the bottom
Speaker 2:  connecting the two parts. Each panel has five rows of keys aligned, kind
Speaker 2:  of like your hand with the tallest one in the middle, like your middle finger
Speaker 2:  and then two more keys, right where your thumb goes. The idea is that you
Speaker 2:  rest one hand on each panel and then you have easy access to all 34
Speaker 2:  keys without moving your fingers or wrists too much. So
Speaker 2:  Jonas buys that keyboard. Oh, and a mouse.
Speaker 5:  I also got this track ball because I got some RSI in the thumb
Speaker 5:  and most of these mouse alternatives you have the the ball of the
Speaker 5:  thumb, but that was really cotu. So I got this like big
Speaker 5:  track ball thing, which I move with the fingers. So of course I started that
Speaker 5:  route as well.
Speaker 2:  So he's got all this and feels like he's set. But the thing about Ferris
Speaker 2:  keyboards is that generally speaking, all the keys are blank. This thing
Speaker 2:  isn't a normal QWERTY keyboard like you're used to. And so you actually have
Speaker 2:  to decide where you want all the keys to go and oh boy,
Speaker 2:  is that quite the rabbit hole? It turns out there's nothing really magic
Speaker 2:  about the QWERTY layout that we're all used to. There are a lot of
Speaker 2:  theories about where Kie came from. Actually one you hear a lot
Speaker 2:  is that it was created for typewriters and that actually it deliberately
Speaker 2:  moved the commonly used keys away from each other so that the typewriter
Speaker 2:  mechanisms wouldn't crash into each other. I'm honestly not sure if that's
Speaker 2:  a myth or the truth, but that is kind of the common story that's out there
Speaker 2:  now. And really the reason we all use these keyboards
Speaker 2:  is just that we've used them all for so long. There's honestly not a better
Speaker 2:  reason that KTI has won except that it has won. And
Speaker 2:  retraining our brains to a new way of typing is just too much work.
Speaker 2:  But when you start thinking about it, when you really step all the way back
Speaker 2:  and start thinking about it, there are a lot of ways it could be better.
Speaker 5:  Quirk is like one of the worst or if not the worst
Speaker 5:  keyboard layout that's actually used. I mean there are a lot of
Speaker 5:  different ways you can evaluate keyboard layout. Some, and almost
Speaker 5:  no matter what way you choose to evaluate corti is really,
Speaker 5:  really bad. I don't really care. If, you want to argue
Speaker 5:  that Mack is better than war or if it's better than workman,
Speaker 5:  but all of these are so much better than QWERTY.
Speaker 2:  Isn't it weird that If you type quote unquote correctly, the only thing your
Speaker 2:  thumb ever does is hit the space bar. You're wasting two perfectly
Speaker 2:  good fingers on a single key, not to mention the easiest to hit
Speaker 2:  key on the whole keyboard. Also, your index finger is typically
Speaker 2:  more dextrous and powerful than your pinky. So why isn't it given
Speaker 2:  more to do and why are letters like O and A and even E,
Speaker 2:  the most common letter right in the middle of the keyboard, I should say
Speaker 2:  by the way, that keyboards and keyboard needs vary widely
Speaker 2:  across languages. One reason a lot of non-English speaking countries
Speaker 2:  have gravitated to software keyboards in particular. And one of the reasons
Speaker 2:  phones have been so successful in those places is that they can be customized
Speaker 2:  and vary so much more. But for my purposes here, I only know how to type
Speaker 2:  in English, so I'm gonna focus on English keyboards. Jonas does type some
Speaker 2:  in Swedish too, but that didn't figure too much into his story. Talking
Speaker 2:  to Jonas got me wondering about keyboard layouts. I know about like
Speaker 2:  Dvorack, which rearranges all the letter keys to try and put the most common
Speaker 2:  letters in combinations right on the home row so that you don't have to move
Speaker 2:  your fingers as much. But there are actually a million others too. There's
Speaker 2:  Mack, which does the same thing as Voac, but rearranges them in a slightly
Speaker 2:  different way. There's workman which tries specifically to minimize how
Speaker 2:  much your fingers move side to side, which is one of the most painful things
Speaker 2:  for them to do and how much work your pinkies have to do. There's one called
Speaker 2:  hands down that is particularly useful, If, you type in multiple languages
Speaker 2:  on and on and on. There are so many more of these than I realize. The one
Speaker 2:  I'm most interested in personally is called beak, L-B-E-A-K-L. It's
Speaker 2:  designed to do most of the same things as the rest, minimize finger and wrist
Speaker 2:  movement, especially side to side balance the load between your two hands,
Speaker 2:  make it easier to use the same finger for multiple letters in a row. But
Speaker 2:  bele is also big on shifting work from your ring and pinky finger
Speaker 2:  to your thumb. There's a website that I found with the principles of Bele
Speaker 2:  theory, which is a thing, and one of them is to exploit the
Speaker 2:  powerful thumbs to their maximum potential. What a cool sentence that is.
Speaker 2:  So you could put, let's say the E key, which again is the most commonly
Speaker 2:  used key on the keyboard on your thumb. It's wild and different, but
Speaker 2:  intellectually this makes sense to me. Anyway, Jonas tried Beagle and a bunch
Speaker 2:  of others and he started to lock in on something that felt really
Speaker 2:  good to type on, like physically good. And he also started to realize
Speaker 2:  that especially for his purposes, using a keyboard involved a whole
Speaker 2:  lot more than just typing the 26 letters of the alphabet.
Speaker 5:  When people talk about keyboard layouts, they almost
Speaker 5:  always refer to just the alpha keys like a, B, c,
Speaker 5:  up to set and it's like, oh, you have Mack. Well, they just
Speaker 5:  changed all these letters, but the numbers and the enter keys
Speaker 5:  and the space and everything else, they're always on the same, in the same
Speaker 5:  place. But when you use like a really small keyboard like
Speaker 5:  I do, then you don't even have this keys. So this is
Speaker 5:  something that you have to design
Speaker 2:  For Jonas. There was one app in particular that he cared about most. This
Speaker 2:  is like the only thing he talked to me about in our whole conversation, VIM,
Speaker 2:  it's a 30-year-old outrageously customizable text editor.
Speaker 2:  It's one of those apps that people, particularly programmers, kind of live
Speaker 2:  their whole life inside of.
Speaker 5:  One of the things about whim is that you have all these strange key
Speaker 5:  bindings. You can almost talk to any Vim user about this.
Speaker 5:  What is their number one fear of switching to a new layout?
Speaker 5:  It's well will make Vim key bindings work.
Speaker 5:  And you have like this arrow keys like
Speaker 5:  HJKL, and you have them on a regular keyboard. It's on the home
Speaker 5:  run. It's super convenient and most Veeam users
Speaker 5:  abuse them. People use them too much because, well, that's what
Speaker 5:  people do. So they also always worry, well, will this work?
Speaker 5:  I mean, should I, because switching to another layout, it's a
Speaker 5:  huge task. You need a ton of effort. Like nevermind just
Speaker 5:  designing your own, just learning something new is really, really
Speaker 5:  painful. And do you risk going into
Speaker 5:  this journey and you end up with something that might not
Speaker 5:  work for the tool that you use. And you know, myself and a lot of
Speaker 5:  other people who use wim, we use WIM for everything. I mean, we use
Speaker 5:  WIM all the time when we're programming, when we're writing. I mean there
Speaker 5:  are hours and hours every day we, we use this tool.
Speaker 5:  So I mean, I would say that it's something that I was
Speaker 5:  worried about from the beginning. It was something I looked at
Speaker 5:  when looking at other keyboard layouts because you, you don't
Speaker 5:  want to have your most used key, like J is one of the least
Speaker 5:  used keys in English. So most keyboard layouts that
Speaker 5:  try to optimize for English, because most do that they will just put
Speaker 5:  J in the worst spot. But then as a Vem user that's like, oh,
Speaker 5:  that sucks. I can't lay out anymore.
Speaker 5:  Well it, it's not that bad. I mean a lot of people use something
Speaker 5:  like a navigation layer or they try to force themselves to reduce
Speaker 5:  the usage of yay and the others movement keys w
Speaker 5:  jump to in the next word for instance. And it's a lot better to use that
Speaker 5:  than the Veeam Arrow keys, but it was still something
Speaker 5:  that I was worried about.
Speaker 2:  So for an extremely specific, extremely customized use case,
Speaker 2:  Jonas decided to get an extremely specific, extremely customized keyboard.
Speaker 2:  There's no world in which you or I could sit down and use his computer,
Speaker 2:  which is actually a thing about this whole process that I kind of love. We
Speaker 2:  all use the same gadgets in the same super prescribed ways
Speaker 2:  now. And Jonas just decided to blow all that up and set up
Speaker 2:  something that worked just for him and nobody else.
Speaker 5:  The this was just for me to reduce my RSI.
Speaker 5:  And I mean, should I do this because of popularity or or
Speaker 5:  because I want everyone else to use it. No, I don't. I just
Speaker 5:  want it to feel good for me. And it's the same reason why I
Speaker 5:  spent hours of configuring my own Neo VE
Speaker 5:  configuration. I mean that that's just time sink that will,
Speaker 5:  no one will ever get any use of it. It's just for me. And
Speaker 5:  it's the same for my layout really. And
Speaker 5:  I know there are a lot of people who designed these like general
Speaker 5:  layouts, but I really feel that customizing the layout,
Speaker 5:  even If, you just, you know, change escape to a better
Speaker 5:  position because as a wind user escape is like a super important key. So
Speaker 5:  maybe you just change that. And I think customizing things
Speaker 5:  is actually a bit underappreciated in the keyboard
Speaker 5:  layout community. I mean, a lot of people want to make
Speaker 5:  these generalized good things like, oh, this is the perfect layout
Speaker 5:  for English. And I think more people should try to
Speaker 5:  customize, especially when you go down this rabbit hole of choosing
Speaker 5:  a smaller keyboard or a more iCal keyboard.
Speaker 2:  So Jonas starts experimenting at this point. He puts in a layout, uses it
Speaker 2:  for a while and starts trying to really notice what's working and what
Speaker 2:  isn't. I both do and don't recommend doing this for yourself by the way,
Speaker 2:  because it'll make you strangely self-aware of how you type.
Speaker 2:  And at least for me, I'm convinced it's making me worse at typing. I think
Speaker 2:  about it much more than I ever have and I'm not sure that's a good thing.
Speaker 2:  But Jonas got really good at figurine out what worked and what didn't.
Speaker 2:  And most importantly, what hurt and what didn't.
Speaker 5:  I think there are two directions you can do this. One is
Speaker 5:  to take the purely algorithmically approach. You create
Speaker 5:  a computer program that optimizes to find the perfect layout for you and
Speaker 5:  then you just tweak the settings. Oh, I don't like same finger
Speaker 5:  diagrams. So this is a penalty for having these two keys
Speaker 5:  on the same finger. And then you just tweak all these
Speaker 5:  settings all the time until you find something that's good. So that that's
Speaker 5:  one way of doing it. I did not do that. I instead
Speaker 5:  went mostly on feel. So when
Speaker 5:  designing the alpha layer, I looked a lot at the same finger
Speaker 5:  diagram because I know that it was something I really
Speaker 5:  disliked. So oh, maybe I can switch around these three
Speaker 5:  characters. And I thought about it like a lot, oh, I'm gonna try it. And
Speaker 5:  I look in this like analyzers, oh, but that
Speaker 5:  diagram is really common. That's not good. So then I went back to
Speaker 5:  the drawing book, but mostly it was think about it,
Speaker 5:  think about it some more, try it. That was
Speaker 5:  basically my approach. It's probably not the best approach,
Speaker 5:  but it was the one I used mostly because I think
Speaker 5:  it's extremely hard for me to put down this
Speaker 5:  feeling of how good this feel into numbers.
Speaker 5:  You can do a basic exercise to just, how hard is it to press
Speaker 5:  one key on your keyboard? So if it's on the home round, you can
Speaker 5:  put a zero because it's the easiest, but in the edge of the screen of
Speaker 5:  the keyboard, is that the four or is that the three or
Speaker 5:  maybe a five? I tried to do this exercise and every time
Speaker 5:  I went back to do it again I got a different result because
Speaker 5:  it's so freaking hard for me to just put these things into
Speaker 5:  numbers. So that's why I gave up on the idea and I just said, oh,
Speaker 5:  I will just try it, feel it and change it whenever I
Speaker 5:  dislike something.
Speaker 2:  Did you ever try something and then just immediately the first
Speaker 2:  time you hit the key you were like, I hate this, this feels bad. Failed attempt.
Speaker 5:  Yes, I think I had R and underscore like they're
Speaker 5:  not on the same finger now, but I, I tried it and it's,
Speaker 5:  oh, I can just switch these two keys. It would be much better.
Speaker 5:  And the first time I, I used type something because in coding you have like
Speaker 5:  r and underscore quite often next to each other when you type
Speaker 5:  variable names with snake case, I was like, oh I hate this. And I
Speaker 5:  immediately just threw it away.
Speaker 2:  Once you start to think about this stuff in terms of minimizing pain and
Speaker 2:  movement, you come across all sorts of hacks. One thing I had never heard
Speaker 2:  of but Jonas and others talk about a lot is the idea of a repeat
Speaker 2:  key.
Speaker 5:  I don't remember exactly where I got this idea from, but the repeat key
Speaker 5:  basically repeats the last key you pressed. So for instance,
Speaker 5:  If, you want to type fool, you press
Speaker 5:  FOOL, but in this case you press
Speaker 5:  FO, repeat L, why is this useful? Well,
Speaker 5:  If, you are just looking at same finger programs, which I don't
Speaker 5:  like. I dislike pressing the same key multiple times.
Speaker 5:  So instead of typing O with the middle finger, I type
Speaker 5:  middle finger and then the pink, which is my repeat key
Speaker 5:  location right now. So you can do this like rolling motion
Speaker 5:  and rolling motions, they're really quite nice and
Speaker 5:  a lot of different keyboard layouts optimize more for rolling
Speaker 5:  motions than same finger diagrams. So I think
Speaker 5:  empty gap is one layout which has really good rolls.
Speaker 2:  Rolling meaning kind of just the way your fingers move from
Speaker 2:  into out,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, into out or out win. If they're not next to each other,
Speaker 5:  they're usually really easy to press.
Speaker 2:  This is what I mean when I say it's a deep rabbit hole. The people who work
Speaker 2:  on this stuff are thinking about keyboards the way I think we all should
Speaker 2:  as incredibly important, incredibly complex tools that get used
Speaker 2:  for countless hours every day and in which even a small improvement
Speaker 2:  can be a huge deal. And there are so many small improvements out there.
Speaker 2:  One thing a lot of keyboard tinkerers like to use is what's called a one
Speaker 2:  shot key. Instead of pressing and holding. So If, you wanna capitalize something,
Speaker 2:  you hit shift and then the letter you want, instead of having to hold, shift
Speaker 2:  down and stretch your hand all the way across the keyboard, it's a little
Speaker 2:  thing but can be a real pain reliever. The problem is all that
Speaker 2:  improvement is fighting against literally a hundred years of muscle memory
Speaker 2:  in how to use QWERTY keyboards. And so the improvements keep losing.
Speaker 2:  It took Jonas someone who was deeply dedicated to this two years
Speaker 2:  to get around to something that fit, that he didn't feel like he needed to
Speaker 2:  obsessively tweak anymore. I tried a bunch of times to get him
Speaker 2:  to describe kind of his mental model of his keyboard, how he
Speaker 2:  designed it, how it works, and how he uses it. And he kind of couldn't do
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 5:  I was worried you, I would have to explain, oh, where is X? Oh, where
Speaker 5:  is this? Because I can't, it's almost all muscle
Speaker 5:  memory right now. I mean if I really think about it, sure
Speaker 5:  the most used keys I could probably map out. But I mean
Speaker 5:  most of it is just I need to sit down and press the buttons
Speaker 2:  Since he can't explain it. Let me try Jonas's layout, which he now calls
Speaker 2:  T 34 is basically a bunch of layers of keys.
Speaker 2:  The top layer is the alphabet and some basic punctuation. And he put
Speaker 2:  common letters like T and K and I in the center and e
Speaker 2:  on his thumb. He has two modifier keys that then let him go down
Speaker 2:  a layer to a new set of keys. This part he does explain pretty well.
Speaker 5:  So for instance, you can have, oh, where do you have your arrow keys? Well,
Speaker 5:  I just press down my left thumb and then I have arrow keys on the
Speaker 5:  right hand just below my fingers. I also have it on the left hand,
Speaker 5:  like in the arrow configuration that normal keywords have as well.
Speaker 5:  So when I press the thumb, I activate the navigation layer.
Speaker 5:  And then you have this like, like, like you say, you, you stack the
Speaker 5:  keys on top of them. So that's a way you can access arrow
Speaker 5:  keys, function keys. I also access number keys because I don't
Speaker 5:  have a number or symbols, et cetera. So yeah, I don't know
Speaker 5:  how many layers I have. It ends up quite a lot. I have a lot of
Speaker 5:  layers that don't even remember, like I had this idea of
Speaker 5:  wanting to be able to type regular shortcuts because
Speaker 5:  like control X is a super common shortcut
Speaker 5:  in a lot of different applications, but I have X
Speaker 5:  on the right hand, so sometimes I just want to use
Speaker 5:  the mouse with my right hand. So I don't want to remove my mouse
Speaker 5:  and do control X. So I have a layer. Well,
Speaker 5:  control X is on the left side, so layers is a super
Speaker 5:  important thing.
Speaker 2:  This all feels to me a little like trying to use Excel just with a keyboard,
Speaker 2:  remembering all of the navigation tools and keyboard shortcuts and formulas
Speaker 2:  and everything else. But Jonas says that once he figured it out, it began
Speaker 2:  to feel much better, at least for him. I should again be clear here
Speaker 2:  that never for one second, did he think he was designing a better keyboard
Speaker 2:  for everybody, just a better keyboard for himself. And honestly, in this
Speaker 2:  case, even better, depends on how you define the word.
Speaker 5:  I thought I would really enjoy this process of gradually getting
Speaker 5:  better. Like, because I had this idea in my head.
Speaker 5:  Another cool thing is to be a really fast typer. So I want
Speaker 5:  to, you know, continue with practicing every day until I, I
Speaker 5:  beat my old score and maybe even surpass it. But then I just figured,
Speaker 5:  ah, this is just super hard work, it's really
Speaker 5:  boring and I cannot do it anymore. So I'm not
Speaker 5:  even close as fast as I'm on a regular keyboard,
Speaker 5:  I don't really care that much that I'm a bit slower. I mean I
Speaker 5:  really care about my hand not hurting every day.
Speaker 2:  So victory, right? As for whether it was worth all the time and energy to
Speaker 2:  get to this point, well debatable,
Speaker 5:  I actually started its journey when we had our second child, our
Speaker 5:  middle child, and he was awake like one to two hours
Speaker 5:  every night. He's on my chest in some kind of strap and I just standing
Speaker 5:  and I don't want to play with him because I want him to sleep. So I, I ended
Speaker 5:  up just standing in front of my computer and doing stuff and
Speaker 5:  that's when I really designed most of my layout and learned most
Speaker 5:  of my layout. So in the middle of night, like for six months or something,
Speaker 5:  I was just like a bit sleep deprived and maybe that's what
Speaker 5:  it takes to go on on this kind of journey. But I don't know.
Speaker 2:  All that said though, he does kind of think everyone should go
Speaker 2:  through at least a bit of this process. And I think I agree If, you spend
Speaker 2:  hours a day with your wrists cocked awkwardly and stretching painfully
Speaker 2:  around a keyboard. Why shouldn't you invest the time and energy to get
Speaker 2:  something better?
Speaker 5:  The first thing I would recommend is just to get the programmable
Speaker 5:  keyboard If. you use Wim, you know that escape is the best
Speaker 5:  key there is and there are lots of different ways to, to solve this.
Speaker 5:  But you If, you have a programmable keyboard, you can just move it to caps
Speaker 5:  lock or you can make a combo on the home row. Or maybe you
Speaker 5:  use emax and you say that, oh the control key is
Speaker 5:  the most horrible key there is because you need like a
Speaker 5:  a six finger If. you use emax, you really should have a six finger. So you
Speaker 5:  can press that damn control key all the time. If, you have a
Speaker 5:  programmable keyboard, then you can just move control up to caps lock. You
Speaker 5:  can even have escape and caps lock on the same key. So
Speaker 5:  If, you tap it, it's escape and If, you hold it down, it's control. So that's
Speaker 5:  really the first thing I would recommend people to do because you don't have
Speaker 5:  to relearn anything. You can just remap escape or
Speaker 5:  control or you can put the navigation layers. Like instead of having the
Speaker 5:  arrow keys like far away on the keyboard, you can just have it on
Speaker 5:  the home row and just hold down something. And that's pretty easy to get
Speaker 5:  right.
Speaker 2:  He also recommended a split keyboard, which makes total sense to me, but
Speaker 2:  I should confess something here. I hung up our call expecting to go make
Speaker 2:  a bunch of changes, explore a new layout, try and combat the pain that I'm
Speaker 2:  also starting to feel typing all day every day. And then I did nothing,
Speaker 2:  just nothing. The thing is I type too much too often
Speaker 2:  and I type really fast and it just seems like so much work to
Speaker 2:  essentially learn what amounts to like a new instrument just to be able to
Speaker 2:  do my job all day. I'm not sure how long I could get away with
Speaker 2:  not filing stories because I can't type fast enough, you know what I mean?
Speaker 2:  So I'm stuck sitting here staring at this stupid QWERTY keyboard on
Speaker 2:  my desk, which apparently everyone agrees is a bad option, but it's kind
Speaker 2:  kind of just the one we're stuck with. And so now I'm looking around my desk
Speaker 2:  wondering what else is like this? What other tech is this way? Just because
Speaker 2:  it is this way. We talk about AI as upending the way we
Speaker 2:  do everything online. And maybe that's good even if the AI isn't good and
Speaker 2:  ultimately isn't going to change everything about how we do everything because
Speaker 2:  maybe it's good to sit down and rethink how we do everything every
Speaker 2:  once in a while.
Speaker 5:  My image of the ultimate keyboard was just a regular keyboard
Speaker 5:  with cooler switches. So that, that was the extent of my knowledge. I,
Speaker 5:  I knew I had this adox, but it's like that's just a weird strange
Speaker 5:  thing. But I mean I think it's when you start
Speaker 5:  going down the rabbit hole, the hole starts to open and you realize,
Speaker 5:  oh there are so many other things.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk
Speaker 2:  about Surface Windows and The future of Microsoft. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  Support for The Vergecast
Speaker 7:  client
Speaker 6:  fun, but it's the experiences that people love the most about traveling.
Speaker 6:  When you get back home, that T-shirt might fade and that snow globe
Speaker 2:  might just hire the entirety of OpenAI. And of course all of that
Speaker 2:  turned out to be nothing. But there have been a few corporate
Speaker 2:  moves and a couple of product launches and even a different non acquisition
Speaker 2:  acquisition That all make me think there is something big
Speaker 2:  going on here in terms of how Microsoft thinks about AI and
Speaker 2:  Windows and Surface in particular. So it's time to do what we
Speaker 2:  always do in these situations, which is get the verges Tom Warren on the
Speaker 2:  line to help us figure out what's actually going on here. Tom Warren, welcome
Speaker 2:  back to the show.
Speaker 8:  Hey, good to be back.
Speaker 2:  I feel like I have to bring you on every time Microsoft does something weird
Speaker 2:  and confusing and you have to make sense of it. I feel like this is, this
Speaker 2:  is not what your job should be, but this is what, this is what I need you
Speaker 2:  for.
Speaker 8:  It does feel like that's my job. It's just explaining Microsoft's mess
Speaker 8:  essentially
Speaker 2:  Just forever like reading the org chart of Microsoft to make sense.
Speaker 2:  And so actually the org chart is where I wanna start. I wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  AI PCs and I wanna talk about services, but we're gonna get to all that in
Speaker 2:  a minute 'cause I actually think what is happening inside of Microsoft actually
Speaker 2:  explains a lot of that stuff. Right? So let's go back to
Speaker 2:  six-ish months ago I think, which is when Pantos Pane announced he was leaving
Speaker 2:  Microsoft. Yes. Describe that moment to me at Microsoft. 'cause he's the
Speaker 2:  guy who'd been there forever. He was a big face of Microsoft, he was in charge
Speaker 2:  of a lot of things. Like what happened when PAOs left.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think it was, it was kind of a surprise, right? I think it took us
Speaker 8:  up by surprise and I think it probably took Microsoft by surprise as well.
Speaker 8:  Like the thing is it was a few days or like before a surfers event,
Speaker 8:  which was also like, oh that's right timing. you know, that they announced
Speaker 8:  it publicly anyway. And I think like catching up with people at the event
Speaker 8:  you could, you got that sense that it was a surprise, you know, this wasn't
Speaker 8:  expected to happen. So yeah, I think that that, that was the big takeaway
Speaker 8:  was it was a surprise. And I think the way that Microsoft kind of responded
Speaker 8:  to it, like Mandela's shapeshifting of Windows was that they
Speaker 8:  split Windows and Surface so, so panel's responsibilities
Speaker 8:  into two different leaders.
Speaker 2:  And if I'm not mistaken, Microsoft had made a big deal out of uniting those
Speaker 2:  things under Panos, right? Yeah. That was like, that was supposed to be this
Speaker 2:  coherent like holistic way of thinking about devices. Right? And that wasn't
Speaker 2:  that long
Speaker 8:  Ago. No, it wasn't and it, it, it was around, actually I think it was
Speaker 8:  just before the pandemic started.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow, okay. Which I guess at this point is a while ago, but
Speaker 8:  It doesn't seem like that long ago. It was a while ago. It doesn't feel like
Speaker 8:  it. Right, okay. But it was interesting timing because it was a few months
Speaker 8:  after Panos and, and the rest of the Surface team had unveiled the, you know,
Speaker 8:  dual screen Surface stuff and that was gonna be The future of Windows and
Speaker 8:  all that sort of stuff. So it, it seemed like that, you know, putting
Speaker 8:  everything under Panos was going to align
Speaker 8:  Surface hardware and Windows software. So that seemed like that was what
Speaker 8:  was gonna happen. That's what Panos had been working on and then they just
Speaker 8:  split it out in a really weird way. So obviously Panos left
Speaker 8:  for Amazon, they gave the Surface hardware stuff to Pav Van
Speaker 8:  Dava Luri, he's been at Microsoft for over 20 years. He's pretty
Speaker 8:  key Surface engineer, he's definitely a key player there. It
Speaker 8:  was pretty instrumental to the Qualcomm and a MD relationships
Speaker 8:  where they've done the customs SQ one processes and stuff for these Surface.
Speaker 2:  So like a natural guy to put in charge of this after partner seats. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, definitely for the hardware side. And then they split off the Windows
Speaker 8:  sort of engineering efforts and all those teams over to, to Macal
Speaker 8:  Perkin who had been at Microsoft for, for a number of years as well. But
Speaker 8:  was essentially his official title was formally now, but
Speaker 8:  CEO of like web and advertising.
Speaker 2:  I feel like he's a name I started to hear with some of the AI stuff over
Speaker 2:  the last year. So is that
Speaker 8:  Right? Yeah, so he was looking after, you'd hear him a lot when he was tweeting
Speaker 8:  for about the Bing Chat stuff. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, okay.
Speaker 8:  Edge maybe all that sort of stuff. So it was difficult for me to wrap my
Speaker 8:  head around this 'cause it was like, it didn't seem like the natural person's
Speaker 8:  takeover windows just given his role, but he's obviously
Speaker 8:  a talented engineer and and leader, but it seems strange
Speaker 8:  for it to go that way given where Windows Windows and Surface have been.
Speaker 8:  So that happened about six months ago. He's been looking after that and
Speaker 8:  then not so much anymore.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So that, that brings us to, to now and basically that has been
Speaker 2:  at least as far as I can tell, sort of pretty cleanly undone
Speaker 8:  Pretty much. Yeah. So the teams that, I'd say most of the teams
Speaker 8:  that went over to AL'S organization have gone
Speaker 8:  back essentially If, you wanna call it that to per van
Speaker 8:  d who was obviously looking after the Surface hardware. So he's now looking
Speaker 8:  after Windows, most of the Windows engineering and Surface hardware.
Speaker 8:  The key thing is that it all kind of ties into a big move
Speaker 8:  that Nadella made. So this is why it's, it's actually happening.
Speaker 8:  And he's obviously hired the former co-founder of Google
Speaker 8:  DeepMind, Mustafa Solomon, and he hired him into a position
Speaker 8:  as CEO of Microsoft ai. So a new group inside Microsoft
Speaker 8:  or you might say the same group that Macal was looking after and
Speaker 8:  has kind of been pushed out slightly. He's given it a lot to
Speaker 8:  Microsoft and particularly on the ads and search side.
Speaker 8:  Like they, they've become a lot more relevant in the last few years on, on
Speaker 8:  that side than they, than they've been before. You can argue they've been
Speaker 8:  pushing Bing in weird ways, pushing edge in weird ways that haven't been
Speaker 8:  too great for consumers.
Speaker 2:  You're saying you don't love giant popups telling you to use Bing Chat?
Speaker 8:  I love it when I'm in the middle of playing a game or like in my Excel spreadsheet
Speaker 8:  and there's this giant, please use copilot or whatever. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  perfect.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's the clippies thing Microsoft has done since Clippy and I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  not a fan. I know, but okay, so if I, if I understand sort of the org structure
Speaker 2:  now you have basically the sort of windows and
Speaker 2:  devices side of things, which is basically like hardware that people
Speaker 2:  use and that's all under Pavan Velu now he has like
Speaker 2:  most of the Panos job is now his.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And he's not like, he's still not on like the senior leadership team,
Speaker 8:  so he still reports up to someone, but essentially he, that's what he's looking
Speaker 8:  after and I think I get the impression that most of that work that he's
Speaker 8:  be looking after is, is how they optimize windows
Speaker 8:  for the new silicon that's coming and you know, the NPUs,
Speaker 8:  all that sort of stuff. 'cause that seems to be pretty key and we'll see
Speaker 8:  talk about that soon. But that's why they, I think they're bringing it back
Speaker 8:  to, to that side 'cause they know they need that engineering effort.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. I do wanna talk about that Yeah, in just a sec because I think
Speaker 2:  how all of this comes like back together in the product is the part of this
Speaker 2:  that I understand the least and right. We're gonna talk about that. But
Speaker 2:  the, the other side of this, we haven't really talked about all of the inflection
Speaker 2:  AI
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Non acquisition acquisition stuff going on. So basically as I understand
Speaker 2:  it, Microsoft hired Mufa Suleman who was the co-founder of DeepMind and then
Speaker 2:  went and founded this company called Inflection ai. Yep. Paid a ton of money
Speaker 2:  for him and a bunch of other executives to come join the company. Didn't
Speaker 2:  call it an acquisition. A lot of people are saying that's because it was
Speaker 2:  worried about the antitrust ramifications of calling it an acquisition. But
Speaker 2:  essentially they acquihire or like whatever the opposite of an acquihire
Speaker 2:  is like higher positioned a bunch of inflection AI people to
Speaker 2:  come do AI for Microsoft. Which again to me says
Speaker 2:  Microsoft doesn't feel like it is where it needs to be
Speaker 2:  in terms of like winning the AI race. And this is the company that 12 months
Speaker 2:  ago was just as confident as you could possibly be about The future
Speaker 2:  of AI and Bing being the thing and making Google dance and that they were
Speaker 2:  really gonna win. This says to me that Microsoft is much less
Speaker 2:  feeling itself maybe than it was a year ago. What's your read of this
Speaker 2:  situation?
Speaker 8:  I think that's, that's spot on. Yeah, so they, a year ago obviously, and
Speaker 8:  I've written about this recently, they, they were obviously all in on Bing
Speaker 8:  and Bing chat, all that sort of stuff. And internally they were talking
Speaker 8:  about picking the Bing brand because obviously there's I think
Speaker 8:  particularly among tech people anyway and, and the, the general consumer
Speaker 8:  can look at Bing and probably be like, don't even know what it is maybe.
Speaker 8:  But along the, along the tech sort of people is is kind of
Speaker 8:  laughed at, right? It's it's frowned upon the the Bing brand. Yeah. And they
Speaker 8:  were talking internally at that time like, you know, it's it's it's 500 million
Speaker 8:  or whatever it's in marketing spend to pick a new name. So they were like,
Speaker 8:  we're gonna go with Bing. That's the way forward. It didn't really shift
Speaker 8:  the needle, right? Like Nadela wanted Google to dance. They, they wanted
Speaker 8:  to get all these, you know, percentage points off of Google. I don't, I think
Speaker 8:  they probably only got about one or 2% if that otherwise they were,
Speaker 8:  they were aiming for for more for there to be an impact. you know,
Speaker 2:  My impression is that most people who use Bing through Microsoft
Speaker 2:  think they're using chat GPT. Yes. I can't prove that but like when I talk
Speaker 2:  to people who are using Bing as AI stuff, they think they're using chat
Speaker 2:  GPT, which is a bad sign for Microsoft.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's probably reasonable. And they obviously rebranded the Bing chat
Speaker 8:  stuff to, to copilot, right. And they've done this Super Bowl ad, all that
Speaker 8:  sort of stuff. So that's, that's all linked in with this and like when I've
Speaker 8:  been speaking to people about working under Macal, it
Speaker 8:  sounds like it was run as, as kind of like a startup atmosphere there
Speaker 8:  where you're, you're constantly work, like you're trying to do as much out
Speaker 8:  of as little resources as you have. So it seems like it was kind of
Speaker 8:  a bit crunchy over there and I think there was some micromanaging
Speaker 8:  going on there as well. There's some, some of that sort of stuff that that's
Speaker 8:  been happening, which to fair is probably happens in a bunch of
Speaker 8:  organizations anyway. But it seemed like it just, I think from the fact that
Speaker 8:  Nadela has gone and hired someone into the CEO position,
Speaker 8:  it clearly wasn't working right. Like wherever they were doing in that team
Speaker 8:  wasn't working. And that's the key point that I think
Speaker 8:  Bloomberg reported that Nadella was frustrated at that team or
Speaker 8:  frustrated that the timeline's there or something. 'cause he obviously wants
Speaker 8:  to go fast and Microsoft has been going very fast on co-pilot in office
Speaker 8:  and in that world where, where they can push it and actually there's revenue
Speaker 8:  opportunities there and you see it in the stock price and all that sort of
Speaker 8:  stuff. So they want to really push it on the consumer side as well and obviously
Speaker 8:  it hasn't skyrocketed to relevance. So, but I will say though that
Speaker 8:  I think it's the first time I've known people to be downloading the Bing
Speaker 8:  mobile app or actually talking about Bing. Right? That's true. Yeah. So
Speaker 8:  it is, it's had some sort of impact but obviously not not enough.
Speaker 2:  And it does seem like, I will say credit where credit's due for Microsoft
Speaker 2:  in terms of like baking copilot into the
Speaker 2:  office apps and stuff and, and sort of giving people like real
Speaker 2:  actual business uses for ai. It's done a better job I think
Speaker 2:  than anybody, right? Yeah. Chat sheet PT is sort of neater
Speaker 2:  and Gemini is weird and whatever and as a, as consumer
Speaker 2:  brands, those are really the two that people talk about. But in terms of
Speaker 2:  like the whatever, $30 a month you're trying to get IT departments to pay
Speaker 2:  for, I actually think Microsoft is at least my own perception
Speaker 2:  ahead of everybody else on that front. So credit where credit's due for that.
Speaker 2:  It's just, that's not a victory for Bing.
Speaker 8:  No, exactly. Like the good thing about copilot in in that
Speaker 8:  office space is the teams integration where you can literally like, you know
Speaker 8:  how you're like, do I do really need to go to that meeting or not? Mm. Can
Speaker 8:  I catch up like the notes and you don't even have to worry about, you just
Speaker 8:  click on a link and it tells you if someone even spoke about you and you
Speaker 8:  can just click like, and it will just instantly go to that part. It's like,
Speaker 8:  oh that's awesome. It's pretty, yeah, it's pretty wild what they've done
Speaker 8:  for the team's integration and, and also like you, your Outlook,
Speaker 8:  like I tested out the copilot Pro stuff, which is for consumers actually
Speaker 8:  the team stuff isn't available for consumers but I tested that out and the
Speaker 8:  most impressive part of that is you go into Outlook and there's an email,
Speaker 8:  you summarized the email at the top of it. So, which is really useful when
Speaker 8:  you have a back and forth with like customer support rep and you're like,
Speaker 8:  I can't even remember what I was doing in this email. Like there's, there's
Speaker 8:  loads of little interesting touch points to it. It's still a little
Speaker 8:  bit still and it needs to mature and stuff. Yeah. But yeah they have, they
Speaker 8:  have nailed some of it on the office side but on the Windows side they've
Speaker 8:  been promising a bunch of stuff and it hasn't, I'm, I'm not sure what this
Speaker 8:  A IPC stuff is yet so Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Many of neither. So let's talk about that. Yeah. 'cause we came on this show
Speaker 2:  a few weeks ago when Apple announced the new MacBook errors, right. And we
Speaker 2:  made a lot of fun of Apple for saying that these are really great AI
Speaker 2:  PCs which amounted to essentially like you can do some photo
Speaker 2:  editing and also use the internet, thus these are AI
Speaker 2:  PCs, right. And Microsoft and Intel and others are out here making
Speaker 2:  all this noise also about AI PCs and they,
Speaker 2:  they have the copilot key and it feels like if they want to be
Speaker 2:  consumer winners in this space, it seems like Microsoft is betting a lot
Speaker 2:  on really having like a hardware
Speaker 2:  instantiation of AI be the thing. Yeah. But like just
Speaker 2:  back all the way up for me. Like when Microsoft says IPC, the hell is it
Speaker 2:  talking about?
Speaker 8:  That's what I wanna know. Yeah. That's the key question at the moment.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, like I think IPC is definitely a bit of a
Speaker 8:  marketing term right now because Microsoft's saying all this stuff and
Speaker 8:  it's like the definition which we actually learned this week from Intel is
Speaker 8:  that it needs to have the latest CPUs and GPUs and an
Speaker 8:  NPU, right? So the newer processing unit, which is a chip that we've seen
Speaker 8:  on a bunch of arm powered Windows laptops for years now. And
Speaker 8:  essentially it's been there and accelerates tasks like background blowing
Speaker 8:  on a video call and like noise canceling when you're dog barking behind
Speaker 8:  you on a, on a call. So there's obviously other instances and software
Speaker 8:  developers are working on stuff that will will be utilize there. But for
Speaker 8:  all intents and purposes, that's the most consumer friendly option you have
Speaker 8:  for that mpu right now. So what else is the MPU
Speaker 8:  gonna do? What other AI tasks are gonna leverage that in Windows? That's
Speaker 8:  still the mystery. So although Microsoft's come out saying here's our Surface
Speaker 8:  Pro 10 for business, yes, that's the full name of the product in
Speaker 8:  itself, first Surface AI pc, it still
Speaker 8:  doesn't really explain like why or like, 'cause the AI
Speaker 8:  stuff that they have been pushing is co-pilot, which is cloud based. So it
Speaker 8:  doesn't need an NPU right locally to accelerate or anything. So there's just
Speaker 8:  that, that's a missing part of the puzzle and I think that's all gonna
Speaker 8:  make sense on May 20th when they, when they do this Surface and
Speaker 8:  Windows event.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What do we know about the surfaces so far? Microsoft just released
Speaker 2:  a couple of businesses surfaces. Yeah. Which seem like that
Speaker 2:  reading your story about them, you seem to see those as sort of a hint at
Speaker 2:  what we might see from the consumer facing surfaces, but also those might
Speaker 2:  be different. And I don't know like what, what, what's your sense of kind
Speaker 2:  of how much we know about this next generation of services that's coming?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so it is, so they announced the Surface Pro 10 for business and the
Speaker 8:  Surface Laptop six for business. And they're both running Intel
Speaker 8:  core ultra chips, which do have NPUs. And I'd say
Speaker 8:  beyond that it's some webcam changes, but the designs are pretty much the
Speaker 8:  same. It's not, it's, it's pretty much a a, a very plain release, but some
Speaker 8:  good upgrades for for business customers
Speaker 2:  And the hardware's good. Like I like the Surface and the Surface Laptop.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I think to the extent that it's like desperate for a
Speaker 2:  hardware redesign, like whatever, but I think that what you just described
Speaker 2:  to me in no way makes these things qualify as I PCs. No. So that,
Speaker 2:  that's still where I'm stuck, right? It's like what is the A IPC story inside
Speaker 2:  of this thing?
Speaker 8:  So on May 20th they're gonna do the same devices but for consumers.
Speaker 8:  Okay. There'll be some tweaks to designs. The Surface Proton is supposed
Speaker 8:  to get an ole display, which is nice. There's all all all sorts of stuff
Speaker 8:  you expect from the consumer side, but more importantly
Speaker 8:  they're not gonna be Intel. So they're not gonna be core ultra
Speaker 8:  PCs. They're gonna be Qualcomm Snap Drag and X Elite or Elite
Speaker 8:  XI can't remember which way it goes. So ARM-based, which is
Speaker 8:  not unusual for Microsoft to do ARM-based surfaces. They've done Surface
Speaker 8:  Pro X in the past, but it's unusual for them to only do that for consumers.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. As the main option. That's a pretty big
Speaker 8:  Deal. And they, I mean they could I guess offer it later. It could be some
Speaker 8:  sort of exclusive, but as far as I know, they're launching exclusively
Speaker 8:  with Qualcomm, which is, I think that speaks to some sort of
Speaker 8:  confidence in these Qualcomm chips because Qualcomm's been promising its
Speaker 8:  performance to match MacBooks and stuff for years and it's never really delivered.
Speaker 8:  Right. So
Speaker 2:  The year of Windows on Arm has been every year for like a decade at this
Speaker 2:  point. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But it seems like Microsoft is really confident, from what I
Speaker 8:  understand internally, that they're going to even be able to beat M
Speaker 8:  three performance, which is wow. Which is interesting. Yeah. 'cause even
Speaker 8:  if they can beat like that
Speaker 2:  Would be a huge deal.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like it, it, it seems like they're unusually confident, which I
Speaker 8:  don't usually see,
Speaker 2:  I mean forget M three performance, if it can get to like Apple's M1
Speaker 2:  performance on these things. Oh yeah. Like that's a huge leap forward
Speaker 2:  both for Qualcomm in general, which can then go sell these things to other
Speaker 2:  people also. But also for the Surface line. Yeah. Like that
Speaker 2:  would make the Surface probably more interesting to more people
Speaker 2:  than it has been in a really long time.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think, I think it's gonna be super interesting obviously 'cause these
Speaker 8:  chips are obviously gonna go into regular laptops as well. Right. And it
Speaker 8:  does feel like with the rumors of, was it a MD and Nvidia potentially
Speaker 8:  doing Windows on Arm next year or the year after? I can't remember the exact
Speaker 8:  year. It does feel like there's something going on here and Intel keeps
Speaker 8:  inviting me to briefings about the Core Ultra. So they obviously know that
Speaker 8:  something's going on. So I feel like there is something going on here, but
Speaker 8:  I'm not fully committed to trusting that this is gonna be M three performance.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And in terms of the AI stuff, right, like I think the one part
Speaker 2:  of the AI story that I do buy is that basically
Speaker 2:  efficient performance goes a really long way.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Definitely.
Speaker 2:  Granted every computer with good performance and good battery life is a better
Speaker 2:  PC for ai. Yeah. Is that an AI pc? No, that's just like a
Speaker 2:  pretty good Laptop. Yeah. In 2024. But I digress. But as you,
Speaker 2:  we've seen Microsoft on the consumer side, I feel like try a bunch of
Speaker 2:  different ways to put AI in front of people, right? There's big chat, they've
Speaker 2:  made all this big deal about Edge, they're trying to put it in the start
Speaker 2:  menu. What's your sense of what, if anything is,
Speaker 2:  is working there? Like what, what would you bet on kind of being the front
Speaker 2:  face of AI on Windows going forward?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think co-pilot's definitely the front face. So Intel obviously
Speaker 8:  had these specs and there was the chip side, but then there was the, it has
Speaker 8:  to have access to co-pilot software, which is like, sure it's Windows 11,
Speaker 8:  whatever. But it has to have the co-pilot key as well for it to be
Speaker 8:  an AI PC in Microsoft's definition. Which is like, okay, interesting.
Speaker 2:  So it has to do AI and it has to have an AI button. Yeah, that's what I'm
Speaker 2:  hearing. That's it. And then it's an AI
Speaker 8:  Pc. You get the AI stick, I dunno if they're gonna have stickers on these
Speaker 8:  things, but I mean, you never know.
Speaker 2:  That would be amazing. Instead of Intel inside, it should just start saying
Speaker 2:  AI inside AI inside. Like that's the stuff right there.
Speaker 8:  That's it. But the copilot is definitely their, their portal
Speaker 8:  now. How they'll get away from it just being a chatbot or
Speaker 8:  seen as just a chatbot on on the side in Windows, which is basically what
Speaker 8:  it is right now. That's gonna be interesting to see how it integrates for
Speaker 8:  the apps. They do have something coming called, I think it's called AI
Speaker 8:  Explorer and it sounds real creepy, but it's going to essentially record
Speaker 8:  everything you do on your PC and then say you were, I dunno,
Speaker 8:  researching a holiday last week, you could say to it, I was looking at
Speaker 8:  holidays last week, but I can't remember where it was. And then it'd be like,
Speaker 8:  oh, you were looking like holidays to Europe last week. Do
Speaker 8:  you wanna check out the tabs that you had? Oh sure. And then you click and
Speaker 8:  it brings up all the tabs you were working on, documents, whatever. So it's
Speaker 8:  like a timeline of how you were using your PC and the state it was in and
Speaker 8:  all that sort of stuff. Dunno exactly how it's gonna work in reality,
Speaker 8:  but that's, that's what they've been, that's what, that's what they're building
Speaker 8:  at the moment, essentially. So that's gonna be the The killer. The killer
Speaker 8:  feature for, 'cause it's gonna leverage the NPU obviously to, to quickly
Speaker 8:  pull up this, this stuff and, and reference it, which sounds
Speaker 8:  very similar to the Windows 10 timeline feature they tried to do, which was
Speaker 8:  like a similar sort of thing but sort of going across mobile apps.
Speaker 8:  But it needed app support so it was kind of like dead in the wall without
Speaker 8:  developers actually supporting it. This doesn't need app support, they can
Speaker 8:  just do it 'cause they, you know, it runs on top of Windows,
Speaker 2:  It knows what's on the screen.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean privacy minefield. But yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well, yeah, I, I remember I wrote about this company Rewind, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Maybe a year ago that is doing something very similar and theirs is
Speaker 2:  like a separate app that you download that then gets permission to record
Speaker 2:  your screen and all this stuff. And in talking to people about that,
Speaker 2:  everybody immediately goes one of two ways where it's like, oh awesome, that
Speaker 2:  runs locally on my computer and doesn't go anywhere else. Kick ass.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What an incredible productivity tool that's gonna be. And then a bunch
Speaker 2:  of other people who are like absolutely not under no circumstances. Never
Speaker 2:  ever, ever, ever, ever. Yeah. And I, I literally, I talked to a bunch of
Speaker 2:  people around that story and found no one who is in the middle of those two
Speaker 2:  points. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That I, I think that's definitely what this is gonna be like. It's, yeah,
Speaker 8:  it's, it's obviously gonna run locally and all that, but it's still, it doesn't
Speaker 8:  matter if it's recording you, it's still weird. Right. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I agree. But I will say if that becomes kind of part of the interface
Speaker 2:  of a computer, which I actually think done well is pretty interesting, the
Speaker 2:  idea of like, 'cause you, I mean you think about your browser history, right?
Speaker 2:  Like the fact that you can't sort of QWERTY your browser history to be like,
Speaker 2:  what was that page I was looking at about X, Y and Z is silly. Like you should
Speaker 2:  be able to do that. The information's right there. Yeah. It has it anyway.
Speaker 2:  Right? So to be able to take information that like of course it already
Speaker 2:  has and do something with it, that's a pretty compelling use of
Speaker 2:  AI to me. Again, I, I wonder what that will look like and whether
Speaker 2:  it will totally collapse this supposed good performance of battery
Speaker 2:  life of my computer.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And and a advertising companies basically have access to your search
Speaker 8:  history. I mean not, not in the literal sense exactly, but by tracking you
Speaker 8:  all around the web. So, and they can make relevant queries. So it would
Speaker 8:  be really useful to be able to look back in useful AI powered ways.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, I see the, I see the big benefits of it. It's just how they sell
Speaker 8:  it and the previous aspects and everything else.
Speaker 2:  Do you think all the other Windows manufacturers are gonna be into
Speaker 2:  the copilot idea and co-pilot key the same way that Microsoft is?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think probably because usually they, they follow,
Speaker 2:  I guess they don't have much choice in a lot of
Speaker 8:  Cases. Yeah. And Microsoft will say you can put, you know, some of your stuff
Speaker 8:  where you can make a tiny bit of revenue on everything and they have all
Speaker 8:  these big deals with OEMs to incentivize all this sort of stuff so that
Speaker 8:  they'll have like marketing deals. It would just basically be
Speaker 8:  one of those things where it's like if you're an OEM, you kind of have to
Speaker 8:  go with it because we, we obviously saw in the past support for Windows
Speaker 8:  and Arm from a bunch of OEMs. Some of them pulled it pretty quick, but they
Speaker 8:  all kind of, most of them did one or two models just in support
Speaker 8:  of it. So I think, I think there will be support for it. I think most of
Speaker 8:  them will probably ship the copilot key eventually as well, even
Speaker 8:  if not all of them have yet. But yeah, I think it'll be pretty broadly
Speaker 8:  supported.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And for Microsoft, it seems like this event in May
Speaker 2:  actually turns out to be a pretty big deal, even if it is, you know,
Speaker 2:  relative sort of spec updates of things. Like, I, I don't know, my, my last
Speaker 2:  question for you was basically gonna be like, what do we think year two of
Speaker 2:  Microsoft's all in on AI BET is gonna look like? Right? And I kind of feel
Speaker 2:  like what it sounds like is we're gonna know the answer to that much more
Speaker 2:  clearly when we see this new hardware that like that is going to be
Speaker 2:  the way to see what all this looks like.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think the, the key is the Snapdragon chip, like how, how that performs
Speaker 8:  if it lands, well then you can imagine there's gonna be next gen AI
Speaker 8:  PCs, which they, they will see talking about internally. I think these are
Speaker 8:  considered next gen, whereas perhaps the stuff that's in the market right
Speaker 8:  now of NPUs is, is you know, current gen or whatever. But yeah, I think year
Speaker 8:  two will be, I hope it's like more fleshing out windows
Speaker 8:  and how it's actually using all this, this NPU power
Speaker 8:  and leveraging it all locally on the device. 'cause it's still, that's
Speaker 8:  the main feature. I think there's gonna also be a, a video streaming
Speaker 8:  improvement as well. That's the other kind of main feature that they, they're,
Speaker 8:  there's two features that they're, they're kinda selling for the next gen
Speaker 8:  AI PCs, but marketing slogan,
Speaker 2:  It's interesting to hear you talk about AI as the sort of startup
Speaker 2:  inside of Microsoft. It like, it actually makes a lot of the last 12 months
Speaker 2:  make a lot of sense. Yeah. Both in terms of this sort of like
Speaker 2:  flailing around all over Windows trying to figure out what to do. But also
Speaker 2:  some of the stuff like the growth hacking inside of Edge, right? Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  inside of Windows, like that's the kind of stuff that big mature companies
Speaker 2:  do less of, but startups do lots of.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Yep.
Speaker 2:  And that culture clash I think is like maybe why it
Speaker 2:  felt so bad as a user to get some of that stuff over the last year where
Speaker 2:  it's like, Microsoft, this is gross. Like leave me alone. I'm just trying
Speaker 2:  to use your web browser for god's sake.
Speaker 8:  But it's, it's interesting because the Windows engineers have obviously gone
Speaker 8:  back to the Surface side, but they've kept Bing Edge and copilot on
Speaker 8:  that Microsoft AI side. So that does suggest that they'll be doing
Speaker 8:  all of the AI work within those, those three brands. So we might
Speaker 8:  not get as, I dunno as as pushy, hopefully as
Speaker 8:  pushy stuff in the Windows experience itself. Yeah. So,
Speaker 2:  But Edge is probably still gonna be messy.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I did wanna mention one thing that, yeah, the interesting thing that
Speaker 8:  I think they're gonna say, and I, well I I kind of know from sources is,
Speaker 8:  you know how Microsoft used to say a PC in every home was like the Windows
Speaker 8:  slogan, right? It's gonna be a copilot for every person. Like
Speaker 8:  that's how they're gonna sell this now. Oh yeah. And, and they're hoping
Speaker 8:  to get to like 50% of new laptops, like by
Speaker 8:  the end of 2026 will be, you know, have all these, all
Speaker 8:  the NPU hardware on them.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. And that's very telling. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  When you get to that scale then it's, it's quite telling of their, their
Speaker 8:  ambitions and where they might go with us. So
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, well we're, we're gonna have to check back in in
Speaker 2:  May. I'm so skeptical of these Qualcomm chips. Tom, I cannot even tell you
Speaker 2:  same boy. I hope they're awesome.
Speaker 8:  I'm so skeptical of I PC slogan marketing
Speaker 8:  nonsense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If anyone knows what an AI PC is, please email us birch cast@birch.com.
Speaker 2:  I wanna know. I wanna
Speaker 8:  Know too.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take one more break and we'll be right back with the
Speaker 2:  first cast. Hotline. Thank you sir.
Speaker 8:  Alright, thank you.
Speaker 9:  Hi, I'm Taylor Lorenz, host of Power User. You've probably seen
Speaker 9:  those videos on TikTok where somebody gives money to a stranger who's down
Speaker 9:  on their luck. It all seems really warm and fuzzy
Speaker 9:  except
Speaker 10:  They never see the person who's embarrassed by it, who never wanted
Speaker 10:  to be a part of
Speaker 11:  episodes are out now. We're gonna do three or four part series every
Speaker 11:  quarter. So about 12 to 15 episodes a year. Unlocking Us
Speaker 11:  will always drop on Wednesdays. And now you can find me wherever
Speaker 11:  you normally listen to your podcasts. You can get new episodes as soon as
Speaker 11:  they are published by following unlocking us on your favorite podcast app.
Speaker 11:  And as always, stay awkward, brave and kind.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one. The email is Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We love all of your questions. We try to answer at least one on the show
Speaker 2:  every week. Thank you to everybody who has been calling in. The questions
Speaker 2:  have been so weird the last few weeks. I love it. I wish we
Speaker 2:  could do more of them. We're gonna do more of them. We've definitely gotta
Speaker 2:  do a Hotline episode soon because we've got a bunch of really fun ones to
Speaker 2:  get into. For now we have a question from Josh.
Speaker 12:  Hey David, this is Josh calling from Northern Washington State.
Speaker 12:  I recently watched a World War II documentary on Netflix, which is pretty
Speaker 12:  meh. Now my question is, I like World War II
Speaker 12:  documentaries, so how should I rate this
Speaker 12:  on Netflix? Should I give it the thumbs up, the two thumbs up or the thumbs
Speaker 12:  down because I wanna see more World War II documentaries. So
Speaker 12:  how does the algorithm take it? If I say thumbs down, will it not
Speaker 12:  recommend any more documentaries for me? Or if I give it two thumbs up,
Speaker 12:  would it say, oh, you like mediocre documentaries, I'm gonna recommend more
Speaker 12:  mediocre documentaries for you. I'm really confused on how to train the
Speaker 12:  algorithm when it comes to mediocre shows and all of these
Speaker 12:  algorithms that you know, really want to show me things rather than me letting
Speaker 12:  me choose things. Really appreciate your help with this. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  If you've been listening to this show for a while, you know that recommendation
Speaker 2:  systems are like an obsession of mine. So in order to answer this
Speaker 2:  question, I went back to an interview I did last year with Pat Fleming,
Speaker 2:  who is a senior director of product management at Netflix. Basically
Speaker 2:  he runs the member experience team. So everything that you do when you
Speaker 2:  use the app, that is his responsibility. And one of the things that is his
Speaker 2:  responsibility is all of this recommendation stuff. You can listen to
Speaker 2:  a lot of our interview in an episode from last fall. I'll put that in the
Speaker 2:  show notes. But one of the things we talked about specifically was
Speaker 2:  basically how to tell Netflix what you do and don't want to watch.
Speaker 2:  He gave me a bunch of information on kind of what Netflix cares about, what
Speaker 2:  it's paying attention to, what you can do to signal it, all this good
Speaker 2:  stuff. So the first one is, let me just play you a clip from that interview
Speaker 2:  in which he described a few of the things that Netflix is looking for. The
Speaker 2:  biggest one is what you watch, what you watch and don't matters
Speaker 2:  most. But here is Pat describing some of what Netflix cares about.
Speaker 13:  You could think of titles as being broken down into these constituent components.
Speaker 13:  This metadata, it's, is it a movie or a film? What's its originating country?
Speaker 13:  How long is it? What language is it available in genre? Perhaps
Speaker 13:  some tagging about attributes of the title. And those things all help to
Speaker 13:  sort of round out what a title is like and then you match that against member
Speaker 13:  taste and preferences and take that sports docs, drama,
Speaker 13:  baking shows, If, you watch any two of those things and lots of people watch
Speaker 13:  all three of those things, then it's a pretty good chance that that third
Speaker 13:  genre might be interesting to you. And so some point in time you'll discover
Speaker 13:  some genre that what wouldn't otherwise have been your consciousness and
Speaker 13:  try it out on Netflix.
Speaker 2:  One of the other things Pat and I talked a lot about was these thumbs. I've
Speaker 2:  always been fascinated by the thumbs versus stars thing.
Speaker 2:  Here's actually how Pat described why Netflix goes with the thumbs
Speaker 2:  thing. Two thumbs up, one thumbs up or thumbs down. Instead of like a zero
Speaker 2:  to five stars ranking.
Speaker 13:  When you really love it, give it two thumbs up When you love it, give it
Speaker 13:  a thumbs up and If, you didn't like it, that's okay, let us know. Give it
Speaker 13:  a thumbs down. So that's one very concrete way.
Speaker 2:  I actually like that explanation a lot and it really makes sense to me. I
Speaker 2:  think about things like Yelp where everything seems to be 3.5
Speaker 2:  stars and you don't know whether that's good or bad. Any restaurant on Yelp
Speaker 2:  that's over four stars I assume is great and anything that's under like
Speaker 2:  3.8 I assume is awful. That doesn't make any sense, but that's
Speaker 2:  kind of where we are. And then you get in an Uber and anything other than
Speaker 2:  five stars essentially means I would like for you to be fired, which also
Speaker 2:  doesn't make any sense. So we're in this odd place where different levels
Speaker 2:  of stars mean different things depending on where you are and there's no
Speaker 2:  real rubric for it. So I think in this case the thumbs up, thumbs down
Speaker 2:  thing is much easier to parse. But again, for our friend Josh
Speaker 2:  here, not quite as easy to parse. One more thing about the thumbs. I
Speaker 2:  think this is actually kind of relevant, which is that a thumbs down
Speaker 2:  is very important. So what I would say in this case is, unless you
Speaker 2:  truly loath this documentary and don't ever wanna see anything like it,
Speaker 2:  do not thumbs down. Because what I heard from Pat is that they'd love
Speaker 2:  to have more information about why you gave something a thumbs down,
Speaker 2:  but they really don't.
Speaker 13:  The magic would be the longer that you spend, the better that final
Speaker 13:  recommendation would be because we would then known so much more about the
Speaker 13:  things you could have been interested in and might not have been interested
Speaker 13:  in. So one thing that's a little more challenging is extracting
Speaker 13:  say negative feedback from you. So it would be nice for us to know with
Speaker 13:  a little bit more precision when you skip over something, whether you spend
Speaker 13:  a little bit of time with a trailer and you say, oh, that's not for me tonight.
Speaker 13:  Sometimes that's a little more challenging for us to know precisely in the
Speaker 13:  moment. And that's an area where we wanna spend a little more time.
Speaker 2:  So basically where Pat landed on that one is if you're going to
Speaker 2:  do a thumbs down, they're going to take that as a very strong signal that
Speaker 2:  you don't wanna see this anymore. And it's possible that over time Netflix
Speaker 2:  will get better at understanding what you mean by that. Whether like Pat
Speaker 2:  said, you never wanna see it again or you just don't wanna see it tonight,
Speaker 2:  but I would use that pretty sparingly and as a kind of
Speaker 2:  gavel that just says, get this out of my face. So that's a thumbs down. Wouldn't
Speaker 2:  do that for this one. So we're down to one thumbs up or two thumbs up for
Speaker 2:  this one here is how Pat described the difference, which I would argue is
Speaker 2:  both helpful and unhelpful.
Speaker 13:  Thumbs is a simple way for you to provide feedback
Speaker 13:  on whether you like something or didn't like something. The the trick on
Speaker 13:  stars is sometimes you might rate something very highly on the stars because
Speaker 13:  that's how something you think something ought to be perceived. So it's
Speaker 13:  critically acclaimed and and so you feel like it, it deserves many stars
Speaker 13:  as opposed to how did you actually feel about it? And that's what's more
Speaker 13:  meaningful to improve your recommendations is the reflection of
Speaker 13:  how you actually felt about something and whether it was good for you. And
Speaker 13:  so thumbs has the benefit of one being simpler and two,
Speaker 13:  hopefully being a better reflection of what you actually love
Speaker 13:  or didn't love about what you're watching on Netflix.
Speaker 2:  Okay? Right. Helpful and unhelpful. But I would say for you Josh,
Speaker 2:  I think we are squarely in one thumbs up
Speaker 2:  territory. To me, I think of it as one thumbs up is like,
Speaker 2:  I had a nice time or I'm glad I watched this,
Speaker 2:  or I'm psyched that this exists and was being recommended to
Speaker 2:  me. It's kind of like a, anything that you see that you'd make the noise
Speaker 2:  of just like, yeah, it was good. Like that to me is one thumbs up, right?
Speaker 2:  It's not, I'm staking my reputation on the quality of this.
Speaker 2:  This is the greatest thing that I've ever seen. I would watch this every
Speaker 2:  single day if it made sense for me to do so. It's just like, yeah, it's,
Speaker 2:  I had a nice time. It's how I feel about like 95% of movies I've ever watched
Speaker 2:  on planes, right? Not the worst way to spend two hours. We'll do it again.
Speaker 2:  Probably not going to write about it in my diary at the end of the day. Whereas
Speaker 2:  two thumbs up is like, yes, please Netflix ruin
Speaker 2:  my recommendations with this one. I wanna see everything that you
Speaker 2:  think is associated with this specific title. The people who made it
Speaker 2:  the thing it's about when it came out, what it looks like, the colors in
Speaker 2:  the background in the third scene. Like yes, Netflix, yes.
Speaker 2:  And I don't think we're there on this one. So I think we are squarely
Speaker 2:  in one thumbs up territory. I'd be curious to know what
Speaker 2:  everybody else thinks, how you would rate this. But I feel like I'm saying
Speaker 2:  yeah, show me more stuff kind of like this. But I want you to know this was
Speaker 2:  not the best version of this one. Thumb up. Before I go though,
Speaker 2:  I went back through the interview with Pat and tried to pull out a bunch
Speaker 2:  of the things that he told me about how to signal to Netflix what you do
Speaker 2:  and don't like. So lemme just run through a few of them. One of the ones
Speaker 2:  that he said is If. you go to the upcoming stuff, the stuff that hasn't come
Speaker 2:  out on Netflix yet. If, you watch a trailer for something, but especially
Speaker 2:  If, you hit the remind me button to get notified when something comes out
Speaker 2:  that's a super strong signal that you like that stuff. It means you went
Speaker 2:  way out of your way to actually go and get it and declare your
Speaker 2:  intention to watch it to Netflix. That's a super strong signal. So is watching
Speaker 2:  stuff to the end. Netflix cares a lot about where you fall out of a show,
Speaker 2:  so the more of it you watch the better. And I would say even in the case
Speaker 2:  of like a documentary you oughta like but isn't your favorite If, you just
Speaker 2:  sort of leave it on and leave the room until it ends. That's a pretty good
Speaker 2:  signal that you wanna see more of this. Whereas If, you shut it off after
Speaker 2:  three minutes. That might be a strong signal that you don't, all of this
Speaker 2:  is tricky push and pull stuff, but how far you watch is a strong signal.
Speaker 2:  What you scroll past is also a strong signal. This kind
Speaker 2:  of goes with the thumbs down that Pat was talking about where if I scroll
Speaker 2:  past 10 thumbnails of things, it's very hard for Netflix to figure
Speaker 2:  out why I don't wanna watch those things, but it knows that I don't wanna
Speaker 2:  watch those things and it's getting stronger and stronger at
Speaker 2:  recommending stuff after that, right? It can say not only here's what you
Speaker 2:  watched and liked, but okay, you don't wanna watch this, you don't wanna
Speaker 2:  watch this, you don't wanna watch this. Oh that must mean you're in the mood
Speaker 2:  for a movie or a cooking show or whatever it has to be. And so that
Speaker 2:  stuff is coming more slowly, but actually what you don't watch is
Speaker 2:  a real signal. So is what you search for. Even when you search for
Speaker 2:  stuff that's not on Netflix If, you go in and type in the title of something,
Speaker 2:  it'll both give you the recommendations for things similar to that that you
Speaker 2:  might watch on Netflix, which again, If, you go watch Strong Signal that
Speaker 2:  you like that, but also it just shows Netflix what you care about. It's
Speaker 2:  tracking that stuff. It wants to know what you wanna watch, even the stuff
Speaker 2:  that's not on Netflix. So that is a strong signal. One other one is
Speaker 2:  just the taste profile that you have. I don't know, If, you do this too,
Speaker 2:  but I always just leap through the thing at the very beginning of any
Speaker 2:  music service or streaming service or whatever where it's like pick three
Speaker 2:  titles that you like. But it turns out that's actually pretty important and
Speaker 2:  goes a long way towards sort of kick-starting the personalization that
Speaker 2:  Netflix and all these other services do. So if you're new to Netflix or
Speaker 2:  If, you want to go back in and do it again. That is a thing you can do. And
Speaker 2:  it is apparently more important than I have given it credit for. It's called
Speaker 2:  your Taste Profile and Netflix cares a lot about it. But again, the single
Speaker 2:  most important thing you can do according to Pat, it's just watch stuff.
Speaker 2:  It is much more attuned to what you click on and
Speaker 2:  what you actually watch than anything else. So I'm kind of in this
Speaker 2:  position where every time I scroll on Netflix or click on anything, I'm petrified
Speaker 2:  of what I'm teaching the algorithm. I think we all feel this way about YouTube
Speaker 2:  and TikTok and all these other things where it's like, oh no, did I linger
Speaker 2:  too long? Is the app gonna think I like this and show too much of it? To
Speaker 2:  me, I think Netflix is working on that a little bit. But again,
Speaker 2:  the fact that you went in and watched this whole documentary is a
Speaker 2:  stronger signal to Netflix than how you rate it. So If, you
Speaker 2:  want more of these documentaries. I wouldn't worry too much about it. Just
Speaker 2:  keep watching the documentaries. That's my main advice. One thumb up for
Speaker 2:  Netflix, two thumbs up for cool documentaries.
Speaker 2:  All right, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody on
Speaker 2:  the show. Thank you to everybody who called the Hotline and sent us emails.
Speaker 2:  And thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything we
Speaker 2:  talked about and my old conversation with Pat in the show notes on The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. Read the website. It's a good website. There is so much stuff going
Speaker 2:  on this week, it's nuts. As always. If you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  feelings, keyboard layouts I should know about or anything else. Email
Speaker 2:  us Vergecast to The Verge dot com. Call the Hotline eight six six