# Transcript
ID: 7238662a-6884-452b-889a-c32a11fa22c5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6989202478239955338/6030817754285655545/s93290-US-4366s-1711324052.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of scaled EV production:
02:50 - Verge producer Will Poor tags along with a former Uber Eats driver who ditched the delivery apps and is trying to start a one-man gig work revolution.
This Seattle Delivery Person Is Breaking Free of the Apps
https://tonydelivers.co/
18:54- The Verge's David Pierce and Andrew Hawkins discuss Rivian's new vehicles they announced last week, and what it will take for the company to compete with Tesla.
Rivian R2, R3, and R3X launch event: the EV company’s more affordable SUVs are here
Rivian’s CEO talks R2 and R3 launch, and why he has ‘complete certainty’ EVs will win
Rivian R2 revealed: a $45,000 electric off-roader for the masses
Rivian owners now have access to Tesla Superchargers
Rivian surprises with R3 and R3X electric SUVs
54:37 - David and Allison Johnson answer a question from The Vergecast Hotline about foldable phones.
Google Pixel Fold review: closing the gap
Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 5 review: a little better is just good enough
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (22 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of scale DV
Speaker 1:  production. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am in the park walking my
Speaker 1:  dog, but also doing some headphone testing. So I discovered a month or
Speaker 1:  so ago that I was wearing headphones too often and it was actually making
Speaker 1:  my ears itch, and I had switched from like the
Speaker 1:  AirPods Pro Sony Link Budd style that actually shove into your ear
Speaker 1:  to just a normal pair of AirPods that just kind of hangs there. But even
Speaker 1:  that wasn't solving my whole problem. So now I'm on this weird quest for
Speaker 1:  what I guess I would call non headphone headphones. I'm trying to find
Speaker 1:  something that doesn't go in my ear but will still play music and
Speaker 1:  won't annoy everyone around me. So I've been testing smart glasses, like
Speaker 1:  the stuff you get from Meta or Amazon, I've been testing things like these.
Speaker 1:  The Shocks, headphones, their bone conduction headphones. They just like
Speaker 1:  send sound through your cheekbone instead of your ear. It's all sort of fascinating.
Speaker 1:  I'm not sure any of it is as good as what I left behind, but at least my
Speaker 1:  ears don't itch anymore. So we're making progress. Anyway, we have an awesome
Speaker 1:  show coming up for you today. We are gonna do two things. First, we're gonna
Speaker 1:  tell a delivery story. Will Poor went out on the streets of Seattle
Speaker 1:  and met a guy who is taking on Uber, Eats and DoorDash and this whole
Speaker 1:  crazy delivery industry all by himself. Super fun.
Speaker 1:  You're gonna like it. Then we're gonna talk about Rivian, which just launched
Speaker 1:  two new cars that people are very excited about. But in the process of that,
Speaker 1:  I discovered I don't really understand anything about this company or
Speaker 1:  why we think it might win because there's really no evidence to
Speaker 1:  suggest that it's going to. So we're gonna get into that. We're gonna answer
Speaker 1:  a question from the Hotline, all kinds of fun stuff. But first I just got
Speaker 1:  the notification that these batteries are about to die, which means it's
Speaker 1:  the end of the dog walk. This is The Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. All right, I made it home. Everything's charging. I have to
Speaker 1:  say I like the bone conduction headphones so far, although the shocks ones
Speaker 1:  that I was wearing were pretty expensive, and I also bought another pair
Speaker 1:  from a brand I can't pronounce that is just like a bunch of consonants in
Speaker 1:  a row on Amazon for like a sixth of the price. And they look basically
Speaker 1:  identical. So we'll have to see If. you really get what you pay for there.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, let's get into the show. For years now, I've been
Speaker 1:  conflicted about these delivery apps like DoorDash and Uber Eats. They are
Speaker 1:  super convenient and they're helpful and Sometimes, I don't want to cook
Speaker 1:  or go out, and most of us don't live within walking distance of a million
Speaker 1:  good restaurants. Like I get it. I get why they're helpful and good, but
Speaker 1:  I also can't shake this idea that actually these services are bad
Speaker 1:  and they're bad for everyone involved. They make your meals more expensive,
Speaker 1:  often more than you know through sneaky price increases. Like
Speaker 1:  the menu on Uber. Eats is sometimes just more expensive than the
Speaker 1:  menu at the restaurant. They also don't pay delivery people enough
Speaker 1:  or offer them the protections or benefits that the people who work there
Speaker 1:  should get. And for the most part, historically speaking, they're not even
Speaker 1:  a very good business for the companies running them. It's hard to make money
Speaker 1:  for anybody, including the restaurants, the drivers, everybody.
Speaker 1:  It just seems bad. So what are we doing here? Anyway, a couple of
Speaker 1:  weeks ago, there was this guy who went viral online because of some posters
Speaker 1:  he had put up around Seattle saying basically, skip the apps, call me
Speaker 1:  instead, I'll deliver your food. He became kind of a folk hero
Speaker 1:  online. So we sent our producer will pour to go see what's going on.
Speaker 3:  This is one of those stories that exists because of a perfect storm type
Speaker 3:  situation. Here's what happened for years gig workers
Speaker 3:  here in Seattle. Notably, delivery drivers have been pissed at the lousy
Speaker 3:  pay they've been earning in this very expensive city. So in
Speaker 3:  2022, the city council stepped in and mandated a higher pay rate
Speaker 3:  for app-based delivery workers.
Speaker 4:  It's a good day for gig workers. As the city of Seattle's new ordinance takes
Speaker 4:  effect.
Speaker 3:  The new PayScale went into effect this past January and the apps
Speaker 3:  didn't take the change graciously
Speaker 5:  In reaction. Apps like Uber, Eats and DoorDash began charging
Speaker 5:  customers $5 in what they're calling a local operating fee.
Speaker 3:  That's on top of the service fees and delivery fees that apps
Speaker 3:  routinely charged to say nothing of. Tips and customers are
Speaker 3:  finding their limits. Fewer people are ordering from the apps, gig workers
Speaker 3:  are feeling even more squeezed and everyone is pointing fingers at everyone
Speaker 3:  else.
Speaker 6:  Food delivery orders plummeting. Since Seattle implemented new minimum
Speaker 6:  wage requirements for delivery workers a month ago.
Speaker 3:  Good. This kind of battle is playing out in other markets too. New York City
Speaker 3:  enacted similar rules last year, which the apps have also been fighting tooth
Speaker 3:  and nail. But there's one thing Seattle has that no one else does.
Speaker 3:  A guy named Tony Isles who I am trying to literally chase down
Speaker 3:  right now,
Speaker 7:  I always carry like a tennis ball in my pocket for like the round fluidity
Speaker 7:  of a ball. I just like the idea of like when I was in San Francisco, I had
Speaker 7:  a conversation with my buddy and I was like, do you think shapes have thoughts?
Speaker 7:  And I think I do. I think they do. I think that they influence the way that
Speaker 7:  you think. Yeah, and I, I always carry that tennis ball. So. I always feel
Speaker 7:  like I have like a fluid mind.
Speaker 3:  Tony is telling me this, while flying across downtown Seattle on a
Speaker 3:  rented e-bike in the pouring rain, I'm on my own rental trying
Speaker 3:  to listen and keep up at the same time. We're weaving in and out of bike
Speaker 3:  lanes, dodging construction and crashing through puddles that could be
Speaker 3:  potholes.
Speaker 3:  It's chaos, which is partly the setting and partly
Speaker 3:  Tony's fluid mind. In the first 30 minutes or so of pedaling, we
Speaker 3:  have talked about Maslow's hierarchy of needs, China's social credit score
Speaker 3:  and the Stanford Prison experiment. And I haven't asked any of the questions
Speaker 3:  I came to ask.
Speaker 7:  There's this idea called the method of Loki. I don't know if you know what
Speaker 7:  that is. I don't. It's like this way of remembering things
Speaker 7:  verbatim historically in like these ancient societies. It was also this,
Speaker 7:  this book that I read, it was called Moonwalking with Einstein. Take a left.
Speaker 7:  Hey,
Speaker 3:  If we get separated for any reason, just go finish your delivery
Speaker 3:  and text me when you're done. I'll, I'll find you again. All right.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Oh, 'cause I'm hustling.
Speaker 3:  Well, I just realized that I signed up to do a story about a delivery guy.
Speaker 7:  You're all right man. And
Speaker 3:  I don't know how I expected this to go, but
Speaker 7:  It's a pleasure meeting you. I
Speaker 3:  Got, I gotta up my game here. Tony's
Speaker 3:  backstory is pretty simple. He was driving for Uber Eats when
Speaker 3:  those new fees suddenly killed demand. So at the beginning of February,
Speaker 3:  he decided to go it alone. He put up some very DIY flyers
Speaker 3:  downtown with an offer, text him a food order from any restaurant
Speaker 3:  within a couple square miles and he'll get it to you for five bucks.
Speaker 3:  No taking a cut from restaurants, no service fee, no delivery
Speaker 3:  fee, no local operating fee, just a tip if you're feeling
Speaker 3:  generous. He went viral pretty much instantly.
Speaker 8:  Right now on Kro seven tonight, growing frustrations for Seattle's new food
Speaker 8:  delivery rules,
Speaker 6:  One driver becomes his boss's competitor.
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 3:  Think I now, just a few weeks later, Tony is a full on local
Speaker 3:  celebrity. He's all over the news, Reddit, Twitter slash
Speaker 3:  x, and he says the orders have followed. The biggest challenge is Cadence.
Speaker 3:  He might get five texts all at once and then nothing for a while. So
Speaker 3:  he's trying to figure that out along with the fame. Has this amount of attention
Speaker 3:  been weird? Oh,
Speaker 7:  It's crazy. I mean, it's just like all of a sudden my opinion matters.
Speaker 7:  And a lot of people are asking me, they're just like, how much money are
Speaker 7:  you making? And I'm like, right,
Speaker 3:  Right.
Speaker 7:  I'm like, well, I'm not a monetary guy, I'm not a business orientated
Speaker 7:  person. But what's interesting is, is like I feel like I've introduced
Speaker 7:  a solution for like a social thing.
Speaker 3:  Tony's social solution goes something like this because of apps
Speaker 3:  like Uber, Eats and DoorDash. Yes, delivery has gotten expensive,
Speaker 3:  but more than that it's gotten rushed and sloppy and impersonal.
Speaker 3:  It's just bad vibes all the way down and it's ruining takeout for everyone.
Speaker 7:  It's such a hard position to be in.
Speaker 3:  For who?
Speaker 7:  For, for everybody. Every party that's involved. The restaurants. Yeah, the
Speaker 7:  city, the people that are working as a deliverer, they're
Speaker 7:  in this terrible toxic relationship with somebody like the
Speaker 3:  Restaurant owners and the apps and the apps and the drivers and just
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 3:  That whole, that whole thing.
Speaker 7:  Well just like think about it, last time you went into a restaurant and some
Speaker 7:  driver goes in and is like cuts in front of you and you're just like, what
Speaker 7:  in the world? Like, hey man, I've been standing here for five minutes. What,
Speaker 7:  what? What's your problem? you know that that person is, they're like, they're
Speaker 7:  hustling, right? So they're going in. Yeah. And they're not thinking about
Speaker 7:  that at all because that's not their psychology.
Speaker 3:  No, they gotta keep moving, right? And from where Tony's standing,
Speaker 3:  the Apps are moving in precisely the wrong direction.
Speaker 7:  I think that they, the apps have this kind of misaligned misdirection
Speaker 7:  of where they think the market is and what, what they're planning for. I
Speaker 7:  think that their whole goal is to like send robots to the buildings and
Speaker 7:  you know, send automated cars and it's like, okay, well if
Speaker 7:  that's your solution then you might bleed for a while, right? Like, and so
Speaker 7:  it's like, yeah, I'm not a monetary guy, but I, I could tell you how to make
Speaker 7:  it work a little bit better.
Speaker 3:  Tony's whole thing is to strip all the tech and anonymity outta the process
Speaker 3:  and be your friendly neighborhood delivery guy. And he thinks people will
Speaker 3:  actively prefer a more social alternative, even if that care and attention
Speaker 3:  limits him.
Speaker 7:  I'm almost like kind of certain, once I get to a certain number of people
Speaker 7:  that order from me, I almost kind of want to cap it to kind of
Speaker 7:  ensure the law of of Dunbar
Speaker 3:  Dunbar's number is another favorite Tony topic. It's a theoretical limit
Speaker 3:  to the number of social relationships any one person can maintain.
Speaker 3:  You wanna cap the number of people that order from you so that you can
Speaker 3:  stop and chat for a couple of minutes so you can get to know repeat
Speaker 3:  customers Wouldn't
Speaker 7:  Even call 'em customers. I would just, I would just call them my friends,
Speaker 7:  the homies, you know? There you go. Yeah, they're, they're literally like,
Speaker 7:  yo Tony, can you get this for me? And I think that's kind of the thing is,
Speaker 7:  is like when you try to turn it into a business to customer relationship
Speaker 7:  versus a person to person relationship, they're not gonna be his understanding.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, if I, if I forget your drink right now, someone will be like, Tony,
Speaker 7:  it's fine. Yeah, you don't have to go back to Chipotle. Totally. But if I
Speaker 7:  forget on Uber Eats, they're gonna be like, yo man, what's going on here?
Speaker 3:  In short, Tony thinks that there is a whole lot more to delivery than speed
Speaker 3:  and cost. But yes, he is cheaper than the competition
Speaker 3:  and often faster too.
Speaker 7:  I've never seen anybody run through a target. I picked up somebody's target
Speaker 7:  stuff and I was running through the target.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna run here real quick. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I follow Tony as he makes two, maybe three deliveries back to back
Speaker 3:  some chicken and a shake from Dave's hot chicken. Hey,
Speaker 7:  Is it, does it come with a drink or anything?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, lemme get a salad from a Healthy Bowl place called Evergreens.
Speaker 3:  I'm honestly not a hundred percent sure it was such a blur. But at each
Speaker 3:  pickup and drop off, Tony lives up to his own pitch. He's
Speaker 3:  courteous, warm, casual, and chatty. So
Speaker 7:  Man, how you doing? Today
Speaker 3:  We pull up to our next destination, a big apartment building, and while we
Speaker 3:  wait in the lobby for Tony's customer, sorry, his homey to come down,
Speaker 3:  he's recognized by a stranger.
Speaker 7:  You're the guy. Thank. Yeah, I am. Nice. So nice to meet you. Nice to meet.
Speaker 3:  I stop and chat with Tony's homie for a few minutes. How far away? He says
Speaker 3:  that he and his roommates have ordered from Tony maybe 10 times in the past
Speaker 3:  month.
Speaker 9:  I was just scrolling through Reddit one day and then I saw someone posting
Speaker 9:  a, they posted a picture of one of his flyers that were posted
Speaker 9:  like in the city and I was like, oh, that's pretty interesting. It's cheaper
Speaker 9:  than DoorDash. So I was like, let me give it a try. And then ever since it's
Speaker 9:  like been me and my roommates I go to, oh,
Speaker 3:  Nice. So you guys are like serious regulars at this point.
Speaker 9:  Like I was saying like between the three of us type
Speaker 3:  Thing. And were you Uber Eats DoorDash people before that?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, exactly. DoorDash mainly. And then it was just like got expensive,
Speaker 9:  so we're like, let's see what else? There's,
Speaker 3:  What's the like the Tony experience like and how is it different from
Speaker 3:  the, the apps?
Speaker 9:  I think it's a lot nicer because first of all, all you have to do is just
Speaker 9:  like text him. So that's already a lot easier. He's much faster
Speaker 9:  and it's always nice like having like a quick conversation with him. And
Speaker 9:  like the lobby, he always waits. He's fun to talk to. He is a, he is a very
Speaker 9:  chill guy. Like we've had some nice conversations. It's cool.
Speaker 3:  At the end of the lunch Rush Tony and I sat down at a cafe to talk some more.
Speaker 3:  I went into the story wanting to know whether a guy like Tony can make it.
Speaker 3:  Seattle's minimum wage is almost $20 an hour. So to match
Speaker 3:  that, he'd need four deliveries an hour, not accounting for tips,
Speaker 3:  which after seeing him in action definitely feels doable. but it
Speaker 3:  is a hustle. In other words, it's still gig work and
Speaker 3:  Tony's only working the lunch and dinner rushes right now. So after this
Speaker 3:  whole adventure, my question remains, can he make it?
Speaker 3:  It turns out that is Tony's least favorite question.
Speaker 7:  I'm looking at it as like, I just understand people, you know people, they
Speaker 7:  all have their perspectives and all I'm trying to be is the glue that glues
Speaker 7:  you in that connective tissue so that that way you can get off Reddit and
Speaker 7:  stop arguing about how much money I'm making, get off Reddit
Speaker 7:  and stop arguing whether it's gonna be financially responsible. I can figure
Speaker 7:  that out on my own.
Speaker 3:  I get the sense that Tony has become a kind of avatar.
Speaker 3:  Everyone's putting all their thoughts and feelings about the gig economy
Speaker 3:  onto him. I think that's why his story blew up online. If, you're
Speaker 3:  frustrated by big, powerful companies making life more annoying.
Speaker 3:  He's the folk hero to root for, which is just way too much
Speaker 3:  for Tony to take on.
Speaker 7:  All of a sudden, like people are texting me and they're like, you got a great
Speaker 7:  business mind. And I'm like, what are you talking about? And I think that
Speaker 7:  what people are trying to do, they're trying to box me. They're trying to
Speaker 7:  say, Tony fits here. And I think what they're, they're lacking of
Speaker 7:  understanding is, is like, I actually don't fit anywhere.
Speaker 7:  I'm this like round ball that's just rolling down the street. Like
Speaker 3:  The one in your
Speaker 7:  Pocket. That's exactly, exactly.
Speaker 3:  Tony has no idea whether tonydelivers will make it or
Speaker 3:  what will happen to food delivery more broadly. He just knows that something
Speaker 3:  needs to change.
Speaker 7:  Like what they tried to do is they tried to put food on a conveyor belt
Speaker 7:  and deliver it like an Amazon package. And it's not gonna work. They're winning
Speaker 7:  right now, but at the end of the day, it is not gonna work. It's too expensive.
Speaker 7:  They're like waiting for things to be solved and they're hoping,
Speaker 7:  they're hoping that somebody down the line is like intelligence is gonna
Speaker 7:  hit that s-curve. They're gonna be able to plug in the robots and they're
Speaker 7:  gonna, they're gonna be able to do it. And I'm here to tell you it's not
Speaker 7:  gonna work
Speaker 3:  As kg as Tony is about his own future. He will say that he's been
Speaker 3:  fielding calls from all over the country, people who have heard his story
Speaker 3:  and wanna do what he does.
Speaker 7:  So it's like, all right, well how can I then be the Energizer bunny for
Speaker 7:  some things that we do like and that we do think about and maybe that I can
Speaker 7:  kind of more positively impact in a different sense. Just
Speaker 7:  giving people the right direction, energizing their buddy, you know, so
Speaker 7:  to speak. Giving them the battery to to to kind of the right mindset.
Speaker 3:  So what does this all reveal about the gig economy? Well, Tony
Speaker 3:  has clearly tapped into something and in spite of his grander
Speaker 3:  pronouncements, what he's saying is pretty straightforward.
Speaker 7:  I think that what it represents, I think personally is like
Speaker 7:  this idea that we don't need the Apps.
Speaker 3:  We're so used to Apps mediating all of our activities that
Speaker 3:  at this point, what if not Apps actually feels
Speaker 3:  revelatory, but it's telling that Tony's customers are
Speaker 3:  more than happy to ditch Uber, Eats and DoorDash at the drop of a hat
Speaker 3:  or the drop of a new fee. And if big tech companies really do
Speaker 3:  double down on automation and robots, more people
Speaker 3:  might actively seek out more humanity, more
Speaker 3:  idiosyncrasy, more Tony. Tony
Speaker 3:  himself wants to experiment and meet people and hopefully
Speaker 3:  pay the bills. And if he accidentally starts a revolution along the way,
Speaker 3:  all the better.
Speaker 7:  It would be nice to be known as the guy that was trying to connect us back
Speaker 7:  together. That'd be kind of cool, but not in like the sense of like, this
Speaker 7:  was the guy, it was just more like, oh, like this. Tony Isles mentioned this
Speaker 7:  and we thought it was like a good idea and it worked. And then like eventually,
Speaker 7:  like we reconnected.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. So a couple of weeks ago the EV maker Rivian
Speaker 1:  launched some new cars.
Speaker 13:  I'm so excited to have all of you here. Let me introduce you to R two.
Speaker 1:  The cars look great actually and people got particularly excited about the
Speaker 1:  R three talk
Speaker 13:  About R two's sibling, which we call R three,
Speaker 1:  Which is a little crossover style EV coming someday,
Speaker 1:  but I couldn't stop thinking during this event like who even
Speaker 1:  is Rivian. Over the last few years, this company has been set up as one
Speaker 1:  of the most exciting companies in the car industry and a real
Speaker 1:  genuine Tesla rival. But from everything I hear and read,
Speaker 1:  it is very much still a startup. It doesn't make that many cars, it's bleeding
Speaker 1:  money and it's not lighting up the sales charts. So
Speaker 1:  what gives here is Rivian really the golden child. We
Speaker 1:  sometimes make it out to be. I asked the verges Andy Hawkins to come on and
Speaker 1:  help us understand where Rivian came from, why it's so well liked, and
Speaker 1:  whether it really has a shot to win like Tesla level win.
Speaker 1:  Andy Hawkins Welcome back to The Vergecast.
Speaker 14:  Hey, how's it going?
Speaker 1:  I'm confused. Ah, where did this company come from and how did it become
Speaker 1:  kind of the one that we talked to next to Tesla? Yeah,
Speaker 14:  So I. Think the most interesting thing about Rivian was that it was a secret
Speaker 14:  for a very long time. The company was actually, I think founded in like
Speaker 14:  2008, but it didn't come out of stealth,
Speaker 14:  as they say, until around
Speaker 14:  20 17, 20 18.
Speaker 1:  That's a long time.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Which is I think a, a much longer time to be sort of secretive than
Speaker 14:  I think your average company that's in the stealth mode. So that was kind
Speaker 14:  of interesting right out of the gate. And then secondly, they had a very
Speaker 14:  compelling proposition right away, which was that, you know, we're gonna
Speaker 14:  make Electric vehicles only electric vehicles. They're going to be
Speaker 14:  adventure themed, they're gonna be for off-roading, for camping, for
Speaker 14:  exploring nature, and it's gonna have a very
Speaker 14:  distinctive design language. And so If, you look at sort of the first couple
Speaker 14:  products that the company introduced several years ago, the
Speaker 14:  R one T truck and the R one SSUV, they're both very
Speaker 14:  similar looking to each other and they have this kind of design that is
Speaker 14:  very friendly. It has kind of a cute face with big oval headlights
Speaker 14:  that kind of look like eyes with a light bar that kind of runs across
Speaker 14:  the middle of the, of the grill. It just has like kind of a very friendly,
Speaker 14:  approachable design to them. And then also I think the products themselves
Speaker 14:  were very clearly meant to slot into those
Speaker 14:  segments in the auto industry today that are the most popular pickup trucks
Speaker 14:  and large three row SUVs So I think a lot of people
Speaker 14:  saw this company as you know, a very serious contender that they weren't
Speaker 14:  some sort of vanity play. They were gonna try to actually
Speaker 14:  compete with some of the legacy automakers as well as Tesla. And I think
Speaker 14:  a lot of people were very compelled by the, by the image, by the optimism
Speaker 14:  and the friendliness that the company was trying to put out there. It's,
Speaker 14:  and So I think that those are the couple reasons why a lot of people are
Speaker 14:  very interested in Rivian and, and you hear a lot of people talking about
Speaker 14:  them today.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so part of why I've always thought this company was odd is that
Speaker 1:  some of what you just described is kind of the playbook in this space,
Speaker 1:  right? This is what a, a bunch of these companies have tried to do is go
Speaker 1:  for the kind of most obvious segments of this thing, but also
Speaker 1:  to kind of like sell you this beautiful vision of a better electric future
Speaker 1:  of cars, which I think all of these companies have sort of spent a decade
Speaker 1:  doing is like making grand promises about how everything's gonna be
Speaker 1:  electrified. So you might as well go along for the ride, but I feel like
Speaker 1:  from the jump when Rivian came out, we put
Speaker 1:  Rivian up in the kind of stratosphere of like one of the serious
Speaker 1:  players in a way that I feel like we don't talk about Polestar that way.
Speaker 1:  We don't talk about lucid that way. We don't talk about kind of this other
Speaker 1:  handful of, of companies that are actually, you know, out there producing
Speaker 1:  cars in some volume. But Rivian from the beginning was like held up
Speaker 1:  next to Tesla as kind of one of the great promises of the
Speaker 1:  electric car. Why?
Speaker 14:  You know, I don't know if that's true. Exactly. Okay. If I could just push
Speaker 14:  back a little bit please. I do think that they were, they
Speaker 14:  generated a lot of excitement and a lot of people were very interested
Speaker 14:  in them and I think that the company's founder and CEO
Speaker 14:  RJ Scri presents sort of like a very interesting figurine contrast
Speaker 14:  to Elon Musk. He was a lot more polished, not so prone
Speaker 14:  to any racist rants on social media platforms or, or
Speaker 14:  what have you. Sure. And just seemed like, you know, sort of like a very
Speaker 14:  trustworthy, serious business guy who had like a definite vision
Speaker 14:  for the company. Which is not to say that the company I think was immediately
Speaker 14:  elevated to the same status as Tesla because I
Speaker 14:  think the, the fact remains, you know, they, they're a low volume company.
Speaker 14:  They only sell several tens of thousands of vehicles every year
Speaker 14:  as compared to Tesla, which sells over a million cars every year. Or even
Speaker 14:  the legacy automakers which sell millions upon millions of cars, right?
Speaker 14:  And so, you know, it's, I think there was a lot of excitement and I think
Speaker 14:  through that haze of, of excitement, I think that there, people could
Speaker 14:  make the assumption that this was like a company that was on par
Speaker 14:  at the same level as the rest of the, the industry or, or even
Speaker 14:  some of the upstarts like Tesla. But I, I think that the reality of the
Speaker 14:  situation was they only make a few vehicles every year. They only had two
Speaker 14:  models that were available to consumers plus an electric delivery van,
Speaker 14:  which was only available to Amazon exclusively for a while, but is now Oh
Speaker 14:  right. Supposedly gonna be sold to some other companies as well.
Speaker 1:  That was a big deal, right? Amazon made a lot of noise about buying a lot
Speaker 1:  of trucks from Rivian. That was gonna be a big thing. It was
Speaker 14:  A huge deal and I think that that was one of the things Amazon's
Speaker 14:  backing their investment in the company, their commitment to buying a hundred
Speaker 14:  thousand electric delivery vans from Rivian plus an investment from Ford
Speaker 14:  as well, gave a lot of people the impression that this was going to be the
Speaker 14:  next big electric car company. When in reality they were going to confront
Speaker 14:  a lot of the same challenges as Tesla and even
Speaker 14:  as the legacy automakers are really confronting at the moment too. And if
Speaker 14:  anything, it was going to be a lot tougher for Rivian because as a new player,
Speaker 14:  as a, what they call pure play EV, a company that only makes
Speaker 14:  EV electric vehicles and not any hybrids or internal combustion
Speaker 14:  vehicles. So they have no other revenue to fall back on if the market
Speaker 14:  dips, which it is now, and I assume we're gonna talk about they're gonna
Speaker 14:  take it square in the chin. And I think that that's playing out. There's
Speaker 14:  a lot of excitement still about the company. There's a lot of promise, but
Speaker 14:  a lot of questions in The future is a little cloudy I would say.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah. I am curious how the message from
Speaker 1:  Rivian has changed over the years because like you're talking about, I think
Speaker 1:  If, you rewind to even 2017, there was this sense that like,
Speaker 1:  we are going to have EVs, they're going to be everywhere and they're gonna
Speaker 1:  be everywhere soon. And everybody was talking about self-driving was gonna
Speaker 1:  be the thing we were gonna have like the Uber fleets of self-driving
Speaker 1:  cars. And by now the whole world was gonna be different. And obviously that
Speaker 1:  is extremely not what happened. Yeah, I'm,
Speaker 14:  I'm getting PTSD just from you right, saying all of this. Do you
Speaker 1:  Remember when 2020 was gonna be the year of the fleet of Uber
Speaker 1:  robot taxis? Oh yeah. Like that was the year they all gave us, it's insane
Speaker 1:  in retrospect, but I think if I am Rivian like
Speaker 1:  you, you've sort of built up this story over time about what you're doing
Speaker 1:  and why it's important. But I know we recently talked to rj, the CEO EO after
Speaker 1:  the most recent launch, which I want to talk about. There's a sense that
Speaker 1:  they're just trying to still sort of beat that same drum that they're like,
Speaker 1:  this is coming, it's gonna work, everything's gonna be fine. And I feel like
Speaker 1:  we haven't done that yet. So like should we keep believing this guy that
Speaker 1:  this is gonna come true?
Speaker 14:  Great question, answer. I don't know. So
Speaker 14:  two things I think that obviously electric vehicles are
Speaker 14:  not poised to take over all personal transportation in
Speaker 14:  the next week or so,
Speaker 1:  But by 2020 they will
Speaker 14:  Actually, I still have hopes for 2020. No, but it's not coming quite
Speaker 14:  as quickly as we thought it was. Which is not to say that it won't come
Speaker 14:  eventually. And I think a lot of the serious people
Speaker 14:  that are operating this business, a lot of the automakers, the
Speaker 14:  people whose jobs it is who get paid lots of money to make these types of
Speaker 14:  predictions are saying that electric vehicles are still The future despite
Speaker 14:  a slowdown in sales growth and a lot of investment pullback
Speaker 14:  from some of the major companies, factories are getting stalled. Even
Speaker 14:  Rivian is putting a pause on its plan to build a $5 billion factory in,
Speaker 14:  in Georgia as sort of a reflection of this kind of the reality that we're
Speaker 14:  facing today. And that's because of a lot of different reasons. I think
Speaker 14:  first and foremost, the industry kind of put all its eggs in one basket
Speaker 14:  and brushed maybe a little bit too quickly towards this goal,
Speaker 14:  not realizing that both the charging infrastructure was not going to
Speaker 14:  keep a pace with their own desires to sell electric vehicles, but also that
Speaker 14:  consumers were not going to be as eager to make the switch as they thought
Speaker 14:  they would be. And that's because of a lot of reasons. The the charging
Speaker 14:  is not, is not that great. The prices are still really too high
Speaker 14:  for a lot of people. Politics have kind of reared their ugly head and have
Speaker 14:  complicated a lot of this for some folks. So it's just looking
Speaker 14:  a lot messier and it's maybe going to take a little bit longer than people
Speaker 14:  thought it was. But that's not to say that eventually the
Speaker 14:  majority of cars that are sold in this country and other countries will
Speaker 14:  be electric. We're already seeing it in some countries in the, in the world.
Speaker 14:  China has been making a lot of progress in pushing up the volume of,
Speaker 14:  of EVs Europe is I think a little bit further behind.
Speaker 14:  But they're, they're making a lot of progress as well. Norway. Norway is
Speaker 14:  this country where you would think because of how cold it is that nobody
Speaker 14:  wants to buy EVs because EVs don't run well in the cold. But yet I think
Speaker 14:  over half the count the vehicles sold in that country are electric. Huh.
Speaker 14:  Tesla does very well there.
Speaker 1:  Good for Norway. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  That's right. They're showing us the way the Norway seriously
Speaker 1:  So,
Speaker 14:  I think it's just, it's gonna take a little bit longer. Customers are showing
Speaker 14:  a lot of preferences for hybrids for example, they wanna be eased in to
Speaker 14:  this hot bath that's being drawn for them by the auto industry. They don't
Speaker 14:  wanna just jump right in. That's a terrible image that you can feel free
Speaker 14:  to edit that out. I don't know why I said that. That's,
Speaker 1:  It's good. It's, it's a little gross in the way that all of these should
Speaker 1:  be. I think that's, that feels right. So
Speaker 14:  Anyway, so amidst all of this you have Rivian a small company with a lot
Speaker 14:  of buzz trying to do its best and it's struggling.
Speaker 14:  I mentioned the factory, they're losing a lot of money. you know, their
Speaker 14:  cash pile is dwindling so they have to make what's called a volume play.
Speaker 14:  They need to say, okay, we need to start selling a lot of cars. The cars
Speaker 14:  that they have right now, the truck and, and the SUV are very expensive.
Speaker 14:  They're over 70, $75,000. You can get up to 80,
Speaker 14:  $80,000 with options just, that's just too expensive for most people to
Speaker 14:  afford. So they need to make a play for that middle segment, which is why
Speaker 14:  we got the R two reveal a $45,000
Speaker 14:  mid-size SUV that can go over 300 miles on a, on a single
Speaker 14:  charge and accelerate from zero to 60 in under three seconds.
Speaker 14:  Allegedly So I think that that's why the R two is a very important car
Speaker 14:  for Rivian. It's their play at the mass market. They're saying we need to
Speaker 14:  start selling more cars to more people and here is the product that's going
Speaker 14:  to be the the one to do it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  The R two strikes me as maybe more than just an important car for
Speaker 1:  Rivian, like an important car for this whole industry
Speaker 1:  right now because correct me if I'm wrong, but there's really not a ton
Speaker 1:  out there in kind of this price range and this
Speaker 1:  sort of specific level of coolness. Like we were talking before we started
Speaker 1:  recording about Hyundai and Kia and I actually think what those companies
Speaker 1:  are doing in this space is really interesting. But I, I also think fundamentally
Speaker 1:  the people who want a car like this are maybe more likely than most to be
Speaker 1:  looking at these cool new brands. I notice Rivian
Speaker 1:  on the road, like the, the amount of Rivian that I'm aware of
Speaker 1:  relative to the amount of Rivian that exist is so much higher than any other
Speaker 1:  car on the road right now. Do you know what I mean? It's
Speaker 14:  Very distinctive. Yeah. It really, it draws attention to itself for sure.
Speaker 1:  Right. And I think that's really powerful and important and If, you can do
Speaker 1:  that with a car that many people can actually afford.
Speaker 1:  That seems like a potentially huge deal. But then there are two questions
Speaker 1:  where one is this actually something lots of those people want and then two,
Speaker 1:  can Rivian actually get around to making enough of them to make a difference?
Speaker 1:  And I do feel like those are both still pretty open questions. Right,
Speaker 14:  Absolutely. you know, the fact that the car is not gonna go into production
Speaker 14:  until early 2026 I think is also gonna be an issue. I
Speaker 14:  mean that's a, that's that might as well be 2000 years from now, you know,
Speaker 14:  and, and we
Speaker 1:  Might have self-driving by then Who knows exactly.
Speaker 14:  So whether or not like, you know, the R two is still generating excitement
Speaker 14:  then is I think, you know, very much an open question. But that's not to
Speaker 14:  say that people were very excited, at least the people in my very narrow
Speaker 14:  view of social media, very excited about this car. Lots of people
Speaker 14:  ver that were kind of tripping over themselves to praise it. They loved
Speaker 14:  how it looked. They liked the specs, they liked the price. But you know,
Speaker 14:  it's like I said, it's gonna be up to the consumers as to whether or not
Speaker 14:  it actually turns out to be a popular one and whether or not Rivian can
Speaker 14:  survive long enough to actually put it into production, which is gonna be
Speaker 14:  a huge challenge for the company.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. What's been the, the read on the R one T and the R one s
Speaker 1:  so far? Are they generally they're very cool when I see them. I like them,
Speaker 1:  but what is the kind of broad consensus on whether these are actually good
Speaker 1:  cars?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, no, people really love them. They have a very dedicated fan base.
Speaker 14:  It's very different than the Tesla fan base. It's very interesting If, you
Speaker 14:  go on to like Reddit and some of the message boards and listen to, you
Speaker 14:  know, sort of like what people talk about and they talk about the cars that
Speaker 14:  a lot differently. There's obviously less focus on RJ syringe, the
Speaker 14:  CEO as some sort of Lord and Savior, which contrasts very much with what
Speaker 14:  Tesla does,
Speaker 1:  Which I'm assuming RJs pretty happy with.
Speaker 14:  I'm sure he is. I'm sure he is. But yeah, these are well loved cars that
Speaker 14:  people who own them love them. I think the software
Speaker 14:  experience leaves a little bit lacking, but that's typical across the
Speaker 14:  industry right now. The car industry as a whole is kind of fumbling the
Speaker 14:  ball when it comes to software. The cars do not have Apple CarPlay or Android
Speaker 14:  Auto, which is not a very popular decision and a lot of the owners would
Speaker 14:  love to see phone projection brought into the, into their cars. But
Speaker 14:  that said, the cars themselves are very delightful, but they're expensive
Speaker 14:  as I mentioned before. And so the segment of the population that actually
Speaker 14:  owns these vehicles is still very small. You notice them, they're very
Speaker 14:  noticeable, but still, I mean like, you know, your eyes glaze over the Toyota
Speaker 14:  Highlanders and the, you know, the Rav fours and the the Honda pilots
Speaker 14:  because there are just so many of them. Whereas the Rivian stand out, which
Speaker 14:  I think, you know, is a good selling point. But I think it kind of obscures
Speaker 14:  how actually small the, the population of people who own these vehicles
Speaker 14:  actually is.
Speaker 1:  Oh for sure. I'm pretty sure there's just one in my neighborhood, but I just
Speaker 1:  notice it every single time I see it. So I'm like, God, there's a lot of
Speaker 1:  Rivian out there. It, it does seem like, to your point about Tesla, I think
Speaker 1:  there's a thing that Rivian did kind of accidentally really
Speaker 1:  well it seems like, which is it grew right as Tesla
Speaker 1:  I think was peaking in people's minds as like a cool
Speaker 1:  company that was gonna save the world and be good for it. And every time
Speaker 1:  I hear RJ talk, you get the sense that he's trying to still
Speaker 1:  be optimistic and happy and like tell you about a better world
Speaker 1:  in increasing distance from what people perceive about
Speaker 1:  Elon Musk. Musk in particular. Right. And Tesla, for better and for worse
Speaker 1:  has always been super attached to Elon Musk. So it feels like if I'm
Speaker 1:  Rivian or frankly any of these other companies, like all the people who
Speaker 1:  believe in the mission but are falling out of love with Elon Musk, for one
Speaker 1:  reason or another, are looking for somewhere to go and
Speaker 1:  care about and put their money in and put their fandom in. Those
Speaker 14:  People are gettable. Those people are all gettable. Do
Speaker 1:  You think they are? The other thing that I wondered is like, are we just
Speaker 1:  gonna get past that and these are just gonna go back to being cars? Well,
Speaker 14:  Yeah, I mean something interesting that RJ said in our interview with, with
Speaker 14:  Abigail Bassett or the writer who who interviewed him for us was that,
Speaker 14:  you know, he was very impressed with what Tesla has been able to do,
Speaker 14:  but that new cars that are Electric sold each year has just reached
Speaker 14:  about eight to 9%. And what he was interested in, it was going after
Speaker 14:  that 90% that are still not buying electric
Speaker 14:  vehicles. I mean that's, you know, that's the obvious line that he's gonna
Speaker 14:  deliver of course. Which helps sort of sell the prospect of the R
Speaker 14:  two as this mass market volume play that they are hoping it will
Speaker 14:  be. But yeah, I think that he needs a model three
Speaker 14:  and Rivian is looking for a Tesla model three moment, I think with the R
Speaker 14:  two here because you know, Tesla, for a long time there was no
Speaker 14:  guarantee that that company was going to succeed. Right. In fact they very
Speaker 14:  nearly failed many times, especially during the model three ramp up. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Tesla was just as precarious as Rivian is now, like if
Speaker 14:  Not more so. Okay. Absolutely. And you know, it was only because of the
Speaker 14:  car's popularity and the company's ability
Speaker 14:  to get it out in the numbers that it did, which started slow
Speaker 14:  and then eventually ramped up to a pretty steady clip that people were starting
Speaker 14:  to actually get their vehicles most likely at the expense of Tesla's
Speaker 14:  employees who have, numerous of them have sued the company for many, many,
Speaker 14:  many problems that they've had. But yeah, that prospect I think is still
Speaker 14:  up there on top of the hill and I think Rivian sees it up there and it needs
Speaker 14:  to get up to that moment where they're starting to produce cars
Speaker 14:  at a steady clip and people are loving them and buying them, which is, I
Speaker 14:  think given the current situation around EV sales and
Speaker 14:  the sales growth slow down is why things are, are
Speaker 14:  as complicated for the company. So yeah, I think he wants, he wants to
Speaker 14:  get to that, to that Tesla moment. What's most interesting to me about the
Speaker 14:  image that he's projecting and how RJ talks about the company, especially
Speaker 14:  just in the words that he uses during these events, is they may aspire to
Speaker 14:  be like Tesla, but I think they would rather be more like Apple.
Speaker 14:  Hmm. The way that they talk and the way that they present their products
Speaker 14:  and the way that people talk about their products feels more like Apple
Speaker 14:  than Tesla, which is like optimism and the design is very friendly
Speaker 14:  and RJ is out there literally talking about one more thing
Speaker 14:  and revealing the R three and the R three X, which is the classic Steve
Speaker 14:  Jobs line, although Elon stole it as well I think a couple times. But that's,
Speaker 14:  you know, that's all Apple. So, you know, there's been lots of talk should
Speaker 14:  Apple buy Rivian Apple's own car project ended?
Speaker 1:  I was gonna say, being Apple in cars might not be the thing to shoot for
Speaker 1:  here, right.
Speaker 14:  So I think a lot of people sort of see like a possible synergistic moment
Speaker 14:  here. Like, oh you need a car, apple, here's, here's a, here's a struggling
Speaker 14:  car company that would slot perfectly in with your line of products. I don't
Speaker 14:  know if RJ or Tim Cook are talking or whether or not that
Speaker 14:  would, that would be appealing to them at all. But you know, there's that,
Speaker 14:  that certainly doesn't stop the talk that's out there.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's an interesting way of thinking about it and it does make me wonder
Speaker 1:  if somewhere RJ is sitting around being like, do I need a little more of
Speaker 1:  a God complex if I'm gonna make any of this work? Like you get the sense
Speaker 1:  that too much God complex bad, but maybe you need a little bit
Speaker 1:  like if, if If you don't believe it, how is anybody else going to, you know
Speaker 1:  what I mean?
Speaker 14:  Right, exactly. Just a little bit of confidence. That's all it takes.
Speaker 1:  That's what I, that's what I tell you all the time. Just a little bit of
Speaker 1:  God complex Andy and everything will be fine. But So I, I think this moment
Speaker 1:  is so interesting to me for exactly the reason you're describing, right?
Speaker 1:  There's the R two and I think I, I also want to know what you think about
Speaker 1:  the R three because it was the, it was the one more thing, the sneaky little
Speaker 1:  thing that kind of got everybody really excited. Like my favorite thing
Speaker 1:  about the R three reveal was everybody posting pictures of SUVs from the
Speaker 1:  nineties that look exactly like the R three, but then everybody being like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, I don't care. I still want it. And like there is something about this
Speaker 1:  space that people still like feel real feelings about even that
Speaker 1:  they're becoming these sort of increasingly mainstream family cars.
Speaker 1:  Like Well
Speaker 14:  Yeah, and especially because If, you look at some of the design that's out
Speaker 14:  there today and just the, the vast majority of cars that people buy that
Speaker 14:  it's, it's, there's very little that distinguishes one car from the next.
Speaker 14:  They've all totally, I think it's like the industry has all just sort of
Speaker 14:  settled on this kind of shape of a car, this kind of
Speaker 14:  SUV crossover shape that is the most popular amongst all the cars
Speaker 14:  and it kind of has scrubbed out a lot of the, the things that
Speaker 14:  made like cars unique and interesting to people. There's just very little
Speaker 14:  to differentiate one brand from the other. I mean, you like, yes, you can
Speaker 14:  probably notice, you know, A-A-B-M-W grill is different from a Ford from
Speaker 14:  a, you know, and the shape of a of a Mercedes is a little bit different
Speaker 14:  than maybe a, you know, an Audi. But in the end of it, I think If you
Speaker 14:  sort of did like a blind taste test with like a bunch of people. I think
Speaker 14:  that, you know, they would have some difficulty distinguishing one car from
Speaker 14:  the next, which is I think a lot of why you see some excitement around Rivian
Speaker 14:  because there is something that's distinctive about it. There is something
Speaker 14:  that's kind of, especially with the R three that's very retro futuristic,
Speaker 14:  right? It has like this kind of hatchback shape that is very
Speaker 14:  reminiscent of like, you know, seventies era VW golfs
Speaker 14:  or I saw some people talking about the La Neva, which
Speaker 14:  I was not overly familiar with. I'm not like a huge car guy. So I don't
Speaker 14:  really go too deep into like the lore, but like the La Neva, I was,
Speaker 14:  I didn't like reading lots of articles because I, I'm fascinated now by
Speaker 14:  this like little legendary Russian off-road hatchback that is
Speaker 14:  like fascinating and it does look a lot like, like the R three X
Speaker 14:  especially, but you, you know, So I think, think that that was appealing
Speaker 14:  to people, especially If, you sort of look at, at all of our products, our
Speaker 14:  phones look the same, our cars look the same, our laptops all generally
Speaker 14:  look the same, our TVs all look the same. So you just want something that's
Speaker 14:  out there that gives you a sense that like, you know, I'm attaching myself,
Speaker 14:  I'm making this consumer choice that gives me a little bit of a, an elevate,
Speaker 14:  you know, it distinguishes me from my neighbor or somebody else. And
Speaker 14:  I think the Rivian kind of offers that to people, which is why they get
Speaker 14:  so worked up about it.
Speaker 1:  Totally. And I'm just, I'm just looking at a picture of the R three right
Speaker 1:  now and you're right, and I hadn't really thought about this, that it walks
Speaker 1:  that middle really well where like some of the Electric cars we've seen
Speaker 1:  really for a decade now are all trying to look like they're from like
Speaker 1:  a thousand years in The future. And even there's a Hyundai dealership just
Speaker 1:  down the street from me and literally every time like an Ionic five comes
Speaker 1:  by, it's like, oh look a spaceship. Like you just, you built a spaceship
Speaker 1:  that now just sits in my neighbor's garage. Like, cool, fine.
Speaker 1:  Some people want that, lots of people want a car and it turns out like it,
Speaker 1:  it's okay that it can look like a car, but also like it's five
Speaker 1:  years from The future, not 5,000. And I think like
Speaker 1:  what you're talking about with Rivian rather just like we took a a thing
Speaker 1:  people are familiar with and like, and just kind of like jazzed it up a
Speaker 1:  little bit is like maybe exactly what people want.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. I think people were, were especially eager to see some, some angles
Speaker 14:  brought back in to the EV design because a, a common
Speaker 14:  critique that you'll hear is that all the EVs look like jelly beans
Speaker 14:  So true is very much what the Teslas look like. And I think you're now
Speaker 14:  just now starting to see some pushback against that.
Speaker 14:  I think you're seeing it from Rivian. There's another company called Scout
Speaker 14:  Motors that's gonna be coming on the scene pretty soon. They're owned by
Speaker 14:  Volkswagen. It's an old, also an old like seventies,
Speaker 14:  eighties era off road brand that's that's being revived and, and brought
Speaker 14:  back and made into an all electric brand. And you know, Ford has
Speaker 14:  talked about, you know, maybe electrifying the Bronco. So, you know, I think
Speaker 14:  there you're gonna start to see some differentiation in sort of like what
Speaker 14:  these cars look like and Rivian needs to get out there before everyone else
Speaker 14:  because pretty soon that space is gonna get super crowded. Especially the
Speaker 14:  mid-size SUV space. I think we've got our fair share of
Speaker 14:  crossovers. We've seen them all the Mustang Mach e the model Y,
Speaker 14:  the Volkswagen ID four, the Ionic the Kia, and
Speaker 14:  now we need to start seeing something that's a little bit roomier but also
Speaker 14:  just something different that looks different that gives somebody the idea
Speaker 14:  that like, okay, this is not just the same jelly bean that I
Speaker 14:  I'm I've become used to in the EVs.
Speaker 1:  I will never unsee the jelly bean now and I feel like I hate you for that.
Speaker 1:  Like So I can't, I can't stop thinking about jelly beans that I can, I can
Speaker 1:  picture them in my head now, but it does seem like what that puts
Speaker 1:  Rivian up for is a very consequential next like
Speaker 1:  three years. Because also, like you were saying a minute ago, every
Speaker 1:  other car company has been promising to do this kind of stuff over the next
Speaker 1:  few years. So this idea that, you know, Rivian was
Speaker 1:  early and had some good ideas and made a cool car with a lot of people like,
Speaker 1:  and now it needs to figure out how to make lots of them. Like I
Speaker 1:  think to me at least one of the lessons we've really learned over the last
Speaker 1:  couple years is just how far ahead Tesla was. Rivian strikes me as
Speaker 1:  not nearly that far ahead and in fact is kind of at a moment where like
Speaker 1:  it needs the R two to work in a pretty big way or
Speaker 1:  else it's gonna have a pretty big hole to dig out of. Right. Am I being too
Speaker 1:  pessimistic about its chances there?
Speaker 14:  Not at all. I mean one of the, the stat that jumped out to me the most was
Speaker 14:  that I think in its most recent earnings filing, the company said that it
Speaker 14:  loses $47,000 for every vehicle that it sells.
Speaker 14:  Good Lord. So to give you a sense of how unprofitable things are for Rivian
Speaker 14:  right now, that's the price of the R two. That's, you know, basically how
Speaker 14:  much they're, they're planning on charging for this new vehicle. Wow. Which,
Speaker 14:  you know, just goes to show, you know, sort of like how crucial it's going
Speaker 14:  to be for them. There are cash pile is dwindling, they're running outta
Speaker 14:  money, they have this, this factory plan is on pause. you know, they
Speaker 14:  did not sell as many vehicles as they thought they were going to. I think
Speaker 14:  it was around 57,000 last year. And this year they're
Speaker 14:  saying that it's gonna stay pretty flat. They're gonna sell basically the
Speaker 14:  same that they did last year, which is not something that investors see
Speaker 14:  a lot of confidence in. Obviously they wanna see growth. This company in
Speaker 14:  a company that sells the same number of vehicles that it sold last year
Speaker 14:  is not really exhibiting growth in the way that I think a lot of people
Speaker 14:  would like to see.
Speaker 1:  Is that because Rivian can't make enough to satisfy demand? Or is it because
Speaker 1:  maybe everybody who wants the stuff that Rivian is already making
Speaker 1:  has
Speaker 14:  One. So for a while they were supply constrained, they were not able to
Speaker 14:  make as many as people wanted. Okay. And now they are
Speaker 14:  demand constrained because not many, not as many people can afford Right.
Speaker 14:  The vehicles as they would like because they are expensive. The ones that
Speaker 14:  they sell now, the R one s and the R one T. So yeah, it's kind of it,
Speaker 14:  it's, it's been flipped on them and they're running into these problems
Speaker 14:  and all, and it's not just Rivian every, all the companies are sort of in
Speaker 14:  this weird liminal space right now where they need to make more
Speaker 14:  vehicles, they wanna sell more vehicles, but people all don't wanna buy
Speaker 14:  as many as they thought they were because the prices are still too high.
Speaker 14:  The used market still is mostly Tesla. The,
Speaker 14:  the vast majority of the EVs that are for sale that are used are Teslas.
Speaker 14:  And those are, you know, those are on the used Tesla, that's 21,000,
Speaker 14:  22,000. That's pretty attractive. And Tesla keeps cutting its own prices,
Speaker 14:  which is also driving other companies to cut prices as well,
Speaker 14:  which reduces margins and makes things more difficult in terms of trying
Speaker 14:  to eke out a profit. But the company does say that it will be
Speaker 14:  profitable in the fourth quarter of this year. Whether that's, you know,
Speaker 14:  EBITDA profitable or operationally whether they have free cash flow. It's
Speaker 14:  not exactly clear quite yet. But they say that by pausing
Speaker 14:  this plan to build a factory, which was going to obviously
Speaker 14:  expand their ability to make more cars, they're gonna be able to get the
Speaker 14:  R two out the door faster because they're gonna make it at their factory
Speaker 14:  in Illinois. And that's going to be able to reach customers faster, which
Speaker 14:  they say was going to increase their chances of kicking that revenue
Speaker 14:  stream up and, and getting it flowing a lot faster and improving
Speaker 14:  their financial situation. So Yeah, we'll, we'll have to see.
Speaker 1:  So they know they need to be in the game here if they do a Tesla and
Speaker 1:  like promise a thing in two years that ships in five years, like they're
Speaker 1:  probably dead in the water.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And they've already confronted a lot of issues around wait times
Speaker 14:  and software issues. I mean it's, you know, you can set your clock to it
Speaker 14:  in terms of like these companies and the same problems that they're running
Speaker 14:  into. Yeah. You would think, you know, seeing the Tesla playbook,
Speaker 14:  you know, you would also see the trade-offs and the, and the pitfalls that,
Speaker 14:  that were along the way. But it's the same thing there. I mean they had
Speaker 14:  a problem with their software was bricking the cart for a little while they
Speaker 14:  had to push a software update. I do think that the R two in particular,
Speaker 14:  that was the, this is their gonna be their, their model three. This is the
Speaker 14:  one that they think is gonna be the high volume seller.
Speaker 14:  The R three is gonna be the icing on the cake. you know, that's gonna be
Speaker 14:  like the fun little cousin to the R two. But that's gonna be the real play.
Speaker 14:  That's, that they hope is gonna be the one that takes over the streets and,
Speaker 14:  and transforms them from a small company to hopefully one that's successful
Speaker 14:  and, and has a, a future ahead of it.
Speaker 1:  Okay, fair enough. Does it seem like there's any other
Speaker 1:  company kind of, of Vivian's size and
Speaker 1:  prestige that might just totally eat its lunch? Yeah,
Speaker 14:  Polestar, they're a performance brand. People who like to go vroom, vroom
Speaker 14:  really fast like the Polestar. Sure. Which is cool. They're cool cars. They're
Speaker 14:  really cool. They're also kind of apish in a way. They're all white and
Speaker 14:  they have even that they're, it's Google's Android software native. There's
Speaker 14:  just something that's very Apple about, about Polestar.
Speaker 1:  But Polestar seems to, to your point, have no particular interest in like,
Speaker 1:  they're not trying to be Toyota.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. No, I don't think so. They're trying to be Mercedes. They're trying
Speaker 14:  to be Audi that's, you know, and that's, that's fine. There's a lot of money
Speaker 14:  to be made in that segment as well. Yeah. I think the one, the, what they
Speaker 14:  have to be worried about is Ford and Jeep. And I mentioned
Speaker 14:  Scout as well, but I, I, I don't think Scout really has, we don't
Speaker 14:  really know what they're gonna be yet. But I do think Jeep in particular,
Speaker 14:  given sort of the similarities and the overlap in the
Speaker 14:  customers that are interested in these cars in Rivian vehicles, has the
Speaker 14:  potential to eat Rivian lunch such as you, as you put it. So, and Jeep has
Speaker 14:  said that they are coming out, you know, with all electric there's gonna
Speaker 14:  be an all Electric wrangler. There's going to be an all electric Grand Cherokee.
Speaker 14:  They're coming. Also, if, I think if Subaru got off its ass and actually
Speaker 14:  made some good, some good EVs, that could hurt as well. 'cause there I,
Speaker 14:  I see some overlap in, in customers there, but Subaru is, is sort of
Speaker 14:  in the same campus as Toyota. They're kind of dragging a little bit on the
Speaker 14:  EV roll rollout. So Rivian still has a, has a possibility here. And
Speaker 14:  I do think that they could have a, a first mover advantage if they, if they
Speaker 14:  can get the R two out and the timeframe that they said that they will.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And as we've learned, there's nothing like an existential threat to
Speaker 1:  your company to get you to actually ship your car.
Speaker 14:  It's very motivating. I've heard, I've not experienced it myself, but Yes.
Speaker 14:  And then, yeah, but then like the China question kind of looms over all
Speaker 14:  of this, right? Like it will China eventually be able to sell its
Speaker 14:  cheap electric vehicles in the United States is a huge question.
Speaker 14:  Elon Musk has said himself, that would be a devastating blow to the auto,
Speaker 14:  to the EV industry in the, in the United States. And BYD in
Speaker 14:  particular, China's biggest automaker has said that they're gonna start
Speaker 14:  building a factory in Mexico, which is right on our doorstep. So,
Speaker 14:  you know, the tariff situation is still very unfriendly to Chinese made
Speaker 14:  EVs the, obviously the policy situation, you know, is very bad
Speaker 14:  for them. It's, it would be very expensive for them to try to sell, but,
Speaker 14:  you know, it's still a, an open possibility.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. So it's gonna be in a big couple of years, I feel like we've
Speaker 1:  been saying for, for 10 years, it's gonna be a big couple of years, but this
Speaker 1:  one feels, this one feels real.
Speaker 14:  Yes. It does feel, I mean, like, I think like we're starting to see a lot
Speaker 14:  of pieces fall into play. All the automakers are jumping on the Tesla
Speaker 14:  charging bandwagon. They're all gonna start using Superchargers. They're
Speaker 14:  giving out adapters to their customers. They're gonna have the Tesla port
Speaker 14:  built in natively on the vehicle themselves. There are two, for example,
Speaker 14:  is gonna be the first Rivian vehicle to have the Tesla NACS char charging
Speaker 14:  port in the vehicle. So those vehicles will be able to charge at Tesla supercharger
Speaker 14:  stations. That's gonna be huge as we start to see that get adopted
Speaker 14:  widespread. And then you've got the incentive that are available,
Speaker 14:  the federal EV tax credit can now be taken at the dealership. You
Speaker 14:  go into a dealership, you're like, I wanna buy an electric vehicle. Does
Speaker 14:  it meet these criteria? Do I meet the criteria? If so, yes,
Speaker 14:  great. You get a $7,500 discount right at the, at the point of
Speaker 14:  sale. That's gonna be huge. Big incentive, I think for a lot of people to
Speaker 14:  buy Electric cars. And I think more of these mass market cars, more of these
Speaker 14:  volume players like the R two, I think the Chevy Blazer went through a bit
Speaker 14:  of a software issue, but now is back and available for sale as well as the
Speaker 14:  Chevy Equinox. EV is gonna be coming out. These are common, normal
Speaker 14:  everyday vehicles that most people can afford. And if they are sold at a
Speaker 14:  price point that car buyers think is right for them, I think you're gonna
Speaker 14:  really start to see things shoot up in terms of sales
Speaker 1:  Growth. Fair enough. So yeah, we're, we're gonna get a real answer on Rivian
Speaker 1:  here one way or another pretty quickly. Whether this company is like a neat
Speaker 1:  brand that has sold a good story about itself or is a real power player.
Speaker 1:  And it makes me feel better to know that that's coming because I've come
Speaker 1:  into this being like, do we know anything about whether Rivian is actually
Speaker 1:  gonna work? And I feel like the answer is we don't, but we're about to.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And I think that, you know, they have a lot of smart people that work
Speaker 14:  for them, and it, it seems like they have a lot of interesting partnerships,
Speaker 14:  but yeah, there's a lot that's still up in the air. I think that it'll be
Speaker 14:  a really interesting year for them and for, for the rest of the industry.
Speaker 1:  Totally. I do love the headlights. I am normally a gigantic
Speaker 1:  antagonist
Speaker 1:  We're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is 8 6 6
Speaker 1:  Verge one one. The email is Vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love
Speaker 1:  all your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show every week.
Speaker 1:  Before we get into this one, first of all, thank you to everybody who called
Speaker 1:  and emailed about TikTok. You had awesome feedback, it was great to hear
Speaker 1:  from you. I promise NELI, Alex and I are all still friends. We're gonna get
Speaker 1:  to a bunch of your feedback on Friday. I think I wanna give all that stuff
Speaker 1:  a few more days to play out just because there's a lot happening really fast.
Speaker 1:  And one of the things we talked about last week was the huge lack of information
Speaker 1:  that we have and we're starting to get more information. So we're gonna get
Speaker 1:  to all of that on Friday. So stay tuned for now we have a question from
Speaker 1:  Terry.
Speaker 17:  Hi, this is Terry in Philadelphia and I'm preparing for a professional
Speaker 17:  exam and every time I do, I become obsessed about a particular piece
Speaker 17:  of technology thinking that if I buy one more gadget that will make the
Speaker 17:  stress of this thing, that will define the arc of my life, or at least what
Speaker 17:  my salary raises this year, just kind of go away. That current
Speaker 17:  obsession are folding phones. I'm a massive man
Speaker 17:  with hands that can just hold an entire country ham.
Speaker 17:  So it feels like a folding phone would be perfect for
Speaker 17:  the fact that I, I seemingly of the hands of a steel worker despite being
Speaker 17:  an actuary. And one of the thing that gets me is whenever I read a review
Speaker 17:  and one of the dings is this expense is how to
Speaker 17:  interpret the fact that I'm now like a year out from the Fold
Speaker 17:  five and the Pixel Fold and I can get them all used for like
Speaker 17:  $800 off. Do I just effectively
Speaker 17:  add one point to The Verge review score? How?
Speaker 17:  How do you factor in the fact that stuff gets cheaper when you're
Speaker 17:  interpreting the review on a review site? Any insight
Speaker 17:  would be great. Love the show. Stay classy.
Speaker 1:  All right, this is one of my favorite and one of the most relatable questions
Speaker 1:  we've gotten on The Vergecast in a long time. Allison Johnson's here to help
Speaker 1:  me answer it. Hi Allison.
Speaker 18:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  Do we love Terry? I feel like we love Terry. Yes. I feel like the thing where
Speaker 1:  I'm like I have a big project to do, let me buy a gadget that will solve
Speaker 1:  all of my problems is extremely, extremely relatable. I
Speaker 18:  Feel seen. Yeah. Like this planner
Speaker 18:  is gonna do everything for me.
Speaker 1:  I, I have brought you here 'cause I think there are two questions inside
Speaker 1:  of this question, both of which I wanna talk about. One is for
Speaker 1:  our massive man friend Terry with huge country ham
Speaker 1:  hands is about foldable phones. The right call, that's question number one.
Speaker 1:  And then question number two which I wanna get to is how do you think about
Speaker 1:  price in a review like that and how should we think about price of these
Speaker 1:  things over time as they inevitably come down? But let's just start with
Speaker 1:  the beginning thing. The foldable phones question is about foldable phones
Speaker 1:  gonna solve all of Terry's problems forever for the rest of his life.
Speaker 18:  Yes Terry, I have great news. All you need to do is
Speaker 18:  spend upwards of $800 on a gadget. No, I think there's
Speaker 18:  something there. I think that's fair to,
Speaker 18:  to think that you have a phone that's like normal size when
Speaker 18:  you wanna do something kind of fiddly or you just want more screen space,
Speaker 18:  open it up and you have like almost a tablet. So I think
Speaker 18:  that's real. I think Terry is is on the right track.
Speaker 1:  I'm curious what your experience has been with foldable phones in terms
Speaker 1:  of like the productivity they enable. Because for me,
Speaker 1:  I've used most of my foldable experiences with the Pixel Fold at this point.
Speaker 1:  And what I have found is that as a thing for
Speaker 1:  just more screen real estate, whether it's like I have a PDF that
Speaker 1:  isn't, you know, scaling well to my phone or whatever or a thing I want
Speaker 1:  to actually mark up with a pen, foldable phones. Awesome. The thing that
Speaker 1:  has not worked for me that I have found very frustrating is I hoped that
Speaker 1:  typing would be better on about foldable phones. 'cause you can do the split
Speaker 1:  keyboard thing and sort of type with two thumbs on a bigger screen and it
Speaker 1:  would be better. I have not found that to be the case at all, but I'm
Speaker 1:  curious what you, what your experience has been like, what do you get from
Speaker 1:  the bigger screen that way?
Speaker 18:  Yeah, I, for me it is the productivity stuff and like the,
Speaker 18:  the scenario I keep coming back to is like I just hate
Speaker 18:  tabbing around between apps and you just always end up doing it where I'm
Speaker 18:  like planning dinner with friends and you're in the little chat
Speaker 18:  app, you gotta switch to Google Maps, you gotta look at a PDF of the
Speaker 18:  restaurant's menu, the foldable phones let you put
Speaker 18:  two things on the screen at once and like hold two thoughts in your head
Speaker 18:  at one time. I so appreciate them for that. I'm will
Speaker 18:  occasionally indulge in like a game that's like
Speaker 18:  fun on a bigger screen, but for me it's definitely the
Speaker 18:  like, oh I can just like breathe and like put all these things out
Speaker 18:  or like I have a little Spotify and a little window and do lingo. It's just
Speaker 18:  like a little bit more of a a computer
Speaker 18:  experience than a phone experience. I agree. Typing is weird.
Speaker 18:  It feels strange.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I keep thinking I'm gonna get used to it but I haven't. But the, you're,
Speaker 1:  you're totally right. The two apps side by side thing, especially for something
Speaker 1:  like research and note taking is really useful just for me being
Speaker 1:  able to have like the browser on one side and a Google doc or my
Speaker 1:  notes app or whatever on the other is amazing. And I never noticed how
Speaker 1:  annoying it is to constantly switch between apps on my
Speaker 1:  iPhone as I have after using the Pixel Fold a bunch. So I'm with you. So,
Speaker 1:  okay Terry you should buy it. It's gonna be amazing. Let's talk about prices
Speaker 1:  because I think you were on this show when all this stuff first
Speaker 1:  came out and I think we, we more or less agree $1,800 is a
Speaker 1:  ludicrous amount of money to pay for a phone. Like If you want to and you
Speaker 1:  have the money go with God, right? But $1,800 is
Speaker 1:  a tremendous amount of money, but these things are now a
Speaker 1:  year or in the the Galaxy folds case sometimes a couple of years old,
Speaker 1:  the prices are coming way down. Does that make you think differently about
Speaker 1:  them?
Speaker 18:  This is the question I ask myself every day. Just even when you
Speaker 18:  consider when one of these phones comes out, especially Samsung
Speaker 18:  will, they'll throw a new phone at you If you trade
Speaker 18:  something in or If you sign up on your carriers,
Speaker 18:  you promise to pay them thousands of dollars over the next three years,
Speaker 18:  they'll throw a phone at you. So what does a phone really cost is a question.
Speaker 18:  I think there is kind of a calculus as you know, when you
Speaker 18:  get to like a year out, the prices will kind of come down.
Speaker 18:  Sometimes, I, think Foldables have been a little more
Speaker 18:  stubborn. But the thing to kind of balance that with is always
Speaker 18:  like, what do we think is coming out next is it's gonna be a
Speaker 18:  big year, like a big leap forward this year. I
Speaker 18:  would argue that the Galaxy Z Fold four to five,
Speaker 18:  like not much changed there. And If, you If you were
Speaker 18:  looking at a, at a Z Fold four and skip the five.
Speaker 18:  That probably would've been a good call there. I think there's some interesting
Speaker 18:  things coming up this year where the, the Pixel Fold
Speaker 18:  looks like it might get a little thinner and kind of a,
Speaker 18:  a less like rectangular shape where it's, it's like real
Speaker 18:  kind of squat and wide sort of maybe
Speaker 18:  something like the one plus open, which I think has the best
Speaker 18:  format of like when it's closed and when it's open.
Speaker 18:  So all that's to say, I don't know, I don't know how you think about the
Speaker 18:  price you do wanna factor in like the years of security
Speaker 18:  updates in the os updates that your promise, like you,
Speaker 18:  if you're buying a model that's a year out of date, you have to minus one
Speaker 18:  year on all those things. Those are, you know, and I keep that in mind,
Speaker 18:  but I would kind of keep an an ear to the ground on like what's coming
Speaker 18:  up and then see what the deals are now and just don't forget
Speaker 18:  that when the new phone comes out you, you can usually do pretty well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's, it's a tricky one because I think my go-to advice
Speaker 1:  on all technology for a long time has been buy
Speaker 1:  the most expensive, best newest thing you can afford and then keep it
Speaker 1:  as long as humanly possible. And that I, that advice I mostly stand by
Speaker 1:  except that I obviously recognize that many people can't for
Speaker 1:  whatever reason afford the best and biggest and newest thing. Right. And
Speaker 1:  I think particularly with foldable phones, that's really complicated because
Speaker 1:  there isn't, like you're saying that sort of graceful scaling that happens
Speaker 1:  where like If, you wanna buy an iPhone 13 in this
Speaker 1:  the year 2024. I think that's a perfectly valid thing to do.
Speaker 1:  It's not what I would do because of my aforementioned belief in buying the
Speaker 1:  new thing and then keeping it forever. But the iPhone 13 is a really good
Speaker 1:  phone. There is no version of that three years ago
Speaker 1:  in foldable funds and they're getting better so much faster and they're so
Speaker 1:  not yet mature that and like as soon as you brought up the Pixel Fold, I'm
Speaker 1:  like, I just think about how much better like the Pixel watch got from one
Speaker 1:  to two, like the Fold, Google has a long history of making like kind of
Speaker 1:  NELI first things and then pretty good second things. And so even at
Speaker 1:  a thousand dollars, like are you gonna buy that phone and then
Speaker 1:  in six months be like, I should have just bought the
Speaker 1:  $1,800 one because it's dramatically better Or should you have waited six
Speaker 1:  more months after that, but then at that point you're waiting for the folder.
Speaker 1:  It's like, it's just a forever, it's
Speaker 18:  Like a hamster wheel. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  It really is. But I'm curious for you as a reviewer, like this is something
Speaker 1:  I've struggled with over the years in reviewing products is how much to think
Speaker 1:  about what they cost. And I think sometimes it's really obvious, right? Like
Speaker 1:  we, we, I I made a big show of yelling $3,500
Speaker 1:  a lot when we talked about the Vision Pro. But in terms of like as you're
Speaker 1:  reviewing a phone about foldable phones or even just, you know,
Speaker 1:  the most other kind of thousand dollar ish phones, do you spend a lot of
Speaker 1:  time thinking about the price as you're reviewing it?
Speaker 18:  I do. Kind of trying to bear in mind like the, the way that
Speaker 18:  most people buy phones, especially in this country is looks very different
Speaker 18:  that, you know, nobody's walking into Verizon and just putting a thousand
Speaker 18:  dollars on the table. So that kind of figures in, but you know,
Speaker 18:  even when that's the case, like you have a whole lot of capital
Speaker 18:  with like, if you're ready to, to switch to a new
Speaker 18:  wireless carrier, you can like easily get a thousand dollars phone out of
Speaker 18:  that. So like just the, just kind of keeping in mind
Speaker 18:  the weight of that that you know, anybody's potentially
Speaker 18:  putting down on one of these devices. And I do think of them
Speaker 18:  as they're kind of a moment in time, the review So
Speaker 18:  I, I bear in mind like the prices of the other things
Speaker 18:  out there and they may be discounted, they may have some
Speaker 18:  special deal going, but I think
Speaker 18:  I come back to the M-S-R-P-A lot as kind of an apples to apples
Speaker 18:  like gut check of, you know, this costs this
Speaker 18:  amount of money for real and this one cost this
Speaker 18:  or is that a good deal? And there there's just a lot of like 40
Speaker 18:  chess going on in, in my mind somewhere. but it all
Speaker 18:  has to kind of come out in a way that hopefully makes sense
Speaker 18:  to people.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I was used to try to think about like, okay, If, you gave this to me
Speaker 1:  as a gift and it was free, would I like it? And that's kind of one version
Speaker 1:  of the question. And then the other one is, is it worth the cost? And the
Speaker 1:  problem with phones is, is they exist literally on every single part of
Speaker 1:  the spectrum between the two.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, right. It's,
Speaker 1:  It's so complicated.
Speaker 18:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  In a way that like I pretty much know what an iPad costs, right? Like
Speaker 1:  you just have no idea what your next phone is gonna cost in the
Speaker 1:  strangest way. But okay, let's, let's answer a couple of quick questions
Speaker 1:  here for Terry and then we're gonna get outta here. Question number one is,
Speaker 1:  should Terry just buy an iPad
Speaker 18:  Ooh? Well
Speaker 1:  Like is that the better idea?
Speaker 18:  I, you know, there's something to that. I'm sort of coming around
Speaker 18:  to this idea of like, wouldn't it be nice to have more gadgets that
Speaker 18:  are just good at doing the thing that you want them to do? Like we've just
Speaker 18:  for concept, I know we've spent a lot of time like cramming as many
Speaker 18:  things as we can into a phone and like that's fun, but sometimes,
Speaker 18:  like we were both looking at this like standalone voice recorder
Speaker 18:  today, which is like, what a novel idea. Your phone can do that. But
Speaker 18:  anyway, that's a long way to say like that's an option. And if the
Speaker 18:  kinds of things he wants to do with it are just
Speaker 18:  better on a tablet than, you know, think about a tablet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, I've been debating this ever since I, I first heard Terry's question
Speaker 1:  and I think the thing I've come around to is the question is do you need
Speaker 1:  to have it in your pocket? Right? Because Terry is like, I'm a big guy, I
Speaker 1:  have big hands. I if, if the answer is like, I want to carry this thing around
Speaker 1:  with me all the time, foldable phones because like you can tell yourself
Speaker 1:  you're gonna carry an iPad with you all the time. I have told myself that
Speaker 1:  many times. It's just never true. The idea that I, I'm just gonna have it
Speaker 1:  with me all the time. Not true. But if you're like, I'm mostly at
Speaker 1:  home and I want a thing that I can like sit with for my reading and research
Speaker 1:  or whatever, I think the iPad's the better advice. The the other thing is,
Speaker 1:  if Terry wants about foldable phones, which one would you recommend
Speaker 1:  right now? And, and the thing for Terry is Terry does care about the
Speaker 1:  price but, but we are here to tell Terry all things considered here is
Speaker 1:  the one we think you should buy. What do you think the answer is right now?
Speaker 18:  Yeah, I like my general pick right now
Speaker 18:  is the Samsung is the Galaxy Z, Fold five. I think
Speaker 18:  they're just kind of, they kind of had a head start and they've figured
Speaker 18:  out a couple more things. you know, with the durability and with the
Speaker 18:  software that I think Google and OnePlus, those are really the
Speaker 18:  only two other options in the us They're still kind of figurine
Speaker 18:  out. I say that with the asterisk of like the Z Fold five
Speaker 18:  form factor might
Speaker 18:  a new one pretty
Speaker 1:  sometime, even if it doesn't come out till the fall. So you, you'll at least
Speaker 1:  have kind of a hint about what's coming. But I think I'm with you that If,
Speaker 1:  you wanna buy a phone that is both a year old and likely to still be good
Speaker 1:  for a while. It seems like Samsung is probably the safest choice. Yeah. Even
Speaker 1:  if it does feel like a TV remote,
Speaker 18:  It does, but it, it's gonna solve all of Terry's problems,
Speaker 18:  I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1:  There we go. Terry, good luck on all of your endeavors with your foldable
Speaker 1:  phones. I hope that helped Allison. Thank you as always. Thank
Speaker 18:  You.
Speaker 1:  All right, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who came
Speaker 1:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 1:  we talked about on The Verge dot com, especially the Rivian stuff. We had
Speaker 1:  a lot of really good coverage, including that conversation with RJ Escar,
Speaker 1:  the CEO. We'll put some links in the show notes, but you know, The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com, it's a website, we love it. As always, If you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 1:  feelings, or other cars