# Transcript
ID: 4e8ec2a5-fb8b-47b4-a19d-607f2e701dcc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3012207021001092461/2008771675531718216/s93290-US-4301s-1719302558.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the many definitions of electronic paper:
03:12 -The Verge’s David Pierce takes a look at the Boox Palma, a phone-shaped e-reader that runs Android. He also compares notes with Clockwise’s Matt Martin and writer Craig Mod.
The Boox Palma is an amazing gadget I didn't even know I wanted
New Pop-up Walk, Reading Digitally in 2024 — Roden Newsletter Archive
30:06 - The Verge’s Nathan Edwards and Tom Warren join the show to discuss their experience using Microsoft’s new Surface Copilot PCs. They also answer a question from The Vergecast Hotline.
Surface Laptop 7th Edition review: Microsoft’s best MacBook Air competitor yet
With Copilot Plus, the new and improved Windows PCs are here
Microsoft’s embarrassing Recall
Microsoft makes Copilot less useful on new Copilot Plus PCs
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (27 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the many, many
Speaker 2:  definitions of electronic paper. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am
Speaker 2:  at the park for research and journalism as you do. So, I have this
Speaker 2:  new device, it's called the Daylight DC one and it's a tablet
Speaker 2:  obviously, but the idea is that it's a different kind of tablet.
Speaker 2:  It doesn't use a big, bright, colorful screen like the iPad, but
Speaker 2:  it's also not an E Ink screen, which has sort of slow refresh rate and doesn't
Speaker 2:  have some of the things that you want from like a smoothly scrolling, easy
Speaker 2:  typing tablet. It tries to be a middle ground and I find that middle
Speaker 2:  ground really interesting. I've been using this tablet a lot. They really
Speaker 2:  want you to use it outdoors. It's called the Daylight. It comes in this
Speaker 2:  like plush sort of outdoorsy case instead of like
Speaker 2:  the sleek metallic fabricy thing you normally get with a tablet. And
Speaker 2:  it's designed to just be a simpler kind of technology. And I have
Speaker 2:  a lot of testing lifts to do with this thing, but so far it's not that impressive
Speaker 2:  a gadget. But I still find it fascinating 'cause I think this idea that what
Speaker 2:  if instead of totally, you know, ground up, reinventing every kind of
Speaker 2:  gadget that exists in the world, we just tweaked the formula a little
Speaker 2:  bit. Different kinds of screens, different sizes, different shapes, different
Speaker 2:  fabrics, different textures. And maybe that changes the way that we'll feel
Speaker 2:  about these things and the way that we use them in more interesting ways
Speaker 2:  than just, you know, throw it all away and try again. To some extent. That
Speaker 2:  is actually what we're gonna talk about in this episode. First, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about an e ink device called the Book's Palmer that I'm sort of
Speaker 2:  obsessed with. We'll talk about why in a few minutes after that we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about the new Surface Laptop and Surface Pro from Microsoft, which are
Speaker 2:  still very gadgety gadgets, but they're making this big bet that AI
Speaker 2:  and a new kind of chip from Qualcomm can change how you feel about
Speaker 2:  something that still looks like a tablet and still looks like a laptop, but
Speaker 2:  might mean something else to you. It's very gadgety episode, but it's also
Speaker 2:  I think gonna get strangely philosophical in spots. I'm very excited about
Speaker 2:  it. We also have a question new from the hotline. Lots to get to. All that
Speaker 2:  is coming up in just a second, but I have never played pickleball before
Speaker 2:  and those people are playing pickleball. I'm gonna go learn how to play pickleball.
Speaker 2:  This is The Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  is like the world's best problem to have by
Speaker 2:  is an E Ink screen. The EIN Carta 1200 if you're really curious,
Speaker 2:  which makes the Palma kind of the exact middle between a smartphone
Speaker 2:  and a Kindle. And for me that turns out to be kind of perfect.
Speaker 2:  The Palmer launched last fall and I remember being sort of interested in
Speaker 2:  it back then. Books the company, it's BOOX by the way,
Speaker 2:  has been making these interesting EIN Android devices for a while and they
Speaker 2:  started out kind of clunky but have steadily gotten better over time. The
Speaker 2:  Palmer launched last fall and I remember being sort of interested in it back
Speaker 2:  then. Books the company, it's BOOX by the way,
Speaker 2:  has been making these interesting EIN Android devices for a while and they
Speaker 2:  started kind of clunky but have steadily gotten better over time. It's a
Speaker 2:  China-based company and it sells like a million different devices.
Speaker 2:  There's the books note Air three C and the books tab Ultra and the books
Speaker 2:  page and the books Leaf and the books Leaf two and the books note Air two
Speaker 2:  and the books go and the books go color. Basically every size of
Speaker 2:  e-reader, You can imagine You can get. I already have a lot of
Speaker 2:  E-readers though I read a lot on my iPad. I have a couple of
Speaker 2:  Kindles of various sizes and generations. I have a remarkable tablet
Speaker 2:  that I really like. I'm honestly good on E Ink devices. The
Speaker 2:  Palmer is also $280, which is a lot for an e-reader. But
Speaker 2:  I ended up getting one anyway because over the months since it launched I've
Speaker 2:  seen a surprising number of people talk about how much they love this thing.
Speaker 2:  So I got mine a couple of months ago and I have to say I understood the appeal
Speaker 2:  pretty much right away. For me, there are two things about the Palmer that
Speaker 2:  have actually made it stick in my life. The first is just the size. The fact
Speaker 2:  that it fits in my pocket and is really easy to hold in one hand is a
Speaker 2:  total game changer. That sounds sort of ridiculous to say, but it's really
Speaker 2:  been true. It's easier for reading in bed, it's easier to bring with me
Speaker 2:  on a walk or to a coffee shop. I can lug the Palmer the same way I lug
Speaker 2:  my phone and that has just made me have it around more often. The second
Speaker 2:  thing is the fact that it runs Android, which I mean obviously, right? That's
Speaker 2:  like the whole book's thing. Instead of just having to do everything through
Speaker 2:  Amazon on a Kindle or through Barnes and Noble on a nook, you get the whole
Speaker 2:  universe of Android stuff. For me as a reader, that means I can have three
Speaker 2:  crucial things on the device at the same time. The place I read books, which
Speaker 2:  happens to be the Kindle app, the place I read articles, which is an app
Speaker 2:  called Read Wise Reader and the place that I save webpages and other links
Speaker 2:  to get to later, which is an app called Raindrop. All of my reading, no matter
Speaker 2:  what form it takes now lives on this one device with an e Ink screen.
Speaker 2:  Any app with pagination You can scroll with the volume buttons on the side,
Speaker 2:  which I really love. The battery lasts a long time, somewhere between like
Speaker 2:  a few days and a week depending on how I use it. I'm not distracted by other
Speaker 2:  stuff because I don't have any other stuff because TikTok and YouTube all
Speaker 2:  really suck on an Ian screen. It's just perfect. I did also
Speaker 2:  install Pocket Casts and Spotify, which are where I listen to podcasts and
Speaker 2:  music. So now this thing is both my Kindle and my iPod, I
Speaker 2:  go online to download new stuff, then I put the thing in airplane mode and
Speaker 2:  I'm good to go anyway. I sound like I'm shilling for the books Palmer and
Speaker 2:  I kind of am. I love this thing, but it's not because this is some
Speaker 2:  magnificently perfect unique gadget. It's kind of flimsy. I wish the screen
Speaker 2:  were higher res. I wish it supported a stylist. It's pretty slow even when
Speaker 2:  you're just trying to get to the home screen. And most problematically by
Speaker 2:  far it's running Android 11, which is now four years old and I am
Speaker 2:  deeply worried it's never going to get updated past that. The upside of Kindle
Speaker 2:  is that my Kindle from whatever six years ago still works great.
Speaker 2:  There are lots of things about the palm ads that I wish were better and very
Speaker 2:  little about it actually that someone else couldn't do better. But that's
Speaker 2:  actually what's been so fun about using this thing. It has totally proven
Speaker 2:  to me that there is something in this hardware combination, an e ink display
Speaker 2:  in the body of a smartphone with all the apps I need. That's it. It's worse
Speaker 2:  than my phone at a lot of things, but massively better than my phone in
Speaker 2:  just enough ways that it's worth having around. I've spent a lot of time
Speaker 2:  testing out new kinds of gadgets this year. Smart glasses and AI pins
Speaker 2:  and foldable devices and weird new ideas about tablets. And
Speaker 2:  as it turns out the thing I like the most is just a new take on the smartphone.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, I wanted to know what other people liked about the Palmer and why
Speaker 2:  this thing has been such a hit with people who have tried it. So I called
Speaker 2:  up a couple of them to chat about it. The first person I called was Matt
Speaker 2:  Martin. He runs a company called Clockwise and I actually caught him a few
Speaker 2:  weeks into parental leave. He said he found the Palma the same way I did
Speaker 2:  because people just wouldn't stop talking about it.
Speaker 6:  People in my feed that that really loved good products, good design seemed
Speaker 6:  like hit the zeitgeist somehow in like the little tech world that we live
Speaker 6:  in. I also am having a new kid and I was like, well I aspire
Speaker 6:  to read more. I aspire not to, you know, spend my 30 minutes
Speaker 6:  before bed on. Sure. You know, Instagram reels. And so
Speaker 6:  I got it and I have to tell you, like the thing that I find really
Speaker 6:  quite compelling about it, even after using it for a month or so, is
Speaker 6:  having a full OS on it. Like the Kindle, you're in Amazon's
Speaker 6:  little world where, you know it's the Kindle operating system running on
Speaker 6:  top of Android, but you know, you only have access to what Amazon gives you.
Speaker 6:  It is basically a full version of Android. You can go to the Google Play
Speaker 6:  store. I downloaded the New York Times app, I downloaded instant paper,
Speaker 6:  I downloaded Libby and I downloaded the Kindle app, which by the way makes
Speaker 6:  for just as good a reading experiences on a Kindle. And that's actually,
Speaker 6:  it's the combination of the portability and being able to like flip through
Speaker 6:  online articles that are cultivated in the New York Times and actually flip
Speaker 6:  through things. It's actually pretty, I wouldn't say it's revolutionary,
Speaker 6:  but it's, it's an evolution that transforms the device for me to make it
Speaker 6:  pretty compelling and something I reach for.
Speaker 2:  I totally agree. The argument I have heard against this device is
Speaker 2:  basically like, just download those apps onto your phone.
Speaker 2:  You do this. Like what is the point of having a whole separate dedicated
Speaker 2:  device just for this? And I think to some extent
Speaker 2:  the answer is like, Inc is nicer to look at. Right? But it also feels like
Speaker 2:  there's some, there's something about having a thing that feels like a
Speaker 2:  dedicated device. Yeah. Even though it's not a totally dedicated device
Speaker 2:  that it's like I could put all the stuff I don't wanna look at on the
Speaker 2:  Palmer and for some reason I haven't and I don't feel tempted to, there is
Speaker 2:  a web browser and no part of me is tempted to go look at the web browser.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I like, I have a hard time figuring out why that is.
Speaker 6:  So I am addicted to New York Times little games. Mm. I play with
Speaker 6:  friends and I, and I was like, oh I can play connections on here. Even that
Speaker 6:  I find not compelling to do. Like if it's outside of reading, I
Speaker 6:  don't really want to do it on the Palm. I, and I think that the, the answer
Speaker 6:  is probably not a very exciting one, which is that you know,
Speaker 6:  as humans, you know there's the old anecdote that we were probably all taught
Speaker 6:  in Psych 1 0 1, which is that physical environment matters. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  if you set up an environment for a specific context, your brain actually
Speaker 6:  is kind of hardwired to take in the context and get prepared for that. And
Speaker 6:  I think a separate device matters here a bit like if I'm in the context of
Speaker 6:  my phone, there's just like that muscle memory like, you know, iOS
Speaker 6:  has become so refined at getting between the applications so quickly.
Speaker 6:  Like I can have a random thought and this happens all the time. Like sometimes
Speaker 6:  you're reading, you're in a slow section, you have that random thought about
Speaker 6:  like, oh what was that thing that I wanted to buy on Amazon?
Speaker 6:  And you were there without even thinking about it. And now I'm on like a
Speaker 6:  rabbit hole of attention that I didn't mean to be on.
Speaker 2:  This is part of the reason I've been so interested in this gadget ecosystem
Speaker 2:  for so long is I think anybody who says, oh just use your smartphone differently.
Speaker 2:  It's a matter of willpower is just like, no
Speaker 2:  you're wrong. And that's not how it works. Yeah. And also I don't, my phone
Speaker 2:  is very good at a lot of things and I'm happy it's good at those things.
Speaker 2:  So what, give me the full list of the apps you have on there. You mentioned
Speaker 2:  Kindle, New York Times, what else do you have? That's
Speaker 6:  Basically it, man. I mean, so it was kind of wild. I realized when I was
Speaker 6:  logging in everything that I could install one password and like it would
Speaker 6:  just work. Oh that's smart integrated. Which is, you know, it's a full and
Speaker 6:  solid Android. So I have in addition to those, I have one password
Speaker 6:  Audible Wikipedia, but I really, the home screen is just four
Speaker 6:  apps. It's just Kindle piece paper or New York Times and Lib.
Speaker 6:  'cause again, it's a dedicated device for me. I don't really even seek out
Speaker 6:  the other applications. You said, like you said, there's a web browser and
Speaker 6:  I don't, I don't really have any impulse to go use that.
Speaker 2:  Do you wish there were things this thing could do that it doesn't? What do
Speaker 2:  you dislike about the Palmer?
Speaker 6:  Not yet. Honestly, I'm, I'm very happy with it so I'll ask her to all this
Speaker 6:  which is like, look, let's just acknowledge that we're weirdos. I, I wouldn't
Speaker 6:  scream for the mountaintops that everybody should go get a books Palmer.
Speaker 6:  Sure. Like my mom would probably love this thing, but also she probably
Speaker 6:  shouldn't get one. Like it's fine. And I'm also not like, I don't
Speaker 6:  quite nerd out despite my profession being in a company that focuses
Speaker 6:  on focus time and helping give people more time in their day. I actually
Speaker 6:  don't geek out on like all these different apps that try to, you know, give
Speaker 6:  you more time to focus or prune your little garden when you're trying to
Speaker 6:  focus your elements. But I just find the thing compelling because it helps
Speaker 6:  me read like that's it. Full stop. Full story. Yeah, I was at a
Speaker 6:  pediatrics appointment and I stuck in my pocket 'cause I knew we'd be waiting
Speaker 6:  around and I was sitting there and I pulled it out and read an article that
Speaker 6:  I'd saved instead of pulling out my phone and looking at some dumb crap on
Speaker 6:  Instagram and like, I don't know, small win but kind of feels good
Speaker 2:  The way Matt put that was something I've been thinking about a lot ever since.
Speaker 2:  When I have my phone in my pocket, my impulse when I pull it out is to open
Speaker 2:  Threads or TikTok or Instagram. I can fight that impulse and
Speaker 2:  be productive and do the thing that I wanted to do, but that's still the
Speaker 2:  impulse. When I have something like the Palmer in my pocket, I open it up
Speaker 2:  and my impulse is to open up Read Wise or the Crosswords app. It just
Speaker 2:  incentivizes a different kind of behavior in a way that I really like.
Speaker 2:  After I talked to Matt, the next person I called is probably the single person
Speaker 2:  most responsible for all the other people in my threads feed. Talking about
Speaker 2:  the Palmer, it's this guy,
Speaker 7:  I'm Craig Mod and I'm a writer and photographer and I make books.
Speaker 2:  Craig wrote a blog post in early May about why he loves The Palmer, which
Speaker 2:  got a lot of people excited. Craig has been thinking and writing about digital
Speaker 2:  reading for a really long time. So for him to love a reading device
Speaker 2:  is a pretty meaningful thing actually. Especially because as he told me,
Speaker 2:  he never expected to love a digital reading device ever again.
Speaker 2:  Oh.
Speaker 7:  I totally stopped helping for the best a long time ago. Okay. That's why
Speaker 7:  I stopped writing about it. That's why I stopped talking to companies that
Speaker 7:  would like, you know, people would email me, be like, Hey, I'm doing a startup
Speaker 7:  around digital books. It's like instantly into the trash. Like no. They're
Speaker 7:  like, yeah,
Speaker 2:  Good luck with that.
Speaker 7:  I know how that song ends. Earlier
Speaker 2:  This year though, the folks that read Wise called up Craig to talk to him
Speaker 2:  about some digital reading stuff. He's actually an advisor to the company
Speaker 2:  these days, but he also does just like the app and so do I. It's very good.
Speaker 2:  And they ended up showing him the Palmer. He bought one along with one of
Speaker 2:  the other larger books tablets and immediately fell in love with it.
Speaker 2:  So we compared notes for a little while.
Speaker 7:  I'm excited about this idea that Ian screens are cheap enough
Speaker 7:  that anyone can kind of produce these devices now and Android as
Speaker 7:  an operating system and you know, in general touch base tablet operating
Speaker 7:  systems, like whatever, we've figured 'em out. We figured 'em out a long
Speaker 7:  time ago. There's no cancer to be solved in
Speaker 7:  tablets anymore. It all works the same. They're all, they're all fine. And
Speaker 7:  so like Android is totally good enough. So like the fact that You can kind
Speaker 7:  of stick an Android computer into a device that has a great ink screen
Speaker 7:  and run the Kindle app. Which by the way, Kindle devices are just
Speaker 7:  Android devices.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, that's true.
Speaker 7:  They're just running the Kindle app and that's all they run. And the books
Speaker 7:  folks runs every Android app in the app store runs the Read Wise Reader
Speaker 7:  app. So suddenly you have all your long form reading
Speaker 7:  beautifully synced between all your devices. The Read Wise Reader app is,
Speaker 7:  is actually really thoughtfully done. The scroll design that they released
Speaker 7:  earlier this year.
Speaker 2:  Do you do the paginated scroll?
Speaker 7:  Yes, yes. And I love it. I think it's so good.
Speaker 2:  I turned that on the second they launched it and I, yeah, it was, I have
Speaker 2:  switched to and from Instapaper a hundred thousand times
Speaker 2:  just because it Paginates. Yeah. And I don't, especially for very long
Speaker 2:  things, I just don't wanna scroll it like a webpage. No. I told the Read
Speaker 2:  Rise folks like a year ago, like, please dear God, just give me pagination.
Speaker 2:  And they were like, I don't know, I'm not sure anybody except you wants that.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, all right, fair enough. Understood. And then they launched
Speaker 2:  it and it was instantly, everything about my reading life got better.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no and it, they did a really good job with it and I love how they do
Speaker 7:  the breaks and with like the book's, Palma You can set the volume
Speaker 7:  buttons as the scroll buttons and it's just perfect. One-handed reading
Speaker 7:  and there is something, you're absolutely right, scrolling and reading long
Speaker 7:  texts sucks. It sucks. And this is one of the reasons why I think if
Speaker 7:  you looked at engagement on laptop screens, like long text, I can't
Speaker 7:  read something over a thousand words on a laptop. I just can't do it. And
Speaker 7:  so I've given up on it so everything gets sent to reader. You know, you just
Speaker 7:  click the little icon, you know, in your extensions bar and Chrome or whatever
Speaker 7:  and boom, it's in reader read Wise Reader and you know, it's on
Speaker 7:  all these devices waiting to be read beautifully. Paginated You can do
Speaker 7:  note taking, highlighting synced beautifully. It goes into obsidian, the
Speaker 7:  obsidian synced notes. You can see them, you click on 'em, it opens a read
Speaker 7:  wise reader on the web. All the loops are closed for engagement around
Speaker 7:  longform reading. And I have found since getting these devices, because
Speaker 7:  I used to send long form articles to the Kindle, but it was such a clumsy
Speaker 7:  affair and the notes weren't really synced and saved and it just felt like
Speaker 7:  I was throwing things away and I'd never be able to go back to them. And
Speaker 7:  the, and the archive was bad. Now that I can use Read Wise Reader and I have
Speaker 7:  an E Ink device that has essentially a week long, two week long battery life,
Speaker 7:  I never think about charging these things. Even now it's like 44%. I've been
Speaker 7:  using this for the last week and now that I can do that, that ecosystem has
Speaker 7:  completely reinvigorated all of my digital reading and long form reading.
Speaker 7:  I've read more long form articles in the last three months than I have probably
Speaker 7:  in the last year. And that's awesome. I just love it I love it. I love that
Speaker 7:  everything that the Kindle had a monopoly on, which was mainly hardware and
Speaker 7:  screens that's gone. The moat is totally gone
Speaker 7:  and it feels like we are at this now at this precipice, high refresh
Speaker 7:  ink screens, low cost Android devices. Let's go
Speaker 7:  like, let's do something interesting around this space. Like it's just really
Speaker 7:  exciting.
Speaker 2:  What is it about the Palma in particular that sort of speaks to you?
Speaker 7:  Well it's You can just have it in your pocket. This is one of the things
Speaker 7:  that drove me insane about the Oasis is like, I like the oasis. The shape
Speaker 7:  of it is shaped so it can't fit in any pocket known to man.
Speaker 7:  It's the craziest shape I've ever seen in my life. It doesn't fit into
Speaker 7:  any pocket. I don't know how they did it. They like, it's like they went
Speaker 7:  around the world and they checked every pocket and they're like, okay, make
Speaker 7:  it one millimeter bigger than every single angle. Well you know, so this,
Speaker 7:  you know, this Palma I'm holding right now, it's so light, it
Speaker 7:  fits anywhere. You can just have it in your breast pocket. You can have it
Speaker 7:  in your pant pocket, whatever. So it is my like go-to thing to have on
Speaker 7:  trains. Whenever I'm traveling I pull this thing out and I'm reading on it.
Speaker 7:  It's also my bedtime computer, you know, it's like You can be in bed, all
Speaker 7:  the lights are off the, all the back lights stuff on these books. Devices
Speaker 7:  are pretty well done. It's kind of like a, I dunno if it's a warm back light,
Speaker 7:  but it's like You can have it low enough or it doesn't really feel like it's
Speaker 7:  affecting sleep. It's just perfect. One-handed, it's not heavy. It's not
Speaker 7:  gonna fall on your face in a weird way. You can be on your side. You got
Speaker 7:  it in your hand with your thumb on the, the volume controls and You can just
Speaker 7:  easily go through an article until you fall asleep. It's like a gentle lullaby
Speaker 7:  of a reader. It's great. and it makes you wonder why hasn't someone
Speaker 7:  made an E Ink phone? Because yes, it's, so
Speaker 7:  everything that I'm looking for in a device is like these palm, this, the
Speaker 7:  palm of the refresh rate is high enough. I mean, have you watched video on
Speaker 7:  these things? It's really wild. Like it disincentivizes you
Speaker 7:  from watching video, but the fact that this E Inc screen can update fast
Speaker 7:  enough to show you video and it looks like video. Yeah. and it doesn't have
Speaker 7:  that much ghosting. That just means that You can do highly
Speaker 7:  interactive interfaces that wouldn't be annoying to type messages on. Do
Speaker 7:  the basics. You could run Google Maps on this thing and Zoom and do searches
Speaker 7:  and it would be fine. And I would love to have this as my
Speaker 7:  main driver so much more than, you know, the Dopamine Casino
Speaker 7:  iPhone where it's like vying for your attention every two seconds and all
Speaker 7:  the notifications look so good and it's just such a juicy device to be spending
Speaker 7:  time with. But this Palma, it really has
Speaker 7:  reconfigured like, 'cause I hadn't been paying attention to the state of
Speaker 7:  E Ink and so, you know, the state of ink for me was whatever the latest Kindle
Speaker 7:  was doing. And you know, you don't really get a sense of how good it is with
Speaker 7:  the Kindles and these books. Devices have really blown my mind just how
Speaker 7:  fast E Ink can be and how joyful it is
Speaker 7:  to run all these different apps in the Inc.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What do you do on the Palmer other than read?
Speaker 7:  That's it. So that's, I mean that's the other great, all I, all I run is
Speaker 7:  reader and Kindle, but I've, you know, poked around on the, if I need to
Speaker 7:  do a web search, which I very rarely do, but if I need to, I can. And if
Speaker 7:  I need to buy a Kindle book, I can go to the Kindle website and run that.
Speaker 7:  And like the fact that I can do that and it doesn't feel like a burden
Speaker 7:  or like I'm taxing the machine, you know? Whereas like on the Kindle, anytime
Speaker 7:  you had to load up the experimental, the experimental now like
Speaker 7:  14 years later, still experimental browser
Speaker 2:  Disaster
Speaker 7:  Doesn't work. Doesn't work well at all. Yeah, no, absolutely terrible. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's just made me go, wow, there's a whole world of e Inc exploration that
Speaker 7:  hasn't happened and can happen now. And the, the technology is clearly like
Speaker 7:  the IP is, I think there's a lot of IP issues or whatever. It's exp it was
Speaker 7:  expensive to license before. Maybe that's all changed. Yeah. And yeah, and
Speaker 7:  now You can make things like this, which is incredible. I love it more, more
Speaker 7:  Ink please.
Speaker 2:  I agree. And I actually think the, what you said though, like if you need
Speaker 2:  to You can, to me it's like the perfect description of everything about the
Speaker 2:  Palma because like, yes, You can watch video, but it sucks. Like it's not,
Speaker 2:  you wouldn't wanna sit and watch a video, but ultimately it's like if I need
Speaker 2:  to watch a video in service of the thing that I'm reading for a minute, it's
Speaker 2:  there. I will get through it, I will get the thing that I need out of it
Speaker 2:  and then I'll go back to reading, which is what I'm after here for sure.
Speaker 2:  And so that to me is like, the fact that it does all of these things, the
Speaker 2:  fact that it does them poorly has actually become a feature, not a bug for
Speaker 2:  me. Which is not what I expected when I first got this device.
Speaker 7:  It's the absolute perfect amount of friction. Yeah, yeah. Whereas the Kindle
Speaker 7:  is too much friction for doing most things. The books, devices, it's
Speaker 7:  like just a little bit of friction where it's like, as you say, it's like
Speaker 7:  you wouldn't wanna go surf YouTube and be like, all right, let watch M-K-B-H-D,
Speaker 7:  you know, is most recent video on this thing. But if I needed
Speaker 7:  to watch a little interview with Dennis Johnson talking about
Speaker 7:  train dreams or whatever, like I could pop into that for a second and be
Speaker 7:  like, exactly like you said, get what you need to get out of it and go back
Speaker 7:  into the reading. And that's, that's exciting. And you know, and I think
Speaker 7:  the perfect amount of friction is exactly what no one is willing to
Speaker 7:  bake into most devices. And this is kind of happening almost like as a byproduct,
Speaker 7:  a natural, a natural byproduct of the technology. And that feels
Speaker 7:  organic and really lovely.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Is there anything you would change about the Palmer? Like as a,
Speaker 2:  as a gadget?
Speaker 7:  I'd probably get rid of the camera. I'd simplify it even more. I
Speaker 2:  Forgot it had a camera. Just this moment was the first time I've thought
Speaker 2:  about the Palma's camera since the second I got it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I've, I've taken a few photos with it. It's kind of funny to then look
Speaker 7:  at them, you know, later and it's like, oh yeah, that's right. I could take
Speaker 7:  photos with this. But like, I would probably put the volume
Speaker 7:  rockers on both sides. So you could do page change on both sides of it and
Speaker 7:  just really optimize for like, if you're holding it with your right hand
Speaker 7:  or left hand, you have the exact same kind of hardware interaction model.
Speaker 7:  I'd probably move the power button to the top because I think that's the
Speaker 7:  best place for all power buttons. I think the iPhone power button on the
Speaker 7:  side was the worst hardware change they made to the iPhone in the history
Speaker 7:  of the iPhone. I mean, just because how many times do you accidentally,
Speaker 7:  you know, do screenshots and yet, you know, anyway, I love
Speaker 7:  power on the top, which by the way, this other books model does power
Speaker 7:  on the top in their Okay. In their tablet. And that feels really good. And
Speaker 7:  then just, yeah, just have those, have those page from buttons on both sides.
Speaker 7:  And then I think that's it. Maybe the screen, like I do feel like the screen
Speaker 7:  on this thing is not extremely well protected. You know, I I
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting. Yeah, I would love to see a Gorilla Glass version of
Speaker 7:  this. What would that feel like? How much heavier would it make? It, it,
Speaker 7:  I wouldn't want the body to be metal. I think this plastic body,
Speaker 7:  I think the texture on the back of it is fine. I think lightness is, is
Speaker 7:  is a huge bonus when it comes to devices like this. Agree. And
Speaker 7:  I just worry, like sometimes when I put it in my bag, I'm like, is this screen
Speaker 7:  gonna get messed up? I'm still treating it, I'm not babying it at all.
Speaker 7:  I'm, I'm just throwing it in my bag and I'm like, okay, whatever's gonna
Speaker 7:  happen is gonna happen. But I do feel like a stronger, even
Speaker 7:  just like a couple generations old Gorilla Glass might be a really interesting
Speaker 7:  modification. I don't know what the IPX rating is, but I'd wanna make sure
Speaker 7:  it would be like fully submersible that those would be, you know, I see the
Speaker 7:  Palma more as like a long form reading Renaissance device rather than a digital
Speaker 7:  book Renaissance device. I buy it. Hopefully it can be that too though. Hopefully
Speaker 7:  it can create better interfaces for digital books as well, not just for long
Speaker 7:  form articles.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Yeah. And honestly like I, I have spent so many years
Speaker 2:  wondering why Amazon has not just built a decent way to read web
Speaker 2:  articles on the Kindle. And if if books just makes Amazon do that, it will
Speaker 2:  have done the world a great service. But I don't think it's ever gonna happen.
Speaker 7:  It's never gonna happen. No, no, no. Like you just have to accept that there's
Speaker 7:  a certain size of company that internally just doesn't
Speaker 7:  doesn't have the willpower Yeah. To do these things that where that, you
Speaker 7:  look at the spreadsheet and you go, what's the market cap of this? What's
Speaker 7:  the, you know, duh. And it's essentially a rounding error, you know, it's
Speaker 7:  zero and it's just not gonna happen unless
Speaker 7:  you have a C-level person who owns it. And I think with Jeff out
Speaker 7:  of Amazon, I don't know anyone there who is an avid old
Speaker 7:  gq, you know, Esquire reader or whatever, right? It's like we've gotta
Speaker 7:  make this amazing to read old gay to lease articles or whatever, you
Speaker 7:  know, it's like, yep. So thankfully we don't have to, because
Speaker 7:  the EIN technology is now trickled down to everyone else
Speaker 7:  and companies like books, which we should say, and I think it's important
Speaker 7:  to say books is a bad open source citizen, I don't know if you know about
Speaker 7:  this, but like they are using I think Android models or
Speaker 7:  Android software in a way that breaks the, the terms of the open
Speaker 7:  source license. Oh, Interesting. Like if Hacker News ever, like if a books
Speaker 7:  dev like device article comes up on Hacker News, you know, people go nuts
Speaker 7:  about this and bring it out. Sure. And I think it is, I think it is important
Speaker 7:  to bring up Yeah. Because they are effectively violating the
Speaker 7:  license and I, and I think it would be very easy for them to not violate
Speaker 7:  it. And I think we should talk about this in PO in podcasts like this and
Speaker 7:  say, Hey books, can you just be a good citizen? It's like such a dumb, easy
Speaker 7:  thing to do, why aren't you doing it? And we'd love to, you know,
Speaker 7:  it would help me even more enthusiastically recommend these
Speaker 7:  devices. You know, I, I know anecdotally I have probably sold
Speaker 7:  at least a couple hundred of these things in the last couple of months. At
Speaker 7:  least I believe it. These are people just messaging me directly. So I may,
Speaker 7:  it's probably in the thousands of folks who've bought Palmas and are using
Speaker 7:  them and in fact anyone listening to this who has bought a Palmer and has
Speaker 7:  had, you know, had an interesting experience with it, I'd love sent please
Speaker 7:  right into us. Tell us what changes you would like to see. Yeah, I would
Speaker 7:  love to, I'd love to hear what pe, how people are using these things or thinking
Speaker 7:  about it. But it does seem like we are in this moment where maybe, maybe
Speaker 7:  just maybe digital reading of long form stuff could, the interfaces
Speaker 7:  for it could change the way we interact with these libraries could
Speaker 7:  change. And it's, it's an exciting moment.
Speaker 2:  I really agree with what Craig said there. I do think this is an exciting
Speaker 2:  moment. I think there are a lot of companies out there being like, we will
Speaker 2:  replace your smartphone. And I think that's mostly ridiculous. But I also
Speaker 2:  think that there are a lot of things that can be done better than the way
Speaker 2:  our phones do them. And it's fun to watch gadgets explore that. Sometimes
Speaker 2:  they get it wrong like the humane AI pin, but there's still something to
Speaker 2:  the idea that not everything should be inside of your smartphone. I've been
Speaker 2:  using the RayBan Meta Smart Glasses as a way to take photos without sticking
Speaker 2:  my phone in my kid's face. I've been using the Apple Watch as a faster way
Speaker 2:  to set reminders or take notes and I've been using the Palmer as a way to
Speaker 2:  read and listen to stuff without the rest of my digital life getting in the
Speaker 2:  way.
Speaker 2:  thanks to a new set of chips from
Speaker 2:  the future of Windows than it once did. But we're still getting some of these
Speaker 2:  devices. I still have lots of questions. Companies basically across the
Speaker 2:  PC industry are all in on this copilot plus PC idea. We're starting
Speaker 2:  to see tons of new models, we're gonna have lots of new reviews, but personally
Speaker 2:  the ones I'm most excited about are the ones that come from Microsoft. Microsoft
Speaker 2:  has been at, I think, the forefront of Windows hardware for a pretty long
Speaker 2:  time. And with the new Surface Pro and the new Surface laptop is really
Speaker 2:  trying to, I would say, show the rest of the industry how this
Speaker 2:  copilot plus PC thing can work. So Tom Warren and
Speaker 2:  Nathan Edwards on our team have been reviewing those devices. They haven't
Speaker 2:  told me anything about how it's going and I am desperate to find out. So
Speaker 2:  I'm going to use the fact that we are here on The Vergecast to make them
Speaker 2:  tell me things about these new devices. Let's get into it. Tom Warren.
Speaker 2:  Hello. Hello. Nathan Edwards. Hello.
Speaker 1:  Hi David.
Speaker 2:  First let's just level set a little. I wanna know the Microsoft gear
Speaker 2:  you both currently have right now. Tom, what do you have in your
Speaker 2:  possession that you've been playing with?
Speaker 9:  So I have the 13 inch surface laptop, seventh
Speaker 9:  edition, not seven seventh edition.
Speaker 2:  That's very important. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  The 15 inch model as well. Okay. The laptop. And I've also
Speaker 9:  got the Surface Pro 11th
Speaker 9:  edition.
Speaker 10:  It's the 11th edition. Yeah. 11th
Speaker 9:  Edition. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  For our purposes we're just gonna call them the new ones because God help
Speaker 2:  anyone who tries to keep all these numbers in their, in their brains. Yes.
Speaker 2:  And that's both of you, so God help both of you. Nathan, you're on the pro,
Speaker 2:  which pro are you on?
Speaker 10:  I have the top of the line New pro. It's also
Speaker 10:  13 inches. It's got, they, they of course sent the tricked out version 32
Speaker 10:  gigs of ram one terabyte of storage and the
Speaker 10:  elite 8,100 processor.
Speaker 2:  So this is like, if, if there is going to be one that kicks ass, it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be this one.
Speaker 10:  Yes. This is their $2,100 without the keyboard
Speaker 10:  model.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's serious business. So I, I have a lot of
Speaker 2:  questions for both of you about both of these vices, but I feel like the
Speaker 2:  place we have to start is with the chips, right? Like that is there, there
Speaker 2:  are lots of stories of this thing, but I feel like the question most people
Speaker 2:  wanna know is like, did did Qualcomm do the thing? Here
Speaker 2:  are these things actually good. So Nathan, let's start very top of the line
Speaker 2:  and then Tom, I want to hear your more like mainstreaming experience, but
Speaker 2:  what have you, what have you seen so far Nathan? How do these things hold
Speaker 2:  up?
Speaker 10:  It does not disappoint me.
Speaker 2:  Really? Yes.
Speaker 10:  That's
Speaker 2:  So exciting.
Speaker 10:  I don't have to think most of the time I don't have to think about the fact
Speaker 10:  that it's not X 86. It's not perfect. And there are like places
Speaker 10:  in which it's like not the top runner but it's a good
Speaker 10:  laptop, it's a good laptop, a good Windows laptop with an arm
Speaker 10:  processor,
Speaker 2:  Which you like really cannot overstate how big a thing that is to be
Speaker 2:  able to say at this moment in time. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  And Tom has the Pro X and I, he's done a little bit of
Speaker 10:  like digging it out and brushing the dust off and I want to hear more on
Speaker 10:  that. But like this, I'm not fundamentally fighting the thing
Speaker 10:  except in the sense that I would be fundamentally fighting Windows anyway.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like generally with a few edge exceptions it it like just works.
Speaker 2:  Tom, has that been your experience too?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, pretty much. And I'm, I'm obviously using the
Speaker 9:  999 90 9 cent surface
Speaker 9:  laptop and that's the base model. So I've been using that one primarily
Speaker 9:  for the past week. 'cause I mainly, because we obviously didn't get these
Speaker 9:  beforehand for review embargo and all that sort of stuff, so I was
Speaker 9:  like I don't want the tricked out one. I want to test what the base model
Speaker 9:  one is because it's got 16 giga Ram 256 giga storage and
Speaker 9:  in the x plus processes, which is I think for me
Speaker 9:  now testing the, the elite is around about 20% better
Speaker 9:  performing but roughly so that that's kind of the gap. But
Speaker 9:  in real terms, if you're just using it day to day, you're probably not gonna
Speaker 9:  notice that unless you're really pushing it. But yeah, in terms of app
Speaker 9:  compatibility I'd say like you know like the
Speaker 9:  90% of the apps you're gonna use aren't gonna be emulated and the
Speaker 9:  the key one being the browser, right? Which obviously everyone kind of lives
Speaker 9:  in these days. But then outside of that, yeah there's gonna be some app
Speaker 9:  compatibility things, some weird things like Google Drive
Speaker 9:  desktop still doesn't work but that isn't necessarily because it can't emulate.
Speaker 9:  It's probably 'cause Google's just flagged it not to. So there's like these
Speaker 9:  weird things of like the past 10, 12 years of Windows
Speaker 9:  and Arm being a bit crappy coming back to sort of haunt it at this time.
Speaker 9:  But Microsoft, Qualcomm have done a quite good job at like getting these
Speaker 9:  software vendors to sort of play ball and it's definitely a lot better than
Speaker 9:  I've ever used in the past.
Speaker 2:  That is super exciting. Nathan, have you run into anything that just like
Speaker 2:  flatly didn't work?
Speaker 10:  I mean yeah, so Premier Pro does not work but they told us it wasn't gonna
Speaker 10:  work. You're gonna hate this Arc. Arc refuses to run.
Speaker 10:  That's disappointing. It's my browser of choice on both
Speaker 10:  Mac and Windows these days, although it's much better on Max still. And
Speaker 10:  they were just like, sorry we don't support ARM 64. Let us know if you want
Speaker 10:  us to, to put my name in a little form, please let me know. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Please, please let it be known that we want it to, if you're listening,
Speaker 2:  yeah we, we would like that. But I would say that alone, those are things
Speaker 2:  that presumably will get updated over time. And Tom, your point about the
Speaker 2:  history of this maybe being a problem that there are a lot of folks who were
Speaker 2:  like actually turned it off because the experience was so bad who are now
Speaker 2:  gonna have to be convinced to turn emulation stuff back on. My
Speaker 2:  hope would be if the performance is as good as you guys are describing that,
Speaker 2:  that'll start to happen fairly quickly. So even the stuff that exists hopefully
Speaker 2:  won't exist for too much longer.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And and and with the Adobe stuff like, so we've Premier Pro is quite
Speaker 9:  a funny one because they disabled it or like blocked it on the
Speaker 9:  X Elite but they forgot to do it on the X plus. So I got it installed
Speaker 9:  and then I think they realized like a day later and then it like dropped
Speaker 9:  outta my creative cloud but I still have it installed and I can understand
Speaker 9:  why they blocked it 'cause so I tried to process like a
Speaker 9:  4K, a 20, a 22nd 4K video right on on this thing.
Speaker 9:  and it was like stuttering, like I, you couldn't just play it without it
Speaker 9:  skipping and dropping frames and all that sort of stuff. I tried to explore
Speaker 9:  it and it was gonna take five minutes to export and that was like for a 22nd
Speaker 9:  four game video that's like obviously way too long. And
Speaker 9:  for comparison, this is really unfair comparison but I'm gonna make this
Speaker 9:  comparison anyway, I tried out my desktop pc, which is a 4,900
Speaker 9:  K and a 49 A and it exported in seven seconds. So
Speaker 9:  I can see why they have Premier Pro blocked on there 'cause it's not a good,
Speaker 9:  good experience. I feel like if you were trying to edit in that you would
Speaker 9:  come you like, I feel like you'd make editing mistakes just from the basic
Speaker 9:  like trying to crop a video or in the timeline and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 9:  It's just very lacky because it's obviously, yeah, it's not been optimized
Speaker 9:  and that is a heavyweight app that will hopefully be better later this year
Speaker 9:  once they release the actual ARM 64 version which they, they've promised
Speaker 9:  to.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So it, it seems like the, the performance promises
Speaker 2:  that we've gotten, some of it is like you won't notice the
Speaker 2:  difference And Nathan, it seems like that's kind of in your experience that
Speaker 2:  most of the time you don't have to think about the fact that this is an ARM
Speaker 2:  processor instead of an X 86 processor, which on its own
Speaker 2:  giant terrific win. Microsoft in particular has also made a lot of noise
Speaker 2:  about how it like beats the crap out of Apple silicon and everybody is
Speaker 2:  making large grandiose performance claims here.
Speaker 2:  Like in terms of actual raw performance, like good
Speaker 2:  enough is, is a huge deal And that's frankly I would say like that's the
Speaker 2:  benchmark and it sounds like we've mostly cleared it and that's very exciting.
Speaker 2:  How good are these actually that you've seen so far?
Speaker 10:  Well I wanna preface by saying Joan Aelius has our big benchmark
Speaker 10:  article coming in a few days. That'll be the big word on it, the official
Speaker 10:  word. But they are single core, they're not as good as
Speaker 10:  the M three at all. Okay. They do pretty well on most things
Speaker 10:  compared to the core ultra stuff and compared to
Speaker 10:  Rise N 8,000. But it's like, it's not like it's not crushing anybody.
Speaker 10:  They do, they on the reviewer's guide did this very funny
Speaker 10:  58% faster than the M three.
Speaker 10:  It is on very specifically on cbe, multi-core.
Speaker 10:  Okay. Notably it has about 50% more cores.
Speaker 10:  Each of those core is slower than the M three single core. There's just
Speaker 10:  more of them, which is, you know what Sure, yes sure fair. You did it
Speaker 10:  like good job. But it's competitive. They're competitive. Which
Speaker 10:  is more than I could say for any Snapdragon based Windows
Speaker 10:  laptop before.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Just to be in range feels like
Speaker 10:  In range. Yeah. A
Speaker 2:  Victory.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Battery life is decent.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That was the next thing I was gonna ask about because this is hopefully
Speaker 2:  the other big byproduct of switching to arm. What, what
Speaker 2:  have you seen on the Pro Battery Lifewise?
Speaker 10:  So I haven't gotten a full day of battery out of it but
Speaker 10:  I've been doing a lot of benchmarking. Okay. I haven't had like a full day
Speaker 10:  of what I would consider my normal workday. Just like
Speaker 10:  doing spreadsheets and word docs and Slack. Slack is
Speaker 10:  still a battery killer every time I look at the battery usage thing, Slack
Speaker 10:  is right up there. Maybe not as bad as it used to be on Arm
Speaker 2:  Slack is pretty bad on everything to be fair. It is. We should just do an
Speaker 2:  episode at some point where we just sit and yell about all the apps that
Speaker 2:  are grossly un inefficient and messy on computers and
Speaker 2:  we would spend a lot of time talking about Slack. I suspect
Speaker 10:  It's funny. It does to the computer what it does to our attention span
Speaker 2:  Just slowly destroys it. Yeah. Tom, what are you seeing on the laptop?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, really, really good battery life. To be honest. On the first day I
Speaker 9:  was like working outside and it was like I had this screen at a hundred percent
Speaker 9:  brightness. I downloading like multiple steam games, doing video calls,
Speaker 9:  working in Photoshop, all that sort of stuff. So I'd say that was probably
Speaker 9:  more than my sort of average workday of, of using a laptop.
Speaker 9:  But I still got around about seven hours battery life on that day. And then
Speaker 9:  in the evening I charged it up to like a hundred percent. I was using it
Speaker 9:  indoors at like, you know, 50% brightness. You didn't need the a hundred
Speaker 9:  percent brightness and I think in around four hours it
Speaker 9:  only drained 25%. So Okay. I was like, okay, that's
Speaker 9:  good. And then I closed the lid and it had like 70 whatever percent
Speaker 9:  remaining at like 11:00 PM and I woke up the next day, did some stuff and
Speaker 9:  then I ended up grabbing the laptop about midday and it still had that 70%.
Speaker 9:  It was like, I think I went to, went to sleep at like 72 and it had
Speaker 9:  70% and I was like, okay, that's, that's good as well because
Speaker 2:  That's pretty exciting
Speaker 9:  Half the time. Yeah. Half the time you close a lid on Windows laptop, you're
Speaker 9:  kind of like, is it gonna wake like just keep this thing plugged in 'cause
Speaker 9:  it's not actually gonna, it's gonna just drain the battery overnight.
Speaker 9:  So I've never seen it do that. It's usually like one or 2% it
Speaker 9:  drains overnight. Yeah. And and to be honest, I haven't left it long enough
Speaker 9:  for like, you know, five or six nights to see whether that is one or 2% per
Speaker 9:  day or if that's just a, you know, every time you sort of
Speaker 9:  sleep at. But yeah, I, the battery life is phenomenal as long
Speaker 9:  as you are in the native apps. Yeah. As long as you're doing sort of the
Speaker 9:  lightweight stuff. So if I, if I had a day, I think I had a day where
Speaker 9:  I was working predominantly in like Slack and Discord and Chrome
Speaker 9:  and, and WhatsApp, you know, not not too heavy lifting apps
Speaker 9:  and I think I charged it and I think I got sort of
Speaker 9:  sort of like something like six hours and it, and it was about down
Speaker 9:  down 30% in those six hours.
Speaker 2:  Wow, okay.
Speaker 9:  Which is pretty Yeah. Which is quite surprising. So Yeah. But, but then
Speaker 9:  if you start downloading stuffing on Steam, like, which is an emulated app.
Speaker 9:  Sure. Like I, I could notice it drop by like five
Speaker 9:  to 10% just from downloading a big game on Steam.
Speaker 2:  Not even playing, just downloading.
Speaker 9:  Just downloading
Speaker 2:  Just as soon as it needs to do an emulated app. Yeah. You can feel it working
Speaker 2:  harder
Speaker 9:  And, and steam's quite vigorous when it's downloading and unpacking games.
Speaker 9:  True on the CPU. Yeah. So it's understandable it's done that, but yeah,
Speaker 9:  it's emulated. So I'd, I'd be very curious to see if there's ever gonna be
Speaker 9:  a on 64 STEAM client and whether that would improve that. I'm sure there
Speaker 9:  will
Speaker 2:  Be. Yeah. It feels like it's coming but it seems like to me the, the, the
Speaker 2:  two levels of battery tests are like, the first is
Speaker 2:  sort of the, the cross country flight test where it's like I can, I can use
Speaker 2:  it in the airport and then like watch two movies on it
Speaker 2:  and then get to wherever I'm going without it dying. That's like, that's
Speaker 2:  test number one. It feels like any laptop that can't pass that test sucks.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then there's the like use it all day and you know,
Speaker 2:  use it and don't charge till the next morning. And this doesn't seem like
Speaker 2:  it's quite gotten there, but it does seem like it probably passes the cross
Speaker 2:  country flight test, which again for a pretty powerful Windows laptop is
Speaker 2:  a big victory and at least it's like it's not as good as Apple, which
Speaker 2:  is pretty easily in the like I can use it all day and then charge it at lunch
Speaker 2:  the next day with a lot of things. This doesn't feel like it's quite there
Speaker 2:  but it's almost there. And that's something
Speaker 9:  I think it probably is.
Speaker 2:  Okay if you're not doing the emulated stuff.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. As long as you're not doing emulated stuff. I think so. Like I don't
Speaker 9:  do the battery tests that other sort of reviews do where they just have a
Speaker 9:  bunch of tabs or a bunch of videos going because that stuff is, it's not
Speaker 9:  real world. You know, that's the stuff that Microsoft always says, you know,
Speaker 9:  15, 20 hours of video
Speaker 2:  Offline video playback. Like who is that for? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's like, but I do the real world stuff and I think like I charged
Speaker 9:  it on Friday and I used it a bunch over the weekend and then
Speaker 9:  I haven't charged it since Friday and it's 1220 7%.
Speaker 2:  Oh, alright then. Yeah. We're onto something there. Nathan. It sounds like
Speaker 2:  the pro is not quite as good though. It doesn't, it doesn't quite hang as
Speaker 2:  well.
Speaker 10:  I would say I haven't had the time, I haven't had the like extended amounts
Speaker 10:  of time to test except it was, yeah lemme tell you a CBE Murders
Speaker 10:  Murders the battery life as does actually what killed it was Blender. So
Speaker 10:  if you use Blender, don't get a Snapdragon thing yet. Like if that's part
Speaker 10:  of your workflow, it is emulated and it's not hitting the GPU
Speaker 10:  course at all. It's just pure CPU compute, it's brute forcing it,
Speaker 10:  it takes oh boy a long time and it's not pretty. That
Speaker 10:  will like where we're at now, like if there's an app that you need that's
Speaker 10:  not native yet, that's not to say this won't be a good choice, but I
Speaker 10:  wouldn't go for it yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And also if ever a setup was going to set your computer on fire
Speaker 2:  Blender running on the CPU would be would be the answer. Yes. I suspect
Speaker 10:  It got, it got toasty.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I would imagine.
Speaker 10:  But not on the keyboard. 'cause that's detachable.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. Okay. Wait, I wanna get into all the AI stuff, but we have to talk
Speaker 2:  about that for a minute. I totally forgot about that. This is very exciting.
Speaker 2:  Tell me about this new keyboard setup and how you've been using it.
Speaker 10:  So the Surface Pro has a detachable keyboard. It connects by pogo
Speaker 10:  pins. That is the way it's always been. You can pull it off. It's like a
Speaker 10:  little folio thing. This year. They finally put a battery in it.
Speaker 10:  Not all of them, but there's the, the pro flex keyboard. It's Bluetooth,
Speaker 10:  it's got a battery, you want to take it off, you pull it off and it
Speaker 10:  still works. And that feels like, obviously this is the way
Speaker 10:  detachable keyboards ought to be. Yes. Like often they're just like, here
Speaker 10:  is a Bluetooth keyboard or here is a pogo pin keyboard and you sort of
Speaker 10:  have to pick. Pogo pin is great because it doesn't run outta
Speaker 10:  battery. But also if you're in a situation where you want to detach the
Speaker 10:  keyboard, then all of a sudden it's dead. But I love this thing.
Speaker 2:  So how have you actually used it in practice? Like what? Give me the, the
Speaker 2:  detached use case.
Speaker 10:  Well for example, for ergonomics, if you want to put the screen on like
Speaker 10:  a big pile of books to get it higher up and keep your keyboard down below,
Speaker 10:  You can do that. That's kind of the use case as
Speaker 2:  Someone I've spent years with like the, I would have the screen in the middle
Speaker 2:  and I would put my laptop up on a stand next to it as kind of a second display.
Speaker 2:  Having, being able to use the surface keyboard as the keyboard down
Speaker 2:  on my desk for that. Incredible.
Speaker 10:  I will say that it is $350 And. if you, if your
Speaker 10:  use case is like you're mostly at home with the thing running this
Speaker 10:  as like your desktop basically, and then you shove it in a bag once in a
Speaker 10:  while and take it with you. You can buy a lot of really nice keyboards.
Speaker 10:  Yes. For $350 and then still have room in the budget for like
Speaker 10:  the regular flex keyboard to take with you. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You can buy several really nice keyboards for $350.
Speaker 10:  You can buy one really nice keyboard.
Speaker 2:  You can also buy one. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It's like a fur, a third of the price of the surface light
Speaker 2:  As well. I know, it's nuts. Yeah, it's truly nuts.
Speaker 10:  It's $350 or 500 bucks basically with the slim
Speaker 10:  pen. And like many people consider a keyboard to be an important part of
Speaker 10:  a laptop.
Speaker 2:  Many people are saying
Speaker 10:  Yeah, but Microsoft their, their big thing is like, listen, we give you
Speaker 10:  options. You can have the regular pogo pin one You can have the Bluetooth
Speaker 10:  one. If you already have a flex keyboard from a previous Surface pro You
Speaker 10:  can just use that. It's backwards compatible. It's fine. Yeah. So like I
Speaker 10:  used to be like, oh why, why? This isn't really a
Speaker 10:  $999 laptop. It's 1200 bucks once you have the keyboard. But like I
Speaker 10:  do actually appreciate the optionality.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no I, I totally buy it. Is there any other hardware stuff we should
Speaker 2:  talk about? I feel like for the most part the hardware is as it has been
Speaker 2:  and it's still pretty good. I guess the OLED screen is new. The old screen
Speaker 2:  is nice. Is that exciting? Has that changed your life in any meaningful way?
Speaker 10:  It doesn't change my life. I mean, so it is 120 hertz variable.
Speaker 10:  It goes up to 600 knits and then I think 900 knits of peak brightness for
Speaker 10:  HDR. Right. It's a nice screen. I will say 50% brightness or whatever, not
Speaker 10:  quite enough. I keep having to crank it up a little bit and it does have
Speaker 10:  a little faint grain to it at peak brightness where You can see the, the
Speaker 10:  touch sensors in the panel. Several have noticed this. We were
Speaker 10:  talking back channelings like Microsoft was like, Hmm, we haven't noticed.
Speaker 10:  And several readers like,
Speaker 2:  They're like, don't worry about it. You're not seeing what you think.
Speaker 10:  Fine. It's fine. It doesn't bother me. WeCh noticed it. But no,
Speaker 10:  it's a nice thing. I will say you're still in Donga life. Two
Speaker 10:  USBC ports. They do still have the surface connector on the other side,
Speaker 10:  which is like a magnetic proprietary connector. Which again, Microsoft is
Speaker 10:  like, listen, you wanna charge with that? That's fine. You can charge via
Speaker 10:  USBC. That's fine. I have it connected to my, usually I have it connected
Speaker 10:  to my like 32 inch 4K monitor with A-U-S-B-C
Speaker 10:  and it powers the laptop at full speed. It runs all that stuff. But
Speaker 10:  right now when you're not hooked in two USB ports, seaports
Speaker 10:  is still pretty limiting. Yeah, especially 'cause there's no headphone Jack.
Speaker 2:  I, yeah, it's not enough. I agree. I've gotten used to it as a MacBook Air
Speaker 2:  user for years. But then yeah, every, every time
Speaker 2:  I am forced to encounter a computer with more, it's like, oh, this is delightful.
Speaker 2:  Like I have a, I have a surface laptop studio from a couple of years ago
Speaker 2:  and that thing just feels like it has infinite ports compared to this one.
Speaker 10:  It's just nice. Like right now we're, so we're recording and I have my
Speaker 10:  headphones plugged into U-A-U-S-B-C dongle and that takes up one
Speaker 10:  port and I have our microphone plugged into USBC and that takes up the other
Speaker 10:  port and that's all the ports I'm charging from the surface
Speaker 10:  connector. So I'm glad that that's there. That's it. Yes, I have dongles
Speaker 10:  and gizmos and gadgets golo, but like it'd be nice.
Speaker 9:  What do you think of the track pad?
Speaker 10:  It's fine. It's a track pad. I don't hate it. I don't love it.
Speaker 9:  So I started using it today after using the bigger surface
Speaker 9:  laptop track pad for the last week. And I keep hitting the bottom of the
Speaker 9:  key, like the, 'cause it's, they've made it vertically smaller.
Speaker 10:  Yes, it is a little compressed. It's small. You're right.
Speaker 9:  I don't like that because, because the, the slim pen is always on display
Speaker 9:  now as well up top.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So you've lost a little bit of, they've, they've just sort of shifted
Speaker 9:  the keyboard down accordingly. So,
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I don't love that.
Speaker 10:  The little cradle for the s slim pen does charge the pen, which I do like,
Speaker 10:  that's nice because I have an air with the new pencil pro,
Speaker 10:  that thing just goes flying all over the place. Like it magnets to the top
Speaker 10:  to charge. Yes. But it just, it's just every time I pick it up, the pen
Speaker 10:  flies off into the distance. I'm amazed I haven't lost it yet.
Speaker 2:  You might have a magnet problem but that's, that's for another day. So wait,
Speaker 2:  let, let's just talk about the AI stuff here for a few minutes before we
Speaker 2:  switch gears. The promise of all of this stuff is that it
Speaker 2:  will do on device AI things that will make everything wonderful.
Speaker 2:  Recall obviously its own story, not here. We'll worry about that
Speaker 2:  another time. What stuff have you guys noticed in the course of testing
Speaker 2:  these things that feels like it is part of the sort of AI PC future?
Speaker 2:  I just wanna say as soon as I said that Nathan's webcam started moving
Speaker 2:  around, which I suspect is an answer to my question,
Speaker 10:  A lot of gimmicks and a couple slightly useful features.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Hit me with the useful ones first.
Speaker 10:  So the Windows studio effects on the webcam, some of them
Speaker 10:  are kind of nice like, so they, they use this absurd like ultra wide
Speaker 10:  webcam on the surface pro that like makes you look like you're being looked
Speaker 10:  at by a 4-year-old. You're looming over them and so they, they use
Speaker 10:  the studio effects to crop that down to like center you and it follows you
Speaker 10:  around the frame. Like you've got your dedicated camera person like the
Speaker 10:  Nest hub Max does, it's also got fake eye contact thing like Nvidia
Speaker 10:  uses.
Speaker 2:  Oh no, that stuff creeps me out.
Speaker 10:  I mean yeah, it's creepy.
Speaker 2:  It feels like a good idea. It's one of those things that like once that's
Speaker 2:  not creepy it'll be great. But at least everything I've seen
Speaker 2:  so far it, it veers toward creepy.
Speaker 10:  Is it creeping you out right now?
Speaker 2:  Now you pointed it wasn't until you pointed it out and now I feel like I'm
Speaker 2:  looking too deep into your eyes through a webcam.
Speaker 10:  So there's that. It does have live captioning, which is on device and it
Speaker 10:  can caption any video that's playing on your computer. Oh that's
Speaker 10:  cool. I tried it a couple times. I tried it in a video call
Speaker 10:  with Antonio and with Joanna and it translated
Speaker 10:  Italian like spoken on the fly pretty well. But it was
Speaker 10:  like, you know, where's the library level Italian? Sure. I tried playing
Speaker 10:  it on Netflix. I was watching Delicious in Dungeon. You'll be shocked that
Speaker 10:  it could not keep up nor did it match the quality of the
Speaker 10:  actual human translated subtitles.
Speaker 2:  But it's serviceable in a pinch I guess
Speaker 10:  It seems to be okay. Little slow. But like it's cool that it can do that
Speaker 10:  on device. That's a cool use of the NPU. I've not been that impressed
Speaker 10:  with any of the image creation or co-creation stuff, although
Speaker 10:  I'm curious if Tom has a different experience.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Tom have you, have you seen any features that have jumped out to you?
Speaker 9:  I mean there's not a lot, let's be honest that that stuff feels like a
Speaker 9:  bit of a side show to the, the windows and arm stuff really. I don't know
Speaker 9:  why they need to make such a big deal out of it because it, it's,
Speaker 9:  it's like they're laying the foundations for this stuff but it's not quite
Speaker 9:  there yet. So, so you've got like paint in paint, they've got image
Speaker 9:  co-creator, which is, which is interesting on the on the surface laptop because
Speaker 9:  one thing I should say is that it doesn't support pen and per anymore. Like
Speaker 9:  whereas you could use this slim pen before on the previous module, you can't.
Speaker 9:  Now the image co-create of feature here pretty much relies on you
Speaker 9:  drawing what you want to see, which obviously You can do on a trap pad, but
Speaker 9:  it's kind of a little bit not the best way to, to draw. You just wanna do
Speaker 9:  it on the screen what you'd have to touch. So yeah,
Speaker 9:  that feature seems a little bit less useful than on the Pro
Speaker 9:  if I'm honest, because it's just way more easy just to draw. But even still,
Speaker 9:  it just uses like a, a local AI model, which I think
Speaker 9:  it's using. Is this stable diffusion? It's using I think,
Speaker 10:  Yeah, they told us it was stable diffusion
Speaker 9:  And the results are pretty bad. They terrible, honest.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I
Speaker 2:  Mean what would you expect from paint? I like, I, I don't know how high my
Speaker 2:  high, my bar for quality would really be there.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I tried to draw, draw like a dog on a beach with a ball
Speaker 9:  and it drew the dog fine, but it just refused to pick up the fact that I'd
Speaker 9:  drawn a ball and in the prompt I'd said I wanted a ball. It was just like
Speaker 9:  this lonely dog looking all sad on the beach and it just, yeah, it just
Speaker 9:  looked junk. Anyway. But even though it's using a local AI
Speaker 9:  model, you still need to be connected to the internet. And I know this because
Speaker 9:  when I first did Hands on May 20th, you could turn off the
Speaker 9:  wifi and do the image creation in in a
Speaker 9:  photos app it and it had no filters. So you could put Bill
Speaker 9:  Gates, you know, whatever, you could do the typical Mario stuff and it would
Speaker 9:  generate it and it was really bad 'cause it's stable diffusion, it wasn't
Speaker 9:  very good but you could do it. But they've changed that now. So you have
Speaker 9:  to sign in, you have to be online even though it's using a AI local
Speaker 9:  model to do that.
Speaker 10:  The same is true for co-creator. Yeah. Like it generates it on device with
Speaker 10:  the limited model that it has and then it runs it by the safety filters
Speaker 10:  just in case.
Speaker 9:  That's right. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  But it, it could just, why not just send it off to a more powerful model
Speaker 10:  somewhere else?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's an odd way of doing that. You're actually doing all the
Speaker 2:  hard stuff in the place where you wouldn't wanna do the hard stuff. It's
Speaker 2:  a very weird system in general though. It feels like the read on these so
Speaker 2:  far, at least to me seems like the basics are good,
Speaker 2:  right? That like Tom, what you're saying is that the Windows Unarm thing
Speaker 2:  is a much bigger deal that it's like, okay we've now done the thing that
Speaker 2:  yeah, windows now works pretty well on Arm, we'll we'll solve some of these
Speaker 2:  last remaining apps and use cases. But the question of like,
Speaker 2:  so what do we do with that? Doesn't really seem like it's been answered yet
Speaker 2:  that like the, and and I guess maybe that's supposed to be recall, right?
Speaker 2:  That like this is what we get with all this new stuff, but the the
Speaker 2:  like what is now possible and cool and new and exciting
Speaker 2:  because we've made Windows on arm work and because these Qualcomm chips are
Speaker 2:  good, it doesn't really feel like either of you have found a super exciting
Speaker 2:  compelling answer to that yet. Is that fair?
Speaker 9:  No, I I think it's because they're pretty much laying the groundwork for
Speaker 9:  this stuff. Yeah. So it's kind of like build it and they'll come. That's
Speaker 9:  the, that's their approach, right? And obviously recall is
Speaker 9:  supposed to be the flagship feature here, but obviously we can't, we can't
Speaker 9:  try it yet. So I mean I have been using it for like two weeks on the surface
Speaker 9:  Pro X when it was, you know, you could hack it to, to get it working
Speaker 9:  so I got some falls on it. But yeah, like I feel like even
Speaker 9:  with that, it's not like a massive selling point like that
Speaker 9:  that's, that's not really, I don't think the reason you're gonna buy this,
Speaker 9:  this laptop, it's mainly 'cause you want a good performing laptop
Speaker 9:  that's and light and it actually has good battery life, you know? And that's
Speaker 9:  as a base model at 999 bucks is like pretty
Speaker 9:  compelling. Yeah. Like it's a hundred dollars less than a Mapa M three model.
Speaker 9:  That in itself is compelling enough I think to get people to buy it. So I
Speaker 9:  don't, I don't know why Microsoft had to kind of like put these AI tricks
Speaker 9:  in there that aren't, they're not really that impressive maybe recall.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, sure. That might be impressive for controversial
Speaker 2:  Nathan, is that where you've landed to kind of very good device, nice job,
Speaker 2:  but there is, this is not like a brand new day for the PC era
Speaker 2:  yet.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I mean I think that all of the AI stuff is, they have
Speaker 10:  this processor and they're trying to figure out reasons to use it. It's
Speaker 10:  free real estate. They're looking for something to do with AI because
Speaker 10:  AI is buzzy, it's on the chips anyway. They've got the NPUs, what are you,
Speaker 10:  you gotta find something to do. But the reason to buy this thing, yeah,
Speaker 10:  like Tom said, it's got good battery life. It's a, it's nice.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, like it's, it's it's, it's a third option. It's a good option.
Speaker 10:  Not for gaming but for like normal productivity stuff, like it seems like
Speaker 10:  a good value. Yeah. And yeah, I just kind of ignore the AI
Speaker 10:  stuff for now. If somebody will find something useful to do with it, maybe,
Speaker 10:  probably like they've got the compute there even just as it is. If
Speaker 10:  that, if that module wasn't there at all, I don't think I'd notice and it
Speaker 10:  wouldn't change my opinion that much.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. I'm sitting here looking at my new iPad Pro
Speaker 2:  and I feel precisely exactly the same way about it.
Speaker 10:  I tried to work on an iPad a couple weeks ago on vacation and I hated
Speaker 10:  every second of it and I was like, why can't they just, you know
Speaker 10:  the refrain. Oh yeah, just put Mac OS on it, whatever. Just put a real
Speaker 10:  operating system on it. I will say I got the Surface Pro and I opened it
Speaker 10:  up and I was like a real operating system. I can have two Windows side
Speaker 10:  by side. I can run something in the background, I can do stuff, I can
Speaker 10:  download utilities. I have a clipboard manager, you know what? And I
Speaker 10:  can still watch Netflix if I really want to.
Speaker 2:  It's not a bad setup. Alex Kranz has been running around for two months saying
Speaker 2:  everybody who thinks they want an iPad Pro actually wants a surface. And
Speaker 2:  I think she's not crazy about that. No,
Speaker 10:  She's not wrong. I mean you very much still are using Windows
Speaker 10:  11 and therefore you're on, you're like, especially on a surface,
Speaker 10:  you're like fully locked into Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  Alright, this is actually a good segue into a question we got on the hotline.
Speaker 2:  We need to take a break really fast. Can you guys stick around and help me
Speaker 2:  answer this question? Yes,
Speaker 10:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  All right, cool. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast hotline as
Speaker 2:  always, the number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. Send all of your questions. You
Speaker 2:  can also email vergecast at The Verge dot com. Send us all of your questions.
Speaker 2:  The weirder the better. We've gotten some weird ones and I enjoy it very
Speaker 2:  much. This week we have a question about precisely what we've been talking
Speaker 2:  about and it comes from Dean.
Speaker 16:  Hey, my name is Dean, I'm from Northern Virginia. The
Speaker 16:  question that I have is regarding Windows 11 computers
Speaker 16:  and what's gonna happen in the market now that the new Windows on
Speaker 16:  arm units are being released. Will the market be
Speaker 16:  some new style Windows 11 and some of the
Speaker 16:  old ones still on the market or do you think soon
Speaker 16:  the X 86 architects will be completely gone and people will only
Speaker 16:  be able to purchase the So-called AI PCs
Speaker 16:  and I was wondering if there'll be a massive, you think there'll be a massive
Speaker 16:  fire sale as the X 86 inventory gets
Speaker 16:  cleared out. Do you think there'll be a high end, low end situation where
Speaker 16:  the new architecture will be at the high end and the X 86 will be at the
Speaker 16:  low end? Just wondering how you see the PC market shaking out once
Speaker 16:  the AI PCs, windows on arm PCs come on
Speaker 16:  the market. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right Nathan, you were making several faces during that. Tell me what
Speaker 2:  you think.
Speaker 10:  I do not think that Snapdragon, I don't think that ARM is going to wholesale
Speaker 10:  replace X 86 for Windows computers. Certainly not on the low
Speaker 10:  end because at least for now Microsoft has mandated 16
Speaker 10:  gigs of RAM and I think it's 2 56 gigs of storage. And the cheapest
Speaker 10:  copilot plus PC we've seen so far is about a grand. I don't
Speaker 10:  think we've seen anything under the 9 99 mark at the moment. They don't
Speaker 10:  really have anything that can compete with like a $400 Windows laptop on
Speaker 10:  price, nor do they have anything for gaming. They don't work right now
Speaker 10:  with dedicated GPUs. The internal GPUs are not
Speaker 10:  for gaming at all. No, I mean You can do some casual stuff but
Speaker 10:  they're not gonna high wholesale replace. I don't think it's gonna be a
Speaker 10:  high low either because I think there's still gonna be your high end X 86
Speaker 10:  stuff, not just for gaming but for anything that requires serious graphical
Speaker 10:  processing. Also compatibility issues. Like
Speaker 10:  I think this is gonna end up at best. It'll be a third option at the
Speaker 10:  soda fountain and I think a good option for a lot of people, especially
Speaker 10:  for the productivity thin and light space. But yeah, we have a lot of unknowns
Speaker 10:  about how Intel's next processor architecture is gonna go
Speaker 10:  lunar lake or Lake and Tom I think can speak much better to that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Tom, I'm curious your read on this, because you've been reporting a
Speaker 2:  lot on how bullish Microsoft is on all of this and
Speaker 2:  how much kind of muscle and marketing weight it's putting behind this. And
Speaker 2:  I feel like if I were to squint at it a little, I could imagine a world in
Speaker 2:  which Microsoft is really excited about, you know, arm being the future of
Speaker 2:  everything on Windows. What is your sense of where we're headed there? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  I think it's, look, they obviously tried to start doing this since 2012 and
Speaker 9:  it's been a long time coming and I think this is the beginning of a transition.
Speaker 9:  I, I don't know if it will fully, you know, displace Intel and a MD,
Speaker 9:  but I do wonder if, if a MD really has much of a market in the
Speaker 9:  laptop side of things going forward 'cause they're always a second choice
Speaker 9:  anyway and now this kind of, does this make them a third choice? I don't
Speaker 9:  know. Like it's, it's, it's gonna be interesting to see, to see how that
Speaker 9:  shakes out. But then Qualcomm are about, about to rev their chips next year
Speaker 9:  as well, so, which will probably be coming around about the same time as
Speaker 9:  we see M four MacBooks. So that's gonna be interesting. So I think this is,
Speaker 9:  this is a train that's not gonna slow down now. It's kicked off the way it
Speaker 9:  should have done originally or at least a few years ago anyway. And
Speaker 9:  I think it's, it's definitely not gonna slow down. I would, I wouldn't be
Speaker 9:  surprised if we see a lot more sort of
Speaker 9:  PCs and and cheaper ones in like sort of like the 20 20, 25, 20 26
Speaker 9:  era. So, so
Speaker 2:  It, it seems like best case scenario is not
Speaker 2:  that arm wins, but that this just makes everything more
Speaker 2:  exciting and more competitive, right? That Intel has to
Speaker 2:  get its act together because there's real competition and so it starts doing
Speaker 2:  better and a MD starts doing better and all of a sudden we have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  really good options instead of a bunch of, I would say increasingly
Speaker 2:  non-competitive options, which is where we've been for a while now thanks
Speaker 2:  to Intel. I also wonder about that because then it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  how do you make a Windows that works with everything all of these ways?
Speaker 2:  So I guess Nathan is the best outcome here that we get one
Speaker 2:  winner or the other in some meaningful way because it'll like make the software
Speaker 2:  better and make everything make more sense. Or should we, you know, let a
Speaker 2:  thousand chip flowers bloom and everything will be fine.
Speaker 10:  I mean that's windows isn't it? Let a chip a thousand flowers bloom,
Speaker 10:  like the whole thing backwards compatibility forward. Its compatibility
Speaker 10:  sideways, compatibility like, but
Speaker 2:  That's been part of the challenge, right? Like I think that if you want to
Speaker 2:  describe whatever mess exists inside of Windows, I think You can ascribe
Speaker 2:  a lot of it to that exact thing. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  You can, I mean I don't think if there's gonna be a winner, an
Speaker 10:  overall winner, I don't know, I just don't see it. There's so much on
Speaker 10:  X 86, I don't think it would be arm, like they don't have the
Speaker 10:  pull, they're, they're beholden to huge enterprise deployments
Speaker 10:  in a way that Mac frankly is not. They can be like, Hey, heads up
Speaker 10:  we're switching silicon entirely, right? And
Speaker 10:  you're gonna have to deal with it and I don't think
Speaker 10:  Microsoft can or wants to do that, but yeah, may maybe this makes things
Speaker 10:  more complicated for developers. They're like, okay great, now I gotta make
Speaker 10:  an arm 64 version two.
Speaker 2:  So it does seem like the, the idea that these copilot
Speaker 2:  plus PCs are going to like immediately sweep the market and be so much better
Speaker 2:  that they're going to like take over, at least from y'all's experience
Speaker 2:  so far, it doesn't seem like we're there yet that this is what
Speaker 2:  we have is like a meaningful new competitor, not an entire
Speaker 2:  new paradigm that is so much, drastically better than anything we've had
Speaker 2:  before. Maybe we'll get there, maybe buying an ARM thing right
Speaker 2:  now is a smart future proofing decision as this stuff gets better. But it
Speaker 2:  doesn't sound like either of you would sort of going away say,
Speaker 2:  this is the obvious new future and everything else is going to be relegated
Speaker 2:  to the side quickly. Right? Is that fair?
Speaker 9:  It's definitely important to point out that the, the copilot plus stuff
Speaker 9:  isn't just arm true. Yeah. So there is gonna be Intel and a MD ones
Speaker 9:  coming and even even like that listener who asked the question
Speaker 9:  like, is is this gonna be like a transition? There's gonna be a fire sale?
Speaker 9:  No. Like that's not really gonna happen because essentially the premium
Speaker 9:  end of the market is gonna be all copilot plus PCs from now on. Like that's
Speaker 9:  just the, the standard thing apart from like maybe the gaming laptops are
Speaker 9:  slightly different, but even some of those are gonna be copilot PCs. We've,
Speaker 9:  we've seen those from Nvidia and a
Speaker 2:  still just like this much theoretical, we don't have quite the features.
Speaker 2:  We don't have Intel's
Speaker 2:  The Verge dot com. I'm gonna have a story about the Daylight DC one probably
Speaker 2:  sometime this week. So keep an eye out for that. We'll put some links in
Speaker 2:  the show notes. But as always read The Verge dot com. It's a cool website.
Speaker 2:  And, if you have thoughts, feelings, questions,
Speaker 3:  Expand your world with meta AI. Now on
Speaker 3:  Instagram, WhatsApp, Facebook, and Messenger.