# Transcript
ID: ade6240d-c72a-4842-be37-07531966a6cc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4996903728059485304/3063947398153752635/s93290-US-4460s-1730804571.mp3
Description: November 6th marks 10 years to the day since Amazon surprise-launched a new, cylindrical device called the Echo. It introduced the world to smart speakers, and to the idea that you might be able to get stuff done just by shouting aloud in your living room. But a decade in, what has Alexa really accomplished? The Verge's Jennifer Pattison Tuohy joins the show to talk through the history of Alexa, Amazon's struggles to improve and extend its voice assistant, and the promise of a language model overhaul that might in theory make Alexa far more useful. There's a chance Alexa's second decade might be even more interesting than the first.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Farfield Microphones.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here updating maybe the single
Speaker 1:  most important list in my life. I'm a person who thinks
Speaker 1:  enlists If. you haven't figured that out from listening to their show in
Speaker 1:  recent years. I have a list of all of the stuff that I have
Speaker 1:  to do. I have lists for all of my like frequent flyer accounts.
Speaker 1:  Everything is bullet points, everything is lists. It's just how my brand
Speaker 1:  works. But the list that is the most important to me is one I've been
Speaker 1:  keeping for the last several years, and it's called How to Be a
Speaker 1:  Grownup. So I'm sure I've complained about this on the show before, but they
Speaker 1:  never tell you when you're a kid that being an adult is just like a series
Speaker 1:  of small maintenance tasks and none of them are very hard, but they're
Speaker 1:  impossible to remember to do. And because you don't do them, things
Speaker 1:  break horribly. So over the years, as I've discovered each of these
Speaker 1:  tasks, I've added it to the list and I've added reminders so that now
Speaker 1:  at intervals, every three months, let's say I get one that's like, Hey, change
Speaker 1:  the air filter in the furnace so that the air isn't disgusting in
Speaker 1:  your house. And all of these tasks are like quick and simple. It's just
Speaker 1:  remembering to do them or even that they're a thing you're supposed to do
Speaker 1:  is the problem. The most recent one, by the way, is
Speaker 1:  remember to change the air filter on the dehumidifier that I
Speaker 1:  put in the laundry room because the laundry room stinks because of all the
Speaker 1:  moisture. Like there are like eight grownup tasks that backed all
Speaker 1:  the way into change the air filter. So now every couple of months
Speaker 1:  I have a task that is going to remind me to change the air filter, or at
Speaker 1:  least just like hose it down so that the laundry room doesn't stink.
Speaker 1:  This is being an adult. It's not that much fun. But here we are anyway.
Speaker 1:  We are not here to talk about lists or dehumidifiers. We are here to talk
Speaker 1:  about Alexa. So this week, Wednesday specifically, is the
Speaker 1:  10 year anniversary of the very first Amazon Echo. You might
Speaker 1:  remember the one that kinda looked like a can of tennis balls or like a Pringles
Speaker 1:  can. It had the blue ring, it had the far field microphone in a
Speaker 1:  surprising way. It was like a fully formed vision for a new
Speaker 1:  way of computing. And 10 years later, in a strange
Speaker 1:  way, I think it has actually been both more and less
Speaker 1:  transformative than we might have expected. And so we're gonna spend the
Speaker 1:  whole hour with Gen Tui talking through all of that. How
Speaker 1:  far have we gotten? Where is left to go? Is this actually the right
Speaker 1:  path for the future of computing? Alexa got a lot of people excited.
Speaker 1:  Google with Google Assistant has made huge moves towards this
Speaker 1:  same kind of thing. Siri was around before Alexa,
Speaker 1:  but has changed a lot because of Alexa, I think. And now with ai we
Speaker 1:  have this giant push towards something very similar. And
Speaker 1:  so the question as always is, is this what we want? Is this the
Speaker 1:  right answer? And what can we learn from the first 10 years of Alexa
Speaker 1:  about what it'll take to get there? We're gonna get to all of that, but I
Speaker 1:  should just warn you before we start, turn off your Alexa devices. I'm sure
Speaker 1:  I've set them off several times already and for that I'm very sorry, but
Speaker 1:  we are going to say that word So, so, so many times
Speaker 1:  in the next hour, go on a walk, put on headphones,
Speaker 1:  I don't know, like put pillows around you so that you're in just a little
Speaker 1:  fort where it's you and The Vergecast. Do what you gotta do, but turn the
Speaker 1:  speakers off. 'cause otherwise it's gonna, it's gonna get rough out there.
Speaker 1:  I have also set mine off two times since I've been sitting here.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna get through it together. Friends, all that is coming up in just
Speaker 1:  a second. But first, literally I have to go turn off 30 or 40 devices
Speaker 1:  or else this is gonna get really, really, really messy. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. All right, let's just get into Alexa stuff. But before we do,
Speaker 1:  let me just really quickly set the scene. So it's
Speaker 1:  November 6th, 2014, 10 years ago this Wednesday,
Speaker 1:  The Verge dot com. It's a website. We're like three years old and
Speaker 1:  all of a sudden Amazon just drops this
Speaker 1:  thing on its website. It's, it was in the morning of that
Speaker 1:  day and it just appeared. Let me just read you the headline from our
Speaker 1:  story. This is at 11:56 AM on
Speaker 1:  November 6th, 2014. It's by Chris Welch. And I love this headline very much.
Speaker 1:  It says, Amazon just surprised everyone with a crazy speaker that talks to
Speaker 1:  you, kind of tells you everything you need to know, right? The
Speaker 1:  thing was called Echo, it was priced at $199.
Speaker 1:  You could buy one for $99. If, you were a prime member. And If,
Speaker 1:  you got an invite. It, it was very odd thing. We'd never
Speaker 1:  really seen anything like it before. And going back and reading over
Speaker 1:  those early days, it's very funny to see the
Speaker 1:  reaction to these things that it was like, why does this exist? What is it
Speaker 1:  gonna be for? Why do I have this? And the big idea from
Speaker 1:  Amazon was not voice assistance in general,
Speaker 1:  but that it could be a different finite
Speaker 1:  physical thing, that it could be a piece of furniture in your house and that
Speaker 1:  that might change how you use it.
Speaker 1:  I think that kind of worked. Amazon was right about a lot of things, but
Speaker 1:  it was also wrong about a lot of things. And I think If, you rewind 10
Speaker 1:  years, a lot has changed and also nothing
Speaker 1:  has changed. Anyway, we have lots to cover. And there's also maybe,
Speaker 1:  maybe some huge Alexa news coming for us that might
Speaker 1:  change the next decade for all of this too. Lots to get to.
Speaker 1:  We're doing this for the whole show. Let's just get into it. Jen Tuy.
Speaker 1:  Hello.
Speaker 3:  Hi, David. How are you doing?
Speaker 1:  I'm good. I have, I have a sick child, So I. Haven't left my house in several
Speaker 1:  days or slept in several days. So, I'm not a hundred percent
Speaker 1:  sure not where I am or what's going on, but otherwise, otherwise we're
Speaker 1:  good. Oh,
Speaker 3:  I like delirious David. It could be really fun.
Speaker 1:  This, this might be the longest VERGE cast in history. It's very possible.
Speaker 1:  I, I take no responsibility for anything I say in the course of this segment.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I should just say that at the beginning of every Vergecast, actually,
Speaker 1:  that would be like the, the legal disclaimer that's like, this is all based
Speaker 1:  on fictional people and characters, not real.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So we're here to talk about Alexa because I guess Alexa
Speaker 1:  is 10. I was trying to think back to this and I'm like, what was the beginning
Speaker 1:  of Alexa? Because if, if I remember correctly, 10 years ago,
Speaker 1:  Alexa started in a deeply strange way.
Speaker 3:  Yes. It really was a very interesting launch. I think
Speaker 3:  very much influenced by the spectacular failure of the fire
Speaker 3:  phone a few months prior. Oh,
Speaker 1:  Was that really only a few months before
Speaker 3:  It happened? Just prior and Oh wow. I think I actually
Speaker 3:  wasn't deeply into tech journalism at the time, but I, I remember
Speaker 3:  some of this. I mean, you, you reviewed the original Echo, so you were right
Speaker 3:  in the midst of all of this. But looking back, doing some research over the
Speaker 3:  last few weeks, basically it sounded like
Speaker 3:  Amazon had this really quite impressive new technology. They were looking
Speaker 3:  to debut, but they were so burned by how badly the fire
Speaker 3:  phone went down that they sort of stealth launched
Speaker 3:  the, their, their New voice assistant Alexa, which came in the new
Speaker 3:  Echo Smart speaker. And this was the first consumer smart speaker
Speaker 3:  that anyone had seen. It just dropped with I think just a press
Speaker 3:  release and a video. And there was a lot of, you know, reporting
Speaker 3:  of like, whoa, where did this come from? This was, you know, a sort of stealth
Speaker 3:  launch. And it was announced as their, you know, this was
Speaker 3:  a smart speaker that you could talk to control with your voice.
Speaker 3:  It's had sort of a few key experiences at the start, which was
Speaker 3:  playing music, answering questions from Wikipedia.
Speaker 3:  And it was, you know, it was a really exciting idea. And the tech
Speaker 3:  press was very, you know, very into it. Lots of, oh my goodness,
Speaker 3:  what's Amazon done here? And, you know, where, where is this gonna go?
Speaker 3:  And there was a lot of excitement, but you couldn't actually get one. And
Speaker 3:  I think they didn't even send out review units. This was how, how much they
Speaker 3:  were, you know, learned from their previous mistakes. And I think,
Speaker 3:  correct me if I'm wrong, the verb actually went out and bought one in order
Speaker 3:  to get to review it. And this was, and it, you had to
Speaker 3:  get on a wait list, which is something that Amazon's done subsequently with
Speaker 3:  their sort of day one edition products that don't necessarily
Speaker 3:  have a very clear use case yet. And they're kind
Speaker 3:  of putting it out there to sort of explore where the community might
Speaker 3:  might take it. And that was very much what Echo and Alexa
Speaker 3:  launched as, as a sort of experiment.
Speaker 3:  Although it, you know, they revealed later that they had been spending years
Speaker 3:  working on this technology in particular the Farfield
Speaker 3:  microphones, which gave you this really cool new ability
Speaker 3:  to be able to talk to a voice assistant from anywhere in the room and not
Speaker 3:  be tied to a computer or a phone. And privately, you know, the ambition
Speaker 3:  that they revealed later was that this would be
Speaker 3:  akin to Star Trek's computer, an all knowing ever
Speaker 3:  present computer that can know what you want,
Speaker 3:  do anything you ask it to, and you can converse with in natural
Speaker 3:  language and do anything, control your lights,
Speaker 3:  destroy your enemies, put up your shields.
Speaker 3:  But you know, you get the, you get the idea,
Speaker 1:  Small ambitions, really super, super chill idea from Amazon at
Speaker 1:  the time.
Speaker 3:  So really was exciting technology. So yeah, it, it came out in
Speaker 3:  2014, November 6th was when they announced it.
Speaker 3:  I think you could start to buy it within a few months.
Speaker 3:  I believe the first review unit you reviewed was January time.
Speaker 3:  Okay. It wasn't until spring of 2015
Speaker 3:  that regular people could buy it. And then it finally went on
Speaker 3:  general sale. You didn't have to sign up in,
Speaker 3:  I think it was July of 2015. Wow. And I got mine under the
Speaker 3:  Christmas tree.
Speaker 3:  I put it on my Christmas list, my husband got it for me, and he's,
Speaker 3:  he presented to me Christmas morning, he said, I have no idea
Speaker 3:  what this is, why you want it, but it was on your list.
Speaker 1:  You got the original tennis ball can,
Speaker 3:  The original tennis ball. Yeah. Amazing.
Speaker 1:  I still have mine around here somewhere. I Oh, did you? And I assume it still
Speaker 1:  works.
Speaker 3:  Mine does. Mine's in my husband's garage. That's awesome. And he uses it
Speaker 3:  for music and it works. It works brilliantly. And actually, you know,
Speaker 3:  at the same time for Christmas, I got him something off his list. I had
Speaker 3:  no idea what it was either, it's something called a Craig Pocket Hole
Speaker 3:  jig. I don't know if that, do you have any idea what that
Speaker 1:  No, that sounds like something you can't legally say on a podcast. Like we're
Speaker 1:  gonna get an explicit tag for that. I don't
Speaker 3:  Know. So yeah, so, you know, this is a small peek into the chewy household
Speaker 3:  there, but yes, it was quite funny. I mean, these two very different
Speaker 3:  gadgets, what a pocket whole jig does, I found out is helps
Speaker 3:  make holes in wood so you can build furniture. And in fact, he built
Speaker 3:  the piece of furniture I'm podcasting from right now with that. So that's
Speaker 3:  a nice full circle.
Speaker 1:  Big Christmas in the Chewy household. Yes. 2015. So what's,
Speaker 1:  what's wild about that is a, you've just brought up a bunch of really
Speaker 1:  awful memories of trying to wrangle an echo to review.
Speaker 1:  So thank you for
Speaker 3:  That. I want to hear that story.
Speaker 1:  So I think the, the two hardest times I've ever
Speaker 1:  worked for a review unit of something were the, the
Speaker 1:  original Snap spectacles, which I drove
Speaker 1:  two and a half hours to a vending machine in Big Sir.
Speaker 1:  And got there right after they sold out the last one. So I bought them from
Speaker 1:  a stranger for $600. That was how I got Snap Spectacles,
Speaker 1:  ssp the first time Snap Spec. I literally scalped Snap spectacles. And
Speaker 1:  then the amount of time that I spent trying to
Speaker 1:  convince someone at Amazon to send me an echo, I mean
Speaker 1:  months of being like, I don't, I don't know how to be clear
Speaker 1:  about this. We would like to review this. Can I have one please to review.
Speaker 1:  And they were just like, ah,
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 1:  Dunno. And so we just, we just bought one and reviewed it and I
Speaker 1:  had forgotten the context they were launching this thing into, because
Speaker 1:  it is really funny to look back, especially with
Speaker 1:  how important Alexa really quickly became, like, I think
Speaker 1:  it's very telling that it went from a, a secret launch to under your
Speaker 1:  Christmas tree in 12 months. Yes. Like, it, it, once it happened, it happened
Speaker 1:  really fast. It did,
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But the way that it happened, it's, I could never tell if Amazon
Speaker 1:  just wasn't sure if it was anything or was desperately afraid it
Speaker 1:  was Fire Phone 2.0. And I think you're probably right that they were afraid
Speaker 1:  it was Fire Phone 2.0 because like you said, it has also come out since then
Speaker 1:  that this is a thing they'd been working on forever. Jeff Bezos was very
Speaker 1:  behind it and very excited about it and had big ideas about it. They were
Speaker 1:  just terrified it wasn't gonna go well, I guess. Yeah. And this was
Speaker 1:  before Amazon was just in full on like Yolo hardware mode. We're just gonna
Speaker 1:  try stuff and who cares if it goes well? Like it was a big bet that they
Speaker 1:  kind of didn't want you to think was a big bet.
Speaker 3:  Yes, yes. I mean, it was almost sort of like a, you know, as said,
Speaker 3:  like a test gadget. Like, oh, maybe even if a developer gadget, because you
Speaker 3:  know, that's what they pushed really hard was developers developing skills
Speaker 3:  for Alexa to give it more capabilities.
Speaker 3:  And that's something they've done, they've followed through on in the 10
Speaker 3:  years we've had the Echo devices. You know, it's not
Speaker 3:  a locked down proprietary device that, you know, is trying to lock you
Speaker 3:  into. Oh. So all of my devices in my office
Speaker 3:  are not designed to respond, but unfortunately the devices
Speaker 3:  in my living room, gimme one second. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  You're good.
Speaker 3:  Alexa. Turn on Do not disturb. Sorry about that. I think I've got 'em all.
Speaker 3:  So it wasn't a lockdown proprietary device designed
Speaker 3:  to sort of keep you in Amazon's ecosystem. You know, say like an iPhone
Speaker 3:  was at the time. It really was a sort of, let's see what this can do.
Speaker 3:  And you know, they developed, they had software development kits, they even
Speaker 3:  had Far phone, the far field microphone kit. They,
Speaker 3:  they allowed other manufacturers to put the technology
Speaker 3:  into their devices. It really was sort of like, let's see what we can do
Speaker 3:  with this new technology. Which was exciting. It was very exciting time,
Speaker 3:  I think.
Speaker 1:  And it worked really well. Like, I went back and read my review
Speaker 1:  from January of 2015, and on the one hand I had a bunch
Speaker 1:  of issues using the thing, but on the other hand, I still have all those
Speaker 1:  same issues 10 years later, which we'll get to. But I think the
Speaker 1:  extent to which Amazon made sort of a small
Speaker 1:  number of promises about what this thing was gonna be really good at and
Speaker 1:  was basically a hundred percent correct. Yeah. Is really kind of
Speaker 1:  incredible. They're like, you're gonna use this thing for music, you're gonna
Speaker 1:  use it for basic informational lookups. You're gonna use it to set timers,
Speaker 1:  you're gonna use it to convert, you know, grams to ounces and like check,
Speaker 1:  check and check. They, they like really
Speaker 1:  understood what the thing was for, from the very beginning in a way that
Speaker 1:  I had forgotten how correct. They, they really were,
Speaker 3:  They were for I, I agree. And you know, it did have, in those early days,
Speaker 3:  it was a big success. You know, I think within the first two years they'd
Speaker 3:  sold 5 million devices as the reports I'd seen, which I mean,
Speaker 3:  it's not iPhone, but, you know, it's still, it's impressive for a brand new
Speaker 3:  piece of technology.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, it's easy to, it's easy to forget now, but like smart speaker
Speaker 1:  was not a thing. No. That existed before. Like, nobody even knew how to,
Speaker 1:  why you would want this in your house or what it would do. And the,
Speaker 1:  I I don't know, If you remember the moment, but I do of like
Speaker 1:  walking in and the, the moment where you're just like, play,
Speaker 1:  you know, play whatever song, play Beyonce, play Taylor Swift, and it just
Speaker 1:  does. Yeah. And all of a sudden you're like, oh, I want everything to work
Speaker 1:  like that. And like, spoiler alert, it doesn't. But there were e even
Speaker 1:  at the very beginning, there were just enough of those moments that it was
Speaker 1:  like, as soon as you were in a room with an echo, you kind of got
Speaker 1:  it. And I feel like it was, there was like a really cool virality to that
Speaker 1:  thing at the very beginning that was very powerful.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And what, for me as, as someone who was really just getting, I
Speaker 3:  said into sort of tech journalism, but had always been a tech hobbyist, it
Speaker 3:  was a great, it was a real revelation to bring this type of technology
Speaker 3:  into my home as opposed to being in my hand or on my lap or on my
Speaker 3:  desktop. Especially for my family. I mean, my kids were very young at,
Speaker 3:  at this age. I mean, I think my son was three when Alexa,
Speaker 3:  or three or four, and my daughter was maybe two. And you
Speaker 3:  know, we were, it was great to be able to just call out and, you know,
Speaker 3:  play Beyonce and have a dance party and tell
Speaker 3:  stories and jokes and it really, it, it helped
Speaker 3:  bring technology into a much more usable
Speaker 3:  space in our homes. And, you know, I even at that age, at that year,
Speaker 3:  in that time, I was feeling that sort of parent guilt
Speaker 3:  of being on devices and, but, but there's so much still that's great
Speaker 3:  about technology for being a parent, you know, playing
Speaker 3:  music and reading audio books, things that we, you know,
Speaker 3:  I al I wanted to do with my kids, but I didn't wanna have to pull out my
Speaker 3:  phone to do it. So it really opened that sort of accessibility
Speaker 3:  to technology in the home. And that's, and I felt like there was
Speaker 3:  so much potential and so much that was exciting at the time,
Speaker 3:  but it also felt like we never really went that far beyond.
Speaker 3:  and we did get a lot of promises
Speaker 3:  from not, maybe not promises might be too strong a word, but a lot of very
Speaker 3:  strong indications from Amazon and, and Jeff Bezos and, and
Speaker 3:  Dave Limp the devices and services head at the time that
Speaker 3:  this was going to be so much more, this was
Speaker 3:  going to be the Star Trek computer or this, that was what they
Speaker 3:  were working towards. And it has been really interesting
Speaker 3:  to kind of see that they have not got there
Speaker 3:  and that we do use Alexa today very much. And I was,
Speaker 3:  when I was sort of going back through the research here, I looked at my list
Speaker 3:  of what I asked my device to do today versus
Speaker 3:  what I did, you know, five years ago or seven years ago. And
Speaker 3:  it really hasn't changed that much. And that, that that sort of
Speaker 3:  key difference feels like a big failure. And I'll
Speaker 3:  tell you the reason why is because it's just not that reliable is, you know,
Speaker 3:  the long and the short of it. And this is something I've seen, you know,
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm in many user groups, Facebook groups,
Speaker 3:  discords, Reddits forums where people who
Speaker 3:  use Echo and Alexa complain or praise
Speaker 3:  or discuss the device and, and the assistant. And it just seems
Speaker 3:  like there's a universal consensus that it kind of hits a plateau
Speaker 3:  and it can still mostly do those basic things,
Speaker 3:  but there really hasn't been that next
Speaker 3:  exciting use case that next exciting development for
Speaker 3:  the technology. There's some really interesting use cases, especially around
Speaker 3:  accessibility and elder care where, you know, they're
Speaker 3:  valuable use cases. People being able, you know, who have
Speaker 3:  accessibility challenges, being able to, you know, open your shades
Speaker 3:  or turn your lights on and off, being able to, we've got, we had a,
Speaker 3:  we've written, I've written a number of pieces about using Amazon devices
Speaker 3:  to look after elderly parents. There's so many key use cases,
Speaker 3:  but they are solving specific problems. That
Speaker 3:  ultimate idea of this ambient voice
Speaker 3:  assistant that can manage your home, that can
Speaker 3:  be like computer in Star Trek and
Speaker 3:  be this sort of omniscient, omnipresent, artificial intelligence
Speaker 3:  hasn't arrived. Maybe a lot of people don't want it, but I do.
Speaker 3:  And I'm, I was excited to see that come and I feel like we just almost
Speaker 3:  feel like further away from that than we were. A lot of
Speaker 3:  problems I encounter when using Alexa in my home. Is
Speaker 3:  it not doing what I expect it to do if I have set up sort of a
Speaker 3:  more complicated routine that I've tried to get it to do things like lock
Speaker 3:  my back door, adjust my thermostat, turn the lights off, dim them in
Speaker 3:  this room, you know, turn the TV on all, you know,
Speaker 3:  multiple different things at once, which is, you know, one of the sort of
Speaker 3:  core use cases now of the smart home side of Alexa. Nine times
Speaker 3:  out of 10 something doesn't work or it doesn't hear me correctly and it does
Speaker 3:  something differently from what I've asked it to do. And so that's
Speaker 3:  happened, that happens to me so often that I have basically got to the point
Speaker 3:  now where all I use it for is to turn lights on and off other than
Speaker 3:  those core use cases of playing music in certain timers, which I think
Speaker 3:  everyone can agree Alexa is great at. It's
Speaker 1:  Very good at it. Well, and and I think, I think that's, that's kind of the
Speaker 1:  key open question for me with a lot of this stuff is
Speaker 1:  who and what is to blame for that fact, because I actually think there
Speaker 1:  are a bunch of possibilities, right? There's, there's one world in which
Speaker 1:  you say, okay, Amazon just didn't do it right.
Speaker 1:  Like you, you could as a sort of failure of technology. The the far field
Speaker 1:  microphone doesn't work, the natural language processing doesn't work, whatever
Speaker 1:  cards on the table. I actually don't think it's that one, but I'd be curious
Speaker 1:  to know, If, you do, there's a version of it that says it's kind
Speaker 1:  of an ecosystem problem that actually what happened is there's just not enough
Speaker 1:  stuff that it's even theoretically able to do that. Like
Speaker 1:  the problem with building a Star Trek computer is like the Star Trek computer
Speaker 1:  can do an awful lot of stuff and you have to build all that stuff and they
Speaker 1:  never did. And then there's a third thing that that basically says
Speaker 1:  like maybe this just isn't the right interface to do
Speaker 1:  all of that stuff. And I think there might even be other possibilities,
Speaker 1:  but I keep coming back to like, I agree that we didn't get the Star Trek
Speaker 1:  computer, right? Like, I think everyone agrees we didn't get the Star Trek
Speaker 1:  computer, but why didn't we, the longer we
Speaker 1:  go, the more complicated that question becomes to me. And
Speaker 1:  I'm, I know you've thought a lot about it this in research a lot about it.
Speaker 1:  Like do you do, do you have a thing over the decade of Alexa you
Speaker 1:  can pinpoint to be like, this is where we kinda lost the thread.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think capitalism
Speaker 3:  fair, I think Alexa and Echo started out as a, you
Speaker 3:  know, a very ambitious, exciting new technology.
Speaker 3:  And then Amazon was like, oh wow, we've sold, we've sold 5 million
Speaker 3:  of these in two years. Let's make hundreds more
Speaker 3:  of all shapes and sizes. Let's put it in a ring. Let's put it in
Speaker 3:  earbuds, let's put it in cars. Let's, let's make small ones fat
Speaker 3:  ones short. Ones tall ones, ones with screens. And
Speaker 3:  they, I think the company focused far too much
Speaker 3:  time developing new, killing
Speaker 3:  more echo devices. Yeah. When they didn't work.
Speaker 3:  Trying to expand this technology into
Speaker 3:  every corner of our lives. Having encouraging other companies to make
Speaker 3:  Alexa powered speakers and devices, putting it in
Speaker 3:  microwaves and clocks and a, a lot of energy
Speaker 3:  on that. Not enough energy on actually
Speaker 3:  developing the core technology. And I'm not an engineer and as you say, I,
Speaker 3:  I think that has been a challenge that whether the technology is actually
Speaker 3:  at the point where we could have had a better Alexa sooner than
Speaker 3:  today or a few years time, but that doesn't mean it couldn't have got
Speaker 3:  better
Speaker 3:  in incrementally. And there have been, you know, there's a many more
Speaker 3:  capabilities of the voice assistant today than there was
Speaker 3:  when it started. But the, the interface which you
Speaker 3:  alluded to is the problem. There, there is so many things it can do.
Speaker 3:  Maybe not very many things you want it to do, but there are many, many things
Speaker 3:  it can do. You know, fart jokes is the obvious one.
Speaker 3:  Lots of lots of great
Speaker 3:  comedic and entertainment things, not as so many
Speaker 3:  useful things. Like you want an as when you think of an assistant, I want
Speaker 3:  an assistant to, you know, order me a pizza or I want an assistant
Speaker 3:  to plan my day for me. Those types of things never got better. You could
Speaker 3:  connect your Google account, your Google calendar to it, or you could
Speaker 3:  set up, you know, your photos through Amazon photos, but there just
Speaker 3:  weren't very many core good use
Speaker 3:  cases that meant I need to use this device every day. It was very,
Speaker 3:  it's been very much, it's fun to use this device, but there
Speaker 3:  was no kind of breakthrough. This is why I have to have this device
Speaker 3:  in my home other than some of those niche, more niche use cases we discussed
Speaker 3:  earlier. And I I feel like, I mean, Amazon's a hardware company,
Speaker 3:  although it started out as a website, it's really ma it has
Speaker 3:  become a hardware company. Yeah. Every, I mean there's a, you know, the
Speaker 3:  in VERGE law and tech journalist and law, when you go to an Amazon event
Speaker 3:  event, one of their four hardware events, you were prepared to write up
Speaker 3:  75 new gadgets in 30 minutes.
Speaker 1:  What was it? Was it 2018 the year that it was just 700,000
Speaker 1:  new Alexa gadgets all at once? That was the year of the clock and the microwave,
Speaker 1:  right? And yeah, everything, anything that exists in your house now it has
Speaker 1:  Alexa now
Speaker 3:  It has it. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Do you want that? Doesn't matter. You have it now. That was the, that was
Speaker 1:  the pitch. But
Speaker 3:  I could, I mean, I can see the value there, like connect all the things
Speaker 3:  and then Alexa can do everything you want it to do. But it was the getting
Speaker 3:  Alexa to do everything you wanted to do part that they never
Speaker 3:  made better. You had to use the Alexa app, which is one of, is
Speaker 3:  probably the single worst piece of smart home software I have ever used
Speaker 3:  it. I agree with that. It has incrementally got better, but it is still
Speaker 3:  really difficult. I
Speaker 1:  Was just about to say it's, it's night and day better than it was even a
Speaker 1:  few years ago and it's still pretty bad. Like it's, it's rough.
Speaker 3:  And they've tried to address that, you know, they came out with the new Echo
Speaker 3:  hub, so you have an interface that you can use. Yeah. But again,
Speaker 3:  it was the voice interface is what needed to get better. The voice interface
Speaker 3:  needed to be, we need to be able to talk to our voice
Speaker 3:  assistant in the way you can talk to str well not you can, but
Speaker 3:  Picard could talk to Star Trek's computer. Right. Just say what you're thinking,
Speaker 3:  say what you want to happen and it do it for you. It understand and
Speaker 3:  be able to do it for you. And we've never got anywhere closer. Alexa's never
Speaker 3:  understood better what you want than she did on day
Speaker 3:  one. It, it, that never got better. Which
Speaker 1:  I, I think is that, I think that's the perfect way to put it. Because one
Speaker 1:  of the things I always enjoy about using Alexa, just from a sort of like
Speaker 1:  perverse doing technology science work, is
Speaker 1:  you go in and you look at something that went wrong and just
Speaker 1:  the question is always like, did it misunderstand me? And actually it very
Speaker 1:  rarely does. At least in my case, I go in and it, like, I can
Speaker 1:  say even very complicated long, you know, multi
Speaker 1:  word, long sentence things. It's transcription is very
Speaker 1:  good and, and it's, it's natural language processing is very good. And so
Speaker 1:  it's like it knows what I want. Right? Like that is not
Speaker 1:  the challenge. No. And you could think that yelling at a speaker from across
Speaker 1:  the room would be a hard problem. And it, and it is, but actually again,
Speaker 1:  from pretty close to the very beginning, Amazon more or
Speaker 1:  less solved that problem. Yeah. There's somewhere after that first
Speaker 1:  step of like, I have declared my intention to my device and
Speaker 1:  my device has registered that intention correctly and that it falls apart
Speaker 1:  and it has never, that part, like you're saying, has never gotten, I I would
Speaker 1:  say even meaningfully better, much less very good.
Speaker 3:  No, I agree. And and that's where the Star Trek computer idea came
Speaker 3:  in. You know, that this device could sort of manage your home
Speaker 3:  for you. I mean, Alexa leaned hard into the smart home as
Speaker 3:  soon as they realized that this was, you know, a great use case for voice
Speaker 3:  control. You know, even though it wasn't part of the initial plan,
Speaker 3:  but to begin with it was incredibly clunky. And
Speaker 3:  you know, I I've spent the last eight years
Speaker 3:  trying to use Alexa to run my smart home smoothly.
Speaker 3:  And my sort of touch point throughout this time has been like a good
Speaker 3:  morning routine. Like this is what you always hear about when you talk about
Speaker 3:  voice control and smart home. It's like you can set up this good morning
Speaker 3:  routine, goodnight routine. I'm leaving routine and your whole home will
Speaker 3:  just work magically. And I, from the days of Wink,
Speaker 3:  remember Wink. Oh yeah. That was one of the first times I try
Speaker 1:  Not to remember Wink, but every once in a while
Speaker 3:  That was one of those first smart home hubs that worked with Alexa
Speaker 3:  and you used to have to say trigger my good morning routine. And my
Speaker 3:  husband still says trigger to every time he asks Alexa to do
Speaker 3:  something. Oh my goodness. Sorry.
Speaker 1:  This is good. We're leaving all of these in. This is, this is the point people,
Speaker 1:  this
Speaker 3:  Is there so many in my house,
Speaker 3:  Alexa do not disturb. See this? It never
Speaker 3:  gets right. But yes. So, and over the years I have
Speaker 3:  tried to, you know, it sort of as I've been my touch point, like whether
Speaker 3:  we have reached a, a sort of magical moment where
Speaker 3:  the smart home just works and you know, this kind of goes back, you know,
Speaker 3:  circles back to Star Trek with, you know, I think the
Speaker 3:  infamous line and I can deliver it in an English accent
Speaker 3:  and I will do my best
Speaker 3:  computer tea L Gray hot.
Speaker 3:  Ooh, that was good.
Speaker 3:  I don't do a good card. Sorry, I have to get my Shakespeare on. It was solid.
Speaker 3:  I I approved that, but yes. You know, so, and for me it was
Speaker 3:  coffee, black strong and I wanted, I
Speaker 3:  wanted to get outta my bed, I wanted the lights to turn on. I
Speaker 3:  wanted BBC radio two to start playing. I wanted a
Speaker 3:  coffee to start brewing, maybe, you know, my shower to start running
Speaker 3:  thermostat to adjust and then say 20 minutes later,
Speaker 3:  the kids' lights in their room go on, their alarm goes off. You know,
Speaker 3:  things that I would have to go and do manually myself. But having
Speaker 3:  a smart home assistant do all of this for me, save me time in the morning,
Speaker 3:  make me less stressed, make everyone happy. Right. And so
Speaker 3:  the first problem I came across was a personal one,
Speaker 3:  but one that really kind of goes to another key area where
Speaker 3:  the smart home in general and Alexa hasn't succeeded, which is context.
Speaker 3:  So my husband has been for most of his career a shift worker.
Speaker 3:  So he works 24 hours shifts and then he would come home and sleep for
Speaker 3:  12 hours. So for me, having a motion sensor or using Voice
Speaker 3:  to start my morning routine was not gonna work because
Speaker 3:  I would wake him up. And also I only wanted the bedroom lights to turn on
Speaker 3:  when he wasn't there, not when he was there. So, you know, there was nothing,
Speaker 3:  there's nothing that Alexa could do to differentiate, didn't have the context
Speaker 3:  of what was happening in, in the room. Then the other issue was
Speaker 3:  trying to use a motion sensor to trigger a routine is something
Speaker 3:  you've only really been able to do in the last couple of years. Motion sensing
Speaker 3:  support for Alexa was really spotty for years. It
Speaker 3:  worked through ZigBee initially, but nine times out of 10, a
Speaker 3:  ZigBee motion sensor you connected to Echo would either not stay connected
Speaker 3:  or wouldn't work. Yeah. And again, maybe not
Speaker 3:  Amazon's problem might, but you know, when you're connecting to different
Speaker 3:  ecosystems, you need your smart assistant to be able to troubleshoot these
Speaker 3:  things for you so that you don't have to spend 30 hours
Speaker 3:  a week troubleshooting your smart home to get these things to work. Right.
Speaker 3:  And then the fresh brewed coffee, this is
Speaker 3:  a capability that we should have had years ago. You
Speaker 3:  can rig up a smart plug If, you have the right type of
Speaker 3:  coffee machine that has a physical on off
Speaker 3:  switch, or you have a smart Alexa connected coffee
Speaker 3:  machine that on average costs between one
Speaker 3:  and $2,000. There's one from spin and then there's
Speaker 3:  one recently from Bosch. There. There's
Speaker 3:  just, there's just so much friction. So you, I'm testing the Bosch coffee
Speaker 3:  maker and in theory it should make me a latte when I say
Speaker 3:  good morning, but okay, I spend in preparation
Speaker 3:  for, when I was sort of researching all this, I spent about
Speaker 3:  four hours trying to get her to work. This is,
Speaker 1:  This is the like key Alexa calculus that has
Speaker 1:  never tipped in Alexa's favor, right? Yes. You can. A lot of what you just
Speaker 1:  described, you can in theory right.
Speaker 3:  Set
Speaker 1:  Up, right? Like the, the one of the things Amazon has tried to do to
Speaker 1:  its credit is enable some of this stuff, right? Yes. And like, I get a lot
Speaker 1:  of crap on this show for hating Apple shortcuts because
Speaker 1:  it gives you a lot of power, but it is essentially a, a like really complicated
Speaker 1:  scripting language. Yeah. And so Sure right. If you are willing to do the
Speaker 1:  work to learn all of that. Great. The problem is then
Speaker 1:  you, you've spent a bunch of money, you've done a ton of work, it doesn't
Speaker 1:  work all the time. And then now I'm doing a bunch of maintenance. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  so at each step along the way, you've lost a significant part of what makes
Speaker 1:  this thing compelling in the first place. And now you're just doing,
Speaker 1:  you're, you're like doing a bit trying to get Alexa to work, right? It feels
Speaker 1:  cool, but it's not actually less work.
Speaker 3:  No, it's more work.
Speaker 1:  Right. And so you, you get to a point where the, the math of
Speaker 1:  how much time am I spending to make coffee every morning just
Speaker 1:  doesn't tip in Alexa's favor. And I it's true with so
Speaker 1:  many things. And that, that has always been the thing for me that it's like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, I could make the good morning routine work, but it would only work
Speaker 1:  half the time and I'm gonna go have to fix all the things it doesn't get
Speaker 1:  right every morning. And it's just not, I'm I, I'll just walk into the room
Speaker 1:  and turn the light on. That works.
Speaker 3:  Oh David, it works. You're breaking my heart.
Speaker 1:  No, but it's it, and it kills me too because I want all that stuff to work
Speaker 1:  and like once a year I go through the work of setting all this stuff up again
Speaker 1:  and then the third time in a row it doesn't work. Doesn't, I'm like, ah,
Speaker 1:  nevermind. And I just tear it all out of the wall again
Speaker 3:  Or it works. But there's one thing actually that you didn't, you'd
Speaker 3:  forgot that you don't want it to do that one time like right. Your son's
Speaker 3:  sleeping and they don't have to go to school that day, but it still turns
Speaker 3:  the light on in their room. Yeah. You know, so, and that's, again, that goes
Speaker 3:  back to the context, you know, it, it needs to know more about
Speaker 3:  your, your home and be more intelligent and not just
Speaker 3:  command and control.
Speaker 1:  That is actually a perfect segue into all of where this stuff is headed,
Speaker 1:  which I think we're 10 years in and we're kind of at, at the beginning of
Speaker 1:  maybe a next decade of new things on this front. So we're gonna take a
Speaker 1:  really quick break. Will you stick around and talk to me about all that stuff
Speaker 1:  too?
Speaker 3:  Of course, I will be right here.
Speaker 1:  Alright, good. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Jen two is still here. Hi Jen. Hi. I just
Speaker 1:  like talking about Alexa. This is fun. This is, this is delightful. I have
Speaker 1:  been on the hill of voice assistance. We'll change everything for a
Speaker 1:  very long time and I have mostly been wrong. So let's talk
Speaker 1:  about the ways the future might prove me and you. Right.
Speaker 3:  One day. Yeah, because I, how long do we get?
Speaker 1:  Let's say 10 more years. Okay. I think the, the first decade, not so much
Speaker 1:  for us. Decade number two, maybe we're
Speaker 3:  Right in there
Speaker 1:  Hard maybe. So let's talk about kind of where we are at
Speaker 1:  this moment, both in terms of what Alexa is and
Speaker 1:  kind of what we know about where it's about to go. And I think
Speaker 1:  you, I think relatively recently got to go see some version of like
Speaker 1:  the, the perfect like platonic ideal of an Alexa
Speaker 1:  system, right? That like Amazon's fever dream of what your house might look
Speaker 1:  like.
Speaker 3:  Yes. I did. I went for a tour of Amazon's
Speaker 3:  smart Home lab, which is in their Seattle headquarters.
Speaker 3:  And I was, I was excited when they suggested
Speaker 3:  the idea and they said, you know, we can show you everything we have set
Speaker 3:  up. And it's sort of like an idealistic, like this is what
Speaker 3:  the sort of ultimate Alexa powered, ambient
Speaker 3:  smart home looks like. You know, everything is connected and set up
Speaker 3:  and you just need to say a few words. I was hoping
Speaker 3:  for a bit more motion sensing action, like ambient action. But
Speaker 3:  there was, you know, this was, this was kind of like their ideal So I was
Speaker 3:  expecting honestly to be kind of blown away.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean if ever it's going to feel like magic. It should be Yes. Literally
Speaker 1:  Amazon with infinite resources and all of the people who made this thing
Speaker 1:  at its disposal Yes. Should be able to make it feel like magic.
Speaker 3:  They should,
Speaker 1:  I'm not, I'm not looking forward to where we're headed here.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it it, it was, I'm gonna say it, it was very
Speaker 3:  disappointing. Oh
Speaker 1:  No, how so? It
Speaker 3:  Was a very nice apartment, beautiful views.
Speaker 3:  Sunny day too. Seattle. Okay.
Speaker 3:  But it was pedestrian, you
Speaker 3:  know, they had everything they, you know, hundreds of devices that could
Speaker 3:  work with the voice assistant, echo devices
Speaker 3:  everywhere, you know, robot vacuums, ring
Speaker 3:  devices, fire TVs, and then lots of third party things.
Speaker 3:  But they, they had like Lutron, Casser lights had switch bot,
Speaker 3:  robot fingers, tons of fun gadgets. But
Speaker 3:  ultimately it was all still command and control. And you know, as we
Speaker 3:  talked about, and Amazon has said along
Speaker 3:  with, in the same breath of, you know, this, our aspiration is a Star Trek
Speaker 3:  computer. Our aspiration is an ambient smart home,
Speaker 3:  a sort of a home that responds to you proactively
Speaker 3:  without you having to do anything or do something very minimal.
Speaker 3:  Just say a few words or maybe press a button and
Speaker 3:  what you want happens. And they had set up in
Speaker 3:  the house, different routines in each room. So there was like a,
Speaker 3:  a watch TV routine. There was a leaving the home routine
Speaker 3:  and of course a good morning routine, which I was excited to
Speaker 3:  try out it always a good morning, go to bed and got ready to have
Speaker 3:  to start my day. And again, the no motion
Speaker 3:  sensors So I had to, I had to say a command
Speaker 3:  to get things going. And it did the normal stuff, turned the lights on,
Speaker 3:  started the shower, which is something I've always wanted. But again, really
Speaker 3:  expensive. If you've looked into Mowen or cola smart showers,
Speaker 3:  it's not cheap. So, you know, it just didn't sort of have
Speaker 3:  that ambient feel. And, and also it
Speaker 3:  was really slow and really laggy. And again,
Speaker 3:  I'm like, guys, this is, this is your sort of
Speaker 3:  ultimate setup and you're basically just reaffirming my feeling
Speaker 3:  that this is still basically a remote control
Speaker 3:  for your home. Which, which is great, that has its use case, but
Speaker 3:  it is not Star Trek computer and it is not an ambient smart home.
Speaker 1:  I actually, I love that distinction. 'cause I think one other thing you and
Speaker 1:  I have talked about over the years and that I've been forever fascinated
Speaker 1:  by is universal remotes, which Yeah. Which I actually think as a
Speaker 1:  gadget are, are sort of woefully underdeveloped and under
Speaker 1:  considered. And the idea that I can just sit and hold a thing and it becomes
Speaker 1:  like a magic wand for all of my gear strikes me as a
Speaker 1:  much more attainable than some of the other stuff we're working on. And b,
Speaker 1:  really cool and useful, like I, I have, I have six or
Speaker 1:  seven remotes just for the stuff here in my basement. And in
Speaker 1:  terms of like actual human utility, putting all of that into one usable
Speaker 1:  device makes a lot of sense. And So I think to your point, it's not nothing
Speaker 1:  to turn this into something that can go do an individual
Speaker 1:  thing on your behalf. Right. Having like one interface for all of that stuff,
Speaker 1:  even a command at a time is not nothing. It's also nowhere
Speaker 1:  near the like big ambient computing
Speaker 1:  something. It can do everything for you. And a, a word
Speaker 1:  that Amazon has used more and more over time is proactively correct. Right?
Speaker 1:  Like the idea is not just that you should be able to ask it to do it for
Speaker 1:  you and it will, yeah. It should be able to do it for you. Yes. Like just
Speaker 1:  the fact that you have to say good morning in order to tell it that you've
Speaker 1:  woken up and to start the routine is actually a failure of the system.
Speaker 1:  It should just know you've woken up and do the things for you. Right. Like,
Speaker 1:  and again, all that technology is there. Yes. There's these people, like
Speaker 1:  again, it costs 'em billion dollars, but like you can buy the eight sleep
Speaker 1:  thing that tracks your sleep and the, the, the pieces of the puzzle are
Speaker 1:  sitting there and Alexa was supposed to be the thing that put them all together
Speaker 1:  in such a way that you didn't have to and, and right now we're still on the
Speaker 1:  universal remote phase.
Speaker 3:  Well, and to Alexa's credit, it is, if there is one thing that is
Speaker 3:  more difficult to navigate than voice control, it is a universal
Speaker 3:  remote.
Speaker 1:  Fair. Fair.
Speaker 3:  There
Speaker 1:  Are like eight Logitech harmony owners out there screaming and yelling at
Speaker 1:  me. I want you to know I hear you and, and I love you, but it's true.
Speaker 3:  But you know, universal remotes have their place, but there's also a reason
Speaker 3:  why there are very few of them around. Yes. But what
Speaker 3:  the problem with the universal remote and with Alexa as it
Speaker 3:  is today, is that specific nomenclature, the fact that you
Speaker 3:  have to say specific words to get Alexa
Speaker 3:  to do something or press a specific sequence of buttons on your
Speaker 3:  universal remote. Right. But yeah, it's, it's that the ambient part
Speaker 3:  is, is the intelligence and none of neither of
Speaker 3:  those things currently have the intelligence. And you know,
Speaker 3:  there are, that's where, that's the next step
Speaker 3:  in the smart home. Whether it's Amazon that can bring that intelligence or
Speaker 3:  another company. There are many, many trying. Yes, there are.
Speaker 3:  That's what we need. We need the systems that can understand
Speaker 3:  context, that can understand everything that's in our
Speaker 3:  home. I mean, when I spoke with Dave Limp, when they had their last event
Speaker 3:  in October of 2023, he, you know, he said, we, we have
Speaker 3:  feeding all of every smart home manual ever made into Alexa
Speaker 3:  to make it more intelligent so that it knows the devices in your home.
Speaker 3:  That's what it, it needs that knowledge, but then it also needs the
Speaker 3:  intelligence to be able to act on them. For example, I have a
Speaker 3:  smart faucet in my kitchen and if I go
Speaker 3:  up to it to, or I can use Amazon, I can use
Speaker 3:  Alexa to have it do fun things like dispense two
Speaker 3:  cups of water at 90 degrees, you know, perfect for baby
Speaker 3:  bottle. You can set these presets. But I have to,
Speaker 3:  I'll be standing in front of the faucet and I will have to say, Alexa,
Speaker 3:  ask Moen to dispense two cups of water at 90
Speaker 3:  degrees. And sometimes it will say
Speaker 3:  okay and sometimes it will say, I can't do that. Please set
Speaker 3:  up your devices again. Or something along those lines like who's mul?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then my, my husband was watching me try and play
Speaker 3:  with this the other day and he said, shouldn't it just know that you're standing
Speaker 3:  in front of the kitchen f it? Yes. And when you say I want two cups of hot
Speaker 3:  water, just do it. And it should and it could.
Speaker 3:  That is a future we could have. There is enough technology just even in echo
Speaker 3:  devices and also in devices like from Apple
Speaker 3:  and Google that you'd have in your home there smarts. Because things like
Speaker 3:  UWB radar, there's the technology is there.
Speaker 1:  I mean, for God's sake, Amazon owns Ring which makes a drone with a camera
Speaker 1:  that will fly around your house. Like
Speaker 3:  Allegedly.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Fair it allegedly. We'll do that. It's a fair
Speaker 1:  point. But yeah, like all again, and I think we should just
Speaker 1:  say, and then move on from the fact that like all of this
Speaker 1:  requires a deep like privacy
Speaker 1:  trade off. Yes. In a way that should make people uncomfortable. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  is is a trade off that we are going to need to reckon with as people if
Speaker 1:  that technology is ever going to get to what you're describing, we
Speaker 1:  are going to have to make some like very conscious decisions about, I
Speaker 1:  want my speaker to be aware that I'm standing
Speaker 1:  at the sink and we should just leave that conversation for another time.
Speaker 1:  Because I think that is a place where like everyone is going to have to make
Speaker 1:  personal decisions about how they feel about that stuff. But that is what
Speaker 1:  it
Speaker 3:  Requires. I do need to just interject because we've gone in almost an hour
Speaker 3:  and I haven't mentioned the M word, but this is where Matta could help. Oh
Speaker 3:  God.
Speaker 1:  Well that's the everybody,
Speaker 3:  So whilst it's up to the platforms, how they implement and
Speaker 3:  my money would be on Amazon using the cloud. Gosh, not sure why,
Speaker 3:  but anyway, a platform, a smart home platform using
Speaker 3:  Matter can keep all of that information entirely local
Speaker 3:  and use that data locally. So, but we'll put a pin in that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  We'll, we'll, we'll we'll have many more chances to have that version of
Speaker 1:  the conversation. But to your point, this is
Speaker 1:  the future everyone imagines. Right? I think that the really interesting
Speaker 1:  point we're at right now is anyone thinking about this kind of
Speaker 1:  ambient computing future thinks about it roughly the same way. The goal
Speaker 1:  is the same. And we're at a moment right now where everyone thinks it's the
Speaker 1:  same technology that's gonna get us there. Which again brings us
Speaker 1:  to Dave Limp a year ago
Speaker 1:  who I, I don't know, I guess in retrospect like
Speaker 1:  way pre announced a gigantic reboot of Alexa.
Speaker 1:  Is that is, am I overstating it to put
Speaker 3:  It like that? No, no. I mean they, they, he got on stage and demoed a
Speaker 3:  new, very much more conversational Alexa. That was the kind
Speaker 3:  of the big show off was being able to talk to the voice
Speaker 3:  assistant naturally not having to constantly repeat the
Speaker 3:  wake word and have it, it had more personality. Like it
Speaker 3:  was kind of joking with him. And it it that sort of natural
Speaker 3:  conversation, which was again the sort of the North star, the Star Trek
Speaker 3:  computer being able to speak naturally and have a conversation
Speaker 3:  is something they've been working towards. And this demo did show
Speaker 3:  that it was almost a reality.
Speaker 3:  They also at this, at that event talked about how
Speaker 3:  Alexa was being able to do more of what we've been talking about here and
Speaker 3:  sort of do more intelligent
Speaker 3:  responses. One of the things is sort of multi-step routine. So
Speaker 3:  you could create something just by telling Alexa
Speaker 3:  a list of things you want it to accomplish, you know, more like, like to
Speaker 3:  a computer and have it just
Speaker 3:  reel those off without you having to go into an app and set up a routine
Speaker 3:  and then set up a trigger so you don't have to spend your time programming
Speaker 3:  your smart home. You just think, oh actually I want this to happen right
Speaker 3:  now. Alexa do it for me and it will do it. And then,
Speaker 3:  you know, this, this is a sort of their new vision,
Speaker 3:  how it's going to get there. I mean ultimately what I would like is
Speaker 3:  something like that un I would like to be able to have Alexa
Speaker 3:  follow through on the commands that I have, but also understand
Speaker 3:  the context of them. So for example, an idea I sort of came
Speaker 3:  up with what I would love to be able to say something like, Alexa tell
Speaker 3:  my son not to forget his science project. You know, set the alarm when he
Speaker 3:  leaves in the morning, then unlock the back door at 4:00 PM for the plumber,
Speaker 3:  lock it again at five and then preheat the oven at six
Speaker 3:  o'clock. But if I'm running late, adjust the time, you know, so you don't
Speaker 3:  burn the house down and, and it would need, but Amazon's
Speaker 3:  gonna need a lot more context to be able to do this type of thing. And this
Speaker 3:  is the type of thing that we're already seeing hints of in
Speaker 3:  the other ecosystems. Like that's some of what Siri
Speaker 3:  may be able to do in terms of the intelligence Siri, not the smart
Speaker 3:  home control but understanding like that I'm running late. Oh now there goes
Speaker 3:  Siri,
Speaker 1:  This is great.
Speaker 3:  She's on it. Don't worry.
Speaker 1:  I'm glad I look forward to what she comes back with. Netting to the internet
Speaker 1:  there it's info check the whole app sir. Everybody alright
Speaker 1:  keep going.
Speaker 3:  Sorry, I forgot about that one.
Speaker 1:  This is great. We're leaving all of this in. This is the most, this is a
Speaker 1:  real show not tell thing we're doing here. I love it.
Speaker 3:  I can go with Google next. Hey Google, you pipe up.
Speaker 3:  No he it doesn't. Listen there's one right here.
Speaker 3:  Nothing. Nothing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. This is why the Alexa team is not afraid of Google and
Speaker 1:  Apple.
Speaker 3:  Okay, sorry. But yeah, and I that context,
Speaker 3:  context aware voice assistant is the kind of, you know, the holy
Speaker 3:  grail for me that is the computer, that is the ambient technology
Speaker 3:  and you know, you could, you know, speaking of like the type of technology
Speaker 3:  that Apple said it's bringing to Siri with a contextually aware Siri,
Speaker 3:  you could imagine, and this may be something a little bit
Speaker 3:  out there and might scare most people.
Speaker 5:  I don't have an answer for that. Is there something else I can help with?
Speaker 3:  Is that, is something like this. Okay, so it's, so night.
Speaker 3:  I'm working in my home office. My mom is bringing the kids
Speaker 3:  home and she's texted me that she's bringing a frozen pizza. So
Speaker 3:  my smart assistant sees the text message, knows that it's my mom and not
Speaker 3:  me 'cause I'm also mom
Speaker 3:  and starts preheating the oven, you know, so that
Speaker 3:  the frozen pizza can go in as soon as they get home, unlocks the
Speaker 3:  door at six 30, which is when they said they were gonna arrive
Speaker 3:  turns on the air purifier because it knows the oven's on. And then after
Speaker 3:  we've had dinner, the robot vacuum will just automatically start
Speaker 3:  a quiet, clean and mop of the kitchen. And then if someone
Speaker 3:  has thought to shut the dishwasher, it will start running automatically.
Speaker 3:  And then I sit down on the couch and without having to say
Speaker 3:  anything or do anything because UWB sensors in my home
Speaker 3:  pod minis or my Alexa soundbar know that we're sitting on the
Speaker 3:  couch. You know, the lights dimmed down, the TV turns on
Speaker 3:  and it knows the kids are there. So it starts playing something
Speaker 3:  family friendly that it knows we like watching, like say last night's recording
Speaker 3:  of the voice. Yes, I do like the voice and we know, and then at eight 30
Speaker 3:  it turns off because it knows it's bedtime. Maybe my
Speaker 3:  Moen smart faucet, if they had one for the bath, would start running a bath
Speaker 3:  for me at the right temperature, turn the lights on upstairs, play
Speaker 3:  some soothing music. And I haven't had to do anything
Speaker 3:  my assistant and my home have has pulled
Speaker 3:  all that together for me. I mean, is that the dream or
Speaker 3:  does that slightly terrify you? I,
Speaker 1:  I mean both to be honest. And I think, I think that's mostly
Speaker 1:  the dream. I think there are bits and pieces of that that I think
Speaker 1:  the, the sort of perfectly proactive assistant is actually the wrong
Speaker 1:  answer. Like, one thing I've learned over time talking to people who work
Speaker 1:  at streaming companies is that the idea of you just sit down and
Speaker 1:  it plays the perfect thing for you is actually not correct. It's, it's the
Speaker 1:  like the, the Amazon thing of like, what if they could just ship you the
Speaker 1:  stuff that you want? Like people like to shop right? People like to browse.
Speaker 1:  And even the thing that is technically the perfect thing for you to watch
Speaker 1:  David.
Speaker 3:  David, you don't have a 13-year-old and a 16-year-old.
Speaker 1:  Listen, I didn't say it's a good thing that people like to do this, but people
Speaker 1:  do like to do this. And, and, and the idea of like, If,
Speaker 1:  you sit down even if what you want to watch is the voice, if it just puts
Speaker 1:  the voice on for you, it feels weird. And So, I think there are, there are
Speaker 1:  things about like if my house just starts drawing me a bath at bath time,
Speaker 1:  there's something odd about that. But if it, if it can chime in and be like,
Speaker 1:  Hey,
Speaker 3:  Would you like me to?
Speaker 1:  Right. That, that starts to feel really valuable. Right. So, I think there's
Speaker 1:  a really interesting interface question there. Yeah. Where
Speaker 1:  it's like Friday night and it's like, oh, is it movie night tonight? And
Speaker 1:  you're like, yes it is. And then it does the whole thing. Whereas instead
Speaker 1:  you have to come, it's proactive. Right. And, and, and when you have a personal
Speaker 1:  assistant, you talk to them. Right. It's not like, I know I
Speaker 3:  Don't want to talk,
Speaker 1:  But like If, you had a human personal assistant, you would talk to them and
Speaker 1:  they would ask you questions and that's, that's a fine set of interactions.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. You wouldn't have to say their name and then a series of words in the
Speaker 1:  correct order. Right. So, I think there's, there's a bunch of really interesting
Speaker 1:  interface questions there, but with the, with
Speaker 1:  the LLM stuff that everybody is betting on right now. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  The thing I keep thinking about is that what it will definitely do, I feel
Speaker 1:  very good about the fact that large language models are going to make
Speaker 1:  understanding your queries better.
Speaker 1:  Right. Like we, we have ample evidence now that for things like speech to
Speaker 1:  text and for natural language processing and text to speech LLMs are very
Speaker 1:  good. They're better than the systems we had before So I. Think the idea
Speaker 1:  that I'm going to be able to say that paragraph of things
Speaker 1:  that you just said to Alexa and it will understand them.
Speaker 1:  I feel very good about that. Yeah. It but as we've seen for 10 years,
Speaker 1:  that's only part of the process. Yeah. And LLMs don't solve any of the other
Speaker 1:  parts of the process. Yeah. And I think it, it, like, I think your,
Speaker 1:  your point about what Google and Apple can do here is, is really important
Speaker 1:  because A, they both have access to your phone, which gives them location
Speaker 1:  data, it gives them lots of information about your contacts, which is really
Speaker 1:  important. All this kind of stuff. I also think Google has a big advantage
Speaker 1:  because it's connected to things like your calendar and your email
Speaker 1:  more intimately in a lot of ways. And also has like your web search, which
Speaker 1:  is very powerful. Apple gets a lot of that because if it's Google deals,
Speaker 1:  like there's some weird antitrust things going on here, but Amazon doesn't
Speaker 1:  have any of that and really doesn't have a path to getting any of that in
Speaker 1:  any
Speaker 3:  Way that can tell unless feed it to it. Which is an extra step on yours.
Speaker 3:  On your part, right?
Speaker 1:  Sure. And I think like do I want to give Alexa
Speaker 1:  access to my Gmail is again, personal question choice. There are
Speaker 1:  probably upsides to doing that over time. Like
Speaker 3:  Kinda like trip it forward my emails. Right?
Speaker 1:  Exactly.
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  But I think like I, I have found myself using Gemini a lot to look
Speaker 1:  for information in my Google stuff and that's really
Speaker 1:  powerful and Amazon just has none of that. And so Alexa has none of that.
Speaker 1:  And I think if I were to like Galaxy Brain, all of the
Speaker 1:  crazy gadget launches Amazon has had over the years, they're so
Speaker 1:  desperate to put Alexa in front of you at all times that you will just
Speaker 1:  accidentally end up giving it all of that information. Seriously. Like and
Speaker 1:  I think that's not a crazy strategy, right? To say if you're wearing
Speaker 1:  glasses that have Alexa baked in, you're gonna talk to to Alexa more and
Speaker 1:  thus you're gonna tell it more information. You're gonna have it remind you
Speaker 1:  of more stuff. It might gain more information just by listening.
Speaker 1:  Like there are a lot of things they can do with that kind of ubiquity,
Speaker 1:  but A, it doesn't have that B, it's not going to anytime soon. And C, even
Speaker 1:  that I don't think is enough So, I get to this point where I'm like maybe
Speaker 1:  Alexa is about to get a lot better at the thing it was already good at and
Speaker 1:  not that much better at anything else. But maybe that's cynical.
Speaker 3:  Well it definitely feels like there is a big reset coming. I mean we got
Speaker 3:  the tease of the new Alexa or the remarkable Alexa as it's been
Speaker 3:  reportedly referred to in there was a big piece
Speaker 3:  by the Wall Street Journal sort of talking about all the problems
Speaker 3:  Amazon has had. And that was the rumor is that it's remarkable.
Speaker 3:  I think. I'm not sure about remarkable, I'm not a big fan of that, but anyway,
Speaker 1:  Also kind of a sick burn of 10 years of Alexa. Yeah. That's like we had
Speaker 1:  pedestrian and Alexa now we have Remarkable. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's tough. But you know, they have a new hardware Chief
Speaker 3:  Panos pane who friend
Speaker 1:  Of The Vergecast
Speaker 3:  Friend of The Verge cast who did not want to talk about New Alexa the last
Speaker 3:  time he did not had him on. No, he did not. Not at all. But he did
Speaker 3:  hint quite heavily that it's, it's coming.
Speaker 3:  And this year I picked up on in that conversation
Speaker 3:  and I think there is a big reset and we
Speaker 3:  haven't had a fall event this year. It's the first time in a while. So we
Speaker 3:  haven't had dozens of new devices. Mo we've instead there's been dribs
Speaker 3:  and drabs of news coming out over the last few weeks that you
Speaker 3:  would've totally been part of a big event. Like there's a new outdoor arrow
Speaker 3:  ring has finally got 24 7 recording new Kindle,
Speaker 3:  lots of Kindles, so many Kindles. There's also more devices going
Speaker 3:  away. Oh, interesting. We know the echo dot with clock
Speaker 3:  RIP that went a few months ago. Rumor has it, the Echo show
Speaker 3:  15 is on the outs. It's been outta stock for a long time.
Speaker 3:  More services being killed Alexa together, which was their
Speaker 3:  home care service, which I really, I thought was a, a great service.
Speaker 3:  But you know, we are seeing a big reset. We've seen Andy chassis has been
Speaker 3:  reported that he's sort of culling the devices and services division,
Speaker 3:  but I, I'm hoping that this is all in a sort of streamlined
Speaker 3:  effort for what I said at the beginning of the conversation is that they,
Speaker 3:  they had too much emphasis on gadgets and gizmos
Speaker 3:  and not enough on the core value proposition
Speaker 3:  of what the assistant can offer and trimming the craft
Speaker 3:  and hopefully bringing everything together in
Speaker 3:  a much more focused, usable way
Speaker 3:  with a, you know, better ui, better voice interface
Speaker 3:  powered by LLMs. I think, I know they have their own
Speaker 3:  Alexa MLLM, but there's been reports that they're also gonna be using,
Speaker 3:  I think, is it Claude? So there's, there's lots going on.
Speaker 3:  It's just a question of are they gonna get it right,
Speaker 3:  is it going to be a new hardware shift? Which would
Speaker 3:  be a tough sell because there's a lot of, a lot of
Speaker 3:  echoes out there. Yeah. But also I kind of feel like we need it, like the
Speaker 3:  Echo has sort of become, you know, a throwaway gadget.
Speaker 3:  You know, I saw so many reports in my research of people like, well I have
Speaker 3:  three or four echo dots in cupboards and
Speaker 3:  drawers and just don't use them because they're commoditized cheap and
Speaker 3:  you can buy them for $18 and there's no real expectation of anything
Speaker 3:  great coming out of a cheap piece of hardware on
Speaker 3:  your table. Yeah. You know, I, there's it, it's,
Speaker 3:  it's definitely a moment where I think they have
Speaker 3:  the opportunity to do something pretty
Speaker 3:  exciting just like they did 10 years ago when they launched Alexa
Speaker 3:  on November 6th, 2014. But are we gonna
Speaker 3:  get it?
Speaker 1:  Do you think Amazon is right to still call it Alexa? I think
Speaker 1:  what question we've been asking a lot is are the, are the
Speaker 1:  old ways of thinking about these voice assistants the right way to think
Speaker 1:  about the next wave of them? And Google is basically killing Google
Speaker 1:  assistant in favor of Gemini. Apple still seems to be using
Speaker 1:  Siri, but Apple Intelligence is very much the sort of bigger
Speaker 1:  umbrella brand than Siri is at this point. Amazon appears
Speaker 1:  to still be all the way bought into Alexa as the thing
Speaker 1:  and is very much going to sort of bake new technology
Speaker 1:  into all of the existing stuff rather than just kind of wiping the slate
Speaker 1:  and starting over. Do you think that's the right call?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so from talking to all three people at all three of
Speaker 3:  companies about this, it sounds like the technology, there's a, there's
Speaker 3:  a real disconnect between what the current voice assistants can do and what
Speaker 3:  the LLMs can do. And the LLMs cannot
Speaker 3:  do a lot of what the current voice assistants can do. Right. Like I
Speaker 3:  had heard rumors from one company that they basically were having to come,
Speaker 3:  you know, rebuild everything they had done for their previous voice assistant
Speaker 3:  for their new LLM. And it's like, why are we doing this, this, you know,
Speaker 3:  reinventing the wheel. So it feels to me like a merge, a
Speaker 3:  meshing or emerging of the two makes the most sense. But again, not an
Speaker 3:  engineer. This may be a technical impossibility. There may be too much technical
Speaker 3:  baggage buried underneath Alexa and Siri and Google's
Speaker 3:  assistant that just will not mesh with the future pathway.
Speaker 3:  But I think we need to keep the names, we do not need new names.
Speaker 3:  That's fair. That, that's just, that seems like a non-starter to me and
Speaker 3:  especially for Amazon. I mean they spent a decade building a very
Speaker 3:  recognizable brand that they constantly tell me people love, like people
Speaker 3:  love their Alexa. I think that's true.
Speaker 1:  I think people think Siri sucks and Alexa is great.
Speaker 1:  Yes, yes. Limited but great
Speaker 3:  And Google's smarter.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, well Google assistant is kind of, it's like the, the nerdy weird kid
Speaker 1:  in the corner, right? That it's like, it's very cool, but no one really talks
Speaker 1:  about it. But it's, it does some impressive stuff. But
Speaker 1:  I do think it's true that I think, I think you could have made the case that
Speaker 1:  walking away from Siri would've been a smart move for Apple. Yes. Just given
Speaker 1:  the baggage of Siri. I don't think Alexa has that baggage. I think no, people
Speaker 1:  mostly have settled into this thing is for music and timers, but like you
Speaker 1:  said, it costs $18, so who cares? And now if Amazon
Speaker 1:  can say, oh, this thing that you bought now has incredible new capabilities,
Speaker 1:  that's really powerful. Yeah. I I I, it remains to be seen
Speaker 1:  whether that is the case. And I think with a lot of LLMs, we continue to
Speaker 1:  be sold a bill of goods that is not based in reality
Speaker 1:  in a lot of ways. Yeah. But also I tend to think you're right.
Speaker 1:  I I I could imagine a world in which Amazon is like, here's a whole new brand,
Speaker 1:  we're changing everything. But also like these things are everywhere.
Speaker 1:  They're pretty simple hardware and it's all in the cloud anyway.
Speaker 1:  So like if they can just suddenly upgrade everyone's speakers in some massive
Speaker 1:  way, that becomes, that becomes pretty powerful.
Speaker 3:  Well my original Echo, which is in my husband's garage according
Speaker 3:  to Dave Limp at the event last year will be updated to support the new Alexa.
Speaker 3:  It might have
Speaker 1:  Another 10 years in it, it might,
Speaker 3:  Who knows. Yeah. I mean that's pretty impressive. And that's, that's a whole
Speaker 3:  infrastructure that I don't see Amazon getting rid of and
Speaker 3:  yeah, I think that is, that's the, that's the right move.
Speaker 3:  Make Alexa smarter and it the capabilities and the
Speaker 3:  possibilities just get, get really interesting. I'm excited to see what they
Speaker 3:  can do. I just want them to hurry up and do it. I
Speaker 1:  Know you and me and everybody at this point, but here's what we're gonna
Speaker 1:  do. You're gonna have to come back when they launch it, which as far as we
Speaker 1:  know might be in like the next couple of weeks, like next
Speaker 3:  Week. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But we're both going to review whatever the new Alexa is on the very first
Speaker 1:  echo. I'm gonna find mine, it's somewhere and we're gonna talk about it.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna have 10-year-old hardware with brand new software and we're gonna
Speaker 1:  see if it, if magic has really happened
Speaker 3:  In that. Sounds like a good plan. Awesome.
Speaker 1:  Alright Jen, thank you as always. Again, I suspect we will see you again
Speaker 1:  very soon.
Speaker 3:  Sounds good. Thanks. See
Speaker 1:  Ya.
Speaker 3:  Bye.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 1:  take a question from the Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 1:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot
Speaker 1:  com. We love all of your questions. Please keep sending them,
Speaker 1:  keep calling in. Hearing from you is the absolute best. We got a
Speaker 1:  bunch more episodes to do this year, cannot wait for your
Speaker 1:  hotline questions. Love everything that everybody's been sending. Thank you
Speaker 1:  as always. This week we have both a question
Speaker 1:  and a product idea about AirPods. Hear it.
Speaker 6:  Hey Vergecast, this is Kyle calling in from Texas and I had a question for
Speaker 6:  y'all. I was listening to your episode on the new hearing aid updates to
Speaker 6:  Apple's AirPods. And while the new update sounds exciting and I'm looking
Speaker 6:  forward to seeing how people benefit from the testing capabilities and hearing
Speaker 6:  aid functionality, your discussion got me thinking don't
Speaker 6:  kill me. But I sometimes do the same thing that y'all mentioned where if
Speaker 6:  I'm ordering something I just take one of 'em out. And in most social settings
Speaker 6:  nowadays that seems to pretty consistently communicate that you're listening
Speaker 6:  to the other person, especially since nearly all headphones, pauses, whatever
Speaker 6:  you're listening to. But since that doesn't work for those using AirPods
Speaker 6:  as hearing aids, I had an idea, what if Apple added LEDs
Speaker 6:  to their headphones? This would, hi, keep copying Samsung's
Speaker 6:  new models. But even though it would take some time for everyone to learn,
Speaker 6:  it might allow you to tell if someone else wearing AirPods can hear you
Speaker 6:  speaking to 'em. It would kind of be like the way Apple tried to have eyesight
Speaker 6:  on the Vision Pro communicate where the user is paying attention, but
Speaker 6:  hopefully not in a way that's deeply in the uncanny valley. I thought
Speaker 6:  it was a fun idea, but maybe we'll instead we'll just get used to people
Speaker 6:  wearing headphones in public. But I was really interested to hear if y'all
Speaker 6:  thought it might work. Thanks again so much for taking my call. Love
Speaker 6:  the show. Bye.
Speaker 1:  Okay, I shared this call for two reasons. One because
Speaker 1:  I actually think it's an awesome idea and I think the idea of putting
Speaker 1:  some kind of notification LED on AirPods
Speaker 1:  to signal really whatever you want it to signal, but in this case it would
Speaker 1:  be to signal that they're in hearing aid mode actually fits with what we're
Speaker 1:  seeing from a lot of technology right now, right? He mentioned
Speaker 1:  the face stuff on the Vision Pro, but to me this sounds more like
Speaker 1:  what you see on the latest run of Smart Glasses. Probably the easiest
Speaker 1:  example is the RayBan Meta Smart Glasses where they actually
Speaker 1:  have a light that says essentially you're being recorded.
Speaker 1:  And I think that stuff is still pretty new and we're still figuring it out.
Speaker 1:  And I mean you rewind back to Google Glass and the idea of there being a
Speaker 1:  light suggesting that you were being recorded didn't actually help
Speaker 1:  anybody and just made everything feel gross and bad and didn't solve a lot
Speaker 1:  of problems. But I think we're at a point now where those kinds
Speaker 1:  of things can be communicated, right, where you're saying,
Speaker 1:  okay, this is, this is listening to you in some way. And I actually think
Speaker 1:  the idea of using an LED to mean essentially you are being
Speaker 1:  captured by my device in some meaningful way kind of works, right? Whether
Speaker 1:  it's the camera is on and I can see you and I'm taking video of you
Speaker 1:  or my headphones are capturing what you're saying and feeding it to me.
Speaker 1:  Either one of those If you that all the way down is just you are being captured
Speaker 1:  in some way. And I think if that's all we need these LEDs to signify,
Speaker 1:  that can really work. It'll take some marketing work to get people to
Speaker 1:  understand that and it'll take some time for it to sort of societally catch
Speaker 1:  on. But I would actually rather land in
Speaker 1:  that place than just pure, constant acceptance
Speaker 1:  of headphones. Because if we get to the point where you're wearing headphones
Speaker 1:  and I still assume that I can talk to you, I think that's bad and
Speaker 1:  I think that's wrong. Frankly, in a lot of ways, headphones as a signal
Speaker 1:  of leave Me alone are actually really powerful and valuable.
Speaker 1:  And also it's just true that a lot of the times when you're wearing
Speaker 1:  headphones you can't hear other people. So having a much more aggressive
Speaker 1:  signal that says, I can hear you. I am capturing you in some
Speaker 1:  way works for me. So I, think that's a great idea. I hope Apple does something
Speaker 1:  like it. I think we might be giving Samsung a little too much credit.
Speaker 1:  Samsung just like put LEDs on the Galaxy Buds
Speaker 1:  three pro that don't really do anything. I think they light up when you
Speaker 1:  turn on the find my feature, which like, sure, but they
Speaker 1:  can't show battery, they don't show when they're, you know, in various
Speaker 1:  modes. There are a bunch of things they could do there. I think the lights
Speaker 1:  actually look good in Samsung's case, they're mostly just aesthetic, but
Speaker 1:  it's proof that you could do something like this. And I think that's very
Speaker 1:  compelling. So I'm in favor of this idea a hundred percent. I hope Apple
Speaker 1:  does it, but the other reason I share this is because we get a lot of feedback
Speaker 1:  from people when Chris Welch and I talked about the hearing aid mode on the
Speaker 1:  AirPods, and especially when we talked about the societal
Speaker 1:  shift that is coming for headphones, and I think I've been
Speaker 1:  pretty blase about it to a certain extent, right?
Speaker 1:  Like I look at my nephews who are both teenagers,
Speaker 1:  they most of the time just have one AirPod in and I don't really think anything
Speaker 1:  of it, but then I talk to lots of other people who view that as
Speaker 1:  rude and off-putting and deliberately removing yourself from a
Speaker 1:  social situation in some way. I'm confident they don't see it that way,
Speaker 1:  but it might be that way. Anyway, So, I think that
Speaker 1:  piece of it is complicated and it's not gonna get easier. But
Speaker 1:  if we want these devices to be these kinds of always on
Speaker 1:  augmented reality devices that are genuinely useful for people's
Speaker 1:  health, but also more and more useful just in day-to-day life for
Speaker 1:  people, that is going to require
Speaker 1:  these huge societal changes. So either we get, you know, the LEDs
Speaker 1:  or we're gonna have to figure out the right and wrong ways to wear
Speaker 1:  headphones. And I would just wanna know what everybody thinks about that.
Speaker 1:  This is the thing we've gotten a lot of feedback about. I'd like to hear
Speaker 1:  your thoughts too. How should we think about headphones
Speaker 1:  in the real world, especially as headphones become more than
Speaker 1:  just music devices, as they become something that actually augments your
Speaker 1:  ability to go through your life while also being a way to listen to music
Speaker 1:  And TikTok, how do we navigate that? What is the right
Speaker 1:  answer for headphones? Should we enter a world where we're all wearing headphones
Speaker 1:  all the time and we just kind of figure it out? Should headphones just be
Speaker 1:  outlawed forever? And things that are hearing aids should look like hearing
Speaker 1:  aids? Is there an interesting answer somewhere in between both
Speaker 1:  culturally and in product? I wanna hear all your feedback. This has turned
Speaker 1:  out to be a much bigger, more interesting thing than I expected.
Speaker 1:  So please hit us up. I want to hear everything. We're gonna keep talking
Speaker 1:  about this in more and more ways in the coming months because I think this
Speaker 1:  matters in some pretty big ways. Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today.
Speaker 1:  Thank you to everybody who was on the show. Thank you for listening. Thank
Speaker 1:  you for calling the hotline. Thank you for being part of this with us. There's
Speaker 1:  lots more about everything we talked about, including this like mini package
Speaker 1:  of stories we did about the legacy and future of Alexa at the
Speaker 1:  verse.com. I'll link to all of it in the show notes, but as always, read
Speaker 1:  the verse.com. It's a big week this week. Go vote If. you haven't
Speaker 1:  voted yet. And if you're listening to this on Tuesday in the United States,
Speaker 1:  go vote. Read our election package. Lots of great stories in there.
Speaker 1:  Read the endorsement, go vote. Best of luck. To everybody out there, as
Speaker 1:  always, If, you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other Alexa devices
Speaker 1:  you would like to set off inside of my house. You can always email us at
Speaker 1:  vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline. It's six six VERGE one
Speaker 1:  one. we love hearing from you. This show is produced by Liam James, Wil Poor
Speaker 1:  and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is VERGE production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 1:  podcast network. Neil, and I'll be back on Friday to talk about,
Speaker 1:  honestly, I couldn't even guess at this point because it's an election week
Speaker 1:  and I suspect we'll be talking about that plus some other product news plus
Speaker 1:  a bunch of Apple stuff that's shipping this week. Lots to do. We'll see you
Speaker 1:  then. Rock and roll