# Transcript
ID: 3a60e263-c544-408f-bf77-e95435db80e3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8023180389053704756/-1405572123636034953/s93290-US-4711s-1707091902.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the Apple Vision Pro review rating, changes to the TikTok app, streaming news, and more.
Speaker 2:  Hello. And Welcome. To Vergecast, the flagship podcast of putting windows
Speaker 2:  all around you and then walking around them and looking at
Speaker 2:  them and being in the future.
Speaker 5:  The future. Yeah, that's iTunes most specific genre.
Speaker 2:  It's Vergecast. I'm your friend NELI. David Pierce is here. Hi Alex. Cranz
Speaker 2:  is here. Hi. I'm your
Speaker 7:  Friend that really misses Microsoft's windows.
Speaker 2:  The HoloLens people are so mad at me.
Speaker 2:  They're like, how did you do this whole review? And you never mentioned HoloLens,
Speaker 2:  the thing that invented spatial compute, and it's true, Microsoft invented
Speaker 2:  a number of these words with no regard for what they meant.
Speaker 2:  They're like, HoloLens is mixed reality. That means augmented reality,
Speaker 2:  this VR headset and windows. That's Windows mixed reality. Like just
Speaker 2:  anything. Yeah, any, all the words meant the same thing. And I have done
Speaker 2:  some very cool HoloLens demos in my life. I put on a
Speaker 2:  HoloLens and I changed a spark plug on an A TV in
Speaker 2:  the basement of a Microsoft building and it it guided me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it put arrows like, go to this drawer, open this drawer, I
Speaker 2:  don Dunno if any of that was real or if it was totally state, whatever it
Speaker 2:  was awesome. I was like, this is definitely the future of changing spark
Speaker 2:  plugs in an A TV as long as the room is set out exactly right and the computer
Speaker 2:  knows where all the parts are. Like this is how we should change spark plugs.
Speaker 2:  Which by the way, if you set up the room exactly right and you know where
Speaker 2:  all the parts are, you no longer need the computer to change the spark plugs
Speaker 2:  because you
Speaker 5:  Put the spark plugs where they go,
Speaker 6:  It's,
Speaker 2:  But whatever. You outsource that. But they were like, imagine a, a mechanic
Speaker 2:  on an airline. And now I'm like, man, I wish Boeing had bought more HoloLens.
Speaker 2:  They're also in Seattle. Just putting that out there. Microsoft, the
Speaker 2:  problem with the, the HoloLens, oh, and I did a very cool demo. Microsoft,
Speaker 2:  one of the few companies in VR that has ever solved co-location.
Speaker 2:  So I wore a HoloLens and someone else was wearing a HoloLens and
Speaker 2:  we were looking at the same thing at the same time. And like I would
Speaker 2:  interact with, it was like a model of something and I would interact with
Speaker 2:  it and they would spin it the other way. And no one else, as
Speaker 2:  far as I can know, very no other company is on a, a commercial scale. I don't
Speaker 2:  think the Quest headsets can do that. The Vision Pro can't do it. Okay, that's
Speaker 7:  Cool then.
Speaker 2:  Right? So I, I to all credit to HoloLens, the HoloLens
Speaker 2:  is a gigantic failure, which is why I
Speaker 2:  didn't mention it. It failed as a product.
Speaker 2:  The person who was leading the project got forced out of Microsoft for sexual
Speaker 2:  misconduct allegations. They did a bunch of layoffs on the team.
Speaker 2:  They've reorganized their hardware portfolio and they say quote, and this
Speaker 2:  is a real quote, we'll make a next version of the HoloLens when the time
Speaker 2:  is right.
Speaker 7:  Oh, there you is. It is it. Right.
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 2:  you know what they're gonna do? They're gonna make a bunch of AI stuff and
Speaker 2:  print money instead of being like, you can change a spark plug with our glasses
Speaker 2:  on.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I'll, I'll never be able to change a spark plug
Speaker 2:  Though. Yeah. Anyway, so shout out to the HoloLens people. I just,
Speaker 5:  HoloLens also objectively the coolest product name in this entire
Speaker 5:  category.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. A hundred
Speaker 5:  Percent. No question. HoloLens kicks ass.
Speaker 2:  It's good. It's a good name. Yeah. And the first one was cool and the second
Speaker 2:  one was even better. From what I'm told, I never tried the second one. And
Speaker 2:  you know, if, if you have the perfect spark plug set up,
Speaker 7:  Are
Speaker 2:  You that thing kicked ass?
Speaker 7:  Are you saying you, you don't fondly remember the Acer ah,
Speaker 7:  1 0 1 db EY
Speaker 7:  Windows mixed reality headset that had a good day. That's a good ring. Say
Speaker 7:  it
Speaker 5:  Slower. Slower.
Speaker 2:  But Addie and I just decided what the words would mean in our
Speaker 2:  review. We made a sidebar. We're like, this is what mixed reality means and
Speaker 2:  this is what augmented reality means. And then Addie was like, you know,
Speaker 2:  this is a flip of how Microsoft wanted it. And it's like, I don't care.
Speaker 2:  Like I'm putting my foot in the ground and this is what we're saying. Anyhow,
Speaker 2:  so that shout out to the HoloLens people. I feel you. It was a cool
Speaker 2:  demo.
Speaker 5:  Did any magic leap people get at you?
Speaker 2:  The Magic Leap people were just happy to be mentioned,
Speaker 2:  Right? Like your product is a true AR product. Optical AR
Speaker 2:  that has fatal compromises in it and no one should buy. They're like, oh
Speaker 2:  my God. Finally the validation we deserve some people, I
Speaker 2:  will say two things. Some people, I basically called the top on
Speaker 2:  two technologies in this review. I said, camera based pass
Speaker 2:  through has is might be a dead end. And I, I feel that it might be a dead
Speaker 2:  end. And I said, hand and eye tracking it. There's a
Speaker 2:  part of it that's valuable for some things, but it's also a dead end. It
Speaker 2:  cannot be the primary input. And I heard from people who've been working
Speaker 2:  on this who have shipped, wait,
Speaker 5:  Sorry, real quick. We should just say, by the way, this is your review of
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro, which went up this week. We talked a bunch about it on Tuesday.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. But if, if you, if you haven't been living inside of Eli's brain
Speaker 5:  for the last week or so, he's talking about the Apple Fission Pro,
Speaker 5:  which we just got to so fast.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say that's what I, no, this is right. I woke up, I used this
Speaker 2:  app called Sleep Cycle on my, to my, my alarm clock. And
Speaker 2:  yesterday I woke up and it basically congratulated me on finally
Speaker 2:  getting some sleep. Oh boy. It was like, good job. You've got
Speaker 2:  400% more sleep last night than you've been getting.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, this is a disaster. So yeah, I'm wired now. I've like got
Speaker 2:  too much sleep. But the amount of caffeine, I've basically only eaten Cinnamon
Speaker 2:  Toast Crunch this week. It's bad. All of it's bad. The inside of
Speaker 7:  Your mouth after that much Cinnamon Toast Crunch.
Speaker 2:  Well, I didn't eat it all in one go. Yeah, but it's, it's cumulative.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It it's cumulative in that each bowl is 25 grams of sugar.
Speaker 2:  We'll miss you. Yeah. I'm just like, why the crash is gonna be bad.
Speaker 2:  We're not buying this anymore. But that's, I would like get home and be like,
Speaker 2:  what can I eat? You know, like fast cereal cereal and I was like this
Speaker 2:  cereal. Anyhow. Yes. Vision Pro Review. I heard
Speaker 2:  the, the, the two things in my view that I, that were like the big
Speaker 2:  ideas that I didn't overly highlight is a Vision Pro is the best version
Speaker 2:  of a device with camera based pass through and hand and eye tracking they've
Speaker 2:  ever seen. And I was like, it might have inadvertently proved that these
Speaker 2:  are deadheads and I have heard from people who have shipped
Speaker 2:  millions of devices with camera pass through and who have invested
Speaker 2:  millions upon billions of dollars and hand and eye tracking. And they
Speaker 2:  were like, you have a point about camera pass through.
Speaker 2:  It's good for what it's good for and like it's not a dead
Speaker 2:  end if you use it. Right. But Apple's trying to make it do too much, which
Speaker 2:  I thought was really interesting feedback.
Speaker 5:  That's fair. Because it is like on the, on the Quest three, it's useful in
Speaker 5:  spots, right? It's like the, I'm playing a VR game and I like double tap
Speaker 5:  on the headset and it opens up So I can like see what's around me or whether
Speaker 5:  I just kicked my dog or whatever. But it's not like you don't, you don't
Speaker 5:  live in the pass through. And so for that, I think pass through works fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Apple is like default state is passed through and I think, I think
Speaker 5:  that might be where it's pushing too hard.
Speaker 2:  There's a really cool app that Gen two E posted on the site where
Speaker 2:  it's shortcuts. Yeah. And you can put it the shortcuts all around your house.
Speaker 2:  So you get all these shortcuts by your TV and all this stuff and that's really
Speaker 2:  cool. It's like, oh, but to use that, you have to word this all the time.
Speaker 2:  Right? So not no longer useful. So it, this is the
Speaker 2:  argument, this is a simulator of what Apple really wants, but they're like,
Speaker 2:  look, camera pass through has its uses, but if you try to
Speaker 2:  pretend it's ar you're gonna run into the problem. We agree with you there.
Speaker 2:  And then the note about eye tracking and this person has spent a lot of money
Speaker 2:  on eye tracking in their life was you are overloading an
Speaker 2:  input channel by trying to use it for output, which is
Speaker 2:  fascinating.
Speaker 5:  We had explain, so
Speaker 2:  Your eyes are an input channel, so you're used to taking in a lot of
Speaker 2:  information with your eyes or an input channel and then you overload it by
Speaker 2:  trying to use it as an output channel to control the device. Oh, that's smart.
Speaker 2:  And so the the, the feedback was you, you hit on something that
Speaker 2:  this industry has been talking about for a long time. Hmm. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 2:  you can't overload your input channels as output channels. And you'll run
Speaker 2:  into this problem with eye tracking because you have to look at what you
Speaker 2:  wanna look at and you have to look at what you wanna control instead of what
Speaker 2:  you're looking at.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Because historically eye tracking was just to like enhance it.
Speaker 7:  So like if you kind of glanced to one side, the camera would move so you'd
Speaker 7:  see what was ever whatever was over there. Yeah. That's
Speaker 2:  Like render, that's foveated rendering,
Speaker 7:  Right? Yeah. And it didn't really well
Speaker 2:  Like, but that's to save processor cycles.
Speaker 7:  Right. But no, it it also made it a smoother experience. It made it like
Speaker 7:  less, oh I'm just staring at some screens. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. So you It's a blurry. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It made it a nice experience. And even when you do it just on a regular
Speaker 7:  laptop screen, I did a, I reviewed way too many Toby laptops once
Speaker 7:  upon the time. It was really useful 'cause you could just kind of look at
Speaker 7:  things and, and it would pop up and make it a little brighter and make it
Speaker 7:  a little easier. But like anytime I would try to like control the computer
Speaker 7:  with it, I was like, oh I hate this. Yeah. Because I'd like glance at my
Speaker 7:  watch and my character just start running around in circles.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And this is overloading and input channels output. So you, when you
Speaker 2:  use it the way you're describing Yeah. For foveated rendering for highlights.
Speaker 2:  Right. That make it a little brighter. You're enhancing the input channel.
Speaker 2:  Right. When you use an output channel, you might overload yourself. So this
Speaker 2:  person was like, yeah, in the history of eye tracking, this is a thing that
Speaker 2:  we understand. And then they said, I had it wrong
Speaker 2:  on hand tracking. Oh, that there's, the industry
Speaker 2:  believes in hand tracking. They're gonna get it right because it is the most
Speaker 2:  natural way of doing things and there's a lot of work being done.
Speaker 2:  I keep pointing at it's the computer is always washing hands and the vision,
Speaker 2:  regardless of that joke, the Vision Pro does mis register. A lot of hand
Speaker 2:  input also cannot differentiate between your hands and someone else's hands.
Speaker 7:  Also, you personally look really goofy doing it in the office.
Speaker 7:  It's, it was so good. Wait,
Speaker 5:  Hold on. So if you're just sitting at your desk on the Vision Pro, I can
Speaker 5:  just stick my hands in front of your face and start literally typing
Speaker 5:  on your keyboard.
Speaker 2:  Sure can. Or, or you can just put your hand in front and click your fingers
Speaker 2:  together and it'll register a click.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna do this
Speaker 5:  Tot you so much when I see you, I can't wait
Speaker 2:  To do this assuming that I'm wearing the headset. What a good prank. It's
Speaker 2:  a good prank. So you screw people like the, when I say the thing is lonely,
Speaker 2:  it does not contemplate anyone else being around you who is not on their
Speaker 2:  best behavior. Which is all the time all other people are not on their best
Speaker 2:  behavior.
Speaker 7:  Is it just assuming that like the pass through will suddenly pop on and you'll
Speaker 7:  see David being like Yew,
Speaker 7:  I assume that's the noise David's gonna make.
Speaker 5:  That's what I do when I type. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The only AR features in it specifically it recognizes
Speaker 2:  David Peterson makes that sound So I.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, I thought this was all really interesting feedback 'cause people
Speaker 2:  who have been working on this stuff for a long time were like, we like to
Speaker 2:  review, here are the things we think you got right, right and wrong. And
Speaker 2:  the camera based pass through as a replacement for
Speaker 2:  true AR feels directionally correct to me. Right.
Speaker 2:  This it might be the ceiling for that eye tracking. They're like
Speaker 2:  yeah, you know, people are gonna react to it differently. We'll see this
Speaker 2:  is the first big eye tracking at scale that will
Speaker 2:  happen. And then they're like, you're just wrong in hand tracking. So we'll
Speaker 2:  see. I the fact that like it just mis registers input to me
Speaker 2:  is again, people are gonna, by the time you are listening to this, people
Speaker 2:  will have them. By the way, I, Justine has already worn a Vision Pro on a
Speaker 2:  cyber truck just
Speaker 7:  Immediately. Yes. Like as soon as the embargo lifted she was walking
Speaker 2:  Out the truck and she's, I mean she's funny as hell. So like I appreciate
Speaker 2:  that she did that. Yeah. But like some other kind of YouTuber, not I, Justine
Speaker 2:  who is wonderful, some other kind of YouTuber is gonna do the actual thing
Speaker 2:  with the cyber truck and the Vision Pro and with the clock is just ticking
Speaker 7:  Unsafe. Don't do that. Don't
Speaker 5:  Don't do it.
Speaker 2:  They're not gonna listen to us. They're doing it for the views man. Don't
Speaker 7:  Do it for the clicks. Do something else. Cool.
Speaker 2:  Do the, so we'll see. I'm excited for people to actually get their hands
Speaker 2:  on this outside of just experiencing other people's experiences
Speaker 2:  and I'm, I'm very curious to see how people react to hand and eye tracking
Speaker 2:  in particular.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Also, if you got one as you're hearing this on Friday
Speaker 5:  the second, it's the day this stuff is coming out. If you got one, call us
Speaker 5:  and tell us about it. We'll this will be a super fun thing to do on the hotline
Speaker 5:  for the next few weeks. I just wanna hear people's experiences. Yeah. With
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro. Tell us what you're doing. Tell us what's cool. Tell us what
Speaker 5:  sucks. Give us, give us your like 62nd review of the Vision Pro.
Speaker 5:  Literally whenever you want. Call the hotline. Send us emails. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  I'm dying to know. You can tell me, tell I'm, tell me I'm wrong. Whatever
Speaker 2:  you want. I I'm dying to know how you feel about this product 'cause it is
Speaker 2:  new and that's what's exciting about it, which leads me into the score. So
Speaker 2:  a lot of people have asked me about the score and I will tell you, and David
Speaker 2:  in particular will tell you that I drove myself crazy
Speaker 2:  trying to give this thing a score after I'd written the review. Yes. Confirmed
Speaker 2:  bonkers. Like, 'cause I'm the one who says World of no sevens
Speaker 2:  and I gave it a seven. It's like, oops. So if You don't know World of
Speaker 2:  no sevens, the thing I say all the time, which is you seven is just the
Speaker 2:  default score. It is milk toast. And so if you say world of oh
Speaker 2:  sevens, it forces you to make a very hard choice between six and eight.
Speaker 2:  And I am the person who says this and I definitely gave this thing a seven
Speaker 2:  and I tortured myself over that seven. And
Speaker 5:  You got it wrong.
Speaker 2:  And David thinks I should have given it. You got it
Speaker 7:  Wrong. I, I tend to agree with, I was genuinely shocked 'cause I, I didn't
Speaker 7:  participate in the review, but, but we, you know, we did The Vergecast and
Speaker 7:  So. I went as soon as it posted and I click and I scrolled down and I saw,
Speaker 7:  saw that seven and I was like, but we, it felt like a six in The Vergecast
Speaker 7:  that we recorded. This is interesting.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I sat on The Vergecast and I have to own this. Yeah. Inconsistent
Speaker 2:  input system is a full point deduction. And at that moment in time, and I,
Speaker 2:  this is a hundred percent true, the score that was
Speaker 2:  entered into our little score database was a six. Oh mm. What? And I
Speaker 2:  said that knowing that I'd already typed the six into that database, what
Speaker 7:  Pushed you back up to a seven? I
Speaker 2:  Had a conversation with Verin and Becca in particular. Becca
Speaker 2:  are wonderful video directors who u made this whole review with me and
Speaker 2:  used it a lot in the course of that review. And they
Speaker 2:  reminded me that it was really fun.
Speaker 7:  So so it lost a point for inconsistency. Gained a point because
Speaker 7:  it's fun as hell.
Speaker 2:  It lost a point for Incon. Vien was we, we were re we were like, we were
Speaker 2:  in it. We were like, we opened up our own how we rate page and like read
Speaker 2:  our own definitions of the numbers. Like you're in and office
Speaker 2:  with people for hours upon hours arguing with the dumbest. Like you just
Speaker 2:  like fall down the rabbit hole completely. We discussed bringing back
Speaker 2:  decimals, which we had got rid of a couple years, like the whole thing.
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 2:  Vern's line was we need a, we need a number that means fantastic but useless
Speaker 2:  'cause that he's like, this is fantastic. I have no idea why I wanna use
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 5:  What about the number that says it's $3,500?
Speaker 5:  Do you know how many you want fun buying a Nintendo Switch and you'll have
Speaker 5:  $3,200 left. Isn't that cool?
Speaker 2:  So look, like I say I was at six for a long time. Yeah. It was a six.
Speaker 2:  I I swear to you it was a six and Becky was like, but you have
Speaker 2:  had like the thing you are doing the, you were constantly talking
Speaker 2:  about this thing that you keep coming back to like I'm lonely in here is
Speaker 2:  'cause you're having fun and you want other people to have fun with you.
Speaker 2:  Which is not how I feel about the Meta quest, which is like, this is fun.
Speaker 2:  Like, nah, I'm swinging a bat around like there's not a point where I'm look
Speaker 2:  at this thing that you is wild that I want you to see. Like the
Speaker 2:  art gallery of webpages that I made in our cafe. I was like, this is cra
Speaker 2:  like nothing else can do that right now. The me Quest can sort of do it,
Speaker 2:  but they're kind of shaped like this is like perfectly locked in place windows
Speaker 2:  and you can just leave the room and come back. That's your point is it was
Speaker 2:  fun. It was a full point deduction for the stuff I complained about and
Speaker 2:  it it earned its way back into the seven zone.
Speaker 2:  'cause it's not an eight. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. I was gonna say it was never an
Speaker 2:  Eight. It was, there was no point. Was this thing getting an eight?
Speaker 7:  Did it ever go to five
Speaker 2:  So I was texting with Dan Sert. Yes. Wonderful reviews that are number one
Speaker 2:  Dex fan in the world. Dan Sert traitor. Dan just left The Verge. So he was
Speaker 2:  not part of this review. We wish him well on his new journey in life. It's
Speaker 2:  gonna be really fun for him. But Dan texted me after the review and was like,
Speaker 2:  seven, huh. And I was like, dude. And like
Speaker 2:  literally people were jumping out of the woodwork to quote Dan at me
Speaker 2:  throughout this process because Dan's quote is, you never regret giving
Speaker 2:  something a lower score ever. Like if you just
Speaker 2:  instinctively pick the lower score and you won't won't, it's five years from
Speaker 2:  now you won't have regretted it. You might be like, ah, I gave that stupid
Speaker 2:  thing in eight. Why'd I do that? Yeah, but you'll never be like, I judge
Speaker 2:  it too harshly. Like literally I'm like walking down the street and people
Speaker 2:  are like, you know what Dan would say? He's like haunting me.
Speaker 5:  And I will say that's not, that's not a like judgment
Speaker 5:  decision. That's not saying like we reflexively hate products. That is like
Speaker 5:  a decade of hard worn experience. Yeah. And this is the mistake that you
Speaker 5:  made NELI is you got sucked in by the thing being fun. Like
Speaker 5:  that's a stupid reason. It's just a stupid reason.
Speaker 5:  Like this is a $3,500 computer. You don't judge your MacBook
Speaker 5:  on whether it's fun. You judge it on whether it does the things it is
Speaker 5:  supposed to do. And this fundamentally doesn't it? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There are a lot of things that it is supposed to do that it either doesn't
Speaker 5:  do or doesn't do very well and it is $3,500.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 2:  Look, I take the criticism and I, I look, I knew
Speaker 2:  what I was buying. I was buying a bunch of people telling me that I did give
Speaker 2:  in a high score, including David on this very podcast. I knew how this
Speaker 2:  Vergecast would start today when I gave it that seven. You did.
Speaker 5:  But wait, I just, I just wanna point at the tension of this, which I think
Speaker 5:  is both the tension you felt in reviewing this. And the reason we all think
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro is so interesting is that it is objectively
Speaker 5:  cool and new and interesting, right? Like the Joanna Stern, our friend of
Speaker 5:  the Wall Street Journal made a video and there's a moment in it where she
Speaker 5:  sets two timers and puts them over two different things on her stove.
Speaker 5:  Like that kicks ass. It's so small and so silly, but
Speaker 5:  it's so cool and people really responded to it. That is not a reason to buy
Speaker 5:  a $3,500 product or to wear a headset on your face all day. but it
Speaker 5:  is. Which she said, right. but it is cool. It is
Speaker 5:  undeniably cool. The shortcuts thing you were talking about is like undeniably
Speaker 5:  cool and I wanna live in a world where that is part of my life. I will not
Speaker 5:  wear the headset and I will not buy the headset in order to get that thing.
Speaker 5:  But like that's that tension, right, where you have these moments where you're
Speaker 5:  like, oh this is it. Like they, they did it, this is it. And then you have
Speaker 5:  to weigh that against what is this thing I have on my face? What does
Speaker 5:  that mean for like my life? Is this worth the cost? And you even said in
Speaker 5:  the review, right? We, we review things not just based on like what they
Speaker 5:  might be someday, but what the thing is in the box. But that is so
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 2:  But that's not, that's not what got it to seven. I I that's my rule.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  A good rule. It's the right rule, but it's, it's so hard to do, especially
Speaker 5:  in this case because a apple has a longer history of being
Speaker 5:  right about these things than most. So like most of the time you
Speaker 5:  genuinely should not assume this thing will ever get better for any reason.
Speaker 5:  Because most of the time it doesn't with Apple it usually does. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  so you have to believe that more than with most companies. But then also
Speaker 5:  it's 3,500.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so here's how I've that price thing also wait on
Speaker 2:  my mind. Another good argument for six, if it's a phone review
Speaker 2:  and even in in phone reviews now it's like you're just reviewing iPhones
Speaker 2:  for people who buy iPhones. You're very rarely writing a review for
Speaker 2:  somebody with an Android phone. Totally. Except for like blunt curiosity.
Speaker 2:  If the camera's good or bad,
Speaker 2:  my assumption going into this was that I was not writing buying advice. The
Speaker 2:  people who are buying the Vision Pro are buying the vision pro whether or
Speaker 2:  not I think it's good or bad. So what was that score speaking? So the score
Speaker 2:  was like, okay, like however many they sold 80,000, 120,000.
Speaker 2:  The vast majority of people are gonna try this thing on. And my guess is
Speaker 2:  after a while they're like, yeah it's seven and like that is where that came
Speaker 2:  from, right? Is eh, it kind of works a all the time. But oh man,
Speaker 2:  Sometimes I have really good time Like that, that exact thing. The reason
Speaker 2:  it's world of no sevens is the that is why I got there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Because sometimes you're like, oh this is great. And then sometimes
Speaker 2:  you're like, I'm looking at the look at the right and
Speaker 2:  like that is like a okay but real challenge in there. 10
Speaker 2:  years from now, it's not broken. The last Apple product I gave a six to was
Speaker 2:  the Apple Studio display whose webcam basically shipped an unusable
Speaker 2:  state. Right. And I was like, this is six. 'cause this display technology,
Speaker 2:  the panel is fine, but the backlight technology is steam powered
Speaker 2:  and this camera's effectively broken six. And that was what,
Speaker 2:  $1,200? $1,300.
Speaker 5:  $1,600.
Speaker 2:  1600. I should have given that a
Speaker 5:  Five. Yeah, you should have That's what I was about to say. You scored that
Speaker 5:  thing too high.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. Maybe I'm just wrong, but
Speaker 5:  I will say a bunch of people pointed out the similarities between what
Speaker 5:  this thing is and what the original Apple Watch was, which I think
Speaker 5:  is really interesting because you gave both a seven and I think you were
Speaker 5:  right about the Apple Watch and wrong about this. And I've been trying to
Speaker 5:  figure out what it is. Interesting. I know what it is.
Speaker 2:  Wait, wait, I wanna hear what David series. I
Speaker 5:  Have two theories. One for it is $3,500
Speaker 5:  and the other is, I think the first Apple Watch got
Speaker 5:  the form factor almost right. And hadn't quite figured
Speaker 5:  out the use case, but it was like still a nice thing to where I got furious
Speaker 5:  at the first Apple watch because it didn't tell the time. Yeah. The screen
Speaker 5:  wasn't on all the time. Like how dare you a watch if you don't tell me the
Speaker 5:  time when I look at you. but it it like the, the
Speaker 5:  thing was there, right? It was close enough to being what the thing should
Speaker 5:  be and it already did some of the things you would want it to. So it was
Speaker 5:  like, that felt closer to me than this in which the thing
Speaker 5:  itself is nowhere near what it's supposed to be. Nope. Not even close. And
Speaker 5:  so that's where it loses me. Like I deduct a full 0.4. Absolutely
Speaker 5:  no one thinks this is what this is supposed to look
Speaker 2:  Like. Yeah. I will say I feel very vindicated by the modern
Speaker 2:  rereading of the Apple Watch reviews. I got raked over the Kohls for giving
Speaker 2:  that thing a bad score. Yeah, it holds
Speaker 5:  Up. It really does.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, this thing is a, I believe I used the word bobble. I was
Speaker 2:  like, this thing is a bobble and you will buy it if you, and if you buy it,
Speaker 2:  you will like it because people like Bobs, but it is not fashion.
Speaker 2:  It is technology that looks like fashion and they need to figure out what
Speaker 2:  it's for. And it took them three generations to get there and they
Speaker 2:  totally rebooted the software. And I was like, no one will ever. And like
Speaker 2:  for a long time people were like, you were just unnecessarily harsh. And
Speaker 2:  this time like literally our screenshots comparing my two reviews
Speaker 2:  being like, oh, this is the same exact thing and the only thing I will
Speaker 2:  remind everyone of is one, I was right. I'll always remind you that. No,
Speaker 2:  but two,
Speaker 2:  the, the path wasn't set when the thing was launched.
Speaker 2:  Right. So being like this thing happened to the Apple watch means it will
Speaker 2:  happen to the other thing they had to adjust.
Speaker 2:  Right. And actually the review is like, it adjusts them.
Speaker 2:  Like they take the feedback from the market, from the customers, from the
Speaker 2:  reviewers and they like make decisions based on it. And one of
Speaker 2:  the big decisions they had to make along the way was we are totally rebooting
Speaker 2:  watchOS to make the interface different, to completely
Speaker 2:  decrease our reliance on third party apps in an app store.
Speaker 7:  You're just telling me your watch review should have been a six,
Speaker 5:  But also Apple with the Apple watch. And this is true of a lot of Apple things,
Speaker 5:  right? Apple starts by getting the hardware pretty close to Right.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna,
Speaker 5:  The software away it's
Speaker 2:  Alex will be joining Dan Seavert in the world Beyond.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Can we just re-review every Apple product we've ever done right now
Speaker 5:  Let's just rescore them all. I
Speaker 2:  Have a lot. Yeah, go ahead.
Speaker 5:  The the watch hardware was very close and then the question is how do we
Speaker 5:  make this thing into what it ought to be inside of
Speaker 5:  this box? And Apple. Apple usually gets the box, right? In this case neither
Speaker 5:  one of them is right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Well it like the watch shipped to people and they could use it
Speaker 7:  and they could set it up and they didn't have issues with it and lots of
Speaker 7:  people bought one
Speaker 2:  Wait, famously Carl Lagerfeld could not set his up and really she does not.
Speaker 2:  Do you not know about this? This is like an old ette joke. Carl Lagerfeld
Speaker 2:  was photographed, you know, they gave it to all the fashion people beginning.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They photographed Carl Lagerfeld wearing proudly wearing it with the
Speaker 2:  setup screen on the face.
Speaker 2:  And that's like we call, we started calling it Lagerfeld where you're just
Speaker 2:  like wearing a dead Apple watch just as a, as a fashion accessory. That's
Speaker 2:  awesome. but
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 7:  Again, that was another reason to give it a seven because it was like a fashion
Speaker 7:  thing. Not necessarily a good one, but it was fashion. And this is just like
Speaker 7:  such a developer kit. Yeah. That I keep m like I keep thinking about
Speaker 7:  that a lot. Like it feels like such a developer kit.
Speaker 2:  They, they just won't say it man. There was a story in Vanity Fair, a
Speaker 7:  Beautifully photographed story in Vanity
Speaker 5:  Fair. It was
Speaker 7:  Stunning.
Speaker 2:  A photograph story in Vanity Fair. Tim Cook is wearing the headset.
Speaker 5:  He's blinking. Yeah. Did you notice this? His
Speaker 2:  Eyes are closed.
Speaker 5:  His googly eyes on the front of the headset are closed. He's blinking in
Speaker 5:  the photo.
Speaker 2:  That's very funny.
Speaker 5:  It's fantastic. They
Speaker 2:  Should put that on the website. Anyhow, there's a story in
Speaker 2:  Vanity Fair and it is, I mean honestly a story could be from 10 years
Speaker 2:  ago. I know Nick Bilton who wrote it. Nick is a very nice guy. I've had a
Speaker 2:  taco at a party at his house before. Like he's a very nice guy,
Speaker 2:  but it could have been written 10 years ago about vr. Right, right. Like
Speaker 2:  the line is like Tim Cook saw himself on on the moon. He knew it was the
Speaker 2:  future. Like that line has been written about Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 2:  and Palmer. Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah you could have just like done find and replace Magic
Speaker 7:  Leap for every time they say Vision Pro at that review.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you remember a Magic Leap? Was it Wired that ran the story
Speaker 2:  where Yes. Ronney Ovitz was like, I'm hacking the GPU of your brain. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Like we've just been here man. Like
Speaker 2:  and So I think Apple can't say it's a developer kit. They can't
Speaker 2:  place themself in the long line of companies that have
Speaker 2:  been doing this for a long. They have to say it's finished. Which is why
Speaker 2:  they have to, they have to have entertainment and they have
Speaker 2:  to do this. James Cameron is in that Manny fair piece quoted as
Speaker 2:  saying this will change everything. And it's like, dude, you have done more
Speaker 2:  scuba diving VR than anybody.
Speaker 7:  I have been thinking about that quote specifically more than anything else
Speaker 7:  that's come out of this whole situation. Yeah, because James Cameron is
Speaker 7:  like, not generally a guy. I was gonna say he's not generally a
Speaker 7:  guy prone to hyperbole, but he did once declare himself king of the world.
Speaker 5:  Don don't know if that was hyperbole at some point,
Speaker 2:  At that moment in time. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But when it comes to like technology, he's not usually a guy prone to hyperbole.
Speaker 7:  And so when he's like, no, this changes everything and he's specifically
Speaker 7:  talking about the display technology. Yeah. Like, which sounds really, really
Speaker 7:  incredible. I was like, is there something there? Like have we missed
Speaker 7:  something that James Cameron is seeing and that we're not besides like
Speaker 7:  the inside of the headset?
Speaker 2:  It is legitimately amazing display technology. I I have nothing but admiration
Speaker 2:  for how hard it was to build those displays. They are genuinely amazing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. They are available apparently on the market. The same person
Speaker 2:  who told me hand tracking being something they believed in was like, you
Speaker 2:  know, Meta could have bought those. Like they, that was a thing that Meta
Speaker 2:  had the opportunity to buy. But Meta is a version of headset would've been
Speaker 2:  even more expensive because Meta doesn't have
Speaker 2:  M1 chips or M two chips. They would've had to go and buy chips with more
Speaker 2:  power and more battery and they're like, this is, we can't go this way. Right.
Speaker 2:  So Apple uniquely was able to make use of these displays,
Speaker 2:  which are again an engineering marvel. But like
Speaker 2:  James, they're just better than what you have now. Right.
Speaker 2:  They're just like linearly better than the thing you have now. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  that if you're James Cameron, like you should be able to see like,
Speaker 2:  yeah, this is the step. Like this is the step change that changes at all
Speaker 2:  is like not the thing.
Speaker 7:  I really wanna like sit him down and be like, did they just like cherry pick
Speaker 7:  your quotes here.
Speaker 2:  They run Apple TV plus man. I know. Like
Speaker 7:  I need, I just need to know more from Jim. Jim call me. I know you listen
Speaker 7:  to Vergecast. He does.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  We'll talk about the the sub too. Jim
Speaker 2:  Was a guy who told me about Meta. He's the source. If you're listening Tim
Speaker 2:  Cook. That's not true at all. Not, not even like the slightest picture.
Speaker 2:  A little bit. It's, it's, by the time you're listening to this, it is will
Speaker 2:  be out. I'm sure some of you are driving. Your car is wearing it right now.
Speaker 2:  Stop it. Pull over to the side of the road.
Speaker 2:  Apple today. A little bit more Apple announced along with the
Speaker 2:  launch division Pro 600 apps will be at
Speaker 2:  launch. Which seems like a good number.
Speaker 7:  It's a lot
Speaker 2:  For, for a new platform. It's a good number. Is it? I think So
Speaker 5:  I mean it's fine. It's some apps. But like this is the company that spends
Speaker 5:  a lot of time talking about hundreds of thousands of apps and millions of
Speaker 5:  apps. 600 is is
Speaker 7:  Good. I'm gonna point out, I once got really roasted for being, for
Speaker 7:  complaining about how few games launched with a Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 7:  Granted I did say it when Zelda came out and it was one of the best games
Speaker 7:  ever made.
Speaker 2:  But like, here's the 600 apps. I don Six
Speaker 7:  Hundred's.
Speaker 2:  Impressive 600 is great.
Speaker 5:  600 is Vision Pro, like built for spatial computing.
Speaker 5:  It's also gonna have all the iPad stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  1 million apps. 600 Vision Pro apps. Sure. Which I will
Speaker 2:  just point out is
Speaker 2:  999,900 600. 999,400.
Speaker 5:  400.
Speaker 2:  400. Yeah. No, that's a a hundred. That's a million. Yep. Okay. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  do this math right. Math please leave this in. No,
Speaker 2:  do not leave this in. Leave it in. Everyone's gonna find Dan if we leave
Speaker 2:  this in.
Speaker 2:  All right. Which I'll just point out is
Speaker 2:  999,400 iPad apps.
Speaker 2:  That's a lot. iPad apps.
Speaker 7:  That's a lot. iPad
Speaker 2:  Apps. Anyway, among this, it's 600 is not bad if it's the right 600. But
Speaker 2:  I'll just point out among the 600 they announced
Speaker 2:  compatible apps from top cable services including Charter
Speaker 2:  Spectrum, Comcast, Xfinity, Cox Contour, sling tv, and Verizon
Speaker 2:  Fios.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's what I want.
Speaker 2:  If you are rocking the Verizon Fios app space, like I,
Speaker 2:  what are you doing man?
Speaker 2:  Like paying your bills. If you, if you buy the space computer
Speaker 2:  and take it out of its little marshmallow and put it on your head, you're
Speaker 2:  like, let's open the Charter Spectrum app. What are you doing
Speaker 2:  man?
Speaker 7:  Well you gotta pay your bill so you can keep downloading stuff. Like
Speaker 2:  It's, it's, that is the funniest. And that obviously you're trying to point
Speaker 2:  out like
Speaker 7:  Entertainment.
Speaker 2:  It's entertainment. It's
Speaker 7:  Not Netflix,
Speaker 2:  It's fine. Do you know what those apps, streaming four 80 p that they lie
Speaker 2:  is seven 20 p. That is the lowest bitrate video you can get.
Speaker 2:  Which is hilarious to me because I,
Speaker 2:  this is all buried in the review. I should quick post on this side just to
Speaker 2:  break it out. It will not support VR video on YouTube. It's just like won't
Speaker 2:  do it. Right. And they're like, because the VR video on YouTube is too low
Speaker 2:  quality
Speaker 7:  Apple.
Speaker 2:  So it doesn't have a YouTube app. And if you go try to watch on 360 video
Speaker 2:  on YouTube, it just won't work the end. Can I say
Speaker 2:  one more Weedsy thing and then we can break out of this go? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's very weedsy, but people asked us this question a lot
Speaker 2:  and I didn't know the answer when we did the old episode. How does it smell?
Speaker 2:  How does it smell? Okay. It smells like the future. Obviously
Speaker 2:  the faintest whiff of roasted marshmallows.
Speaker 2:  People ask about the MAC display sharing and I finally know how It works,
Speaker 2:  which is very complicated. It is basically a 27 inch like studio
Speaker 2:  display or iMac display. So you tell your Mac, you're sharing to it, your
Speaker 2:  Mac imagines a 27 inch 5K display. Ah mm. It
Speaker 2:  runs the interface at 25 60 by 1440, which is a perfect two to one
Speaker 2:  scale. That's how a 27 inch iMac works by default. You cannot change
Speaker 2:  it. So a 27 inch iMac display can run it at other resolutions and it'll be
Speaker 2:  fine. This one, it says it gives you a low resolution warning. So it wants
Speaker 2:  to run at this two to one scale, then it takes that 5K
Speaker 2:  display and sends it as a 4K video stream to the Vision Pro, which you, you
Speaker 2:  can then resize it will no. So it is not Pixel perfect at all. It
Speaker 2:  looks great. I I have no complaints about how it looks, but the thing that
Speaker 2:  is happening is that it is imagining a 5K display that a Mac knows how
Speaker 2:  to run at because that is the 27 inch I mac, the 27 inch studio
Speaker 2:  display. It runs the interface at 25 60 by 1440. But if you're running something
Speaker 2:  4K, it has enough pixels to just do it 'cause it's 5K display. But then the
Speaker 2:  thing that is happening is streaming at
Speaker 2:  4K to the Vision Pro. So it compresses that and it makes us
Speaker 2:  smaller.
Speaker 7:  It sounds both technologically cool and also like I just
Speaker 7:  hate it from in the same way. I hate when people say Yeah this is
Speaker 7:  seven 20 P streaming. Yeah. When it's secretly four 80.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Or lies. Or if they're like, this is hd. Yeah. And it's seven 20 lies Fox
Speaker 2:  just putting that out there. Anyway, everyone will ask me that question and
Speaker 2:  I that is the answer. And so it, it is correct. They keep calling it a 4K
Speaker 2:  Mac display. It's actually a 5K Mac display, but it's actually running at
Speaker 2:  25 60 by 1440 and whatever. It looks fine and you'll
Speaker 2:  use it unless you need Pixel perfect accuracy. In which case take your face
Speaker 2:  All right, that's enough. Talking with our eyes. Let's talk about our ears,
Speaker 2:  huh?
Speaker 5:  All right, lay on this plane in Patel. Let's go.
Speaker 2:  I tried. It's been such a long week. The Cinnamon Toast Crunch Crash
Speaker 2:  is real man. It's happening
Speaker 7:  In real time in front of me.
Speaker 2:  Just melting over here. No, it's big news. This maybe bigger news
Speaker 2:  than vision, bro. I, it's bigger news than it will impact more people more
Speaker 2:  directly. Okay. Yeah, that's true. Cause more damage to the economy than
Speaker 2:  you can I imagine. Josh Hawley is gonna write a build about it soon.
Speaker 2:  The Universal Music Group in a fight with TikTok has pulled its catalog
Speaker 2:  from TikTok. Its catalog includes Taylor, Swift,
Speaker 2:  Drake, Olivia, Rodrigo Bad Bunny, basically
Speaker 2:  I think U2 is in the mix.
Speaker 5:  Billy Eilish is on here. Harry Styles, Justin Bieber. Adele,
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All of
Speaker 2:  Them. Universal. CEO Lucian Grange, who by the way was profiled in the New
Speaker 2:  Yorker this week talking about his worries about the music industry in generated
Speaker 2:  AI obviously ahead of them pulling
Speaker 2:  their music from TikTok. They said TikTok has offered them horrible terms
Speaker 2:  and is trying to bully them. They were this bad news for and
Speaker 2:  it's gone. If you go look at Taylor Swift on TikTok right now, her catalog
Speaker 2:  is gone. All those videos, all of those TikTok videos that have Taylor Swift
Speaker 2:  and Olivia Rigo and all those other arson copyright notices.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And there's just a huge portion of TikTok that is now silent.
Speaker 5:  It's nuts. And I assume this is ultimately just a negotiating
Speaker 5:  tactic on both sides. And they'll, this feels to me sort of like a carriage
Speaker 5:  dispute with cable companies where it's like it's actually in everybody's
Speaker 5:  interest to resolve this. And they will. but it Universal is clearly
Speaker 5:  trying to prove that it is willing to pick this fight because I think
Speaker 5:  TikTok has reached a point that, like I've been thinking a lot about Roku
Speaker 5:  reading about this. 'cause there was this long period of time where Roku
Speaker 5:  was like every streaming company's favorite
Speaker 5:  streaming platform because it didn't have competitive content, it wasn't
Speaker 5:  an advertising business, it was just the place people bought hardware to
Speaker 5:  go to apps. And that was perfect for all the apps. Right. And so everybody
Speaker 5:  worked with Roku even when they wouldn't work with each other. When Apple
Speaker 5:  and Amazon were beefing, they still both worked with Roku and then Roku got
Speaker 5:  big enough that it said, we are going to start selling
Speaker 5:  advertising on our own and we're actually gonna start making our own content
Speaker 5:  and we're gonna start competing with you. But we're so powerful now that
Speaker 5:  there's nothing you can do about it. Yep. And, and Roku started sort of just
Speaker 5:  eating chunks of that market away. And it had gotten so big that there was
Speaker 5:  nothing any of these players could do about it. And I think TikTok believes
Speaker 5:  it is now that powerful. Yeah. That TikTok grew so much
Speaker 5:  on the back of essentially like Goodwill and free marketing for all of these
Speaker 5:  record labels and all the music being out there and became this like center
Speaker 5:  of culture and now is turning around and saying like, look how
Speaker 5:  powerful we are. You're gonna play by our rules now. Yeah. And I think Universal
Speaker 5:  is one of the few companies probably in a position to actually hold
Speaker 5:  fast against that.
Speaker 2:  Especially 'cause of its table of artists. And Universal, to be clear,
Speaker 2:  is a big old school bully record label.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like Lucian Grange is a very good operator. He has led the music
Speaker 2:  industry through Universal through many shifts and he gets what he wants.
Speaker 2:  Yep. He's the one who, when Fake Drake showed up on YouTube
Speaker 2:  is Lucy and Grange who pushed YouTube and Google into being like, here
Speaker 2:  are responsible AI things and here's a new monetization system for
Speaker 2:  AI generated music on YouTube. I dunno, that's great for the world. It's
Speaker 2:  great for Universal music. Yes. Yeah. Right. And that's, that's his job.
Speaker 2:  And he's gonna, but he has shown the ability to bully
Speaker 2:  platforms using his gigantic catalog of artists. Right.
Speaker 2:  And the artists all like him because,
Speaker 5:  And there's hardly anybody with that specific kind of leverage against these
Speaker 5:  platforms. Yeah. And he's,
Speaker 7:  He's going after AI in this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Specifically he wants protection against Generat of AI on this platform
Speaker 2:  just as he has it on YouTube. I think the difference between TikTok and YouTube
Speaker 2:  in this context is that YouTube is a music listening
Speaker 2:  platform. And this is long confused, like YouTube itself, like
Speaker 2:  YouTube YouTube, Google, very data-driven organizations.
Speaker 2:  Susan Ky, the former CEO of YouTube used to say things like, we're a music
Speaker 2:  service. Because if you look at the data, the thing people
Speaker 2:  do the most on YouTube is they listen to music. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. There's literally a stat on YouTube that is most
Speaker 5:  watched non-music, video video on YouTube. Yeah. Like that's how big
Speaker 5:  music is, is like Mr. Beast keeps breaking the non-music video
Speaker 5:  record. Yeah. Right. 'cause that's YouTube is music videos slash
Speaker 5:  everything else. Right.
Speaker 2:  Oh, right. And like the lo-fi beats girl, like Yeah. People turn on YouTube
Speaker 2:  and they just like get access to music. Yeah. And so YouTube is a
Speaker 2:  streaming and they, you know, they YouTube music exists and they, they've
Speaker 2:  grown this thing and YouTube knows that. You know,
Speaker 2:  Google executives now will tell you YouTube is a licensing product. Google
Speaker 2:  searches a fair use product. YouTube is a licensing product. They know they
Speaker 2:  need these relationships with the labels to preserve the existence of YouTube.
Speaker 2:  Especially 'cause what people do the most is they just listen to music. Right.
Speaker 2:  TikTok is a discovery platform. Right. So and that is
Speaker 2:  where their power comes from. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But I think I, I think music is still like intrinsic to its
Speaker 7:  success to
Speaker 2:  It, but
Speaker 7:  It has
Speaker 2:  To listen. But TikTok to Spotify is the pathway there.
Speaker 7:  Right. For, for music. But I'm saying for TikTok, the reason people
Speaker 7:  go watch this stuff is because it's music. Like Right. But it's everybody
Speaker 7:  doing cool
Speaker 2:  Soccer. But if your TikTok what you, what the data is showing you is people
Speaker 2:  discover new songs on TikTok and then they go to Spotify and listen to them.
Speaker 2:  Right. And you're saying to the music industry, you will not be able to
Speaker 2:  break new artists to a younger generation without us. So you believe that
Speaker 2:  you have all this, whereas YouTube is looking at its data and saying if the
Speaker 2:  music goes away, all of this is gone.
Speaker 7:  Right. But I, I think UMG is saying you need us because
Speaker 7:  otherwise the kids won't have any content to do their dances to,
Speaker 2:  But they they will have other, this is the TikTok bet, right? Right. If your
Speaker 2:  TikTok is, this is how you end up here, you're saying there will be other
Speaker 2:  music.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They're hoping that somebody else is as big as Taylor Swift, which
Speaker 7:  is like Right bold. Travis Kelsey is gonna start his own record. Like
Speaker 2:  Right. The Super Bowl is in two weeks. This is a bad time to not have Taylor
Speaker 2:  Swift on your, on your, on your platform.
Speaker 5:  Well it's an interesting one though because like the, the, the three names
Speaker 5:  we put in our story, which I think is sort of fascinating, are Taylor Swift
Speaker 5:  Drake and Olivia Rodrigo. Right. I think Taylor Swift obviously does not
Speaker 5:  need TikTok. TikTok is more in need of Taylor Swift
Speaker 5:  than Taylor. Swift is TikTok. Right. don don't think that's arguable Drake.
Speaker 5:  Same. Olivia Rodrigo, interesting case. Olivia
Speaker 5:  Rodrigo very famous artist came up on Disney channel, had lots of things,
Speaker 5:  but also her music broke in a big way on TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Would Olivia Rodrigo be as big as she is now without TikTok?
Speaker 5:  Who knows. Right? And, and she's huge. And I think ev the,
Speaker 5:  I think you're right that the bet TikTok is making is that everyone who is
Speaker 5:  not an a plus plus list artist
Speaker 5:  needs TikTok more than TikTok needs them because there're, it is just an
Speaker 5:  infinite supply of up and coming musicians all over TikTok
Speaker 5:  everywhere.
Speaker 2:  Right. Are you gonna break the little Boothing guy without Universal music?
Speaker 2:  Like maybe you are right? Maybe. Yeah. What's the other look? Is
Speaker 2:  TikTok just gonna do sea shanties? Yes. Maybe like,
Speaker 2:  you know, like, do you remember Ricky desktop? We did a profile, lets see,
Speaker 2:  Ricky desktop,
Speaker 5:  The DJ guy.
Speaker 2:  He did the dice, beat the boat, beat the chicken wing beat. And then he,
Speaker 2:  he was like, oh, now I'm a real producer and he won't talk to us anymore.
Speaker 2:  Aw I don Ricky desktop. If you're out there, man, I hope you made it dude.
Speaker 2:  Chicken Wing beat was fired.
Speaker 5:  It was,
Speaker 2:  It was. But like that's tiktoks bet is there's an infinite supply of new
Speaker 2:  things to discover in Universal's. Bet is. You need rr like we have
Speaker 2:  the stars.
Speaker 7:  That's why I think this is fascinating. Like historically, I I just thought
Speaker 7:  it was really interesting both because what David said earlier about how
Speaker 7:  this is like the fights with the carriage fees. Yeah. It's the same thing.
Speaker 7:  Like, oh, we are in a new entertainment age where now these fights are no
Speaker 7:  longer happening between TV companies and, and big studios. They're happening
Speaker 7:  between music companies and big social media platforms. And that's just
Speaker 7:  like, that's a we're in a whole new space. Yeah. And, and, and
Speaker 7:  it's still rapidly developing. And now you have this whole generation of
Speaker 7:  kids and it's like, okay, they're gonna stay on this platform that is doing
Speaker 7:  their girl Taylor dirty, which is certainly a messaging that UMG can and
Speaker 7:  has pushed. Yeah. Or are they going to,
Speaker 2:  Are you gonna protect Taylor Swift against ai? Yeah. That's what all Universal
Speaker 2:  has to say. And the, the tiktoks right answer right now is like no.
Speaker 5:  Well, and given, I mean a Taylor Swift is Taylor Swift,
Speaker 5:  but also what's been happening with this, like the, the images that
Speaker 5:  non-conceptual generative AI stuff of Taylor Swift on Twitter like
Speaker 5:  this is, I I would not purport to
Speaker 5:  say that Universal timed this intentionally and perfectly, but boy, if they
Speaker 5:  did, did they time it perfectly? Well,
Speaker 2:  Their contract was up on January 31st. They, they, the contract was
Speaker 2:  pages ago. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The timing just worked very well for them. But, but it did. And I think
Speaker 5:  it is all of these things are very much coming together. And also one other
Speaker 5:  wrench to throw in here is TikTok is relentlessly trying to
Speaker 5:  close the TikTok to Spotify pipeline with TikTok music,
Speaker 5:  which it is continuing to work on and continuing to test and continuing to
Speaker 5:  roll out all over the world. And so TikTok is
Speaker 5:  becoming this thing where if It works and if TikTok music works,
Speaker 5:  it's going to just like take the whole music industry
Speaker 5:  inside of it. Yeah. And so if you're Universal you're like, okay, if we sign
Speaker 5:  a bad deal now and TikTok music hits it suddenly becomes a really
Speaker 5:  bad deal because now there's no, there's no out, there's nowhere to go because
Speaker 5:  we've lost a whole generation of music listeners to this one
Speaker 5:  app and service.
Speaker 2:  Can I just, can I offer you some very, I just realized this, a very funny
Speaker 2:  media inside baseball drama tidbit. Sure. The New
Speaker 2:  Yorker this week has a profile of Lucian Grange. Conde
Speaker 2:  Wired's cover this month is Z Show the
Speaker 2:  CEO of TikTok. And they're just like battling it out across the covers of
Speaker 2:  Conde Nest. It's pretty good. It's very good. I, but that's like where
Speaker 2:  we're at, right? Like these people are out in public trying to advocate for
Speaker 2:  themselves. I think TikTok is in danger. Look, I've called the top on this
Speaker 2:  episode on camera pass through and eye tracking. I feel
Speaker 2:  like we're close to calling the top on TikTok. Wow.
Speaker 7:  Really?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If you TikTok, you know, it's a pandemic phenomenon.
Speaker 2:  They didn't just grow through like good vibes. They bought billions
Speaker 2:  of dollars of Facebook advertising to get app installs. Right. So
Speaker 7:  And that really pop Was it musically?
Speaker 2:  It was musically. They bought musically and you know, they've got AI and
Speaker 2:  the recommended, but like, this is a pandemic phenomenon that felt really
Speaker 2:  good in that time. Like everyone's together, we're all doing these dances.
Speaker 2:  Like we create cultural moments.
Speaker 7:  We need to escape life and all we have to do is flick.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. And here's all these people talking. We're all baking bread.
Speaker 2:  The the kids are doing call and responses in department stores. You remember,
Speaker 2:  you know, like they would all yell the thing and they yell the other like,
Speaker 2:  what was it? It was, it was dirty.
Speaker 2:  Which is great. That's what I love. Yeah. It was just fun. Like
Speaker 2:  kids are terrifying. Their parents with this app is like, that's what we're
Speaker 2:  here for. That's why The Verge exists, and now it's in the middle of
Speaker 2:  what Co Doc Toro would call the in acidification cycle. Right? Right. So
Speaker 2:  TikTok is no longer full of organic wonderful content from people
Speaker 2:  who are bored in the pandemic. It's full of people trying to sell you stuff.
Speaker 2:  Right. Including TikTok and more, more so than YouTube. Right.
Speaker 2:  YouTube, you can have AdSense and you can just make videos and YouTube runs
Speaker 2:  the pre-rolls and you get some money. And that's the end of that. The,
Speaker 2:  the TikTok creator fund does not work that way, and it like doesn't even
Speaker 2:  pay that much money. So if you get success on TikTok, you
Speaker 2:  immediately start looking for a brand deal. Right. And you, you just see
Speaker 2:  this, this thing happen so fast, and so it has
Speaker 2:  just become like less good feeling in the
Speaker 2:  same way that I would, I would say Instagram has had the exact same problem.
Speaker 2:  Like Instagram is influencers now it's a
Speaker 7:  Catalog.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. It's a, and TikTok is just headed that way and they've added
Speaker 2:  the TikTok shop and now they're doing this thing where they're incentivizing
Speaker 2:  horizontal videos Yeah. That are over a minute long to compete with YouTube
Speaker 2:  and they're gonna add this music service. And you're like, you're getting
Speaker 2:  farther and farther away from the thing that made it
Speaker 2:  worth spending billions of dollars to at Appens install. Well,
Speaker 7:  They're, they're doing the Elon Musk. They're trying to do an an Everything
Speaker 7:  app.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, maybe. I just think like, when you open it, it's no longer like,
Speaker 2:  here's a bunch of delightful things that are hap like it and maybe I just
Speaker 2:  need to reset my algorithm or something.
Speaker 5:  No, it's, it is what it is. I mean, and now like, I think the TikTok shop
Speaker 5:  is the thing, right? Like, I hate it. If you wanna point at one thing, if
Speaker 5:  you wanna call the top Yeah. It's the TikTok
Speaker 2:  Shop. By the way, to be clear, I'm not calling. I'm saying I feel comfortable
Speaker 2:  saying we might be close to calling the top. No,
Speaker 5:  NELI called the top. You heard it here first. Everybody done
Speaker 5:  four outta 10 on TikTok for me, like
Speaker 7:  Hour.
Speaker 5:  But no, the, the shop, not only did the TikTok shop come in
Speaker 5:  and all of a sudden two outta three videos you saw was somebody trying to
Speaker 5:  sell you something from the shop. John Herman at New York Mag wrote a really
Speaker 5:  good piece about, he did a live stream after putting
Speaker 5:  a used pencil in the TikTok shop and got thousands of
Speaker 5:  viewers because TikTok just absolutely boost engagement
Speaker 5:  through the roof as long as you're selling something. And now TikTok is running
Speaker 5:  a test. We had a story this week where it's actually identifying
Speaker 5:  products in videos with AI and offering purchase links to
Speaker 5:  them. So not only is it incentivizing everybody to deliberately sell you
Speaker 5:  stuff, it is going to sell you stuff even when you don't mean to sell stuff.
Speaker 5:  And all of the incentives on this platform now are going
Speaker 5:  to be to sell you stuff from the TikTok shop, which by all accounts is being
Speaker 5:  wildly subsidized and everything's very cheap and it's all sort of sketchy
Speaker 5:  and weird. But like that is going to break this platform faster
Speaker 5:  than anything else.
Speaker 7:  I have a question. Yeah. About the shop. Do you guys, like when you see the
Speaker 7:  little orange button, do you just scroll Yeah. Past it as
Speaker 2:  Quickly as possible? When I see the live indicator or when I see the TikTok
Speaker 2:  shop, I'm like gone. Except same, same. There's one that gets me every time
Speaker 2:  and it's wrecking my whole algorithmic situation. It is
Speaker 2:  constantly trying to sell me off-brand DeWalt batteries.
Speaker 7:  And you're like, Ooh,
Speaker 2:  I get so many TikTok shop live streams for like, you can buy five DeWalt,
Speaker 2:  six amp hour batteries for just 20 bucks. Look at how well they're, and it's
Speaker 2:  like, those are gonna light my house on fire and I just keep watching. They'd
Speaker 2:  be like, are they gonna light on fire in this video?
Speaker 7:  And it's also just QVC feel like anytime I see the live ones, I'm like, I,
Speaker 7:  I don't watch QVC when I had like television. Why am I gonna do it on a TikTok?
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 2:  Gotta go buy some batteries. I, it's in my brain. You think about
Speaker 7:  It. Yeah. They got you.
Speaker 2:  It's not even QVC. It's just a guy being like, look at these, look at how
Speaker 2:  cheap these batteries are. Yeah. Seriously.
Speaker 5:  It's, yeah. It's not even as good as QVC. Like QVC tries a lot harder than
Speaker 5:  this. But I also think like this, this is the same thing. And this is TikTok
Speaker 5:  feeling itself, right? Yeah. I think Instagram, somebody wrote this, I think
Speaker 5:  it was John Herman, but if it wasn't, I'm, I'm stealing this thesis from
Speaker 5:  somebody else. So to whoever it was, I'm sorry, I forgot who you
Speaker 5:  are. But Instagram has sort of identified this
Speaker 5:  same thing where it's like, what if we made everything for sale but has done
Speaker 5:  it very slowly and carefully because there is a sense of like, we don't wanna
Speaker 5:  ruin the experience or at least not ruin it very quickly. TikTok doesn't
Speaker 5:  give a shit about that. Yeah. TikTok is just like, oh, you like our
Speaker 5:  app shopping now. And there is this sense of like, TikTok I
Speaker 5:  think feels like it is inevitable now. Like it has won in a way
Speaker 5:  that it can now turn on anything. It can change the algorithm. It can say,
Speaker 5:  oh, we're doing horizontal videos now. It's literally going 90 NELI TikTok
Speaker 5:  is going, literally going
Speaker 2:  90. Oh my God. I'm not ready to do that at all.
Speaker 5:  No, I'm not even saying in reality, the app is going 90.
Speaker 2:  They want
Speaker 5:  You to make horizontal videos.
Speaker 2:  So one of my favorite things to do, this is gonna make me sound very pretentious
Speaker 2:  when I say it. Whenever I leave America,
Speaker 2:  I like to read books about America.
Speaker 2:  It's just like a thing. I, I
Speaker 7:  Also just tuck into some Tocqueville as soon as I leave.
Speaker 2:  Not like that.
Speaker 2:  I'm just
Speaker 5:  Magic Neil. I just like unfurling the Pledge of Allegiance on the plane.
Speaker 2:  Not like that. So one of my very favorite books is called The Conquest of
Speaker 2:  Cool. It is about the American advertising in the sixties,
Speaker 2:  after all the GIS came home and they got money and
Speaker 2:  that's when the counterculture started. And it, it is, if you like Mad
Speaker 2:  Men, you should read this book. 'cause it is the thesis of Mad Men, right?
Speaker 2:  Is we're gonna take the counterculture, we're gonna take rebellion, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna repackage it and sell it to people. And that means Americans just our
Speaker 2:  culture is like kind of sarcastic and ironic all the time,
Speaker 2:  right? Like we, we sell rebellion here in America and like selling out it,
Speaker 2:  this is the most sellout our culture has ever been, but it's still like,
Speaker 2:  ah, you sold that. Like that's, we're just not as sincere people here in
Speaker 2:  the United States of America. Other countries are very
Speaker 2:  sincere, which is why I always read about our culture when I go, because
Speaker 2:  the contrast is real. And so you can see a little
Speaker 2:  bit of that over commercialization because Instagram is
Speaker 2:  American company that feels very American. Like it understands the thing
Speaker 2:  that it is, and it knows it can't just slam shopping into your face
Speaker 2:  culturally, the designers, the product managers atmosphere, like there's
Speaker 2:  a lot of people who live here. Like it's an American product in that way,
Speaker 2:  that it's American. They try to be very global. Like Instagram is huge all
Speaker 2:  over the world. I I'm not denying that. I'm just saying there's a cultural
Speaker 2:  aspect to the product's design that is reflective
Speaker 2:  of the fact that you cannot just walk up to an American and be like, buy
Speaker 2:  the shit. Like, it just kind of does. It sometimes just doesn't work, right?
Speaker 2:  Like there's, there's a little bit of ironic detachment that we accept here
Speaker 2:  that we expect here. TikTok is just it rep
Speaker 2:  it is a Chinese company. And I think there's a little bit of that.
Speaker 2:  Like the reason there's everything apps in China, if you go to those places,
Speaker 2:  they're ultra commercialized in a very different kind of way. Yeah. And I
Speaker 2:  think, I'm not even saying it's good or bad, I'm just saying that, that it's
Speaker 2:  a different culture. No,
Speaker 7:  You, you can feel it. 'cause I think I also see it with
Speaker 7:  how we're very reviews driven in this, this culture. Like in, in America,
Speaker 7:  you go on Amazon, you go to places and you still are checking like, okay,
Speaker 7:  does this have a good score? Am I gonna get this? And, and that, that shop
Speaker 7:  app is like,
Speaker 2:  No. So there's none of it, none of that.
Speaker 7:  It's just like you wanna buy it, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There's just a different vibe. Yeah. And I, again, I don't, I don't,
Speaker 2:  I I really am being careful. I don't mean to say like in a xenophobic way.
Speaker 2:  I'm like literally just identifying a cultural difference
Speaker 2:  in how the commercial content is presented to you in this app that I think
Speaker 2:  is reflective of something else. Well, and
Speaker 5:  You look at apps like Shein and Temu and like Wish
Speaker 5:  Back in the day and like that vibe is
Speaker 5:  a lot of that comes from China and is very much percolating all over the
Speaker 5:  US now, right? Like there were all these years where all these different
Speaker 5:  kinds of companies tried to make this influencer driven shopping work,
Speaker 5:  which has been huge in China for years, right? Like a, a person will get
Speaker 5:  on camera and just talk about products they like and they sell millions of
Speaker 5:  dollars. And that has never been a thing in the US and it is like rapidly
Speaker 5:  becoming one because that portion of culture
Speaker 5:  and commercial life is very much been exported to the US and I think it's
Speaker 5:  happening really fast. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  It's just
Speaker 7:  QVC
Speaker 2:  Sort of, so it's just like sort of Yeah, but
Speaker 5:  It's a really different generation, right? Like
Speaker 2:  QVC is different. Actually it, I think it's, I was watching QVC in the lobby
Speaker 2:  of a hotel recently. It's a rock in life. What I read here,
Speaker 2:  I was
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 2:  Highs and lows,
Speaker 7:  So much excitement
Speaker 2:  Signing the Apple security NDA for the Vision pro watching QVC in the hotel
Speaker 2:  lobby, right? Highs and lows. And they were selling
Speaker 2:  electric snowblower with a cord. And the poor woman
Speaker 2:  had to be like, this cord is so convenient. And it was like just amazing.
Speaker 2:  It was like some of the most amazing performance I've ever seen. I was like,
Speaker 2:  screw the, screw the Oscars. Like, find this woman,
Speaker 2:  this is the best actress in America.
Speaker 2:  And like yeah, TikTok has some of that element to it, but a lot of it's just
Speaker 2:  like showing you stuff like there's, there isn't that weird
Speaker 7:  That that performative like isn't
Speaker 2:  Best. Like Amazon has more QVC in it. And I'm telling you that I think that
Speaker 2:  is like reflective of the sort of just like detachment you
Speaker 2:  need. Yeah. Like it's, it's authentic, right? It's like very American
Speaker 2:  authentic in its way. Oh, but it's not, but it obviously isn't. But
Speaker 2:  that's what I mean, like yeah. There's, you have to build a little bit of
Speaker 2:  artifice in our culture to go dead into selling. Right?
Speaker 2:  Right. And in other cultures you don't. And that's just a cultural difference.
Speaker 2:  And it's interesting to David's point to see that come through in the apps.
Speaker 2:  What's really interesting is Meta doesn't operate in China,
Speaker 2:  so we have not sent that back the other way. Right. Which is just
Speaker 2:  like also fascinating. Consider and it's good. I think for good reason they
Speaker 2:  don't operate in China. Right? Like they don't want to give data to the Chinese
Speaker 2:  government. Yeah. Google doesn't operate in China for the same reason
Speaker 2:  Apple does. Interesting. So this moment for TikTok where I'm saying
Speaker 2:  closest to calling the top, I wonder if that will be part of it too, where
Speaker 2:  their, their arrogance about what they are and what they represent to this
Speaker 2:  culture is gonna run into their ideas about what will work. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think that's right.
Speaker 2:  Right. And to, to run into sort of the essential nature of like
Speaker 2:  how Americans wish to consume advertising is gonna be really interesting.
Speaker 2:  'cause it's not like the TikTok users aren't already complaining about TikTok
Speaker 2:  shop. Right? Like they already don't like it. And now you're gonna take Taylor
Speaker 2:  Swift away and her label boss is gonna say you, they won't protect her from
Speaker 2:  AI clones of her voice. Like that's a, that's a
Speaker 2:  dangerous position. And there are
Speaker 7:  So many.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. That's enough TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Killing it. This is the
Speaker 7:  Worst. I hate it. I hate it so much.
Speaker 2:  I I have been on such a like good healthy, clean eating
Speaker 2:  diet and exercise and this is the last week just reviewing this thing. I'm
Speaker 2:  just like, gimme the sugar. It's
Speaker 5:  A real, I think like everybody could, there, there's a version of this that
Speaker 5:  is very much like when you had like finals week in college. Yeah. And like
Speaker 5:  the whole rest of your life just sort of collapses around you.
Speaker 5:  That's what NELI has been through for the last seven days. Except in a,
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 7:  Was like you would see him and the rest of the
Speaker 7:  team that worked on it and you Yeah. Yeah. It was like, oh you guys are in
Speaker 7:  finals.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And now I have senioritis. Right. Let's string and Miller let you
Speaker 2:  go to six class.
Speaker 5:  We're doing any work again.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 11:  This week on unexplainable, we're talking about the slight month of,
Speaker 11:  we're talking about the science of swearing.
Speaker 11:  If you stick your hand in a bucket of ice water, you might be able to tough
Speaker 11:  it out for a bit. But if you start saying something like donkey
Speaker 11:  eater, you'll be able to keep your hand in there way longer.
Speaker 12:  And the stronger you experience, that's where we're just being the better
Speaker 12:  the painkiller It is.
Speaker 11:  But you don't get the same power from words like fudge only things like,
Speaker 12:  Which raises all these intriguing questions about what's happening when
Speaker 12:  we're f swearing
Speaker 11:  For new episodes every Wednesday. Listen to Unex
Speaker 11:  Playable.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back Lightning Round
Speaker 7:  Sponsored by Cinnamon Toast Crunch.
Speaker 2:  Do we have any individual sponsors of Lightning Round this week? I got some
Speaker 2:  emails last week, individual listeners who wanted to sponsor Lightning and
Speaker 2:  Liam, I've asked our sales team to reach out. Oh my God. If
Speaker 2:  you're an individual listener of the show and our sales team reaches out
Speaker 2:  to you, set the highest price you can think of. It's like
Speaker 2:  $50 million. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But also if you just Venmo NELI 10 bucks. We'll, we'll we'll do it. It's
Speaker 2:  Fine. Wait, I guess it's the other way around. Our sales team should set
Speaker 2:  a high price. I don't know how advertising works. That's why I haven't
Speaker 2:  been able to sell the Lightning around to anyone.
Speaker 7:  Give us money.
Speaker 2:  I'm handing it, I'm giving it away to Smeg left and right.
Speaker 2:  You want a weird old fridge Smeg. Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  Weird that Smeg has not reached out yet. So strange.
Speaker 7:  That's a weird name to choose.
Speaker 2:  Actually, one of my favorite TikTok videos I've seen recently is a guy who
Speaker 2:  refurbish his fridge. Really? And I think they know, it's like they're listening
Speaker 2:  to me. Yeah. So like, show 'em some fridge videos.
Speaker 7:  They're listening. All right.
Speaker 2:  Cranz, what you got? I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  Be mean and do two Ooh. I haven't reviewed a giant headset
Speaker 7:  this week. That's so I'm gonna be selfish. We'll allow it and do too. So
Speaker 7:  my first one is, is streaming stuff, which is Hulu is cracking down on
Speaker 7:  password sharing. It's, it's been a while, but they, they said, yeah, we're
Speaker 7:  in on this too. We also want more of your money, which means more of you
Speaker 7:  need to use your passwords. Sign in. David,
Speaker 7:  how are you feeling about that?
Speaker 5:  This sucks. So, I, I forget where I first heard this. I think it
Speaker 5:  was on somebody on the the Town podcast, which is a very good podcast that
Speaker 5:  everybody should listen to who was saying that we as society
Speaker 5:  screwed up by not being angrier when Netflix did this.
Speaker 5:  Because we all just kinda rolled with it. We were like, oh yeah, Netflix
Speaker 5:  isn't gonna let you share your Netflix password. That sort of makes sense.
Speaker 5:  And then it worked and everybody else is like, oh dope, we can do that too.
Speaker 5:  We should have been so much angrier at this. Yeah. 'cause this sucks
Speaker 5:  and is bad and is just shaking users down
Speaker 5:  for every penny they can get from them. And we've just all kind of allowed
Speaker 5:  it to happen. And I can't get mad now that Hulu's doing it because I didn't
Speaker 5:  get mad when anybody else did it. But I wish I had, I should have been angrier.
Speaker 5:  We all should have.
Speaker 2:  Can I tell you a text I got literally as we've been podcasting? It's from
Speaker 2:  my sister. It's a screenshot of Netflix and it says, looks
Speaker 2:  like our Netflix jig is up.
Speaker 2:  This is real. Alex is looking at it. It's
Speaker 5:  My version specifically is Hulu. I have an incredibly insecure
Speaker 5:  password on my Hulu because I haven't changed it in probably a decade.
Speaker 5:  Because there, I mean there honestly must be 30 people out there in the world
Speaker 5:  using my Hulu account, including at least one ex-girlfriend.
Speaker 5:  I've been married for a long time now. Like it's, it's, it's
Speaker 5:  bad times coming
Speaker 7:  For a lot of people. Hulu sharing Hulu passwords is how I found out a friend
Speaker 7:  had a baby. It's because I was like, where's all this baby contact Wow. Coming
Speaker 7:  from? That's this is too much. And I was like, oh, she's still got my password.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's rude. Stop watching baby stuff. Make a new account.
Speaker 2:  So I. Amazon also launched ads this week, right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Amazon. Like speaking
Speaker 5:  Of things we should get loudly mad about.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It, it feels like between last week and this week we're really like
Speaker 7:  fully swung into the dark ages of streaming. We're fully in that moment where
Speaker 7:  like, it sucks 'cause it, it, it sucks.
Speaker 2:  This is when the cable bundle just like comes roaring back. It's
Speaker 7:  Here, right? Like no,
Speaker 2:  It's not here. You can't just be like, I'll, I mean this is why Apple's announcing
Speaker 2:  the Charter Spectrum app and a vision.
Speaker 7:  I was, I was like, you can if you like I, I I like Verizon. Verizon's like,
Speaker 7:  would you like Disney Plus and Hulu? Yeah. For like a little less
Speaker 7:  money and maybe we'll throw in Apple tv.
Speaker 2:  No, I want like an old school cable box app now. Give me a grid guide. Start
Speaker 2:  playing stuff as soon, soon as I open
Speaker 7:  It. That's what I'm saying. That's,
Speaker 2:  I mean this is just too b we're about to have the CO2 behind. So I'll just
Speaker 2:  ask her if this is what's happening. It's, but man,
Speaker 2:  I wish one of these services would be like, all right, we're just doing it.
Speaker 2:  All the content's in 4K and it's everything.
Speaker 7:  The Apple TV kind of does that, but
Speaker 2:  It's not everything.
Speaker 7:  They don't have a lot,
Speaker 2:  Even baseball and Apple TV Plus isn't in 4K and they own it. That's
Speaker 7:  'cause they're doing sports. If they weren't doing sports
Speaker 2:  Tv, everything 4K and Apple TV plus and they, they literally own it, they're
Speaker 2:  gonna get to doing 180 degree 3D video of soccer
Speaker 2:  before they stream it in 4K to a tv.
Speaker 5:  God, that's real. I
Speaker 7:  A hundred percent believe that. By
Speaker 2:  The way, Addie called this out yesterday and I didn't mention it in this,
Speaker 2:  it started to talk with the vision program. Apple keeps flying on 360 videos
Speaker 2:  and they're 100% 180 degree videos. Oh yeah. You turn around it's just black.
Speaker 2:  And they're like, but it's a 360 degree. It's like,
Speaker 7:  No, you have to go all the way around. Did you show him the, the Michelle
Speaker 7:  Obama video?
Speaker 2:  Just like I, I can't, why do you think I was trying to watch YouTube vr Dude
Speaker 7:  Relive the moment I
Speaker 2:  Was like, be there again. A million years ago, a little baby
Speaker 2:  NELI Patel interviewed Michelle Obama at the White House with VR cameras.
Speaker 7:  I was so jealous of that video.
Speaker 2:  And we're just reliving it again. We're just reliving it. They're like, well,
Speaker 2:  a new frontier of immersive entertainment. I was like, no, I was with the
Speaker 2:  first lady in a circle. You look all around,
Speaker 2:  you could watch Trey Shehorn, our executive producer being like, ramp that
Speaker 2:  up. Just like our current producer is doing right now.
Speaker 5:  Six outta 10.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 5:  Great. Alex, what was your other one? But
Speaker 7:  Yeah, but my other, my other Lightning round is, so
Speaker 7:  Amazon was gonna buy iRobot, the, the, the robo vac company and
Speaker 7:  the EU said, no, can't do that. Yeah. So it, so they pulled out
Speaker 7:  the CEO of iRobot. Colin Eng is is gone.
Speaker 7:  350 people are getting laid off. Oh
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 7:  The companies like, and it sucks. And, and Tui are incredible
Speaker 7:  reviewer of everything. Smart Home wrote a really lovely piece this week
Speaker 7:  just being like, they were doing it. They were doing all the cool stuff.
Speaker 7:  And they're having to compete with companies like ufi who is owned by a bigger
Speaker 7:  company. Like all of the other big robo vacs are owned by companies in
Speaker 7:  China with lots and lots of money behind them. And iRobot's out there being
Speaker 7:  like, we're gonna figure out robotics in the home all by ourselves with no
Speaker 7:  money. But yeah, so, so it's kind of a bummer. It's, it's unclear what's
Speaker 7:  gonna happen with iRobot. 'cause it seems like they really needed that acquisition
Speaker 7:  for the influx of cash because in order to compete with their competitors,
Speaker 7:  they either have to like make their already very expensive, Robax
Speaker 7:  more expensive, or they have to not com
Speaker 7:  or like they need money. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So I'll say two things about this. One, the reasoning that iRobot and
Speaker 2:  Amazon gave was we see no pathway to approval in the
Speaker 2:  eu. Yes. Which is now what everyone says. Yes. And you know, the
Speaker 2:  eus argument was Amazon sells these vacuums. They're gonna buy this vacuum
Speaker 2:  company and prioritize their own vacuums against other vacuums. You can feel
Speaker 2:  how that, about that However you want. Amazon, just like every other company
Speaker 2:  is doing layoffs and cost cutting and
Speaker 2:  Dave Limp, the old head of hardware is gone and Panos pane for Microsoft
Speaker 2:  is in and they're cutting that whole division down. There's a part of me
Speaker 2:  that says blaming the Europeans is a very convenient excuse to not
Speaker 2:  randomly buy a robotic vacuum company.
Speaker 5:  It's certainly possible
Speaker 2:  For a smart home strategy that has not panned out for Amazon. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  It doesn't, their, their strategy just doesn't make sense
Speaker 2:  So, I'm just saying like, yeah, it's great to blame the EU and I encourage
Speaker 2:  you to blame the Europeans at any given time. The EU culture is so broken,
Speaker 2:  they have no apps just putting that out there.
Speaker 5:  Well there's also there, there's a weird thing happening where like the Roomba
Speaker 5:  was a genuinely like groundbreaking thing. iRobot
Speaker 5:  has made a lot of really good products for a really long time. That thing,
Speaker 5:  to your point, Alex is becoming completely commoditized, right? Like you
Speaker 5:  can get a pretty good, it's not as good as the best Roomba,
Speaker 5:  but a pretty good robot vacuum for like less than $200
Speaker 5:  now. These things are getting cheap really fast.
Speaker 5:  And then the other thing was, iRobot's whole idea was like, we are
Speaker 5:  based on the knowledge that we're getting and the understanding that we have
Speaker 5:  of Your home, literally because we have a thing that's in there mapping where
Speaker 5:  your chairs are. Yeah. We're gonna be able to understand Your home in a
Speaker 5:  uniquely powerful way and we're gonna be able to do things with it. Like
Speaker 5:  remember when this got announced and all of a sudden everybody was panicked
Speaker 5:  about Amazon having the literal floor map of my house. Like that's a real
Speaker 5:  thing. Yeah. But there's also a ton that a company like Amazon with its resources
Speaker 5:  can do with that. If like NELI is saying you believe that Alexa and
Speaker 5:  Robots and Ring and all that stuff. Like, you can see how it all comes together,
Speaker 5:  but it seems increasingly clear that Amazon has just decided that's not
Speaker 5:  a winning strategy for Amazon.
Speaker 2:  Well, we have not heard a word from Pan ESP Pan yet. Yep. He's got the,
Speaker 2:  he's not a retiring man, you know? Yeah. He's
Speaker 2:  a very aggressive personality. He wants to win. I'm dying to hear what his
Speaker 2:  vision for all this is. We know what Dave Lim's vision was. He
Speaker 2:  has been on decoder. We've talked to him lots and lots, but it,
Speaker 2:  he never actually brought Ring and Alexa and all this other stuff together
Speaker 2:  in a cohesive way. Right. They're very separate ecosystems. one of my favorite
Speaker 2:  things about Amazon is they run Ring and Blink two different home security
Speaker 2:  camera systems that don't talk to each other.
Speaker 7:  It's such a mess.
Speaker 2:  It's just utterly bizarre to me. Talking about QVC. The Blink
Speaker 2:  QVC commercials are incredible. So good. If you ever watch one, it's just
Speaker 2:  like these cameras just run on batteries. Like, it's just like, what is happening
Speaker 2:  here?
Speaker 7:  Eli, I think you have a beautiful future as a QVC host.
Speaker 2:  I would do so. Well, I can speak directly to the American Psyche, by the
Speaker 2:  way, the Europeans have one app, it's called Spotify. Apple hates it.
Speaker 2:  That's what I got for you.
Speaker 2:  The, by the way, the other thing I wanna say, I feel very badly for the people
Speaker 2:  who are gonna lose their jobs. Yeah. And I, I hear an argument out in the
Speaker 2:  world that's like, if you don't allow these exits, all these people lose
Speaker 2:  their jobs. I will just remind everyone that what happens when big companies
Speaker 2:  by smaller companies is that they lay everyone off and the companies fail
Speaker 2:  and they go away anyway. Yep.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I it's, it's one of those things where, I don't know, like, it seems
Speaker 7:  like iRobot was always kind of like, not Dubin great. Yeah. This was probably
Speaker 7:  always gonna happen regardless of who bought them. And now it's just like,
Speaker 7:  well, we don't have to hide, we can't hide behind that anymore. We're laying
Speaker 7:  these people off. The CEO is leaving.
Speaker 2:  Amazon had bought this company six months now. They would've laid off 300
Speaker 2:  people. Yeah. Warner Brothers, Warner Bros. Discovery bought Warner Brothers.
Speaker 2:  They just, she was get keep getting rid of them. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Mergers are bad is my general argument that I'll keep making The Europeans
Speaker 2:  have it right there. They're good at that. But I do think there's a little
Speaker 2:  bit of, a little bit of opportunistic un undoing of the deal.
Speaker 7:  I, I like that's a, that's a good theory. I I like that theory.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. David, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  There's so many I want to talk about, but I will avoid talking about top
Speaker 5:  level domains for one day.
Speaker 2:  That was gonna be mine. Okay. You can
Speaker 5:  Have that. That's so cool. I'll talk about Snap, which I think
Speaker 5:  today Thursday announced that it is recalling and
Speaker 5:  refunding every single pixie drone that it sold because of
Speaker 5:  a problem with the batteries Ooh. And I just want to
Speaker 5:  sort of briefly mourn Snap interesting
Speaker 5:  hardware company, which I believe is dead.
Speaker 7:  There was just one drone, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was called the Pixie. It was like we had a, we had a great video
Speaker 5:  about it. Alex Heath made a really cool thing in like a Yeah, I remember
Speaker 5:  like weird carnival looking building
Speaker 7:  His joy as it like flew out of his hand. It's
Speaker 5:  Delightful. And it's such a cool idea is like, it, it was essentially like
Speaker 5:  autonomous little yellow drone that could land in your hand and fly around
Speaker 5:  and take pictures of you and like, makes perfect sense for what Snap is trying
Speaker 5:  to do. Snap also sort of relentlessly trying to make spectacles a
Speaker 5:  thing, but has been very quiet about that for a while now.
Speaker 5:  I just, there was a, there was a minute that that's not true. There were
Speaker 5:  a lot of minutes where I believed Snap was like a
Speaker 5:  sneaky company that was gonna win in a lot of really big ways. And I
Speaker 5:  am mourning the end of that thesis a little more every single day. Oh
Speaker 5:  yeah. But RIP the Pixie, which flew
Speaker 5:  apparently too high and too hot and too fast.
Speaker 2:  And its batteries explo.
Speaker 5:  Its batteries exploded.
Speaker 2:  It's amazing that Instagram and Meta got there faster with the
Speaker 2:  Raybans than snapped it with the spectacles. Yeah. Well
Speaker 7:  I think money had something to
Speaker 2:  Do with that. I'm sure money had something to do with it, but that people
Speaker 2:  were lining up for those spectacles. Like Snap was a big platform
Speaker 2:  and it never made the turn out of teens messaging
Speaker 2:  Right. To whatever the next thing is. Like they invented the filters. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean do you remember how best, how long the, I, the, the joke went that
Speaker 5:  Evan Spiegel was the chief product officer at Facebook in addition
Speaker 5:  to being the CEO at Snap. Like it was true for a long time
Speaker 2:  And it turns out the product he needed to invent was advertising revenue
Speaker 2:  that is still much better at that than Evan Spiegel. Yep. All mine is
Speaker 2:  top level domains.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, buddy. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm so excited about this story, especially because it's
Speaker 2:  such a bad top level domain. It's,
Speaker 2:  it's not great if you know anything about the internet. So if you are a huge
Speaker 2:  nerd like me or Cranz Yeah. You have a lot of local,
Speaker 7:  Not David. David's not nerdy
Speaker 2:  Enough. Yeah, absolutely. No, no. There's one thing I know is that Cranz
Speaker 2:  and I are navigating to more local devices on our network than David can
Speaker 2:  even contemplate David's out there being like this pixie drone's amazing.
Speaker 5:  Right? I'm outside, you know, driving cool cars and picking up
Speaker 5:  chicks and you guys are just like 1 9 2
Speaker 5:  0.168. Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 2:  So you, if you have configured a router, if you
Speaker 2:  like me, have a little raspberry pi Tamagotchi doing a home bridge
Speaker 2:  situation. If you're like Cranz and you operate, I write server questionably
Speaker 2:  legal plex server.
Speaker 7:  It's legal
Speaker 2:  For the local community.
Speaker 2:  I still don't have the password. I'm just saying if you're like crayons and
Speaker 2:  you've been ripping Blu-rays to your plex server
Speaker 7:  Over a decade very legally,
Speaker 2:  You know Yeah. You gotta type 1 92 0.168, do whatever
Speaker 2:  to get to your right. And sometimes you
Speaker 2:  can fudge it with a dot local domain. There's all this stuff you can do.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And sometimes it doesn't work. So, I can the internet corporation for
Speaker 2:  assigned names and numbers, incredible name for this organization that we
Speaker 2:  do not talk about enough.
Speaker 5:  Did not know that's what that stood for. That
Speaker 2:  This company, it's a, it's a, that's a long story, but it's just amazing
Speaker 2:  that like got themselves to, I can, you know, they just
Speaker 2:  reversed engineered the acronym, the internet corporation for assigned names
Speaker 2:  and numbers has proposed a new top level domain
Speaker 2:  for devices on your own network. So instead of typing 1
Speaker 2:  9 2 0.168, you'll
Speaker 2:  type whatever internal
Speaker 5:  NELI internal.
Speaker 7:  Nope. Hard pass.
Speaker 7:  Not to
Speaker 2:  The other choice. My friends was do private.
Speaker 7:  They should have put a pearl on there.
Speaker 2:  They, they ultimately chose dot internal
Speaker 2:  as it found. Quote dot private may carry the unintended imputation
Speaker 2:  of privacy.
Speaker 2:  I don't know. Yeah. I'm just saying Local was sitting right
Speaker 2:  there.
Speaker 2:  Stuff dot internal
Speaker 7:  Get out.
Speaker 2:  Like my Home bridge is HomeBridge local. You can't, I'm happy to tell it
Speaker 2:  to you because if you try to go to it, you'll go to Your home Bridge. This
Speaker 2:  works. I'm
Speaker 7:  So excited
Speaker 2:  To hack guys. That's like a hack. That's like a, that's like a Bonjour hack
Speaker 2:  or whatever. Yeah. This is like a different, like an actual top level
Speaker 2:  domain that will mean this thing on the internet. And they went with DOT
Speaker 2:  internal because dot private. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's too much.
Speaker 2:  The implication would is private, not the other thing.
Speaker 7:  I think we found that actually we're not the nerdiest people. It's, I can,
Speaker 2:  Anyway, there it's not done yet. It's not happening. You can go to the I
Speaker 2:  can website and leave comments. Please behave yourselves. Wink,
Speaker 2:  wink. It's ridiculous. I love it.
Speaker 2:  I lo I like, I like that people have so much stuff on their own
Speaker 2:  networks that this is a thing that we, I just like, people used to
Speaker 2:  insist that no one would ever have anything on their own network.
Speaker 5:  You know what else you could have done as the tlds.network? What, what a,
Speaker 5:  what a crazy idea that would've been
Speaker 2:  Yeah, my stuff. My
Speaker 5:  Stuff stuff I think is the one.
Speaker 7:  My dot stuff.
Speaker 5:  My dot stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Be Behind Firewall.
Speaker 5:  Behind Firewall. David, no Girls Allowed. That's my, that's my
Speaker 5:  local network.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. Simon's gonna write in and correct me on how Dot Local
Speaker 2:  actually works, but I know it's not official. TLD that's why I'm saying it.
Speaker 2:  I will say
Speaker 5:  In the abstract, I love the idea of having a name for
Speaker 5:  your local stuff. don don't. Instead of all of the IP address
Speaker 5:  Nonsense.
Speaker 7:  I memorized all of those IP addresses so long
Speaker 5:  Ago. It feels like a you problem.
Speaker 7:  I don't wanna have to go back and redo that. I need to know where my,
Speaker 7:  my doorbell is at all times.
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry. Here's how Local works. Local is a special use domain name reserved
Speaker 2:  by the internet engineering task force. The IETF, the
Speaker 2:  rivals to ican. don don't know the rivals Shark,
Speaker 5:  Jet
Speaker 2:  Shark fight. I think they should fight and it is not allowed to be a top
Speaker 2:  level domain. Oh. It has been reserved by the IETF.
Speaker 2:  If ICAN comes and takes it, that's a task force baby.
Speaker 2:  All right. That's, that's, I I'm sorry. It has been a
Speaker 2:  very long CIN Week
Speaker 7:  M Toast Crunch NELI. It's in the house. I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm, look, I love you all. Thank you for listening to The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast or watching it. I'm sure you have some complaints to leave in the
Speaker 2:  comments. Just do it. Just engage. Come back and engage again tomorrow
Speaker 5:  And next time you're in a meeting. If there's just two of you there and then
Speaker 5:  a third person joins, just say that's a task force baby.
Speaker 2:  I, I'm sorry, but you knew what you were getting. That's
Speaker 2:  it. That's The Vergecast Pro.
Speaker 15:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 15:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast
Speaker 15:  is the production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is
Speaker 15:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 15:  week.