# Transcript
ID: 5270b00a-6bf3-4604-a17e-091a361d796f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5958848496846593825/3189816373527604054/s93290-US-3918s-1712648988.mp3
Description: The Verge’s David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Alex Cranz answer questions from The Vergecast Hotline all about the TikTok ban debate and the US v Apple case.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Super App Regulation. I'm
Speaker 2:  your friend David Pierce and I am what I would call
Speaker 2:  desperately on a hunt for solar eclipse classes. It's Monday morning,
Speaker 2:  it's like three and a half, four hours until the eclipse and like a
Speaker 2:  super genius planner that I am just didn't go get eclipse glasses.
Speaker 2:  I think I sort of thought that sunglasses would work. Turns out that is not
Speaker 2:  correct and terrible science and you should not listen to me about
Speaker 2:  anything to do with the eclipse. So now I'm running around trying desperately
Speaker 2:  to get glasses and so far it's not happening. Target was out. Staples had
Speaker 2:  a sign on the door that clearly somebody had just like hastily printed basically
Speaker 2:  saying like, leave us alone. We don't have any eclipse glasses. I'm now
Speaker 2:  going to every sort I can think of, including some that just obviously won't
Speaker 2:  have Eclipse glasses trying to convince someone to sell me these
Speaker 2:  glasses. I have realized I will pay what amounts to an alarming amount of
Speaker 2:  money for these glasses, but I don't think it's gonna happen. Anyway, we
Speaker 2:  have an awesome show coming up for you today. I was in New York last week
Speaker 2:  and took the opportunity of all being in the same city to drag NELI into
Speaker 2:  the studio and grab Alex and just talk about TikTok
Speaker 2:  and Apple and all of the stuff that's been happening over the last couple
Speaker 2:  of weeks. We've talked a lot about the TikTok Pan and Apple Antitrust and
Speaker 2:  we've heard a ton from you. Questions you have for us, thoughts you have
Speaker 2:  about the things that we think, feelings you have about all of what's going
Speaker 2:  on. And we figured we'd just spend an hour talking about it. We got a bunch
Speaker 2:  of really great emails and a bunch of really great Hotline questions and
Speaker 2:  so that's what this whole show is. It was really fun, I really enjoyed it.
Speaker 2:  It got deep and kind of emotional at times in a
Speaker 2:  really interesting way as all of this Apple Antitrust and TikTok band
Speaker 2:  specifically stuff tends to do. Super fun, really awesome show. All of
Speaker 2:  that is coming up in just a second, but like I said, I have three and a half
Speaker 2:  hours to get some eclipse glasses. It's probably not gonna happen, but wish
Speaker 2:  me luck. Anyway, this is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  two things that we've talked about on the show the last couple of weeks.
Speaker 2:  So we're just gonna dive into a bunch of it. Nilay Patel here. Hi NELI. Hello
Speaker 2:  Alex. Cranz also here. Hey, what's up? Neela and I are in this small studio
Speaker 2:  that I've never been in before. It's very exciting.
Speaker 5:  There's a frame TV in here I wanna point out it's, I'm
Speaker 2:  Not gonna, we're not we a lot. We have a lot to get.
Speaker 5:  I'm just letting you know thoughts. The
Speaker 2:  Two things we're gonna talk mostly about here are the Apple Antitrust stuff,
Speaker 2:  which we talked a lot about and the TikTok ban. We're gonna do Apple first,
Speaker 2:  then we're gonna take a break, then we're gonna talk TikTok and we got a
Speaker 2:  ton of feedback. So what I tried to do was find Hotline voicemails from people
Speaker 2:  that were like roughly representative of the feedback. So some of them
Speaker 2:  have questions that we should ask specifically. Some of them are just kind
Speaker 2:  of points a lot of people made that we should talk about. We have three for
Speaker 2:  Apple and four for TikTok. This is going to take us four hours.
Speaker 2:  Let's go. All right, the first voicemail we got is from Harrison.
Speaker 6:  Hi David and B Crew. My name is Harrison. I have a question
Speaker 6:  about the Apple DOJ case. What I'm trying to
Speaker 6:  understand is why people are going after
Speaker 6:  Apple specifically. Apple has 60% market share in the
Speaker 6:  United States and people like to say that like iMessage is a lock in or that
Speaker 6:  green bubble envy is a thing, which it totally is, but I feel
Speaker 6:  like people are getting upset that Apple like won
Speaker 6:  capitalism. It feels like they made a product that won based off of
Speaker 6:  popularity and not necessity because we all use SMS and then
Speaker 6:  iMessage is built on top of that. It kind of feels like trying to force
Speaker 6:  Apple to be, to open that up or to open other parts of the iOS
Speaker 6:  experience up. It would be kind of like making it so
Speaker 6:  Sony has to put God of war on the Xbox or that like I
Speaker 6:  have to be able to put the brake pads from a Honda Accord onto
Speaker 6:  a Hyundai Tucson or something. It, it feels like we're just trying to like
Speaker 6:  create an argument for the sake of an argument. I would just genuinely like
Speaker 6:  to know what is it about this case with Apple
Speaker 6:  that makes it a bigger deal in Antitrust than something like Amazon Web
Speaker 6:  Services and Amazon storefronts or Google with Gmail
Speaker 6:  or search I guess. Thank you. Have the rest of your day. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I wanna reframe this question very slightly before we get into it
Speaker 2:  because there is a part of this premise that I disagree with, which is that
Speaker 2:  we're only going after Apple because there is Antitrust action against all
Speaker 2:  of these companies. But the reason I picked this one is because I would say
Speaker 2:  the most consistent piece of feedback we got was that
Speaker 2:  this is just the DOJ picking on Apple for being too successful and,
Speaker 2:  and that what is this fight if not just trying to turn Apple into Android
Speaker 2:  or make it worse and why are we mad at Apple for being so successful? So
Speaker 2:  I figure that is a thing we should address here that this question is also
Speaker 2:  very much about. So NELI you, you were nodding through this whole question.
Speaker 2:  What do you think?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think those are, those are good points. I agree with you David If,
Speaker 5:  you look at the landscape of Antitrust actions, the
Speaker 5:  governments around the world are going after all these companies just all
Speaker 5:  over the place. Yeah. So there's that. They'll just set that aside
Speaker 2:  Including explicitly Amazon storefront and Google search. Yeah. Like this
Speaker 2:  is the, all that stuff is in this in a very real way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then I want to just focus on two words. Winning capitalism.
Speaker 5:  I'm a capitalist. Pretty unrepentant. So I think, I think
Speaker 5:  you should win capitalism. I think you should try really hard. I I think
Speaker 5:  that's a good, I think that works. The problem is you have to have a
Speaker 5:  functional market for other people to try to win. And so that these cases
Speaker 5:  are all premised on, once you've won in one place, you shouldn't
Speaker 5:  be able to take that power and prevent anyone from winning in another place.
Speaker 5:  And I think in particular with the iPhone Apple's
Speaker 5:  desire for control or desire for quality or desire
Speaker 5:  for fees, you pick and choose in what order
Speaker 5:  they're in the equation and how they're weighted desire for services. Revenue
Speaker 5:  has precluded a bunch of other kinds of businesses from existing and
Speaker 5:  competing with Apple. And that's actually the problem, right? It's that you
Speaker 5:  get these companies that have a monopoly in one area and maybe they've
Speaker 5:  earned it. I think iPhones are really good phones. I think their cameras
Speaker 5:  are really good. Like all the stuff, I think they've earned that stuff. And
Speaker 5:  then you take that and you say, and now we will make sure that no
Speaker 5:  one else can compete in another area or we will make sure that we have an
Speaker 5:  advantage in some other area that is unrelated to where we won.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's the part where If, you want a functional
Speaker 5:  capitalistic market. You have to have markets, right? People have to be
Speaker 5:  able to pick and choose freely and vote with their dollars, which I
Speaker 5:  believe is more efficient than like voting for politicians in
Speaker 5:  centralized control structures. Like I, I, I would rather vote with
Speaker 5:  my dollars than vote for politicians. Like that's just a, a thing that I
Speaker 5:  believe. And so you just look at the iPhone and you're like, oh, it's actually
Speaker 5:  pretty hard to vote with your dollars here. Is it pretty hard to vote with
Speaker 5:  your time? And if Apple doesn't want that to exist, it just doesn't. And
Speaker 5:  I think that's the heart of these cases and I think it gets lost. When I
Speaker 5:  interviewed Jonathan Cantor on Decoder, he made
Speaker 5:  a point of saying there is more interest in Antitrust by young people
Speaker 5:  than there ever has been before. Hmm. Because people can feel that their
Speaker 5:  options are being limited by a handful of big companies across the entire
Speaker 5:  like economy. And that's, that's the heart of it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It seems to me that thinking about this one compared to Amazon
Speaker 2:  and Google, I actually feel like I can explain that tension very easily
Speaker 2:  with Amazon and Google because there is sort of one specific thing, right?
Speaker 2:  With Google it's, we built a very successful search engine. It is not illegal
Speaker 2:  to win. But then what Google did is use all the money that it made
Speaker 2:  from said successful search engine to basically buy all the real
Speaker 2:  estate on the internet so that no one else could have a successful search
Speaker 2:  engine. At least that is the allegation, right? Whether that will win or
Speaker 2:  not, I don't know. But that is at least sort of a straightforward version
Speaker 2:  of the thing you're talking about the thing that Amazon allegedly did where
Speaker 2:  it would crawl the web to find sellers who were selling stuff cheaper
Speaker 2:  off of Amazon and then ruthlessly penalize those people on Amazon. Same
Speaker 2:  thing, right? That is you created a big market and then you used it to punish
Speaker 2:  everybody who played elsewhere. I don't know that there is one thing that
Speaker 2:  feels as obvious to me in the Apple suit that we've seen so far.
Speaker 2:  Is there one that you can point to that feels kind of, 'cause I think this
Speaker 2:  is part of what people are responding to and Alex, I'm curious how you feel
Speaker 2:  about this too. 'cause it seems like, yeah, the Apple thing is about sort
Speaker 2:  of so many things and I think to some extent, and Alex, we talked about this
Speaker 2:  on the show, the wallet one feels to me like maybe the most straightforward
Speaker 2:  version of this where like Apple built a thing and then didn't allow anybody
Speaker 2:  else to build said thing. That is a version of the thing. I
Speaker 7:  I think it's, it's both about protecting markets and and allowing
Speaker 7:  markets to exist, right? Like, like part of this case is saying Apple has
Speaker 7:  said these markets cannot exist. And the other part of it is that
Speaker 7:  Apple has made the experience for consumers fundamentally
Speaker 7:  worse. And it has such a large market share that that worse is now
Speaker 7:  impacting people in a really real and measurable way. And
Speaker 7:  that's the part I think about the most. 'cause I think, I think NELI is right,
Speaker 7:  right? Like they went in and they said, okay, you can't have these markets
Speaker 7:  like If, you wanna have cloud gaming. It cannot exist on this, which means
Speaker 7:  60% of Americans cannot have this unless they choose
Speaker 7:  to vote with their dollars elsewhere. But all this lock-in is keeping them
Speaker 7:  from doing that. And then the other part of that is If, you wanna send
Speaker 7:  a message to your mom with a photo in it. That photo is now
Speaker 7:  degraded because Apple has willingly chosen to degrade its services
Speaker 7:  to keep people locked in. And those two things are like both existing
Speaker 7:  at once. So it's like Apple won at capitalism and then made everything
Speaker 7:  worse as like a victory lap is kind of part of this
Speaker 7:  case. And that part I'm like, yeah, I mean maybe that
Speaker 7:  should be illegal. Maybe that shouldn't be a thing that's happening. And
Speaker 7:  that's a tension of the case, right? That the tension of the case is like,
Speaker 7:  is that allowed? And I think that's where it becomes almost like a philosophical
Speaker 7:  argument of like, should that be allowed? And I'm on the ca, like I love
Speaker 7:  consumers, I wanna help consumers. That's my job as a consumer technology
Speaker 7:  reporter. I wanna make sure that they're protected. And so I'm like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  we shouldn't make things measurably worse just because we win at capitalism.
Speaker 7:  And a lot of people are like, yeah but you win at capitalism, you get to
Speaker 7:  do what you want.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. By the way, this is like a tension of the American economy dating back
Speaker 5:  a hundred years or or more, right? Right. Like the reason called
Speaker 2:  Railroads.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like the reason it's called Antitrust is because there was a form of
Speaker 5:  business that called trusts and we like knocked them all down and built
Speaker 5:  Antitrust law. I highly recommend reading The Curse of Bigness by Tim Wu,
Speaker 5:  which is a little, it's like a booklet. It's not, it is not even long. It's
Speaker 5:  just like a fun readable history of Antitrust. But this is the idea is that
Speaker 5:  you should have competition in our market and If, you don't
Speaker 5:  protect the competition in our market. Then you're gonna end up with a handful
Speaker 5:  of big companies that run everything and they will not be as good for you.
Speaker 5:  And by the way, I think a bunch of big companies in our markets right now
Speaker 5:  would love to be regulated monopolies like just up and down. Yeah, they
Speaker 5:  would love it. Facebook would love to be a regulated monopoly and be in charge
Speaker 5:  of everything and make all the money and not have to compete. That just,
Speaker 5:  I, I don't know. It feels sicky to me. I think with the iPhone in particular,
Speaker 5:  you're right, it's like hard to point at one thing. But I'll give you one
Speaker 5:  example. Sure. There are ads in the setting screen. Mm, that's brutal.
Speaker 5:  That's a good one. That's brutal, right? And it's like that's just the clearest
Speaker 5:  self referencing that anyone can do. And it's like this sucks.
Speaker 5:  Like fine, okay put ads in the setting screen but at least let
Speaker 5:  other competitor apps have as much access to the phone. It should not
Speaker 5:  be that because I picked an operating system one time or I preferred one
Speaker 5:  camera that all of these other choices down the line get
Speaker 5:  made from me by some corporation that wants to extract 30%. I just don't
Speaker 5:  I that feels icky. Like ah, it's my money stay, stay away from it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. What a truly perfect segue. That just was into question number two
Speaker 2:  because there's more we should talk about on that point. But this next question
Speaker 2:  basically asks it directly. It's from Josiah.
Speaker 8:  Hi David. My name is Josiah and I of course have a question about the
Speaker 8:  DOJ versus Apple situation. A lot of the stuff in that
Speaker 8:  complaint is about like Apple forcing companies to do things either the Apple
Speaker 8:  way or just not at all. And I feel like that is an area where
Speaker 8:  Apple being the bully to these other companies does result in a
Speaker 8:  lot of benefits for me as a user. The nightmare scenario is like thinking
Speaker 8:  about the wallet and NFC access and obviously opening that up has
Speaker 8:  the intent of creating a bunch of different competitors that have better
Speaker 8:  features and then that requires Apple to make their thing better. And I would
Speaker 8:  love to live in that world. But far more realistically, I feel like the world
Speaker 8:  we live in is one where the second the court says Apple
Speaker 8:  exclusively can't lock users in, then every other
Speaker 8:  company is just going to say, oh cool. And they're gonna remove their card
Speaker 8:  from the Apple like wallet and they're going to make their own wallet and
Speaker 8:  then they're going to make me use exclusively their wallet to use their thing.
Speaker 8:  And that's hell because then all of a sudden I have my Amazon
Speaker 8:  card is in my Apple wallet and then my Delta tickets and my Sky
Speaker 8:  Miles card are in my Delta exclusive wallet. And how does that not
Speaker 8:  just like result in a worse experience for everybody on the backend? Like
Speaker 8:  how can we force Apple to open up? Is there
Speaker 8:  a way to force Apple to open up that doesn't just allow all these other
Speaker 8:  companies to be like, Ooh, apple can't be the monopoly, so I would like to
Speaker 8:  and then lock everybody else out of their new thing. Is that
Speaker 8:  possible or is by forcing people to open up, we're going to inevitably
Speaker 8:  struggle with interoperability. Thanks. Hopefully it wasn't too long.
Speaker 7:  I got an answer for this one. So I think it is down to the
Speaker 7:  idea of capitalism is that competition would happen. The idea of capitalism
Speaker 7:  is that Apple would say, okay, other people can make their their wallets
Speaker 7:  and they can, they can now do this as well. And then Apple has to make sure
Speaker 7:  their wallet is the best wallet and and force people to, like Netflix
Speaker 7:  was an example of this, right? Hulu were example of this. They were, they
Speaker 7:  were early movers in these fields and they said, okay, we're gonna be the
Speaker 7:  best and everybody else is gonna come work with us. And if they don't work
Speaker 7:  with us then their product is gonna be measurably shittier, IE
Speaker 7:  Paramount plus. And and that's what, that's what's gonna happen. And,
Speaker 7:  and that theoretically is what would happen in this case too, right?
Speaker 7:  Chase may say, okay, we're gonna go make our wallet app and not use Apples
Speaker 7:  anymore. And if their wallet app is worse, then people might be like, well
Speaker 7:  it's not that hard for me to move over to Bank of America or Wells Fargo
Speaker 7:  or whatever. I'm just gonna move my business over there because I need the
Speaker 7:  convenience of this other product that's much better.
Speaker 2:  So having just switched banks, I take unbelievable offense to that
Speaker 2:  premise that switching banks, this is, this is one of the things this
Speaker 2:  question made me think about is like maybe where we're headed is we're about
Speaker 2:  to realize lock-in is more real more places than anybody has reckoned with.
Speaker 2:  And actually what we're doing is we're starting down this like incredible
Speaker 2:  hill of trying to get out of the holes that we've dug ourselves into
Speaker 2:  over the years. but don don't know Neil. What do you, what do you make of
Speaker 2:  this question? So
Speaker 5:  Specifically with wallets, I have an answer. Okay. And then, and then we
Speaker 5:  can abstract it with wallets. Everybody wants your credit card to be everywhere.
Speaker 5:  There's no incentive for anyone to make you use a different wallet app.
Speaker 5:  The incentive is for your credit card to be everywhere, right?
Speaker 2:  Because they want you to
Speaker 5:  Use your credit card, they want you to use your credit card. And you can
Speaker 5:  see this play out on the web already where every storefront has like
Speaker 5:  15 payment service buttons. Like that is true. Do you wanna use shop pay?
Speaker 5:  Do you wanna use Google Pay, Amazon Pay Apple, like whatever. Just pay us,
Speaker 5:  like pay us the money.
Speaker 2:  PayPal and Venmo, which are the same company, they're like, we don't care.
Speaker 2:  Just do any, just do something
Speaker 5:  Any way to get your money. They'll do it. So the incentive at least for that
Speaker 5:  one is for payment services to make it easy for you to spend
Speaker 5:  money. So I think that one will be fine. I think there are other ones
Speaker 5:  where the incentives will be get over here and we'll lock you in in other
Speaker 5:  ways. What I'm hopeful for is that yep, we'll all
Speaker 5:  perceive that and that'll be annoying in some ways. But then over time that
Speaker 5:  annoyance will actually reduce how much people use some of these services
Speaker 5:  or the switching costs will be obvious. Alex brought up Netflix. I think
Speaker 5:  we've all gone through this now in the streaming example where every
Speaker 5:  streamer was like, we have these exclusives music services. We were like,
Speaker 5:  we have these exclusives. And then people are like, but I don't care.
Speaker 5:  Like whatever. And then like most of the streaming companies have gotten
Speaker 5:  90 and put their stuff on Netflix. Like I think the economy should wax and
Speaker 5:  wane in these ways. And I think right now it can't.
Speaker 5:  It can't because you picked an operating system, which is weird. Like I,
Speaker 5:  that's too many decisions to give away.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah. Yeah. I mean I think I buy the premise to some extent that If,
Speaker 2:  you give everybody access to everything. You suddenly
Speaker 2:  will get a thousand ads on your setting screen. And that actually, that's
Speaker 2:  a worse outcome than only Apple being allowed to show me ads on the setting
Speaker 2:  screen. Just from a pure like user experience perspective. And I think then
Speaker 2:  you have to believe that, oh okay, people will ditch their iPhones because
Speaker 2:  there are too many ads on the setting screen. you
Speaker 5:  Know, there's a counter example, it's just like sitting in front of all of
Speaker 5:  us all the time, which is we use the web on our computers every day. The
Speaker 5:  model for computing is not only on phones. Yeah. Think there's,
Speaker 5:  that's there's a whole other one. Like you buy any desktop computer
Speaker 5:  and then you put another application environment on it in terms of a web
Speaker 5:  browser and then you have multiple computing application layers and multiple,
Speaker 5:  like all this stuff is just like pure chaos. And it, that market seems to
Speaker 5:  be fine. Like from what I got, like all this seem to enjoy it. It like people
Speaker 5:  make things, the browser companies seem to be doing fine. Like there's new
Speaker 5:  innovative browser companies. All of a sudden, like the market changes,
Speaker 5:  people are selling laptops from what I understand Alex, they they keep making.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. They do that every day. You look at this other thing and you're
Speaker 5:  like, well that works fine until
Speaker 2:  Google comes along and ruins it for everybody. But then, but then we get
Speaker 2:  another other stuff that shows up and starts to work. Yeah, I think that's,
Speaker 2:  I think that's largely right. I think what I wonder is how many things
Speaker 2:  we're about to discover don't have the incentive structure of
Speaker 2:  things like credit cards. Yeah. And actually I, as you were talking about
Speaker 2:  the, the Netflix stuff, Alex, I was thinking about all of these companies
Speaker 2:  that have shown up trying to be like the, the search service
Speaker 2:  for streaming and Netflix sometimes
Speaker 2:  works with them and is usually part of the search stuff. And there was a
Speaker 2:  really funny thing recently where a bunch of people discovered you can search
Speaker 2:  on the Apple TV app and get Netflix stuff and everybody got really excited
Speaker 2:  and it was like, no, that's been there for a while. But what it won't do
Speaker 2:  is show up in the continue watching stuff and it won't show up in the
Speaker 2:  recommendations. And it's like Netflix wants to own that experience. They'll
Speaker 2:  take search because you gotta be there. But Netflix still wants to own that
Speaker 2:  experience. Yeah. And is powerful enough that it can get away with not being
Speaker 2:  part of that. And it just makes me wonder there are, there are more things
Speaker 2:  like that that are gonna be out there. I think
Speaker 5:  The foundational premise of this question is also really interesting, which
Speaker 5:  is like Apple makes people do things the right way, which is Apple's rep,
Speaker 5:  right? Right. They're like, we have a user experience and If, you wanna be
Speaker 5:  a part of it, you gotta do it our way.
Speaker 2:  Right? But this is the correct answer in some certain way,
Speaker 5:  But there's a correct answer. And like part of that's true. Like that's Apple's
Speaker 5:  history. Like there're like there is a correct design answer. I think that's
Speaker 5:  being corrupted by Apple's financial interests. And then I think like
Speaker 5:  actually you look around and you're like, eh, we made a bunch of weird decisions.
Speaker 5:  Like we all have to deal with H EICs. Yeah. Right, right. Like that's weird.
Speaker 5:  Like did that, was that the right answer? Yeah. Like I don't know, TikTok
Speaker 5:  started supporting HT R videos and it's just a mess. Like it is just a
Speaker 5:  mess. It looks like shit and like everything is too bright. And then also
Speaker 5:  kind of grainy. Instagram has the same problem with H share videos. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, this is just because Apple is like now the videos are HDR
Speaker 5:  and it forced everyone to like deal with it and it's like, ugh,
Speaker 5:  this isn't great. And it's like these are just choices that Apple is sort
Speaker 5:  of like making down the line. I think one piece of evidence that, you know,
Speaker 5:  it's kind of the lumbering monopoly is that the polish on some of that stuff
Speaker 5:  isn't there the way it used to be. Yeah, yeah. And it's still coasting
Speaker 2:  And it doesn't matter. Yeah. It doesn't matter. It it gets, they get away
Speaker 2:  with it. Yeah. I think that's fair. We have one more question from Peter.
Speaker 9:  Hey, this is Peter in Brooklyn. Just heard the episode about the Apple
Speaker 9:  lawsuit with the US government and wanna say one thing people
Speaker 9:  never point out about super apps is that China has one because
Speaker 9:  the Chinese government has banned everything else and they
Speaker 9:  want everyone to be in one app because it's easier to collect all the data
Speaker 9:  and mess with all the information in one place. So
Speaker 9:  maybe that's why China and India have one and no one else wants it. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Just something to think about. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  So I just, I want to add one thing to this before we talk about it, which
Speaker 2:  is I think another consistent piece of feedback we got when we
Speaker 2:  talked about the Antitrust stuff was people saying why would you want super
Speaker 2:  apps? Those are just monopolies of their own and they have
Speaker 2:  just as much, if not more lock-in than many of these other systems. Why
Speaker 2:  are we the three Vergecast co-hosts? Yeah. Standing so hard for
Speaker 2:  super apps.
Speaker 5:  All right, so maybe I, I didn't say this as clearly as I could have because
Speaker 5:  I was on a beach drinking, literally drinking a bi enchilada
Speaker 5:  and my audio was coming through AirPods. I think the
Speaker 5:  DOJ is talking about super apps. 'cause that's a sexier idea than web apps.
Speaker 5:  That is my fundamental belief.
Speaker 2:  That's what I think too.
Speaker 5:  I I think they can point to be like, we could turn Facebook
Speaker 5:  into a super app and then you would just like leave your iPhone and buy
Speaker 5:  a cheap Android phone and Facebook would take you there and that would bring
Speaker 5:  down prices of phones in the market. And that's one way it fine. But it's
Speaker 5:  actually web apps could do the same thing. Right? I think of my phone in
Speaker 5:  many ways as a vessel for Google Services, which are also slowly
Speaker 5:  degrading over time. But that was a real problem for Apple about five years
Speaker 5:  ago when people would buy iPhones and then load 'em up with Google apps and
Speaker 5:  Apple realized, oh, we need services that can compete with this across the
Speaker 5:  board. Right. And those services has to be everywhere. That's why Apple Music
Speaker 5:  is on Android. Like they know that some of these services have to be everywhere.
Speaker 5:  So I, I don't know. I don't know that I want super apps either. I I just,
Speaker 5:  my belief is that they, they couldn't pick web app. Like you can't
Speaker 5:  be like, apples are killing the web. Like that is somewhat famously
Speaker 5:  the argument they made about Microsoft in the nineties. Right. So I think
Speaker 5:  they had to pick something new and shiny And. honestly, I think
Speaker 5:  because Elon keeps talking about turning X into a super app, I think they
Speaker 5:  wanted to court that particular political base.
Speaker 2:  You think it also might just be in the lexicon in a way that like If you
Speaker 2:  say progressive web apps, everybody's eyes kind of start to glaze over
Speaker 2:  except for guest listeners, which is why we love you. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. That's what I mean. I, there's, there's an element of politics
Speaker 5:  here. Like the United States government is like doing a thing. I think they're,
Speaker 5:  they are communicating as political actors, you know, they, this is law like
Speaker 5:  the d OJ is law enforcement. The cops are like doing stuff and they need
Speaker 5:  people to believe in their power as cops. Okay. Like I, I just, I'm not
Speaker 5:  out here saying we need a Chinese style super app. I like the point is
Speaker 5:  If, you had one and in the markets where there are one, you see the
Speaker 5:  switching costs between iPhones to other phones are very low and people switch
Speaker 5:  between them all the time. And that is true in Europe, that is true in China,
Speaker 5:  that is true in India. There are other ways to make those switching costs
Speaker 5:  low. They just happen to be the web and it's only us here in our little,
Speaker 5:  little Vergecast club that know that and care about that as much as we do.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Alex what do you think?
Speaker 7:  I mean, ditto, it's just, just, I, I totally agree with NELI on
Speaker 7:  that. Like, I don't think anybody necessarily wants a super app, but it's
Speaker 7:  a really good example to use in this thing. And it's a really good
Speaker 7:  example to show like we could have cheaper phones. This could be a lot cheaper
Speaker 7:  and we don't necessarily need super apps for that. It could be the Google
Speaker 7:  suite, it could be the Amazon suite, it could be another monopoly like tech
Speaker 7:  companies suite who can say, but, but we should have choices and just
Speaker 7:  choices at all. And, and to have just a whole
Speaker 7:  style of app forbidden from 60% of phones
Speaker 7:  in the United States because Apple doesn't feel like it and is threatened
Speaker 7:  by it is like bad. Yeah. Even if those apps themselves maybe
Speaker 7:  aren't great.
Speaker 5:  And I would point I once again point to desktop computers where you can just
Speaker 5:  Yep. The entire application model is the web and that's fine. Right. And
Speaker 5:  like do people switch between Windows and Mac all the time because you can
Speaker 5:  just use Google search and YouTube. No, they don't. They have, they still
Speaker 5:  have preferences and the computers are still expensive, but
Speaker 5:  a lot of them have gotten way cheaper in a way that, you know, phones have
Speaker 5:  not, and I, we have evidence of this, right? Like Apple talks about not wanting
Speaker 5:  parents to buy their kids cheap Android phones because that worries them
Speaker 5:  that if they people can just access the service on a good enough phone, they
Speaker 5:  won't buy expensive iPhones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think that's right. Alex, we're about to get to the portion of
Speaker 2:  our show where you and I get repeatedly accused of being China loving
Speaker 2:  communists. Would you like, would you like to briefly explain why you'd like
Speaker 2:  WeChat to come to America and and it'll make everything better and solve
Speaker 2:  all of our problems?
Speaker 7:  No. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I don't think it will. I I don't think we need it in this country
Speaker 7:  and I don't think, I think super apps are probably, I I think to, to
Speaker 7:  Peter's point, monopolies themselves and we probably don't need them in this
Speaker 7:  company country, but we also should probably be able to have them if we really
Speaker 7:  want them. Like the choice should be there. The whole idea of capitalism
Speaker 7:  is we have choices and it's like, okay, I would like that choice.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Also, millions of Americans routinely
Speaker 5:  choose to use meta products like all the time.
Speaker 5:  All the time. Like all the time. Like we are just a like a little
Speaker 5:  bit away from that thing actually being real. Yeah. And it's not like
Speaker 5:  John Gruber keeps pointing this out when you give people the choice of do
Speaker 5:  you want a free service with personalized advertising? They're like, yes.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, but would you, what If, you didn't have that and you could
Speaker 5:  pay for it. And they're like, no.
Speaker 10:  Right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No man.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. No, that's right. Alright, well we should get to TikTok stuff, but
Speaker 2:  first we gotta take a brief break. We'll be right
Speaker 10:  There.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Alex and I are card carrying members of the Chinese
Speaker 2:  Communist Party. Oh, I
Speaker 5:  Always want, can
Speaker 2:  I see your card? And NELI NELI is the lone bastion of free
Speaker 2:  speech and goodness here on The Vergecast, but is
Speaker 2:  also occasionally, sometimes a monster who believes
Speaker 2:  in the opposite of capitalism and hates everything. It's really been fun
Speaker 2:  times listening to Yeah, the, the feedback to the TikTok band stuff we
Speaker 2:  so much feedback about the TikTok thing, including somebody who called us
Speaker 2:  I think three times to yell at me specifically in increasingly
Speaker 2:  well-spoken ways. It's like they, they call that's good. They weren't happy
Speaker 2:  with how they did so they called again and then they did it. It was unbelievable.
Speaker 2:  But anyway, he did
Speaker 5:  That person More people should call and yell at David in an increasingly
Speaker 5:  polite ways.
Speaker 2:  No, no, no. They were not increasingly polite, increasingly well argued ways.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  See. Okay, I'll take that too.
Speaker 2:  Do that again. Yeah. Alright. But let's get to a few of them starting with
Speaker 2:  a question we got from Brandon.
Speaker 11:  Hello, my name is Brandon, I'm based in Cleveland. I have thoughts about
Speaker 11:  your conversation on The Verge cast about the TikTok ban.
Speaker 11:  Not to be a complete conspiracy theorist, but I feel like there is a bunch
Speaker 11:  of ulterior motives for getting rid of TikTok that have nothing to do with
Speaker 11:  national security. First of which is that most of
Speaker 11:  Congress is funded in part or in some significant way by apac.
Speaker 11:  And APAC is sort of losing a propaganda or on TikTok regarding
Speaker 11:  the Gaza situation. Secondly, it's sort of a source of like
Speaker 11:  unfiltered current events information that kind of gives
Speaker 11:  pumped out to viewers before sort of party officials
Speaker 11:  kind of get the chance to formulate talking points about it. But I think
Speaker 11:  that there's just sort of a best of interest to kind of eliminate the wildcard
Speaker 11:  of like unmediated current events news from the
Speaker 11:  landscape on an election year. But the national security and sort
Speaker 11:  of like China angle of it is sort of like a convenient sort of
Speaker 11:  top level reason to use to get rid of the app. But I feel like
Speaker 11:  it just sort of is, you know, one hand that's washing the other and the
Speaker 11:  other hand is really the true reason why both sides of the aisle want to
Speaker 11:  get rid of the app. But that's just my thoughts. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Two things going on here. One, we got a surprising number of voicemails
Speaker 2:  that start with not to be a conspiracy theorist and then dive deep down
Speaker 2:  into it. Yeah. Which is just delightful and is perfectly in line with this
Speaker 2:  entire conversation. But I do think this question of the
Speaker 2:  Israel Hamas war being sort of the catalyzing event for a lot
Speaker 2:  of this came up a lot and we talked about it a smidge in the episode
Speaker 2:  that we did on it, but it's, it's been reported on a lot and there's been
Speaker 2:  this question still ongoing of like, what does the government know and
Speaker 2:  why haven't they told us? Yes. Right. Without,
Speaker 5:  Without question they have
Speaker 2:  Not been clear. Now, a couple of weeks later, I just wanna come back to this
Speaker 2:  thing about like, okay, what, what do we know about what this is actually
Speaker 2:  about and what's going on and what the US
Speaker 2:  government believes it is actually doing here?
Speaker 5:  Okay. I don't want to talk about APAC too much. Like you can, you really
Speaker 5:  can fall down a, a wild ride of conspiracy theories. Yes there. But
Speaker 5:  I will point out that yesterday as we're talking probably last week
Speaker 5:  as people hear this, Joe Biden told Netanyahu on
Speaker 5:  the phone, the situation of Gaza is unacceptable and conditioned further
Speaker 5:  aid for Israel on some lasting solution to that situation.
Speaker 5:  So the pressure has worked Fair enough. I think embedded in
Speaker 5:  this question and much of the feedback that we got is an
Speaker 5:  assumption that the TikTok algorithm is neutral. Mm.
Speaker 5:  And then what's happening on TikTok is a neutral representation of how
Speaker 5:  everyone in America feels. And people are like the kids
Speaker 5:  are speaking and TikTok is show it's like fighting back. Right? And it's
Speaker 5:  like, maybe, maybe that's true. I also believe the situation Gaza us untenable
Speaker 5:  and there should be a ceasefire. But I don't believe that the TikTok algorithm
Speaker 5:  is neutral. There's no evidence that it is right. There's no evidence that
Speaker 5:  bite dance or the Chinese government, it's not like, you know what the fastest
Speaker 5:  way to break lasting Western peace would be would be to break the
Speaker 5:  United States support of Israel. Like that is a true thing. That's a thing
Speaker 5:  that you could do. And the pr putting pressure on that alliance in particular
Speaker 5:  like resets the world order, can you do that through the mechanism of fucking
Speaker 5:  TikTok? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like, but I I think like if to
Speaker 5:  accept that premise that it's because of what happened in Gaza and that young
Speaker 5:  people arguing against a war is what is causing
Speaker 5:  the United States government to say TikTok is a pro. Like you have to accept
Speaker 5:  somewhere in there that the algorithm is neutral. That it is a neutral
Speaker 5:  representation. And I think that's a huge assumption that you should not
Speaker 5:  just make lightly. I also think my formative experience as a young
Speaker 5:  person was the war in Iraq and I, no one listened to
Speaker 5:  me either.
Speaker 5:  Like my friends got arrested, marching down Lake Shore Drive protesting that
Speaker 5:  war and that straight up like no one, like we were
Speaker 5:  loud. I wish I'd had a TikTok then I would've made a lot of videos. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so I, I hear that frustration. I feel it very keenly. I feel the same
Speaker 5:  way about this war in all Wars, but I, I think the presumption that the
Speaker 5:  algorithm is neutral is one that If, you wanna make that claim. I would just
Speaker 5:  encourage you to challenge that presumption and, and think about how much
Speaker 5:  you're relying on it. But like at least yester at least you know,
Speaker 5:  the pressure has worked in some minor way.
Speaker 7:  Well and this is also a trend we see with social media every time
Speaker 7:  like a, a social media that is used by younger people tends to have
Speaker 7:  this moment where everybody's like, why is nobody else talking about this?
Speaker 7:  And it's like, well because you're just on this particular, you're just on
Speaker 7:  Tumblr in 2016. That's why nobody else is talking about it because you haven't
Speaker 7:  left Tumblr, you're just on TikTok in 2024. That's why nobody else
Speaker 7:  is talking about it because you haven't left this app and If, you go and
Speaker 7:  you look and elsewhere, elsewhere If, you look at other media, you will see
Speaker 7:  that this stuff is being covered. And I think that's a trend we see a lot.
Speaker 7:  And on TikTok in particular because of the algorithm, because of the way
Speaker 7:  it is really, really good at disseminating information really, really quickly.
Speaker 7:  We've seen that accelerate. We've seen that be a lot louder and a lot faster
Speaker 7:  than it was in those other cases. And which we have seen, like, to be clear,
Speaker 7:  we've seen it, we saw it with live journal back in, in 2004
Speaker 7:  with with the, the war in Iraq 2003, 2004. You see it again and again
Speaker 7:  and again and it's a behavior where younger people who are starting to really
Speaker 7:  get into media literacy and starting to really think about these things,
Speaker 7:  they go, they get on an app, they find other people just like them and they're
Speaker 7:  like, why is nobody else talking about this? Why is this being held for me
Speaker 7:  and these other areas? And the truth is, it's not, it's just being
Speaker 7:  discussed in a different way. It's being discussed maybe with a little less
Speaker 7:  heated rhetoric or whatever. But also I do wanna, I do kind of agree with
Speaker 7:  him not about that part, but I agree with him certainly about like there
Speaker 7:  are other reasons why the TikTok ban is being pushed. And it is, I would
Speaker 7:  certainly agree it is not just national security reasons. I think there's
Speaker 7:  a massive financial incentive for both the United States and for
Speaker 7:  the many, many companies based in the United States that are direct competitors
Speaker 7:  to TikTok. And those are the people that, like they do, they Meadow,
Speaker 7:  mark Zuckerberg would be delighted if TikTok got shut down
Speaker 7:  tomorrow. you know? Yeah. Like Elon Musk would be delighted if it got shut
Speaker 7:  down tomorrow because that means more users back on their platforms. So I
Speaker 7:  think like we can't ignore the fact that there are certainly other incentives
Speaker 7:  here that are, that are encouraging this. But we also have to like
Speaker 7:  deal with the facts as we are given them. And like when we start to think
Speaker 7:  about, well what if it, you know, why is nobody reporting on this stuff?
Speaker 7:  People are reporting on it, people are looking into this stuff, people are
Speaker 7:  examining it. But if we don't have proof, if we don't have like real
Speaker 7:  quantifiable facts, we are just like pissing in the wind
Speaker 7:  being like maybe something's happening over there. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Also, I, you know, most of Congress believes that what they're going to accomplish
Speaker 5:  is a sale of TikTok and that I don't like If you believe
Speaker 5:  they're gonna sell it. Like then you also have to believe that someone's
Speaker 5:  gonna find the big algorithm dial and turn it like towards Israel
Speaker 5:  and that implies that that dial exists and it is currently pointed towards
Speaker 5:  God and like it can be turned and then now you're right back at the problem
Speaker 5:  of who controls that dial. And so I would just like, it's that assumption
Speaker 5:  that is like, do you believe that the Instagram reels algorithm is neutral?
Speaker 5:  I do not. It mostly shows me babes. Like it just fully
Speaker 5:  believes that that is what I want from that. And like I can't type
Speaker 5:  trucks exploding into Instagram like more loudly. Like
Speaker 5:  that's the thing I actually want. Yeah. And the TikTok algorithm is like,
Speaker 5:  you definitely want trucks exploding and then here are some of the weirdest
Speaker 5:  gadgets ever made. You should buy them.
Speaker 2:  So TikTok gets you TikTok
Speaker 5:  Is what I was like, you are gonna buy so many vacuum cleaners, here's some
Speaker 5:  cut rate anchor batteries, we're doing it this week. That's what's happening.
Speaker 5:  And it's like these algorithm of, we all know that the algorithms have preferences
Speaker 5:  and biases and can be shaped by the people who control them. The
Speaker 5:  question for for this is who should do that? Should it, should it exist in
Speaker 5:  our country? Should it exist? If Rupert and Murdoch bought TikTok, would
Speaker 5:  you be pleased about that? Why or why not? Right? And then the question is,
Speaker 5:  would you be pleased that the Chinese government has that same power?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think that, I think that's fair. And then the, you know, tangential
Speaker 2:  to the question of is the algorithm neutral is like on what
Speaker 2:  vectors can you move the knobs? Right? And it's like that comes back to
Speaker 2:  what do these companies want and who is really in charge? And it's like,
Speaker 2:  that's where all of this gets so messy for me, right. Because it's like I
Speaker 2:  doubt sincerely that it would be good for tiktoks business
Speaker 2:  to move the Gaza knob one way or another. I do
Speaker 2:  think it moves the shop knob to move the business.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's just obviously true. Like it feels true being on TikTok. But
Speaker 2:  then there's all of those questions next to the fact like you're talking
Speaker 2:  about Alex, that the three of us sitting in this room have completely different
Speaker 2:  experiences of TikTok. So to be, to sit here and talk about TikTok as
Speaker 2:  a single thing is essentially impossible. And this is where like I just start
Speaker 2:  running in circles on all of this, right? Like we're essentially using different
Speaker 2:  apps. Yeah. I would bet 95% of what the three of us see on
Speaker 2:  TikTok does not overlap. Yeah. And what do you do with that? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  it's so weird. Well, you, you explain Jojo Siwa
Speaker 2:  to
Speaker 5:  To NELI right before the show starts. No, I refuse to know any of this information.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  NELI got to, I'm sorry. I know there is a, there is an entity called Jojo
Speaker 2:  Siwa and that's all the informationi.
Speaker 5:  I've refused to even acknowledge that it is an entity. I know that there
Speaker 5:  are words that people say that sound like that.
Speaker 2:  I see. Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  By the way, my belief is that the Instagram algorithm only shows me babes
Speaker 5:  'cause I refuse to engage with it. And its default is like, huh,
Speaker 5:  will this work today?
Speaker 2:  I know you want babes.
Speaker 5:  It's like we don't know anything about you babe.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Alright, let's get to the next one, which in the name of fairness
Speaker 2:  is very mad at me specifically. But we got a lot of these that are very mad
Speaker 2:  at me specifically. And as a good journalist, I feel obligated to air one
Speaker 2:  this person, they said their name in a way that I couldn't identify. So we're
Speaker 2:  just gonna call them St. Louis. So this is from St. Louis.
Speaker 12:  From St. Louis and listening to the latest episode of the Birge Cast
Speaker 12:  and taking my fist at the clouds and yelling into the
Speaker 12:  ether because David and Alex are just,
Speaker 12:  I don't know, I guess they've been brainwashed by TikTok or something to
Speaker 12:  start from first principles, right? The most compelling reasons
Speaker 12:  for banning TikTok and then just work your way down to the least compelling.
Speaker 12:  First and foremost when Nila mentioned the 1932 was
Speaker 12:  Communications act, known corner ownership of media. Boom right there.
Speaker 12:  You don't need to go any further. That right there is justification for
Speaker 12:  banning TikTok. It should have been done a long time ago. We don't need
Speaker 12:  to have any debate. We're done, period. Next China
Speaker 12:  bans us social media. Why would that be? Why would they think they should
Speaker 12:  do that? Maybe because if they think it's being done to them, it's
Speaker 12:  because they're doing it to you, right? I mean, it's kind of a tit for SAT
Speaker 12:  thing. But again, you can find that with the other one. And again, I don't
Speaker 12:  think we need to debate it any further. Second, you guys are talking about,
Speaker 12:  well what are they doing? This is all hearsay, blah blah, blah. I don't
Speaker 12:  know. You guys have a have a, you know, a whole website and you seem
Speaker 12:  to like to investigate, you know, shit related to technology and whatever.
Speaker 12:  How about looking into the differences in content between, you know, the
Speaker 12:  different platforms? I would hazard a guess, and I take a big
Speaker 12:  bet that the types of content on TikTok
Speaker 12:  versus reels versus YouTube shorts is
Speaker 12:  quite different. Meaning pick a controversial subject, be it,
Speaker 12:  you know, the Israel, Hamas for Taiwan, et cetera,
Speaker 12:  that there's a dramatic difference in the number of pros
Speaker 12:  and cons posts that are presented on these different platforms.
Speaker 12:  Hi.
Speaker 2:  So the two things in here, one, he brings up a bunch of stuff we've been
Speaker 2:  talking about and, and I think the question of content differences is very
Speaker 2:  interesting, but I specifically wanna talk about this one because a lot of
Speaker 2:  people responded to our talk about the TikTok ban by saying, well, China
Speaker 2:  does it to us, the end problem solved, we should, we can do
Speaker 2:  it back. And I don't find that argument credible at all,
Speaker 2:  but I am open to discussion on that. And NELI in particular, I wanna
Speaker 2:  know what you think because you are the most pro band of us,
Speaker 2:  I would say.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't, I I've heard that argument a lot. It makes sense in like,
Speaker 5:  its way like straight tit for tat like, but China
Speaker 5:  also directly controls its information economy and it is
Speaker 5:  an authoritarian government and I don't think we should do that.
Speaker 2:  Well. So this is kind of where, where I lateral to,
Speaker 5:  I just wanna be clear. Like I I I, I believe in the First Amendment in
Speaker 5:  a very real and meaningful way. What I'm saying is
Speaker 5:  there's a reason in the United States we don't allow a ton of foreign
Speaker 5:  ownership of media. There's a reason that historically if we have not allowed
Speaker 5:  concentration of media ownership, because we know that's dangerous to
Speaker 5:  like the plurality that makes the democracy strong and all this stuff. And
Speaker 5:  so like that, that's its own argument. That is not, they do it so we can
Speaker 5:  do it too,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. I think to me there are sort of two
Speaker 2:  inclusive questions inside of that. One is like, is China
Speaker 2:  does something we can do it back a good argument. And I I think
Speaker 2:  no, for the reasons you just said, I don't want to be like,
Speaker 5:  I think that argument feels, I I wanna be clear. I think that argument feels
Speaker 5:  good. Sure.
Speaker 2:  But I
Speaker 5:  Also, but when you, when when you like run around being like, what we want
Speaker 5:  to preserve is a plurality of media, like no one gives a shit when you're
Speaker 5:  like, they do it to us. Like, everyone's like, yeah, like that feels good.
Speaker 5:  I I understand why the argument is made and I understand why it feels
Speaker 2:  Good. Right? And I think the, it it ladders up to an argument that
Speaker 2:  I think a lot of the Antitrust conversation also ladders up to, which is
Speaker 2:  what do we think our government's job is to do here? And I think in, in a
Speaker 2:  lot of ways there is this belief in America that
Speaker 2:  like the, the market regulates itself and this is how we talk about this
Speaker 2:  stuff in capitalism and all this stuff. But then the question of what is
Speaker 2:  the government's role in that is like, it, it has, it has occurred to me
Speaker 2:  a number of times that this is a thing we should spend a lot of this year
Speaker 2:  talking about is what the government's job is and
Speaker 2:  should be and what that actually looks like in practice. Because I think
Speaker 2:  a lot of people in America feel like what the EU is doing to tech companies
Speaker 2:  is like way overreaching and heavy handed and ridiculous. But it
Speaker 2:  is like culturally, I think in a lot of places in Europe, it is less out
Speaker 2:  of bounds with how things normally work. But to me, all of this
Speaker 2:  stuff sort of circles around this question of like, is the government's job
Speaker 2:  to govern what I look at on my phone? I don't
Speaker 5:  Know. No, I just wanna be very clear about that. No, like
Speaker 5:  I really don't believe, but
Speaker 2:  You want them to ban on TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, again, I think the, your question about like what can the government
Speaker 5:  do and can the market regulate itself? The pendulum has swung pretty wildly
Speaker 5:  over the last 40 years towards no regulation, right? And
Speaker 5:  now it might just slowly be swinging back, right? Like
Speaker 5:  there's 1980 Ronald Reagan, Robert Bork, we've done that Dakota
Speaker 5:  episode. There's like a total deregulation of the market. You can see it.
Speaker 5:  Jonathan Cantor mentioned it to me, same thing. He's like, 1980 this happened
Speaker 5:  and now it pendulum might just be swinging back like just a little bit and
Speaker 5:  people are like, Ooh, that's weird and that's fine. Like that is inside
Speaker 5:  of our market. The thing that I'm saying about TikTok in particular
Speaker 5:  is If, you find out they're doing the bad thing. We can't
Speaker 5:  go arrest the Chinese government. Right? You, you can't do it. You cannot
Speaker 5:  hold them accountable in, in specific ways. I mentioned this on the last
Speaker 5:  show, and I'll say it again. Their kids aren't here. The people who run by
Speaker 5:  dance, you know, their, their kids are there, they're in China, they're in
Speaker 5:  Singapore. So I, there's just a thing that's different, like our experiences
Speaker 5:  here in this country are valuable to us and our
Speaker 5:  media ownership is just a part of that. Like it really is a big part of that.
Speaker 5:  Like I said this as a joke at the end of the last episode, I think we should
Speaker 5:  also break up Sinclair Broadcasting and Clear Channel. Sure. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  massive concentration of media ownership across the country is not good.
Speaker 5:  It only gives you like a singular point of view and puts too many people
Speaker 5:  in charge of what too many people see and feel. There's that really famous
Speaker 5:  video that I think Deadspin made ages ago that was just Sinclair News
Speaker 5:  anchors all saying, all reading the same speech about the fake news. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that is horrifying, right? That's horrifying. And the reason you have
Speaker 5:  media ownership rules is to make sure that doesn't happen. And so like I
Speaker 5:  I landing all of my, like we should ban TikTok
Speaker 5:  criticism in that idea, right?
Speaker 5:  Which is the people who make the media in the United States who shape opinion
Speaker 5:  in the United States who have control over what people see and experience.
Speaker 5:  This has skin in the game here. Fair enough. Alex. And there should be, and
Speaker 5:  there should be more competition in that. Any
Speaker 7:  Thoughts? Yeah, to NE's earlier point, I think, I think he's right that like
Speaker 7:  we took our eye off the ball for a very long ki time in this country. We,
Speaker 7:  we stopped paying content and we stopped caring to regulate companies.
Speaker 7:  And historically we did that a lot. And some of our biggest and most like
Speaker 7:  vibrant economic moments in this country were when we were heavily
Speaker 7:  regulating companies. And so a lot of this is just like culture
Speaker 7:  shock. If, you haven't done something for 40 years and you start doing it
Speaker 7:  even a little bit. Everybody's gonna be like, the hell are you doing over
Speaker 7:  there? But at the same time, like I see the TikTok stuff and I'm like, well
Speaker 7:  that feels kind of hypocritical of us to be like, well, we have to shut down
Speaker 7:  TikTok because it has this really large control
Speaker 7:  over our, our media and, and it has this really
Speaker 7:  important impact on our media when Disney has what, like
Speaker 7:  80% of American box office and, and has this enormous
Speaker 7:  control. And so the only difference between those two is one is in China,
Speaker 7:  and one is Bob Iker. That's
Speaker 5:  A huge difference. Like Disney's here, and, and, and Ron DeSantis is like,
Speaker 5:  here's a weird law about not saying that anyone can ever be gay, which is
Speaker 5:  going like super well for Ron DeSantis, right? Like then Disney got into
Speaker 5:  a political fight and they lost a tax district and
Speaker 5:  they gotta get it back. There was an investor fight that Disney just had
Speaker 5:  to win. Like the consequences of Disney's speech in
Speaker 5:  America are real. Right? And yes, it is true. They have
Speaker 5:  mostly succeeded in all of their fights, but they had to fight.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, right. There were, there were actual, they were held accountable for
Speaker 5:  their positions. And I agree with most of their posi, not all of
Speaker 5:  Disney's positions, I would hasten to say, but some of their
Speaker 5:  positions here about being inclusive, like all that stuff, like a
Speaker 5:  meaningful political element in the United States tried to punish Disney
Speaker 5:  for that stuff and Disney fought back and largely has won or not
Speaker 5:  won, or come to some set of accommodations with the Florida
Speaker 5:  government. Like whatever happened there is different than whatever.
Speaker 5:  If we find out TikTok is doing the bad thing. Yeah. Right. And that's, I
Speaker 5:  think that is just a massively important, like, I don't know, like Disney
Speaker 5:  has employees in the United States, like if Disney has 80% of the box office.
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry, I was reading my, I was reading my little red book that
Speaker 7:  I, I received, I didn't hear anything
Speaker 5:  That I was just saying like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  No, I, I think there is a, there is a fundamental difference, right? Like
Speaker 7:  the, the argument here, the, the core argument of this TikTok thing is
Speaker 7:  who is allowed to dominate conversations in America?
Speaker 7:  And I think that argument shouldn't happen at all. Who should be allowed
Speaker 7:  to dominate conversations in America? No one shouldn't have that. Like
Speaker 7:  Disney shouldn't be as used as it is. TikTok certainly
Speaker 7:  shouldn't be able to just have everybody believe a conspiracy theory or know
Speaker 7:  who the what's up brother guy is with just like a little twist
Speaker 7:  of the algorithm. That's bananas. No one should have that kind of
Speaker 7:  monopoly on our culture and on our media. But at
Speaker 7:  the same time, I kind of agree with the fact that like, we probably don't
Speaker 7:  want foreign actors in, in, in the United States controlling
Speaker 7:  stuff, right? Like we, we, we don't necessarily want that because we've seen
Speaker 7:  time and time again. But banning TikTok doesn't solve that. Russia has found
Speaker 7:  many ways to get into our country and, and influence
Speaker 7:  us at a mass scale using American tools. Like the tools themselves
Speaker 7:  are the problem. It's not who owns them because the tools are the thing that
Speaker 7:  is disseminating the information. We, we saw that in 2016 with
Speaker 7:  how Russia manipulated Facebook and other social media platforms and there's,
Speaker 7:  that's just proof like that, that happened.
Speaker 5:  There was a bunch of reporting about how there was a Russian disinformation
Speaker 5:  campaign around Kate Middleton. Yeah. And it's like, oh, they just keep doing
Speaker 5:  it. They, oh, they, they're still at it. They're,
Speaker 7:  They're still doing it.
Speaker 2:  I'm realizing as we talked that I think I would be more compelled by your
Speaker 2:  argument NELI if I felt like the US was regulating anything
Speaker 2:  that like
Speaker 5:  We have like a functional government. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  If we were preventing the American owned services from doing
Speaker 2:  the things we're accusing TikTok of, I would be more compelled by the argument
Speaker 2:  that since we can't prevent TikTok from doing it, the responsible thing to
Speaker 2:  do is kick them out. I think if If you draw that line,
Speaker 2:  that sort of makes sense to me. But that assumes that we are
Speaker 2:  capable of doing it to anybody and there's really no evidence that we're
Speaker 2:  capable of doing that to anybody. Well,
Speaker 5:  There's one huge prohibition, which is the first amendment. It really,
Speaker 5:  really gets in your way. Right? It's like a real problem. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  good problem. A problem that I, I think we should continue to have.
Speaker 2:  I swear there will come a time on the show where I make you earnestly argue
Speaker 2:  against the first time. Exactly. I'm so excited about it. It's
Speaker 5:  Very challenging. You have to believe, and I think this is why a lot of the
Speaker 5:  people who don't think TikTok should be banned or sold, sold who,
Speaker 5:  who think this is all crazy. You have to believe that American companies
Speaker 5:  have in some way the best interest of Americans at heart or America at
Speaker 5:  heart. And I don't think that's easy to believe. I think it, if I walked
Speaker 5:  up to most people and I was like, Disney isn't a champion of American values
Speaker 5:  to pick, what are you talking? Right? If I said that about Facebook or Apple
Speaker 5:  or Google or Pfizer, whatever, like most people do not
Speaker 5:  believe that that is the case. Right? I don't know that I believe that that
Speaker 5:  is the case, but it is, when I talk about challenging assumptions,
Speaker 5:  that is one assumption at the heart of the idea that big companies in America
Speaker 5:  should have all kinds of freedoms and
Speaker 15:  prohibition laws fail, so this will probably go that way. Love the pod.
Speaker 15:  Have a good one.
Speaker 2:  Ditto. Nilay. Patel. TikTok is Digital Crack. That's, that's the
Speaker 2:  headline here.
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure that's the,
Speaker 2:  I wanna pose this as as a question because I think this is kind of where
Speaker 2:  we ended the last time we talked about this and I, I I want to end here too.
Speaker 2:  Is there a version of this that accomplishes anything? A
Speaker 5:  Version of what
Speaker 2:  TikTok ban? Like can you, a, can you ban TikTok
Speaker 2:  in a, in an actually practically enforceable way and B
Speaker 2:  would it do anything? Because I think there's, there's a real nihilism setting
Speaker 2:  in in a lot of this conversation that's like, whatever, it's, it's,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. First of all, just to be, I think as of today, TikTok is
Speaker 5:  not banned Correct. And there is no movement on a bill in the Senate.
Speaker 2:  Alex and I are winning that bet so far. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's no movement on a bill in the Senate to actually ban TikTok,
Speaker 5:  so whatever. Yeah. Right, right. Then
Speaker 5:  there's the other reality, which is the bill would potentially force a
Speaker 5:  sale and there's a lot of people who might want, want to
Speaker 5:  buy it and you might just end up in that situation. Yep. So there's a lot
Speaker 5:  of things that have to happen first, and many of them don't end up in the
Speaker 5:  thing as banned. But I think If, you do ban it like it, I don't think people
Speaker 5:  are just gonna be staring at like a blank screen on their phone. Like, just
Speaker 5:  like Wistfully thinking about when Charlie Delio started dancing again.
Speaker 5:  you know, like I, they, they're gonna just like move on. Okay,
Speaker 2:  But let me pause at this. So the, the, what this does is prevent app stores
Speaker 2:  from carrying it, right? Yeah, that is, that is essentially what this man
Speaker 2:  looks like. There are what, a couple hundred million people in the United States
Speaker 2:  who already have TikTok on their phones. I don't think there's any real precedent
Speaker 2:  for Apple and Google reaching out and proactively deleting apps from
Speaker 2:  your phone. Yeah. So that's just a lot of people who have TikTok still
Speaker 2:  already. It also VPNs exist. People
Speaker 2:  have done
Speaker 5:  A lot of work. I love the idea of work to like some small country like becoming
Speaker 5:  a honeypot VPN station for TikTok, like Monaco. you know, it's like
Speaker 5:  everyone is just like VPNing through Monaco and Monaco's TikTok becomes
Speaker 5:  us TikTok.
Speaker 2:  It's like the, I forget which country it is, but the country that owns the
Speaker 2:  AI domain is suddenly that's like a meaningful part of the GVP as all these
Speaker 2:  companies. It's
Speaker 5:  Great. Yeah. Great. All of these things could happen and I agree many,
Speaker 5:  look, the Chinese great firewall works, but it, it's not perfect. Right?
Speaker 5:  And the idea that we would put one up and it would work perfectly is like
Speaker 5:  nonsensical. Like, yes, some people are still gonna use TikTok, but the app
Speaker 5:  won't be able to get updated and people won't be uploading content
Speaker 5:  to a thing that looks like, it's not like it will result in some kind of
Speaker 5:  weird decline over time and fine. But there's just so many
Speaker 5:  steps from here to there. Like so, so many steps from here to there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. Alex, you and I have been on on the same page about this and
Speaker 2:  I'm curious where I've landed after, you know, two more weeks of this is
Speaker 2:  I think most likely outcome by a pretty wide margin. Nothing happens.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Second most likely outcome, it gets sold
Speaker 2:  in some way, shape, or form. Not to Steven Mnuchin, but to somebody else.
Speaker 2:  Big, giant planet sized gap down to option
Speaker 2:  number three, which is that TikTok actually gets banned in a meaningful way.
Speaker 2:  Do you disagree or disagree?
Speaker 7:  It's not gonna get banned. It, it, it, it won't get banned. And, and I think
Speaker 7:  even a sale is gonna be super unlikely because who's gonna buy it? Who's
Speaker 7:  gonna have the money and not have a monopoly as soon as they
Speaker 7:  own it. Right. And also then I think we just come back to that conversation
Speaker 7:  of wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. It's not okay for the Chinese government
Speaker 7:  to manipulate us through TikTok, but it is totally okay for
Speaker 7:  Disney or Larry Ellison or whoever
Speaker 7:  to manipulate us through TikTok. Well, that's not good. Like I,
Speaker 7:  I think it's just such a stupid, stupid ban. And
Speaker 7:  for, for those reasons, I understand like the rationale behind it and the
Speaker 7:  legal theory behind it and, and all of that. I, I get that, but at the same
Speaker 7:  time I'm like, the hypocrisy of it is so outrageous and I'm like, don't be
Speaker 7:  so dumb.
Speaker 2:  I've decided that the funniest possible outcome is that one branch of the
Speaker 2:  government forces it to be sold to YouTube and then
Speaker 2:  four minutes later, Lena Khan files a lawsuit against two
Speaker 2:  for, for Antitrust.
Speaker 7:  That'd be good.
Speaker 2:  You gotta keep the government wheels turning. Yeah. Yeah. We're just gonna
Speaker 2:  keep a lot of lawyers employed.
Speaker 5:  Well, when I think of what the founding fathers really wanted, it was a self-perpetuating
Speaker 5:  cycle of government actions.
Speaker 2:  It's beautiful. All right, we got one more and then I'm gonna let you guys
Speaker 2:  get outta here. This has nothing to do with TikTok or Apple, but it is Apple.
Speaker 2:  It is a perfectly Verge casty question and so I'm obligated to play it. This
Speaker 2:  is from Michael.
Speaker 16:  Hello, this is Michael from San Francisco. So I've been
Speaker 16:  loving you guys' coverage on The future of the web and I love how obsessed
Speaker 16:  with the web you are. And I too am obsessed with it and
Speaker 16:  I'm trying to find more and more web apps to replace the apps on my phone.
Speaker 16:  So I'm wondering what web apps, not native apps, but like,
Speaker 16:  whether they be PWAs or just web pages, like what
Speaker 16:  are the web apps you guys use day to day? What are some of your favorite
Speaker 16:  web apps? Thanks. Goodbye.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I just, I want to just, we're, we're gonna do two each. Okay.
Speaker 2:  This is, these are the rules and neither none of us can say The Verge because
Speaker 2:  The Verge is the best web app that exists. You should download it to your
Speaker 2:  home screen. It's actually very good on your home screen. Highly recommend
Speaker 2:  everybody's furiously scrolling through their phones right now. Yeah, so
Speaker 2:  I'll go first. The two web apps that I use the most, I would say at this
Speaker 2:  moment are, I use an app called Feed Bin as an RSS reader
Speaker 2:  that is fantastic on the web. It's super late and super fast. It's where
Speaker 2:  all of my stuff comes into. I started piping my YouTube subscriptions into
Speaker 2:  there so that I get new things from the channels I subscribe to without
Speaker 2:  the rest of the YouTube interface. Love it. Feed bin.com. It's amazing. I
Speaker 2:  think it's like five bucks a month, cannot recommend it highly enough. And
Speaker 2:  the other one, there's two I could choose from here, but the other one I'll
Speaker 2:  pick is a to-Do list app that I have started using and
Speaker 2:  stopped using and come back to because this is the, the Sickness with which
Speaker 2:  I live that way. It's called twos, TWOS. And it is like
Speaker 2:  just a perfectly made, very simple list
Speaker 2:  making app with reminders and integrates with your calendar. And it is just
Speaker 2:  fast as hell. And a lot of the app works offline even in your browser. It,
Speaker 2:  it, it rules. Cannot recommend it enough. I love a good simple, fast
Speaker 5:  Choose.com.
Speaker 2:  I think it's twos app.com.
Speaker 5:  Ah, that explains a lot of thing.
Speaker 7:  That's very cool.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so those are my two Alex. What do you got?
Speaker 7:  Story Graph is is probably my big one. It's a good read replacement. That's
Speaker 7:  kind and it is, it just slaps. It is fantastic. I don't use
Speaker 7:  any of the social parts of it, I just use it to track what I'm reading and
Speaker 7:  anytime somebody says which book should I read, I immediately open that and,
Speaker 7:  and start flipping through it. 'cause I just adore it. And then my other
Speaker 7:  one is probably like a console I use on to to, to
Speaker 7:  interact with my Raspberry Pie. That it, it's just like amazing. Like it's
Speaker 7:  the pie hole console and you can just like, there's like a web app version
Speaker 7:  of it and, and I adore that. Like a lot of smart home stuff has
Speaker 7:  web apps and I'm just like, yeah, this is great. And I, so I was looking
Speaker 7:  through it and I was like, oh, I guess most of my web apps are like smart
Speaker 7:  Home, quick access.
Speaker 2:  It's perfect. I love it. And that's like, it, it connects to all your stuff.
Speaker 2:  It does all
Speaker 7:  This stuff and it does it. Yeah. And they work. Yeah. And it's great.
Speaker 2:  That's good. Yeah. Pie Hole is a good app. All right. Neela, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  Well, I wish I'd gotten this question knowing that I wasn't allowed to say
Speaker 5:  The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's just cheating. It's like, it's a website. It's,
Speaker 5:  It is very good on the, on the thing. I want to issue one correction last
Speaker 5:  week or two weeks ago, I said Notion Calendar on the Mac was native. Mm.
Speaker 5:  That's an electron app. It just happens to be very good. And the person who
Speaker 5:  wrote it was tweeting about how happy he was.
Speaker 2:  He was very proud. Yeah. That you, you confuse it for being a native app.
Speaker 2:  That's good. Which means all the people who build bad electron apps, shame
Speaker 2:  on you. Yeah. Do better.
Speaker 5:  You got nowhere to hide. So yeah, I, I have a home
Speaker 5:  bridge and I use the Home Bridge web app on my phone all the time,
Speaker 5:  mostly to update the plugins, but that's like a thing that I use all the
Speaker 5:  time. I go to that web and then it's actually interesting that I don't think
Speaker 5:  of these as web apps. They're just little web servers in my house. So Homer
Speaker 5:  just runs in my house. That counts. Yeah. And then my Sony receiver has a
Speaker 5:  little web server in it to change all the settings and of course it does.
Speaker 5:  I spends so much time just like monkeying with the little settings on the
Speaker 5:  center of the receiver. That's amazing. you know the, this question, like
Speaker 5:  it gets at the heart of something I was looking@twostwosapp.com
Speaker 5:  and you open it and the banner is like, download our app Yep. At the top
Speaker 5:  of the screen. Yep.
Speaker 2:  It's actually better on the web than any other platform and it's still wants
Speaker 2:  you to download an app, which I think is fascinating.
Speaker 5:  A lot of this question is just like Apple does not want that thing to happen.
Speaker 5:  That happened to its laptops,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. And, and yeah, there, there's gonna come a time when
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna write 40,000 words about how annoying it is when you open up like
Speaker 2:  Reddit or any other site and it's like, isn't this better in the app? And
Speaker 2:  I'm like, no, I on our website have a good website. Yep. If it's better in
Speaker 2:  the app, it's your fault. Yeah. But yeah, anyway, the web is great. We love
Speaker 2:  the web. Please ask us questions about the web. Alright, we gotta get outta
Speaker 2:  here. NELI. Alex, thank you as always for doing this and I suspect we'll
Speaker 2:  have more of this to do in the very near future. Peace. That's it for The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast today. Thanks to NELI and Alex for doing this with me. And thank
Speaker 2:  you as always for listening and for sending in all of those Hotline questions
Speaker 2:  and emails. We love getting all of your feedback. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about, by the way, at The Verge dot com. I'll put some links in
Speaker 2:  the show notes. But also the TikTok ban and the Apple stuff is all happening
Speaker 2:  sort of constantly all the time. Even just recently, there's a
Speaker 2:  huge lawsuit about the Apple Watch that is very much a regulatory question
Speaker 2:  about Apple. Even separately from the Antitrust stuff. There's just a lot
Speaker 2:  going on. Before we go, two quick housekeeping things. One, this
Speaker 2:  coming weekend, April 13th on Saturday, I'm gonna be
Speaker 2:  in Chicago at the Chicago Humanities Festival along with a couple of my colleagues
Speaker 2:  doing a series of panels, all about AI and creativity.
Speaker 2:  Trying to figure out what does AI mean for people who wanna
Speaker 2:  make things and what does it give them in terms of tools? What does it take
Speaker 2:  away? How do we as consumers understand what this stuff
Speaker 2:  is when some of it is made by humans and some of it's made by ai and that
Speaker 2:  line starts to get really blurry. We're gonna spend a whole Saturday afternoon
Speaker 2:  sorting through all of that with some really interesting people. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  put the link in the show notes, we'll put it in the description. If, you
Speaker 2:  want to get tickets. If you're in Chicago, you want to come hang out and
Speaker 2:  talk about ai? Please do. We would love to have you. It's gonna be incredibly
Speaker 2:  fun. Thing number two, we have been nominated for a Webby Award
Speaker 2:  for best technology podcast. It's very important, A, that you
Speaker 2:  vote for us because we wanna win this award very badly. And B, that we
Speaker 2:  beat NELI and decoder. It's so, so important. NELI
Speaker 2:  is nominated for decoder as best business podcast and he can totally
Speaker 2:  win that. Sounds great. Love that for Eli. Enjoy that. I wanna beat
Speaker 2:  him for Best Technology podcast so bad. Plus he wins. Anyway, great news
Speaker 2:  all around. Go to the Webbys. We'll put the link in the show notes, put the
Speaker 2:  link in the description, please vote for The. Vergecast. We love, particularly
Speaker 2:  when we win the People's Choice Award, because it comes from you all the
Speaker 2:  listeners who say you like this show, we want all your feedback, we want
Speaker 2:  all your thoughts. But the Webby Award is really cool looking and I want
Speaker 2:  one really bad. That's enough for now. Please go vote for us. Come see us
Speaker 2:  in Chicago. Can't wait to hang out. As always, If, you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  feelings, or more you wanna say about TikTok in China. You can
Speaker 2:  always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the Hotline eight six six
Speaker 2:  Verge one one. Truly the Hotline is my favorite thing about The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  It's so fun hearing all of the things you have to say, some of which is super
Speaker 2:  mean and doesn't make it on the show, some of which is really nice and doesn't
Speaker 2:  make it on the show, some of which is somewhere in between. It's great. We
Speaker 2:  do a Hotline question on the show at least once a week, so please keep 'em
Speaker 2:  all coming. This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Will
Speaker 2:  four The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. NELI, Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about some fun gadget
Speaker 2:  reviews we got coming this week and everything else happening in tech. We'll
Speaker 2:  see you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 3:  Support for this podcast comes from Smart Water. Want to get a little more
Speaker 3:  from every sip. Smart water alkaline doesn't just taste crisp and pure. It's
Speaker 3:  loaded with everything you need to perform at your best. Whether you're running
Speaker 3:  marathons or boardroom meetings, elevate how you hydrate and pick up a smart
Speaker 3:  water alkaline today. To learn more, visit drink smart water.com.