# Transcript
ID: 4f34efc9-7f5d-4284-b1e3-73f92622ff9d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1835416012460039360/-467514313423100449/s93290-US-5532s-1733829500.mp3
Description: A week ago, The Verge launched a subscription. And you had questions! So we have answers. The Verge’s Helen Havlak and Nilay Patel join the show to talk about how we priced the subscription, why ad-free podcasts are hard to do, Apple News, what we do during ad breaks, and much more. And if we didn’t answer your question, let us know! Call the Vergecast Hotline at 866-VERGE11, or email vergecast@theverge.com, with all your questions. Thanks to everyone who sent them in!
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Inside Baseball. I'm your
Speaker 2:  friend David Pierce, and I am outside for the first time in kind of an alarmingly
Speaker 2:  long time. I was sick most of last week. Plus it's just like gray
Speaker 2:  and dreary and cold and just gross outside. So I've mostly spent
Speaker 2:  the last week just kinda lying on the couch, feeling bad for myself and watching
Speaker 2:  shows I've seen 50 times before, which no complaints. It's a terrific
Speaker 2:  way to spend your life, but I just needed to get outside. So we're just out
Speaker 2:  for a walk. By the way, I've gotten some questions from people over the last
Speaker 2:  couple of weeks who are like, David, what are you doing during these
Speaker 2:  intros? Are you actually doing these things or are you like lying to us?
Speaker 2:  And the answer is, I'm always doing these things. I've done these intros
Speaker 2:  from a train. I've done these intros from a paint shop. I've done
Speaker 2:  them while putting together Legos. I did one at one point
Speaker 2:  like in a courthouse, and I don't think I was supposed to do that. I
Speaker 2:  don't think I got in trouble, but probably not a good idea,
Speaker 2:  but I'm here for you. The other question I've gotten a bunch is, David, why
Speaker 2:  do you start the show this way? Nobody cares. Just get to the tech news and
Speaker 2:  to that, I say that is terrific feedback and a perfectly fair point.
Speaker 2:  It's also probably not gonna change. So I'm real sorry about that. Questions
Speaker 2:  like that, by the way, are all we're gonna do on this show today. We've
Speaker 2:  gotten a lot of questions over the last week, especially since we launched
Speaker 2:  our subscription last week about The Verge and about The Vergecast and
Speaker 2:  about ads, and about how the media works and about how podcasts work. And
Speaker 2:  so we figured we'd just answer as many of them as we can all in one place.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk to Helen Haack, our publisher, and Neela Patel, my
Speaker 2:  co-host, your friend, my boss, about all of this stuff,
Speaker 2:  the business, the editorial, how we think about what we make and who we make
Speaker 2:  it for and how we charge for it. All this stuff. I think this stuff really
Speaker 2:  matters. It's gonna get really wonky and detailed at some points. And if
Speaker 2:  you're not interested in like deep thoughts on the future of media, there
Speaker 2:  might be spots here that aren't for you. But I think this stuff really matters
Speaker 2:  and it's a story about the internet and about what it means to try and make
Speaker 2:  it work. We're going through a lot of this stuff, but we're far from the
Speaker 2:  only ones going through it. So I think talking through what it looks like
Speaker 2:  and how we're navigating it might actually be interesting. We're gonna find
Speaker 2:  out all that is coming up in just a second. But first, I'm
Speaker 2:  not done on this walk. It feels good to be outside. I forgot how good it
Speaker 2:  feels to be outside. So we're gonna keep doing it then we'll get to it. This
Speaker 2:  is The Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, fun fact it started raining, I
Speaker 2:  don't know, 45 seconds after I turned off the camera for that intro,
Speaker 2:  So I went inside. It's better here. I was wrong. Don't
Speaker 2:  listen to me about going outside. Inside is where it's at. Alright, we
Speaker 2:  have a lot of questions to do. Let's just get into it. We're gonna do this
Speaker 2:  in two chunks. First, we're gonna talk to Helen Hala about some
Speaker 2:  of the more sort of explicitly businessy things about
Speaker 2:  The Verge and The Vergecast. I think as you've heard us talk a lot about
Speaker 2:  on this show, we try really hard to keep those two things as far apart as
Speaker 2:  possible. So Helen is gonna talk to us about as much of
Speaker 2:  the money as we possibly can. Then Neli is gonna come on and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk, I would say more broadly about how we make the show and how we make
Speaker 2:  The Verge and how we think about all of this stuff. There's gonna be some
Speaker 2:  overlaps, I suspect, between these two segments because Neli and Helen are
Speaker 2:  both tasked with thinking kind of big picture about The Verge at
Speaker 2:  all times. But it felt useful to pull these two things apart. So
Speaker 2:  first we're gonna talk to Helen. We got some questions including the number
Speaker 2:  one by a mile question that you all had about
Speaker 2:  The Verge and The Vergecast for this meta show. So let's just dive into it.
Speaker 2:  Helen, have luck. Welcome back to the show.
Speaker 5:  Thank you so much. Excited to be here.
Speaker 2:  It's been a minute. I feel like you're, you're allowed to invite yourself
Speaker 2:  on anytime. So I assume the fact that it's been a while just means that you
Speaker 2:  don't want to be here ever and I have dragged you here against your will.
Speaker 5:  I'm just an invisible presence behind The Verge that's been here for 10 years
Speaker 5:  and is in everyone's dms, but rarely appears in public.
Speaker 2:  Is it 10 years now?
Speaker 5:  It was 10 years in November.
Speaker 2:  David, my, my Helen origin story is that you and I ran
Speaker 2:  CES together one year right after you joined and right
Speaker 2:  before I left. And so we had this like insane
Speaker 2:  crucible of a CES and then parted ways for a long time and
Speaker 2:  now we get to work together again.
Speaker 5:  We spent a lot of time in that CE Cs trailer where
Speaker 5:  I learned that David is really good at writing headlines
Speaker 5:  and Cs from a VERGE perspective is exhausting,
Speaker 5:  but fun.
Speaker 2:  Some, some things don't change, it turns out. Alright, so before we get into
Speaker 2:  some of the questions we got from folks, let's just, let's just set up kind
Speaker 2:  of who you are and what we're doing here. So you're the VIRs publisher,
Speaker 2:  what does that mean?
Speaker 5:  That means, first and foremost for this show, I'm Eli's boss. That's very
Speaker 5:  important. But what that really means is I am the layer of the company,
Speaker 5:  Vox Media, our parent company in between editorial, the newsroom
Speaker 5:  and the business side. So my job is to oversee the
Speaker 5:  newsroom and kind of buffer it from the business things when we talk about
Speaker 5:  the firewall between editorial and business. Hi, I'm Helen, I'm the firewall.
Speaker 5:  You're the firewall, I'm the firewall. That's really good.
Speaker 5:  And So I spend a lot of time making sure that The
Speaker 5:  Verge is making enough money to support our journalism.
Speaker 5:  I spend a lot of time working on management problems,
Speaker 5:  strategy problems. I spend a lot of time on the phone with Neli.
Speaker 5:  But yes, I, I think for you know, all intensive purposes, my
Speaker 5:  most important job is the firewall between the business and The Verge
Speaker 5:  such that we keep it running and keep everyone employed while also doing
Speaker 5:  great work.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I feel like I always think of you as the person whose job is to be
Speaker 2:  simultaneously the most high level and the most
Speaker 2:  in the weeds of anyone at The Verge.
Speaker 5:  Yes. One way I sometimes explain my job to people is I spend
Speaker 5:  30% of my time just on straight up management headaches. I
Speaker 5:  spend 30% of my time on what are our biggest businesses that
Speaker 5:  we need to take care of that has historically been advertising. So I spend
Speaker 5:  a bunch of time going to client meetings, events,
Speaker 5:  all of those fun things, and I spend 30% of my time working on new businesses.
Speaker 5:  Where do I think The Verge needs to be in the future? And the biggest one
Speaker 5:  of those this year has been subscriptions, which I know we're gonna talk
Speaker 5:  about later.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So to that point actually, one of the questions we've gotten a bit
Speaker 2:  of is both why this, like why
Speaker 2:  do a subscription to the website, but I would say more significantly the
Speaker 2:  question seems to be why now as opposed to, you know, people
Speaker 2:  who've been doing this for forever, there are lots of folks who haven't.
Speaker 2:  Why was this the time,
Speaker 5:  Well, I'll take those questions maybe separately. Sure. The why subscriptions
Speaker 5:  and why now, why subscriptions? I think anyone who listens to The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast has heard Neli and you David talk about Google
Speaker 5:  Zero and some of the forces that are shaping the internet in the future.
Speaker 5:  There have been a lot of pressures on media businesses over the years.
Speaker 5:  The Verge is a big advertising business, but when you look at
Speaker 5:  how does a big digital advertising business work today,
Speaker 5:  things that are pressure on that business model, a lot of ad
Speaker 5:  technology is made and sold by companies like Facebook
Speaker 5:  and Google. They own an outsized portion of the total digital media
Speaker 5:  advertising pie. Fox Media has insulated ourselves from that a bit by
Speaker 5:  also having our own ad tech stack called concert, which I don't think we
Speaker 5:  talk enough about, but that's definitely one pressure.
Speaker 5:  Another is the pressure of distribution on our scale. So
Speaker 5:  advertising, you make a lot of money in advertising If you could charge high
Speaker 5:  rates for it because the product you make is really good or maybe
Speaker 5:  you're not sharing a cut of that with someone else, you make money because
Speaker 5:  you're reaching a lot of people. And that's where distribution has really
Speaker 5:  changed since, you know, 2016 Facebook was sending a
Speaker 5:  fire hose of traffic to everyone, right? Google has been
Speaker 5:  sending fire hoses of traffic to every publisher in the world. And
Speaker 5:  with the rise of generative search that's changing,
Speaker 5:  search is changing a lot. And so, you know, NELI and I have
Speaker 5:  been talking for a long time about how do we prepare The Verge for a point
Speaker 5:  where we're not getting a ton of traffic from other people's platforms
Speaker 5:  and so we need our own audience. That was the whole premise of our
Speaker 5:  redesigned website in 2022. And so the kind of next
Speaker 5:  extension of that, how do you insulate the business model from
Speaker 5:  some of these big forces? Well, it's subscription. What drives a
Speaker 5:  really good subscriptions business. It's really good content that reaches
Speaker 5:  a lot of loyal people and so it was kind of the obvious
Speaker 5:  next place to go. That being said, we've been really
Speaker 5:  cautious, I would say, in how we've approached it to try and keep a big
Speaker 5:  free product of The Verge going. At the same time, a
Speaker 5:  lot of people use The Verge as a daily news utility. If we don't wanna be
Speaker 5:  so dependent on other people's distribution, I think we need to tend to that
Speaker 5:  daily habit, make sure we do a good job there. But you know,
Speaker 5:  I think the challenges of running an internet content business are
Speaker 5:  huge. They're only getting harder and worse. I think
Speaker 5:  the place we need to be to insulate ourselves from all that change is
Speaker 5:  to have a healthy subscriptions business. And then why now you know, the
Speaker 5:  best time to launch. What is the cliche saying the best time to plant a
Speaker 5:  tree is 10 years ago, the next best time is tomorrow. Right?
Speaker 5:  Same with subscriptions. The best time to launch a subscription business
Speaker 5:  is 10 years ago. The next best time is tomorrow.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Do you think the ultimate goal here is
Speaker 2:  to kind of be all of those things at the same time? Like we, we
Speaker 2:  talk about, you know, there's the, there's an advertising business and there's
Speaker 2:  a subscriptions business and there's having a huge audience and there's having
Speaker 2:  a dedicated audience. And I feel like a lot of what we've seen in media
Speaker 2:  over the last few years is people betting on one or the other
Speaker 2:  and very rarely all of the above. Do you think it's possible to bet on all
Speaker 2:  of the above?
Speaker 5:  When you say all of the above? The, the thing I would maybe clarify
Speaker 5:  is I think where people got into trouble as media businesses was
Speaker 5:  betting on total traffic and total page use
Speaker 5:  and what has become really clear as X
Speaker 5:  has stopped sending meaningful traffic as Zuckerberg has gotten
Speaker 5:  less interested in news, is that
Speaker 5:  true audience is different from a bunch of page views. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And so when we're thinking about what do we need to invest in,
Speaker 5:  it's true audience who comes to us directly, things
Speaker 5:  we know about those people, right? Like you could look at the
Speaker 5:  total VERGE page views, but the people who are true VERGE
Speaker 5:  audience, those people on average do a lot of page views for us.
Speaker 5:  That's where a lot of our meaningful audience comes from. And so if I were
Speaker 5:  to say what we need is a large, loyal audience of
Speaker 5:  real people who truly care about and form habit around The Verge.
Speaker 5:  And that is the single biggest asset. And on that
Speaker 5:  asset you can support several kinds of businesses. You could support
Speaker 5:  an advertising business, you can support a subscriptions business, you could
Speaker 5:  support a commerce business. But the true currency
Speaker 5:  that I think any media brand needs in order to survive the next
Speaker 5:  13 years is a direct loyal audience
Speaker 5:  who actually has affinity and builds habit around your brand.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. I remember my, my old boss at Wired, Nick Thompson always used
Speaker 2:  to say when, when they were doing the paywall over there that
Speaker 2:  the beauty of this system is it just aligns us better with the
Speaker 2:  people who read our stuff. He's like, that's just, we're gonna do
Speaker 2:  lots of other things. But this idea that we are now pulling in the same direction
Speaker 2:  as the people who come to our website every day feels pretty good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know, I think there's the part of a subscription business that's
Speaker 5:  just business, right? This is another revenue line for us. But one thing
Speaker 5:  I'm really excited about is, okay, if we're gonna build
Speaker 5:  loyalty and habit, what we really need people to do is come
Speaker 5:  directly to The Verge, log into The Verge, spend a bunch of time on The Verge,
Speaker 5:  maybe become a commenter, interact with our people and getting
Speaker 5:  people to subscribe and pay for something
Speaker 5:  actually ends up deepening their relationship. And it makes us, I think,
Speaker 5:  more directly accountable to our audience. I think we have always felt directly
Speaker 5:  accountable to our audience, but in a way like you all listeners with Vergecast
Speaker 5:  who might now be VERGE subscribers, you are our clients, we have a
Speaker 5:  job we have to do for you, we have standards we have to meet. And
Speaker 5:  I think it aligns editorial and business incentives
Speaker 5:  in a really great way. I wouldn't say that's, that advertising is
Speaker 5:  opposite. You know, I think advertising rewards good journalism
Speaker 5:  if you're trying to do, you know, like a good direct
Speaker 5:  advertising business. Yeah. But I am excited for the,
Speaker 5:  the way this will change our relationship to our audience.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Well, with that in mind, let me give you three questions that our
Speaker 2:  audience has been asking us that I think you're the, you're the best person
Speaker 2:  to answer. The first one is, I would
Speaker 2:  say by, by several orders of magnitude, the most asked
Speaker 2:  question over the last two weeks, both before and
Speaker 2:  after we announced the subscription, which I gotta kick out of and it is,
Speaker 2:  it is ad free podcasts in general and ad free Vergecast
Speaker 2:  in particular that is not part of the subscription.
Speaker 2:  Where is, where is your mind and, and the verges mind on
Speaker 2:  ad free podcasts?
Speaker 5:  I love Vergecast listeners, I know you all want ad free podcasting.
Speaker 5:  I think look first David, I wanna set some context about media.
Speaker 5:  It is a bloodbath out there right now. Like our competitors are cutting jobs,
Speaker 5:  newsrooms are moving away from reporting on news journalism, jobs
Speaker 5:  keep going away. And so success for The Verge in our
Speaker 5:  subscription product is not that we are like
Speaker 5:  making a bunch of Im media executives super rich and buying
Speaker 5:  Supercars success is like we get to continue to exist and
Speaker 5:  if we're super successful, maybe we get to give a few more journalists jobs
Speaker 5:  next year and have their work here on The Vergecast. So
Speaker 5:  it's, this is not like a big remarkable profit
Speaker 5:  engine. The media business famously wildly profitable.
Speaker 2:  You're not buying several fancy new cars as a result of this
Speaker 5:  Is what you're saying. No, I'm so sorry Neli, I won't be buying you a new
Speaker 5:  truck.
Speaker 5:  So if the virtuals really well next year, what that looks like is we get
Speaker 5:  give a few more journalist jobs and we get to continue to exist.
Speaker 5:  So I wanna set that context of like what
Speaker 5:  we're trying to do here is continue to exist, make more things, make better
Speaker 5:  things, right? But you know, there's a reason PR people outnumber journalists
Speaker 5:  six to one in this country right now. It's because virtually every journalist
Speaker 5:  could leave the industry and make more money elsewhere. A big place The Verge
Speaker 5:  has lost reporters to is actually Google. We love you Dieter,
Speaker 5:  but we don't leave. Like we all care about the work. We really like working
Speaker 5:  with our colleagues. It's kind of earnest and corny. Sorry David, but
Speaker 5:  that's why we keep doing this
Speaker 2:  Thing. I know we try to avoid saying that out loud, but it is true
Speaker 5:  Without the way I've talked a little bit about why subscriptions and why
Speaker 5:  now in the subscription product on the website we did a
Speaker 5:  premium ad experience and we did it instead of an ad-free experience. And
Speaker 5:  I'll kind of explain why The Verge makes most of our money in advertising
Speaker 5:  today. We are not in a situation where The Verge is in such trouble.
Speaker 5:  We need to make a hard pivot because there's no advertising left. And the
Speaker 5:  only thing that will save us is subscription revenue. We still have a pretty
Speaker 5:  good ad business and we need to take care of that thing because it's going
Speaker 5:  to be paying our bills for the next several years. Subscriptions are a really
Speaker 5:  long game. And so as we build this thing, we cannot afford
Speaker 5:  to mess up our advertising business or the virtual be in bad trouble. So
Speaker 5:  as we were looking though at what do people want from The Verge
Speaker 5:  website? Well they wanted fewer ads, they wanted better ads, they definitely
Speaker 5:  didn't want the churn boxes. And so we said, okay, if we can't do ad free
Speaker 5:  because we need to take care, care of our ad business. And what people are
Speaker 5:  really talking about is they don't want it to interrupt their reading experience
Speaker 5:  so much. They don't want some of the like video ads. They don't want the
Speaker 5:  out upgrade chum boxes. We can make that happen, right? So
Speaker 5:  we did a premium ad experience and then benefits of that to the
Speaker 5:  ad side are, you know, those chum boxes and some of
Speaker 5:  those other ad units, those are served by third parties. And so any ad sold
Speaker 5:  there aren't sold directly by Vox Media. So someone else is taking a cut.
Speaker 5:  So when I got rid of those in our subscription, what I can also do is say
Speaker 5:  to our advertisers, If you wanna reach the premium VERGE audience who
Speaker 5:  subscribes and pays for us, the only way to do that is to buy your ads directly
Speaker 5:  from Vox Media. And I love that because then I don't have to give a cut of
Speaker 5:  any revenue to anyone else, right? And that helps me insulate my business.
Speaker 5:  I mentioned earlier Vox Media makes their own ad tech. It's like a weird
Speaker 5:  part of the business, but it's an important thing of like now I can serve
Speaker 5:  my own ads. I don't give anyone else a cut. And so the end
Speaker 5:  result of the premium ad experience on the website is we tend to the ad
Speaker 5:  business, we maybe actually give us a really powerful good tool
Speaker 5:  to do better in the ads business. And we do
Speaker 5:  service for our audience to streamline the page, maybe make more people read,
Speaker 5:  maybe make people have a better experience so they read more pages and that
Speaker 5:  it all kind of works. So that's the website. We did
Speaker 5:  not include podcasts at launch in part because we are just trying to
Speaker 5:  launch the best time to launch a subscription is 10 years ago. So we're just
Speaker 5:  trying to get out the door. Yeah. But there's two barriers that make podcast
Speaker 5:  advertising a little bit harder for us to figure out. One is
Speaker 5:  technical and one is business. So I'll talk about those separately. On the
Speaker 5:  technical front, we don't control any of the platforms where people are listening
Speaker 5:  to podcasts. I doubt many of you VERGE casters are like clicking a megaphone
Speaker 5:  embed on our website. If you are we left, I bet you are listening to the
Speaker 5:  show on YouTube in Apple Podcasts and Spotify
Speaker 5:  in wherever you get your podcasts, right? So we don't control that, which
Speaker 5:  means it's a little hard to have an ad-free
Speaker 5:  podcast feed because we're not in control of a platform. So the way
Speaker 5:  most people do it today is they have their main feed which contains ads
Speaker 5:  and then they create a separate feed that is the ad free
Speaker 5:  feed that they give to subscribers that does take people off
Speaker 5:  the main feed, which reduces their total numbers there.
Speaker 5:  And then if the distribution platform does anything algorithmically in terms
Speaker 5:  of recommendations, you've taken a bunch of audience out of your main
Speaker 5:  feed, but you've also taken like the most engaged audience out of that feed.
Speaker 5:  So that can be a little bit risky, right? Right. You know, apple has now
Speaker 5:  offering Apple podcast subscriptions, but that is in their platform. They
Speaker 5:  own the customer relationships, they own the credit cards. That's not good
Speaker 5:  for our business. And so there's the technical barrier, it
Speaker 5:  can be overcome, but that's just one thing that we're thinking
Speaker 5:  about that is
Speaker 2:  Both like the beautiful and complicated thing about podcasts is that there
Speaker 2:  just is no one who can wrap their arms around the whole
Speaker 5:  Thing. Yeah. So it's, it's kind of a hacky solution. Yeah, yeah. You make
Speaker 5:  a, you make a separate feed and you give it to a bunch of people and if
Speaker 5:  they unsubscribe, I think it's not really easy to cut them off from that
Speaker 5:  feed. But like all of this is like solvable, right? Yeah. It's not ideal
Speaker 5:  but it's solvable. You can come up with solutions. Plenty of people have
Speaker 5:  come up with solutions to do this. I would say the bigger issue for
Speaker 5:  us is the business issue. So when we were launching and we were figuring
Speaker 5:  out what to charge for VERGE subscription, we wanted to keep the price point
Speaker 5:  pretty low so that it was accessible to as many people as possible for
Speaker 5:  the people who make The Verge part of their daily utility. And we did not
Speaker 5:  wanna come in super high on pricing and both alienate our
Speaker 5:  core VERGE people, but also like limit the number of people
Speaker 5:  we could, you know, entice into a subscription. The thing is,
Speaker 5:  podcast ads are currently worth more than website ads. I think for those
Speaker 5:  of you who are listening to this podcast, you have David and Neli in your
Speaker 5:  ears. It is a more engaging ad
Speaker 5:  format than a banner ad. Even the most engaging banner ad I
Speaker 5:  would say, my guess is podcast advertising is by and large
Speaker 5:  outperforming some other forms of advertising, which means it's very
Speaker 5:  expensive and advertisers happen to love The Vergecast. As
Speaker 5:  you have seen, advertisers are even buying the lightning round on The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We will never understand why, but we are grateful that they do it.
Speaker 5:  So for us to take ads out of The Vergecast for again,
Speaker 5:  the most engaged people, that would cost us a lot of money and it would
Speaker 5:  cost us more money than we are charging for a subscription. So then we have
Speaker 5:  kind of two possibilities. One is to say,
Speaker 5:  okay, is there some kind of ad light experience similar to what we're doing
Speaker 5:  on the website? Like what is fewer ads that's few enough that
Speaker 5:  you vergecast people would not be still furiously angry that there are
Speaker 5:  ads. Is it one pre-roll? Like what does that look like?
Speaker 5:  I think that's one avenue to explore. The other is to say,
Speaker 5:  okay, maybe there's a price or a separate tier of VERGE
Speaker 5:  subscription such that we could take all ads outta The Vergecast without
Speaker 5:  killing our business. And I think both of those are things we
Speaker 5:  will be exploring. I know people want it, I would like to be able to give
Speaker 5:  it to people and I think we'll be able to figure it out. But those are just
Speaker 5:  the business realities of podcasting ads and why it's a little
Speaker 5:  harder for us to lose those. Because again, while I would like
Speaker 5:  everyone here to maybe dream that a ton of people are getting
Speaker 5:  wildly rich off digital media, it is just not the case. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so what we are trying to do here is continue to exist,
Speaker 5:  hire a few more journalists.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. The goal is to be able to keep making The Vergecast like that's,
Speaker 2:  that's fundamentally what we're here to do. That's, that's a good
Speaker 2:  answer. And I will say just to everyone who has written in it's, it's this
Speaker 2:  and it's chapters on the podcast and I promise you we hear you
Speaker 2:  and we, we we are, we are thinking about both all the time
Speaker 2:  and, and again, thank you to everybody who writes in and tells us their feelings
Speaker 2:  because you all have a lot of them and I very much enjoy it. All right, two
Speaker 2:  more simpler questions and then I'm gonna let you get outta here. Question
Speaker 2:  number one is we got a bunch of questions about Apple News
Speaker 2:  both in terms of like, should I read the website if I want
Speaker 2:  to support The Verge is should I read and subscribe there or should I
Speaker 2:  read it in Apple News? Plus now that it's an Apple News Plus and
Speaker 2:  just a bunch of people trying to figure out the sort of content mix. We used
Speaker 2:  to have a lot of stuff in Apple News, now we're in Apple News Plus. What,
Speaker 2:  how does that factor into kind of the broader subscription thinking here?
Speaker 5:  I'll say the broader subscription thinking is that now we charge for The
Speaker 5:  Verge, there is a VERGE subscription, which means we are giving less of The
Speaker 5:  Verge away for free. And in particular we are giving less of The Verge
Speaker 5:  away for free on other people's platforms. And so
Speaker 5:  a great way to support The Verge is to Subscribe to The Verge and use our
Speaker 5:  website, put a bookmark on your homepage, read us there.
Speaker 5:  That's terrific. We are also participating in Apple News Plus,
Speaker 5:  so going forward in Apple News, you will need to be an Apple News Plus
Speaker 5:  subscriber in order to read The Verge there. And I know there were some people,
Speaker 5:  it sounds like actually more people than I thought who were loyal VERGE readers
Speaker 5:  who were reading us for free in Apple News were really sad now.
Speaker 2:  Same. I was very surprised by how many people noticed us being gone
Speaker 2:  from Apple News.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I was actually surprised not because
Speaker 5:  there's not a ton of Apple News users who consume their news that way.
Speaker 5:  That's totally a way people consume their news, but more that
Speaker 5:  within Apple News people were like loyally
Speaker 5:  following The Verge specifically. Yeah. Because it is more of an algorithmic
Speaker 5:  news pla or I guess in their case it's more of an editor curated news experience
Speaker 5:  where it's a bunch of different publications. So I think the surprising thing
Speaker 5:  to me there is not
Speaker 5:  was more like they're curating so many publications that there's people who
Speaker 5:  specifically care about The Verge for reading Apple News. But
Speaker 5:  the reality is we are now charging on our website. I would hate to
Speaker 5:  be charging people for something on our website and then giving it away for
Speaker 5:  free somewhere else that would not feel also fair to the people who are paying
Speaker 5:  us on the website. And so for that reason, I would say
Speaker 5:  two important ways you could support The Verge would be subscribing to The
Speaker 5:  Verge or If you are an Apple News Plus subscriber or would like to consume
Speaker 5:  your news that way, subscribe to Apple News Plus and then a Read a Bunch
Speaker 5:  of VERGE content in Apple. And that also supports us and that's fine by me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's a, that's a, the that win-win I think is actually a useful thing because
Speaker 2:  a thing we hear surprisingly frequently is people being like, I want to
Speaker 2:  support The Verge. What is the best way to do that? And the thing I always
Speaker 2:  have told people is come hang out on the website and now I feel like it's
Speaker 2:  come hang out on the website and pay for the website. But also like If you
Speaker 2:  are an Apple News Plus person and wanna stay that way, that's fine. That
Speaker 2:  that works for us too. Yeah, that
Speaker 5:  Supports us too. All right, that's
Speaker 2:  Good. All right, one more, this is a question from Tim
Speaker 2:  that I'm just gonna read verbatim because I thought it was really interesting
Speaker 2:  and I wanna know what you think Tim says. So you've often spoken about how
Speaker 2:  adding a subscription model to something that is otherwise ad supported can
Speaker 2:  change how ads are sold or what the value of them is. It changes the demographics
Speaker 2:  of the free users in a way that reduces the value of the ads. And then
Speaker 2:  basically like what, what do we do with that now that The Verge has made
Speaker 2:  the shift? Was that part of the thinking of making the shift?
Speaker 5:  Well definitely, I mean I think you just heard me explain why we did a premium
Speaker 5:  ad experience instead of ad free and it was for exactly this reason.
Speaker 5:  If we were to take all of our content and make it totally
Speaker 5:  ad free for VERGE subscribers, that weakens your advertising
Speaker 5:  business both in terms of scale, like how much
Speaker 5:  audience is there, how engaged that scale is.
Speaker 5:  And then also I think advertisers perceive
Speaker 5:  that someone who is paying for The Verge is someone
Speaker 5:  who truly loves The Verge, truly cares about The Verge. And if an
Speaker 5:  advertiser wants to work with The Verge, that's exactly the person they wanna
Speaker 5:  most reach are like super fans. And so
Speaker 5:  Tim is dead on that. The reason we did not do Ad Free is
Speaker 5:  because we thought it would be too damaging to our advertising business,
Speaker 5:  which again will pay our bills for the next several years at least, in which
Speaker 5:  I think can happily coexist. And so this is in the world of digital media
Speaker 5:  where again, like success is like journalism continues to happen,
Speaker 5:  but you're seeing the same pressure play out on like
Speaker 5:  platforms like Netflix, right? Netflix was ad free for a long time and
Speaker 5:  has finally had to reckon with the fact that even as a subscription business,
Speaker 5:  they're cheaper subscription tiers. They're not charging
Speaker 5:  enough money to make up for the money they would make just doing ads.
Speaker 5:  And so there is definitely a fine balance If you put too many ads and you
Speaker 5:  alienate people and they don't wanna consume your content, that's a bad
Speaker 5:  experience and it's bad for the advertiser too. So
Speaker 5:  I guess all of which is to say that's exactly why we're doing premium ad
Speaker 5:  experience and non ad free. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. And then how did we land on the price? $7 a month, $50 a year?
Speaker 2:  Where is that? Is that number art? Is it science? Where did that come from?
Speaker 5:  Ooh, that's good. How did we land on price? So we wanted to be
Speaker 5:  affordable enough that we thought a lot of people who Subscribe to The Verge
Speaker 5:  could pay for us. We did a survey last year to ask people like, would
Speaker 5:  we be part of your kind of personal expenses or business expenses?
Speaker 5:  Hmm. And by and large what we heard is we would be part of people's personal
Speaker 5:  expenses. We didn't therefore want to charge hundreds and
Speaker 5:  hundreds of dollars a year that we assumed people would be billing back to
Speaker 5:  our workplace.
Speaker 2:  Right? Which is like the Wall Street Journal money. Like that's a different
Speaker 5:  Kind of expense D or the information or some of those
Speaker 5:  competitors, right? I think I would assume a lot of those
Speaker 5:  subscriptions are being billed back to the workplace. What we heard is people
Speaker 5:  wanna Subscribe to The Verge because they personally love The Verge and it's
Speaker 5:  part of not just their work utility, but it's also something that brings
Speaker 5:  them entertainment and joy. And so those are the people
Speaker 5:  we wanna reach with our subscription people who have a true
Speaker 5:  relationship with The Verge people who make it part of their daily habit.
Speaker 5:  And so we didn't wanna price too high that we would
Speaker 5:  not be able to reach those people. And so we did a bunch of competitive research,
Speaker 5:  we did a bunch of research on what it will cost us to like
Speaker 5:  run this thing. We did a bunch of research on what is turning off all the
Speaker 5:  ads that we turned off cost, right? And what do we need to cover there?
Speaker 5:  And so we kind of put all of that together to arrive at the price.
Speaker 5:  We did decide to charge significantly less if people subscribe annually than
Speaker 5:  monthly. That's because I want a long-term relationship with people.
Speaker 5:  Our annual subscription also right now comes with this incredibly cool
Speaker 5:  magazine content goblins that is deranged and perfect and wonderful. It's
Speaker 2:  Fantastic.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. As a former engagement editor who did marketing and SEO before
Speaker 2:  You were a content goblin.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  We've all done it at one point. It's okay.
Speaker 5:  Well no, we're all still content goblins. That's true, David.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, so we, we had to be expensive enough to cover our costs and make
Speaker 5:  this a good business. But I wanted to be cheap enough and Neli and
Speaker 5:  I think everyone wanted to be cheap enough that we thought people could afford
Speaker 5:  this as part of their daily entertainment, maybe more so
Speaker 5:  than an expensive subscription they bought through work. Fair
Speaker 2:  Enough. I like it.
Speaker 5:  I don't know, it's, there's not actually like that many great places to hang
Speaker 5:  out online anymore. I don't know if like this is part of the
Speaker 5:  canon of AI content that hits the web or how the social platforms are working.
Speaker 5:  Like there just aren't that many fun places on the web anymore. I think The
Speaker 5:  Verge fills that for a lot of people. I want it to fill that for a lot of
Speaker 5:  people. Yeah. And so we wanted to price where it could be
Speaker 5:  part of people's regular budget.
Speaker 2:  And it is very fun to just be increasingly focused on
Speaker 2:  making The Verge dot com a fun place to hang out like that
Speaker 2:  in addition to all of the like high-minded journalistic ideals. Like that's
Speaker 2:  a really fun problem to try and solve is just make it a fun place to be.
Speaker 2:  And that is like, that is a real goal we have. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That was quick posts, right? That's what we wanted to do with the new
Speaker 5:  website was create a homepage. That's so fun. You sit there
Speaker 5:  and you refresh it all day. Right? I mean David, I think you know this, but
Speaker 5:  I joined The Verge because I was a super VERGE fan in my
Speaker 5:  past life when I worked in marketing for
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So there's more business stuff to talk about and I
Speaker 2:  suspect we will talk about some of it. But let's switch gears a bit
Speaker 2:  and talk about how we make the things that we make and
Speaker 2:  how we think about the world that we live in. And who better to do that with
Speaker 2:  than your friend. My co-host, my boss
Speaker 2:  Verges editor in chief Neela Patel. That sounded like a wrestling intro.
Speaker 2:  That was pretty fun. We have a lot of questions for Neli. We're gonna spend
Speaker 2:  a bunch of time talking about all of this stuff. So let's just dive into
Speaker 2:  it. Neli, hello. Hello. I just want you to know that Helen was here
Speaker 2:  before you and she called herself the firewall. She was like, hi, I am
Speaker 2:  Helen. I'm the firewall. And that's awesome. And that is what you have
Speaker 2:  to live up to on this episode. You need a nickname that you give yourself.
Speaker 2:  That is so good that I agree to it.
Speaker 7:  The fire.
Speaker 2:  The fire. There we go. All right. That's pretty good. Okay, so we got, we
Speaker 2:  got a lot of questions around a couple of different themes. So I
Speaker 2:  have tried to sort of break this up thematically, but you're gonna notice
Speaker 2:  it just gets more random as it goes because we've just got a lot of questions.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna answer as many of 'em as we can. By the way,
Speaker 7:  Can I just agree with you that Helen is an incredibly hard act to follow?
Speaker 2:  Oh God, yeah. So
Speaker 7:  There's a reason we made her, our boss. We're like, you should be in charge.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's, it's very real. Okay. We have what
Speaker 2:  I would call like a, like a gentle controversy to start with, which I'm very
Speaker 2:  excited about. So let me, let me, I'm gonna play you a question and then
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna read you an email and I think they're, they're together. So we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about them
Speaker 7:  Together. If this isn't about whether or not theater at large of The Verge
Speaker 7:  should have a shitty TV in good taste, I'm gonna be very disappointed.
Speaker 2:  No, I think everyone's actually pretty kind on that one.
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm the outlier on that one, but, but that's okay. I'm good with it.
Speaker 2:  All right. Lemme just play this question for you.
Speaker 8:  Hi, this is Jessica from Massachusetts. One of the things that I've always
Speaker 8:  appreciated about The Verge was the wall that you put between the
Speaker 8:  sales department and the newsroom. Now that you have
Speaker 8:  lightning round sponsorship and now that the team is
Speaker 8:  aware of who the sponsors are, how are you going to maintain
Speaker 8:  that journalistic integrity? Thanks so much. Love you guys, but
Speaker 8:  listening for you.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so we have that. And I'd also like to read you an email we got from
Speaker 2:  Max,
Speaker 7:  My daughter,
Speaker 2:  Not your daughter. Okay. But you never know Max, max does have thought the,
Speaker 7:  The email is, why do I have to be quiet?
Speaker 2:  Max writes, NELI has said multiple times that he keeps a firewall between
Speaker 2:  the newsroom and the ad team. And it's been said that they would make money
Speaker 2:  if the news people read the ads versus ad people. Neli goes as far as to
Speaker 2:  not directly say the companies that are sponsoring the lightning round, but
Speaker 2:  David does ad reads for The Vergecast. Liam, I know he's the producer, but
Speaker 2:  he does appear as a voice from time to time. Also does them, what makes those
Speaker 2:  reads different or acceptable? Why can David do ad reads but Neli can't.
Speaker 2:  Different questions, same thing,
Speaker 7:  Respond. Wait, no, I think they're different things. Are they?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Why do you think they're okay? Well then let's, let's pull them apart.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think they're different things?
Speaker 7:  So we can look at our own website and see who our advertisers are all the
Speaker 7:  time. That's a very normal thing. So knowing who the Lightning ad
Speaker 7:  sponsors are to me is not any different than
Speaker 7:  knowing whatever that, you know, whatever wireless carrier
Speaker 7:  is buying ads on our site around iPhone time.
Speaker 7:  It's been 13 years. I know the wireless carriers buy ads on our site around
Speaker 7:  iPhone time. I think you can see that that doesn't really affect
Speaker 7:  how we cover the wireless carriers, right? So knowing who the Lightning ad
Speaker 7:  sponsor is to me, is it, that's just all of a piece, right? It's,
Speaker 7:  we can, we can see the product that we deliver to the audience
Speaker 7:  and we just don't let that affect us. Like where they come, they go, the
Speaker 7:  rule is the advertising team doesn't get to tell us what to
Speaker 7:  do and we don't get to tell them what to do. Right. And
Speaker 7:  that is very difficult. Like I, there are, there are ads
Speaker 7:  on this show that I know people would prefer we didn't have.
Speaker 7:  But because the advertising team doesn't get to get to tell us what to do,
Speaker 7:  our ability to, to open the door and start telling them what to do is
Speaker 7:  challenging. 'cause then the door's open. Right now we're
Speaker 7:  negotiating and I don't wanna have that negotiation. So that's just different
Speaker 7:  to me. Right. It's, we're aware of what they're doing. 'cause we, at the
Speaker 7:  end that we, we assemble the whole product and we put it out in the world
Speaker 7:  and the lightning round is new. And it's funny and it's funny that the first
Speaker 7:  sponsor was a big company, but we have ideas for that too. So I
Speaker 7:  we're just gonna work that out. It's, it's new, but I think
Speaker 7:  that is a familiar expression of the firewall. And the reason I was
Speaker 7:  joking that I'm the fire is because the, the people that yell the most, the
Speaker 7:  yelling usually goes in one direction. It's me that way.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say, I think you spend a lot of time telling sales what to do.
Speaker 2:  They're just not obligated to listen to you, I think is the
Speaker 2:  key difference,
Speaker 7:  Right? My job is to protect the user experience of the website, right? Right.
Speaker 7:  And so like, you can just look around at advertising supported websites and
Speaker 7:  you can see the things that we have not done. And that is a lot of me and
Speaker 7:  Helen agreeing that we are not gonna do those things. And then I'm just the
Speaker 7:  heavy, like I, I get to yell, right? She has to go run our business.
Speaker 7:  So that's that the, so does that have I adequately
Speaker 7:  separated these two things? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, I think that's fair. And I think the, the, the point that I was gonna
Speaker 2:  make about the the firewalls is what you said. That it actually, it exists
Speaker 2:  in both directions, which is that like they see the stuff that we make and
Speaker 2:  we see the stuff that they sell, but neither side has any
Speaker 2:  idea of what's going on. And like, we didn't know, I didn't know when I made
Speaker 2:  the rundown for the show who was advertising in that show. So Right. It's
Speaker 2:  like knowing who they are is I think less
Speaker 2:  compromising than if we understood more of the process and how much money
Speaker 2:  was involved and what was sold for when and to whom. Like that
Speaker 2:  we stay away from very much on purpose. But like you're right, I can, I can
Speaker 2:  look at our webpage and tell you who's advertising on it and I think by and
Speaker 2:  large that's mostly fine. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I can pull that even farther back. We trade on a lot of old school
Speaker 7:  journalism, right? We're built on a foundation that has been around for a
Speaker 7:  long time. So when you were printing magazines,
Speaker 7:  the advertising was printed in the magazine. Right? And
Speaker 7:  you had to physically assemble that product and decide where the
Speaker 7:  ads would go If, you know, I was a car and driver reader in the nineties
Speaker 7:  in Wisconsin when I was a kid. And half of the letters the editor were like,
Speaker 7:  why are there BMW ads are on the BM BMW review? You're biased. And like they
Speaker 7:  would print the letters just so they could say, look, no, we're not. Whether
Speaker 7:  or not you believe them in the nineties and Car and Driver, they did give
Speaker 7:  a lot of good reviews to, to BMWs back then. But this is just like an
Speaker 7:  old muscle, right? You have an editor in chief and you have a publisher and
Speaker 7:  we, Helen and I have a great relationship, but she's the business and I'm
Speaker 7:  the newsroom and we're supposed to have a little bit of tension. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And that's good. Like that's, that's what we mean by the firewall is she
Speaker 7:  has to go be, make us money. And I have to just spend the money. Great.
Speaker 7:  I didn't know you were reading the ads and I'm just gonna tell you that you
Speaker 7:  have to stop.
Speaker 2:  I think I've read one ad this year. Okay. For whatever it's worth.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. So we should talk about this in two ways. One is just
Speaker 2:  realistically, you are my boss and you get to tell me what to do. So like,
Speaker 2:  you, you win this fight. But
Speaker 2:  I think as, as a, as a co-host of The Vergecast, I, I do wanna press
Speaker 2:  on this slightly 'cause I think this is something I just have less religion
Speaker 2:  about than you do on podcast ads in particular. Yes.
Speaker 2:  And I just wanna poke at it, right? Like the, the line for me of
Speaker 2:  like, we don't make branded content, right, is like so, so,
Speaker 2:  so clear and so clean and so important to everything that we do, right?
Speaker 2:  So like when, when years ago, like branded
Speaker 2:  blog posts were like a huge business for Buzzfeed and it was a thing everybody
Speaker 2:  was talking about. Like the the divide between those two things was always
Speaker 2:  very clear to me. It's, that's
Speaker 2:  less problematic for me in podcasts then. Like it's,
Speaker 2:  it's not quite as stark for me there. Like you see a lot of podcast ads where
Speaker 2:  one thing they really want is like personal experience, right? So you hear
Speaker 2:  your podcast host talk about the product they got and why they like it. That's
Speaker 2:  part of the ad. The advertiser pays more money for that and we just, resolutely
Speaker 2:  won't do that. We just don't do it. And
Speaker 2:  the middle ground there where it's like the
Speaker 2:  host who is obviously reading an ad reads an ad
Speaker 2:  is just like a common part of the form of
Speaker 2:  podcasts and frankly just makes me feel less
Speaker 2:  gross than it would in some other forms. And I can't
Speaker 2:  totally describe why, but that's where I'm at. Like, I
Speaker 2:  think the, the advertiser I read an ad for is like, not somebody we
Speaker 2:  would ever cover. I would never do it for somebody we would ever cover.
Speaker 2:  And yeah, I don't know. It felt okay and it always comes to me as like, here's
Speaker 2:  a thing to do. I'm like, sure. And I just read it and it's over.
Speaker 7:  I would say one of the major challenges of having David work at your organization
Speaker 7:  is David's like, yeah, I will do everything. And then you're like, wait,
Speaker 7:  that rocket ship is gone. I have tore that and that's
Speaker 7:  very much the David Pierce experience and I love it. I have no complaints
Speaker 7:  about that. But the, I think the,
Speaker 7:  I think I've just been radicalized over the past five to 10 to 13 years
Speaker 7:  of running this place. Okay. I think that nuance is gone. I
Speaker 7:  think it is dead. And I particularly think that
Speaker 7:  the new audience, the younger audience that came up in influencer world
Speaker 7:  does not even know that there should be a firewall. Does not even know that
Speaker 7:  we're trading on hundreds of years of traditional
Speaker 7:  journalism editor, publisher dynamics. We're gonna print a
Speaker 7:  magazine and the, the ads are gonna sit next to the reviews and there's a
Speaker 7:  whole ecosystem and there's lots of crotchety old journalists who talk about
Speaker 7:  the fights. Like they don't even know that existed. 'cause it's gone. Right?
Speaker 7:  We're we're, we we're just rebuilding the ecosystem from scratch for better
Speaker 7:  or worse. And most of the creators we compete with
Speaker 7:  have decided that the, they, there's not a wall. The wall
Speaker 7:  exists within themselves. Right. And they have to, and I think a lot of them
Speaker 7:  do a good job of explaining where their lines are gonna be fine.
Speaker 7:  Our line is just very different. And I think the second we make it more complicated
Speaker 7:  where we lose, right? And so like we, us
Speaker 7:  saying, well, you know, we have a list of approved advertisers that we'll
Speaker 7:  do host reads for, but we won't do personal, like in
Speaker 7:  the broad ecosystem of stuff. Like I think that message
Speaker 7:  just gets lost, right? And the idea that you can pay us to say
Speaker 7:  stuff is the only message it comes through. So that's why I've been like
Speaker 7:  very over the years, like I used to read some of the ads and I thought it
Speaker 7:  was funny when we restarted the End Gadget podcast, we had no ads. 'cause
Speaker 7:  who was gonna buy our show with me and Josh and Paul just like
Speaker 7:  start like restarting this old podcast. It was sitting around and when we
Speaker 7:  got our first ads, we were like thrilled, right? Because it was like validating.
Speaker 7:  And I can see a bunch of creators feel the
Speaker 7:  validation of, oh, an
Speaker 2:  Advertiser. Oh yeah. The first Brandand deal is a moment as a creator.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Right? And I, I'm totally sympathetic to that. So like,
Speaker 7:  I've had all the experiences. I just think now at this point when
Speaker 7:  we are rebuilding this ecosystem from scratch for an audience that has no
Speaker 7:  familiarity with it, where the, the instinct and the expectation
Speaker 7:  is you can pay people to say things on social platforms.
Speaker 7:  I think we just have to be harsher about it. And fundamentally what what
Speaker 7:  we're selling with our subscription is like, this is, this is the thing that
Speaker 7:  keeps us from having to do that to keep the lights on. And maybe that's too
Speaker 7:  harsh. I, I think, I think at the end of the day, like the
Speaker 7:  internet destroys nuance and I'm, I'm just, I'm willing to be a little
Speaker 7:  harsher to preserve the clarity of our message around how the
Speaker 7:  journalism is made than maybe I was a few years ago. Right? Like,
Speaker 7:  that's fine. Like Josh once gave away a car out on The Verge and like, and
Speaker 7:  he was like in the back of a Ford, like giving away a car. Like we've, we've
Speaker 7:  done all the things and we've had all the experiences and I, I think what
Speaker 7:  the thing that I'm just really settled on
Speaker 7:  is it's too hard to convey the nuance. We just end up
Speaker 7:  over-communicating what the advertising and why the advertising didn't affect
Speaker 7:  us than about the journalism. And I would rather just spend our time
Speaker 7:  focused on the journalism.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. I mean, I feel like that argument is the same one for
Speaker 2:  why you won't shut up about this on our site and on the podcast
Speaker 2:  and wherever and why we're doing this episode. Right? Like I think a a thing
Speaker 2:  I have realized over time is that like you're,
Speaker 2:  you, you, we are doing this as a publication sort of performatively and
Speaker 2:  it's on purpose, right? Like it is, we, we are making more out of this than
Speaker 2:  we need to because that is the, the tide is pulling the
Speaker 2:  other way.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And look, these are very traditional standards we were talking about,
Speaker 7:  right? We have peers and friends at traditional
Speaker 7:  newsrooms who are like, why do you guys talk about this so much? This is
Speaker 7:  just how it works. This
Speaker 2:  Is what I mean. Like, we came up with an ethics policy and you were like,
Speaker 2:  I have done ethics. And I was like, no, other people have had ethics
Speaker 7:  Policy. Yeah. And our ethics policy, to be a hundred percent honest, was
Speaker 7:  totally stolen from Walt Mossberg at the Wall Street Journal, right? Like
Speaker 7:  we just boosted theirs and that we've, you know, slowly iterated on it over
Speaker 7:  the years. This is old stuff, but I think the failure of
Speaker 7:  the journalism industry, not the media industry, the journalism
Speaker 7:  industry is not communicating how the information is made.
Speaker 7:  Every other industry is like, look at how cool it is that we made this thing.
Speaker 7:  You wanna watch a Dorito get made, there's infinity content that's like,
Speaker 7:  watch this corn turn into a Dorito. And you're like, wow,
Speaker 7:  that's really cool. You wanna watch how journalism gets made? No one ever
Speaker 7:  talks about it. They're just like, here's the story where the New York Times
Speaker 7:  don't question us. And I, I think in this ecosystem,
Speaker 7:  when so many creators on social platforms are so powerful and so influential,
Speaker 7:  and they talk about how they make this stuff all the time, we can play a
Speaker 7:  little bit of that game. And all we're really saying is we're doing this
Speaker 7:  the old fashioned way, right? Like, we are just gonna remain
Speaker 7:  independent. We have new competitors who have substantially the same
Speaker 7:  policy as us, four or four media substantially the same policies as us, right?
Speaker 7:  I'm not saying this is totally unexpected. I, I think the
Speaker 7:  piece of it that's new is we have to communicate about it very loudly.
Speaker 7:  And I think this is the part we can argue about. We have to draw much harsher
Speaker 7:  lines to make the message simple enough for the modern internet.
Speaker 2:  And that's just that. Yeah, I think that's fair. I mean, and I think, I think
Speaker 2:  we, we ultimately land in not that different places, right? Which is that
Speaker 2:  like, in a vacuum,
Speaker 2:  this is a sliding scale, but we're just, we and you in particular are just
Speaker 2:  choosing not to treat this as a sliding scale because like, I'm just going
Speaker 2:  to live all the way at the top because it, it is a slippery and hard to explain
Speaker 2:  slope as soon as you start going down it. And that's fine. I buy that
Speaker 2:  logic. It is, I I would say there are probably people who work at
Speaker 2:  Vox Media who wish you would be a little less,
Speaker 7:  We would militant so much money if I read the ads, I just wanna be
Speaker 2:  There. It's like that.
Speaker 7:  I don't wanna, I don't, that's my point. I'm not gonna shade this. We would
Speaker 7:  make a ton of money if we read the ads. And actually another weird piece
Speaker 7:  of our structure and being a media company and making
Speaker 7:  traditional journalism is that if David and I were just creators,
Speaker 7:  literally we would make the money if we read the ads, yes.
Speaker 7:  Like individually, we would just cash the checks and then, you know,
Speaker 7:  buy, buy cars. Like that's what I would do. I dunno, David too,
Speaker 7:  I'd make David buy an ed team.
Speaker 7:  We don't do that. We, when a company cashes the checks and then we use it
Speaker 7:  to pay for our newsroom, right? And we've got this huge newsroom
Speaker 7:  behind us that does most of the work that we just talk about in the show.
Speaker 7:  And I like that. I want to keep making journalism jobs. I,
Speaker 7:  I want to keep hiring 22 year olds who have no idea what they're doing and
Speaker 7:  watch them graduate and go to senior positions and start their own things
Speaker 7:  in the future. We've done a lot of that over 13 years, and that's just because
Speaker 7:  of the revenue. So yeah, we could make a lot more money.
Speaker 7:  We wouldn't make it as individuals. Maybe we could fund our newsroom, but
Speaker 7:  I think we would, we would end up destroying the core value of the newsroom.
Speaker 7:  And you can see many of our competitors that have made those kinds of deals
Speaker 7:  or made those kinds of trade offs do not exist anymore. Right. Because
Speaker 7:  ultimately the only thing you're really selling is your credibility. And
Speaker 7:  once you let that go, it's gone.
Speaker 2:  Right? And there's a, I mean, like, you, you can draw a a straight line
Speaker 2:  from the end of that sentence too, and this is why we did this subscription,
Speaker 2:  right? Like, it is, it just, it it aligns all of that stuff
Speaker 2:  much more cleanly when the people who consume our
Speaker 2:  stuff are the ones who pay for that stuff. There's just no
Speaker 2:  weirdness in that circle in a way that is really, really clarifying and
Speaker 2:  helpful.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think, I think it's challenging and like I said, we would
Speaker 7:  make a lot more money if I read the ads. Like it's not lost on me. And
Speaker 7:  it is, Helen is one side of the firewall and I'm the other, and I'm the one
Speaker 7:  who says, we're not gonna make that money. That it, that money is, that money
Speaker 7:  is too expensive. Yeah. Right. Is like a, a way that I think about it. It's,
Speaker 7:  it costs too much to make this money. We will not make more money in the
Speaker 7:  future. We'll just make it in the beginning and then we'll be, now we'll
Speaker 7:  be competing against people who will do even worse things that we will not
Speaker 7:  do, and I don't wanna compete with them. And the good news w
Speaker 7:  weirdly, is that the more we stay harsh, the more
Speaker 7:  we are differentiated, the more stable the demand remains. Right? People
Speaker 7:  want to buy advertising on our site because big brands
Speaker 7:  want to buy advertising on our site because they know they can't buy us,
Speaker 7:  which is weird. That's just a weird outcome in the right, in the media
Speaker 7:  ecosystem. Lots of CEOs wanna come on decoder all the time
Speaker 7:  because they, they know they can't tell me to do. And like,
Speaker 7:  I think a lot of them want to prove to their teams that they can take the
Speaker 7:  heat. Weird. That's just a weird, it's counterintuitive notion
Speaker 7:  in a world where a bunch of, you know, like Casey
Speaker 7:  Newton is always joking with me that the podcast ecosystem is like, you can
Speaker 7:  pick two names out of a hat and they've interviewed each other on a podcast
Speaker 7:  And there's like rules and like a lot of them are programmed and like whatever,
Speaker 7:  right? A lot of it is branded content is bought and paid for and we're not.
Speaker 7:  And because we're so loud about it, we have a long list of incoming,
Speaker 7:  we're we're not lacking for people who wanna show up and, and, and talk on
Speaker 7:  our show. So I, there's greater value there over the long term. And
Speaker 7:  being focused on that long term is really hard. And I mean, it's ecosystem
Speaker 7:  that quite frankly is like dying by the day. Yeah. So that's where
Speaker 7:  part of subscriptions come in is like, how do we make something healthy and
Speaker 7:  resilient? How do we diversify revenue? And then how do we make sure that
Speaker 7:  we're still selling the thing that we're selling, which is independence.
Speaker 2:  All right. That's good.
Speaker 7:  All right. Wait, can I, we we have to address why Liam gets to read the ads?
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, sure. Okay. Well here, let me, let me play the next question. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which I think is a, is a good way to get into this.
Speaker 9:  Hi, Jolene Joseph here calling from my closet. So I just wanna do a David
Speaker 9:  intro there. Yeah. I'm just curious actually about how
Speaker 9:  you decide to do ads on the show in particular.
Speaker 9:  Y'all talked about this a little bit, but I'm really curious on how you make
Speaker 9:  the decision on who reads those ads. I remember at some point
Speaker 9:  Neli was reading some HubSpot ads.
Speaker 9:  This was at least, I wanna say a few years ago. I don't forget
Speaker 9:  because I used to work at Salesforce. But yeah, I'm just curious
Speaker 9:  how you make that decision on who is gonna read the ads, whether or not
Speaker 9:  somebody who is actually a host of the show versus
Speaker 9:  producer versus somebody else. It seems like there was a change at some point
Speaker 9:  made perhaps to give a little bit more distance. I noticed other
Speaker 9:  shows do this differently. I've been thinking about a bit as I start to do
Speaker 9:  some consulting myself and thinking about paid partnerships and
Speaker 9:  what that actually looks like. And yeah, I just love to get a little bit
Speaker 9:  more insight on how you make those decisions.
Speaker 2:  So there you go. You knew the frame of the question. I just wanna get more
Speaker 2:  people's voices onto the show. I
Speaker 7:  Do like the fake David intro.
Speaker 2:  You'd be alarmed at how often I'm in my closet recording
Speaker 7:  Face. Yeah, you'd be alarmed at how often David is faking the intro. He is
Speaker 7:  like, I'm riding a horse. He is like doing the coconuts in the closet. How
Speaker 2:  Dare you. How dare you.
Speaker 7:  This is the inside baseball man. That's something people want. David has
Speaker 7:  so many coconuts in his closet,
Speaker 2:  So yeah. Why, why Liam?
Speaker 7:  So the, the, the reality of we would make a lot more money if we read the
Speaker 7:  ads is real, right? And that is just demand in the market that what they
Speaker 7:  want is social reads. What they want is what David is talking about, what
Speaker 7:  personal experience they're trying to trade on. The trust you have with the
Speaker 7:  voices you're hearing that's advertising that
Speaker 7:  is just fundamentally how advertising works. They're like, you trust this
Speaker 7:  person now they will sell you a cell phone in that If you
Speaker 7:  watch television advertising, you're like a random SNL celebrity selling
Speaker 7:  you Verizon. That's just a thing that is happening left and right. So that's
Speaker 7:  like the foundation of advertising. And I honestly, I have no
Speaker 7:  like, moral complaints about that. That's how that industry works. And it's
Speaker 7:  worked for a long time and I think people understand it. Where I think it
Speaker 7:  gets dicey is we as journalists should not be endorsing things, especially
Speaker 7:  as product reviewers. And there's other categories where it maybe it makes,
Speaker 7:  makes sense, but we do so much product reviewing and we should not be anywhere
Speaker 7:  near products at the same time, we know the demand in the market is there.
Speaker 7:  So our solution here is that Liam is a character on our show. He is a
Speaker 7:  familiar voice, but he is just the producer of the show. He's not
Speaker 7:  writing product reviews for the site. He doesn't have editorial control over
Speaker 7:  his show, which I have a lot of sympathy for Liam being the producer of the
Speaker 7:  show that the editor in chief hosts real pain in the ass. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Huge, huge pain in the ass. So
Speaker 7:  just insulated enough. And then the rule is Liam doesn't get to do anything
Speaker 7:  except read the copy that is delivered to him. So there's not
Speaker 7:  even that back and forth weirdness. We think that's a
Speaker 7:  good solution, right? We think it matches with the experience
Speaker 7:  everybody else has on other podcast, which is like, here's a familiar voice
Speaker 7:  reading this thing. It's not our voices.
Speaker 7:  Right? So we, we solved that problem and, and maybe we've gotten it wrong.
Speaker 7:  You you should tell us, but it it, it creates enough of
Speaker 7:  the same product where our sales team can go into the market and compete
Speaker 7:  without causing all of the downstream problems because it's not us.
Speaker 7:  And like, in a very real way, it's not us. I'm open to the
Speaker 7:  feedback, but I, I think there's enough division there where I'm not, the
Speaker 7:  nuance isn't being crushed or I'm not relying on the nuance. Like it's a
Speaker 7:  different person. I would say my dream for the longest time
Speaker 7:  has been to bring back the hype desk and have an on staff influencer who
Speaker 7:  just lives on the hype desk. Yep. This is the loneliest job in America.
Speaker 7:  You get to be part of The Verge, but not in the newsroom. And your job
Speaker 7:  is to just do branded content and never talk to anyone in the newsroom.
Speaker 7:  'cause you have to maintain the wall. You can see why no one has signed up
Speaker 7:  for this. It's coolest this job.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like be alone, be the thing you can buy in The Verge that it's totally isolated
Speaker 7:  from everyone else. Does not seem like a great job, but it's one
Speaker 7:  of the other ways we've, we've thought about the solution here. I don't know
Speaker 7:  if that's ever gonna happen, but it's, I'm, I'm, we're trying to find ways
Speaker 7:  to be competitive in the market and still preserve
Speaker 7:  the, the credibility that is the fundamentally the thing we're selling. But
Speaker 7:  Liam's here, Liam, do you have anything to add to this? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I would just say I get ad requests on a regular basis. It's not something
Speaker 3:  I communicate to Neli or David at all. They have no idea
Speaker 3:  what ads I've read that week and what get included in the show. So that's
Speaker 3:  one of the ways we create that boundary.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I do enjoy the emails I get every week from people complaining about one
Speaker 2:  ad or another. And that's how I find out who advertises on our show most
Speaker 2:  of the time is from people who are mad
Speaker 7:  About it. So those emails are really interesting. I I think they're, they're
Speaker 7:  proof that people can't tell the difference,
Speaker 7:  right? That, that it's all one experience. And mostly our
Speaker 7:  competitors take responsibility for the whole experience. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair.
Speaker 7:  And we, we just don't, and like that's, I think that's weird. I think it's
Speaker 7:  dissonant for a lot of people, but I fundamentally, I I
Speaker 7:  don't know If you can keep them
Speaker 7:  separate while you're taking the junkets and while you're accepting the brand
Speaker 7:  deals and negotiating their rates. I maybe some creators can, again,
Speaker 7:  there's lots of them who have really laid out exactly what they will and
Speaker 7:  want to. Michael Fisher, Mr. Mobile has been very complimentary of our ethics
Speaker 7:  policy over the years. He has done an excellent job of laying out what he
Speaker 7:  will and won't do and how it will work for him, but he still takes the money.
Speaker 7:  Right. And like, you've gotta trust him. I think a lot of people do. I think
Speaker 7:  they, I I I think that's a reasonable position to take. Like he's laid it
Speaker 7:  out. He's been explicit, he's very clear. That's not every creator. And I
Speaker 7:  think that's too hard for us at scale. I can't run a whole
Speaker 7:  newsroom being like, I've made up some rules. Like it has to be simple and
Speaker 7:  it has to be simple for the audience.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. We have a few more quicker ones that are less about
Speaker 2:  Eli's feelings about ads. Let's just plow through these before we get to
Speaker 2:  take a break. Let me, let me play you a couple. This I think might have been
Speaker 2:  my favorite question we got this entire time.
Speaker 10:  Hey, this casters, I've been listening to your podcast for forever, and
Speaker 10:  I've always wondered what exactly happens during ad breaks. Do you like
Speaker 10:  chat for five minutes and then return, or do you resume recording
Speaker 10:  immediately? Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Do people wanna know Neli?
Speaker 7:  I'm so sad about this. This is a real,
Speaker 7:  we're gonna destroy your suspension of disbelief. I'm really sorry
Speaker 7:  about this. Like, I, I don't wanna tell you,
Speaker 7:  we don't know. We just say, okay, we gotta stop and then we hit a
Speaker 7:  button to pause the recording and then another button to start again. And
Speaker 7:  we just keep going.
Speaker 2:  Sometimes we get seltzers. I would say that's like the main ad break activity
Speaker 2:  is, is a beverage. Yeah. But
Speaker 7:  The, the show is not recorded in real time.
Speaker 2:  There are people out there who want us to do The Vergecast live
Speaker 2:  more. I would say that's a thing we will probably do occasionally. But there
Speaker 2:  are people who are like, I want the unedited live version of The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  And I'm like, it would blow your mind.
Speaker 2:  No, you don't.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We just are like, we we should take a break. All right. We're back
Speaker 7:  like literally in the same breath. I say those words sometimes. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. That's a good one. All right. Let's see.
Speaker 7:  This is like finding out that they do jeopardy all in one day and they just
Speaker 7:  change our clothes. Like I was heartbroken.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I had a friend very recently who won several episodes of Jeopardy
Speaker 2:  in a row, and I've only gotten like bits and pieces of the process of how
Speaker 2:  they do it. And it is, it was like a hundred years ago, he
Speaker 2:  filmed like a week's worth of stuff in an afternoon. Like just insane. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it has ruined jeopardy for me forever. I don't even, it, it's fine, but
Speaker 2:  I hate it. I can't watch it anymore.
Speaker 7:  The only thing, the only thing I'll say about Jeopardy, one more thing about
Speaker 7:  Jeopardy. I'm not prone to believe conspiracies exist because often too
Speaker 7:  many people have to keep a secret, right? Like, we landed on the moon and
Speaker 7:  I know we land a moon because not enough people could keep the secret and
Speaker 7:  we faked the moon landing for this long. Agreed. And then you're like, they
Speaker 7:  keep Jeopardy a secret for a long time and you're like, Hmm, what are the
Speaker 7:  drones doing over New Jersey? Like, that's fully where my head goes every
Speaker 7:  time. I don't know,
Speaker 2:  I'm, I picture Jeopardy is like a fully autonomous show. There's like, the
Speaker 2:  room is always there recording and people just come in and make a show
Speaker 2:  sometimes.
Speaker 7:  And the people who know like never leave the room.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Yeah. They live there. It's fine. To
Speaker 3:  Any of our listeners who enjoy the Great British Bake Off, do not look up
Speaker 3:  how they make that show. It will ruin it for you.
Speaker 2:  See. Yeah, that's
Speaker 7:  Good. You asked us what we do during ad breaks and now we've ruined a baking
Speaker 7:  show. Yeah, we're doing great.
Speaker 2:  We're so sorry. All right, next up.
Speaker 11:  Hi Vergecast. John Roco here. Two things for you. First, ever since you
Speaker 11:  started doing all these additional podcasts, it's like, it's like so many
Speaker 11:  podcasts. I loved it so much better when it was concise and it was just,
Speaker 11:  just the Friday episode. 'cause now it's super hard for me to keep up with
Speaker 11:  my other podcasts because all these podcasts are so
Speaker 11:  good. I just subscribed. I love you guys. Keep up the great work. Thank
Speaker 11:  you.
Speaker 2:  So I wanted to pick this one because this is a question we've gotten a bunch,
Speaker 2:  which is basically like, we do a lot more vergecast than we used to.
Speaker 2:  And that is part of what you brought me here to do a couple of years ago.
Speaker 2:  Do you want to, do you want to explain how we think about The Vergecast now?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, you know, part of the answer is it's your job to figure it
Speaker 7:  out, but the thing that I'm reacting to most is the idea that we used to
Speaker 7:  be concise.
Speaker 7:  I don't, yeah, I don't know If you listened to our first album that was like
Speaker 7:  a, you know, a quadruple sided pr prog
Speaker 7:  rock exploration. It was, it was not Concise Sand
Speaker 7:  Anisa is what we made. I
Speaker 2:  Remember the early days of The Verge, we would record in the studio, in our
Speaker 2:  office at four o'clock and we would leave at like six 30, like
Speaker 2:  physically exhausted at the end of some episode. So it's like, I can't talk
Speaker 2:  anymore after this episode.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So I appreciate that in the, in the over the
Speaker 7:  haze of time We concision has been added to our list of qualities.
Speaker 7:  I actually think having more episodes lets us be more focused because
Speaker 7:  we're not trying to cram every idea into one thing. And really
Speaker 7:  as you run a media company of whatever size, you start to
Speaker 7:  realize you have to make more focused products. They have things have to
Speaker 7:  go find their audiences. Our TikTok channel isn't really look at anything
Speaker 7:  like our homepage. And our homepage isn't really looking at anything like
Speaker 7:  our YouTube channel. And that's just how it goes, you know? And for
Speaker 7:  the podcast in particular, I think we know that
Speaker 7:  the Friday show has a big audience that does not want us
Speaker 7:  to mess with it too much. And there's just too much to fit into this show.
Speaker 7:  And the Tuesday show is, is allowed to tell more narrative kinds of stories
Speaker 7:  and build its own audience and wants a different kind of thing. So my
Speaker 7:  recommendation to anyone who thinks you're doing too much podcast
Speaker 7:  is figure out what you want from us and that we have probably provided
Speaker 7:  to you. And that's a way for us to grow the audience
Speaker 7:  as opposed to just extracting more from the audience we have. And that's
Speaker 7:  really what we're after, is we want to grow our audience, particularly like
Speaker 7:  new audience. People have not encountered us before. We wanna go find them
Speaker 7:  with stories that are interesting and bring them into the fold. And you do
Speaker 7:  that with focus. Yep.
Speaker 2:  That's a good answer. I have no notes.
Speaker 7:  David's like, I'm doing three more episodes a week.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Listen, eight days a week, Vergecast. Here we go. All right, one more
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna take a break.
Speaker 10:  Hey, this is Leo calling from beautiful Holland, Michigan. Hey, I got a
Speaker 10:  question about The Vergecast meta episode and maybe a little bit of an axe
Speaker 10:  to grind. Hey, I'm wondering, you guys a couple years ago went through all
Speaker 10:  the work to make this beautiful redesign and rebrand of the theme song and
Speaker 10:  all that. I'm an audio podcast listener, so maybe this isn't true on the
Speaker 10:  YouTube version, but you guys have this great theme song and then a year
Speaker 10:  or two later you chopped it down. So we just had bu bu bubu,
Speaker 10:  bu bu, which is a little bit of a bummer. And now for the last month or
Speaker 10:  two, it's just been bump bump, bump bump. Welcome To The Vergecast. And
Speaker 10:  what, what's the deal do you think? We don't have the attention span for
Speaker 10:  it. Is this the TikTok ification of the show? Love to hear your thoughts
Speaker 10:  about why the theme song's been trimmed. Thanks guys of the show.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Liam, why has the theme song been trimmed?
Speaker 3:  Good question. He was close with the TikTok ification. It's not quite
Speaker 3:  TikTok though, it's YouTube. We want the YouTube to
Speaker 3:  match the audio feed. And on YouTube, starting out with a big long theme
Speaker 3:  song is just kind of, you know, not something people will
Speaker 3:  sit through. So we made a compromise and shortened it down. But I think this
Speaker 3:  person's right. I don't really like it either. So Eric, our,
Speaker 3:  our audio engineer and I, we're gonna go back to the drawing board and see,
Speaker 3:  see what we can do with our theme song to refresh it and not be
Speaker 3:  so jarring, for lack
Speaker 7:  Of a better word. That's the third episode. Every week is just the full theme
Speaker 7:  song we should just publish it with. There
Speaker 3:  You go. I love that. Yeah. Can we sell ads against that?
Speaker 7:  We had a lot of fun. Breakmaster Cylinder who also did the decoder theme
Speaker 7:  song. Did the revamped Vergecast theme. I
Speaker 7:  don't, this is just some lore. Josh Polsky wrote The Vergecast
Speaker 7:  theme and really we were listening to that MGMT song that everyone liked.
Speaker 7:  You can see there's a direct line Oh yeah. Of inspiration there. So then
Speaker 7:  we had that one. It was great. And then we don't, we didn't have the stems
Speaker 7:  like Josh, he just like made it on his computer and like, here's the thing,
Speaker 7:  like we made it all lost the midst of time. So we had to
Speaker 7:  like redo it so we could do all the stuff David's doing on the Tuesday episodes
Speaker 7:  with music beds and stuff. Like, we just needed more stuff.
Speaker 7:  So this was a good time to like make more stuff. And it was really fun to
Speaker 7:  work with Breakmaster Cylinder. And there, I've always been worried that
Speaker 7:  we made it too aggressive. Like it's a cool thing to listen to,
Speaker 7:  but like there's like a saxophone break in it. Yeah. Which you,
Speaker 7:  if
Speaker 2:  Memory serves specifically requested in the theme
Speaker 7:  Song I did. It was my idea. Abstraction. Breaking it. So I think it's good.
Speaker 7:  I think I like, I like that people like it, but it, that's just
Speaker 7:  the lore of it is like literally Josh made the original theme
Speaker 7:  in garage band, like overnight and like all
Speaker 7:  lost to the midst of time. Like I've asked him like it's just gone.
Speaker 7:  Like it's not gonna come back. Yeah. So we just needed to remake it and
Speaker 7:  we had an opportunity to do it. We should use it more though 'cause it's
Speaker 7:  very good.
Speaker 2:  It is very good. And by the way, If you wanna blame YouTube for it, you should,
Speaker 2:  but you should specifically blame YouTube music and the way that it interacts
Speaker 2:  with YouTube and just the truly insane way that YouTube has approached podcasts.
Speaker 2:  But that is for another show. Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna come back and we're gonna grab back our way through the rest of these
Speaker 2:  questions. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back with Neli Patel. We have some more questions. Neil, I
Speaker 2:  took one sip of water during that ad break If you wanna know how long
Speaker 7:  It was. No, we talked for five minutes. Neil and I, well Liam read stuff.
Speaker 2:  Sat for five minutes and listened to the as.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's run through a few more. So th this is kind of a grab bag
Speaker 2:  set of questions. We got a lot of people who just have questions about The
Speaker 2:  Verge, how we work, how we're thinking about things. So we're just gonna,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna plow through a bunch of 'em as fast as we can. Sound good?
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Fabulous. All right. Here's the first one.
Speaker 12:  Hey guys. Now that The Verge has gone subscription, it's kept me wondering
Speaker 12:  about The Verge redesign. Again, I make websites and
Speaker 12:  digital products and things for a living and the redesign was kind of huge.
Speaker 12:  It kind of felt a little bit like Ben Thompson's aggregation theory of like
Speaker 12:  aggregating stuff from other sources and pulling the value into your own
Speaker 12:  homepage. And I'm curious how it worked just like as a
Speaker 12:  person who, who does this for a living? Did it work? To what extent did
Speaker 12:  it work? So I apply this same theory, other websites, a lot of, any
Speaker 12:  insights you can give. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  So we got a couple versions of this question. So just to, just to make it
Speaker 2:  very slightly broader than this, the, the question we got several times was
Speaker 2:  essentially it's been a little over two years since our redesign. We've
Speaker 2:  done the subscription, which is obviously another huge change to what The
Speaker 2:  Verge is doing. Looking back, did the redesign work?
Speaker 7:  Yes. And it's actually really funny you mentioned Ben Thompson because when
Speaker 7:  we launched the redesign he was like, oh, that's aggregation theory. And
Speaker 7:  I went onto his podcast and talked about it for an hour. Nice. 'cause that
Speaker 7:  is exactly what it is. If you have a big direct audience that you are already
Speaker 7:  serving, the easiest thing to do is make the
Speaker 7:  product more useful. And I actually got this idea in a pretty
Speaker 7:  tangential way. We had done a bunch of surveys about how people felt about
Speaker 7:  different tech companies and the most loved tech companies were Google and
Speaker 7:  Amazon every year that we ran the survey and Apple is actually kind of at
Speaker 7:  the bottom of the, the list of the big tech companies. And we were just like
Speaker 7:  trying to figure out why. And it's like, oh, these are utilities. People
Speaker 7:  use Google on Amazon every single day. Yep. And they kind of don't, they
Speaker 7:  just like use, they hold their iPhones to use Google and that probably has
Speaker 7:  shaped a bunch of our coverage, but it also shaped a bunch of our product
Speaker 7:  thinking, which is people come to our homepage every day and we should make
Speaker 7:  it as useful as possible. And then people will come back.
Speaker 7:  And this has come up also with Blue Sky recently. And the
Speaker 7:  way they treat links, like I think they've been pretty open. Like we're part
Speaker 7:  of the web, we will send you away. 'cause we know if we send you away to
Speaker 7:  high quality things, you are more likely to come back. Yep. That,
Speaker 7:  that same idea we've had the whole time, we will send you away. We are happy
Speaker 7:  to link out, we're happy to link to our competitors. We have some ideas about
Speaker 7:  how to make that more seamless in a world of paywalls.
Speaker 7:  Stay tuned. But we, we just
Speaker 7:  know that making our own product more useful after two years
Speaker 7:  has worked Right. Time spent, our homepage has gone up by like minutes.
Speaker 7:  No one can move that number. Like it is an impossible number to move on almost
Speaker 7:  every product and our redesign accomplish it. 'cause there's just more to
Speaker 7:  look at and more places to go and then people come back.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The idea of a homepage was like a, an open
Speaker 2:  question not very long ago. I mean like one, one of the things we talked
Speaker 2:  about, you showed me the very early versions of this before
Speaker 2:  I came back and I had come from a place where we were having genuine
Speaker 2:  conversations about like, is it even worth having in caring for a homepage?
Speaker 2:  And I think I would say both history and the rest of the media
Speaker 2:  industry has proven homepage is pretty much correct the last couple
Speaker 7:  Years. Yeah. And not to harp on this, 'cause David hears me harp on this
Speaker 7:  all the time, but it is just about owning your own distribution. Right? This
Speaker 7:  is why people have email newsletters. They can email it to you directly and
Speaker 7:  there's not an algorithm between you and the audience. Our homepage is just
Speaker 7:  us. Here's a feed of stuff we liked. And you can
Speaker 7:  come look at our list of things that we liked. And people, I think people
Speaker 7:  enjoy that 'cause they know that we made it not the Facebook algorithm
Speaker 7:  made it or the X algorithm made it or whatever. So there's some
Speaker 7:  value there. I don't know if that's a thing you can just like Cold Start,
Speaker 7:  because it only works If you have an audience. It might work If you can
Speaker 7:  communicate to a big enough audience that this is what you're doing and there
Speaker 7:  there's continual value there. But the idea that your product should
Speaker 7:  directly be the most valuable thing that you make and you can show it to
Speaker 7:  people and you're, you don't let someone, someone else's distribution
Speaker 7:  get in the way that is everywhere in media right now. Right. That
Speaker 7:  is every newsletter author that is every homepage redesign that you're seeing.
Speaker 7:  It's, oh, we gotta take control of our distribution.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Totally agree. All right, next up we have a question from Clemente
Speaker 2:  who says, I'm a huge fan of The Economist and I especially love their
Speaker 2:  print editions. There's something quite different sitting down with a nice
Speaker 2:  thick magazine with a bunch of amazing art. You guys could take
Speaker 2:  a page from The Onion and come out with a couple of editions a year, maybe
Speaker 2:  including your best long form pieces. Would The Verge ever
Speaker 2:  come out in print? We're the last website on earth. Would we ever be print?
Speaker 2:  That's Clemente question. And we have, I want to excuse
Speaker 2:  things like content goblins, which is amazing. Yeah. And everyone we've made
Speaker 2:  a lot of over the past year. But like, I think, I think the question is like
Speaker 2:  an ongoing sort of serious print product of our
Speaker 2:  journalism. Is that a thing you'd ever made seen?
Speaker 7:  Will we print out the website and mail it to you several times a year, but
Speaker 7:  like pretty a pretty, yeah. Maybe
Speaker 7:  like the world's most qualified maybe and the
Speaker 7:  qualifications are a, a number of things have to go
Speaker 7:  our way in unlikely directions for that to be worth our time.
Speaker 7:  I wanna do it. Which is why it's a maybe I think it would be really fun.
Speaker 7:  And I've only ever worked in digital media and I've always just been jealous
Speaker 7:  of print covers. I, you, everybody who's listen to the show has heard me
Speaker 7:  say, I just wanna circle things in Red Pen. I watch David Haskell, the editor-in-chief
Speaker 7:  of New York magazine. He really does just print out the thing and like look
Speaker 7:  at the layouts. That's awesome. Yeah. Right. Like, it's cool.
Speaker 7:  It's a lot of work like closing every issue of New York
Speaker 7:  magazine. We, we watch them do it. They, they work on the floor just above
Speaker 7:  us in the New York office. It's a lot of work and it, that's a
Speaker 7:  50-year-old legendary magazine and work is worth it. We would have to just
Speaker 7:  start all that from scratch. And so maybe we can do it in some small ways.
Speaker 7:  Maybe we can do more regular zines, maybe even build our way up to it. That's,
Speaker 7:  that's the set of unlikely things that has to break our way. It, there's
Speaker 7:  nothing stopping us from doing it. It's just a whole other set of work that,
Speaker 7:  you know, time is a zero sum commodity. Like I, we, we would just have to
Speaker 7:  stop doing some other work to do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. I would personally love to do it just because I want
Speaker 2:  back at Wired, they used to have like a, a row of vertical touch screens
Speaker 2:  and they would put a page up on each one and literally like page through
Speaker 2:  the whole magazine on the, it was awesome. I want that so bad.
Speaker 2:  I don't think it worked, but it was cool.
Speaker 7:  I that's, they
Speaker 2:  Didn't seem to do any work, they just showed it to people and that was awesome.
Speaker 2:  Alright, next question. We're gonna do two more and then I'll let you get
Speaker 2:  out here. Here is one that I very much enjoyed. It's
Speaker 2:  particularly Neli question.
Speaker 10:  Hello, my name is Nick. I'm calling from Minnesota.
Speaker 10:  This is a question for the meta lowercase
Speaker 10:  m how is The Vergecast or The Verge work episode?
Speaker 10:  Neli often says
Speaker 10:  that The Verge is like a Montessori and
Speaker 10:  he just lets people pursue their passions. But I would like to know
Speaker 10:  a little bit more about the nuts and bolts of that. There obviously must
Speaker 10:  be some check-ins and you know, how do you make
Speaker 10:  sure people are moving forward on projects or choosing the right projects
Speaker 10:  or pursuing passions that are relevant to your audience?
Speaker 10:  I am finishing a master's degree in organizational leadership. So these
Speaker 10:  types of people management and organizational development questions are
Speaker 10:  really interesting to me. I'd also like to know how has
Speaker 10:  that shifted as The Verge has grown? Right. It's easy to run
Speaker 10:  a Montessori style team when you have a team of six and make you harder
Speaker 10:  when there's a team of, I don't know, a hundred something. Anyway, bye-bye.
Speaker 2:  I did a decoder question for you.
Speaker 7:  Oh boy. Yeah, if you'd like to hear me contend with that question. I
Speaker 7:  spent an hour a week doing therapy with CEOs and that's all that show is.
Speaker 7:  Yep. How do I do this? Can you tell me? Do you know? Do you know how you're
Speaker 7:  doing it? And the answers are often much more appealing than anyone wants
Speaker 7:  them to be. Yeah, it was easier at the beginning. That's actually the first
Speaker 7:  thing you know, there's still a handful of co-founders on our
Speaker 7:  team, Sean Hollister, Thomas Tricker, like we're all here. David was like
Speaker 7:  employee number one. I think all of us remember when it was
Speaker 7:  like 15 people in one room and we solved every decision by
Speaker 7:  all yelling at each other. Yep. Because no one had kids.
Speaker 7:  That's, that's super real. That's 24 hours a day in one room
Speaker 7:  yelling at each other. And that's how we did everything. And there was a
Speaker 7:  purity to that. I think it came out in the product. I think you could see
Speaker 7:  it in the product. It came out in the stress levels.
Speaker 7:  Certainly it came out in the alcohol use
Speaker 7:  that is totally not scalable. I like, I have as much
Speaker 7:  fond recollection of our startup days as anyone. It was fun.
Speaker 7:  It was, you can't run an organization that way. And even if you're doing
Speaker 7:  the startup days, you still should stop it as soon as you can.
Speaker 7:  That's just not how to do it. So the, and now we're bigger, right?
Speaker 7:  We're much bigger and we're totally distributed. We're not even all in the
Speaker 7:  same room anymore. So we've, we have had to come up with a bunch of other
Speaker 7:  ways to communicate what we're doing and why we're doing it and how we do
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 7:  I think that the job as the editor in chief is just scaling taste
Speaker 7:  like all the publication is, is a taste at the end of the day. That's
Speaker 7:  all. It's like, that's what matters. Like here's some stuff
Speaker 7:  that's in, here's some stuff that's out, that's the whole publication. So
Speaker 7:  for us, it's just a lot of conversations about that. Why is this a verb
Speaker 7:  story and is this good enough? Are the only two questions I think I consistently
Speaker 7:  ask. Everything else is kind of just like on the margin, like tactical, like
Speaker 7:  did you talk to this person or we have, we written a good headline, but the
Speaker 7:  two questions that we come back to that the whole team is kind of always
Speaker 7:  asking is why is this virtual story and is this good enough? And If you get
Speaker 7:  everyone doing that all the time, you don't have to police it, right? Because
Speaker 7:  everyone knows that they're allowed to ask those questions to each other
Speaker 7:  and that they should know the answers and the answer to, is this
Speaker 7:  good enough? Is almost always no. Right? Right. Like that's the right answer
Speaker 7:  to that question. And then, then it's like, well wait, we have to get it
Speaker 7:  out the door. Like we're, we're in a race, we gotta get the story out the
Speaker 7:  door, we'll fix it later or something. Or it's, I need to go back and make
Speaker 7:  it better. And as long as everyone agrees that those are the shape of those
Speaker 7:  questions and that you should be prepared to answer them, then, then you're
Speaker 7:  fine. Like you can really trust everyone to go as fast as they can
Speaker 7:  because at the end of the day, everyone is asking themselves those questions
Speaker 7:  and prepared to ask one another those questions.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's pretty good. And yeah, for more, listen to Neli talk on decoder
Speaker 2:  just incessantly all the time.
Speaker 7:  How you do this.
Speaker 7:  That's
Speaker 2:  All I'm asking you. You joke that you started doing that show to learn how
Speaker 2:  to manage and it feels more and more true every episode, but the thing you're
Speaker 2:  realizing is that no one is good at it. And so it's like, I don't know if
Speaker 2:  that makes me feel better or worse. Do you
Speaker 7:  Have a plan?
Speaker 7:  What is it? Can you say it out loud? Something
Speaker 2:  About doors and decisions. That's all I know. Alright, last
Speaker 2:  one and then I'm gonna let you go. This is a question from Jeffrey. This
Speaker 2:  is going to sound like a really self-aggrandizing way to end this, but this
Speaker 2:  is a question we actually get a lot and I think it's interesting to answer.
Speaker 2:  Jeffrey says, what can we all do to ensure the viability, longevity, and
Speaker 2:  success of The Verge? Obviously the simple answer is subscribing, but I think
Speaker 2:  it's worth it to remind your loyal audience about the need to support the
Speaker 2:  website, whether it's through subscribing or other methods. I have the site
Speaker 2:  bookmarked and check it several times a day, consuming ads and giving you
Speaker 2:  clicks and theoretically some amount of revenue and bypassing the search
Speaker 2:  Google search algorithm and the associated ills. Are there other metrics
Speaker 2:  that help you show your reach and popularity that VERGE lovers should be
Speaker 2:  using? Do article shares matter? Should I click every affiliate link just
Speaker 2:  to help you out? Should I be following my favorite VERGE writers and other
Speaker 2:  social media x blue sky MAs on et cetera? First of all, Jeffrey, I love you
Speaker 2:  for asking this question. Yeah. And second of all, this is a question we
Speaker 2:  get a lot and I think goes back to what we were talking about at the beginning
Speaker 2:  of like of people want the stuff that they like
Speaker 2:  to succeed, right? It's why people cheer on their creators for getting brand
Speaker 2:  deals. It means you get to keep doing this, right? Like we, we want our favorite
Speaker 2:  teams to win. What does that look like for The Verge
Speaker 2:  throwing out, give us $50 a year, which you should do, come be part of the
Speaker 2:  community and comment mean things on all of Eli's stories.
Speaker 2:  What else goes on that list for you?
Speaker 7:  I've just come to accept that our competitors are not other
Speaker 7:  publications. They are creators. Hmm. I think
Speaker 7:  that's fine. I, I hope you've heard me say over and over again. I wish them
Speaker 7:  all the best. I think some of them do excellent work. I hope
Speaker 7:  they're even, I hope all of them are successful on their own terms and they
Speaker 7:  build their own businesses and everyone does a great job and has a good time.
Speaker 7:  We make something different, right? And that, that's fine. Like
Speaker 7:  our product is differentiated from the creator ecosystem
Speaker 7:  by din of the fact that we have our own distribution, that we have whatever
Speaker 7:  traditional journalistic ethics policy, all this stuff.
Speaker 7:  The thing that I think would help us the most in that ecosystem is
Speaker 7:  by having the same kinds of audiences that creators have that are
Speaker 7:  talking about them. And like, If you look at the comment section,
Speaker 7:  like a robust dialogue about what the creators are doing and why they're
Speaker 7:  doing it, and like they evangelize for their,
Speaker 7:  the people. And I, I don't know that any media organizations
Speaker 7:  have contended with that fact. Like as a group,
Speaker 7:  the journalism industry has been too high and mighty for too long.
Speaker 7:  I That is just a failure. Yes. I I see that failure, I perceive that failure
Speaker 7:  very clearly. I think most people perceive that failure and you kind
Speaker 7:  of have the Jeff Bezoses of the world being like,
Speaker 7:  you trust the media less than Congress. The media will have even less than
Speaker 7:  an opinion now. Right? That's what he's doing with the Post, right? Patrick,
Speaker 7:  soon strong at the, at the LA Times billionaire owner of the LA Times is
Speaker 7:  gonna add a bias meter to their stories, an AI powered bias meter
Speaker 7:  to their stories. So you can push a button and he, and like read the other
Speaker 7:  version, like the unbiased version of the story. This is the most undercutting
Speaker 7:  thing you can do to a newsroom possible. Yeah. These are just reactions to
Speaker 7:  the idea that people don't trust the media. Okay. I I think those are wrong,
Speaker 7:  especially for our kind of newsroom, which is inherently
Speaker 7:  evaluative. Like I, we hold the phone and I'm like seven. Like
Speaker 7:  there's no there, there it is. Like, right, there's, there's straightforwardly.
Speaker 7:  We're like, this is bad, like all the time. So I think it's better
Speaker 7:  for us to say we are in a relationship with your audience and it's gonna
Speaker 7:  be the same kind of personal relationship, for lack of a better word,
Speaker 7:  parasocial relationship, where we're real people that you know,
Speaker 7:  and we're accountable to you the way that creators, I think, feel accountable
Speaker 7:  to our audiences on these platforms. There's a lot of dynamics in there that
Speaker 7:  I think are, are hard, but what I'm boiling my answer down to is like, you
Speaker 7:  should care about us. You should communicate with us. You should communicate
Speaker 7:  to other people about why what you're getting from us is
Speaker 7:  different or hopefully better than what you're getting from everything else.
Speaker 7:  Because that's really at the end of it. I don't wanna do a bunch of marketing
Speaker 7:  about our ethics policy. I wanna have an audience that's like, this ethics
Speaker 7:  policy is important to us and see more places try to copy
Speaker 7:  it to increase the quality of the media that people consume.
Speaker 7:  That's a big goal. I I, I just can't do that on my own. And that's, I think
Speaker 7:  the way you can help,
Speaker 2:  But also like, follow us on Blue Sky, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But yeah, but also you might as well also buy every affiliate product.
Speaker 7:  I don't even know how that works. Will I do that? Just send me a check. Personally,
Speaker 2:  I actually think that's the one you shouldn't do. I think If you send me
Speaker 2:  like a personal check Yes. To give it back.
Speaker 7:  I will read your name on the show.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, the the high-minded thing that just in the back of my
Speaker 7:  head all the time is if we are successful
Speaker 7:  doing it this way, we might push some people to
Speaker 7:  try and copy how we talk about our ethics policy and the making of the
Speaker 7:  journalism and the independence. You can see it with the independent
Speaker 7:  newsletter folks, right? That it's happening over there. You can see what
Speaker 7:  the 4 0 4 media post. I don't, I'm not saying you're copy this, but you can
Speaker 7:  see that there's a response to the void of
Speaker 7:  that stuff by talking about it more. And I'm just sort of like
Speaker 7:  hopeful that if we can build audiences
Speaker 7:  that like openly say in the market, this is the thing
Speaker 7:  we like, then there will be more supply of it.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty good. All right. You need to go?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I quit. That was my last day. David's in charge now. Yeah. He's gonna
Speaker 7:  read all the ads.
Speaker 2:  Let's go post Red ads forever.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Neli, we got lots more questions, so we'll, we'll find some other time
Speaker 2:  to, to keep going through some of these things, but thank you to everybody
Speaker 2:  who emailed and called and keep stuff coming. We got, we got
Speaker 2:  lots of stuff left to do, lots of stuff to figure out on the subscription.
Speaker 2:  Lots of new ideas about Vergecast stuff. If you want me to
Speaker 2:  read more ads, tell me lie it won't work, but you can tell 'em Anyway.
Speaker 2:  Neli, thank you as always. Thank
Speaker 7:  You.
Speaker 2:  All right, before we go, Liam, come back just for one second.
Speaker 3:  Sure. What's
Speaker 2:  Going on? We just made some CES plans. You know them better than I do,
Speaker 2:  so tell the people what our CES plans are.
Speaker 3:  Absolutely. The Virgil will be back at CES this year, but
Speaker 3:  what's special is that this year we're doing a live vergecast. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be on January 8th, which is the Wednesday of CES week.
Speaker 3:  It'll be free and open to the public. And yeah, we're,
Speaker 3:  we're hoping to get a bunch of people out there to have good time with us
Speaker 3:  and, and just do live vergecast and talk about CES.
Speaker 2:  Where is it, are we doing it at like the, the Vegas stadium with 60,000 people?
Speaker 2:  Is that
Speaker 3:  Nope, we're gonna be right on the strip. It's at the Las Vegas
Speaker 3:  Brooklyn Bowl of all
Speaker 2:  Places. There's a Brooklyn Bowl in Las Vegas.
Speaker 3:  We're bringing New York to to Vegas this year. There we go.
Speaker 2:  I love it. Yeah, we have a couple more episodes between now and the end of
Speaker 2:  the year, so we'll, we'll keep reminding y'all, but if you're going to CES,
Speaker 2:  it's Wednesday night, come hang out with us. It's gonna be very fun. I'm
Speaker 2:  told there will be food provided. There
Speaker 3:  Will food and drinks,
Speaker 2:  So that's all that matters. All right, Liam, thank you. Of course.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for the first cast today. Thank you to Helen and Neli
Speaker 2:  for being here. And thank you for listening and thank you especially to everyone
Speaker 2:  who called and emailed with questions. People are always like, oh, why do
Speaker 2:  you do these meta shows? Does anyone care? And frankly, I wonder this
Speaker 2:  sometimes too, but it's so fun hearing the stuff that you guys want to
Speaker 2:  know and understand and are thinking about and care about and are
Speaker 2:  engaging with us on. And we're still figuring all of this stuff
Speaker 2:  out as we go too, right? So this is a super fun thing to get to do
Speaker 2:  with all of you, and I'm so, so grateful for everyone who did it. This
Speaker 2:  is one of my favorite Virgin traditions that we do on this show, and
Speaker 2:  incredibly grateful for everyone who is part of it with us. So thank you.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more on our subscription, on our business, on
Speaker 2:  all of the stuff that we've been talking about at The Verge dot com. Eli's
Speaker 2:  note that he wrote when we first launched the subscription last week, I think
Speaker 2:  puts a lot of this in a really good perspective. So I'll make sure that's
Speaker 2:  in the show notes. Keep it locked on the website. Tell us what you want from
Speaker 2:  the podcast. Tell us what you want from the subscription. Tell us what you
Speaker 2:  want from The Verge. We're here doing this with you and we wanna keep hearing
Speaker 2:  from you. So like I said, you can always call the hotline. It's six six VERGE
Speaker 2:  one. One ask questions that way. Email us vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  If I'm being completely honest, I in particular have been bad about checking
Speaker 2:  the email recently because it just got overrun with spam at one point and
Speaker 2:  it became kind of annoying to dig through every single day.
Speaker 2:  But I actually think we solved the spam problem. I've been better at checking
Speaker 2:  it recently. So keep the emails coming. We love hearing from you.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Liam James, Wil Poor and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is VERGE Production and part of the Vox Media podcast network, neela, and
Speaker 2:  I'll be back on Friday to talk about somehow the fact that there is
Speaker 2:  still news in mid-December as we wind towards the holidays. Plus, we
Speaker 2:  have some other fun stuff planned between now and the end of the, we'll see
Speaker 2:  you then. Rock and
Speaker 13:  Roll