# Transcript
ID: 48805543-b15f-4f78-8bc2-10db760fa960
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4284967458140021963/6711366929369937227/s93290-US-5515s-1712319699.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz discuss the Apple Macbook Air M3 review, Jon Stewart's take on AI, and a whole lot more of this week's tech news.
Speaker 1:  Support for the podcast
Speaker 3:  Hello And Welcome To, our chest flagship podcast of best
Speaker 3:  printers, 2024
Speaker 4:  Best printer. Small business. Yeah, office, home use
Speaker 3:  Black
Speaker 4:  And white color.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Label printing. That's my part.
Speaker 3:  That's my favorite sort of evolution of the
Speaker 3:  SEO Spam is the Amazon product name. That is
Speaker 3:  just all of the things.
Speaker 4:  It's everywhere now. Yeah. Yeah. The everything on Amazon is like 60 words
Speaker 4:  long now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is better though. Like the way they name phones
Speaker 5:  at Samsung or the way they name products on
Speaker 5:  Amazon's website.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's Samsung. What? It's 1000%. I wanna be clear. Samsung
Speaker 3:  the Samsung naming conventions. And in fact, most tech product naming conventions
Speaker 3:  are now like performance art. Yeah. They're just like, some words, a
Speaker 3:  galaxy, a number, some other letters. Yeah. Fine.
Speaker 3:  They're
Speaker 5:  Just riffing. It's like jazz.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They're just like, here's some ideas we had, you know? And then
Speaker 3:  what the SEO spam is just all this technology and all this
Speaker 3:  AI and all these algorithms, and we're like, what's the best way to win it?
Speaker 3:  Then just shove all the words in the title field
Speaker 4:  And then off to the side there's like Sony who's just like, would you like
Speaker 4:  16 numbers and letters together? That don't mean that don't mean anything.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. It's very good. Anyway, we're all together in the studios.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm your friend. NELI. David. Pierce is here. Hello? Alex. Cranz is
Speaker 3:  here. Hello. It's been a minute since we were all on the show at the same
Speaker 3:  time. Yeah. Let alone all in the same room at the same time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Wait, how were y'all's vacations?
Speaker 3:  They were good. Yeah. Like very good. I drank a lot of Miami
Speaker 3:  vices, which is when he put a daiquiri in the pina colada.
Speaker 3:  So it's pink and white. Incredible. That's a lot of sugar at 8:00 AM
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And a lot of run. And then
Speaker 4:  At nine, 9:00 AM and 10. But
Speaker 5:  You're getting the fruit, so you're getting your vitamin C.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's what you really, that's what you really want. It was good, but
Speaker 3:  we were, you know, when you travel with a small child, you end up on her
Speaker 3:  schedule like a 5-year-old schedule.
Speaker 5:  So you were in bed by seven?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, we were in bed by nine and we were up at six and hammered by 11, like
Speaker 3:  a 5-year-old. And I was like, wait, this might be the ideal way to
Speaker 3:  live my life. Yeah. Like on this. And then I immediately was like, no.
Speaker 3:  I,
Speaker 4:  Especially when you're on vacation though, like being the first one up has
Speaker 4:  real ramifications. Yeah. You're like, the world is your oyster for like
Speaker 4:  three hours at the resort before anybody else wakes up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You get the best cereal, like the best breakfast. It's the
Speaker 3:  Best. Yeah. Yeah. It was good. How was yours?
Speaker 5:  It was good. I, I mopped.
Speaker 3:  You mopped. Yeah. Did you go on vacation as a small Victorian
Speaker 3:  chambermaid? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Pretty much.
Speaker 3:  Pretty much. I'm gonna do like a lrp.
Speaker 5:  No, I, I really, I really needed to do some mopping, so I did a lot of mopping.
Speaker 5:  I really, my goal was to like, see if I could become one with my couch.
Speaker 5:  Oh, good. For like a whole week.
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's an important kind of vacation.
Speaker 5:  It like, I thought it was great. My dog did not agree. He,
Speaker 5:  he was very frustrated with my vacation, but I had a great time.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Did you watch anything? Have you couch Time is watch time,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. I, I saw girls Five ever. Five ever.
Speaker 3:  Very good girl. Netflix wants me to watch this show and I'm just not gonna
Speaker 3:  do it. You should
Speaker 5:  Do it. It's very
Speaker 4:  Good. It's good. It's good. It is legitimately very good. It's very
Speaker 5:  Funny.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's, it's straight out of the brain of Tina Fey. So like If,
Speaker 4:  you think 30 Rock is funny? You'll think Girls five. Eva is funny and I think
Speaker 4:  30 Rock is very funny and
Speaker 5:  It spends a lot of time making fun of like a very specific
Speaker 5:  neighborhood in Brooklyn that I used to live in. So I'm like, nice.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Oh, that's good. Okay. Yes. I'll give it a shot. Yeah, it's, it's good.
Speaker 3:  It's good. I went through the whole three body problem with Netflix,
Speaker 3:  you know, I was like, I opened Netflix. I was like, I'm gonna watch this
Speaker 3:  show. I watched the whole thing and it wasn't good. I don't, and I was like,
Speaker 3:  this is, I had the Netflix problem again. I need to disclose that I made
Speaker 3:  a Netflix show. Our Netflix show is great,
Speaker 5:  Unlike some
Speaker 4:  Other ones, other Netflix shows.
Speaker 3:  It's called The, future of Less So, but I don Dunno.
Speaker 3:  It was like, that was the thing I did. 'cause we went on vacation, we came
Speaker 3:  back and we like, several days left, like post vacation. Oh,
Speaker 3:  clutch move. Oh yeah. And I was like, how gonna spend this time? It was like
Speaker 3:  watching, watching television. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Of
Speaker 3:  Course. It was amazing. Yeah. And I was like, the show is,
Speaker 3:  it's fine
Speaker 5:  That that's why I, I switched it off and turned on the New Walking Dead show.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. And I like, that's just adorable. It's two people being like, what
Speaker 5:  if we kill a bunch of zombies and make out? And I was like,
Speaker 3:  All right, the spoiler alert people are gonna come to you.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. I'm
Speaker 3:  Sorry. I tweeted one thing about Three Body Problem
Speaker 5:  And they came
Speaker 3:  For you and they came and I was like, this book has been out for a million
Speaker 3:  years. What's
Speaker 5:  The problem?
Speaker 3:  That's fine. Anyhow, it's a, it's a weird
Speaker 3:  springtime week. Yeah. I feel like there was a lot of news the past couple
Speaker 3:  weeks. The the government and the tech companies are just
Speaker 3:  doing a thing. And then this week everyone went on spring break.
Speaker 4:  I think that's literally true. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like everyone was like, we just gotta stop the fighting. Everyone go drink
Speaker 3:  a Miami Vice. We'll come back. We'll get back right back to it after spring
Speaker 3:  break. Well,
Speaker 4:  And now on the flip side, we're now, what, four weeks away
Speaker 4:  from the beginning of like developer conference season? Yeah. So everybody
Speaker 4:  is out of filing legal briefs and into
Speaker 4:  planning for like weird AI product announcements. And this is
Speaker 4:  sort of the, the small doldrums in the middle. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is the Quiet week where we saw them outside getting a beautiful tour
Speaker 5:  of Wall Street with all of the other high schoolers. Lovely.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No, this is the New York visit week. Yeah. When's DC visit week? When
Speaker 3:  do the eighth graders go to dc? It was week, that was last week.
Speaker 4:  The Cherry Blossoms came out. Yeah. And just every
Speaker 4:  13-year-old in America went to the Lincoln Memorial on the same day. It was
Speaker 3:  Unbelievable. Yeah. So that, that's this week where they, we, so the vi's
Speaker 3:  offices are in the financial district of New York, which is very old. There's
Speaker 3:  a bunch of old stuff you can look at. And this is the week where they're
Speaker 3:  all here looking.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're all like, yep. This is some old stuff. I'm looking at my phone.
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook is like, George Washington got hammered in this bar. That's a real
Speaker 3:  thing he thinks about all the time. Yeah. But there's, there's a lot of stuff
Speaker 3:  to talk about. David has structured the show into three
Speaker 3:  lightning rounds,
Speaker 5:  All
Speaker 3:  Sponsor, three Sponsorable Lightning rounds, which no one has
Speaker 3:  yet to sponsor. We get a lot of emails from people, they're like, I'll pay
Speaker 3:  some money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Promises don't pay the bills. Friends
Speaker 4:  hit the Venmo
Speaker 3:  Or leave me alone. We're gonna figure this out. I promise you we'll figure
Speaker 3:  this out. But If, you run a large company. We're
Speaker 3:  good at taking a lot of money. Yeah. Like there's a whole floor of people
Speaker 3:  at this company who's like a huge amount of money. We know what to do when
Speaker 3:  I'm like, someone wants to pay us 20 bucks. They're like, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 3:  DoorDash. Is it cash? Yeah. We should be on DoorDash,
Speaker 4:  But hoping we deliver is like hot podcast. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's like nothing happens. Yeah. And yeah, three lightning rounds. We should
Speaker 3:  start there. We did have a big review this week. Yep. A few weeks after it
Speaker 3:  came out. We hired a new laptop reviewer, Joan and Elias.
Speaker 3:  Her, she, we got her up to Speed crayons. We like let her do a think pad
Speaker 3:  and then we're like, MacBook Air get it done. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And, and she did, she she had a lot of feelings about the
Speaker 5:  MacBook Air M three 15 and 13 inch
Speaker 5:  because they both came out and they're pretty similar. And she was like,
Speaker 5:  they're good MacBooks. They, they got a little faster and then she was very
Speaker 5:  upset because they had eight gigabytes of Ram standard. And, and I,
Speaker 5:  I tend to agree with her, but I know some people on this podcast don't.
Speaker 4:  Well, yes. I mean, we're gonna fight about that for many hours. Some people
Speaker 4:  have
Speaker 5:  Bad takes but say it's okay.
Speaker 4:  It, it brought me such great joy to watch someone
Speaker 4:  else come and go through the same thing that all of us have been through
Speaker 4:  with the MacBooks over the years, which is, this is very good. It's probably
Speaker 4:  the best laptop you can buy. It is a teeny tiny bit
Speaker 4:  better than the last one and slightly more expensive in Apple. Really wants
Speaker 4:  you to buy something much more expensive. Do I give that an eight or a nine?
Speaker 4:  It's like the eternal question of the Macbook Air is like, it's
Speaker 4:  probably the best laptop. It could probably, it's kind of annoying.
Speaker 4:  What do I do with that? Yeah. And it's just like, it's nice to see someone
Speaker 4:  else go through this very intense process because the story of the MacBook
Speaker 4:  era is like, it, it rules like it is, it is pretty hands
Speaker 4:  down the best all around laptop on the planet and yet
Speaker 4:  it's a pretty small upgrade over the last one. It has a bunch of the same
Speaker 4:  deficiencies as the last one. And they desperately, desperately, desperately
Speaker 4:  want you to spend $2,500 on a laptop and not a thousand dollars on a laptop.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Are very good at getting you from one to the other.
Speaker 5:  That's what I did.
Speaker 4:  Is it? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well I went with a back book pro.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you got you. Just, you you let yourself get specked up.
Speaker 5:  I got specked up. I like, like the, that that feeling from, from the early
Speaker 5:  days of the MacBook air where you, you couldn't get the air, you had to get
Speaker 5:  a pro If, you wanted power. I was like, I know, I don't, I don't, I know
Speaker 5:  I could be fine with an air, but I have an air for work. This is really like,
Speaker 5:  it's important for me to know the whole lineup
Speaker 4:  So I can either have a pro to run all my Chrome tabs or I can have an air
Speaker 4:  to run all of my Chrome tabs. Is that
Speaker 5:  What you're going through? Yeah. Well and Crusader Kings three
Speaker 5:  like, it it fair, it plays it beautifully.
Speaker 3:  So what you're talking about is directly related to the eight gigs of RAM
Speaker 3:  situation. Yeah. Yeah. Which is you settle down to buy this laptop. The base
Speaker 3:  configuration should be amazing. The base configuration compared to any other
Speaker 3:  base configuration
Speaker 3:  potentially the best all on laptop. Like that's a, it's a real thing. You
Speaker 3:  can make an argument for sure. Yep. And then you're like, but if I put eight
Speaker 3:  gigs of RAM in this, it will last for two years and then it will die and
Speaker 3:  I'll do this again. So I should put 16 or 32 gigs of RAM into it. And then
Speaker 3:  you're like, I should add some storage to it because if now it's gonna last
Speaker 3:  a long time and then you are quickly at, oh, I should just buy Macbook Pro.
Speaker 3:  Yep. Yeah. I just spend slightly even more money than I
Speaker 3:  can just have a 14 inch Macbook pro
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 5:  O off off the shelf. You don't have to worry about somebody like customizing
Speaker 5:  it and them adding a little shipping time to it. Just get
Speaker 4:  Happy. Yeah. Because what it is it, you go from
Speaker 4:  eight to 16 gigs of ram, that's 200 bucks. You go from
Speaker 4:  the base storage, which is 2 56 to five 12, that's
Speaker 4:  another 200 bucks. So already you've just turned your a thousand dollars
Speaker 4:  or your $1,100 laptop in this case into a $1,500 laptop. At which
Speaker 4:  point you're like, well maybe I'll just get the 15 inch 'cause it's not that
Speaker 4:  much more expensive. Yeah. And then you get, then you're up to there and
Speaker 4:  then it is, I mean it is so perfectly calculated how to get you
Speaker 4:  to buy like the mid spec MacBook Pro. Yeah. It's just unbelievable.
Speaker 4:  It's beautiful. Yeah. And it is not the computer anyone needs. Like
Speaker 4:  I truly do not believe the premise that If, you buy eight gigs of ram, it's
Speaker 4:  only gonna last you two years and it won't work. I think like if you're a
Speaker 4:  person who like really heavily uses your computer
Speaker 4:  Sure. I think if you're gonna spend money on one additional spec, ram is
Speaker 4:  always the thing. So this is totally believe that. I believe firmly that
Speaker 4:  for most people, for most uses the base
Speaker 4:  configuration of the MacBook air storage ram, everything is fine.
Speaker 3:  Crazy. You're a crazy person.
Speaker 4:  It's so much computer.
Speaker 5:  This
Speaker 3:  Is what I'm trying to But not enough Ram. Go ahead. Yeah. This
Speaker 5:  Is what I'm trying to understand is 'cause like you said this and it was
Speaker 5:  like just lobbing a bomb into chat. Mm. In the office. Like, like you My
Speaker 5:  God.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You get so mad at me. Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  I resisted like telling anybody that you said that and then,
Speaker 5:  then you like you were like, yeah, I believe eight gigs and everybody's like,
Speaker 5:  David, what are you doing? And is it because we're
Speaker 5:  all people who use our laptops a lot and always have a
Speaker 5:  bajillion tabs open that that we feel that need for the ram.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's part of it.
Speaker 5:  Like is it, is it like a Verge?
Speaker 4:  It's, I think it's two things. I think half of it is what you just described.
Speaker 4:  I think the other half is we are all literally professionally trained to
Speaker 4:  be sensitive to our computers being slow. And then I look at like my
Speaker 4:  mom who is on a 9-year-old
Speaker 4:  iPad and like doesn't notice that it's a problem. Like it just,
Speaker 4:  it just works fine. She taps a thing, she waits a couple of seconds and it
Speaker 4:  opens and I'm like, do you know how long Safari just took to open mom? And
Speaker 4:  she's like, what are you talking? It just open like it's whatever. I think
Speaker 4:  most people don't spend as much time thinking about how long their tabs
Speaker 4:  take to open as we do. And maybe they should and I think they arguably should.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 3:  For $1,100, I'm just gonna throw back your vision pro
Speaker 3:  criticism for $1,100 being like this computer is
Speaker 3:  a little slow when it's the fastest computer,
Speaker 4:  But it's not slow. It's not
Speaker 3:  Slow. That swap is immediately noticeable. So the argument, the pro
Speaker 4:  I agree.
Speaker 3:  Eight gig argument. I agree. That is that the SSD is so fast that
Speaker 3:  swapping to and from virtual memory using the state of the art, blah, blah,
Speaker 3:  blah, that apple is state of the, all right,
Speaker 5:  Apple
Speaker 3:  Is imperceptible. This is the argument. This is the
Speaker 4:  Argument. And on the new one, apparently the storage is much faster. So that
Speaker 4:  argument might be closer to true.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The argument is wrong.
Speaker 3:  Like the storage is still slower than the ram. It might be very fast, but
Speaker 3:  it's still slower than the ram. And so when you hit the swap, which you can
Speaker 3:  do really easily and I'm macare, they gave Ram
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna bet I'm swapped right now. Let's see.
Speaker 3:  What do you, what do you, what do you do to,
Speaker 5:  He's going into the activity monitor. Oh yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. I didn't know If. you had some like weird utility. David
Speaker 3:  is the proprietor of installer. I hit the swap often has weird utilities.
Speaker 3:  I do have
Speaker 4:  Weird utilities, but I have hit the swap. Yeah. How do,
Speaker 3:  How do you usually it just happens. Hit
Speaker 4:  If. you go to memory, it'll tell you down at the bottom. Oh, swap used.
Speaker 4:  Sorry, keep going. Sorry.
Speaker 3:  Some riveting radio program, open activity monitor
Speaker 3:  and click on memory.
Speaker 5:  It's a how to.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. All I'm saying is that's the argument. And I, at
Speaker 3:  this point in 2024,
Speaker 3:  not a good argument. They should just bump you up to 16 gigs of RAM
Speaker 3:  at standard. And then I think this computer would be amazing.
Speaker 4:  I I do agree with that. I think, I think it would be better if everybody
Speaker 4:  had 16 gigs of ram. I think it's absurd that Apple charges $200
Speaker 4:  to go from eight to 16 when that RAM doesn't cost anywhere near
Speaker 4:  $200.
Speaker 5:  The most enduring scam
Speaker 4:  Apple. Oh yeah. I mean the
Speaker 3:  Margins and it's, and it soldered in so you can't even upgrade it later.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because used to the, the heck was you'd buy it with the garbage ramp
Speaker 5:  and then you just upgrade it as soon as you got
Speaker 3:  It. Yeah. You do the thing where you lift it up the keyboard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And just, and you're done. And now they're like, no, you'll pay us
Speaker 5:  $200 or swap and suffer.
Speaker 3:  Anyhow, all I'm saying is great computer. It, it's like the base
Speaker 3:  storage of the iPhone or the base storage of iCloud. I was like, how much
Speaker 3:  is just enough to annoy you into paying us more.
Speaker 4:  Oh no, that's real. But how much, when was it that
Speaker 4:  you switched your family to Chromebooks?
Speaker 3:  Ages ago.
Speaker 4:  How is that going?
Speaker 3:  Fine. Because I, 'cause I bought, well I
Speaker 4:  Bought You got a lot of 16 gig of RAM Chromebooks running out there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I bought, so it's only one Chromebook. Okay. It was the Google, what
Speaker 3:  was the fanciest one? The thousand pixel dollars? The, no, it was before
Speaker 3:  the,
Speaker 4:  Well there was the Chromebook pixel. That was the the sick one.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm literally Googling bought my mom a Chromebook because I might be
Speaker 3:  the only, hold on, hold on. Lemme just get that right. No, I bought
Speaker 3:  our Chromebook pixel in 2016. Okay. It was,
Speaker 3:  it was a thousand dollars. It has a core I
Speaker 3:  seven and like 16 gigs of ram and it is just, do you really
Speaker 3:  rocking Wow. Because it was so overpowered. Yeah. For its time.
Speaker 3:  Now it's a little underpowered to run Chrome. My 2015 IMAX
Speaker 3:  is such
Speaker 4:  A damning critique of Chrome.
Speaker 3:  It's not great that an I
Speaker 4:  Seven and 16 gigs of ram like barely keep up anymore.
Speaker 3:  My 2015 iMac, which is done now. Oh it's over.
Speaker 3:  Whoa. Wow. It's like the fans are just like on all the time. But it lasted
Speaker 3:  as long as it did almost 10 years. 32 gigs of ram.
Speaker 3:  That's if I have one piece of advice for buying a Mac, which is loaded
Speaker 3:  up, especially 'cause it's soldered in loaded up with RAM at the beginning
Speaker 3:  because you can't fix it. You can't upgrade it. Everything else
Speaker 3:  you'll be fine. Like over time.
Speaker 4:  I do agree with that. I also think 256 gigs of storage, unless you do a lot
Speaker 4:  of media, like if you're If, you just take photos on your phone and
Speaker 4:  upload them to Google Photos and that's your photo strategy. 256 gigs is
Speaker 4:  plenty.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I, I disagree there. I
Speaker 4:  Know you do.
Speaker 5:  Well and then I'm saying this as someone who has a server at home to
Speaker 5:  offload all my big files.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like a super normal workflow for regular people that everybody does
Speaker 4:  at. But
Speaker 5:  Even with that, I'm hitting that 2 56. Like the, the laptop I bought now
Speaker 5:  has five 12. 'cause I was tired of hitting the 2 56 and being like, oh, I
Speaker 5:  have to go delete this game that I play two times a year, but I really wanna
Speaker 5:  have access
Speaker 4:  To it. What's using up all your storage?
Speaker 5:  It it's games.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I mean fair then I, I'll add that to media. That's totally fair. Games
Speaker 4:  are enormous. They're so you download two games now and you've eaten 2 56.
Speaker 4:  But absent those two things, there's very
Speaker 4:  little you're gonna do that's going to take up that much storage.
Speaker 5:  That's true. My mom has like a hundred
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Billion
Speaker 5:  Gigabytes.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. Yeah. And 256 literally, unless you do media, which
Speaker 4:  is huge. And especially now like good God, every photo off the iPhone is
Speaker 4:  enormous now. So like get as much as you can if that's a thing that you care
Speaker 4:  about and you're gonna like be in Lightroom doing stuff, which is another
Speaker 4:  case to get more ram. But if you're just, I firmly
Speaker 4:  believe that most people buy laptops download a web browser and that the
Speaker 4:  end, that is, that is 98% of most people's laptop
Speaker 4:  experience now and like maybe office. And for that the
Speaker 4:  base config is fine. I so firmly believe that.
Speaker 3:  I think you should spend at least 14.99 on the one of 16 gigs of Ram and
Speaker 3:  512 gigs of
Speaker 4:  Storage. And then at that point, why not get the 15 inch? Yeah. Because
Speaker 4:  then there's a, there's a pro
Speaker 5:  I'll sell you and then Yeah. And then you're just at a 14 pro and you're
Speaker 5:  like, you have the 14 pro. Why? Actually
Speaker 3:  I thought the biggest takeaway from Joanna's review is that the M two is
Speaker 3:  still for sale. Yeah. And that's a pretty good deal. If, you can spec it
Speaker 3:  up. Which
Speaker 4:  Is funny 'cause this was also in a lot of ways the story of the M two review
Speaker 4:  was that the M1 is still for sale. Yeah. And now, I mean you can buy
Speaker 4:  the M1 at Walmart for, what is it, like 699 bucks?
Speaker 3:  Did we ever, so this hit while I was on vacation. Yeah. And there was like
Speaker 3:  a furious amount of like conversation about whether Walmart was blowing out
Speaker 3:  old stock or whether Apple was gonna make more M ones and if
Speaker 3:  they, they're gonna make more M ones. Yes.
Speaker 4:  That seems seems to be. I don't know that we've ever actually had that officially
Speaker 4:  confirmed, but that that is Yeah. It's, it's every bit of evidence we have
Speaker 4:  suggests that that is the case.
Speaker 5:  Unclear. It seems like it's gonna be going for a while. And it's not necessarily
Speaker 5:  like they're making more M ones, they just have a
Speaker 5:  ton of stock.
Speaker 4:  No, they don't. That's not how Apple works. Literally. Apple pioneered the
Speaker 4:  idea of not having warehouses. No,
Speaker 5:  No. I mean they have, they have like, they have tons of extra stuff around.
Speaker 5:  That's how we got the iPhone se The iPhone SE came because they had a
Speaker 5:  ton of the, of the, the cases. Right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, sure. Having, having parts that they're very good at making very cheaply.
Speaker 4:  So If you
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yeah. Like, like they, they had a ton of those MacBook air,
Speaker 5:  original MacBook air casings. Right.
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook is like, what are you doing guys? I'm the supply chain guy. Show
Speaker 3:  some N ones,
Speaker 5:  Shove some N ones in them. Send them to Walmart. Send them
Speaker 3:  To Walmart. I think they're still making them. I think they, they've, they've
Speaker 3:  projected out their demand and they're still making them. We have that quote
Speaker 3:  from Walmart in one of our stories where the Walmart guy is like, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  have these for as long as people want them. Yeah. Which has to be,
Speaker 5:  I think it's a huge warehouse like Steven Spielberg style warehouse.
Speaker 5:  And Tim, Tim doesn't like to think about it. You don't bring it up around
Speaker 5:  Tim, but Walmart, Walmart's like, we'll, we'll take care of this for you
Speaker 5:  Tim.
Speaker 6:  Reminder that Apple made the 13 inch Macbook Pro with
Speaker 6:  optical drive for five or six years after
Speaker 6:  they stopped selling
Speaker 4:  It. Liam gets it.
Speaker 5:  Oh, thank you Liam.
Speaker 4:  Wow. Yeah. No, this is, I, what I think is true is I think it's less that
Speaker 4:  Apple has a warehouse full of them somewhere and more that Apple with
Speaker 4:  that wedge design in particular is now at like unbelievable
Speaker 4:  economies of scale. Yeah, that's right. And to just throw that away, like
Speaker 4:  to get rid of all the tooling that's really expensive and the processes that
Speaker 4:  you spin up to do this stuff. Like there is a group of people who
Speaker 4:  want those and will pay that price. And what I think is most surprising is
Speaker 4:  not that these still exist in that Apple would keep making them, but that
Speaker 4:  Apple is interested in selling a $700 laptop at Walmart.
Speaker 4:  Like to me that's a much bigger change than anything else going on here.
Speaker 4:  It's just this is not a thing Apple has ever done before. And it's
Speaker 4:  like, it, there's a world in which you would argue it feels
Speaker 4:  like a company running scared, trying to make money wherever
Speaker 4:  they can. You mean I don't really think it's that, but it is a definite
Speaker 4:  like, strategy change in a way that I think has not been
Speaker 5:  Well Yeah, because talked about, because Walmart is very focused on luxury.
Speaker 5:  Like their, their whole thing is luxury and not Walmart. You take that back.
Speaker 5:  Walmart
Speaker 4:  Very confused, very focused.
Speaker 5:  Lemme lemme read it out. Well I think about Walmart. That's what I think
Speaker 5:  of too. I Yeah, yeah. That, that, that's all switched up. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  like Apple is very well known for being all about luxury.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Walmart less so
Speaker 4:  Le Yeah. Yeah. They just do different jobs. And like if, if Apple
Speaker 4:  wanted to figure out how to sell the best $500 computer,
Speaker 4:  it probably could have, it probably could have done that. 35 years ago
Speaker 3:  They put that computer in Walmart. It was called the iPad. It has been in
Speaker 3:  the Walmart the entire time. Yeah. My two year, you
Speaker 3:  know, in the Woods experience, whole Walmart was the only store I spent a
Speaker 3:  lot of time contemplating what electronic products are in Walmart, in
Speaker 3:  Catskill, New York.
Speaker 3:  It's iPhones. All the iPhones including the pros. And it was
Speaker 3:  iPads and then they just didn't put the Macs in there. And now they have
Speaker 3:  one Mac. And I think the iPad Mac a $700
Speaker 3:  M1 MacBook air, a wedge design and whatever
Speaker 3:  iPads you can get at Walmart Apple's just like, they, you want the laptops
Speaker 3:  like, let's be honest about what people wanna buy here. Yeah. They want laptops.
Speaker 3:  People
Speaker 4:  Are gonna go in looking for an M1 MacBook error and there's gonna be a, a
Speaker 4:  sales person who's like, wouldn't you rather have an a
Speaker 4:  12.9 inch iPad Pro with a magic keyboard and an Apple pencil that's
Speaker 4:  $1,400 all in and somebody's gonna leave with just like a bag full of
Speaker 4:  nonsense. And they're like, I just wanted a laptop,
Speaker 5:  But not at Walmart. There wouldn't be a sales person at Walmart. That's
Speaker 3:  True. It was, it was. Look, I did a lot of shopping at Walmart in the, in
Speaker 3:  my two years of Pandemic Woods living. There was not a
Speaker 3:  lot of salespeople around. It was not a thing. But all I'm saying is to,
Speaker 3:  to connect the dots between the two of you. Yeah. The Apple
Speaker 3:  running scared, maybe less scared. Apple
Speaker 3:  finding every dollar it can find right now. Yeah. And just
Speaker 3:  squeezing is weird. This is the company that gets rid of its old
Speaker 3:  products. Yeah. Like this is the company that's like, we are gonna cannibalize
Speaker 3:  ourselves and now they're selling three generations of the same laptop.
Speaker 3:  We It's weird.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's very different. And it, it changed kind of
Speaker 4:  quietly without Yeah. Like they, they they did. Nobody made any noise about
Speaker 4:  it. But now you look and it's like, it it operates like a very different
Speaker 4:  company than it did even just a few years ago.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I could probably put killing the extraordinarily wasteful and stupid
Speaker 3:  car project. Yeah. This like the pressure on the
Speaker 3:  app store, the anger around the app store antitrust stuff
Speaker 3:  and the we're gonna sell more products at more price points than ever. Like
Speaker 3:  all in a line. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. They, they, they saw that like, money is not infinite.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which it, it is for them. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Historically it has been. Yes.
Speaker 3:  But it's just weird. It's just like a weird moment for that company. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then there was that, I think it was a Reuters story this week that Apple
Speaker 4:  is now working on personal robots. Oh yeah. I was like, okay guys,
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  That'll go good.
Speaker 5:  We'll see 'em when we see
Speaker 3:  'em. We should mention, by the way, as long as we're talking about Apple,
Speaker 3:  they rolled out personas that just like float around with you this week.
Speaker 3:  Haunting in the Vision Pro. We should watch the video at the videos on
Speaker 3:  our various video platforms. It's like Wes and V
Speaker 3:  and Terrible. They just don't seem happy with each other. I gotta be honest
Speaker 3:  with it. I have not wanted to put the Vision Pro back on since I
Speaker 3:  handed our review interview.
Speaker 5:  I was talking to Wes earlier and he was like, I gotta go FaceTime some friends
Speaker 5:  and troll. I'm really good. I'll talk to you later. And I was like, good.
Speaker 5:  Good. Thanks.
Speaker 4:  That feels like the right use of the Vision Pro.
Speaker 5:  That that is the best use.
Speaker 4:  That's a strong use of $3,500. Yeah. Seven outta 10.
Speaker 3:  Alright. Speaking of amazing gadgets, Cranz, you've got one here. Yeah. For
Speaker 3:  opening lightning round.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God. So Chris Welch, if If you, most of you are not in
Speaker 5:  in The Verge office, so you don't get to see Chris as often as than I, as
Speaker 5:  as often as I do. But he's had this suitcase
Speaker 5:  at his desk for a while now. And, and the suitcase, I'd always be like, what
Speaker 5:  is that? He'd be like, it's it's, it's a tv.
Speaker 4:  He'd be like, don't ask about the suitcase. Don't
Speaker 5:  Ask about the suitcase. And he finally reviewed the suitcase. And what I
Speaker 5:  quickly learned was that everyone has been seeing this LG suitcase
Speaker 5:  TV on TikTok. And so a lot of people
Speaker 5:  are like, oh, oh, Chris finally said it's pretty okay. It's time to get it.
Speaker 5:  But really, but I wanna, I wanna be clear, you probably don't need the
Speaker 5:  $1,200 10 80 p
Speaker 3:  No.
Speaker 5:  27 inch TV in a, in a suitcase. It's cool as
Speaker 5:  hell though.
Speaker 3:  It is very cool.
Speaker 5:  It just like, it hits like, like he, he talked about in, in his review it
Speaker 5:  just hits that gadget spot where you just like, yeah. Want this.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's foldy and cliquey and it's a little outlandish. It's a touchscreen
Speaker 3:  for no reason. I sat on the floor and played solitaire for like 25 minutes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It, you just can do that. 'cause it's, it's fun. Yeah. And I just
Speaker 5:  really, really enjoy the thing. And I think it needs, no, it doesn't need
Speaker 5:  to exist in the world. But also I'm like, well maybe I do need one for my
Speaker 5:  bedroom. 'cause I can't figure out where to put a tv. Maybe I just have a
Speaker 3:  In a suitcase.
Speaker 5:  In a little suitcase.
Speaker 3:  The answer's a
Speaker 5:  Suitcase on my bed. Hmm. That'll go
Speaker 3:  Well, you know, you need a ceiling projector.
Speaker 5:  There's a fan up there.
Speaker 3:  Get rid of the fan I saw at, at CES Of course. In some like
Speaker 3:  random booth, like a combo platter, light fan projector. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh well there we go. Then I'm done. That's what I'm gonna get.
Speaker 3:  It's good. And obviously when you turn the fan on the whole thing by slightly
Speaker 3:  it's very good. Very good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What I can't decide about this TV is whether I want it to be much better
Speaker 4:  or much cheaper.
Speaker 5:  That that
Speaker 4:  Was. Because part of me is like, give me the 10 80 piece screen. Give me
Speaker 4:  27 inches, make it 500 bucks. And like, will I buy
Speaker 4:  this thing and take it on vacation with me three times a year? Like Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I probably would. Or am I like I this becomes,
Speaker 4:  you know, the the like basement TV for all intents and purposes
Speaker 4:  and I want it to be better than this. And I'm so torn between those two things
Speaker 4:  because $1,200 for what this thing actually is,
Speaker 4:  is too much. It's
Speaker 5:  Ludicrous.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Both of you have now described wanting this TV to keep it stationary
Speaker 3:  in a room. You're like the basement tv just like buy a TV
Speaker 3:  dude. No, because it
Speaker 5:  Doesn't turn into a
Speaker 3:  Suitcase. Just like buy a tv. Yeah. But why the purpose of a suitcase
Speaker 3:  is that you take it with you.
Speaker 4:  It's my vacation tv. I will say the thing where they're like,
Speaker 4:  put it in the bed of your truck and watch TV is like
Speaker 3:  The dream.
Speaker 4:  It is the dream. It is also just the most specific use case. It's
Speaker 4:  like, I'm going to tailgate with this thing six times a week
Speaker 4:  and it's gonna
Speaker 3:  Be worth it.
Speaker 4:  Like If, you are a season ticket holder to something. Yeah. Yeah. Buy this
Speaker 4:  television. Like that's, that's where I'm at. It
Speaker 3:  Is true. Chris's basic point was like, we need more gadgets again. Which
Speaker 3:  is
Speaker 4:  Absolutely direct
Speaker 3:  Pull on my heartstrings. Well it is. It do I think it should be cheaper?
Speaker 3:  I don't think it should be better. I think it should be cheaper. He,
Speaker 5:  He made a good point that he understood why it was so expensive because it
Speaker 5:  is such a niche product and he's like, if they made it better then it would
Speaker 5:  just be more expensive. $1,200 is also expensive. But like,
Speaker 5:  I don't, I don't know if I fully buy it, but
Speaker 3:  I actually don't buy that at all. Like, you don't, LG can make a good TV
Speaker 3:  for virtually no money. Right. All they've really done here is buy a suitcase.
Speaker 5:  They they put it in a six suitcase.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It really is just a TV and a hinge. Yeah. Like it's not
Speaker 5:  Particularly, but you can, you can plug stuff into it.
Speaker 4:  You can plug stuff,
Speaker 5:  You can play your switch on it. It's, it's got a touch screen so you can,
Speaker 5:  like, you play
Speaker 3:  Solitaire, you buy, you should buy one. There's just something. Buy one right
Speaker 4:  Now. David, there's just something about this one picture in the review where
Speaker 4:  the, the TV is on a couch and it's, it's folded up. The suitcase
Speaker 4:  is open, it's flat and there's two people on either side of it playing
Speaker 4:  chess. And this picture is both like truly
Speaker 4:  absurd because I cannot imagine regular people ever actually doing this
Speaker 4:  and also makes me want it so bad.
Speaker 5:  And you can see that that that that whole conflict in their faces too
Speaker 5:  in the photo.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're kind of like, what is this bad chess app that I'm playing with
Speaker 4:  this enormous television but
Speaker 5:  I'm also having a good time. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Who doesn't have a good time playing Web os? Chess on Suitcase tv.
Speaker 3:  Alright. Speaking of gadgets, my lightning round is the yearly printer
Speaker 3:  review was published.
Speaker 4:  It's big day for you.
Speaker 3:  Big day for me. This
Speaker 4:  Is what I assume you did on vacation the whole time. It was just plan your
Speaker 4:  epic comeback with the printer.
Speaker 3:  So If, you don't know something is happening to Google search right
Speaker 3:  now where various websites,
Speaker 3:  the traffic is declining because Google changed the algorithm
Speaker 3:  and some of them are, we did a decoder with Mia about one of them. House
Speaker 3:  Fresh, the air purifier blog. There's a retro gaming site who's a
Speaker 3:  editor in chief or owner or someone who's complaining on Twitter. Their traffic
Speaker 3:  is, and then a bunch of like content farms. Right. Also.
Speaker 4:  And the idea is to kill the content farms. Yeah. But it it, they are
Speaker 4:  catching some of the good carrying sites.
Speaker 5:  A lot of people catching the strays on this one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's something like the internet as we know it. I believe
Speaker 3:  this to be true. The internet as we know it is about to fall apart.
Speaker 4:  Oh I really agree with that. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Something weird is happening on the internet out there. So my
Speaker 3:  contribution to that is to make stories
Speaker 3:  that pointed out
Speaker 3:  by using the form of the stories, the content farms.
Speaker 4:  It's a very Meta art project. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think The Verge should be an art project. So the answer to the question,
Speaker 3:  what is the Best printer has been unchanging for a decade, which is the cheapest
Speaker 3:  brother laser printer you can find. Yep. But
Speaker 3:  that is like Google cannot accept that as an answer because it's not
Speaker 3:  new enough. 'cause there's not enough shopping links because the
Speaker 3:  data isn't semantic enough. How
Speaker 5:  Many H twos you got in that, that piece?
Speaker 3:  I have one.
Speaker 5:  Gotta have it. And
Speaker 3:  It's just, just me pointing out that lms dunno the answer to the question
Speaker 3:  yet. Anyway. So I wrote the piece once again. We have sold
Speaker 3:  like 2000 printers.
Speaker 4:  It's amazing.
Speaker 3:  Which is just like the funniest part of this whole thing. It's
Speaker 4:  Like's the favorite
Speaker 3:  Part. It's easily, the funniest part of this whole thing is like, what should
Speaker 3:  this actually look like? It should just be like, just buy this one and shut
Speaker 3:  up. Like that's all anyone wants on the internet when they're looking for
Speaker 3:  product advice. And
Speaker 5:  Google's like, no,
Speaker 3:  And Google won't do it. You have to update the page. So you look at the internet
Speaker 3:  and you're like, you type in Best printer and all the top results are like
Speaker 3:  updated last week to point out that a a
Speaker 3:  bad product is the new winner. Or like they, we like, we changed our
Speaker 3:  methodology. And you look at the number of sites that one
Speaker 3:  claim to have reviewed every printer and then claim
Speaker 3:  to have updated those printer reviews yesterday and then also get the
Speaker 3:  answer like
Speaker 5:  Updating it on January 1st, 2024. So that you to say
Speaker 5:  they've updated it in
Speaker 4:  January 1st, 2024. Yeah. 2024.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's cool. It is. So my, my big edit to you in this story was to add a bunch
Speaker 4:  of links to the kinds of things you're talking about. And some of it is is
Speaker 4:  just truly wild. And it's like, I feel like everybody has seen these at some
Speaker 4:  point, right? That you Google one of these and you go onto some site you've
Speaker 4:  never heard of and it's basically just like a product name. People on Amazon
Speaker 4:  like it, here's what they say. Copy and paste a bunch of Amazon results and,
Speaker 4:  and call it a day. But the like, one of them is on
Speaker 4:  people.com, the eight best home printers of 2024 tested and reviewed.
Speaker 4:  Like nothing against, I have not even read this piece, I don't know, but
Speaker 4:  what in the world is People magazine doing caring about printers? Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  how is this what the internet has become?
Speaker 5:  That's how they print the magazine out.
Speaker 3:  It's like CBS news I think was my favorite one. And then I realized
Speaker 3:  like the demographic of CBS news might be looking for printers. I
Speaker 3:  don't know the answer to that question. It's, it's just a very odd that If
Speaker 3:  you like, look at the architecture of our internet. A lot of people are like
Speaker 3:  affiliate weird affiliate clicks will pay for everything.
Speaker 3:  And then you just look at what that means in practice, which is trying to
Speaker 3:  game Google search to get those affiliate clicks and that we're in
Speaker 3:  the death spiral. Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and one of the things Google has been trying to take away recently
Speaker 4:  is sites that not only do that but try to hide it that all have a sort of
Speaker 4:  sneaky navigational part of their site that's not in the nav.
Speaker 4:  They never put it on the homepage. You can never find it. It's like parts
Speaker 4:  of these websites exist exclusively for Google. It's not just stuff that
Speaker 4:  is like made because you see it on Google Trends, which a lot of people do.
Speaker 4:  And that's like, that's a thing we think about. It's a thing everybody thinks
Speaker 4:  about. Like knowing what people wanna know is fine. But like when you go
Speaker 4:  to this deep, deep hole of like, we are going to actively wall
Speaker 4:  this off from the rest of our site so that the people who come here on purpose
Speaker 4:  never even find it. Yeah. It's like that's tough. And that is, that is now
Speaker 4:  a game. A lot of people feel like they have to play
Speaker 5:  People doesn't you? You can find it on the people page. Yeah. People, I just
Speaker 5:  had to go check
Speaker 4:  People's like, what's up guys? We love printers.
Speaker 5:  No, they also love what's
Speaker 4:  Ryan Reynolds up to? Printers,
Speaker 5:  Pool cleaners.
Speaker 4:  Sure. That's
Speaker 5:  Sh and Dandruff shampoo.
Speaker 4:  That's, this is the stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's just very odd. It's a very odd moment on the internet. I like
Speaker 3:  fully believe
Speaker 3:  that this is not sustainable like in any way, shape or form. I give it a
Speaker 3:  year before like the Google fight Internet
Speaker 3:  turns into whatever the next thing's gonna be.
Speaker 4:  I think that's probably right. There was a really interesting, the folks
Speaker 4:  at 4 0 4 Media the other day wrote about a search engine called Coy, which
Speaker 4:  is the one I've used and been talking about for a while. And I just like
Speaker 4:  posted about it and was like, oh yeah, this is good. I've been using it for
Speaker 4:  a while. This is a good story. They were talking about how much better it
Speaker 4:  is than Google and shocked at the number of people I got who were like,
Speaker 4:  I'm done with Google, I'm out. I'm over it. I've moved on. I finally switched.
Speaker 4:  And I feel like Google has had this sort of like inevitability for so
Speaker 4:  long that I just feel starting to crack in a lot of ways. Yeah. Like I think
Speaker 4:  there is this sense that Google is not the
Speaker 4:  only option anymore. And I think AI has kind of undone that in people's
Speaker 4:  brains, even though AI is not actually that good at a lot of search things.
Speaker 4:  But it does, it feels like Google being sort of too
Speaker 4:  Google to fail feels like it's slipping. What was the most in a really interesting
Speaker 4:  way,
Speaker 5:  Recent like search you went to do and Google
Speaker 5:  just totally failed you.
Speaker 4:  I haven't used Google in a while, if I'm being honest. Okay.
Speaker 5:  What
Speaker 4:  About
Speaker 5:  IUII still use it and I still am like, wow, it sucks every day that I don't
Speaker 5:  change
Speaker 3:  My behavior. So it's not a straight Google search. But I actually haven't
Speaker 3:  answered this question 'cause I I've been thinking about it ever since this
Speaker 3:  happened. Yeah. I have a Google, I don't even know what they call them anymore.
Speaker 3:  A net a go. you know, a circle that runs Google Assistant in my bathroom,
Speaker 3:  A Nest hub. What are they called now? Sure, sure. Have they killed Nest yet?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. A Google home. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's it's one of those,
Speaker 3:  You know, a circle? Yeah. Like a fabric circle with a microphone in it. Google
Speaker 3:  Circle. A Google thing.
Speaker 3:  I should know the name of this product. Is it the little
Speaker 4:  Guy? Is
Speaker 3:  It the Home Mini? It's it's a nest tub. Yeah, it's a home mini. Okay. Is
Speaker 3:  that what it is?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  A circle. The
Speaker 4:  Little the little guy. Yeah. With the big hockey puck kind.
Speaker 3:  I highly recommend putting one of those in your bathroom. They're very useful
Speaker 3:  in there. And I, you know, I sometimes I have to play a podcast in
Speaker 3:  the morning. Sometimes I just have it set a time like all this stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I asked it how long it would take to drive to the airport
Speaker 3:  and first it answered and with a number of miles
Speaker 3:  and then it said I can't. And I said, well, well how many minutes will that
Speaker 3:  take? And it just couldn't. And then it sent me some, some stuff on the web
Speaker 3:  and I was like, all of this ai, like all of this
Speaker 3:  AI and Google maps. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like you have that, you have there,
Speaker 5:  All of the skills are
Speaker 3:  Right there. If I just ask Google Maps this question, it would immediately
Speaker 3:  deliver me that answer and you can't. And it's like, well we
Speaker 3:  just didn't close the loop. Yep. And that to me, I was like, oh, I should
Speaker 3:  have just tried something. Anything else would've been fine. And I, I think
Speaker 3:  that that's like the Google loop closing. Hopefully they get
Speaker 3:  better at it. It's like they've had a long time. You wrote about this this
Speaker 3:  week.
Speaker 4:  We're we're gonna get to that, don't you worry.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, that, that's the last one that really failed for me. And I was
Speaker 3:  just like, how is it possible? Like even if at this point if Gemini had
Speaker 3:  just lied to me Yeah. And in like 45 minutes. I don't know. That's prior.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's seems right. Yeah, sure. Right. That feels right. Yeah. About
Speaker 3:  45 minutes. Yeah. Yeah. Like it would've been better than just like, I don't
Speaker 3:  know.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Like there's nothing less useful than asking a robot how far away
Speaker 3:  something is and it's like 25 miles and it's like, cool. Okay, what does
Speaker 3:  that mean to me at this point in
Speaker 4:  Time? Should I run?
Speaker 3:  Like,
Speaker 4:  What's the plan here?
Speaker 5:  Just hustling.
Speaker 3:  What's your last one at Google Field, don't you?
Speaker 5:  Yesterday I was trying to decide, I asked it
Speaker 5:  should I get an impact driver if I already have a regular like power?
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's impossible. That's like too hard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it was too hard for it. It was like, no. And I was like, what power
Speaker 5:  tools should I get? And it was like, here's all the power tools for carpentry.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, I didn't, I just wanted to know what power tools should,
Speaker 5:  like a nerd who wants more power tools get you failed me. I got really
Speaker 5:  upset.
Speaker 3:  That's a really hard,
Speaker 5:  A hard, I went
Speaker 3:  Too hard. Maybe you really, you've opened like that's a Pandora's Box question.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like I have seen videos of people arguing that,
Speaker 3:  that the housing crisis caused people to switch from standard drills to impacts.
Speaker 3:  'cause all the people with experience building houses got forced outta the
Speaker 3:  market and the kids didn't know what they were doing. Like you're touching
Speaker 3:  on a third rail of power tools to that question. It's like somewhere a data
Speaker 3:  center exploded because you ask Google that question.
Speaker 5:  I went like, I had to go like a couple of links in just, I was like, I need
Speaker 5:  something that's not people trying to sell me power tools. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 5:  eventually I got like some people debating impact drivers and they're like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, If, you, you got a lot of sheet rock you got or not sheet rock. You
Speaker 5:  got a lot of drywall, you gotta get up. You get that impact driver change
Speaker 5:  your life. And I was like, well I don't have that.
Speaker 3:  Our publisher Chris Grant is about to run in here. He If you are just generally
Speaker 3:  talking about power tools. He's gonna, he's gonna go crazy. Kick the door
Speaker 5:  Open.
Speaker 3:  Well, I was just saying, but this is my, my prediction a year from now
Speaker 3:  market what, what day is it? April 4th Market a year from now.
Speaker 3:  Whatever Google is today will look radically different.
Speaker 5:  Hey Siri,
Speaker 4:  I No, I agree. And I think, I think Google knows that too. Yeah. I'm not
Speaker 4:  sure they know what to do about it. Do you see the, I don't know if it was
Speaker 4:  a rumor or a report, but there was, I just saw, 'cause some something go
Speaker 4:  by basically saying that Google is now considering charging for its
Speaker 4:  AI stuff, which I find totally fascinating. Like the, the actual
Speaker 4:  AI search stuff would be a paid thing instead of a free thing. Messy and
Speaker 4:  complicated. But like you get the sense Google knows it can't be
Speaker 4:  like this for much longer and it's flailing in a bunch of directions trying
Speaker 4:  to fix it. But I think it seems like the internet is getting crazy
Speaker 4:  faster than Google is getting good at doing things about
Speaker 5:  The solution. They just need to sell some shit in Walmart.
Speaker 5:  Knock $200 off. Sell it in Walmart. You'll be fine. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Some other AI stuff for lightning round. Microsoft is working
Speaker 3:  at Xbox ai chatbot a scoop from Tom Warren.
Speaker 5:  It's just clippy for Xbox
Speaker 4:  And he's right that it needs to be called Xbo. I just thought
Speaker 3:  That it does need to be called X Bot. That is correct. The we Microsoft confirmed
Speaker 3:  it. We are testing an Xbox support virtual agent. An internal
Speaker 3:  prototype of an animated character that can query Xbox support topics
Speaker 3:  with voice or text. This is the general manager of gaming AI at Xbox.
Speaker 3:  The prototype makes it easier and quicker for players to get help with support
Speaker 3:  topics using natural language taking. It's like, this is great, this is
Speaker 3:  cool, but like, how many people are on the daily just like
Speaker 3:  asking Xbox support for help.
Speaker 4:  Why did I lose it? fifa. No, I, the, I mean
Speaker 4:  customer support AI is like,
Speaker 3:  It's common
Speaker 4:  Done. Like that's, that is good or bad. That is The future of everything,
Speaker 4:  right? Like all the, the robot phone trees are gonna be replaced by
Speaker 4:  chatbots. And that's just where we're headed. And that's kinda what this
Speaker 4:  sounds like. I think there is possibly more Xbox could do here,
Speaker 4:  but Yeah. So it's somewhere. It just sounds like it's gonna be an adorable
Speaker 4:  little customer service guy.
Speaker 5:  No way. I, I love this idea of it killing phone crees though. Like if
Speaker 5:  AI kills the phone, Cree, oh my God.
Speaker 4:  Oh that's coming. I really, I That's hard to hear.
Speaker 5:  It's game changed. Changed.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it just, frankly like just online chat,
Speaker 4:  customer service over having to call and wait for a human was delightful.
Speaker 4:  Now all of that is just being replaced by AI bots who are like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  helpful. And my favorite thing is the people who go on to those
Speaker 4:  things. Like the people who went to the car rental company and asked it to
Speaker 4:  like do all kinds of weird stuff. Like this stuff is gonna get bad and crazy
Speaker 4:  and weird. But that is, I think at this moment probably the most
Speaker 4:  slam dunk Yeah. Business use case for all of this. It is just
Speaker 4:  going to eat the customer service industry.
Speaker 3:  Right. 'cause all of, I mean, working customer support is not fun.
Speaker 3:  You are mostly reading scripts of people. Yeah. Just have a robot read the
Speaker 3:  script. Yeah. I just wanna know how they will all respond to me just mashing
Speaker 3:  the zero button over and over
Speaker 5:  Again,
Speaker 3:  Which is all
Speaker 4:  Representative, human
Speaker 3:  Representative.
Speaker 3:  No, thank you. I feel like I never call a phone tree with a problem.
Speaker 3:  The phone tree is designed to solve. Never. It's like I don't need to check
Speaker 3:  my balance. Like I can definitely do that on my phone. Yeah. you know, it's
Speaker 3:  like I need to do something hard.
Speaker 5:  Who calls to check their balance still. Like why are they offering that still?
Speaker 5:  Because I, I've noticed that too. I called the bank and they're like, do
Speaker 5:  you wanna check your balance? I'm like, no, no. I'm, I'm looking at the app
Speaker 5:  right now that told me to call you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm gonna start calling to check my balance. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  How am I doing?
Speaker 3:  What's up? Like I gotta talk to somebody.
Speaker 3:  Samsung says Bixby is not dead.
Speaker 3:  Which is an incredible thing to say.
Speaker 3:  Like, because it implies that Bick, everyone thinks
Speaker 3:  Bixby is dead.
Speaker 4:  Right. My T-shirt that says no Bixby is not dead is causing a lot of
Speaker 4:  questions.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. A Samsung executive tells CNBC that the company is quote, working
Speaker 3:  so hard
Speaker 3:  to put AI features in Bixby, even though they just did a big deal with Google
Speaker 3:  and Gemini is now all over the phone and the phones are running. Gemini.
Speaker 3:  Mini Gemini Nano. I'm not great at Google product
Speaker 3:  names today. Google don't either. Vacation, you know,
Speaker 3:  there was a big awards banquet this week. The awards I drank
Speaker 3:  a lot at them. Just like Google stuff. Google Circle,
Speaker 3:  Gemini. Tiny. That's yeah, you're doing great. It's
Speaker 5:  Fine.
Speaker 4:  You're as, you're as good as anybody including most of Google's product managers.
Speaker 4:  Like don't
Speaker 3:  Worry about. So If, you'll recall when Bixby was announced dog
Speaker 3:  with shoes. If. you are not caught up on Vergecast lore.
Speaker 3:  Bixby the name sounds like a dog wearing shoes. That's the entire
Speaker 3:  joke.
Speaker 4:  That's it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's a good joke. Like
Speaker 3:  If, you were imagine If, you were to draw a picture of something called Bixby.
Speaker 3:  You would imagine a dog wearing shoes
Speaker 4:  Was a butler too.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like a butler could go put like a, you know. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Dog. Fancy dog. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  People have sent us pictures, cartoons. I encourage you to
Speaker 3:  go ask an image generator to make a Bixby dog wearing shoes and send it to
Speaker 3:  us. Long ears,
Speaker 5:  Short ears.
Speaker 3:  Long long. Yeah, that's what I thought. This is a real floppy dog. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's what I thought saying That's what I thought.
Speaker 3:  Bix Bixby. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  but If, you recall the original Bixby, the idea was that it would not compete
Speaker 3:  with like Google Assistant to do go like web queries. It
Speaker 3:  would change the settings on your phone,
Speaker 4:  Right? It was designed to do stuff, never
Speaker 5:  Did it. You're
Speaker 3:  Like, yeah, never the, it was not a good butler. I mean, it was a dog.
Speaker 5:  Dogs aren't good butlers, what do we think we're doing? Inherently sucking
Speaker 5:  at it.
Speaker 3:  What do we think we're doing here? But now they're saying we're working so
Speaker 3:  hard to make it that. Which is fascinating because they still think
Speaker 3:  that is a thing that people want.
Speaker 4:  I think it is. I think like the idea
Speaker 4:  that I can just yell at my phone to do something
Speaker 4:  like go download the Ticketmaster app. Way
Speaker 4:  better user experience than what it actually currently takes to go download
Speaker 4:  the Ticketmaster app. But it just, NELI has never really worked. But I think
Speaker 4:  we're actually at a point with a lot of this AI stuff where like in that
Speaker 4:  sort of limited scope of like things your phone is capable of doing,
Speaker 4:  have the system connect the dots for you that can work.
Speaker 4:  Like, is, is it easier to say, turn on Bluetooth and look
Speaker 4:  for this weird name of headphones that I have? Is that easier than going
Speaker 4:  into the menu and hitting the thing? Like, probably not. But I think Samsung's
Speaker 4:  idea that this is less about like, getting esoteric philosophical answers
Speaker 4:  about the world and more about just like getting the stuff done that you
Speaker 4:  do on your phone. Well it's, I think is
Speaker 5:  Right. It's what we talked about earlier where it's it's customer support.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. It basically
Speaker 5:  Is. Yeah. It's, it's for people being like, I don't know how to turn Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  on on my phone. How do I do it? Right. And Bixby will appear
Speaker 5:  pan
Speaker 4:  A little. Yeah. Like Bixby, my phone's in Portuguese. Fix that. Perfect.
Speaker 5:  Open a gado. I was
Speaker 3:  Gonna read you a quote from Juan June Choi, executive vice President of Mobile.
Speaker 3:  Mobile at Samsung. I believe we have to redefine the role of
Speaker 3:  Bixby so that Bixby can be equipped with generative ai. To be smarter,
Speaker 3:  you have to redefine Bix B's role. Well, not a butler anymore. Well, Bixby
Speaker 3:  has to roll,
Speaker 4:  Has to have a role.
Speaker 3:  We'll see. But so Bixby exists on all of Samsung's other products. You could
Speaker 3:  see how they build an old ecosystem. I dunno, man, I I,
Speaker 3:  I feel like we're all racing to shove AI into these moments. And I
Speaker 3:  think the phone companies are particularly afraid of the rabbits and the
Speaker 3:  humanes and the blah blah blahs. You wrote a piece about this this week.
Speaker 3:  Like the AI gadgets are coming. Yeah. And I think you mentioned
Speaker 3:  developer conferences. I'm confident we're gonna see a bunch of
Speaker 3:  AI stuff in iOS at wwc. Google obviously at
Speaker 3:  io is gonna talk about it a lot. I can't imagine they, Microsoft
Speaker 3:  will talk about anything else that build and
Speaker 4:  It's like, no, I mean, and the problem is all of these companies, there's
Speaker 4:  basically like two sides of the world at this point, right? There's the companies
Speaker 4:  that have done well in smartphones, which is three companies. It's Apple,
Speaker 4:  it's Google, and it's Samsung. Those companies are desperate to figure out
Speaker 4:  an AI reason for your smartphone so that you will keep using
Speaker 4:  your smartphone. Because what they're afraid of is that this new generation
Speaker 4:  of other companies is gonna come in and they're not going to have solved
Speaker 4:  the whole problem immediately. But they're going to have fixed some part
Speaker 4:  of the user experience that people are like, oh, this is the thing that gets
Speaker 4:  me past my phone. And I think that's what I'm particularly looking
Speaker 4:  for with what Humane is doing and what Rabbit is doing. And companies like
Speaker 4:  Brilliant and even Meta with the smart glasses that are getting the ai, like,
Speaker 4:  can they start to pull pieces of what I do on my phone, out of my phone?
Speaker 4:  And if the answer is yes, that starts to kind of
Speaker 4:  get in the way of this, like essentially three company ownership of the smartphone
Speaker 4:  universe, at least in the us. And so it's not at all an accident that you
Speaker 4:  have Apple with Siri, Google with Gemini, and Samsung
Speaker 4:  with Bixby, like desperately trying to figure out how to make your phone
Speaker 4:  AI inside of the existing structure of phones, which is very hard to
Speaker 4:  do because an AI that can do all the things I want it to do is
Speaker 4:  literally not allowed in the way that phones exist right now. So it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be fascinating. And so Apple is either gonna have to say like, oh, Siri can
Speaker 4:  now go download apps for you and do stuff inside of those apps, and it has
Speaker 4:  weird permission that nothing has ever had before. Or it's going to
Speaker 4:  like protect this crazy revenue stream that is the app store at
Speaker 4:  the risk of losing it all to gadgets that come up with a new way to do it.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be a really fun, like three months. Yeah. Pure chaos. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I'm telling you, a year from now. Yeah, that's my prediction in the, in the
Speaker 3:  spring doldrums. I'm just like a year from now. Whole new internet. Yep.
Speaker 3:  All right. We should take a break. We should come back. We have lightning
Speaker 3:  round part two. Still available to be sponsored. Call now.
Speaker 3:  All right. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Support for this podcast comes from Canva. They say Rome wasn't built
Speaker 1:  in a
Speaker 1:  task at hand with no app switching. Finish your deck faster,
Speaker 1:  generate slides and seconds with Canva. presentations@canva.com. Designed
Speaker 1:  for work.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. Lightning around part two.
Speaker 4:  This one's gonna be fast.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna, David pointed out the first lightning round was almost an hour
Speaker 3:  long. We talked about four things,
Speaker 4:  Classic lightning round.
Speaker 3:  We're just gonna go, we're gonna, this is my plan for this one. I'm just
Speaker 3:  gonna read the headlines. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  And then we're just gonna
Speaker 4:  Alex now, just leave, just, it's fine.
Speaker 3:  John Stewart's back on the Daily Show on, yep. Just on Mondays. I think
Speaker 3:  he did a good segment on AI mostly being fake ads. And then
Speaker 3:  he interviewed Lena Khan and basically
Speaker 3:  accused Apple of censoring his previous show on Apple. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And this isn't the first time he's done that. That's the thing I like, that's
Speaker 5:  what I wanted to talk about on the show, was like, what's going on with
Speaker 5:  Apple and John Stewart? Because he keeps being like, Hey, apple
Speaker 5:  censored me more than once. It wouldn't let me talk about China. It wouldn't
Speaker 5:  let me talk to Lena Khan. Like, it wouldn't let me do stupid
Speaker 5:  pokes at technology. What's going on over at Apple? And that's a bad sign.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Although, what's did Apple think they were buying?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like everyone around that
Speaker 4:  I, I've wondered that too. Like, just don't make a deal with John Stewart.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's fine. It's If you if that's, if that's how you feel, just
Speaker 4:  don't have John Stewart like, I
Speaker 5:  Don't know. Well, that's what they eventually decided. Well, right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But I think about like, there, there was a thing Ryan Johnson said a few
Speaker 4:  years ago about how one of the sneaky things about Apple is they'll never
Speaker 4:  let the bad guy have an iPhone in a movie. You guys heard, you've heard that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. And I, I think about that all the time as just sort
Speaker 4:  of like a silly quirk of Apple, right? And there's a lot of things going
Speaker 4:  on with how distribution works. And there's like, now Tom Cruise can
Speaker 4:  never be fighting an enemy with a name because it gets associated with a
Speaker 4:  country and the movie doesn't play in that country. So like, you can move
Speaker 4:  around inside of this landscape in all kinds of weird ways. This one is just
Speaker 4:  like, it just seems like it was a bad fit from the beginning. And
Speaker 4:  I also, I don't know John Stewart personally, but I get the distinct sense
Speaker 4:  that If, you make John Stewart a list of things he can't do. He's gonna then
Speaker 4:  attempt to go do every single one of them. Yeah. And so I feel like it's
Speaker 4:  almost a miracle that lasted this long with Apple. Yeah. But it was very
Speaker 4:  funny to hear him say to Lena Khan, I wanted to have you on my
Speaker 4:  show. And Apple said,
Speaker 3:  By the way, Lena Khan is the chair of the Federal Trade Commission, right?
Speaker 3:  Yep. She leads a lot of antitrust efforts, federal Trade Commission, not
Speaker 3:  the entity suing Apple for antitrust violations. That's the DOJ.
Speaker 3:  But she's the face of a lot of it.
Speaker 4:  She has a lot of feelings about antitrust in general. Yeah, yeah. A lot of,
Speaker 4:  lot of things. And I,
Speaker 3:  The tech companies all hate her. It's like a real thing. Yeah. But it's like
Speaker 3:  weird. Like I, I come back to this all the time. Same as you Alex, which
Speaker 3:  is like these tech companies, they want, they want to do media,
Speaker 3:  and then they get one slice of what it's actually like to do media,
Speaker 3:  which is just having to be okay with things. And they're like, no, thank
Speaker 3:  you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But I mean, they're, they're, we're seeing they're, they're increasing
Speaker 5:  their control in Hollywood. Like they, like Apple is doing pretty well.
Speaker 5:  Apple TV was the second most searched thing during the outage
Speaker 5:  yesterday. Like, like they, they have this power and, and is always,
Speaker 5:  I think, very uncomfortable for me to see any media organization, which Apple
Speaker 5:  now is saying, no, you can't cover something. And, and that's been the
Speaker 5:  way it's been always. Right? There's always been sensors at, at these companies
Speaker 5:  saying, no, you can't talk about this. No, you can't talk about that. And
Speaker 5:  it felt like in the last, I don't know, 10, 15 years, those sensors, their
Speaker 5:  power had really started to wane because we had these different ways of getting
Speaker 5:  this content to people. It wasn't just broadcast television, it was also,
Speaker 5:  it was the films, but it was also streaming, it was also cable, all these
Speaker 5:  other ways. And Apple came in and was like, yeah, network
Speaker 5:  censorship, huh.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 5:  It's cool. And, and just brought it immediately back
Speaker 5:  and it makes sense. Sure. But the
Speaker 5:  last time they were doing it so that they didn't get sued by the
Speaker 5:  FCC, that's why we had network sensors for so long this time they're doing
Speaker 5:  it because Apple doesn't wanna upset people in China because it wants
Speaker 5:  to sell phones in China. And like the motivation is very, very different.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's what makes me the most uncomfortable here Yeah. Is that
Speaker 5:  like we're seeing a very large company exert its influence
Speaker 5:  directly on the things it owns. And then saying like,
Speaker 5:  we're doing it for very greedy capitalism reasons,
Speaker 5:  which is like, fine, that's your job. Your job is to make money. But also
Speaker 5:  if your job is to make money and your job is to create media,
Speaker 4:  But also If, you don't want someone talking about ai. Don't
Speaker 4:  hire that guy China. Don't hire John Stewart. Right. Yeah. That's kind of
Speaker 4:  where I'm at. Like, this is, the part about this I find so confusing is like,
Speaker 4:  there was the thing with Disney forever, right? Where Disney was reluctant
Speaker 4:  to do something like ad Hulu to Disney Plus because this sort of family
Speaker 4:  friendly nature of a platform they call Disney was very
Speaker 4:  important to that company. And that has, I think, changed internally over
Speaker 4:  time. But like that's a stance you can hold. Yep.
Speaker 4:  If that's how you want to feel terrific, don't hire
Speaker 4:  John Stewart. And so, and so to me it's like the, the thing that I
Speaker 4:  find strange is not that Apple has these feelings, but that it really loudly
Speaker 4:  wants to pretend it doesn't have these feelings, and then
Speaker 4:  goes around just sort of quietly trying to steer everyone
Speaker 4:  in the direction that Apple would like, which is honestly Apple's whole mo
Speaker 4:  with everything all the time. Yeah. It's like Apple, apple prefers to be
Speaker 4:  sort of the wizard behind the curtain exerting influence without saying
Speaker 4:  or doing anything publicly. Right.
Speaker 3:  This is the closest Apple has gotten to like, news programming though. Like
Speaker 3:  I'm fine if Apple wants to make, if Apple wants to be a movie studio and
Speaker 3:  it only makes heartwarming movies about uplifting, that's fine. Yeah. Great.
Speaker 3:  You're a great movie studio.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Nobody's mad at the Hallmark channel for not doing like, hard hitting
Speaker 4:  news.
Speaker 3:  I'm furious The Hallmark channel every single day, sir.
Speaker 3:  But like hiring John Stewart is like, we're gonna do news, we're gonna be
Speaker 3:  topical, we're even relevant. And you just see most other big tech companies
Speaker 3:  have, they tried it and they're all running away from it as fast as like,
Speaker 3:  like Instagram threads, we don't want to do news. They're like, this is messy.
Speaker 3:  It's hard. It gets us in lots of trouble. It's not even what people want
Speaker 3:  Instagram threads. The algorithm is only gonna show you content about
Speaker 3:  how to be a tra wife so people can do engagement bait. And it's like, what's
Speaker 3:  happening here all day long? Right. And like, I think Apple
Speaker 3:  hasn't quite had that realization yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that's true. But I, I think there's also just the, the concern
Speaker 5:  that if these are also the companies that are the primary owners
Speaker 5:  of how we view media Yeah. And they all don't wanna do news and they don't
Speaker 5:  wanna like talk about serious issues all the time. Well, that's bad too.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Take a, take a look around the media industry. Let's see how well this
Speaker 3:  is going for everybody. Okay. That's that one. Speaking of Apple antitrust,
Speaker 3:  two things. One, the first European alternative app
Speaker 3:  stores have hit because of the DMA not the good one yet, which is alt store,
Speaker 3:  which is gonna have the emulators in it like an enterprise one has hit,
Speaker 3:  which is perfect. Yeah. Of course. Enterprise software was the first to
Speaker 4:  Go. Yeah. Would you like to jump through a bunch of hoops to download B2B
Speaker 4:  apps? Have we got a store for you?
Speaker 3:  But Kalin Booth, who's in Europe,
Speaker 3:  we hired them to like, look at this stuff. We have a good
Speaker 3:  deep look at it. There are a lot of hoops.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. Its
Speaker 3:  Intense. A lot of hoops.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Let me, let me just read this sentence to you. It made me laugh. Very
Speaker 4:  funny.
Speaker 4:  It goes like this. You begin by clicking a browser based link to load the
Speaker 4:  alternative store. From there you receive a popup informing you that your
Speaker 4:  installation settings don't allow marketplaces from that developer. Then
Speaker 4:  you head into settings, enable the marketplace, return to your browser, click
Speaker 4:  the download link again, and received another prompt asking you to confirm
Speaker 4:  the install. Finally, you can open the store and browse the available apps.
Speaker 3:  Perfect. Whew.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I feel like I'd screw that up by accident. Like,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So the argument is Apple doesn't know if it's things
Speaker 3:  are in compliance with the DMA until they release them. And the European
Speaker 3:  regulators tell them, which is weird, right? Like, if you're gonna be a
Speaker 3:  regulator and you're going to insist that things are designed, you should
Speaker 3:  just say how you want them designed instead of this weird back and forth.
Speaker 3:  But I suspect all of this will change because the way it's designed is they
Speaker 3:  released it and then the European regulators are gonna be like, Al
Speaker 3:  and they're, they're gonna
Speaker 4:  As they do.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And they're gonna say, this isn't good enough.
Speaker 4:  I think that's probably great. I also think I, I'm not terribly bothered
Speaker 4:  by making people jump through several hoops to do this, honestly. Like, I
Speaker 4:  think the, the thing on the Mac where If, you try to download
Speaker 4:  an app from a sort of non-trust source being like
Speaker 4:  the app store, it makes you open settings, find a thing, check
Speaker 4:  that box, and then go do it again. I think that is like the correct number
Speaker 4:  of hoops to jump through. Like, this is the sort of thing you should not
Speaker 4:  be able to do by accident. But If, you wanna do it, you should be able to
Speaker 4:  do it. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I disagree.
Speaker 4:  You should just know. You should have to know that you're doing it.
Speaker 5:  I, I wanna be able to absolutely destroy my phone on accident.
Speaker 5:  I like, I, that's how I learned how to compute and I wanna, I wanna maintain
Speaker 5:  that. And I think like kids today, that's, you know, kids today,
Speaker 5:  the kids today, they gotta learn too. Everybody's gotta learn how to like,
Speaker 5:  just destroy all of their technology 'cause they clicked one wrong box
Speaker 5:  somewhere. And it, it, it makes you, it makes you sharper. It makes you think
Speaker 5:  more. And we, we gotta, we gotta make people sharper and think it
Speaker 4:  More. I like it.
Speaker 3:  This is how we bring down a number of Iranian centrifuges. Yeah. It's just,
Speaker 3:  just let the worms proliferate. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Malware build character.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Basically it does. Like, have you ever brought down an entire computer
Speaker 3:  lab trying to download one MP three? All right, now you're a real man.
Speaker 3:  I, I think there's a balance in there. 'cause Android has had this model
Speaker 3:  for a long time where you can like jump through some hoops and the argument
Speaker 3:  is like, I mean, we've seen it in the epic antitrust case against Google.
Speaker 3:  Like Google knew that people weren't doing it 'cause the hoops were there.
Speaker 3:  Right. But then you kind of don't want a bunch of people accidentally screwing
Speaker 3:  things up. The thing that's really interesting though is
Speaker 3:  Alt Store has Delta in it, which is a Nintendo emulator, by all accounts,
Speaker 3:  a great emulator. Apple won't allow that on its stores.
Speaker 3:  But now you're like, oh, there's an entire use case for the iPhone that's
Speaker 3:  available to me now. Right. Because there's an alternative application distribution
Speaker 3:  model that's worth it.
Speaker 4:  Oh, agreed.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent agreed.
Speaker 4:  And I think it, it is, it's kind of great that, that it, the first
Speaker 4:  thing, because like, leaving aside all the legality questions about
Speaker 4:  emulation in general, like whatever, playing those kinds of games on your
Speaker 4:  phone is so fun. It's so fun. And it, and
Speaker 4:  you're right that it has not been allowed and it's never going to be allowed.
Speaker 4:  And there was a minute where Ry tested the developer thought he was
Speaker 4:  gonna get into the app store proper and then got that sort of
Speaker 4:  ripped out from under him. This is a couple of years ago now. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But now we're at a point where, like, If, you want to
Speaker 4:  go through the hoops, you are going to be able to get your phone to do almost
Speaker 4:  anything. And I think that is the right approach. Yeah. I think it should
Speaker 4:  be hard work to do the dumb stuff you want to do on your
Speaker 4:  phone. Like, I think it should be more than one click of one link to download
Speaker 4:  malware onto your phone. But damnit If, you wanna download malware onto your
Speaker 4:  phone,
Speaker 5:  You should be allowed.
Speaker 4:  You should be allowed. And I think that's fine. And I think it is gonna be
Speaker 4:  interesting to see from a regulatory perspective how they view the hoops.
Speaker 4:  Because I think if, if the goal of the EU and the
Speaker 4:  regulators in general is to make it so sort of like
Speaker 4:  opaque in the process, that it feels like you're downloading an app from
Speaker 4:  the app store, even when you're not, I actually think, think that's a bad
Speaker 4:  outcome. But I also feel like the thing where you have to go
Speaker 4:  essentially check the one box that declares the, like, I know what I'm doing
Speaker 4:  and I'm willing to put up the consequences and then you can move on with
Speaker 4:  your life feels right to me. And this feels like a little overshoot of that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We'll see how it goes. I'm very excited. I mean, this is the experiment.
Speaker 3:  We're, we've never run it before. Like, we'll see how it goes. I,
Speaker 3:  I, I think there's something really exciting to happen here. I agree. David,
Speaker 3:  you've added this extremely fake story about Stephen and buying TikTok
Speaker 3:  without the algorithm. Defend yourself, defend the addition of this. This
Speaker 3:  is a totally fake story. This matter.
Speaker 4:  It's a totally fake story. Well, this is why I added it because, so we, we
Speaker 4:  got a ton of feedback over the last couple of weeks about both the Apple
Speaker 4:  antitrust stuff and the TikTok ban. And we're gonna talk about all that stuff
Speaker 4:  on Tuesday's episode. But for this one, my real question
Speaker 4:  is more theoretical than this. Like Steve Uchin is not going to buy TikTok
Speaker 4:  buying TikTok with the, without the algorithm that not
Speaker 3:  By the A thing, by way, he's the former treasury secretary under Trump.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Who is not going to buy TikTok, doesn't matter who he is, he is not
Speaker 4:  gonna buy TikTok. And I think I'm
Speaker 4:  just fascinated by this question. So there are two pieces of news here that
Speaker 4:  I think are, are related. So one is that Facebook this week rolled out a
Speaker 4:  unified video player for all of its video across platforms. And
Speaker 4:  it's basically all in on precisely TikTok style
Speaker 4:  vertical video. And that plus this thing where it's like,
Speaker 4:  okay, what do you buy If? you buy TikTok without the algorithm just
Speaker 4:  led me to believe like, maybe, maybe the answer is nothing like
Speaker 4:  buying TikTok without, without the algorithm. It's garbage. Is that
Speaker 4:  anything? But then we're at a point where TikTok has actually gotten more
Speaker 4:  and more transparent about what the algorithm is. And so in theory,
Speaker 4:  you could start to do better and companies like Meta have been more explicit
Speaker 4:  about like, we're not going to, you know, show you stuff from your friends.
Speaker 4:  We're not going to buy us anything except engagement and entertainment
Speaker 4:  essentially. So it's like you can actually start to kind of reverse engineer
Speaker 4:  TikTok and without this magical algorithm
Speaker 4:  that is so much of what TikTok has become, you're just buying
Speaker 4:  a brand name, right? Like you're buying, you're buying a license to the word
Speaker 4:  TikTok. And that's well and good, but TikTok without the algorithm feels
Speaker 4:  like, to me it's worth like $5. Yeah, I think that's right. I just
Speaker 4:  don't see it. And I think it, it that if that's going to become
Speaker 4:  the question, and I think so far our theory, which is that this is going
Speaker 4:  to lead to nothing has pretty much borne out. We've basically heard nothing
Speaker 4:  about this since there was all that stuff a couple of weeks ago. I hope he
Speaker 3:  Does
Speaker 5:  That. I hope, like right now as we're recording, oh my God,
Speaker 3:  Signing on the top. I think Voice of the Youth. I think of former treasury
Speaker 3:  secretary Steve Chen. Well, you get all the content, he'd buy all the content,
Speaker 3:  and then you just put any algorithm on top of it and you're fine. Sure.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean that's what you, that's what you'd be buying. You'd be buying
Speaker 3:  all the user generated content that is TikTok.
Speaker 4:  I guess that's true. That's,
Speaker 3:  That's, that's a thing.
Speaker 4:  But also all of that content now exists on all the other platforms too.
Speaker 3:  That's true. That's, so
Speaker 4:  That's kind of where I'm at, right? Like if I'm, if I'm the Instagram team,
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm having meetings where it's like, what does TikTok have
Speaker 4:  and offer at this moment that we can't? And like the, the YouTube
Speaker 4:  Schwarz team I know is asking that same kind of question. Like I know what
Speaker 4:  it's, it's all just sitting there. And especially If, you don't have the
Speaker 4:  algorithm. And the algorithm has been made out to be this like, magical
Speaker 4:  thing that is irreparable and perfect and understands people better
Speaker 4:  than they do themselves. I don't know that it's that, I think part of it
Speaker 4:  is just that like, TikTok is so shameless about the way that it works. And
Speaker 4:  like Adam er, who runs Instagram is like ringing his hands trying to be a
Speaker 4:  good person. And TikTok is just like, TikTok shop, let's go.
Speaker 3:  TikTok is doing the thing. It's happened for you. I think they're testing
Speaker 3:  this. It's definitely happening to me where they just start playing an ad
Speaker 3:  at the end of every video now. Oh
Speaker 4:  No, I have not
Speaker 3:  Gotten that. No. So you're like, you instead of looping, it's just like,
Speaker 3:  here's an ad. And all of those ads for me are for
Speaker 3:  the Land Rover defender, which is utterly confusing.
Speaker 3:  Like that algorithm believes that it can get me to buy a Land Rover
Speaker 3:  defender. And all the ads start with the same sweeping shot of the word defender.
Speaker 3:  So it's like, I never know if it's just like some weird it security company.
Speaker 3:  No, it's the Land Rover Defender. That's what
Speaker 5:  It is. Yep. There it is.
Speaker 3:  There it is again. Definitely not buying a Land Rover Defender's pretty good
Speaker 3:  though. Yeah. It's just like, but they've started doing it. Like they're,
Speaker 3:  the platform is getting, they're squeezing more pennies out of it, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Because it might go away or something might happen. I feel like
Speaker 5:  The, the algorithm's also just getting worse. Like,
Speaker 5:  it keeps showing me this guy going, what's up brother doing this? Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I I am not a sports person. I I don't play
Speaker 5:  Madden. You
Speaker 4:  Were talking about
Speaker 5:  You guys immediately were like, yeah, yeah, we Of course. Maybe
Speaker 4:  That's why like this on his, on his,
Speaker 5:  It's good. Yeah, I know that now because TikTok shown me that
Speaker 3:  Repeatedly. There's not TikTok just made a weird Twitch streamer. A star
Speaker 3:  is like very interesting. It's super weird. All right, mark this down. That's
Speaker 3:  a story. We'll come back to this in Microsoft, but this story solely fake.
Speaker 3:  This dude is not buying TikTok. No, no. Last two little regulatory ones.
Speaker 3:  I think it's very funny that the House of Representatives has now banned
Speaker 3:  its staffers from using Microsoft Copilot because they're putting too much
Speaker 3:  data into an insecure LLM system. Very funny. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Just deeply funny. And then we'll come back to this in more
Speaker 3:  detail, but
Speaker 3:  the FCC has scheduled a vote to restore net neutrality, which is very
Speaker 3:  interesting. It feels like we've already
Speaker 3:  ruined enough things. you know, it's like, it's like hard for anyone to get
Speaker 3:  excited about this. It's like, I'm thrilled we did it. Like, because they
Speaker 3:  took net neutrality away. I I just want to, there are people
Speaker 3:  out there who are like, nothing bad happened when net neutrality went away
Speaker 3:  and one very specific bad thing happened, which is that
Speaker 3:  at t bought Time Warner,
Speaker 3:  like very specific bad thing happened and they thought
Speaker 3:  they could prioritize Time Warner services on at t's network.
Speaker 3:  And then they paid Zach Snyder to make a four three gray scale version
Speaker 3:  of the Justice League.
Speaker 4:  Alex did Bat Girl Die because Net neutrality died. Yeah. Could
Speaker 4:  you draw? I feel like you could draw that
Speaker 5:  Line. I think. I think you can.
Speaker 4:  Because without that acquisition, they don't have all the debt when they
Speaker 4:  get offloaded, which means Zav doesn't have to kill Bat Girl. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 4:  yeah. That's thanks to Jeep Pie. He ruined
Speaker 3:  Bat Girl. I'm believe it. I'm just saying this man in his stupid mug, his
Speaker 3:  stupid oversized Reese's Pieces mug. And everyone's like, no bad things happen.
Speaker 3:  And it's like, actually one very tangible bad thing happened,
Speaker 3:  which is at t had a theory of the case. It was like, we will buy a content
Speaker 3:  service, prioritize it, and preload tiny little
Speaker 3:  clips of Game of Thrones on mid-range and Android phones. Wait and accept
Speaker 3:  all of that from our data caps. This was, this was it.
Speaker 3:  And then we're gonna get Zach Snyder for some
Speaker 3:  godforsaken reason. I know he thought it was the IMAX I aspect ratio.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I know that's what he was thinking. But the reality is
Speaker 3:  he made a four three version of Justice League. That's how I watched it on
Speaker 3:  my tv. It was a square.
Speaker 3:  I'm just Why
Speaker 5:  You, the more you say it, the more I feel like what if net neutrality, like,
Speaker 5:  like actually that was a good thing that that at t was allowed
Speaker 3:  To, we got four three Justice leave.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because it proved that like no one wants that.
Speaker 3:  It does prove I will. I agree with you. Yeah. I actually agree. The market
Speaker 3:  firmly rejected at T'S ideas. Correct. It was like, no, this is
Speaker 3:  stupid. But we didn't need to go through all that pain. We didn't need to
Speaker 3:  fire all those people. We like the layoffs that occurred.
Speaker 3:  The, the, the, the general pain.
Speaker 5:  Thousands of people
Speaker 3:  Affected lobbed upon the American populace
Speaker 5:  With black and white Zack Snyder, justice
Speaker 3:  League four, three Justice League was created. Like, we
Speaker 3:  didn't have to, you know, I'm saying like, I think the layoffs were worse.
Speaker 3:  Like the millions of the millions of dollars of like debt and weirdness
Speaker 3:  and,
Speaker 5:  But we all experienced Zack Snyder movie
Speaker 3:  Rounds of rolling layoffs are bad. I don't think we need to do them. We should
Speaker 3:  have healthy companies in a functional marketplace. But then also
Speaker 3:  there was a four three Justice League
Speaker 3:  also very tangible results. We
Speaker 5:  Had to watch it
Speaker 3:  Results. I watched all like 15 hours of it.
Speaker 5:  You had to do it as a journalist. Like,
Speaker 3:  And the only thing that saved me is because I invest in OLED technology.
Speaker 3:  Oh my God. The, the pillar boxes weren't shining great. They was so bad.
Speaker 4:  How was your bit rate
Speaker 3:  Horrible. ACM X is a garbage bit rate. Get
Speaker 3:  that shit on Bravia Court asap. And excuse that from your data
Speaker 3:  caps. At and t
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying whenever anyone tells you, whenever you see the, the weirdos
Speaker 3:  on the, on the X being like net neutrality led to nothing.
Speaker 3:  Immediately reply with a screenshot of four three, justice League and Grace.
Speaker 5:  I feel like the Venn diagram of weirdos on X
Speaker 5:  saying net neutrality, net led to nothing. And
Speaker 5:  the people who really wanted that four, three movies, the circle,
Speaker 3:  It's just like they couldn't even, they weren't even like just fill, make
Speaker 3:  it 16. Like just do it. No IMAX enhanced, right?
Speaker 5:  Huh? Because we all have those in our house. You don't have an IMAX screen
Speaker 5:  in your house. All that
Speaker 3:  OLED you can get. I, I do like that IMAX enhanced is basically meant we,
Speaker 3:  we took a 21 9 cinema frame and made it 16 by nine. It's just regular
Speaker 3:  now. It's just regular, like Disney. Disney Plus is like IMAX enhanced.
Speaker 3:  Like what does that mean? It's, it's 16 by nine. Yeah. That's like, that's
Speaker 3:  what that has worked out to. It's great. Alright. That
Speaker 3:  vote is coming up. We'll probably have Lauren back to cover in more detail
Speaker 3:  what it actually means. There's some meaningful differences between this
Speaker 3:  version in previous versions. I just wanna point out that again,
Speaker 3:  you live in an America right now in 2024 where
Speaker 3:  Backroll was killed. David lov, can't believe it. Reign of
Speaker 3:  Terror continues. We're down to three wireless carriers and Project
Speaker 3:  Gen five sis
Speaker 4:  All because of the stupid mug.
Speaker 3:  It's a real thing. There's no, by the way, at the same time the same
Speaker 3:  Jit pa, FCC got rid of the privacy protections
Speaker 3:  for broadband carriers and any ability to regulate them all.
Speaker 3:  These aren't our favorite companies. The ISPs, I should note at this time
Speaker 3:  that NB NBCUniversal is a minority investor in Vox Media, which owns The.
Speaker 3:  Verge, and NBCUniversal is owned by Comcast. Right. Which does not love net
Speaker 3:  neutrality. Or me as it happens.
Speaker 5:  I subscribe to Verizon. It's okay.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. IIIF It's nice. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's okay.
Speaker 3:  I'm an at t subscriber. I stream Justice League for free. Oh wow.
Speaker 3:  That was that. It didn't hit my data cap at all. Congratulations.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  Big for you. My at t subscription still locked into Max. And
Speaker 3:  so now I only have Max and 10 80 B. That's very good.
Speaker 3:  All right. We gotta
Speaker 3:  Right. So Tesla's deliveries are weighed down under forecast.
Speaker 3:  I've NELI, I've never seen it before, but various investors and
Speaker 3:  executives are talking about replacing Elon as ceo. That will probably never
Speaker 3:  happen. But even the fact that it is a conversation that has occurred,
Speaker 3:  like in the CNBC orbits,
Speaker 5:  The shine is off,
Speaker 3:  Seems very bad. Tesla stock is generally tanking. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Elon is just tweeting about the woke mind virus instead of shipping more
Speaker 3:  cars or making X Good. It's not great over there. No,
Speaker 4:  No. I think there was a thing about
Speaker 4:  Tesla that made him kind of invincible for a really long time because it
Speaker 4:  was like the, the conversation around Elon for so long was like,
Speaker 4:  say whatever you want. People are voting with their dollars. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  Tesla was on fire, investors loved it. People were buying it.
Speaker 4:  We talked on their show about how there was essentially unlimited demand
Speaker 4:  for Teslas. And at some point in
Speaker 4:  the last year or so that turned, and I think you can probably blame that
Speaker 4:  on a confluence of things. Not all of it is. A lot of people decided
Speaker 4:  they don't like Elon Musk anymore. But I think I had some of it is that,
Speaker 4:  but like this sort of era of
Speaker 4:  power that Tesla had for a long time seems
Speaker 4:  pretty clearly to be, if not over them, under like really serious
Speaker 4:  threat. And as we've been saying, and I think as you in particular, NELI
Speaker 4:  have said a few times on this show, Tesla is both
Speaker 4:  like a great strength and a great weakness for Elon because of the way it
Speaker 4:  ties him to China, because of the way it like has all of his
Speaker 4:  fortunes inside of it. That like what happens to this company is
Speaker 4:  so materially important to what happens to everything else that Elon Musk
Speaker 4:  wants to do, including the way that SpaceX works with the government. Like
Speaker 4:  it's all so tied up. And so you get the sense that as it
Speaker 4:  is starting to turn the other way, it like it, the spiral happens
Speaker 4:  in the reverse direction too. Yeah. Yep. And it feels like it's getting really
Speaker 4:  ugly really fast.
Speaker 3:  So we have a story this week. There's a reputation tracking firm called Caliber.
Speaker 3:  We went, surveyed a bunch of people, the consideration score
Speaker 3:  for Tesla, which is basically consumer interest in brands. The
Speaker 3:  question they went and surveyed people I would buy or continue buying products
Speaker 3:  and services from Tesla if given the chance in
Speaker 3:  November, 2021, 70% of people said yes, that's down to
Speaker 3:  31%. Oof.
Speaker 4:  Whoa. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean that everything about that, because we've, we've seen the quality
Speaker 5:  has dropped. We've seen people talking more about that quality. We've seen
Speaker 5:  people struggling with getting their cars repaired, getting, getting this
Speaker 5:  like customer service is really, really bad there. So yeah. All
Speaker 5:  those things that actually do matter to consumer experience. And and
Speaker 5:  Elon kind of was like, don't worry about it. We're, we're, we're building
Speaker 5:  The future. Eventually people are like, yes, but I want my car to work
Speaker 4:  Now. Right. I also think this ongoing full self-driving fiasco that
Speaker 4:  this company just cannot get out of where it refuses to stop calling.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Full self-driving when it is not full self-driving. And actually what
Speaker 4:  it's doing is really dangerous. Like the, the public perception on
Speaker 4:  that I think is like decidedly negative at this point. Yeah, yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  is really like, even outside of how you feel about Elon Musk, the idea that
Speaker 4:  Tesla is like The future of cars in a lot of ways, like hinges
Speaker 4:  on that.
Speaker 3:  Oh, their entire valuation hinges on that. Right. Like I've watched, I mean
Speaker 3:  I go on CN BBC all the time. I talk to the analysts there. You, you look
Speaker 3:  at how the market values Tesla and it's still built
Speaker 3:  into the idea that you will go to work and your car will like leave your
Speaker 3:  house and like drive itself and be a taxi service.
Speaker 4:  Right. The Tesla is gonna be like infrastructure. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. And like no, it's a car company. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  that's the, but all of the multiple of Tesla is built on the idea that
Speaker 3:  the cars will generate more value than just being a depreciating
Speaker 3:  asset than most people should lease.
Speaker 5:  So did they all think it was Uber?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's like, that's the idea here. Like the multiple. And that's why
Speaker 3:  Elon is constantly talking about AI now. Yeah. All this stuff. And he's like
Speaker 3:  a, like Tesla's really an AI company 'cause he is trying to get this other
Speaker 3:  thing to happen and get this other multiple. And it's like the market is
Speaker 3:  starting to just see a car company, a car company that shipped a triangle
Speaker 3:  instead of a regular pickup truck, a car company that can't
Speaker 3:  deliver. Like, well-made cars on the regular, like all this stuff.
Speaker 3:  And whose CEO is becoming more and more unpopular by the
Speaker 3:  day because he won't shut up. Yep. We, like I
Speaker 3:  talk to a lot of CEOs, they're not all pleasant people,
Speaker 3:  like by and large, like very aggressive type A personalities
Speaker 3:  in the c-suites of American companies. But they know to not,
Speaker 5:  They have people around them. They, they hire publicity Yeah. Firms
Speaker 5:  and stuff, which Elon famously refuses
Speaker 4:  And like, don't tweet. Turns out to be pretty good advice. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Most of the time. Especially about the woke mind virus and the great replacement
Speaker 3:  theory.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If you're a publicly traded company, don't, don't tweet.
Speaker 3:  If you're a publicly traded company that sells Electric cars to extremely
Speaker 3:  liberal people by and large
Speaker 3:  just doing some white supremacy on the sides. Not a great idea for you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Not great for your value.
Speaker 3:  Anyway. It's, it's just a weird time like
Speaker 3:  to bring this all back around X now giving the check marks away to journalists
Speaker 3:  for free. Very funny. Yes. Like all the way back around. They're like, what
Speaker 3:  if we verified some people
Speaker 3:  it's 'cause they, they need people to use the platform. And I, I suspect
Speaker 3:  it won't work. But
Speaker 4:  No, if anything it, it seems to be like, do you remember that
Speaker 4:  moment right after they said you're gonna have to start
Speaker 4:  paying for the blue check? But they hadn't taken it away from people who
Speaker 4:  had it before and all these people were coming out saying, no, no, no. Just
Speaker 4:  so you know, I didn't pay for it. Yeah. It's happening. We're we're doing
Speaker 4:  that again where people are like embarrassed to have a blue check. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But in a way that it is like, it's a, it's a badge of like you are
Speaker 4:  pathetically still using this platform rather than
Speaker 4:  something you're actually part of.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say it kind of works because then you have to go log in and
Speaker 5:  tweet or excuse me post I didn't pay for this
Speaker 5:  check mark. Yeah. Like they, they Gotcha.
Speaker 4:  And your unre regretted user minutes go through the roof. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's enough. Elon talk for one day.
Speaker 3:  Spotify reportedly having a price increase. They, they've realized they
Speaker 3:  increased. They look, they increased prices last year, had their best year
Speaker 3:  ever. They also laid off a bunch of people had cuts so they
Speaker 3:  increased revenue, reduced costs, heartlessly, but do it that
Speaker 5:  That does in fact work. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Usually maths out, there's, it's, there's not a lot of places to go from
Speaker 3:  Spotify. Like I don't think people are like, ah, Spotify's going up. I'm
Speaker 3:  switching to YouTube music.
Speaker 4:  No, people should not and are not doing that.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I think to me, the thing that seems to be
Speaker 4:  true is that 9 99 was the wrong price for streaming music.
Speaker 4:  We just kind of decided this like years ago. It was just like, in the same
Speaker 4:  way that Steve Jobs was just like, what if songs cost 99 cents? And everybody
Speaker 4:  was like, all right. Like a long time ago it was just like 10 bucks a
Speaker 4:  month and this is where we are. And it turns out that is
Speaker 4:  good money for record labels. Yeah. And bad both for most
Speaker 4:  artists and most streaming companies. Well,
Speaker 5:  I mean, Spotify did it because that was when they were, they were coming
Speaker 5:  into the United States where you had this really entrenched market
Speaker 5:  run by Apple. Right. And they were like, okay, we gotta compete with 99 cents
Speaker 5:  songs. How do we do that $10 a month? And you get all of
Speaker 5:  the songs and, and we are all like, yes, that's
Speaker 4:  Victory sick. Yeah. And I think if it had been 20 bucks a month, it probably
Speaker 4:  wouldn't have worked. So, but if it had been 20 bucks a month, it might've
Speaker 4:  been a hell of a lot more sustainable.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, I would say the last 10 plus years of
Speaker 5:  like $10 a month, that's, that's pretty good run for
Speaker 5:  That's better run than like Netflix.
Speaker 4:  Oh, for sure. Yeah. No, I I actually think we as users probably saved
Speaker 4:  a lot of money over the last decade on, on, on
Speaker 4:  Spotify's dime. But I think this feels super inevitable to me. And
Speaker 4:  this will not be the last one. I don't think that, like, it went from nine
Speaker 4:  nine to 10 99 and now the report is, it's gonna go up. I think
Speaker 4:  either one or two more dollars. Right. Yeah. I would not be
Speaker 4:  surprised if a couple of years from now we're at like 15 bucks for
Speaker 4:  Spotify. What? I'll still pay it. Like music services
Speaker 4:  are awesome. I have, I have zero qualms with
Speaker 4:  the fact that I have all the music on Earth available to me at all times.
Speaker 4:  But it is, it is a bummer to see this. I'm more
Speaker 4:  sensitive to this for Spotify because like it's a bad
Speaker 4:  business for Spotify. It's not Spotify being like, we make lots of money,
Speaker 4:  but we want more. Give us more. This is Spotify being like, we literally
Speaker 4:  cannot do this anymore. Please give us more money. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  How do y'all feel like Apple will respond to this?
Speaker 3:  I don't think Apple will raise their prices at all, actually. I think that
Speaker 3:  any price increases get rolled into Apple One. And that's just what they're
Speaker 3:  gonna keep doing. I think Apple Music, they run as a loss leader to get you
Speaker 3:  into that bigger bundle. I
Speaker 5:  Don't even pay for it. I get it through my Verizon
Speaker 5:  account. And I'm like, all right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think Apple is very happy to let that be
Speaker 4:  somewhere between a, an okay business and a slightly
Speaker 4:  less than Okay. Business in service of everything else. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And they want you in that Apple one bundle. Yeah. As hard as they can be
Speaker 3:  when all their services went down. It was like people search for the app
Speaker 3:  store being down and a little bit of Apple TV and nothing else.
Speaker 5:  It was so sad. We were looking at the, the thing we put in like, we're like,
Speaker 5:  well what about Arcade? No. We couldn't even like find the line on
Speaker 5:  the graph. We're like, oh, that's a bummer. That's right.
Speaker 4:  Which is funny because Apple Music is hugely popular. Like it is, it is.
Speaker 4:  Apple Music and Spotify are the two winners in this market by a
Speaker 4:  gigantic margin. It's
Speaker 5:  Not the one people go Googling when they can't get it on their rush hour
Speaker 5:  day
Speaker 4:  Home. Definitely not.
Speaker 3:  All right. Two stories that are in conflict in really interesting ways. Hmm.
Speaker 3:  OpenAI has a new voice cloning model. It only needs 15 seconds
Speaker 3:  of audio to clone your voice. Fascinating. And
Speaker 3:  there was a fake George Carlin special, they settled
Speaker 3:  with the estate of George Carlin. They promised not to do it anymore. Actually,
Speaker 3:  a weird drama inside of that story is whether there was actually
Speaker 3:  AI used to make the fake George Carlin special, or whether they were faking
Speaker 3:  it, which is interesting.
Speaker 4:  Well, they, they admitted to writing it themselves. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  How the rest of it was produced,
Speaker 4:  I think, as far as I know at least has not been really nailed down. But the
Speaker 4:  idea that this was like written, produced, and created by AI just
Speaker 4:  flatly not true. And it's been a really fun thing going around. Like there
Speaker 4:  was this whole story this week about how Amazon's just walk out technology
Speaker 4:  was actually powered by like a thousand contractors in
Speaker 4:  India. Yeah. Manually reviewing your trip through to make sure that you
Speaker 4:  paid for everything. And I think it was Molly White who runs the, the
Speaker 4:  website, like, I think it's, what is it? Web3 is going great. Yeah. Who was
Speaker 4:  basically like, I wish I had been tracking all the times that AI turned out
Speaker 4:  to just be a guy.
Speaker 4:  It's like, and it's, it's really true. And this feels like that too. It's
Speaker 4:  just, it's just a guy. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't help that one of 'em is like from Mad tv. Like one the hosts.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But these two ideas are intention. We've talked about this so many times.
Speaker 3:  Like AI being able to clone a voice or clone a picture, da da da da. And
Speaker 3:  then you have and doing it faster than ever. 15 seconds of our
Speaker 3:  voices to clone us. Yeah. Which we have generated more of that on this very,
Speaker 3:  very podcast. You're welcome. And then it's like, oh, but we
Speaker 3:  have no controls over how those likes are used or any of that is
Speaker 3:  actually being done except for these handful of lawsuits that might bring
Speaker 3:  the whole thing crashing down. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, and Open AI's strategy has been so far to roll it out really
Speaker 4:  slowly and only with a few partners. And it's like, okay, that's fine at
Speaker 4:  the beginning, but then what's gonna happen is you're gonna have a better
Speaker 4:  version of this technology that you give to everybody. Yeah. So like, what's
Speaker 4:  the plan then? Yeah. It's like if they were saying, you know, it
Speaker 4:  takes 900 hours so we're only letting a few people
Speaker 4:  use it because it's hugely intensive. I'd be like, okay, well whatever. But
Speaker 4:  this is like, we found a very good technology, but only a few people can
Speaker 4:  have it. And then everybody can have a very good technology. Like what are
Speaker 4:  we, what are we accomplishing here? Yeah. But I think, I mean this
Speaker 4:  is, this has been coming right? Like the, the, the New York Times,
Speaker 4:  I think it was this week, had a big announcement about how most of its articles
Speaker 4:  are now gonna be available in audio form read by
Speaker 4:  automated narrators like 11 Labs, which is a company we've talked about on
Speaker 4:  this show before, is doing like incredible slash
Speaker 4:  terrifying work synthesizing people's voices. Like this stuff is moving
Speaker 4:  as fast as any other tech in AI right now. And it's
Speaker 4:  getting really crazy really fast. And I feel like
Speaker 4:  probably should be talked about more than it is. Yeah. In the way that we
Speaker 4:  talk about like generated images and how they're being used in political
Speaker 4:  campaigns and all this stuff. Like, you're gonna start, you're gonna get
Speaker 4:  phone calls from Joe Biden telling you not to vote. Like that's a thing that's
Speaker 4:  gonna start to happen. It's already happened. Yeah. It's like it happened.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think like this,
Speaker 4:  OpenAI is typically very good at this and I think is not usually
Speaker 4:  wrong when it says it built something good,
Speaker 4:  but is not great at playing it slow. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  By the one story that hit just as we were, we as we've been talking on the
Speaker 3:  search cast, Neil Mohan who runs YouTube at a conference
Speaker 3:  said, OpenAI should not train its systems on YouTube. Which is
Speaker 3:  not how OpenAI has thought about the internet.
Speaker 4:  No. And who was it? It was, was it Mira ti? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  At OpenAI. Who said to Joanna Stern, our friend
Speaker 4:  Joanna was when they were talking about the video thing, Sora that OpenAI
Speaker 4:  came out with. Joanna was like, are you training this on stuff from the internet?
Speaker 4:  And she was like, ah, some training stuff. Internet, public
Speaker 4:  private. And Joanna was like, are you getting it from YouTube? And she was
Speaker 4:  just like, ah. So I was like, oh, okay. So you're obviously getting it from
Speaker 4:  YouTube. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm like, cool. It's not great.
Speaker 4:  No. If
Speaker 3:  Google sues OpenAI on behalf of YouTube creators for training, it's, it's
Speaker 3:  a weird, there's a copyright apocalypse. We did an entire decoder with Sarah
Speaker 3:  Jang. You can go listen to it, but there's a potential copyright apocalypse.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Mr. Beast is gonna make a video in which he sues OpenAI for a
Speaker 4:  hundred million dollars
Speaker 3:  And then gives the money away. Gives the money away. That would be incredible.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we gotta end this thing. We're way, way over. But David,
Speaker 3:  you should end by talking about Google Podcasts.
Speaker 4:  Well this is a, this is a good, we're circling back around to, we're closing
Speaker 4:  the loop on Google, not closing the loop.
Speaker 3:  Ha. Very
Speaker 4:  Good. Google could stand to learn from us. So Google podcast is dead. Although
Speaker 4:  it's actually not dead. It's like ironically Google
Speaker 4:  has so forgotten about Google podcast that it seems to have forgotten to
Speaker 4:  turn it off. Was that, it was that that
Speaker 5:  Was, its like podcast app.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So it had a dedicated podcast app. It came out in
Speaker 4:  2016,
Speaker 4:  been around for a while. It did what Google does to many of its
Speaker 4:  apps, which is like, it launched, it had big ideas. It seemed kind of cool.
Speaker 4:  It, it got a couple of updates. Google forgot about it. Google launched a
Speaker 4:  competitor and then Google killed it.
Speaker 4:  This is the story of Google apps. And so the,
Speaker 4:  the plan here is to replace Google Podcasts with YouTube music. And they've
Speaker 4:  been making some moves into YouTube music. There is a, I would say strong
Speaker 4:  chance you are watching or listening to this podcast right now on YouTube.
Speaker 4:  Part of the reason Google is investing in YouTube is because that is a vast
Speaker 4:  and massively growing place for Podcasts. But it
Speaker 4:  had this really cool opportunity in Podcasts, right? Like Google, I went
Speaker 4:  back and read their initial thing and in 2016 when they launched this app
Speaker 4:  and they had these big ideas about discovery and helping people find
Speaker 4:  insights inside of Podcasts and doing audio transcription and
Speaker 4:  search and all this stuff. And it's like, oh, that seems good. Like why didn't
Speaker 4:  you do any of that? Yeah. That would've been cool. And instead you just
Speaker 4:  forgot about this app for eight years and then killed it. And YouTube is
Speaker 4:  not gonna do that.
Speaker 5:  Are they gonna release Google Podcasts with Gemini
Speaker 5:  at Google io?
Speaker 3:  Oh my God would be, if they relaunched Google Podcasts at io, that was Would
Speaker 3:  Gemini that
Speaker 4:  Be incredible with
Speaker 3:  Gemini? They could have also solved huge amounts of
Speaker 3:  Podcasts analytics. Yep. And advertising problems. Yep. That everyone has
Speaker 3:  all over the place. Yep.
Speaker 4:  I heard from a lot of people after I wrote this story, I had
Speaker 4:  a paragraph in here basically being like, Hey Google If, you had just done
Speaker 4:  for audio creators what you did for video creators on YouTube.
Speaker 4:  You could have won this industry the same way that you did. And I heard
Speaker 4:  from a surprising number of podcasters who are like, I have been
Speaker 4:  begging slash hoping YouTube would do that for years. Like
Speaker 4:  build the ad tools, do the rev share. Let me post my stuff on YouTube
Speaker 4:  and make money from it as an audio creator. The same way you can as a video
Speaker 4:  creator. And there are lots of, I was about to say good reasons, but there
Speaker 4:  are bad reasons, but there are lots of reasons Google didn't do that. But
Speaker 4:  it didn't do that. And it could have, and that sucks.
Speaker 3:  I remember being in meetings at our company, it's like, Google's coming and
Speaker 3:  we better be ready. And I'm like, dude, yeah,
Speaker 5:  They'll get distracted. Don't worry about
Speaker 3:  It. It's like, I don't know.
Speaker 4:  But also to everyone who wants to know the answer is Pocket casts. Pocket
Speaker 4:  casts
Speaker 3:  If.
Speaker 4:  You want a a good cross platform podcast app that is not going to go
Speaker 4:  away. The answer is Pocket casts. There are other good ones out there. Antenna
Speaker 4:  pods, really good on Android, overcast Apple Podcasts, but If, you wanna
Speaker 4:  know the answer. It's pocket casts.
Speaker 3:  All right. We'll end there with that completely un
Speaker 3:  uncontroversial opinion that no one will
Speaker 4:  The lightning round brought to you by Pocket casts slash
Speaker 3:  No, you gotta pay the money.
Speaker 3:  We can't give this stuff away for free. Man. Perceived value.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, right.
Speaker 4:  I apologize.
Speaker 3:  Brought to you by anything other than Pocket Cast. All right. That's it.
Speaker 3:  That's The Vergecast. I'm gonna call it a few stories. Becca did
Speaker 3:  a comparison video of the Fuji Film X 106
Speaker 3:  versus the Ricoh GR three X. I'm
Speaker 3:  saying it slowly 'cause that's just a lot of letters. It's a lot's, a lot
Speaker 3:  of Roman numerals in that. Yeah, it's not good, but it's really fun. I'm
Speaker 3:  desperate to buy these cameras for no reason other than I just want them.
Speaker 3:  Allison wrote about notifications being bad, which is worth reading. She's
Speaker 3:  right. No takeaways. Yeah. Just like start over. Just like throw all this
Speaker 3:  away. It's bad. And then Liz wrote about Vice,
Speaker 3:  one of the weirdest, wildest stories I think we've done in a long time. We
Speaker 3:  did an entirely decoder with Liz about the story. She's gonna listen to that
Speaker 3:  next week. But the gist of it is we thought we were writing a story about
Speaker 3:  how advertising on the web was like went sideways and couldn't support
Speaker 3:  Vice. 'cause they shut down their newsroom website. Oh. So we thought we
Speaker 3:  were writing about like advertising cookies and programmatic and No, no,
Speaker 3:  we were, we were just writing about crazy people. That's the story. She
Speaker 3:  talked to 20 people. She described reporting that story as a hall of mirrors
Speaker 3:  because all hate each other. They're all lying to each other about each other.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. Beautiful. Including one part where it was revealed that
Speaker 3:  Vice had a Net Jets account that was on, on the budget of
Speaker 3:  their digital division. And then two different people to credit for shutting
Speaker 3:  down. And Vice's response to us was, we have not had a net gen account
Speaker 3:  since 2021. Oh. Which is
Speaker 4:  Like, there you go. Congratulations. So did have a net
Speaker 3:  Gen account. That is what you're saying. We're really proud of you. It's
Speaker 3:  very good. Great story. Go read that. That's it. Oh, by the way, we got
Speaker 3:  nominated for a bunch of Webby Awards. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yay. The People's For Best Technology podcast.
Speaker 3:  The Big Webby and the People's Choice. Go vote for us. We'll have a link.
Speaker 3:  Go vote for us in the web.
Speaker 4:  Wait. Also, listen people, it's, it's so important that you vote
Speaker 4:  for The Vergecast as technology podcast. And not Decoder is also nominated
Speaker 4:  in business podcast. NELI can have his That's all fine. I need you to vote
Speaker 4:  for The Verge cast. It's so important that NELI does not win
Speaker 4:  as decoder. It's so important.
Speaker 3:  Please vote. Vote the broadcast. It really did. The Webbys really did a stir.
Speaker 3:  You. Here, I'll take the business. Win. Give, give this show The tech
Speaker 3:  win. Yeah. You get to have it way. Yes. Decoder ISS nominated in both categories.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Okay. Just look for my face and click on it. That's all I'm
Speaker 3:  saying's gonna be. Great. All right. That's it. We're way over on a slow
Speaker 3:  week. We still went way over. That's it. That's Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One. The Vergecast is the production
Speaker 1:  of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced by
Speaker 1:  Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 1:  Thanks to Canva for their support. Canva wants to make your presentations
Speaker 1:  come as easy as those thoughts that pass through your head. And thanks to
Speaker 1:  their ai, you can start with a simple prompt and watch Canva. Go to work.
Speaker 1:  Choose your favorite style, customize the content, and you're done. It's
Speaker 1:  a serious time saver. Whatever you do for work, Canva presentations can give
Speaker 1:  you a headstart on your deck. You can generate sales presentations, marketing
Speaker 1:  decks, HR onboarding plans. You name it, finish your deck faster.
Speaker 1:  Generate slides and seconds with Canva. presentations@canva.com.
Speaker 1:  Designed for work.