# Transcript
ID: 935665f9-13ce-4592-a66b-18b743dee273
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/527639538614048283/5561764111243391788/s93290-US-5833s-1709819214.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Apple's upgraded MacBook Air, the EU's Digital Markets Act deadline for tech’s biggest “gatekeepers”, and a bunch of tech news from this week.
Speaker 4:  Hello, And. Welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast of European
Speaker 4:  regulations.
Speaker 5:  Oof. Not the most exciting one we've ever done.
Speaker 4:  It's not great. Look, If, you go talk
Speaker 4:  to like entrepreneur, founder, guys,
Speaker 4:  professors, business school professors. That's the word I was looking for.
Speaker 4:  And you're like, what's a good time to start a business? They're like, regulatory
Speaker 4:  change provides opportunities for new business to form. And they say this
Speaker 4:  in an officious academic way and they push their glasses up in their nose
Speaker 4:  and they walk away smoking a pipe. This is that moment
Speaker 4:  only everyone is also having the most emotional reactions
Speaker 4:  to change. Yeah. That are possible.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, it's, it's a lot. Anyway, I'm your friend. NELI. David. Pierce
Speaker 4:  is here. Hi Alex. Cranz is here from Texas.
Speaker 6:  Yes. I I am currently in the 1970s in Texas.
Speaker 6:  Judging from my background right
Speaker 4:  Now, it's a lot.
Speaker 6:  So it's a lot.
Speaker 4:  You got the room divider. It's, there's a lot going on back there.
Speaker 5:  It's a good time. It's a good time. The one decorative plate behind you is,
Speaker 5:  is every house I've ever been in in my life, there's one decorative plate
Speaker 5:  and I always appreciate it. Well,
Speaker 6:  You can't see 'em, but there are, there is more than one decorative plate
Speaker 6:  in this space.
Speaker 4:  Everyone pull over in your cars and mail a picture of your decorative plate
Speaker 4:  to David at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  Yes, please. Thank you.
Speaker 4:  Now if that, we do an entire installer that is just photos of
Speaker 4:  decorative plates. That's pretty good. That's fair. I
Speaker 5:  Should say, speaking of emails that you have requested to everyone who emailed
Speaker 5:  asking for Eli's 10,000 word feature on the Samsung Frame tv.
Speaker 5:  It has been greenlit. I hear you. And now what I would like you to do is
Speaker 5:  yell at NELI for, for not filing 10,000 words about the same
Speaker 6:  Time NELI
Speaker 4:  And TV where it Yeah, just get it done. I have a, I I've, I've already
Speaker 4:  begun to do some reporting, I will tell you,
Speaker 4:  and it is the silliest reporting of all time.
Speaker 5:  Does it mean just yelling at your tv?
Speaker 4:  No, I just ran into the person who runs the art store on the train.
Speaker 4:  That's my reporting. He was like, what's up?
Speaker 4:  Like, there you go. So I'm work, I'm working on it.
Speaker 5:  That's kind, it's your version of all the people who say like, there are
Speaker 5:  all these politics reporters who are like, the best way to get scoops is
Speaker 5:  just get on like an Acela car on Amtrak between New York
Speaker 5:  and DC and just listen to people's phone calls. Yeah. Yours is just like,
Speaker 5:  get on one going into New York City and ask what startup they found.
Speaker 4:  Pretty much, pretty much. I love it. What Samsung
Speaker 4:  acquisition were you in the, in the mid 2010s? I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm working on it. I will say if you're watching this on YouTube, you,
Speaker 4:  I'm in the new studio that our producer Liam has built for me mostly
Speaker 4:  by mailing me Amazon packages, which is great, but he put up the wall right
Speaker 4:  behind me. Very good. Great. With a circular saw that Liam and there
Speaker 4:  is a Frame TV that is yet to be hung on the wall behind me, just looming
Speaker 4:  over the show with a Verge cast logo on it. That's good. It's gonna be
Speaker 4:  great. I can't get away from them if I tried, but I will. I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 4:  I have a lot to say about the Frame tv. That is not this show though. This
Speaker 4:  episode of the show, there's actual news. There's not
Speaker 4:  just me having feelings about mid-range television that we've tared up bit.
Speaker 4:  There's new MacBook Air, we got some Microsoft News coming, there's iPad
Speaker 4:  rumors, then there is the Digital Markets Act in Europe, which went into
Speaker 4:  effect today as we are speaking all the big platforms from Google,
Speaker 4:  Facebook, apple, they're all changing. All of those people,
Speaker 4:  I would say are coping in whatever
Speaker 4:  way you wish to interpret the word cope.
Speaker 5:  There are a lot of people who need hugs it seems like. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Cope is a generous term.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  In whichever way you wish to interpret the word cope,
Speaker 4:  however you wanna interpret the word cope, I would say that our major platforms
Speaker 4:  are coping. That's
Speaker 6:  About right. That's fair.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Let's start with products. Yeah. Let's start with hardware. There's
Speaker 4:  new MacBook air in this world, which Apple just sort of snuck out into the
Speaker 4:  world. David, what's going on?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so we've been kind of expecting Apple to announce
Speaker 5:  it was gonna have a spring event. Normally in March, not every
Speaker 5:  year but many years, it'll do a thing where it launches
Speaker 5:  usually new iPads and then a smorgasbord of other
Speaker 5:  stuff depending on what they're doing. But usually iPads are the center.
Speaker 5:  It seems like this year we're not gonna get that and instead we're gonna
Speaker 5:  get a parade of press releases and the first one that came out is
Speaker 5:  two new MacBook errors. There's the new 13 inch and the new
Speaker 5:  15 inch. They have M three chips. They're basically
Speaker 5:  just spec bumps. Right. Little faster. There was a mention of six G in
Speaker 5:  the press release, which I find personally infuriating. There
Speaker 5:  was lots of noise about them being good for ai, which I think is essentially
Speaker 5:  just a way to say like, these have pretty fast processors and no one else
Speaker 5:  knows what that means. No.
Speaker 4:  I wanna spend maybe an hour on the one paragraph where Apple said these are
Speaker 4:  the best consumer laptops for ai.
Speaker 6:  The best
Speaker 5:  Utterly meaningless sentence.
Speaker 4:  It will not be this hour in this second, not starting now, but
Speaker 4:  later in this episode, we're gonna take that apart word by word.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I'm excited about that. So yeah, it, these new ones, they
Speaker 5:  support dual displays for the first time, which people are excited about
Speaker 5:  if the
Speaker 4:  Lid is closed. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah's, it's really, it's really something. I
Speaker 4:  Feel like my job on this section of the podcast is to copy out everything
Speaker 4:  David is saying.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry.
Speaker 5:  No, that's okay. We got a real, like you finish his, we finish each other's
Speaker 5:  sentences, vibe going on right now,
Speaker 4:  But it at the end of the sentence is real mad.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 4:  Like here's a fact, here's an angrier fact.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I love this. For us, they also killed the wedge. The
Speaker 5:  M1 MacBook error is no longer being sold, which is the end of that design.
Speaker 5:  All that's left is the M two and the M three. I have a lot of feelings about
Speaker 5:  that, but basically it's like new MacBook errors. They're a little better.
Speaker 5:  They're a little less expensive. Here you go. I can see why If you
Speaker 5:  Apple, you don't have an event for this. They're just like, remember The,
Speaker 5:  MacBook, Air. This is The MacBook Air now. And you're like, all right, they've
Speaker 5:  MacBook
Speaker 6:  Air. Well they've been kind of doing that a little bit, right? Like sometimes
Speaker 6:  they're just like, we got, it's a spec bump. You don, you don't need me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you don't need like Tim Cook to dance for this. Just enjoy your spec
Speaker 6:  bump. No,
Speaker 5:  I'm not mad at it. These look like great laptops like it. It is
Speaker 5:  the The MacBook Air is just so thoroughly the best
Speaker 5:  thousand dollar PC on the planet right now that I feel like Apple is just
Speaker 5:  like, you get it
Speaker 5:  here. It's
Speaker 4:  Yeah. you know when they announced these MacBook errors there, there was
Speaker 4:  an event and they kind of didn't have a lot to say like the last event. That's
Speaker 4:  true. With MacBooks at it. They were like, it's 15 inches.
Speaker 4:  you know,
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook just held the camera, just stared it down. It was like,
Speaker 6:  yeah, that's it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We had a whole conversation about the feet on The MacBook Air in the
Speaker 5:  eye. Do you remember that? Because that was the only thing to talk about.
Speaker 5:  It's like, look, there's little feet.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, they did like a demo of pages. Like for real, they did a demo like,
Speaker 4:  you know, and they're like the, it's because the screen is larger. You can
Speaker 4:  make the windows bigger. This was a real thing that happened. Natalie, I'm
Speaker 4:  not making this up even a little bit. That's real So I. Get what you're saying
Speaker 4:  when you say that they're, they've run out of things to say, but when
Speaker 4:  they spec bumped Intel MacBooks, they just spec bumped
Speaker 4:  them, which is fascinating, right? They're like, well here's some new Intel
Speaker 4:  processors. We didn't want to use 'em, but we have to until we figure out
Speaker 4:  how to shove an iPhone processor into here. But here they are. It's a core,
Speaker 4:  whatever Intel says this is called this year, right? Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  they would sometimes do a press release. They sometimes wouldn't. I feel
Speaker 4:  like they've hit that point with the M three, but because they make the M
Speaker 4:  three and they're very proud of it, they have to act like it's bigger
Speaker 4:  than it's Well
Speaker 6:  It's, it's the best processor for ai so they have to promote it.
Speaker 5:  Wait,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yes. That's like exactly what I mean. It's like
Speaker 4:  they have to make up some stuff. Yeah. And the world's best
Speaker 4:  consumer laptop for AI is a wild
Speaker 4:  thing to say. Yep. I agree. They're probably very good
Speaker 4:  at some AI related tasks. They have a list M three includes a
Speaker 4:  faster and more efficient 16 core neural engine along with accelerators and
Speaker 4:  CPU and GPU to boost on-device machine learning, leveraging this incredible
Speaker 4:  AI performance, blah blah blah blah blah. Here's some stuff you can do. You
Speaker 4:  can check your homework with AI math assistance in Good note six.
Speaker 4:  I love it. If you're doing your math homework in good note six,
Speaker 4:  I'm guessing you don't need AI like computers
Speaker 4:  historically great at math,
Speaker 4:  real problem.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm just wondering about that. Okay. You can automatically enhance photos
Speaker 4:  and pixel later probe. That's great. I've talked about how much I like using
Speaker 4:  the enhanced features in Lightroom. If those are faster in the in three,
Speaker 4:  that's great. We're moving background noise from video using Cap Cut. Who
Speaker 4:  on earth is using Cap Cut on a MacBook?
Speaker 5:  I literally didn't know that was a thing you could do. If I'm being completely
Speaker 5:  honest. You
Speaker 4:  See what I'm saying? I'm pretty sure that's the iOS cap cut
Speaker 5:  App. Yeah. That you just use on your Mac. I don't, it's it's kind of a good
Speaker 5:  idea. I can sort of see it. It's a good app. I just, how do you not read
Speaker 5:  all of this as Apple? Just being like, our things are very fast. Do you like
Speaker 5:  to do fast things Come do fast things,
Speaker 4:  But that's what you do every time. Yeah. Try. Okay. So, I'm looking at Cap
Speaker 4:  cut, try out the Cap cut desktop version. It's the iPad version of Cap
Speaker 4:  Cut.
Speaker 5:  Perfect. Great,
Speaker 4:  Great. Beautiful Prove. But I to like, that's not
Speaker 4:  a lot
Speaker 4:  say like it's very cool that Apple has these trips and that
Speaker 4:  by Dance Ships a video editor that makes use of the tools, but
Speaker 4:  that is downstream of the fact that they make TikTok on the iPhone
Speaker 4:  because If, you people don't know Cap Cut is the TikTok video editor broken
Speaker 4:  out and made into an app. And by the way, If, you can figure it out. You're
Speaker 4:  a genius. You don't need ai 'cause the TikTok video editor in
Speaker 4:  are very confusing.
Speaker 4:  Not to say people don't figure them out teens. The teens are brilliant. It's
Speaker 4:  just fast. Things are fast is wild. Then you get down to what people actually
Speaker 4:  think of ai, which is MacBook Air can run optimized
Speaker 4:  AI models including large language models and diffusion models
Speaker 4:  for image generation locally with great performance. Mm. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  I'm also sure that is true. Yeah. I am also a hundred percent
Speaker 4:  sure that Mark Zuckerberg is out here being like, I've bought more Nvidia
Speaker 4:  H one hundreds than anyone else in history. Developers should come here because
Speaker 4:  I have them all.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that there's a huge split in
Speaker 4:  where AI is being deployed and built and you
Speaker 4:  can run it on an M three MacBook error. And I, I think
Speaker 4:  Apple's just trying to,
Speaker 6:  Apple's not the only one that did this though, right? Because like both Lenovo,
Speaker 6:  hp, everybody at CES was like, look at our new laptops. They're
Speaker 6:  the best at running AI stuff. And you're like, what? AI stuff. And they're
Speaker 6:  like AI stuff the best.
Speaker 4:  Can I just offer you one more sentence from this re release?
Speaker 5:  This is the best one. I can't believe it took you this long to get to this.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's been a slow build and I Alex thank you for the AlleyOOP here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Because this here I'm for you here. This was the thing that ended all
Speaker 4:  of the Windows laptops when they're like, you know, like Microsoft
Speaker 4:  copilot because what Apple has written in its press release is in
Speaker 4:  addition to on-device performance, MacBook air supports
Speaker 4:  cloud-based solutions enabling users to run powerful
Speaker 4:  productivity and creative apps that tap into the power of Microsoft ai
Speaker 4:  such as Microsoft Copilot for Microsoft 365 Canva and
Speaker 4:  Adobe Firefly.
Speaker 5:  Can I translate that sentence for you just very quickly? Yeah, please. Yes.
Speaker 5:  The MacBook Air has wifi,
Speaker 5:  we get it. Everybody
Speaker 4:  Like, you know, it's a press internet, like whatever
Speaker 4:  you need to put some words in a press release. I'm not, you know, don't over
Speaker 4:  index on this. It's hilarious. But it's kind of like we are
Speaker 4:  just outta things to say, we're like we made the best laptop. I don't know
Speaker 4:  Chad, GPT say some shit about ai.
Speaker 5:  It's really the funniest set of problems to have because ordinarily, right,
Speaker 5:  they'd be like, okay, here are the list of things that it does that are
Speaker 5:  substantially faster. And this personally says a little bit of that. It's
Speaker 5:  like it Excel spreadsheets are up to 35% faster, which is a
Speaker 5:  completely meaningless statistic about anything. It's
Speaker 4:  Very good
Speaker 5:  Video editing's a little faster. But it's like this whole thing is
Speaker 5:  just a lot of words to say this laptop rules,
Speaker 5:  it already does everything you wanted it to. It's done everything you wanted
Speaker 5:  it to for two generations now. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be fine. Just buy this laptop.
Speaker 4:  What do you want A 16 inch screen, right? Like one
Speaker 5:  Decade. Remember when we fixed the battery and now that's not a thing you
Speaker 5:  worry about in your laptop. You're welcome for that again. Yeah, that's still
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I'll call it the two things. One, they call out the headphone track,
Speaker 4:  which is a personal victory for NELI lap Patel. You can't
Speaker 4:  you, you can't take it off this computer. Nope. It's a disaster. And you
Speaker 4:  know it, you know it in your heart. You shouldn't have taken it off the phone.
Speaker 4:  Especially now that the phones are huge and you gotta deal with it. Second,
Speaker 4:  the two external displays with the lid closed is, what are we doing
Speaker 4:  that by the way, that're closing the lid applies that all the old ones,
Speaker 4:  all the old ones can support two displays with, right? 'cause you got the
Speaker 4:  lid up and another display.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's still just two displays. It's just
Speaker 4:  Two displays. You should let all those people have two displays with the
Speaker 4:  lid closed. You gonna force an upgrade to an M three so they
Speaker 4:  can run Canva in a web browser.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We've made a gigantic performance breakthrough. The display can be over
Speaker 5:  there now. We've done it everybody.
Speaker 4:  It's a lot. What's interesting about this is, you know,
Speaker 4:  it comes on sort of the heels of a report, I believe from Mark Germond at
Speaker 4:  Bloomberg saying they're gonna roll out a bunch of stuff over the
Speaker 4:  next few weeks. So we were expecting the MacBook error.
Speaker 4:  iOS 17.4 is out, that's the DMA compliance release. We'll
Speaker 4:  get to that in a minute. But that is support supposed to support new iPads
Speaker 4:  as well. If in days past a
Speaker 4:  new MacBook, some new iPads, some other new products or whatever that is
Speaker 4:  an Apple event. And I think now the pressure is on them to be like it's a
Speaker 4:  vision pro. It's the next iPhone and
Speaker 4:  I, I wonder if they've just sort of gotten themselves
Speaker 4:  miscalibrated on what people actually care about, which is like new products
Speaker 4:  they will use and buy, buy and use. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I mean this is like the most mainstream product Apple makes in this,
Speaker 5:  in this like category, right? So if ever you were going to be like,
Speaker 5:  here's a thing that many, many, many, many people want and are going to buy.
Speaker 5:  This is the one. but it does make for a deeply uninteresting event.
Speaker 5:  Like I, I feel for whoever would have to stand there and make a long speech
Speaker 5:  about how the M three chip is gonna change your life. Yeah. but
Speaker 6:  It could have been the thing after an iPad with Pro, with an
Speaker 6:  OLED display and you're like, look at the iPad Pro with the OLED display
Speaker 6:  and here's some iPad airs. Those are cool. And then one last thing,
Speaker 6:  MacBook Airs got an M three in 'em now. Great. And we're done. Like
Speaker 6:  that would've been a nice, nice event. I would've enjoyed watching that while
Speaker 6:  you guys fly out to it. It would've been good times.
Speaker 4:  This is the other problem. They have to, they have to make infomercials now
Speaker 4:  for all their events. Yeah. Yep. And I bet the infomercial team is like,
Speaker 4:  we don't, we don't know what to do here.
Speaker 6:  We, it's five minutes long
Speaker 4:  Old MacBook air. It's too hard to hold. Like
Speaker 4:  what are you gonna do? Like someone using a Windows laptop, it explodes into
Speaker 4:  flames. You're like, whereas when you actually had in-person events, you
Speaker 4:  could talk about the computer. Yeah. By the way David, I, I
Speaker 4:  just looked at the, it's 35% faster at Excel
Speaker 4:  and there's a foot, there's a footnote and the footnote is testing was conducted
Speaker 4:  by Apple in January, 2024. See apple.com/ MacBook dash air
Speaker 4:  for more information. Which means Apple just did some tests.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Literally opened one spreadsheet and said that we did it.
Speaker 4:  Very unclear what those tests are and then you go to that webpage and the
Speaker 4:  It does not, it does not tell you what the tests were.
Speaker 5:  That's very strange.
Speaker 4:  If anyone knows how to measure the performance of Excel,
Speaker 4:  let us know. I'm sure you can. I'm I'm sure that
Speaker 6:  No, I used Tom
Speaker 4:  Microsoft team. But is there a standard Excel speed test for
Speaker 4:  computers? No,
Speaker 6:  No. We would make, we made one a place. I worked, we we had one and
Speaker 6:  it had like 50,000 names on it and then you'd have to press a button
Speaker 6:  and it would process all the names and you'd time it. Oh that's fun.
Speaker 6:  And it was, it was a fun test. I mean it was really obnoxious to do
Speaker 6:  but it was, it was kind of cool. And then all of them got to be about the
Speaker 6:  same speed, which was real fast and it was no longer a useful
Speaker 6:  test. So I guess we'll go make a fun
Speaker 6:  Excel spreadsheet again. You
Speaker 5:  Bring up an interesting point with that actually, which is that like with
Speaker 5:  the AI stuff, the idea of this
Speaker 5:  benchmarking kind of tool might actually be interesting again. Yeah, like
Speaker 5:  one thing I think about a lot is the only AI thing I do on my
Speaker 5:  specific computer locally is transcriptions. I have this app
Speaker 5:  called Mac Whisper that I use. I just feed in
Speaker 5:  an audio file that from an interview or a YouTube video I need quotes from
Speaker 5:  or whatever. And it just transcribes it using Whisper
Speaker 5:  from OpenAI and it runs locally on the device. It's pretty fast.
Speaker 5:  but it has this really fascinating, you can either download the small
Speaker 5:  crappy version of it that's really fast or the huge really good version of
Speaker 5:  it that's super slow. And and for me the idea of being able to like
Speaker 5:  cut in half the time it would take me to do the very good one is like a
Speaker 5:  meaningful thing in a way that a faster processor has not been meaningful
Speaker 5:  to me in a very long time. So I think with the image stuff and
Speaker 5:  with that kind of stuff, like local AI is going to mean something
Speaker 5:  and speed of that is going to mean something. I just think for most people
Speaker 5:  we're like a generation or two of devices away from that. And at
Speaker 5:  least for now, basically everything is gonna keep happening in the
Speaker 5:  cloud. So like the most AI forward thing Apple did in this moment is
Speaker 5:  wifi. But like someday I think this will be real. So like the
Speaker 5:  idea that we can be an AI focused laptop, I think is a thing
Speaker 5:  just not yet for most people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. And the questions is like what do you want to benchmark in that
Speaker 4:  case? Is it image generation? Is it AI transcription? Is
Speaker 4:  it text generation? Is it Yeah. Make
Speaker 4:  a image of Hitler that's so not racist. It becomes racist again.
Speaker 5:  It's probably not that one. If I had to,
Speaker 4:  Probably not. I'm guessing that will not be a, a released benchmark,
Speaker 4:  but if someone wants to do it. Sure. So that's
Speaker 4:  that. I wanna talk about the iPads, but before we do that, I feel like we
Speaker 4:  should give Alex a moment to just mourn the passing of the
Speaker 4:  Wedge MacBook Air.
Speaker 5:  I'm bummed
Speaker 4:  Alex. I know you quite a lot of feelings about this. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I had feelings and then I made Victoria write the feelings because I'm in
Speaker 6:  Texas.
Speaker 4:  The power of being had the feelings too. Being the
Speaker 6:  Editor. Yeah. The power of being the editor. Well no, we both had the same
Speaker 6:  feelings, which was like, the wedge was cool and it packed a bigger battery
Speaker 6:  too. Remember like the battery life was really, really good on that in one
Speaker 6:  MacBook Air. And I, I missed that and it was just like,
Speaker 6:  it had an identity. And now The MacBook Air kind of
Speaker 6:  doesn't, like, there's not a big difference between it and
Speaker 6:  the MacBook Pro physically
Speaker 6:  at
Speaker 4:  All. Or any laptop.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, it's just like, okay now it's just a really good laptop and that's
Speaker 6:  cool, but before it was like, it's a really good laptop that's a little like
Speaker 6:  wedge shaped. And four of us noticed that. But us four really cared
Speaker 6:  about it and we were really passionate
Speaker 4:  About it. It remember the first MacBook error, Steve Jobs pulled it outta
Speaker 4:  the manila envelope, which was a big deal to be like, look at how small our
Speaker 4:  computer is.
Speaker 5:  One of the great reveals still
Speaker 4:  So good. one of the great reveals, I encourage you to all
Speaker 4:  go back and look at photos and reviews of that first MacBook Air. It was
Speaker 4:  Garbage, which was such a deeply compromised device. They built it
Speaker 4:  around a custom Intel processor that Intel didn't know what to do with because
Speaker 4:  it was so underpowered. And they're like, and Apple and Steve
Speaker 4:  Jobs and Johnny AV were like, what if Tiny Computer,
Speaker 4:  the ports were on a flat down door on the side. Oh yeah. This thing was weird.
Speaker 4:  It was like a different design language entirely. It was very, it was like
Speaker 4:  Bulbus, the second generation MacBook Care, the iconic
Speaker 4:  wedge shape came later when they had done the
Speaker 4:  iPhone and some other things and they, they were like, what do we bring back
Speaker 4:  to the Mac? And the thing they wanted to bring back the most was instant
Speaker 4:  on when you open the lid. Because Mac didn't used to wake up right away.
Speaker 4:  They, they were computers. They would like, they would like emit steam and
Speaker 4:  like make warring sounds. So the main thing they wanted was when you open
Speaker 4:  the lid, it would be ready to go like an iPhone. It would be ready to go
Speaker 4:  when you hit the wake button and they had to build all this stuff. And that
Speaker 4:  was like the moment The MacBook Air became the MacBook carrier. You had the
Speaker 4:  wedge shape, it was still really small. Alex the battery thing was a real
Speaker 4:  big deal back then. They Yep. They built these, I think they called them
Speaker 4:  terrorist batteries. It was a whole deal. It was a whole thing. Like there's
Speaker 4:  a Johnny I video, he's like, the batteries are in steps, like a terrace,
Speaker 4:  like a thing. Oh yeah, you can go watch it. All that is
Speaker 4:  amazing. Wal Mossberg famously
Speaker 4:  bought like five MacBook errors to like have in his house
Speaker 4:  because he didn't wanna use any other laptop and he was afraid they were
Speaker 4:  gonna discontinue them in that weird period where Apple like stopped
Speaker 4:  caring about the Mac,
Speaker 5:  It was the butterfly keyboard era is what it was like that was the moment
Speaker 5:  that it was like, oh, maybe these are just going to get worse again. And
Speaker 5:  then they stopped and they got better again
Speaker 4:  Because people realized that Max were infinitely more capable than iPads.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What if we just like made computers that were good and people wanted
Speaker 5:  to use what a, what a meeting that must have been.
Speaker 5:  But I think, I mean to me, like I, I've been trying to think about how I
Speaker 5:  feel about the Wedge 'cause the comments on V'S piece are very funny 'cause
Speaker 5:  it's a bunch of people being like, oh, The Verge. You yell at people for
Speaker 5:  not redesigning their stuff every two years and then you yell at them when
Speaker 5:  they redesign their stuff every two years for getting rid of their iconic
Speaker 5:  designs. And I think there's maybe something to that, but I
Speaker 5:  also feel like the wedge was legitimately
Speaker 5:  like an iconic piece of laptop design. Yeah. Yep. And
Speaker 5:  also it was better. Like I, I, I cannot
Speaker 5:  prove it, but I sincerely believe that typing on that like very slight incline
Speaker 5:  with your hands felt better than the flat thing that I'm kind of
Speaker 5:  perching on top of. On other MacBooks. It's why I liked the air over the
Speaker 5:  pro that like it's thinner, it's lighter, but also it, it
Speaker 5:  felt a little better to just have my hands on. Yeah. And maybe I just like
Speaker 5:  need to get used to that. I still mostly use an M1 air all the time and I
Speaker 5:  love it to pieces. And I will say one of the truly wild things for me
Speaker 5:  as a tech lover is now I am two full
Speaker 5:  revs of this device out of date and still have no
Speaker 5:  compulsion to upgrade. Like I just don't need this computer. My M1 air is
Speaker 5:  still good and is going to be for a long time. Yeah. Which is a crazy place
Speaker 5:  for Apple to be, but it is also like as a laptop user kind of amazing.
Speaker 4:  We got a bunch of notes last week after we talked about Apple making and
Speaker 4:  TV and like why they didn't make a tv because the upgrade cycles are too
Speaker 4:  long and now the upgrade cycles are too long. And people were like, this
Speaker 4:  is the weirdest I've ever felt. I don't need a new anything. Yep. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  that is a wild place for any of these companies to be in. Like
Speaker 4:  you just don't need a new one. They all kind of do the things and everyone's
Speaker 4:  chasing whatever shiny object that you think will be The future. But
Speaker 4:  at the point where you're like, well it runs Chrome and using Chrome I can
Speaker 4:  access cutting edge AI system for sake better than ever before.
Speaker 4:  You're kind of at a, you're kind of at a place where you gotta figure out
Speaker 4:  what the next thing a laptop is gonna do. The thing that gets me about the
Speaker 4:  wed shape in particular. And Alex, I'm very curious for your read on this.
Speaker 4:  Apple tried to kill The MacBook Air a lot. Yes. Like
Speaker 4:  they tried really hard. They didn't update it to Retina for years.
Speaker 4:  They just left this thing alone and they tried to push everyone towards that,
Speaker 4:  that weird middle 13 inch MacBook
Speaker 4:  Pro that they made that Yeah. Like obviously wasn't a MacBook Pro. Like
Speaker 4:  the real MacBook Pro had four ports and this one only had two. And it was
Speaker 4:  like you just made a MacBook error and put it in a case of the retina display
Speaker 4:  and called it a MacBook Pro. Phil Siller stood on a stage one
Speaker 4:  year and did like volumetric analysis of The
Speaker 4:  MacBook Air in the MacBook Pro and was like, this one is actually smaller,
Speaker 4:  why won't you buy this one? And everyone's like, I don't know. I like the
Speaker 4:  web shape. And they kept selling them until they, they, they were
Speaker 4:  effectively forced to un kill it. Like their
Speaker 4:  answer to us, to other people who asked was like, people just keep buying
Speaker 4:  this computer. Like we have to just keep making it. Like what do you want
Speaker 4:  us to do? So they updated it, they revved it, they put the retina screen
Speaker 4:  in it. They eventually put the M1 in it. And now I think Alex
Speaker 4:  what they did was they just made that 13 inch MacBook Pro.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And they just called it a MacBook Air. Yes. And that's what that
Speaker 4:  that's the thing you're reacting to. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 4:  That, that's The MacBook Air was a design.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They, they, they had something that was like really thoughtfully designed
Speaker 6:  and stood out and people said, yes, this is a thing I want
Speaker 6:  to own in my house and if I'm Walt Mossberg I wanna own five
Speaker 6:  of them. And, and then they said, okay, what if we just took the MacBook
Speaker 6:  Pro, which is very, very good. I'm, I'm currently podcasting from one.
Speaker 6:  Love it. And we just made it a little lighter and cheaper
Speaker 6:  and we called it an error. That's not the same
Speaker 6:  thing. I mean technically it is, it is the new MacBook air, but it's,
Speaker 6:  it's not quite the same. Like this was a thing that was so
Speaker 6:  well designed. You just wanted to have one. Even if even the underpowered
Speaker 6:  versions of it, you still wanted to have it, even when it had a garbage display,
Speaker 6:  you still wanted it because it was just, it worked. It like the design, everything
Speaker 6:  came together just right and then they said, nah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's all over. And
Speaker 6:  It feels like they're, they're focused more on, on the guts than they are
Speaker 6:  on the outside design, which is fine. Like they've spent a long time only
Speaker 6:  focused on the outside design and not the guts. So it's, it's good that they're
Speaker 6:  thinking about the guts, but I would like a, a balance of design and
Speaker 6:  thinking about really smart guts for your cool laptop.
Speaker 6:  That'd
Speaker 4:  Be nice. You want, do you want them to be beautiful on the inside and the
Speaker 4:  outside? Yeah. The dream.
Speaker 6:  The dream.
Speaker 5:  I think part of it also is that like, I think the thing that Apple may have
Speaker 5:  underestimated for a while is how good The
Speaker 5:  MacBook Air brand is. Yes. Yes. Like I just think about Joanna
Speaker 5:  Stern spending a decade reviewing laptops and being like for
Speaker 5:  $200 more you can buy a MacBook error. Like it became a meme
Speaker 5:  that you, for $200 more you can just buy a MacBook error and that's the
Speaker 5:  right thing to do. Like I think that has a sort of
Speaker 5:  immediate reception in people's minds as like that's the best laptop
Speaker 5:  that is just If. you don't know which laptop to buy. Just buy a MacBook error
Speaker 5:  has been true for so long. Even when it wasn't true
Speaker 5:  and it wasn't true for a minute there because it did get weird and old, but
Speaker 5:  it was still like the default laptop. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  I, to some extent, I think it's wild that Apple kind of tried to throw that
Speaker 5:  away and I think also thought that that was just a story about MacBooks.
Speaker 5:  But I think it's not, I think it is a thing about The MacBook Air and
Speaker 5:  so and so now even when it is essentially just like a, a proin
Speaker 5:  in a very real way. Like the distinction between those two is just incredible
Speaker 4:  Branding.
Speaker 5:  David Minus You. I thought you'd like that the
Speaker 5:  MacBook Pro mini, I don't know, call it whatever you want, but it's
Speaker 5:  like the heir name I think is actually really important and I think Apple
Speaker 5:  understands that in a way that it didn't for a while.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. Lemme make the counter argument just for a second, but then we should
Speaker 4:  move on. Please. Apple's branding is hopelessly confused.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And they are addicted to some words that have lost all
Speaker 4:  meaning but they don't know what other words to use.
Speaker 4:  True. I don't know so true what AirPods Pro are, I just don't What is
Speaker 4:  professional at AirPods? Like unless you're using the Vision Pro, they're
Speaker 4:  necessarily compressed audio and you shouldn't do anything professional with
Speaker 4:  them except appearing cable news from time to time.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like an iPad Pro is just an iPad
Speaker 4:  with a nicer screen and more Ram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I know what a MacBook Pro is that's designed to run like
Speaker 4:  pro applications. I know what a Mac Pro is. I,
Speaker 4:  you know, it's like we're all over the place. What is why, what is the Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro? What is the vision minus like
Speaker 4:  these, these words they, they just have these words that like signify something
Speaker 4:  to their audience. I think you could get to a place where you have a
Speaker 4:  MacBook, remember they used to just have a regular old MacBook and then you
Speaker 4:  could have a MacBook Air which would be an ultra portable, like a
Speaker 4:  12 inch computer. That was really powerful. But I think the problem is consumers
Speaker 4:  have said very loudly what they would like is 13 to 15 inch laptops.
Speaker 4:  And so you have to take your best brand and put it in that box. And MacBook
Speaker 4:  Care is by four the best brand for that
Speaker 5:  Box. Yeah. I think what Apple wants is to have a MacBook and a MacBook
Speaker 5:  Pro and Mac and Apple tried to do that for a while. It's just
Speaker 5:  that it made the MacBook bad and made a bunch
Speaker 5:  of bad decisions about the MacBook and also spent several years
Speaker 5:  sort of steadfastly ruining its entire computer lineup before fixing it.
Speaker 5:  And but I think like 10 years ago, apple
Speaker 5:  wanted to have a MacBook and a MacBook Pro and so
Speaker 5:  badly botched the MacBook that I think it just had to go back to the MacBook
Speaker 5:  era. Like there was a minute they wanted that to be the one, they
Speaker 4:  Should just release that plaque plastic MacBook again. They
Speaker 5:  Should,
Speaker 4:  That black plastic MacBook was a triumph of this one. It was. Alright, we
Speaker 4:  should move on from just naval gazing with The MacBook Air look
Speaker 4:  release a wed shaped computer and Alex will buy it. That's
Speaker 5:  I I will say the fact that I cannot wait for our reviews because if they
Speaker 5:  actually got rid of the fingerprinting is on the midnight one. That might
Speaker 5:  be the thing that makes me actually kind of lust after an M three MacBook
Speaker 5:  air. 'cause the M two one looked great but then you touch it and it's gross
Speaker 5:  forever and hopefully they fix that.
Speaker 4:  So we are in different places because the other rumor is that they're going
Speaker 4:  to refresh the iPad lineup and actually make it make sense that
Speaker 4:  they will have an iPad Pro and iPad Air and then the iPad Air and the iPad
Speaker 4:  Pro are pretty fuzzy right
Speaker 5:  Now. Have you seen the rumor that there's not gonna be a 12.9 inch iPad air?
Speaker 5:  Because that makes sense. Yeah. But what if we had more models? NELI, can
Speaker 5:  I interest you in more iPads?
Speaker 4:  Every now and again I'm reminded that Tim Cook is a supply chain expert,
Speaker 4:  you know and like he's like, what if I just flex on my ability to
Speaker 4:  manage the complexity of the supply chain? That's what I got. You want
Speaker 4:  4,000 SKUs? I got you 8,000 come
Speaker 4:  at me. I'm Tim Cook. I mean that's fine. You could just do it.
Speaker 4:  He's like, how many manufacturers and how many countries double it?
Speaker 4:  Why are you still in the room? By the way, that's the most famous Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  story. I wanna, I think about all the time when he had the meeting about
Speaker 4:  some prom in China and then he looked at his executive and he is like, why
Speaker 4:  are you still here? And the guy got up and flew
Speaker 5:  To China, didn't go home, didn't pack a bag, just went to China.
Speaker 4:  Just went straight to China rules. Wow. Very good. And that's how you
Speaker 4:  get a 12.9 inch iPad air. He's like, what are you doing? This isn't enough
Speaker 4:  Excuse. Get outta here.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't know what his meetings are like at all. Is that You should
Speaker 4:  come on de coder Tim, please tell me what actually goes on in your life.
Speaker 4:  What I think is really interesting about the iPads is they're gonna put an
Speaker 4:  OLED screen in an iPad Pro and I do not need to upgrade my iPad Pro
Speaker 4:  and I will buy that product so fast. Yes, a hundred percent. Why?
Speaker 4:  Because Ola, why, why am I gonna do that?
Speaker 5:  It's the same reason you have a stupid Sony tv. It's
Speaker 4:  The same
Speaker 5:  Reason like there there is just a subset of people in the world
Speaker 5:  headlined by one NELI Patel who If you just say the word ole,
Speaker 5:  they will start just hawking money in your general direction. And when you
Speaker 5:  run out of ideas you just say Ole Now and
Speaker 5:  NELI buys it.
Speaker 4:  That's perfect by the way, can I just say Becky and I watched anyone
Speaker 4:  but you on Bravia core on the new Sony Ole And boy,
Speaker 4:  if there's one movie that does not need to be stringed at 80 megabits per
Speaker 4:  second, it is anything but you,
Speaker 4:  nothing in this movie is moving faster,
Speaker 5:  But that like doubles the amount of stuff that's on Bravia course. So that's
Speaker 5:  pretty exciting.
Speaker 4:  It's like they got one, they did it
Speaker 4:  anyhow. I, I hope they can reconcile the iPad line a little bit
Speaker 4:  with all of these changes and actually be like, okay, the pro has the nicest
Speaker 4:  display. Yeah. Not yeah, the same display
Speaker 4:  with a nicer backlight. We'll see none of this stuff is gonna get an event
Speaker 4:  so that we will have very little opportunity to ask questions
Speaker 4:  about it. you know, like we're gonna get them and we'll review them and that
Speaker 4:  will be that. But I think it's funny that Apple doesn't think adding up its
Speaker 4:  biggest products and announcing them all at once, merits
Speaker 4:  a moment anymore because
Speaker 6:  They're not phones.
Speaker 4:  They're in a place where they have to do really, really flashy things. I
Speaker 4:  I I think they only do the phone 'cause people expect them to do the phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I honestly think with the way they're going right now, unless they
Speaker 4:  change the phone in some giant way that you know, if
Speaker 4:  the next iPhone is a camera bump in a processor bump the argument
Speaker 4:  to not do an event based on what they're doing here is right there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But there's no way they can't do an iPhone event. Right. That's their moment
Speaker 4:  every year.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I do think we're, we're ramping up towards a pretty huge
Speaker 5:  WW DC in June for a variety of reasons. All the AI stuff is rumored to be
Speaker 5:  coming then. And I think like If you want to see a sort of
Speaker 5:  software led hardware cycle coming. I think it probably starts at
Speaker 5:  wwe DC
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I agree with that. And I am very curious to see
Speaker 4:  the best consumer laptop for AI is a clear potential hint
Speaker 4:  towards the next version of Mac os and iOS will have some actual AI features
Speaker 4:  in it besides whatever LLM they claim is powering
Speaker 4:  the world's worst auto Correct in the iPhone keyboard. We should talk about
Speaker 4:  the, the Microsoft news 'cause right next to all of this is the service Pro
Speaker 4:  10 service laptop six Alex, what's going on there?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they, there's some confusion there. Tom, Tom was doing some
Speaker 6:  investigating and because we had one, we
Speaker 6:  had Zach Boden I believe say that we were gonna get a whole
Speaker 6:  new line of surfaces with OLEDs in them
Speaker 6:  announced this month. It sounds like we are gonna get something announced
Speaker 6:  this month, but it's gonna be more for like commercial stuff
Speaker 6:  and then we'll get some consumer stuff later, including
Speaker 6:  some surfaces with OLEDs and arm
Speaker 6:  processors. But we're not really sure if the arm processors are gonna be
Speaker 6:  exclusive to the consumer ones or if we'll also get Intel in them.
Speaker 6:  So there's still things are up in the air, but we're gonna be getting some
Speaker 6:  new surfaces this year. It sounds like we're gonna get a pretty big redesign
Speaker 6:  on, on the Surface Pro and the Surface laptop for consumers, but
Speaker 6:  not necessarily the commercial version.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and the fascinating thing here is that Panas Penne is no longer at
Speaker 4:  Microsoft to run this stuff. So whether or not there's
Speaker 4:  a mission change for Surface or philosophy
Speaker 4:  change for Surface I think is kind of up
Speaker 5:  In date, but we won't see it this time. I think like just the, the product
Speaker 5:  rev cycles are so long that like Panos would've led whatever these are
Speaker 5:  So I. Think if there is an event at which they talk about it, I think that
Speaker 5:  will be interesting. But also we're probably a generation or maybe even
Speaker 5:  two away from new leaders showing big changes.
Speaker 5:  But I also kind of feel like, like I loved the Surface laptop at the beginning.
Speaker 5:  Loved it. It was so nicely designed. It was like soft and
Speaker 5:  comfortable. It came in those good colors. The battery life was like, I loved
Speaker 5:  that thing. And I feel like both the pro and the laptop
Speaker 5:  are kind of long in the tooth at this point. It feels like both
Speaker 5:  are in need of kind of a new idea about what they're
Speaker 5:  supposed to do for you. And I'm sure Microsoft will tell you a whole AI story
Speaker 5:  and there will be a copilot button and everything will be everything. But
Speaker 5:  for me, like the there, there are bits and pieces of the design stuff that
Speaker 5:  Tom has been talking about, but I'm really curious to see if there is a bigger
Speaker 5:  shift in the works here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that thing about the cycles being long when Panas Pane was out
Speaker 4:  there posting about how excited he was about the Alexa hub, I was like, you
Speaker 4:  didn't know that was cunning, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That literally was finished before you started working.
Speaker 4:  M like I wish I could show up and be like, I'm excited about other people's
Speaker 4:  ideas too. I'm in charge now.
Speaker 4:  I I agree with you, but I do think just how they position these products
Speaker 4:  after the leader is gone and there is some new leadership that has to, you
Speaker 4:  know, be accountable for even launching them. Like one thing you do is not
Speaker 4:  make them. Yeah, that's a choice. But I think they're gonna do it. I think
Speaker 4:  they're gonna launch them. I think Microsoft has to be in the game and yet
Speaker 4:  maybe they have a co-pilot button on them. Maybe they put chat CBT right
Speaker 4:  in the camera just to look at you and be like, here's some weird
Speaker 4:  ideas I had. You should leave your wife.
Speaker 4:  That's famously what chat, but he said to you, you remember Yeah,
Speaker 4:  very remember morning for Kevin Ru.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So does Kevin.
Speaker 4:  So do many readers of the New York Times,
Speaker 4:  but I all of that right is like you, you have to make these products for
Speaker 4:  a reason. And one thing we definitely just saw with Microsoft is some
Speaker 4:  big rethinks of why they do things. Yes. Like Xbox just went through
Speaker 4:  a huge rethink of what is Xbox, what are we doing? Why do we make
Speaker 4:  this stuff? And the answer was, we're gonna put the games in only
Speaker 4:  people's platforms now. Like there's more money to be made on the games than
Speaker 4:  than making the games put hardware in your living room. And
Speaker 4:  I, I wonder if Surface is in that place too.
Speaker 5:  IIII think that's very possible. It's gonna be really interesting to see
Speaker 5:  if Microsoft tries to tell a consumer story about these things
Speaker 5:  or is just like, buy these for your point of sale people
Speaker 5:  at work. Which I think it might. Yeah, like I think one of the reasons
Speaker 5:  Panos left was reportedly that Microsoft was pulling back on some
Speaker 5:  of the ambitions for this stuff and that I think you, you might be right
Speaker 5:  that we might start to see pretty fast. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right. We should take a break and we should come back and it's time to
Speaker 4:  get the, the Euro zone, which is a real thing.
Speaker 4:  It's a really cool name for a very boring idea. But we're gonna leave and
Speaker 4:  come back and then we're the VIR has goes to the Euro
Speaker 4:  zone.
Speaker 4:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  safely.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back to clarify for our European listeners, the
Speaker 4:  Euro zone is where they take the euro.
Speaker 4:  It is a very cool name for a very boring thing. Places where you can spend
Speaker 4:  the Euro, which is only 20 of the 27 countries
Speaker 4:  in the EU.
Speaker 5:  The Eurozone is also an amusement park that's just kind of like, it's just
Speaker 5:  Europe everywhere. It's like Epcot, but it's all Europe.
Speaker 4:  You're just like, here's some cheese
Speaker 4:  chocolates. Everyone's very trim. They were, they were, everyone's walking
Speaker 4:  so much. And even that they eat the carbs in the dairy
Speaker 4:  Eurozone. you know, there's a, there's a proposal
Speaker 4:  in in the EU to relabel the fat burning zone on
Speaker 4:  treadmills as the Eurozone
Speaker 5:  Had me the first half. I ain't gonna lie, boy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So look, we're not going to the Eurozone. All right, we're going to
Speaker 4:  the bigger Venn diagram of the Eurozone. the EU itself.
Speaker 4:  Welcome.
Speaker 4:  the EU won't stop. They're, they're, they're doing things. They love regulating
Speaker 4:  companies. It's, it's what they do and maybe they're gonna do
Speaker 4:  a good job this time. Maybe some real changes will happen. We can talk about
Speaker 4:  some changes in the past, which I think informed changes here. But the Digital
Speaker 4:  Markets Act has arrived today, Wednesday, March 6th. The day we are
Speaker 4:  speaking is the day has gone into effect. A bunch of big platforms have
Speaker 4:  been designated as gatekeepers and they have to change how they work. They
Speaker 4:  have to become more interoperable, they have to provide more choices to
Speaker 4:  consumers. All kinds of things are happening. David, can you run us down?
Speaker 4:  There's quite a few. Sure.
Speaker 5:  So there's basically hits six companies. You have Alphabet,
Speaker 5:  Amazon, apple Bite, dance Meta and Microsoft.
Speaker 5:  There is a very real, one of these things is not like the other thing with
Speaker 5:  Bite dance there, which I actually think is very interesting and we should
Speaker 5:  talk about. But essentially all of these companies have been
Speaker 5:  designated as like you said, gatekeepers, which means they are the ones who
Speaker 5:  are so powerful and so important that they should not
Speaker 5:  be allowed to just do whatever they want. And the way that the EU
Speaker 5:  regulates that and has decided has been complicated and everybody is appealing
Speaker 5:  everything and it's all kind of a mess. But essentially we can go through
Speaker 5:  each company if you'd like to. But essentially the way it has boiled down
Speaker 5:  is that these companies now have to offer more
Speaker 5:  transparency and data protections for users.
Speaker 5:  And that shows up in a bunch of different ways. Amazon has had to give
Speaker 5:  advertisers more transparency over like what they're doing and how their
Speaker 5:  ads are doing. Which is a strange and sort of obvious seeming thing.
Speaker 5:  TikTok is now letting you pull a lot of your data out of TikTok and put it
Speaker 5:  into other apps that support it. Meta is giving you more ways
Speaker 5:  to protect your data and not have it shared across meta services. So the
Speaker 5:  idea is like your data should be your data. This is one of the things the
Speaker 5:  EU has been harping on for a long time, right? That I should be in control
Speaker 5:  of my data about me on the internet and all of these six companies are having
Speaker 5:  to do a lot more. Then there are big debates about app stores.
Speaker 5:  I think this one's largely about Apple, at least from what we've seen so
Speaker 5:  far. But we'll hit Google and the Play Store in pretty real ways too.
Speaker 5:  There's the question of like, are you allowed to build
Speaker 5:  in your own apps and preference them over others? So Microsoft
Speaker 5:  in the EU is now allowing you to disable Bing in Uninstall
Speaker 5:  Edge and a bunch of other Microsoft apps. So the idea is just these big companies
Speaker 5:  relentlessly self preference themselves and the EU is essentially saying
Speaker 5:  you have to stop doing that. And there's a fallout in a million directions
Speaker 5:  from that. But that is I think kind of the top line as I've come to think
Speaker 5:  about it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And what's really interesting about that is the amount of big
Speaker 4:  businesses that exist in the world that are
Speaker 4:  organized or at least adapted to that self preferencing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Google searches. I think maybe the clearest example of this in the world,
Speaker 4:  many, many huge industries are just adapted to the notion
Speaker 4:  that Google is where people search for things.
Speaker 5:  Totally.
Speaker 4:  So today I think a bunch of travel services like Flight
Speaker 4:  Airlines and hotels and other kinds of things, put out a letter that's like,
Speaker 4:  we know Google's gonna change, but it should still send us as much traffic
Speaker 4:  as it used to before. Right? And there's like a fear that like change will
Speaker 4:  lead to a different result as opposed to somehow being better but the same.
Speaker 4:  Which is a fascinating way to think about
Speaker 4:  regulatory change. The other thing that's happening is that
Speaker 4:  the changes are hitting things that have never been different.
Speaker 4:  In particular a bunch of Apple services, right?
Speaker 5:  I think those two things are actually really aligned and I'd never really
Speaker 5:  thought about it like that until you just said that. But there is this fascinating
Speaker 5:  thing where it has been like this for so long that
Speaker 5:  actually even if in theory some of these things are going to get better and
Speaker 5:  more pro competition and more fair, which there are a lot of
Speaker 5:  smart people who argue it's actually going to be none of those things. But
Speaker 5:  even if it is those things, it's still going to screw up
Speaker 5:  all of the businesses that are going to be affected by it just because
Speaker 5:  it has been this way for so long and, and just
Speaker 5:  the sheer amount of change that is gonna come for all of these companies,
Speaker 5:  even if it ends up being good in the end, is gonna be such a like
Speaker 5:  crazy whirlwind of new stuff over the next 12
Speaker 5:  months that it's gonna like, it's gonna change a lot of things. And we should
Speaker 5:  say almost all of this is happening just in the
Speaker 5:  EU and the EEA, the European economic area. And if I'm being honest, I
Speaker 5:  don't totally understand the distinction, but I know our international team
Speaker 5:  gets really mad when we say one and it's not the other. So just know that
Speaker 5:  it is whichever one of those is correct is what I'm saying.
Speaker 5:  But we expected a lot of this to be like big global change. I think that
Speaker 5:  the idea was whatever what happened in the EU would sort of roll out everywhere
Speaker 5:  in the world. And that is in almost every case not happening at all. And
Speaker 5:  in fact what's happening is like the, the European internet is going to be
Speaker 5:  one thing and the rest of the world is going to be another So
Speaker 4:  I think one of the reasons we all thought this would happen is
Speaker 4:  I always think about the model of car regulation in the United States.
Speaker 4:  California is a huge market for cars in the United States. It passes
Speaker 4:  some rules. The easiest way to make cars is to make them comply to California's
Speaker 4:  rules. And so California's rules sort of affect everybody else across the
Speaker 4:  country. 'cause the cars are built for California, like emission standards
Speaker 4:  and things like that all happen for California. You can see, okay, Europe's
Speaker 4:  a big market, they're gonna pass some rules. We're gonna have to design the
Speaker 4:  products for the most constricted market that will hit the United States
Speaker 4:  as well. And what all of these companies are saying is, no, our monopolies
Speaker 4:  are pretty good actually. So we're gonna go ahead and
Speaker 4:  spend more money making weird special European versions of our products.
Speaker 4:  And then unless you force us to, we're gonna keep
Speaker 4:  taking the profits, the monopoly profits everywhere else. And I I,
Speaker 4:  that is a rational response. Like many, many, many things
Speaker 4:  are different in the United States versus Europe. Like Europe has a bunch
Speaker 4:  of different regulations than we do. but it, it's weird because
Speaker 4:  I think people assume in idealism of some of these
Speaker 4:  companies that what they want is to compete or what they want
Speaker 4:  is a more level playing field for consumers. And here it's pretty
Speaker 4:  naked that what they want is to preserve their monopoly profits.
Speaker 4:  So they will do a bunch of extra work over there to make a different European
Speaker 4:  internet. And unless they are forced that whatever those goals
Speaker 4:  are will never come here or anywhere else.
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. And I think at this moment there's pretty strong
Speaker 5:  indications that they're right to make that bet that whatever
Speaker 5:  is happening there is not going to percolate elsewhere. Because so far it
Speaker 5:  really hasn't. But at least so far, I mean,
Speaker 5:  am I right to say that the thing that's gonna hit the most people most quickly
Speaker 5:  is this stuff with iOS, right? It feels like Apple is the one that is like
Speaker 5:  changing in the biggest ways, the most quickly. And I
Speaker 5:  guess on the side also pissing off the most people the most quickly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. I think that's a hundred percent what's gonna happen because
Speaker 6:  that's what everybody actually uses right now. And that's actually
Speaker 6:  being changed right now in some cool ways,
Speaker 6:  but mainly ways with, what is it? A lot of feelings
Speaker 6:  is what NELI was saying early.
Speaker 4:  It's a lot of feelings.
Speaker 6:  So many feelings are happening. Apple is like screaming as
Speaker 6:  it goes to do all of this and everybody like in a way that
Speaker 6:  everyone is having to learn more about app store policies than I think most
Speaker 6:  of the European Union ever wanted to
Speaker 6:  in a really, like, I'm just kind of surprised by how, how mad Apple
Speaker 6:  is being about all of this. How loudly
Speaker 6:  angry Apple is being this,
Speaker 5:  It's true of this. And you, you always feel like Apple wants you to not think
Speaker 5:  about all the M missions. Yeah. That make Apple, apple. And
Speaker 5:  now the fact that, like I can tell you developer deals off
Speaker 5:  the top of my head feels like a problem for me, a problem for Apple,
Speaker 5:  a problem for the world. Like yep, this is a strange place we've entered
Speaker 5:  into, and
Speaker 6:  I think it was always gonna kind of happen too, right? If if, if they, like
Speaker 6:  you guys were talking about this, if, if they open it up, if, if we start
Speaker 6:  paying attention to this stuff that we didn't really pay attention to for
Speaker 6:  a very long time, then yeah people are gonna wanna have these conversations
Speaker 6:  about how much money Spotify is getting on the backend and that sort of thing.
Speaker 6:  But at the same time, that is really bad for both Spotify and Apple's
Speaker 6:  business. Yeah. Or not their business, but their reputation with the public
Speaker 6:  more than anything else. Like the business is all gonna keep going. Apple's
Speaker 6:  gonna make a lot of money with this new thing where they have to
Speaker 6:  pay 50 Euro cents
Speaker 6:  cents.
Speaker 4:  European Union, I believe it's pronounced dubs
Speaker 6:  For every download over that first million, including every update, like
Speaker 6:  app update. Like that's insane. That's a lot of
Speaker 6:  money. Yep. And they're being so petulant about it in a way where I'm like,
Speaker 6:  you just got hit with a $2 billion fine. Like
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  What do you do? You wanna get more. That's what usually like,
Speaker 6:  so it's weird. I'm just, I keep being surprised by it.
Speaker 5:  Neil, I am curious how you feel about this. 'cause I, I feel like we've reached
Speaker 5:  a point where this fight has been going on so long,
Speaker 5:  specifically between Apple on one side and Spotify and Epic
Speaker 5:  on behalf of lots of others, but especially those two companies on the other
Speaker 5:  side. And it really seems like no one
Speaker 5:  looks good in any of this fight. Like I, I feel like everyone has lost
Speaker 5:  this fight now and it's just bad times all around.
Speaker 5:  Nobody's happy, everything's worse. This just seems like it's sucks.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm always thinking about the beginning of the app store
Speaker 4:  when the thing that Apple would compare it to was
Speaker 4:  app distribution on pre iPhone smartphones, which was largely
Speaker 4:  handled by carriers. And carriers were capricious and they
Speaker 4:  would get in developers ways and they would charge exorbitant
Speaker 4:  fees
Speaker 4:  and it was bad. It was bad. Yeah. And I would just
Speaker 4:  caution Apple that having a reputation for being
Speaker 4:  capricious and charging huge fees and getting in developers' ways
Speaker 4:  and then issuing press releases saying things like, Spotify has never paid
Speaker 4:  us a cent to be on the iPhone is like, but everyone who has
Speaker 4:  an iPhone paid you the money,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. They bought an iPhone.
Speaker 4:  This is the problem that Apple is running into almost
Speaker 4:  insistently by, in by saying that when
Speaker 4:  you have an application on someone's computer, apple deserves a
Speaker 4:  cut of what happens in that app. And I, that is as simple as
Speaker 4:  it gets, right? Like you either agree with that proposition or you
Speaker 4:  don't. When you have a computer, should the person who sold you the computer
Speaker 4:  be in between you and the things you can do on that computer? There are some
Speaker 4:  really good arguments for Apple being in between
Speaker 4:  the iPhone customer and what they can do on the iPhone. iPhones
Speaker 4:  go everywhere with people. They contain an enormous amount of their personal
Speaker 4:  data. They can track you, they can be used for horrible
Speaker 4:  things. They have a shit load of cameras on them. Just more every year. They're
Speaker 4:  like, we're up to five. you know, it's like
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of reasons where you want a bunch of
Speaker 4:  extremely motivated, very smart computer scientists and policy people
Speaker 4:  sitting between a computer user and the things that can happen on their computer.
Speaker 4:  And in particular what software other people can run on a computer. But you
Speaker 4:  have to have an exit ramp. And the reason you wanna protect the computer
Speaker 4:  user should be for safety, not because of money. And
Speaker 4:  what's happening right now is Apple is using the moral argument for
Speaker 4:  we need to keep our users safe. We need to, to protect them from themselves.
Speaker 4:  When they use these computers that go around in their pockets, everywhere
Speaker 4:  they go, they have pictures of their kids on them and they're using that
Speaker 4:  to justify their economic argument. And that I think that's where it's falling
Speaker 4:  it down. And, and I think that is candidly where some
Speaker 4:  of the people at Apple are at risk of damaging their repu, like
Speaker 4:  their personal reputations inside this community because they keep saying
Speaker 4:  it out loud.
Speaker 6:  It's not even Spotify though for me it's, it's what's happening with Epic
Speaker 6:  and how they were just like, okay, we, we don't trust you anymore so we're
Speaker 6:  gonna take your developer account away again.
Speaker 4:  So this is what I mean this is the one. Yeah. Right. Yeah. This is the one.
Speaker 4:  And it happens. It's so precious. The DMA was announced an Apple's compliance
Speaker 4:  plan with the DMA was announced and Epic immediately reacted by saying, we
Speaker 4:  will have an app store with Fortnite on it in the EU and the
Speaker 4:  Epic game store is gonna happen and we're gonna do it. And we're gonna prove
Speaker 4:  that even under these rules, which we Epic think are too restrictive.
Speaker 4:  'cause there's a lot of rules. Apple's gonna make all these Alternative app
Speaker 4:  stores under a lot of rules which are basically designed to make them not
Speaker 4:  good. Yep. Yep. Right. Like Apple's design of how Alternative app stores
Speaker 4:  should work on, on iOS under the DMA is
Speaker 4:  basically meant to have it not be a viable thing. And Epic's
Speaker 4:  point has been, we're gonna do it. We'll have Fortnite, we'll bring the other
Speaker 4:  game developers on. And even under these restrictions which we think are
Speaker 4:  bad in our malicious compliance, we think it'll be good and prove the point.
Speaker 4:  And Epic today, just literally today before we started
Speaker 4:  podcasting, had a press conference. Tim Sweeney spoke, he
Speaker 4:  took questions from reporters, including our own John Porter and they released
Speaker 4:  a bunch of emails between Epic and Apple, including emails between Tim
Speaker 4:  Sweeney and Phil Schiller where Epic applied to be a developer
Speaker 4:  to make this app store in the EU under, I believe it's Epic's game Sweden.
Speaker 4:  Apple wrote back to Epic and said, how can we trust you? You've done
Speaker 4:  all this stuff in the past. Tim Sweeney wrote to Phil Shoulder and said,
Speaker 4:  you can trust us. Tell me what assurances you need. And they
Speaker 4:  got, they sh and Apple replied, at least according to the emails we
Speaker 4:  have seen from Epic, Apple's free to send us some other emails. But Tim
Speaker 4:  Sweeney said, what other assurances do you need? And Apple replied by sending
Speaker 4:  a letter from a lawyer saying You have criticized the app store and
Speaker 4:  our plan for compliance in the EU, you've proven yourself to be untrustworthy
Speaker 4:  and we are revoking your app store privileges Yh. And it's like, what are
Speaker 4:  you doing? Like why would you do that? Like the
Speaker 4:  only thing that's gonna happen is Tim Sweeney who loves a press conference
Speaker 4:  about how shitty Apple is right. Is gonna hold a press conference about how
Speaker 4:  shitty you are and a bunch of European regulators who you have already
Speaker 4:  accused of being Anti Apple are gonna look
Speaker 4:  at your behavior and find you again. Yep. Like
Speaker 4:  this is not like, I know, I know a lot of kindergartners,
Speaker 4:  I have a kindergartner, I know kindergartners who are more
Speaker 4:  politically adept than this.
Speaker 4:  I just don't understand it. And that's what I, when I'm saying like people's
Speaker 4:  personal reputations like this feels like they are personally mad as
Speaker 4:  opposed to playing the long game with a bunch of regulators. And
Speaker 4:  just because we're speaking the day after Super Tuesday and we all have to
Speaker 4:  think about the prospect of Donald Trump once again being our president,
Speaker 4:  I will remind everyone that Tim Cook did the best
Speaker 4:  job of managing Donald Trump than anyone.
Speaker 4:  Right. Donald Trump went to have put a trade war up on China
Speaker 4:  and Tim Cook managed Apple through a trade war. Yeah. Because he was
Speaker 4:  able to distance himself personally from what Apple needed and
Speaker 4:  what he probably felt and advocate for
Speaker 4:  Apple's interests. And I think here there's just a collapse like there,
Speaker 4:  there's just some angry people. And I think that's super weird.
Speaker 5:  I really, I'm with you. I cannot make heads or tails of how this went down
Speaker 5:  like this because there was also, after Apple made its announcements about
Speaker 5:  what iOS 17.4 was gonna be, one of the things that did that Tim
Speaker 5:  Sweeney hilariously gave Apple credit for was reinstate
Speaker 5:  Epic's developer account. Which it had banned what feels like a million years
Speaker 5:  ago now when the whole Fortnite debacle first happened and started
Speaker 5:  all of the fights between Epic and Apple about this stuff.
Speaker 5:  So there was this sense in which it was like, okay, apple is at least
Speaker 5:  outwardly going to attempt to look like it's turning over a new leaf and
Speaker 5:  play nice in in these spaces.
Speaker 5:  And then to just so swiftly say, just kidding. And just
Speaker 5:  yank the rug out from under them. Again, knowing full well what Epic
Speaker 5:  is gonna do
Speaker 5:  is it's just weird. I just truly cannot figure it out because it is so
Speaker 5:  obvious that it was gonna go like this if this is how you played it. Epic
Speaker 5:  is the single loudest voice building a third party
Speaker 5:  app store. And like Apple either wanted to light this on fire
Speaker 5:  or should have known it was going to be lighting this on fire. So
Speaker 4:  We do have a statement from Apple now that kind of directly gets at what
Speaker 4:  you're saying and it, it just feels like maybe they didn't do it as cleanly
Speaker 4:  as they wanted to. So we reached out to Apple, we asked what's going on here?
Speaker 4:  Apple mad. That's the whole statement. Here's the quote.
Speaker 4:  Epic's egregious breach of its contractual obligations to Apple
Speaker 4:  led courts to determine that Apple has the right to terminate any or all
Speaker 4:  of Epic games wholly and subsidiaries affiliates or other entities under
Speaker 4:  Epic games as control at any time. And at Apple's sole discretion, in
Speaker 4:  light of epic's past and ongoing behavior,
Speaker 4:  apple chose to exercise that. Right. So this is just nakedly revenge.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well and the ongoing behavior is Tim Sweeney continuing to be loudly mad
Speaker 5:  on Twitter about what's going on with the DMA.
Speaker 4:  Great. But I'm just like, you could have just said, in light of the
Speaker 4:  epic's past behavior, You don't have to say ongoing
Speaker 4:  behavior.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, fair.
Speaker 4:  Right. And that's the part where it's like, oh, this company is just a vengeful.
Speaker 4:  You can say, look, we had a lawsuit. They broke the rules. We sued them,
Speaker 4:  they sued us. We had an antitrust trial. The result of the
Speaker 4:  antitrust trial is we don't have to do business with them. We are just gonna
Speaker 4:  not, we're gonna keep not doing business with them. That relationship was
Speaker 4:  broken saying we sort of maybe thought we'd do business with
Speaker 4:  you and we approved a thing and we did some weird letters. Ah,
Speaker 4:  it, you know, like I, I don't know. There's just something that, like
Speaker 4:  If, you want to build a business on these platforms. I don't
Speaker 4:  know that, that feels like a stable foundation. And I think a lot of these
Speaker 4:  companies, Spotify, Netflix, Epic, whoever we've heard now is,
Speaker 4:  David pointed out earlier, we have just heard too much about the
Speaker 4:  reality of doing business on the store. And at the
Speaker 4:  end I think consumers don't know. They don't feel it. Right? Like it's
Speaker 4:  hard to be sad about a thing that doesn't exist. But the point of this regulation
Speaker 4:  is like, what if it was different? What if the stores are more vibrant? What
Speaker 4:  if there were more kinds of apps, including apps Apple would never allow?
Speaker 4:  I I am shocked we have not seen a store spring up
Speaker 4:  just for gambling in, in Europe. Right? Like European laws of
Speaker 4:  gambling are actually much more permissive than laws in the United States
Speaker 4:  about gambling. I'm shocked that there is not already a storefront for
Speaker 4:  gambling apps in Europe because Apple would never allow it. And it's like
Speaker 4:  you can, I, I'm not a gambler. I go to Vegas and I, I ask
Speaker 4:  people how much money they're gonna spend on gambling and I spend that money
Speaker 4:  on limousines 'cause that is a better investment my friend. Every single
Speaker 4:  time it has been for decades. Everyone remembers the lis no one remembers
Speaker 4:  the the black. I remember the Limone pretty good. It was good. I'm
Speaker 4:  not a gambler. It's like, whatever. I'm just saying like that is a world
Speaker 4:  that could exist that is an industry that could exist that Apple right now
Speaker 4:  just prevents from existing. There are lots and lots and lots of things like
Speaker 4:  this and it's hard to prove the negative. And I think Apple not
Speaker 4:  even allowing Epic to prove the negative is like all
Speaker 4:  they're proving is that they're capricious. Yep. And they're, they're pretty
Speaker 4:  mad. And I, I just, I don't know if that is the smart political
Speaker 4:  play and you might feel it's a smart moral play, but it just feels like a
Speaker 4:  bunch of European regulators are not gonna look at that and be like, yes,
Speaker 4:  we, we also have to abide by what an American court said.
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. Well I think in this case, like so much of the question
Speaker 5:  of what's happening on iOS particularly is, is
Speaker 5:  somewhere in this gray area between technically doing
Speaker 5:  what is required, right? The sort of malicious compliance that a lot of folks
Speaker 5:  have con have talked to Apple about and doing things
Speaker 5:  that are just nakedly not solving the problem that you claim they're solving.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like I think the, the Apple's browser choice
Speaker 5:  screen on iOS in the EU is to me perfect
Speaker 5:  malicious compliance. Apple is on the record over and over in the
Speaker 5:  Google antitrust case and elsewhere for saying that it hates choice screens.
Speaker 5:  And it is now required to have a choice screen asking what browser
Speaker 5:  do you want to use as your default browser on your iPhone? And when you upgrade
Speaker 5:  to iOS 17.4 in the EU that you will get that
Speaker 5:  this screen is ugly, it's unhelpful. It takes you to the app store
Speaker 5:  in a really confusing way. It includes a bunch of browsers no one's ever
Speaker 5:  heard of. It's just not good. And, and like it's
Speaker 5:  very clear that Apple has no investment in making it good. And they're like,
Speaker 5:  well you're making us do this dumb thing. We're gonna do it in the dumbest
Speaker 5:  way we can think of that is very hard to fight
Speaker 5:  that. Like, that argument is hard to prove that that's what's happening.
Speaker 5:  It's very obvious that that's what's happening. But this thing where it's
Speaker 5:  like, oh, you, you claimed to be opening up
Speaker 5:  the app store because that is what by law we are requiring you to do. And
Speaker 5:  now you are just eventually shutting down the biggest,
Speaker 5:  loudest player that wants to do this. Just
Speaker 5:  feels like a bad call. Yeah. I think
Speaker 5:  Apple making it really, really hard and arduous to open a third party
Speaker 5:  app store is in a certain way very clever. I think it's, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's conniving and it's cynical, but it's very clever for a company
Speaker 5:  that has a lot to protect in that space. To just pick
Speaker 5:  this fight with Epic again over and over and just kick it out and
Speaker 5:  threaten to have all of this come back at you just seems dumb. Yeah. I just
Speaker 5:  don't get it.
Speaker 6:  I feel like it's, it's a company who is seeing their, their power
Speaker 6:  wane in this marketplace, right? They're, they're seeing it happen really
Speaker 6:  quickly and they have to assert they're dominance.
Speaker 6:  Like they have to show everybody, no, we're the boss, we still control it.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like Spotify, you start mouthing off like this,
Speaker 6:  that what ha that's what happens to you. And that's
Speaker 6:  certainly like a take, that's a thing you can do. Plenty of businesses have
Speaker 6:  played that kind of hardball, but very
Speaker 6:  few that are so consumer facing and, and really dependent on
Speaker 6:  consumer goodwill in a way that Apple is very much dependent on. Like,
Speaker 6:  you know, we have to deal with our, our ISPs even that we hate them.
Speaker 6:  They're some of the most hated companies in the United States, but we have
Speaker 6:  to deal with them because they're monopolies. And this is
Speaker 6:  a very common reaction of a monopoly is to be like, okay, if you're gonna
Speaker 6:  fight our monopoly, if you're gonna try to counter our monopoly, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  like grind you into dust repeatedly. And
Speaker 6:  you shouldn't probably do that if you're someone like Apple
Speaker 6:  who is a monopoly on the App store but isn't necessarily like
Speaker 6:  a monopoly in a lot of other places. Like you can go buy a Samsung phone,
Speaker 6:  you can go buy a Google Pixel, you can just not use Apple
Speaker 6:  products eventually.
Speaker 4:  The best thing you can do when you're a monopoly is not act like one. And
Speaker 4:  I feel like Apple won learn that lesson like a, a very,
Speaker 4:  like, you know, Microsoft when they were the death star,
Speaker 4:  they acted like, you know Yeah. And they got in a lot of trouble. And
Speaker 4:  like, you know why Chrome has way more market share than ie. It's
Speaker 4:  'cause Microsoft got himself in a lot of trouble and the sources stop
Speaker 4:  bundling IE with Windows like that. That's a real thing. Like that was the
Speaker 4:  antitrust case and it's because Microsoft went and killed Netscape with a
Speaker 4:  bunch of moves just like this. And I, I worry
Speaker 4:  all the time with the modern apple that the people
Speaker 4:  who are coming into the company, the people who work there,
Speaker 4:  like, you know, this company's been around for a long time. They have only
Speaker 4:  worked at the Apple that is this Apple and
Speaker 4:  the people who built it from the underdog apple or
Speaker 4:  you know, they're just getting older. It's just like time to retire. There's
Speaker 4:  been a wave of departures from Apple recently reported all over the place
Speaker 4:  and you're just like, oh, If, you walk around
Speaker 4:  like you're that thing and you're not, you don't have that little like chip
Speaker 4:  on your shoulder. You gotta earn it from consumers, right? Like you've gotta
Speaker 4:  take one piece of market share away from Windows every single day, which
Speaker 4:  is what the version of Apple that became this thing came from.
Speaker 4:  Like, you are just gonna act like a bully. Yep. 'cause you have no conception
Speaker 4:  of when you weren't. And I think the flip side of that is consumers,
Speaker 4:  a lot of newer, younger consumers do not
Speaker 4:  have any recollection at all of Apple on the come up.
Speaker 4:  Right. Of that incredible run of Apple just sort of like creating product
Speaker 4:  after product that revolutionized industry after industry. They're like,
Speaker 4:  yep, we grow up, we get a phone, my parents put a watch on me. So I can leave
Speaker 4:  the house without, right? So they can track me everywhere. Like my friends
Speaker 4:  are all on iMessage and they bully people with green belt. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  yo, there's no like long history of Goodwill here. There's just
Speaker 4:  this.
Speaker 4:  Right? And it's like, I can't get Fortnite on my phone 'cause these two billionaires
Speaker 4:  are fighting. And I, like I said, I I will just, I'll end it here.
Speaker 4:  We, we talked about Reregulation for a long time. People are gonna email
Speaker 4:  us. They're gonna talk to me about Apple's business model and how much money
Speaker 4:  they make and stock price. I get all the, whenever we criticize Google, people
Speaker 4:  are like, I bet you, I dare you to short Google. I I can't, we
Speaker 4:  we cannot buy the stock. We cannot do that. And I will just remind you of
Speaker 4:  a quote that I think about maybe once a week. It's in a wired profile
Speaker 4:  of Walt Mossberg walking through the CES show floor. And he had just written
Speaker 4:  a bad review. This is a true story. He had just written a bad review of like
Speaker 4:  the serious radio when it had first come out. And the CEO of Sirius
Speaker 4:  started yelling at Walt Mossberg on the show floor of CES. And he said, you
Speaker 4:  brought our stock price down. And Walt Mossberg looked at him dead in the
Speaker 4:  eye and said, I don't give a fuck about your stock price. And
Speaker 4:  that's it. Like, I don't care about the richest company in the world
Speaker 4:  making more or less money where their stock price goes. I care. Like, are
Speaker 4:  we getting more interesting innovative products? Are we building cooler
Speaker 4:  experiences for people? Do I feel like when I spend my money as a consumer,
Speaker 4:  I've done it in a way that feels good and healthy. I don't know
Speaker 4:  if these regulations are gonna achieve that. I dunno if Apple's compliance
Speaker 4:  or malicious compliance will achieve that. I have no idea. I do know that
Speaker 4:  right now, the way it has been going, our choices are getting smaller and
Speaker 4:  smaller and smaller and more and more of the dollars are flowing to Apple
Speaker 4:  instead of app developers. And that feels weird. So like I'm all
Speaker 4:  for flipping the table and everyone can have their feelings, but I would
Speaker 4:  just caution Apple in particular acting like this
Speaker 4:  right now does not get you the goodwill so that the next time you're like,
Speaker 4:  I think all of you should rewrite your apps in a different language that
Speaker 4:  we invented, people aren't gonna do it. And that's where the power
Speaker 4:  comes from.
Speaker 5:  You know what I've been thinking about a lot recently is Apple Pay, which
Speaker 5:  yeah, I think Apple Pay on the iPhone is like essentially a
Speaker 5:  perfect product. And the way they've integrated it into
Speaker 5:  websites, so that like, like for me it's, it's takeout food over and over,
Speaker 5:  right? Where I'm like, I'm on a website, I'm, I'm ordering and my options
Speaker 5:  are either spend eight minutes entering my contact information, which I
Speaker 5:  can do, but it's 12 fields and I have to go get my credit card and remember
Speaker 5:  what it is. Or I tap the button that says Apple Pay, I double click on the
Speaker 5:  side, it scans my face and I've paid for dinner. That is, that is winning
Speaker 5:  with product in an open ecosystem and it kicks ass. And it is like, that
Speaker 5:  is Apple at its best. The opposite of that is this
Speaker 5:  fight that Apple is in about all the Anti steering stuff and the $2 billion
Speaker 5:  fine that just came from the EU about all the Spotify stuff, which
Speaker 5:  is Apple saying you are not allowed to tell people the other places they
Speaker 5:  can go pay for your stuff. And for years with Apple Music was
Speaker 5:  preferencing Apple Music. Apple Music was allowed to have ads and
Speaker 5:  notifications that Spotify and others are not allowed to have. And that is
Speaker 5:  the opposite of winning with product that is saying, we are going
Speaker 5:  to prevent you from doing anything, including save your customers
Speaker 5:  money because we can. And and to me it's like I I
Speaker 5:  wanna see the Apple Pay Apple and not the Apple Music.
Speaker 5:  Apple can I because
Speaker 4:  That can, I was can I go, can I tell you story about Apple Pay?
Speaker 4:  Yes, please. I,
Speaker 4:  over the weekend, this is like what happens when you're the editor chief
Speaker 4:  attack website. I went to pay with Apple Pay and it didn't work. Mm. Right.
Speaker 4:  My credit card got declined and I was like, this is weird. And I called the
Speaker 4:  bank and the bank was like, apple Pay is having an
Speaker 4:  unexpected upgrade, which is an incredible euphemism, like
Speaker 4:  an absolutely incredible euphemism. It
Speaker 5:  Broke in a cool way.
Speaker 4:  So I was like, that's weird. And I posted on threads about it, like, is anybody
Speaker 4:  else having problems with Chase? And a lot of people got back to me like,
Speaker 4:  this is broken for me all day. It's like email Apple, it's the weekend email
Speaker 4:  Apple. I say, Hey, is Apple play broken? I'm just gonna write story this
Speaker 4:  down. And it took a minute 'cause it's a weekend fine.
Speaker 4:  And they got back to me and they Apple, you can read the story. Apple basically
Speaker 4:  was like, this is Chase's fault. It's not Apple Pays fault. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  great, you know, apple Pay doesn't work, right? Like it doesn't
Speaker 4:  matter to anyone whose fault it is it, what matters is that Apple, like people
Speaker 4:  are trying to pay with their phones, it's not working. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, but it's Chase's fault. And I was like, cool. Like
Speaker 4:  cool. Like I, I will, I will happily write that down, you know, but
Speaker 4:  here's the information I can give you. Have you thought about updating your
Speaker 4:  status page to say it's Chase's fault? Like it's, this is what people are
Speaker 4:  reacting to, this is the information you can give them. And the idea that
Speaker 4:  Apple had a dependency on one of the largest
Speaker 4:  financial institutions in the world and they were like, but blame them.
Speaker 4:  Right? When it's like, but the but what people are holding is a phone that
Speaker 4:  has your logo on it, you know, and it's like when at and t goes
Speaker 4:  down, people don't blame Apple, they blame at and t you're very happy for
Speaker 4:  that. Like that's fine. Like people understand these relationships. But at
Speaker 4:  the end of the day, like you are responsible for the products and like that
Speaker 4:  thing where Apple Pay ISN ant almost perfect product because Apple has
Speaker 4:  managed all these relationships for you. That's what I mean by the
Speaker 4:  hubris. Like yeah Apple's like it's not our fault. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  no, it's your product, right? Let's, it's your magic, right? Like you are
Speaker 4:  the ones who made this almost perfect product and you're pissed that you
Speaker 4:  have a dependency on someone else. And you would prefer Apple in particular
Speaker 4:  is famous for preferring to have no dependencies on anyone at any time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I get it because I would love to have no dependencies on it. But then
Speaker 4:  you look at some of the moves like this web app stuff, right? Where they,
Speaker 4:  the DMA, they said we're going to disallow web apps because we think we have
Speaker 4:  to allow other browser engines. And people said, no, no, no. Like the EU
Speaker 4:  got a little weird and Apple said, okay, we'll have web apps again and we'll
Speaker 4:  just do it this way. I will just remind everyone that the reason
Speaker 4:  Apple exists today at all is because Steve Jobs could
Speaker 4:  do the iMac and tell people they could get on the internet. And the only
Speaker 4:  reason that was a viable thing to say was because what people wanted was
Speaker 4:  web browsers. Yep. And so the web browser on the iMac was
Speaker 4:  approximately the same as the web browser on Windows. And so
Speaker 4:  he could sell you an iMac instead. If he had been like, well you can use
Speaker 4:  here as Microsoft Excel, Microsoft could have just turned off Apple. They
Speaker 4:  could have turned off the business, but because of the internet, like the
Speaker 4:  open application architecture of the internet, he was able to sell Mac
Speaker 4:  again. And it's weird now for Apple to be at the point where they're like,
Speaker 4:  what if we don't have an open application architecture?
Speaker 4:  Right? And like that's weird. Like that's where you came from. The company
Speaker 4:  would've not made it out of nine the 1990s if
Speaker 4:  not for that. And I, I just, I don't know how to like underline for people
Speaker 4:  like a lot of audiences young, but these things are
Speaker 4:  not new. Like these moves are old moves and
Speaker 4:  it's just weird for Apple, which is a company built out of some of these
Speaker 4:  changes a long time ago to be making the same mistakes.
Speaker 4:  Yep. We'll see. Agreed. We'll see there's a chance that this should just
Speaker 4:  result in a bunch of like weird Europeans talking about how much better there
Speaker 4:  are, like 15 browsers are.
Speaker 5:  I also think it's possible this results in nothing. Like I think, I think
Speaker 5:  what Apple clearly wants to change is nothing. And I think you're gonna get
Speaker 5:  a bunch of people who like accidentally set Ecosia as their default browser
Speaker 5:  for 10 minutes and then they go back to Spotify and nothing at all changes.
Speaker 4:  Well, no, here's my real question. The, the one thing that could change that
Speaker 4:  'cause choice screens have not worked in Europe, right? Like right famously
Speaker 4:  in one of our pieces about it, we linked to a long analysis of where choice
Speaker 4:  screens came from and whether they work or not. But what has never happened
Speaker 4:  is you've never been able to pick Chrome. Right? That you, the
Speaker 4:  choice screen has always been designed to make you not pick Chrome.
Speaker 5:  Well it's been designed to make you pick a browser you've never heard of
Speaker 5:  or the only one you've heard of. In this case there are at least two you've
Speaker 5:  heard
Speaker 4:  Of. There's Safari and Chrome. So the idea that people will pick Chrome is
Speaker 4:  actually fascinating. I'm dying to see what happens there. Alright. I don't,
Speaker 4:  I don't know what's gonna happen or anything else but the, the Chrome versus
Speaker 4:  safari and choice screen that seems really interesting. It could
Speaker 4:  We're back, we're out the Eurozone,
Speaker 5:  We made it, we landed in America.
Speaker 4:  We landed in America where we're gonna talk about Elon Musk and pickup trucks
Speaker 4:  in short order. That's really gonna happen here. Alright, we gotta make this
Speaker 4:  lightning round quick. We went on too long. This show is too long. But wait,
Speaker 4:  do we have a sponsor for the lightning round?
Speaker 5:  I don't think so. Sony
Speaker 4:  Bravia Corps, Sony, that's not, that's all Sony has to
Speaker 4:  pay the money to sponsor the Lightning. Other people don't pay.
Speaker 4:  But if you're a big company, you're, if the European Union has designated
Speaker 4:  you a gatekeeper, you have to pay money to sponsor the lightning round. All
Speaker 4:  right, David, what you got?
Speaker 5:  Okay, I have two, which is a good start. One is very fast, which is just
Speaker 5:  that there are now transcriptions in Apple podcasts. Yes. For
Speaker 5:  all of its shows including The, Vergecast. Sometimes they're very wrong in
Speaker 5:  very funny ways, but it's actually a great feature. You can
Speaker 5:  like tap on a paragraph and it'll take you to that part of the show. You
Speaker 5:  can, it's a great way to go back and be like, what was that thing I missed
Speaker 5:  without actually having to like scan back 15 seconds in the show? It's just
Speaker 5:  an awesome feature. I am not an Apple Podcast fan in general, but it
Speaker 5:  is like I'm, I'm tempted back to it because of it.
Speaker 5:  It's just a cool thing. So If, you make a podcast app, do transcripts, it's
Speaker 5:  great. And also don't yell at us for things that get wrong in the transcripts
Speaker 5:  because they're not our transcripts. But my real one is story Sean
Speaker 5:  Hollister's been covering a bunch this week. That is something we talked
Speaker 5:  about a bunch on The Vergecast last year, which is Game emulators. So there's
Speaker 5:  this emulator called Yuzu that was for emulating
Speaker 5:  Nintendo Switch games and basically
Speaker 5:  Nintendo picked a fight and Yuzu just
Speaker 5:  caved. Yeah. And this has been the thing that a lot of the folks
Speaker 5:  in the emulator community have worried about for a long time, which is that
Speaker 5:  emulators are very popular and kind of
Speaker 5:  just unproblematic enough that it has not been
Speaker 5:  worth it for the game companies to pick this fight. But Yuzu kind of crossed
Speaker 5:  that threshold for a couple of interesting reasons. People were using it
Speaker 5:  to play unreleased games. So it got the kind of
Speaker 5:  press and attention from these companies that you don't typically get. And
Speaker 5:  basically what it sounds like happened is Nintendo just showed up and was
Speaker 5:  like, we will crush you to death. And they said, okay, we're shut down
Speaker 5:  and took all their stuff offline. They, they shut down the discord, they've
Speaker 5:  been doing stuff and it has had this real like immediate chilling effect
Speaker 5:  on emulators all over the place. There are folks shutting down Discords,
Speaker 5:  there are folks saying you can't talk about emulation
Speaker 5:  here because of the legal repercussions that we're worried about. And it,
Speaker 5:  it just literally took Nintendo picking one
Speaker 5:  loud fight with one company and all of a sudden it feels like this whole
Speaker 5:  emulator world is kind of in peril. Which is
Speaker 6:  Kind of weird because yuzu like I had it
Speaker 6:  on my steam deck. I maybe I I own a, I own a a
Speaker 6:  Nintendo Switch. I feel totally morally
Speaker 4:  Notable Plex user
Speaker 6:  With
Speaker 4:  My Choices has the emulator on her steam deck. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Who, who knew? but it was always kind of a weird one because generally emulators
Speaker 6:  only emulate older systems. So like it
Speaker 6:  doesn't emulate the PS five, it emulates the PS four or whatever. And
Speaker 6:  Nintendo, because of the switch architecture was really, really easy to
Speaker 6:  emulate. And it has been since the, we, it's just been like super, super
Speaker 6:  easy to emulate and people just started getting more
Speaker 6:  aggressive with that. And it's like, yeah, if, if I can go download the
Speaker 6:  unreleased metro game and play it on my steam deck,
Speaker 6:  that probably is actually a pro. Like I,
Speaker 6:  I was kind of when that happened, I was like, isn't Nintendo gonna come down
Speaker 6:  like a bag of bricks on them? Because that's not how emulators have worked
Speaker 6:  for the last 30 years. And yeah, they they
Speaker 6:  did in fact come down like a bag of bricks on YouTube
Speaker 5:  But also If you wanted to make that same case about a 20-year-old
Speaker 5:  Mario game. It's just as true. Yeah. It's just that it's such a smaller,
Speaker 5:  less interesting business for Nintendo that it's better
Speaker 5:  off just leaving well enough alone and let the people who wanna play these
Speaker 5:  old games who are then probably likely to come by the new games do so. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like it's, it's this very sketchy but sort of workable balance.
Speaker 5:  And I, I do agree. I think Yuzu did something slightly different to Trip
Speaker 6:  Over because it was a current thing. It was current games. 'cause even like
Speaker 6:  the three Ds emulator they had was, it was just,
Speaker 6:  you know, not as many people are paying a, playing a three Ds nowadays. Totally.
Speaker 6:  Or like, there's a really good one called Dolphin for, for we games
Speaker 6:  and, and Game Cube games. And that's a 20-year-old system that's that's that's
Speaker 6:  different than like I can just go buy a bunch, get a bunch of unreleased
Speaker 6:  games on a torrent site and play them on my steam deck and never play Nintendo
Speaker 6:  a dime right now. Like how would you know, like how would you know that Alex
Speaker 6:  that's, that's just piracy. Like
Speaker 4:  That's just, why do you, why do you know that information?
Speaker 6:  I have no idea who I gotta go.
Speaker 6:  I have no idea what's happening here. but it
Speaker 5:  Was always like, you're in Texas. There are no laws there. Yeah. There are
Speaker 5:  no
Speaker 6:  Laws here in Texas. We don't do regulations here.
Speaker 4:  Here's what we do. We roll cold and we play unreleased natural games.
Speaker 4:  but
Speaker 6:  It was, it was all the Jesus thing was always wild. I'm I'm, I wish it didn't
Speaker 6:  have such a chilling effect on the emulator community 'cause like emulators
Speaker 6:  are sick and I still want somebody to make a good N 64
Speaker 6:  emulator, which is still a weird challenge. But
Speaker 5:  We think analog is up to something I'm hoping. Oh my
Speaker 4:  God. Oh right. They did, they did, they did the tease out thing. I will say,
Speaker 4:  you know, the trope at The Verge is that copyright law is the only law on
Speaker 4:  the internet. 'cause it's the only thing that can stop anyone from doing
Speaker 4:  anything for some reason. Well the reason is first matter, but copyright
Speaker 4:  law is the only law on the internet. And here I think there's,
Speaker 4:  we still don't know the answer. Right. It's like actually kind of fascinating
Speaker 4:  that they settled. 'cause what you get is people dunno if emulate
Speaker 4:  are illegal or not. Some of 'em get taken to court. But usually the way the
Speaker 4:  cases are structured is you have a big rich corporation
Speaker 4:  and then an emulator,
Speaker 5:  Which is just like a handful of people in a GitHub. Right. It's like that's
Speaker 5:  the fight. Yeah. So the
Speaker 4:  Big huge corporation shows up and says, ah, we're gonna sue you.
Speaker 4:  That's gonna cost a lot of money. And that usually crushes the thing. Yep.
Speaker 4:  It's the same in the fanfiction community actually. Like fanfiction is something
Speaker 4:  that is sort of just tolerated by large publishing houses. There have
Speaker 4:  been a handful of cases, but like, it's bad. It's probably bad to piss off
Speaker 4:  the people who love your work so much that they're writing their own versions
Speaker 4:  of your work. Yeah. Like that, that's just like a bad move. So
Speaker 4:  it's like tolerated, but you could just stop it If you wanted to or you could
Speaker 4:  at least file a bunch of lawsuits and get everyone to spend a lot of money
Speaker 4:  and chill it out of existence. And I think here what you have is
Speaker 4:  Nintendo probably said, look, we can make your lives horrible.
Speaker 4:  We can cost you a lot of money and we will probably win because we can afford
Speaker 4:  even more lawyers. And you and like Who knows what this, how outcome will
Speaker 4:  be. This could take years or you could just shut it down, pay us the money
Speaker 4:  and this will be over. And I, I I don't, I I
Speaker 4:  I feel conflicted about that. Right. Like that didn't get anyone to an answer.
Speaker 4:  The next stimulator can start. Right. There's no law against it. There's
Speaker 4:  no precedent saying it's illegal. Like you could probably take the source
Speaker 4:  code of yuzu today and start, start it all again. Yep. But these people
Speaker 4:  can't because they signed the, the settlement to make it go away. And I,
Speaker 4:  I just wonder like it some point,
Speaker 4:  the amount of DRM and protection and lockdowns and
Speaker 4:  stuff that is around all digital content is gonna run against
Speaker 4:  the reality that people are gonna build emulators. Right. And like,
Speaker 4:  we just haven't, we just haven't run the process to its end because
Speaker 4:  the money has never been aligned to let us have the fight all the way to
Speaker 4:  the end.
Speaker 6:  Nintendo though has always been pretty consistent with like emulators versus
Speaker 6:  I guess piracy. Like, I think they think of those as two very different
Speaker 6:  things. And for a long time there was a, there's a lot of different ways
Speaker 6:  you can pirate games on, on older Nintendo systems. They,
Speaker 6:  they did a lot of like these cartridges that you can go and you can put in
Speaker 6:  a system and they were really aggressive about stopping those. When, when
Speaker 6:  the three DS system had a pirate, like a little people were out there selling
Speaker 6:  a little SD card, you could put in a three DS and just pirate everything.
Speaker 6:  Nintendo was super aggressive about that. So like the user thing,
Speaker 6:  I know everybody's being like, what does this mean for the emulator community?
Speaker 6:  but it really was more, what does this mean for the game piracy
Speaker 6:  community? And that'll probably piss off a bunch of emulator people.
Speaker 4:  I do feel like there's a difference between selling atoms, like selling physical
Speaker 4:  Nintendos and like, it's a little bit hard, but you can figure it on software.
Speaker 4:  All right, Alex, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 6:  My lightning round is I wanna be really fiscally in irresponsible
Speaker 6:  and get the new Lenovo Legion go. It's $700. Yes.
Speaker 6:  I don't need it. Sean reviewed it. I want it so bad.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's windows, which means it's not as good
Speaker 6:  as the steam deck because the steam deck, the Steam Os is just superior.
Speaker 6:  But you can turn it into a tablet. You can take both of the, the handles
Speaker 6:  off and one of them you can then turn it into a mouse
Speaker 6:  like a vertical mouse. And that is just, that just rules. I just,
Speaker 6:  I want this thing so bad.
Speaker 5:  It's the gadget. Gadget. Yeah. We've covered in a while. I think where it
Speaker 5:  was like Lenovo was basically like, we are prevented for a variety of
Speaker 5:  reasons for making a really great handheld gaming thing
Speaker 5:  because you just kind of can't do that with Windows the way that it works
Speaker 5:  now everybody agrees with that, including Microsoft. So we're just gonna
Speaker 5:  do a bunch of weird fun stuff where you can flip
Speaker 5:  everything around and cool things happen. Is any of it any good?
Speaker 5:  Sometimes, but is it cool and rad and you're gonna want one
Speaker 5:  anyway? Like Yeah, yeah. You do. Yeah. And I do
Speaker 5:  like
Speaker 4:  This. This might
Speaker 5:  Might not be a good device, but I want it anyways.
Speaker 6:  Sean did give it six.
Speaker 4:  The everything old is new again. Vibes of this thing are
Speaker 4:  like, man, I've seen Microsoft try to shove windows
Speaker 4:  on a handheld in so many different ways and now it's like, yeah, it
Speaker 4:  rules now, you know, it's like fine,
Speaker 4:  fine. You want this little crap laptop, you can have it.
Speaker 6:  And I want it.
Speaker 4:  I kinda love it. I love it. I love it. I can't say no.
Speaker 4:  Also, I love, Sean has a long history. Sean is one of our co-founders. He
Speaker 4:  has a long history here at The Verge of extremely
Speaker 4:  like
Speaker 4:  just Sean photo choices. There's no adjective describing except Sean
Speaker 4:  in here. It's like the, it's a Windows handheld is obviously being
Speaker 4:  photographed in a chair outside. They're beautiful photos. They're very good.
Speaker 4:  But like only the mind of Sean Hollister can produce these images. They're
Speaker 5:  Beautiful. I love
Speaker 4:  It. It's very good. It's very, you should go read it. It's, and it's a fun
Speaker 4:  read. All right, here's my lightning round. It's our boy Elon
Speaker 4:  Musk. We haven't talked about Elon on the show for a long time. I feel like
Speaker 4:  we've done a good job, but we can't not talk about this.
Speaker 4:  Elon sued OpenAI this week for a breach of
Speaker 4:  contract, which I will come to saying that when, you know, he was a founder
Speaker 4:  of OpenAI, he gave this company a lot of money. It was supposed to be open
Speaker 4:  source. And now OpenAI is ex
Speaker 4:  proprietary extension of Microsoft. He wants the court to declare
Speaker 4:  the GT four is actually artificial general intelligence and must
Speaker 4:  be open source. It's crazy. The whole thing's crazy. OpenAI released a
Speaker 4:  reply. We thought it would be a legal filing, but it's just a blog post
Speaker 4:  that says Elon's done. Yeah. Like more or less that's what it
Speaker 4:  says with a bunch of emails where Elon is like, we should make
Speaker 4:  OpenAI part of Tesla. We obviously can't compete with Google.
Speaker 4:  Like there's just a bunch of emails in here,
Speaker 4:  which are, which is just a weird way to respond to, it's like, here's the
Speaker 4:  receipts also notably Ilya who has not been heard from
Speaker 4:  since the Sam Altman OpenAI, CEO signed the OpenAI response blog
Speaker 4:  post. Yep. So they're united on this. Here's what I will say about this O
Speaker 4:  OpenAI response and they say they're gonna move to dismiss the lawsuit. All
Speaker 4:  the claims.
Speaker 4:  This is just very basic stuff. And I'll say I got one thing wrong in the
Speaker 4:  blog post, but I did it on purpose as a test If, you believe me.
Speaker 4:  Sure. So I wrote about this. Okay. I'm not wrong, you're wrong. I'm not wrong.
Speaker 4:  I was testing you.
Speaker 4:  Sure. As, as you may know, I was once a lawyer. I was not
Speaker 4:  good at being a lawyer. I'm not claiming that I was a good lawyer. I very
Speaker 4:  quickly moved to blogging about cell phones. That's how
Speaker 4:  my legal career was going. I was like, what if I memorized the name of every
Speaker 4:  HTC cellphone? Right. That was a better choice for me as a person.
Speaker 4:  But I, I did, I did the thing. And I know a bunch of lawyers. I'm married
Speaker 4:  to a lawyer. We got lawyers on our staff. We got lawyers at the company.
Speaker 4:  They're everywhere. Like you can't get away from 'em. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  Hey, can you sue someone for breach of contract if there isn't a
Speaker 4:  contract? And the answer is basically no. Like
Speaker 4:  that fundamentally is the answer. Like you have to have a
Speaker 4:  contract, particularly if the performance of said
Speaker 4:  illusory contract takes place over a year, like longer than a
Speaker 4:  year. Hmm. So for example, I'll give you a law school hypothetical. Alex
Speaker 4:  and I are friends, right. I say to Alex, this is like some real law school
Speaker 4:  shit. I said Alex, like I'm gonna deliver you 50 pieces of
Speaker 4:  lumber a week for $50. Yeah. And Alex says, cool. And then we
Speaker 4:  shake hands, right? And then I show up and I say, here's my 50 pieces
Speaker 4:  of lumber. And Alex says, here's the 50 bucks. And we just do that over and
Speaker 4:  over again for 11 months. Right. you know, the
Speaker 4:  12th month I show up, I deliver the lumber. Alex doesn't pay me the money,
Speaker 4:  I can probably sue her for breach of contract. Rude, you've got all this
Speaker 4:  performance. I, I put, I took the lumber. And by the way, in
Speaker 4:  law school it's like always lumber. It's always something like this. Like
Speaker 4:  things of like, what are, what are you talking about? Like of pay? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You're like, like most law students are like one Ls are 23 years old
Speaker 4:  and the ancient law professor is like, and then what would happen? If, you
Speaker 4:  didn't deliver the lumber. And they're like, what are you talking about?
Speaker 4:  What is I didn't do the reading. So, I I
Speaker 5:  Promised to Venmo you every week. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Like it's always like this. Then you could sue, right. You have this
Speaker 4:  like re I did this thing called reliance where because Alex
Speaker 4:  had paid me before I went, I dropped out the lumber, I left, I assumed the
Speaker 4:  money would come. She didn't pay me. I say, you gotta pay me. I go to the
Speaker 4:  court and say, look at all of this history and then look at the negative
Speaker 4:  thing that happened to me because I assumed that she would do the thing
Speaker 4:  which is pay me the money for the lumber. That for some reason I had been
Speaker 4:  delivering for 11 months without a written contract sick for. And that's
Speaker 4:  like the, the classic law school. Can you enforce a contract that's not written
Speaker 4:  down? Example Elon is saying not that
Speaker 4:  like so much, not that
Speaker 4:  like the most, not that he's saying there is a contract,
Speaker 4:  but the contract called the founder's agreement only
Speaker 4:  exists in other pieces of paper.
Speaker 4:  He's like, it's in these emails I have between me and the other founders.
Speaker 4:  It's in the articles of incorporation that they filed in the state of California.
Speaker 4:  Like court just read some stuff I'd like you to read,
Speaker 4:  write me a contract and then say they breached that contract.
Speaker 5:  Right? He's saying, If, you read all these things. Like you'll, you'll get
Speaker 5:  the idea, right?
Speaker 4:  That when I was donating money to a nonprofit, I assumed that they would
Speaker 4:  do. And it's like ev she's like, If, you are a first year lawsuit and you're
Speaker 4:  listening to this or you attended law school. Or even if you're thinking
Speaker 4:  about attending law school, just ask yourself, you're a judge.
Speaker 4:  You're, you're looking at the richest man in the world. And he's like, I
Speaker 4:  don't know, I'm kind of an idiot. Like I just gave him all this money without
Speaker 4:  a contract. And the judges be like, get outta here. Like my own
Speaker 4:  one L contracts professor, his name is Stuart McCauley used to say to us
Speaker 4:  all the time, what happens? He pays your money and he takes your chances
Speaker 4:  and like If, you buy the stuff and it's bad. Like that's on you. And like
Speaker 4:  here, Elon's like donated the money and he
Speaker 4:  had, he has all these emails, like these other emails are like that opening
Speaker 4:  eye is publishing where he's like, this isn't enough money. We're never gonna
Speaker 4:  succeed. I want total control of this or I'm not gonna give you more money.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, dude, you just didn't have the first thing. Yep. Like the
Speaker 4:  first thing, right? Which is what are the terms of me giving you this money?
Speaker 4:  You didn't write 'em down. It is the silliest one L law
Speaker 4:  school problem I can think of to file a claim for breach of contract and
Speaker 4:  then within the breach of contract claim that the contract does not exist,
Speaker 4:  but is actually located in some emails. Like I cannot tell you
Speaker 4:  what every, like I showed it to Becky and she just gave me the face
Speaker 4:  like I don't want to think about this. I like, she's like, I graduated from
Speaker 4:  law school, I'm a practicing attorney. We don't do this anymore.
Speaker 4:  And then the second one, the claim is for promissory estoppel, which
Speaker 4:  is long term, but that's the thing where it's like I delivered the lumber
Speaker 4:  and Alex to pay me the money and So I, I have what's called
Speaker 4:  detrimental reliance. So I like assumed she would do the
Speaker 4:  thing. Sorry Alex, I assumed Alex would pay me the money that she didn't
Speaker 4:  been pay me for for months and months and months. And then I did the thing.
Speaker 4:  She didn't pay me the money. I've now relied on her promises to me and performance
Speaker 4:  of those promises in the past. There's none of that here because the detrimental
Speaker 4:  reliance is that open air was supposed to deliver a GI,
Speaker 13:  Which you cannot possibly claim.
Speaker 13:  Just what are
Speaker 4:  You talking about?
Speaker 6:  They didn't make skynet.
Speaker 4:  Anyway. It's all very dumb. The thing I got wrong is that I put a joke at
Speaker 4:  the end, another one L law school joke, where I was like, the thing that
Speaker 4:  will happen is OpenAI will, will file a,
Speaker 4:  a motion to dismiss. And I use the federal name of the motion. This place
Speaker 4:  and California quote, it's called a demur. I'm very sorry, I'm not gonna
Speaker 4:  correct it because it's a honeypot for nerds.
Speaker 5:  First of all, that's a nerds, a really good joke. It's a really good funny
Speaker 5:  joke that lots of people got and enjoyed. So great job
Speaker 4:  Sarah John thought it was hilarious.
Speaker 5:  I'm glad. There you go. It's the audience is small, but it's there. I think
Speaker 5:  to me, the wildest thing about this is this now marks two episodes in
Speaker 5:  two weeks in which we have talked about Elon Musk demanding to
Speaker 5:  take over another company. Yes. Last week it was Elon saying, I'll sell
Speaker 5:  Tesla to you Tim Cook, but I wanna be the CEO of Apple. And now
Speaker 5:  it's open AI and true, true co. Like you miss a hundred percent
Speaker 5:  of the shots you don't take. you know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like,
Speaker 6:  Shoot your shot, Elon. Next,
Speaker 5:  Next he's gonna be like, listen Larry Page, just give me Google. Just,
Speaker 5:  just shut up. Just gimme Google.
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean he's actually two Tesla shareholders saying, give me more of
Speaker 4:  Tesla. Which is very funny. Yeah. Yeah. Elon also has a very expansive
Speaker 4:  view of what a contract is. In another case, X is suing
Speaker 4:  the centers for combating digital hate for a report they put out saying
Speaker 4:  hate speech had risen on Twitter. Now X after Elon took over,
Speaker 4:  he, they're claiming this interfered with advertisers, blah, blah,
Speaker 4:  blah. And their legal theory is that it's a breach of the contract.
Speaker 4:  That when they sign up for their Twitter account, they knew they weren't
Speaker 4:  supposed to do X, Y, and Z and they could foresee that they would be
Speaker 4:  interfering in, in X's business relationships by doing whatever they did.
Speaker 4:  And the judge, I want to, I wanna say this as clear as I can. The judge
Speaker 4:  evaluating this case said to ex's lawyers, quote, this is the
Speaker 4:  most VAD extension of contract law I have ever seen.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Says that's incredible.
Speaker 13:  Like, whatcha are you doing?
Speaker 6:  I like you would be, I would be embarrassed if, if I, if I went into court
Speaker 6:  and that I've never been in court, but
Speaker 4:  If I did, you'd be embarrassed until you went to bed on your bed of dollar
Speaker 4:  bills. My wife. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Just dollar though. It's a dollar bill. Just
Speaker 13:  Single dollar ex lawyer.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Those aren't undies.
Speaker 4:  That same law professor Stuart McCauley, a contracts Professor Stuack, we
Speaker 4:  called him. He was, he was very good. He would often ask us as
Speaker 4:  we went through the facts of some esoteric lumber case, why do you think
Speaker 4:  this case was filed? And we would all answer, you know, like
Speaker 4:  some high minded question. And he, he'd start, he would start cackling and
Speaker 4:  he'd be like, no, no, no. The lawyer wanted a BMW.
Speaker 4:  It's like very good.
Speaker 5:  Elon's buying a lot of BMWs
Speaker 4:  Right now. Elon Elon's buying a lot of BMWs. I'm just saying like, If, you
Speaker 4:  want to stand in front of a judge, have the judge call you vapid. Like,
Speaker 4:  I don't think a BMW's enough. You gotta at least hit Aston, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  If not full G wagon situation. There you go. Like
Speaker 4:  a lot of Electric gwa pre-orders are being placed around the, I
Speaker 4:  should run open AI lawsuit. All right. That's it. I'm sorry
Speaker 4:  that we talked about 'em again. Ugh. It's gonna, it's an election year. We're
Speaker 4:  gonna end up talking about a lot. I can feel it coming, but don't worry.
Speaker 4:  We'll also talk about the law of emulation. Josh released the Electric charger
Speaker 4:  this week, the EV charger. It's got some big speakers in the back
Speaker 4:  that make v vroom noises that's coming up next week on To Vergecast. Everybody,
Speaker 4:  we should do a whole thing where we just compare the vroom noises that various
Speaker 4:  muscle car EVs make. We a hundred
Speaker 5:  Percent should. Oh, that's, that's, that's been in the works for a while
Speaker 5:  actually. It's, it's gonna happen. It's gonna be great Next week we're also
Speaker 5:  gonna talk about lying down mode in the Quest headsets for
Speaker 4:  Et cetera.
Speaker 5:  A lot of stuff to get to.
Speaker 4:  Very good. I should tell everyone that we recorded this day early
Speaker 4:  because the three of us will be at South by Southwest on
Speaker 4:  March 8th, doing a live Vergecast. David has set up
Speaker 4:  quite the game for us to play on that stage. If, you are in
Speaker 4:  Texas. Come see us March 8th on the Vox Media podcast stage at
Speaker 4:  South by Southwest. We would love to see you the very next day on March 9th.
Speaker 4:  I'm doing a live decoder in interviewing the CEO of Figma Dylan Field, which
Speaker 4:  will be very fun. Obviously quite a lot to talk about there. Live post Adobe.
Speaker 4:  But Dylan really wants to talk about the web and like The future of the web.
Speaker 4:  Like Figma is a web app. I dunno, If, you caught it. I'm very interested
Speaker 4:  in the web. It's like a thing I care about a bit, so I'm very upset. No idea.
Speaker 4:  With that idea, Alex is like, I didn't know what I was signing up for.
Speaker 4:  March 8th, The Vergecast at South by Southwest March 9th
Speaker 4:  decoder. We have love to see. That's it. That's her Chest.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 3:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One. The. Vergecast is the
Speaker 3:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 3:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.