# Transcript
ID: aa829817-e125-4015-a78b-a6a5cbf7b007
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6305909932565309563/1558328392375371473/s93290-US-6182s-1723821578.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss AI tools announced at this weeks Pixel 9 event, Nilay's TV competition, tech regulatory news, and more.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of our fancy new
Speaker 3:  studio. Look at this guys.
Speaker 1:  It's sick. It's so fancy.
Speaker 4:  I wish I was there to see it in person. Does it smell nice?
Speaker 3:  You know, many times this studio smells like weed when I walk into it, when
Speaker 3:  Alex and I have sat down to record this, the show. Yeah, many times we've
Speaker 3:  commented it smells like weed in here. Yeah, we don't know if that's from
Speaker 3:  our colleagues@vox.com. We don't know if that is from Liam.
Speaker 3:  We don't know if that is from the other people of the podcast here. But today
Speaker 3:  it does not smell like weed. It smells fresh and new. It's good.
Speaker 3:  If you're listening to the show, it's gonna be the same show. It was just
Speaker 3:  our, the space that we recorded has been dramatically
Speaker 3:  upgraded. David was gone for two weeks and they, our amazing
Speaker 3:  studio team took the time to, to rebuild the thing while we were kind of
Speaker 3:  out and about and traveling and recording remotely. and it's just real fancy
Speaker 3:  in here.
Speaker 5:  It does look awesome and truly, even if you're just listening like you won't
Speaker 5:  see it, but like the vibes will be better. It's very moody, you know what
Speaker 5:  I mean? It's like the Neli is like a happier, more
Speaker 5:  optimistic person now that we're in this studio.
Speaker 3:  I mean, I got a giant TV behind me that's the largest frame TV they make,
Speaker 3:  ladies and gentlemen.
Speaker 3:  And there's like a hangout zone, like where sidekicks on podcasts
Speaker 3:  go.
Speaker 5:  Oh, the like retired NFL player who just like only says two things in every
Speaker 5:  episode. Yeah, I love that. That's the job I want.
Speaker 3:  Look, the AJ Hawk corner is right over there. If you're a Pat Maxi
Speaker 3:  fan
Speaker 5:  That I
Speaker 3:  Was thinking,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna do every segment of today's show from a different spot in this
Speaker 3:  room. But it is beautiful. It's very nice. It's funny, you know, we share
Speaker 3:  the studio with other Vox Media podcast network shows. So Andre, I
Speaker 3:  and Evan Turner record in here. And then we have a new show with Megan
Speaker 3:  Rapinoe and Sue Bird that also records in here. And the first time I saw
Speaker 3:  pictures of it was all set up for them. And I was like, where's our game
Speaker 3:  cube? Don't worry. It turns out they just changed the studio
Speaker 3:  around for every show.
Speaker 5:  I do think though, we should find a way to anchor our webby to the shelves
Speaker 5:  so that no one can get rid of our webby. Anytime you do a podcast, you'll
Speaker 5:  see The, Verge cast's webby. That's, those are the rules. I
Speaker 3:  Think that's, I think our YouTube play button is permanently matched all
Speaker 3:  over there. Oh, there go. So if you are an Ex NFL player sidekick, you know,
Speaker 3:  we have a million subscribers. You know it in your heart. You gotta sit under
Speaker 3:  that. That's the mark everybody. Forever.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, I'm your friend Eli. Welcome. David. Pierce is back from vacation.
Speaker 3:  Welcome David.
Speaker 5:  Hi. I picked the worst two weeks of all time to be gone, but I'm very happy
Speaker 5:  to be
Speaker 3:  Back. Yeah, nothing happened while you were on vacation. No.
Speaker 5:  Including not the like culmination of a trial that I covered for months and
Speaker 5:  cared deeply about. and it seems very important to the end of the internet.
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah, super chill. Really.
Speaker 3:  Hey, does anybody know anything about the search engine? Neva? Oh, I guess
Speaker 3:  the guy who wrote the profile of it isn't here at all. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Real bummer. I only reported on them for like a year and a half and
Speaker 5:  didn't get to talk about that at the end. But the good news is that case
Speaker 5:  is gonna go on for six to seven more decades, so Yeah. Yeah. We'll have more
Speaker 5:  chances. It'll be all right.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, there's a long period. And then Alex, you were on Las Rege, you've
Speaker 3:  been on vacation and then you immediately went away to cover The Pixel event
Speaker 3:  in San Francisco.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm, I'm currently on, on the West Coast and not in the room with you
Speaker 4:  otherwise. So we're gonna use a Pixel to just do the add me feature and put
Speaker 4:  me in there with you. But, but otherwise it's, it's a good time out here.
Speaker 4:  It's very nice temperature wise. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The theme of this episode is can you believe your lying eyes and the answer
Speaker 3:  fully, fully? No. So let's start with The. Pixel. There's a lot to talk about.
Speaker 3:  There's there always The Pixel event, which you guys, David, I think you
Speaker 3:  covered a little bit on the Tuesday show. Yep. I want to talk about TVs.
Speaker 3:  So I love talking about TVs. So, so a lot of gadgets to open the show. Then
Speaker 3:  we got a bunch of just stuff in the app store in the EU
Speaker 3:  happening, and then of course we have a lightning round,
Speaker 3:  the deeply controversial lightning round.
Speaker 5:  I can't believe I left. And you still didn't get the lightning round sponsored,
Speaker 5:  like that's, I wanted to come back from vacation. And you were like, congratulations,
Speaker 5:  David. Here is the lightning round yacht that we all bought. We did it, we
Speaker 4:  Spent the money actually on the set. I've
Speaker 3:  Gotten all the way to, in my head, leaving the various
Speaker 3:  Vox Media corporate meetings that I have to go to with like,
Speaker 3:  what if I ended every meeting with, don't talk to me until the Lightning
Speaker 3:  Round is sponsored.
Speaker 3:  I'm not sure this would go well. I'm not sure that it would
Speaker 3:  achieve any goals really, or even my continued employment, but rest
Speaker 3:  assure I've thought about it.
Speaker 4:  You feel really cool.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like why are you talking to me with an unsponsored?
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You sachet out just like a little scarf.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is what I think about my spare time is how to get
Speaker 3:  myself hired. Okay. Let's talk about The Pixel. The Pixel itself. David,
Speaker 3:  you talked about on the Tuesday show with everybody, there's like two parts
Speaker 3:  of The Pixel event, though that I think are kind of important. One was the
Speaker 3:  phone, and then the second is that the phone wasn't introduced
Speaker 3:  until like 20 minutes into the event because what
Speaker 3:  it really was was Rick Oslo who now runs
Speaker 3:  Android and Pixel, talking about Android
Speaker 3:  becoming the platform for Google's AI ambitions and
Speaker 3:  even showing a bunch of AI features on Samsung phones. And I,
Speaker 3:  there's something there that feels very worth talking about to me.
Speaker 4:  The the what You mean the fact that we saw a Samsung phone and a Motorola
Speaker 4:  phone before we saw a Pixel phone at The
Speaker 3:  Pixel. Yeah. That's the simpler way of putting it. I think
Speaker 3:  it's weird, right? There's something to that that I think is really interesting.
Speaker 5:  It's weird and it isn't like it's, it's weird that
Speaker 5:  it's not weird is actually where I'm at with this because like, there,
Speaker 5:  there are three things going on here, right? One is that Rick Oslo
Speaker 5:  oversees Android and Pixel, and that is a very
Speaker 5:  hard job. We've talked about this, that for years Google
Speaker 5:  was like, we have a very hard firewall between our own hardware efforts and
Speaker 5:  our partner ecosystem with Android. Now it's just literally
Speaker 5:  the same dude in charge of it. And that is a, that's a complicated thing
Speaker 5:  to do, especially because for Google, the vast majority of everything
Speaker 5:  that matters about Android does not happen on pixel phones, right? So for
Speaker 5:  Google to come out and say, look, a Samsung phone that does all this stuff
Speaker 5:  is purely just a recognition of what actually matters to Google, which is
Speaker 5:  the Android business, not The Pixel business. Like that is just the fact
Speaker 5:  of the matter. The other thing is, I think
Speaker 5:  Google thinks AI as a thing and Gemini as a thing is
Speaker 5:  more important than all of that, right? Like that is the big bet. So you
Speaker 5:  have to lead with Gemini and you have to lead with Android and then like
Speaker 5:  a while later, show everybody the phone that you made. And then if
Speaker 5:  you, if you also believe as I, as I do, and I think as Google does that the
Speaker 5:  hardware just exists in service of the software which exists in service of
Speaker 5:  the ai. Like, it, it all ladders up. So it's weird
Speaker 5:  that Google ostensibly launched a bunch of gadgets in what was
Speaker 5:  not at all a gadget launch, but like increasingly, this was
Speaker 5:  now two days ago as we're recording this, like it wasn't really a gadget
Speaker 5:  launch. Like they launched some gadgets, but the main most
Speaker 5:  important thing they talked about was not the gadgets, which is very strange.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It felt more like an io. I mean, not not in the room. It, it
Speaker 4:  felt like a pixel event in the room, but the content felt like an
Speaker 4:  IO keynote more than a a Pixel event. 'cause it was just, yeah,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna talk about all these really great features that You can now use
Speaker 4:  AI to generate adorable animals. And Kiki Palmer's here.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  The Kiki Palmer thing. I'm still, I got nothing on on she there. What Kiki,
Speaker 5:  she's there like between the Kiki Palmer thing here and the Sydney Sweeney
Speaker 5:  thing at the facility. Can we just stop with the really awkward celebrity
Speaker 5:  cameos? Nobody has fun. It's good for them. They get paid. That's
Speaker 3:  Great. I say triple down more celebrity cames
Speaker 3:  more random. Neil Patrick Harris at an Apple event.
Speaker 3:  Just get out there, just whoever it is. All right. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  Be Chris Evans at the Apple event. Let, let's, or, or Scar Joe.
Speaker 4:  But no, like Sydnee Sweeney looked like a hostage. Kiki Palmer, like she
Speaker 4:  got to move around.
Speaker 3:  Hey, set the celebrities free. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Don't, don't just make him sit in a chair in awkwardly wave.
Speaker 3:  She was there sort of at the very end, right? Like she was just there to
Speaker 3:  be like, AI is great and there she
Speaker 4:  Like Kool-Aid manned in
Speaker 5:  Basically. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But the, but the thing you're discussing more broadly, which is
Speaker 3:  Google believes it has a huge distribution advantage for,
Speaker 3:  its for Gemini. That distribution advantage is Android
Speaker 3:  and they're gonna put it everywhere and embed it into all of their
Speaker 3:  platforms and services. We, Alex, you're right, we did see that coming in
Speaker 3:  io. That's basically what they said. Yeah. And Rick's message was,
Speaker 3:  now this stuff is here, it's shipping like You can get it. And then, you
Speaker 3:  know, they showed it on a bunch of Samsung Motorola phones and then they're
Speaker 3:  like, and here's The Pixel and then here's a tiny bit of stuff
Speaker 3:  The Pixel can do that the others can't do, which is the Add me feature and
Speaker 3:  the photos and all that, right? Yeah. But there's a sense that Google knows
Speaker 3:  it is better at distributing AI than any of its competitors.
Speaker 3:  It took a lot of digs at Apple, for example. Just secret,
Speaker 3:  not even secret, just like quiet sideswipes
Speaker 3:  at Apple throughout this whole event. Yeah, we're available in all the languages.
Speaker 3:  Apple's intelligence isn't, we don't have to send your data to a third party.
Speaker 3:  Apple's gonna send some of your stuff to open ai like down the line.
Speaker 3:  It was, Google was just reinforcing that it is
Speaker 3:  building the ai, like it has it, it controls it, it runs in the
Speaker 3:  cloud and the best way to get it is through Android.
Speaker 3:  I just don't know if that's gonna get anybody to switch from an iPhone. Like
Speaker 3:  that's actually the thing that I think is the most interesting here. That
Speaker 3:  they're like, Android is the place where you get your AI and everyone's kind
Speaker 3:  of like, okay, now what?
Speaker 4:  Well, I think, I think Gemini Live is probably a good example of that. 'cause
Speaker 4:  that's coming to iOS later this year and that they spent a lot
Speaker 4:  of time on Gemini live. It felt like that's, that's their like answer to
Speaker 4:  chat GT's, voice assistant. And yeah,
Speaker 4:  it really just felt like this moment of, okay, no, you don't actually just
Speaker 4:  need to be on, on an Android device. And I, I personally, I just
Speaker 4:  kept thinking of the fact that just last week they found out that they, something's
Speaker 4:  gonna happen with Google and one of their biggest revenue drivers is their
Speaker 4:  relationship with the iPhone. And so now it feels like their, their phone
Speaker 4:  ecosystem is more important than ever and we just didn't
Speaker 4:  hear a single thing about it besides ai. So yeah, it is a, and it is a little
Speaker 4:  weird that everything hinges on this AI now.
Speaker 3:  So in all the big AI companies have been saying is that they think AI
Speaker 3:  is a platform shift. You can interpret that a lot of ways.
Speaker 3:  Like I, I tried to get Sundar Phai to explain what that means to me. IS
Speaker 5:  Trying to get, Pichai said it's as big as fire. I don't know that there's
Speaker 5:  that many ways to interpret. That's just the one really. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  He's, yeah. I mean, but it's true. But I I what the way I have interpreted
Speaker 3:  platform shift is people are gonna use computers in a
Speaker 3:  different way and that will create many more opportunities to build products
Speaker 3:  and services, right? And, if you look back at the history of platform shifts,
Speaker 3:  you go from, I don't know, dos and text-based
Speaker 3:  computing to mice and keyboards, and then you go
Speaker 3:  from local applications to the web and then
Speaker 3:  you go to touchscreens on phones, right? Yeah. Those are the platforms.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. If You can think of another way to think about the word platform shift,
Speaker 3:  please let me know because I'm sort of dying to figure out how to
Speaker 3:  understand the words platform shift as it relates to ai. And all
Speaker 3:  I've come up with in that framework is, oh, you're gonna talk
Speaker 3:  to the computer instead of typing,
Speaker 4:  Which isn't a pla Well, like that's a platform shift we already had,
Speaker 3:  Right? Except now can do it. Except, except, except now Gemini Live can just
Speaker 3:  like listen to you and maybe take actions on your behalf and maybe you're
Speaker 3:  gonna type to it. Maybe you're just gonna say, I don't know, like go make
Speaker 3:  me an app that can do X and Gemini Live will spit it out and that'll be fine.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Or Siri on with Apple Intelligence will go use the apps for you,
Speaker 3:  which is something that Apple has, you know, it's not gonna ship, but it's,
Speaker 3:  it's what they previewed at wwc. That is, that's the platform
Speaker 3:  shift. That's
Speaker 5:  The platform shift. That last piece is the real platform shift. And this
Speaker 5:  is, this is what I've been hearing from people forever. I think it was Paul Ford
Speaker 5:  recently wrote a really good thing about this where he's, he said, right
Speaker 5:  now we're in the, the like command line era of ai, which
Speaker 5:  is like, the tech is kind of under there, but nobody has figured out how
Speaker 5:  to use it yet. And the idea that you're going to be essentially use
Speaker 5:  a command line to interact with it, which is essentially what writing an
Speaker 5:  AI prompt is, is fine as far as it goes. But that's not
Speaker 5:  the mainstream answer. And that actually what needs to happen is everybody
Speaker 5:  needs to invent the interface on top of that. That makes it interesting and
Speaker 5:  that we have not seen. But I think the, the thing that I hear from
Speaker 5:  everybody is like, this starts to get really interesting when we get to the,
Speaker 5:  it can use your apps for you phase of all of this, because that's
Speaker 5:  where you actually do use your computer differently. Because right
Speaker 5:  now it's like you Right. You can look up information by talking
Speaker 5:  instead of by typing. And, and Alex, to your point A, that exists.
Speaker 5:  B it's not better. Like it's not better. It's different. It's a little
Speaker 5:  faster, but it's not better. And Alex, you've, you've used Gemini live a
Speaker 5:  little, so I'm, I'm curious to hear what you think, but like we're still
Speaker 5:  at this point where it it is, it is sort of a
Speaker 5:  technology in search of a user interface. Yeah. And I
Speaker 5:  think, I didn't like, you see a lot of Google like poking at that. I think
Speaker 5:  The Pixel screenshots thing, which we should talk about, in which I am on
Speaker 5:  record of being fascinated by is an interesting version of that. But like,
Speaker 5:  how you actually push and pull with this thing is
Speaker 5:  such an unanswered question in so, so many ways.
Speaker 4:  I feel like they, they, they definitely haven't figured it out. Like, like
Speaker 4:  I, I only spent a little time with Jim and I live, it was me and Sean, Hollister,
Speaker 4:  Allison, all Johnson, all in our little room trying to talk to this thing.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 5:  Was it the same, I'm picturing a demo like the chat GPT one where it's phone
Speaker 5:  on a table listening to
Speaker 4:  You and you just chat. Yeah. Like you to hold the phone. Like, like I couldn't
Speaker 4:  stand far away from the phone. You have to hold the phone really close to
Speaker 4:  yourself. 'cause otherwise it'll be like, no, I'm not listening to you. But
Speaker 4:  I really struggled with it. 'cause I tried to be very polite in
Speaker 4:  conversations and like, oh, if you're talking, I'm gonna usually let you
Speaker 4:  finish. Not always as Vergecast listeners can attest, but I'm usually
Speaker 4:  gonna let you finish. And, and this one you're like encouraged to interrupt
Speaker 4:  it and, and you're encouraged to interact with it in a way that would be
Speaker 4:  like really rude if you were interacting with a person. And so
Speaker 4:  it's at one point wants you to feel like it's more human and more
Speaker 4:  realistic. And at the other point it's doing that and then like, I got
Speaker 4:  in a fight with it 'cause it wouldn't shut up. Yes. And so I told her it
Speaker 4:  was mansplaining me and it was like, oh, I'm sorry, do you want me to change
Speaker 4:  my tone of my voice? And I was like, and it was a little sassy when it said
Speaker 4:  it. I was just like, did I just get like talk clap
Speaker 4:  back to that by ai? Yes. And then, yeah, this is incredible. Then, then
Speaker 4:  Sean was like, I got this. And Sean just went in and was like, no, shut up.
Speaker 4:  I have a question. And just immediately was just No, no, shush me now.
Speaker 4:  Oh man. And, and it, so like, he was basically a dick to it and it worked
Speaker 4:  perfectly. And I'm like, okay. Was he
Speaker 3:  Like, who knows more about the steam deck? You were me.
Speaker 4:  He might've asked that, but we, we main, he mainly asked it for to stock
Speaker 4:  tips and that it was like, I, I wouldn't personally invest in Bitcoin,
Speaker 4:  but You can do that if you want. It's just incredible. Very
Speaker 3:  High risk. Incredible. Our very first Gemini scandal.
Speaker 3:  No, that's not scandal. That's just good advice. Yeah. Here's my question.
Speaker 3:  So you, you use it, you talk to it, it has some personality. This is,
Speaker 3:  this is the thing, like this is how Google is talking about beating open
Speaker 3:  ai, right? Right. Open AI is gonna put out its voice version.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna sound like Scarlet Hanson or not. It's gonna have personality.
Speaker 3:  It, it takes a breath in the middle of counting numbers as fast as it can.
Speaker 3:  We've all seen that video. It's like they're competing on personality,
Speaker 3:  not content.
Speaker 4:  Right. They're com Yeah, because some stuff, it did really, really well for
Speaker 4:  me. Like I, I, I asked it to fix something, it took me a while to fix on
Speaker 4:  my car and it did it in 30 seconds. It was just great. And another stuff
Speaker 4:  I really struggled with and it, it struggled to understand the questions
Speaker 4:  and if like somebody compared it to being a, a
Speaker 4:  kind of a friend and I wouldn't have friends
Speaker 4:  like this thing because it it, it just talks. It doesn't
Speaker 4:  listen to you. It doesn't respond to you in, in the way that
Speaker 4:  a, a friend might and it's, but it's at the same
Speaker 4:  time it's a computer. So you're just in this weird space where you're like,
Speaker 4:  am I having to be nice to my computer?
Speaker 4:  And I, I don't necessarily want that. I want it to just be my computer
Speaker 3:  What you want. I think that the thesis of The Verge as a whole, as a publication
Speaker 3:  is, do I have to be nice to my computer? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 3:  And we've been struggling to figure out that answer for quite some
Speaker 5:  Time. But I do think in, in a way, those companies
Speaker 5:  pushing that stuff are kind of telling on themselves about the actual state
Speaker 5:  of the technology. Right. Because what has been true for 60 years
Speaker 5:  is that if you give a computer any kind of personality, people will
Speaker 5:  fall in love with it and try to have sex with it and tell it their deepest,
Speaker 5:  darkest secrets. Like it's just true. Like you, you, we, we did a video about
Speaker 5:  this a while ago that was very fun. And it's like in the seventies, this
Speaker 5:  guy made a thing that basically all it did was say your commands back to
Speaker 5:  you as a question. And so you'd be like, you know, my father was mean to
Speaker 5:  me and it would be like your father was mean to you. And people were like,
Speaker 5:  oh my God, it understands me. This
Speaker 3:  Is Eliza.
Speaker 5:  Right? Yes. That was Eliza. Yeah. And, and that's, that's actually a really
Speaker 5:  powerful thing. And I think one other thing I miss while I was on vacation
Speaker 5:  was all the friend drama. I wrote this story about this
Speaker 5:  guy who launched an AI friend and it, everybody went nuts on the internet
Speaker 5:  because there was drama about who owned it. It was the whole thing.
Speaker 5:  I'm very happy I missed all of that drama. But one of the things that Avi,
Speaker 5:  the, the CEO said to me was, he was like, the reason I'm doing this is because
Speaker 5:  it's the only thing AI is any good at right now. And I think that's right.
Speaker 5:  That there is, there is vast gaps
Speaker 5:  between where we are right now with this technology and like true
Speaker 5:  utility in people's lives. But it's pretty
Speaker 5:  easy to make one of these like fun as hell to talk to. Yeah. Because it's
Speaker 5:  not that hard to make them fun as hell to talk to. So what they're able to
Speaker 5:  compete on right now is making them fun as hell to talk to because that will
Speaker 5:  make people use them more, even if they can't do very much and the things
Speaker 5:  that they do, they don't do very well. And so if you're just using this as
Speaker 5:  like a rote, straightforward robotic task machine, you're
Speaker 5:  gonna notice it's bad and you're gonna hate it. Yeah. But if you make it
Speaker 5:  fun and cool and friendly and exciting, it doesn't have to do that much.
Speaker 5:  Right. And I think that's a fine road to go down, but it is so not
Speaker 5:  the same thing as like making it more useful to people.
Speaker 3:  So lemme put that into the framework or the question I was asking
Speaker 3:  Alex, when you were using Gemini Live, did any of it feel
Speaker 3:  like the platform shift? Because that is the big
Speaker 3:  question, right? If you're, if you're Microsoft and you're pouring billions
Speaker 3:  of dollars into this because you missed mobile right? Then this is your
Speaker 3:  chance to reclaim the primary user interface of computers. If you're Google
Speaker 3:  and you're basically communicating that you're gonna bet the company on this,
Speaker 3:  is it there, is it, is there evidence that that is real? Because I don't,
Speaker 3:  I don't know. I I honestly don't know.
Speaker 4:  I it's, no, no. I I think right now,
Speaker 4:  yeah, I think, I think right now the the answer is no for me, I think it
Speaker 4:  is a valuable tool. I was talking with people afterwards who don't even work
Speaker 4:  at Google, work at other companies about the, these kind of things. And they
Speaker 4:  were like, oh yeah, I really like it. 'cause it's a good brainstorming tool.
Speaker 4:  It's a good way for me to like just figure some stuff out. And I, I'm
Speaker 4:  not gonna brainstorm that way personally.
Speaker 5:  That's, it's fun to talk to. Like that's the whole thing.
Speaker 4:  Fun to talk. Yeah. It's not fun to talk to, but, but like, I didn't feel
Speaker 4:  this urge to just, oh, I want this in my car. I did actually want it in my
Speaker 4:  car immediately, so nevermind. I did feel that urge. So
Speaker 3:  That's a platform shift. Yeah. I I slightly mansplaining to her. You're like,
Speaker 3:  This is the future.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. It was like so mansplaining. It was very upsetting. But
Speaker 4:  like as a, as a voice, as as if you think of it as part of the, the
Speaker 4:  evolution of the voice assistant as the digital voice assistant, it's a lot
Speaker 4:  better. It it is a huge improvement over assistant. It's a huge improvement
Speaker 4:  over Siri and, and, and Alexa. But is it a
Speaker 4:  replacement for computing general? Like general
Speaker 4:  computing? No, absolutely not. It's not a platform shift
Speaker 4:  for my phone. It's a platform shift for my Alexa. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well I think even the question of is it better than Google
Speaker 5:  Assistant or Siri or Alexa is a really interesting one because one of the
Speaker 5:  things that's happening is Gemini is replacing Google Assistant kind of all
Speaker 5:  over Android, which is a big deal. Like it wasn't that long ago that Google
Speaker 5:  was out there being like, Google Assistant is the future of everything. And
Speaker 5:  now it's very clearly Gemini and there have been a bunch of people out there
Speaker 5:  testing early versions of this thing. Obviously there are early, we'll see
Speaker 5:  and it just can't do some of the very, very basic timers, basic things
Speaker 5:  you would expect. That's what, right? And so it's like, okay, you have this
Speaker 5:  thing that is more fun to talk to, understands you better, does the
Speaker 5:  sort of basic interface tasks way better, like orders of
Speaker 5:  magnitude better than the stuff that we had before. But it can't do the things.
Speaker 5:  I think it was Jared Newman at Fast Company wrote a thing where he was like,
Speaker 5:  it can't tell me what the weather is. It can't play the
Speaker 5:  podcasts that I have played because it doesn't have access to my apps. It
Speaker 5:  doesn't do turn by turn directions very well. Just all these basic things.
Speaker 5:  It's like, okay, what Google Assistant had is is access to the systems
Speaker 5:  that you actually want on your phone, right? Like it was able to use your
Speaker 5:  apps for you and Gemini can't use your apps for you, but we're
Speaker 5:  replacing the one with the other before it can do both things.
Speaker 5:  Which to me is just, it's like, it's so clear that that is what Google
Speaker 5:  thinks is more important.
Speaker 4:  It feels like a big rush, but I'm also, I feel not
Speaker 4:  concerned about, I feel like that's the kind of thing that they can do a
Speaker 4:  software update and be like, yeah, now it can do timers. Now it can tell
Speaker 4:  you the weather. Like those should be relatively easy things to just pipe
Speaker 4:  in. And I, I think they just haven't because they've been moving that quickly
Speaker 4:  to churn this out and, and compete with Apple. Like to the point of
Speaker 4:  they, this whole event happened a month before. What we assume is
Speaker 4:  gonna be the Apple, the iPhone launch. And traditionally it's how in October.
Speaker 4:  And that was very, I think everybody in the industry was just like, oh, that's
Speaker 4:  just to get ahead of Apple intelligence. And so it definitely feels like
Speaker 4:  they're ru they're, they're they're rushing it, it, but at the same time
Speaker 4:  there's a level of polish there, but it's not perfect, right? Like, like
Speaker 4:  there's with, with Siri and Assistant and stuff like that. You ask it a question
Speaker 4:  and it'll pop up something contextually on the screen for you. So You can
Speaker 4:  see it. There's, there's a visual component and there's zero visual component
Speaker 4:  here. And I think that if anything was the most annoying
Speaker 4:  element of it. 'cause you ask it for questions, you just expect to see some
Speaker 4:  sort of result in front of you and instead you just see this little glowy
Speaker 4:  screen and it's like, okay, cool. Like that'd be, that'd be cool in my
Speaker 4:  meta glasses, that's just not cool on my phone. Yeah, that's a waste of my
Speaker 4:  phone. Even
Speaker 3:  When I use the chat GBT voice mode, which I think I've
Speaker 3:  said this several times, I have mapped the action button on my iPhone
Speaker 3:  halfway through it talking. I'm like, I just need to read this. Like, yeah,
Speaker 3:  yeah. I'm tired of this. Like I can just read much
Speaker 3:  faster than You can. You can machine talk to me robot. We're gonna get another
Speaker 3:  run at this. When the phone's come out, we're obviously going to get a chance
Speaker 3:  to use it more. I wanna talk for one second to wrap up
Speaker 3:  the Android Pixel AI conversation and just talk about the,
Speaker 3:  the photo stuff for half a second. I feel like I could spend five
Speaker 3:  hours talking about what is a photo right now. I would say
Speaker 5:  Historically speaking that that we've proven that several times.
Speaker 3:  So, you know, the The Pixel nine's coming out, Becca's gotten a chance to
Speaker 3:  use the Add Me feature in some of the other photo stuff. You can go watch
Speaker 3:  that video. But we are just in a really weird spot
Speaker 3:  where it seems like the phone makers
Speaker 3:  in particular have utterly given up on the idea that the
Speaker 3:  pictures they take should represent reality. What
Speaker 5:  Was the line that you pulled out, Eli, where like Google was like, we're
Speaker 5:  not even, we they don't, they don't do photos anymore.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So Julian at Wire did the piece on The Pixel camera this year,
Speaker 3:  sat down with a bunch of Google folks, talked about the camera and new features
Speaker 3:  and why it's better. And basically his thesis in this piece is Google is
Speaker 3:  chasing memories, not photos. And so he talked to a Google PM named Isaac
Speaker 3:  Reynolds who says, quote, it's about what you're remembering when you
Speaker 3:  define a memory that has a fallibility to it. You can have a true and
Speaker 3:  perfect representation of a moment that felt completely fake and wrong. What
Speaker 3:  some of these edits do is help you create a moment that is the way you
Speaker 3:  remember it, that is authentic to your memory and the greater context,
Speaker 3:  but maybe isn't authentic to a particular millisecond.
Speaker 5:  Wow.
Speaker 3:  There's a, that's a PhD thesis.
Speaker 5:  Seriously. It's
Speaker 3:  Beautiful. That is a PhD thesis in philosophy right there.
Speaker 3:  Like what is real? Is it what you remember or what actually
Speaker 3:  happened?
Speaker 3:  I don't a PhD thesis, I'm just telling you You can spend the rest
Speaker 3:  of your life chasing down that question. And Google
Speaker 3:  has just made a decision that what they want to do is help
Speaker 3:  people create the memories they felt they were experiencing as opposed
Speaker 3:  to capturing what actually happened. And they're just headed down that road
Speaker 3:  and they have been for some time
Speaker 5:  I think not just Google, that's everybody. Like that's a pretty good summation
Speaker 5:  of the whole industry right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And it, it's, it's bananas to me because
Speaker 3:  we live in a time when like synthetic and fake media
Speaker 3:  is everywhere and You can even see that having
Speaker 3:  it exist at all allows bad actors to call
Speaker 3:  into question the significance or reality of real
Speaker 3:  media. So Trump saying the Harris rally was quote
Speaker 3:  AIed, which can we not make the crowd can
Speaker 5:  Can, can you just pause real fast? Like can we not with the AI as a verb,
Speaker 5:  like AI already means too many things. It's a, it's a huge
Speaker 5:  catchall word that has become sort of meaning. Let's can we not make it other
Speaker 5:  parts of speech too? I
Speaker 3:  Agree. Just you, we should not use language like Donald Trump uses language,
Speaker 3:  but what I'm getting at is you only get to do that if
Speaker 3:  people believe the technology can do it. and it is true that people have
Speaker 3:  believed the technology can do this stuff for years before can, but now they're
Speaker 3:  gonna hold in their hands the capability on a
Speaker 3:  Samsung phone to circle an empty field and say add a crowd, right? They
Speaker 3:  can just do it. They are gonna hold in their hands the ability to add
Speaker 3:  people to photos who weren't there before with add me on a Google Pixel
Speaker 3:  and the companies are marketing this as this makes you more creative. It
Speaker 3:  lets you take the photos you want and now for Google all the way to,
Speaker 3:  we want you to create the memories of the things you thought were happening
Speaker 3:  rather than the things that were happening. I mean,
Speaker 4:  Haven't like Chinese filmmakers been doing that with, we wanna create
Speaker 4:  what I think I look like versus what I actually look like with the face tuning.
Speaker 4:  Like sure it's been happening a while. Like it's one of those
Speaker 4:  things I think what was shocking to me is the ease of
Speaker 4:  access of the tool itself. But I'm not like shocked at putting these
Speaker 4:  tools on the phone, but it's weird that they put it in the camera app.
Speaker 3:  The Add me feature is not like the most ai it's like
Speaker 3:  generating you, right? But it's doing a bunch of cool stuff on a
Speaker 3:  technical level. It's it's doing something cool, right? It's generating a
Speaker 3:  depth map and then using the depth map to realign the multiple
Speaker 3:  photos. That's all very cool. And I'm confident there's a bunch of AI in
Speaker 3:  there that is helping to do that. But it on, at the most fundamental level,
Speaker 3:  what it's doing is compositing two photos together, right? Like you look
Speaker 3:  at the photos that the Hollywood magazines put out with like 500 stars
Speaker 3:  on the cover. Those are often composite photos and we don't,
Speaker 4:  Those are adme photos. Like, like every single poster movie poster you see
Speaker 4:  is one of those adme photos. But like Right.
Speaker 3:  But I'm never like, I wonder if this movie poster happened like
Speaker 4:  Right. But I'll also say the, I got to
Speaker 4:  try it out a little bit at the event. And, and Aby is certainly really
Speaker 4:  cool, but also I would say it's like a, the royal family level
Speaker 4:  of Photoshopping abilities. Ooh,
Speaker 3:  Deep cut Alex. You see some,
Speaker 4:  You see some like hands where hands should not be that sort of thing
Speaker 4:  sometimes. So it's one of those things where it's like, yeah, it'll do it
Speaker 4:  at a glance. It looks awesome, it looks really, really cool. You look closer
Speaker 4:  and, and you see the edges on this stuff. Mm. And I haven't gotten to try
Speaker 4:  it as all of these tools, but like even the, the AI one where you circle
Speaker 4:  things and add like that messed up at the event, they
Speaker 4:  scrolled through it really, really fast and they were like, they're like,
Speaker 4:  here's a hot air balloon. And then they like did another one. It was like
Speaker 4:  a blob and the guy like just speed scrolled past this horrible
Speaker 4:  amorphous blob. It
Speaker 5:  Was pretty great.
Speaker 3:  All I'm getting at is those tools aren't great, but because they exist Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And they are broadly accessible. It's not just that there's a bunch
Speaker 3:  of synthetic photos we can point at and say those are fake bad
Speaker 3:  actors are able to point at real photos and say they are fake and we
Speaker 3:  are just barreling towards no one believes
Speaker 3:  anything. They see. I,
Speaker 4:  I think we're already there.
Speaker 3:  There's a strong argument we're already there. But
Speaker 5:  Do you guys remember a bunch of years ago, Farhad Manju,
Speaker 5:  when he was at the New York Times wrote this really great column about selfie
Speaker 5:  culture and his big sort of thinky
Speaker 5:  thought that I've been thinking about ever since was basically like
Speaker 5:  we've, we've entered into a place where everything that there is to be photographed
Speaker 5:  has been photographed. And so now what's different is that I'm there and
Speaker 5:  that's, it's, it's like a, it's a meaningful thing, right? It's like I'm,
Speaker 5:  this picture is different because it has me in it. In the Grand Canyon, you've
Speaker 5:  already seen pictures of the Grand Canyon, so people are putting themselves
Speaker 5:  in it as like, this is a, this is a new way of seeing this because I'm here.
Speaker 5:  Something like Add Me just breaks that in the most interesting way.
Speaker 5:  It's like we talk about sort of the cultural meaning of photos and
Speaker 5:  I, I was seeing a bunch of people during the Google event be like, how on
Speaker 5:  earth can a photo first social network exist after this? Like
Speaker 5:  if, if suddenly I can be anywhere at any time
Speaker 5:  doing whatever I feel like just gets weird and I get that ame
Speaker 5:  has some like limitations that make that challenging. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, arguably the photo first social media has been weird for a while given
Speaker 4:  that like influencers rent sets that look like planes
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Fair to fake looking like they're sitting in a plane.
Speaker 5:  But at least that like costs money and time and effort. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's not really easy. I agree. Like, like what Pixel has done, what Google
Speaker 4:  has done is just remove a ton of barriers that were
Speaker 4:  already existed, right? Like Photoshop already existed. People faking photos
Speaker 4:  has been happening forever. Yeah. But now it's just like, to to Neely's point
Speaker 4:  really, really easy. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's Samsung faking the moon, but it's you and it's everywhere. Like weird.
Speaker 3:  Two things. One, I, we should have made this set look like a private chat.
Speaker 3:  What were we thinking?
Speaker 4:  Oh my God, we
Speaker 5:  Fun.
Speaker 3:  Fundamental airly. I, this should look like
Speaker 5:  A PJ lying down in the PJ doing podcast.
Speaker 3:  I'm so mad that this room doesn't look like the inside of a private jet.
Speaker 3:  Second what we're talking about the the cost element that you bring up
Speaker 3:  David is the thing. Yeah. It's the thing when when
Speaker 3:  ILM made fake dinosaurs in Jurassic Park, there was not a
Speaker 3:  widespread outcry about people believing dinosaurs are
Speaker 3:  real.
Speaker 4:  A small outcry somewhere. I'm sure.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. There's actually one line from that movie that should have gotten
Speaker 3:  even more outcry, which is you were so busy wondering if you could
Speaker 6:  Never Right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm just pointing out. But when you make it so that everyone's
Speaker 3:  phone, you put Velociraptors in every photo and they look real
Speaker 3:  and you brought the cost to nothing, some people are gonna believe some dumb
Speaker 3:  stuff and like we are just there. And I,
Speaker 3:  I agree with you Alex. Like we might be way past the point of no return where
Speaker 3:  people are just not gonna believe anything's true anymore. Yeah. Like the
Speaker 3:  needle might just be in the red.
Speaker 6:  I'm just deeply cynical. I'm
Speaker 3:  Sorry. Wait. I think we wrote with The Pixel eight last year that we were
Speaker 3:  at the, what is a photo apocalypse? Yeah. I'm just saying, I I'm looking
Speaker 3:  at it now and there's no longer, when we wrote about The Pixel
Speaker 3:  eight, there was some pushback like, we're not doing this, we're being careful
Speaker 3:  you're overreacting. And then this year they're like, You can just put yourself
Speaker 3:  in the right and it's like, oh, we're over it.
Speaker 3:  bourbon and cigar advice. Alright, we should start that show.
Speaker 3:  And my answer is have as much as you want. Yeah, that's, it'll be fine. Just
Speaker 3:  enjoy it. Take one. Yeah, it's fine. It's two or three in. They're all the
Speaker 3:  same. Really. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's enough. We, we've done enough philosophizing about AI and
Speaker 3:  platform shifts and whether or not reality is real. Let's talk about
Speaker 3:  the most important tech story of the week, which is that as
Speaker 3:  promised, I published 2,500 words about
Speaker 3:  judging the 2024 TV shootout.
Speaker 3:  I've never been happier in my entire life
Speaker 3:  doing the shootout, writing the words, avoiding the many other
Speaker 3:  lawsuits that happened this week, because if you remember last
Speaker 3:  week I was gonna do it and then the Google decision came out and the whole
Speaker 3:  week got thrown away and I couldn't talk about TVs this week. I just ignored
Speaker 3:  everything. Google
Speaker 5:  Also really ruining everybody's life is what I'm hearing. Yeah, it's been,
Speaker 5:  it's been a hard time on all of us.
Speaker 3:  A thing we, and one assumes for Google,
Speaker 3:  we should probably, we, there's some regulatory stuff talking about Google
Speaker 3:  is in a world of her right now. We'll, we'll come to that later. But we did
Speaker 3:  it again. We were gonna talk about TVs, we start talking about Google antitrust.
Speaker 3:  Tell us about the TVs you like. These concepts are so inextricably linked
Speaker 3:  for some bizarre reason
Speaker 3:  why
Speaker 3:  no TVs we're no TVs. There's a really high end boutique home theater
Speaker 3:  store in Scarsdale, New York called Valley Electronics. They've been running
Speaker 3:  the TV shootout for 20 years. This was the 20th one. You can go Google all
Speaker 3:  the coverage from 20 years ago, 2004, like plasmas are it amazing. The whole
Speaker 3:  thing's amazing.
Speaker 3:  I bought my Sony a 95 L there because they have stock, it's actually
Speaker 3:  pretty hard to get that tv, but they sell so many of them that Sony gives
Speaker 3:  them special allocations. I went and bought one from them.
Speaker 3:  I got to talk to, to the owner, Robert's son and his wife Wendy.
Speaker 3:  And they were like, do you want to judge the shootout this year? And I
Speaker 3:  just imagine, I was like, yes. Like more than anything, I'm just going to,
Speaker 3:  my wife and daughter will be fine. I'll just wait here until the TV shootout
Speaker 3:  begins. So they called me in to judge it. It was an incredible panel. Like
Speaker 3:  the I You can look at the story. The pictures are adorable.
Speaker 3:  It was just a bunch of nerds in a room like they
Speaker 3:  cleaned. They cleared out the store and they set up
Speaker 3:  three TVs, three OLEDs and three mini LDS from Samsung, Sony, and
Speaker 3:  lg.
Speaker 3:  And they put $40,000 Sony reference monitors,
Speaker 3:  like the ones that used for coloring in Hollywood in front of them. And then
Speaker 3:  the, the first day was quote the objective day
Speaker 3:  where the, the task was
Speaker 3:  across a number of clips that they were playing to judge how
Speaker 3:  similar the TVs were to the reference displays. And the TVs had
Speaker 3:  been professionally calibrated by like famous
Speaker 3:  calibrators on the AAVs forums. Can you I was like in heaven. That's
Speaker 5:  An amazing phrase you just said by the way. Yeah. Calibrated by famous
Speaker 5:  calibrators. Like hell yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like if you're an a VS forum nerd and you have ever just like gone and looked
Speaker 3:  for the settings for a tv, it was probably Cecil need or Dwayne Davis.
Speaker 3:  That's awesome. Who go by classy tech and denic. I was in heaven,
Speaker 3:  heaven, heaven. Like
Speaker 3:  just a bunch of nerds talking about TVs. 14 years. So,
Speaker 5:  So where, where were you on the, on the list of like panelists and experts
Speaker 5:  from most to least qualified? Where would you, you say you were fully deceased?
Speaker 3:  Fully the least. Okay. All the other judges are basically like Hollywood
Speaker 3:  types. Okay. So the director of encoding services at Warner
Speaker 3:  Brothers Discovery, the senior director of technical operations at
Speaker 3:  Paramount, a handful of professional cinema,
Speaker 3:  cinematographers and directors, a handful of professional calibrators. So
Speaker 3:  calibrators are, that's a real job in this industry. People set up their
Speaker 3:  studios, they bring in the professional calibrators to make sure everything
Speaker 3:  is displaying accurately at every point in the chain. So from
Speaker 3:  your camera to your display to your mastering display, this is a real thing.
Speaker 3:  And so those people have kind of the most knowledge of all of the
Speaker 3:  quirks of all of the various displays because they're constantly trying
Speaker 3:  to get them to display accurately. And so what was particularly
Speaker 3:  interesting is they know these TVs really well
Speaker 3:  because these TVs are showing up increasingly
Speaker 3:  in professional operations because fancy studio executives like
Speaker 3:  watching things on big TVs instead of little reference monitors. And
Speaker 3:  they're like, yeah, these Sony A 95 Ls are showing up all over the place
Speaker 3:  as reference displays for the executives. And so they just, and and
Speaker 3:  obviously they do fancy home theaters and other viewing rooms and all this
Speaker 3:  stuff. So it was really interesting to talk to them 'cause they're in the
Speaker 3:  weeds of what these things can and can't do. Yes. Sort of divorced from
Speaker 3:  any marketing or whatever. Like they're just trying to make them look
Speaker 3:  good professionally and they're, they're completely aware of the limits
Speaker 3:  of the TVs. So, and then there's me and I'm like, yeah, I've just been looking
Speaker 3:  at screens for 15 years. I have a lot of opinions. And I thought that was,
Speaker 3:  it was kind of interesting to be that person because it
Speaker 3:  w like we weren't supposed to talk to each other so much, but in, in the
Speaker 3:  conversations we had, it was kind of interesting how much
Speaker 3:  my instincts were to compare things to like phones and tablets and You
Speaker 3:  can see how the TVs relate to what these
Speaker 3:  companies do on their phones and tablets. So I was looking at the Samsung
Speaker 3:  and I was like, oh, that looks like a Samsung. Like I have looked at a lot
Speaker 3:  of Samsung screens over the years and boy does Samsung like nuclear
Speaker 3:  colors. Yeah, Samsung has a move for sure. Yeah. And it's like, oh, and
Speaker 3:  they're, and they were like, why do they do that? I'm like, I don't know.
Speaker 3:  They just always do that. Like every Samsung display ever looked at has just
Speaker 3:  been incredibly bright and colorful even at the expense of accuracy.
Speaker 3:  and it, that was, it was kinda interesting to just have that other perspective
Speaker 3:  in the room. They obviously knew more on the technical
Speaker 3:  elements of the displays. Like they were, they kept bringing up the reference
Speaker 3:  curves on the reference display. Oh wow. And being like, see this? And I'd
Speaker 3:  be like, it's a line, like make it brighter.
Speaker 3:  And eventually, you know, you start to pick up on what they were showing
Speaker 3:  you. But it was just like, it was interesting to have that other perspective.
Speaker 3:  So the, the fascinating thing about all of this is this is
Speaker 3:  the year that Sony made a big bet on many
Speaker 3:  LED TVs as opposed to OLEDs. So Sony's still selling a bunch of
Speaker 3:  OLEDs. Their flagship TV is still an oled. That's a 8 95 L that's a year
Speaker 3:  old now. That came out last year, last September basically.
Speaker 3:  But you know, we're basically a year into it. And the 8 95 L
Speaker 3:  won again, like it just won the shootout. And last year's tv. Last year's
Speaker 3:  TV won the shootout. Wow. That's a quantum ed. So it has a wider
Speaker 3:  color gamut. We think it's a Samsung panel. It pretty much is a Samsung panel.
Speaker 3:  And then this year's Samsung ed we think is
Speaker 3:  the, like the next generation quantum ed, but Samsung is Samsung
Speaker 3:  and they did some weird stuff with colors and like it
Speaker 3:  lost by just like 0.1. Okay. Right. It was just a little bit behind in
Speaker 3:  some things because, and
Speaker 4:  Then the LG was at the back.
Speaker 3:  And so this is a really weird thing is the
Speaker 3:  65 inch LG G four performed much
Speaker 3:  worse than the 83 inch LG G four and
Speaker 3:  the calibrators in the room who have been like setting up these TVs for different
Speaker 3:  people are like, this is the story with these TVs, the 55 and then
Speaker 3:  the 77 and up. Weird all great. The 65 seems
Speaker 3:  to be worse.
Speaker 4:  Oh no, I have to go get a new tv. Well,
Speaker 3:  I mean, look, one takeaway I'll give everyone is like the OLEDs were so close
Speaker 3:  to each other that it was taking like three times the amount of time
Speaker 3:  to score them as compared to the reference. 'cause you had to see where the
Speaker 3:  differences are. Whereas on the mini LED side, you're like, okay, the LGS
Speaker 3:  bad Sam, no one knows what SAM is doing. And then the Sony's pretty
Speaker 3:  good, but I can see these big problems. Right. Yeah. And so the, the game
Speaker 3:  on that first day was you had the reference display that was showing
Speaker 3:  ideally what, you know, the studio or whoever wants you to see in
Speaker 3:  the picture. That's the reference display.
Speaker 5:  Wait, can I ask a really dumb question? Yeah. Is a reference display
Speaker 5:  like the best one? Like is that Yes. Is that how we should
Speaker 5:  think about reference display is? Like this is the perfect television?
Speaker 3:  Yes. No. Yes. So yes and no. I, I'll
Speaker 3:  agree with Alex partially, but n no, it's the most accurate representation
Speaker 3:  of like the content. So
Speaker 5:  It's the one that like changes the least through
Speaker 5:  the whole pipeline,
Speaker 3:  I guess. Yeah. It's like you have a display and
Speaker 3:  it is ideally the same display as the person who did the color on the movie.
Speaker 5:  Got it. Right. Okay. Or, and it feel like sometimes
Speaker 3:  That's same or a display that performs identically to that display, but it's
Speaker 4:  Also like, it does stuff that an OLA just can't do. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like, like a reference display is gonna do a much smoother
Speaker 4:  gradient of color than, than an ED'S capable of. You're gonna see those weird
Speaker 4:  stepping, that stepping issue in an OLED and
Speaker 3:  It, right. So these, these Sony BVMs were a dual layer LCD. So they, they
Speaker 3:  were able to do it right. They had some capabilities, EDS didn't,
Speaker 3:  sorry, they also have giant ass fans in them. So they could
Speaker 3:  run really bright for a very long time. All the OLEDs were dimming
Speaker 3:  you could see.
Speaker 5:  And you said they're what, like $40,000?
Speaker 3:  $40,000? Yeah. Cool. Okay. Interestingly,
Speaker 4:  And they're also small
Speaker 3:  And they're, they're smaller. But interestingly to your point, Alex, the
Speaker 3:  cutie OLEDs have the capability of displaying more
Speaker 3:  colors than these reference displays. So there's places where they
Speaker 3:  actually aren't as capable as the televisions. Right. 'cause and so
Speaker 3:  there were, there were scenes, I forget which movie it specifically was,
Speaker 3:  where we were, it was, I think it was like the, the Saber fight in Rogue
Speaker 3:  One or Darth Vader. Just like lightened people up. Yeah. Spoiler.
Speaker 3:  I mean, rogue One is itself a spoiler. Oh, that's
Speaker 4:  Actually a really good one for that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's great. Spoiler. Darth Vader kills people in a Star Wars movie.
Speaker 3:  What? Oh no. But one of the questions there was like,
Speaker 3:  is this accurate? Because the people who made the movie were just sort of
Speaker 3:  mastering to whatever set of colors, but they couldn't see them.
Speaker 3:  So then it's like, is it different? Is it bad? It was kind of, that was pretty
Speaker 3:  interesting. Right? Yeah. And so the, the reason that the first day was objective,
Speaker 3:  but the goal was one outta five. How much is this the same as the reference
Speaker 3:  display? Which is a really interesting way of thinking about it, a picture.
Speaker 3:  'cause sometimes you're like, this is better. I think this is better than
Speaker 3:  the reference display, but it was different. So you knocked it down and that
Speaker 3:  took a, a while to get your, your head around basically. This
Speaker 4:  Is where like I just, accuracy is king for me in TVs. Yeah. Because I,
Speaker 4:  I've done the calibration. Like I've, I went to to, to
Speaker 4:  ISF and did like the week long course with them and everything. So I, I love
Speaker 4:  the accuracy and so when I hear like, oh, the Samsung is probably doing more,
Speaker 4:  displaying more reds, well those reds were never intended to be
Speaker 4:  displayed according to the reference monitor. So is that actually better?
Speaker 4:  No, because that's
Speaker 3:  Yep.
Speaker 4:  The, like the, the director could never have decided that, so therefore it's
Speaker 4:  not better. Yeah. And we see that a lot with like classic film too. Like
Speaker 4:  all of the, all the stuff they captured on Technicolor is so much more vibrant.
Speaker 4:  And that was before we even had color spaces is like a concept.
Speaker 4:  And, and, and so it's just totally different. and it,
Speaker 4:  it's weird. It's just weird.
Speaker 5:  So you're a real, like what did the, what did the founding fathers intend
Speaker 5:  kind of
Speaker 4:  Person? Yeah. I, I'm, I'm a founder's intent. I'm, me and Scalia are, are
Speaker 4:  just over there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You are truly the An and Scalia of TV calibrations. Whereas NE
Speaker 5:  Is just like, what looks sick now? Like it's 2024 baby giving them reds
Speaker 3:  Lo and I famously love a Samsung display.
Speaker 5:  How many frame TVs do you own?
Speaker 3:  Not even in the mix. I'm just put, I was just putting it out there. I'm sitting
Speaker 3:  next to like a hundred inch frame tv and it's like the T TV
Speaker 3:  quality of frame compared to all of these is like, nah.
Speaker 4:  That's why your, your backs
Speaker 3:  To it present. Can you describe a, a picture quality as present, because
Speaker 3:  that is a Samsung frame TV appears, that's what a Samsung frame
Speaker 3:  TV looks like. Well, fascinating. On the mini, oh, it's all really close.
Speaker 3:  Alex, like
Speaker 3:  some color stuff aside in this, like, you know, the fact that the cutie oles
Speaker 3:  have a wider color gamut is like kind of interesting, but like
Speaker 3:  outside of that context, it would be almost impossible to tell 'em apart.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And, and that, and honestly it was like, the way you could tell was
Speaker 3:  it was taking so long for people to score them because
Speaker 3:  the difference between a four and a five, it was like, am I seeing any, it
Speaker 3:  was like, what is it? It was only the LG that was like, it just was really
Speaker 3:  muddy in dark scenes. It just like didn't have the detail in dark scenes
Speaker 3:  that the other one said weird on the mini LED side, everyone was like, all
Speaker 3:  right, that one's bad. This one's good except for the Sony, because Sony
Speaker 3:  is putting so much emphasis on mini LED this year.
Speaker 3:  Like they're the Bravia nine, which apart from the 8, 9 5 is like the flagship.
Speaker 3:  It's the one they're pushing all mini LEDs. They get hella bright
Speaker 3:  because they're just LCD TVs with an LED backlight.
Speaker 3:  And you're like, oh, this tech has a long way to go. and it could get there,
Speaker 3:  but it's nowhere close. Yeah. Like they look kind of washed out. The colors
Speaker 3:  are a little shifted. The detail isn't quite there. They're still a little
Speaker 3:  blooming. So if you think about how a mini LED backlight works,
Speaker 3:  it's just another screen of
Speaker 3:  pixels behind the screen that light up. Like it's a lower
Speaker 3:  res screen behind the screen that lights up to produce light and it has to
Speaker 3:  match what's on the screen in real time so that you get true. So they're
Speaker 3:  off when there's something black and they're lit when there's something on
Speaker 3:  the screen. So if there's any latency you see blooming
Speaker 3:  right, or if the zone is too big, because it's not one-to-one you see
Speaker 3:  blooming. And so You can see, and the algorithms are like trying to manage
Speaker 3:  all of this as fast as they can with as little latency as possible. The Samsung
Speaker 3:  was like all over the place. Like sometimes like this just looks like a regular,
Speaker 3:  like local dimming tv. The Sony was much better but still had the problems.
Speaker 3:  And then all of 'em, because they're LCDs, their viewing angles aren't as
Speaker 3:  good as the OLEDs and they're huge. Right? These 65
Speaker 3:  inch, 83 inch TVs we're looking at. So if you were too close to them,
Speaker 3:  even just moving an inch or two to the left or right, shifted all the color
Speaker 3:  and brightness and you're like, oh, we're just not close. Like
Speaker 3:  Sony's trying the hardest here, but we're not close. I,
Speaker 4:  I just, I don't understand why we would go backwards on viewing angle
Speaker 3:  Because they're cheaper. 'cause You can get 83 inch TV for much cheaper and
Speaker 3:  it's very bright and it's very impressive. And outside of that room full
Speaker 3:  of the most incredible display nerds I've ever met in my entire life, and
Speaker 3:  I want all of them to come home with me tomorrow outside of that room, I
Speaker 3:  think it would be very hard to tell these TVs apart. But it was like
Speaker 3:  just that experience of paying such close attention
Speaker 3:  to one quality of these products with other people
Speaker 3:  who were doing that same task. It was like very refreshing to me.
Speaker 3:  We weren't judging whether or not Tizen is any good compared to Web Os. We
Speaker 3:  weren't judging how many HDMI 2.1 ports, the Sony TV has not enough,
Speaker 3:  right? Like none of that stuff, game mode, all that. We were like, can this
Speaker 3:  picture be calibrated to match a reference monitor and which one comes
Speaker 3:  closer? And that I I I, there's just a part of that having reviewed
Speaker 3:  so many products over the years and had to think about so many things, it's
Speaker 3:  like, oh, this is actually a really interesting way of thinking about these
Speaker 3:  products specifically.
Speaker 5:  Was there a consistent agreement among the, what was it, eight panelists?
Speaker 5:  That's a lot of people to all point at this same, like, it's both
Speaker 5:  objective and subjective in a certain way. Like, did everybody tend to agree
Speaker 5:  on everything?
Speaker 3:  We weren't, we were also excited to be there when we started judging,
Speaker 3:  we were all chattering and then we were like told to stop. Okay.
Speaker 3:  So our score, I don't know what everybody else scored. You know, like a worry
Speaker 3:  for me is like the consumer reviewer in the group was
Speaker 3:  that I had no idea what I was talking about. I was like, man, I hope my scores
Speaker 3:  are close. And they were in the end, you know, the the
Speaker 3:  average, the, the averages that were released and the rankings that were
Speaker 3:  released were exactly as I had thought them. Okay. So didn't see somebody
Speaker 3:  like the mainstream. You know, I think most people's, the one
Speaker 3:  LG stand in the room who's like, I love blooming
Speaker 3:  that LG mini E is not good. Like, oh, it's like a half-hearted. And to
Speaker 3:  be fair, it was the cheapest TV on display. Yeah. Thousands
Speaker 3:  of dollars. So
Speaker 4:  They put all their efforts into OLEDs anyway. Like Yeah. They just farted
Speaker 4:  that out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. To have it, it is like, let's hedge our bet a little bit. Like maybe
Speaker 3:  this is the thing. But yeah, they have the micro lens array, which
Speaker 3:  increases the brightness on their OLEDs. Like I said, the, the three OLEDs
Speaker 3:  were so close to each other. You can tell that it's a mature
Speaker 3:  technology, right? It's, it's just hit a point of refinement
Speaker 3:  where you have to care a lot about extremely
Speaker 3:  like arcane picture details. And Alex, I think you, and you and I
Speaker 3:  vibe on this, like yeah, I care a lot about arcane picture details. The many
Speaker 3:  LEDs is like all over my, my notes on the color for the Sony Bravia nine
Speaker 3:  were was just the single sentence colors all over the map.
Speaker 3:  Like just all over the place. Like who knows what's going on here. So that
Speaker 3:  was like the first day. The second day was much more subjective.
Speaker 3:  They took down the 60 fives, they put up the biggest available
Speaker 3:  sizes for all the TVs. So that was 77 for the
Speaker 3:  Sony 83 for the LG 85 for the mini LEDs
Speaker 3:  and the Robertson, the owner was like, I've never had more people ask
Speaker 3:  for a head-to-head comparison of two TVs than people ask for the LG G
Speaker 3:  4 83 versus the Sony Mini L led 85. Hmm. Because they're very, they're
Speaker 3:  very price competitive. And one is obviously bigger, right? It's tds
Speaker 3:  people love big, cheap screens. So he is like, this is what everyone wants
Speaker 3:  to see. So those two are right next to each other and the LG just wiped the
Speaker 3:  floor. Wow. Like so much better. Just incredibly better. And
Speaker 3:  the fact that the LG 83 was so much better than 65, that's what everyone
Speaker 3:  talked about. But we weren't doing the intense reference
Speaker 3:  comparison. They took him, they, they set 'em up outta the box, they turned
Speaker 3:  on filmmaker mode to turn off all the bullshit and they turn
Speaker 3:  off energy saver because Energy Saver brings the brightness down.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. E Energy Saver is the number one thing you should turn off on your
Speaker 4:  display. I mean, destroy, destroy the environment. But
Speaker 4:  just go turn. If you have it on right now, go turn it off. Right. We'll
Speaker 3:  Wait. It just significantly reduces the brightest of your panel. So they
Speaker 3:  turn off energy saver and they put 'em in filmmaker mode, or I think Sony
Speaker 3:  calls it professional mode, just turns off all the stuff and they let 'em
Speaker 3:  run outta the box. And that's where like Samsung was the most Samsung. Like
Speaker 3:  your colors, do you like 'em?
Speaker 3:  And I, you know, the, the lg the 83 inch LG just,
Speaker 3:  it was just a great picture, right? Like it, it was right behind the Sony
Speaker 3:  in that evaluation. But we weren't doing numbers. Yeah. We were just sort
Speaker 3:  of ranking 1, 2, 3 for all the clips that we saw. And I, at the end,
Speaker 3:  and we can just wrap it up here at the end, I was basically put the Samsung
Speaker 3:  cutie ole, the S 95 D and the Sony
Speaker 3:  LED were in a tie. For me it was hard, it was hard for me to decide 'cause
Speaker 3:  the Samsung colors were so all over the place and the Sony's backlight was
Speaker 3:  so all over the place and the view angles were weird and I couldn't decide.
Speaker 3:  And in the end I was like, it's an OLED because I know the Samsung can be
Speaker 3:  calibrated and I know the Sony can't. So that's how I picked again,
Speaker 3:  like my takeaway from this was one, I should spend more time in rooms with
Speaker 3:  huge nerds. Yes. 'cause those are my people. That's, and
Speaker 5:  I would say what a hundred thousand dollars worth of TVs on
Speaker 3:  A wall in front. More than that. I mean like, this store is out of control.
Speaker 3:  Like that's just the TVs. We didn't even talk about the audio side of the
Speaker 3:  store. Scarsdale is a wealthy town, this man,
Speaker 3:  like we're moving product and it was great. And he sells, you know,
Speaker 3:  over the country and they've been doing it for a long time. The room was
Speaker 3:  full of Sony's actual mark, like product people, not just
Speaker 5:  Ing people. But, so this like matters. This is not just like a small town
Speaker 5:  bunch of nerds. This is like a big people
Speaker 3:  TV shootout is a thing. There's a press release and like a whole thing. Oh
Speaker 3:  wow. Like there are YouTubers there making YouTube videos. There are YouTubers
Speaker 3:  live streaming with the calibrators. Just talking
Speaker 3:  TVs in the back room. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Big deal. I already assigned me deal, like 10,000 words on the calibrators.
Speaker 5:  So that's coming.
Speaker 3:  That's actually a great name for a show. The calibrators.
Speaker 5:  It is pretty good. I
Speaker 4:  Would, I would watch her listen.
Speaker 5:  And the picture over the course of every episode, the picture just gets slightly
Speaker 5:  better. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, that's my TV story. I finally got to talk about it. It's on the site
Speaker 3:  now. You should go read it. I'm sorry. If you have an LG G four and
Speaker 3:  you, you, it's a great tv. You're fine. Don't listen to me. Just give it
Speaker 3:  a 10. Just say you got it.
Speaker 5:  Alex is so disappointed.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm okay. I'm okay. I'm working through it. I'll be fine.
Speaker 5:  Alex, if you want I'll take your crappy tv. Okay. Anyone who would like to
Speaker 5:  give me their very good TVs, I will happily take them with no complaints
Speaker 5:  whatsoever. You
Speaker 4:  Just be like, oh, it's so crappy. Oh, it's terrible. No.
Speaker 3:  Wait, can I say, can I say one more thing at the, oh, at the opening Soul
Speaker 3:  event, they're talking about the TVs and like what they are and all this
Speaker 3:  stuff. And they said two things. One,
Speaker 3:  they were like TC and high sense aren't here. They asked not to be included
Speaker 3:  in a competition
Speaker 4:  Because they were gonna lose
Speaker 3:  You can just, You can just read into that. And then later Robert was like,
Speaker 3:  one year Vizio was here and it was embarrassing for them.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy.
Speaker 3:  So that's, did you read into that? Whatever you want Physio rough.
Speaker 5:  It's a real like, I will not be running for president in 20, 24 kinds of
Speaker 5:  vibes. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Okay. That was it. That was my TV adventure. Thank you for joining me on
Speaker 3:  this journey. This is why I started The Verge so I could sit in a room full
Speaker 3:  of
Speaker 5:  TVs. Do you think they'll invite you back next year? Did you do a good enough
Speaker 5:  job? I hope
Speaker 3:  So.
Speaker 4:  I hope can can can we come with you? Just, we'll, we'll be quiet. We'll just
Speaker 4:  stand there
Speaker 5:  Alex and I'll live stream it next year.
Speaker 3:  I asked Chris Welch if he wanted to come with me next year and he goes, I
Speaker 3:  don't want to get into that level of smoke.
Speaker 5:  I respect that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it was great. All right. We should talk about just a handful
Speaker 3:  of, I don't know, regulatory things. What do you wanna call them? But
Speaker 3:  the main one that I really want spend just a minute on
Speaker 3:  is Apple. and it, it just can't give itself a
Speaker 3:  break when it comes to the app store and fees. We gets trouble's, unfor error
Speaker 3:  all over the world, right? It has an antitrust lawsuit in this country, in
Speaker 3:  the eu, various charming European bureaucrats
Speaker 3:  wake up every morning thinking about ways to troll, troll Tim Cook on Twitter.
Speaker 3:  Like this company's under a lot of pressure. And then it won't
Speaker 3:  just do things that make its life easier. I dunno how to describe this, but
Speaker 3:  this is, I'm just, I'm gonna tell you this story and you,
Speaker 3:  you, if people out there can figure out why Apple did this, let
Speaker 3:  us know. So Patreon exists, right? You can,
Speaker 3:  You can be a fan of someone. You can pay them some money to do whatever.
Speaker 3:  People on Patreon do knit clothes, make video games, whatever. It's
Speaker 3:  Patreon. They've been in a gray zone
Speaker 3:  with the app store for years because You can
Speaker 3:  pay people money in Patreon and they haven't been charging the fee,
Speaker 3:  right? They haven't been giving Apple the 30%. And I actually had
Speaker 3:  Patreon co Jack Conte on decoder a while ago and I said,
Speaker 3:  have you ever talked to Apple about this? Like, are you an exception? And
Speaker 3:  he was like, no, please stop talking about it. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 3:  Like they know they're in this gray area, okay. And
Speaker 3:  there, there have been other companies that wanna do Patreon, like things
Speaker 3:  like this little company fan house, right? And they did a whole pressure
Speaker 3:  campaign to say, why are you charging our creators 30%? Like
Speaker 3:  this is unfair. You're providing no value to them. Right?
Speaker 5:  And the 'cause the idea is if you sign up for a creator
Speaker 5:  subscription inside of the app, apple will treat that as an in-app purchase
Speaker 5:  and take its 30%, right? Yeah. Okay. So they, they see
Speaker 5:  signing up for whatever my favorite podcast on Patreon
Speaker 5:  at the same as signing up for Spotify through the app.
Speaker 3:  Sure. And, if you wanna be a very pedantic, that is probably
Speaker 3:  the correct interpretation,
Speaker 5:  Except that for years it wasn't like, right. That feels important to keep
Speaker 5:  saying
Speaker 3:  Ex, particularly for Patreon, they have been in this gray area for
Speaker 3:  years. You, you are a Patreon creator, you sign up
Speaker 3:  for Patreon, you agree your Patreon is gonna take 8% and you're
Speaker 3:  gonna take the rest of the money. That's, it's fine. That's a fine deal.
Speaker 3:  Apple's like, we want 30% before Patreon takes 8%.
Speaker 3:  So now it, someone did the math. Instead of needing a thousand true fans,
Speaker 3:  which is the number everybody always says you need 1,554 fans
Speaker 3:  like to make the same money that you were doing before. That's weird.
Speaker 3:  and it is weird because Apple doesn't need this fight right now
Speaker 3:  because it's under all of this pressure for whether or not these fees are
Speaker 3:  fair. Whether the app store is fair, whether Apple has too much power in
Speaker 3:  the market overall antitrust lawsuit in this country. We,
Speaker 4:  I figured out why they did it. Yeah. So whoever sent the email and was
Speaker 4:  like, okay, we're gonna, we're gonna increase, we're gonna start charging
Speaker 4:  the 30% of Patreon is actually like,
Speaker 4:  was placed there by someone else to just make Apple give up
Speaker 4:  s like you
Speaker 3:  Department of Justice sleep agent.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Somebody like, like, like they're, they're just a spy or something.
Speaker 4:  And they were sitting because it just, it doesn't, why would you do that?
Speaker 4:  Why would you
Speaker 3:  Just tonight on the calibrators.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The calibrators went in. They like, they, they like, they, they
Speaker 4:  parachute it in and they were like, okay, we're gonna do this. So that we
Speaker 4:  give even more ammunition for when we go after Apple for
Speaker 4:  all the things we're going after Apple for around the 30%.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Maybe. It just seems like there are ways to make your life
Speaker 3:  easier and there are ways to make your life harder pissing off a bunch of
Speaker 3:  independent creators to whom you are providing no value.
Speaker 3:  Right. You can make the argument that Apple provides a lot of value to its
Speaker 3:  developers, right. They make the APIs, they ship the
Speaker 3:  platform, they run some of the services, they make X code.
Speaker 3:  Sure. It's very debatable. Like truly debatable. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But You can make the argument and a lot of people have, if you are a Patreon
Speaker 3:  creator, no value is coming your way from Apple.
Speaker 3:  He probably actually comes from Patreon and you're already paying him money.
Speaker 3:  Right. So like why Apple's showing up and be like, we want 30%
Speaker 3:  that it's just like too much. Yeah. And I suspect a lot of these Patreon
Speaker 3:  creators are going to tell their audiences about it. And now Apple is right.
Speaker 3:  In a fight with creatives, did they sort of
Speaker 3:  keep walking into like there a crush ad that they had to apologize for? Yep.
Speaker 3:  Like why they just keep making their life harder with these creatives.
Speaker 3:  And I I just don't know for what money, like how like if you took 30%
Speaker 3:  of all of Patreon's revenue and you gave it to Tim Cook, he'd be like, get
Speaker 3:  outta my face. Yeah. Like this is nothing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like this isn't even gas for the jet.
Speaker 5:  It probably isn't. The only thing I can think is that
Speaker 5:  Apple is desperately trying to get to
Speaker 5:  a place where it can say with a straight face that it enforces all of its
Speaker 5:  rules equally. Because one of the things that has happened to
Speaker 5:  Apple over and over is that it keeps saying
Speaker 5:  these are the rules and we we're very clear about them and we apply them
Speaker 5:  to everybody and then every 15 minutes we hear about a
Speaker 5:  sweetheart deal that somebody has from Apple. Right.
Speaker 5:  And there, there are, the rules exist except for all of the exceptions to
Speaker 5:  the rules. And I think if, if you're Apple, one thing to do would
Speaker 5:  be to say, okay, we're gonna need to be able to stand up to regulators and
Speaker 5:  say, look, these are the rules. They exist for everybody. Everybody follows
Speaker 5:  them equally. I don't think that's a good strategy. I don't think it's gonna
Speaker 5:  work, but I think if you're Apple, it is at least one way to be able to say
Speaker 5:  with a straight face, look, these are the rules, we're clear about them.
Speaker 5:  You, you, you don't have to play by them anymore because You can go to alt
Speaker 5:  store or whatever. But these are the rules. I think
Speaker 5:  doing this, this way, and particularly in these very like
Speaker 5:  haphazard ways that Apple seems to be doing this is deeply
Speaker 5:  bizarre. Yes. But I think if, if you're Apple, I cannot think of
Speaker 5:  another reason to pick this particular fight with Patreon right now.
Speaker 5:  Other than that.
Speaker 3:  Well, so just to be clear on some of the timing they told Patreon this was
Speaker 3:  gonna happen a while ago. Yeah. And now it's just happening, but there's
Speaker 3:  no reason that it should be happening. So that's like, it's not that they
Speaker 3:  woke up yesterday and were like, Patreon's gonna pay us. They said, here's
Speaker 3:  a big notice period and now it's happening. And now Patreon is communicating
Speaker 3:  about it. Right. So a more delayed timeline, but still,
Speaker 3:  even if you wanna make the argument, we have perfect enforcement of these
Speaker 3:  rules and there are no exceptions. You're still walking into, and we've pissed
Speaker 3:  everyone off along the way. I'll give you another example. Apple is going
Speaker 3:  to allow Spotify to show pricing in its app in the eu.
Speaker 3:  Just the, the thing that is happening is that
Speaker 3:  Spotify is gonna put numbers in its app. You still can't buy Spotify
Speaker 3:  in the app
Speaker 5:  There. There's a, there's, I I really encourage everyone, if you're not driving
Speaker 5:  to, we'll put this link in the show notes, but open it up and look
Speaker 5:  at the side-by-side screenshots because it is this like big dramatic regulatory
Speaker 5:  moment in this long-term fight between Apple and
Speaker 5:  Spotify. It's a big deal. And then you look at the side by side screenshots.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they are identical except that one of them says 1799 per month,
Speaker 5:  1499 per month and the other doesn't. That's it.
Speaker 3:  And this took like, you know, one of the more powerful government entities
Speaker 3:  in world history to like force the one of the richest companies in world
Speaker 3:  history to let another company show numbers. And you're like,
Speaker 3:  what is the point of this fight? Who gives one
Speaker 3:  solitary shit about this? Like, you can't possibly care
Speaker 3:  it, this cannot matter to your bottom line so much. Or,
Speaker 3:  and it can't be such a good argument that your rules are so evenly enforced
Speaker 3:  that you're willing to die in this hill over displaying literally
Speaker 3:  1799 in the Spotify app. But the, not even letting people buy stuff,
Speaker 3:  just showing the price that You can get on the web versus in the app.
Speaker 5:  The only part of that I would take issue with is the It do, it can't possibly
Speaker 5:  matter so much to your bottom line. I mean, like Apple just reported earnings.
Speaker 5:  It's super, super does matter to Apple's bottom line. And especially if you're
Speaker 5:  Apple looking at a world in which Google is no longer legally allowed to
Speaker 5:  give you $20 billion every year. Like this stuff matters an awful lot
Speaker 5:  to Apple. And, and suddenly the, the, the rent that you get to
Speaker 5:  extract from everyone in the app store goes from a
Speaker 5:  like small but meaningful part of your business to like a giant
Speaker 5:  and meaningful part of your business. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that's part of it too is just they, their, their
Speaker 4:  services, they, because they've been bundling that 20 billion into the services
Speaker 4:  reporting, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's the lion's share of both the services revenue and Apple's profits
Speaker 4:  In a very real way. And, and they've been really big on Yeah, this is, this
Speaker 4:  is our services is doing great and now it's gonna be like, no, it actually,
Speaker 4:  it doesn't. Well
Speaker 3:  The Google remedy is years away. Okay. So I reacting
Speaker 3:  to the Google case, like clamping down on Patreon.
Speaker 4:  That would be
Speaker 3:  Hysterical. A little shortsighted. Yes. Again, I, I think, I don't think
Speaker 3:  it's gas for the jet, like, it, it is not a huge amount of money, but I
Speaker 3:  think their general attitude towards all of these regulators and all these
Speaker 3:  courts saying, yep, these platforms need to open up, has
Speaker 3:  basically been to put a middle finger in the air instead of figuring
Speaker 3:  out how to innovate. Right. And like icky, I
Speaker 3:  like, I just, I'm just saying they could make their lives easier, not harder.
Speaker 3:  And they are consistently choosing harder. Yes. and it, it is
Speaker 3:  bizarre to me. There's a little more regulatory stuff to talk about. 'cause
Speaker 3:  this comes right next to the judge in the
Speaker 3:  epic Google antitrust case saying he will tear the
Speaker 3:  barriers down on the play tour because he ruled that
Speaker 3:  the Play store was a monopoly. And he is like, we're opening up the play
Speaker 3:  to the United States. The, obviously the court in
Speaker 3:  the Google search case found that there was a monopoly and then
Speaker 3:  Google's ad tech case kicks off in early September
Speaker 3:  and that probably is not gonna go poor. Like of all of the cases where we're
Speaker 3:  gonna see a bunch of emails of Google executives saying shady things about
Speaker 3:  money, the ad tech case is the one. Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. It's gonna be great. That's the one. Its so boring and so
Speaker 3:  consequential. Right? So you just see like Google is under all of this pressure
Speaker 3:  and the, the judges in these cases and the regulators in the ER are like,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna tear this company apart. And Apple's sitting there with the big
Speaker 3:  open antitrust case to come
Speaker 3:  and obviously empower Justice Department because they just won their big
Speaker 3:  Google trial and they got the next one coming and then a bunch of e regulators
Speaker 3:  started doing. And it's like, why are you signaling to all of these people
Speaker 3:  that your response to this putting your finger in the air, like it's not
Speaker 3:  gonna work. 'cause they're winning right now against Google in a real way.
Speaker 3:  And maybe Google is more cuddly than Apple. Maybe people like Apple better
Speaker 3:  than Google. However, those optics feel they're
Speaker 3:  on the hunt and they're winning. And so like if you,
Speaker 3:  I don't know, there's just something weird about this. I was like,
Speaker 4:  It's bad optics to go take a cut of 30% from a whole bunch
Speaker 4:  of creators who don't make a lot of, most of them aren't making a ton of
Speaker 4:  money. Right? Like that's bad optics. That's just such an
Speaker 4:  unforced error. It feels like them just stepping in rakes constantly.
Speaker 4:  They're just sideshow Bob. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  If you know what the strategy here is, please let us know. 'cause I'm dying
Speaker 3:  to know, or if you even wanna concoct a strategy, we are not being successful
Speaker 3:  at it. But there's a thing happening like broadly in in the world of tech
Speaker 3:  right now where the regulators are winning. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And the platforms are being pri open and distribution is getting a little
Speaker 3:  crazier and it's like kind of interesting for us, right? Like it means more
Speaker 3:  for interesting things are happening. Like alt store is just a
Speaker 3:  thing that's happening in eu. Emulators are happening all over the iPhone
Speaker 3:  right now because of EU regulation.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. I'm in what I think of as the homeboy chairs.
Speaker 3:  It's beautiful. Look, when you got the NBA players in here doing the podcast,
Speaker 3:  this is where the homeboys sit. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You look like you should be like, you
Speaker 3:  look like a, a professor during the pandemic who like went a little hard
Speaker 3:  on redecorating the home office.
Speaker 3:  That's right. That's also this look, you know, sidekick
Speaker 3:  homeboy's professor with an ax to grind the,
Speaker 4:  The slats are like, it's very trippy. It's a good,
Speaker 3:  It's a good look. So we, we bought very similar slats for the studio at my
Speaker 3:  house. And
Speaker 3:  you know, I dunno whose fault this is or if this is racist, but we forgot
Speaker 3:  to consider that this, they're the same color as me. So
Speaker 3:  we had to stain in the slots.
Speaker 4:  Just turn to the side and you'll disappear in the frame.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. Anyway, this is, well I'm, I'm in a loose hangout.
Speaker 3:  You might call this the hype desk. It's a
Speaker 5:  One one could yeah, one could call it
Speaker 3:  That one, one could say we are now in the market for someone to sit in the
Speaker 3:  hype hype desk doing The Verge chest once again. 'cause we have a hype zone
Speaker 3:  over here in the studio.
Speaker 5:  The, the as yet unsponsored unlaunched hype desk
Speaker 3:  Look saying once we get this lightning round sponsored, we're moving on.
Speaker 3:  But now that I'm in the hype desk, I think David, that makes you, you gotta
Speaker 3:  run the lightning round. And I'm just going to say whether or not things
Speaker 3:  are hype.
Speaker 5:  Okay, good. Well now that, now that I'm in charge, I've picked six things
Speaker 5:  for the lightning round.
Speaker 3:  Classic. Classic Lightning round.
Speaker 5:  No, at Kranz. Let's, let's, let's start with you. You have a fun gadgety
Speaker 5:  one. So you go first. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I got a fun gadgety one. So, so Realme is a, a Chinese
Speaker 4:  phone maker and they make phones. I, I don't wanna, I don't wanna
Speaker 4:  make a big assessment on the quality of those phones. They, they make
Speaker 5:  Phones. We can say that they
Speaker 4:  Are phones and they're really into like making the charging better and faster.
Speaker 4:  And they introduced 320 watt
Speaker 4:  fast charging.
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 3:  That's great.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, they're doing, they said they could do a battery in four minutes
Speaker 4:  and 30 seconds, like a Pixel nine battery.
Speaker 5:  Wait, isn't the plug I have in the wall like seven and a half watts
Speaker 5:  and I'm pretty sure like 30 is like very fast.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So this is, this is insane. Unclear if it will burst into flames
Speaker 4:  as soon as you plug it in. Unclear if it'll set your phone on flame. Do
Speaker 3:  You need like a, like a Thunderbolt four style cable? Like a big thick
Speaker 3:  braided?
Speaker 4:  I wouldn't feel comfortable using Oh,
Speaker 3:  You're not sending this through like a, like a flimsy like lightning cable.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. This is not what you wanna use. Like that random cable you found
Speaker 4:  at the bottom of your desk. Don't, don't use that for
Speaker 3:  This. You're plug like a CCS charger into your phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. So it's USBC right now.
Speaker 4:  Course What
Speaker 3:  Can't USBC do except tell you what it's doing,
Speaker 4:  But they, they haven't really, like, there's no phones that's really
Speaker 4:  fully supported out in the wild. It's just technology.
Speaker 4:  They just said we did it. This was kind of their, they were doing their road
Speaker 4:  show and showing off their, their new technology and it was like, yeah, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna do this soon. So at some point we're gonna have
Speaker 4:  phones charging in four minutes and that'll rule unless they
Speaker 4:  catch on fire.
Speaker 3:  Can I just say my, we'll have to find out. My favorite part of the story
Speaker 3:  is, I mean the story is great. We should try our funds faster. The press
Speaker 3:  image they supplied is incredible. It's just like a happy guy
Speaker 3:  happy in front of a screen that says 321 supersonic charge and he just
Speaker 3:  please this punch.
Speaker 4:  Like, what, what else do you need? That's all you need. Like, that's
Speaker 4:  how I feel when I read 320 watts. Yeah. I'm like, okay. Yeah. Same feeling
Speaker 3:  Like I wish I was giving this presentation right now. Like I, I truly w
Speaker 3:  can we get the words 320 watt supersonic charge on this tv, please.
Speaker 5:  They gimme
Speaker 3:  Smile
Speaker 5:  At it. They call the charger the pocket cannon. Yeah. Which is unbelievable.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Just that's great.
Speaker 5:  That's great.
Speaker 3:  Tremendous
Speaker 4:  And everything about it's wonderful and, but we'll have to see if it
Speaker 4:  actually does it not just in a demo on
Speaker 4:  that they're showing up the tech. I
Speaker 5:  Say I, I have for years thought that the thing that all
Speaker 5:  these companies say that it's like, you know, the battery is
Speaker 5:  trash but it charges pretty fast. You can get from zero to 50% in 35
Speaker 5:  minutes. I've always kind of thought that was nothing like who cares? But
Speaker 5:  the idea of fully charging my phone in four and a half minutes, it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, I can plug in my phone, I can brush my teeth and my phone is going
Speaker 5:  to be at like, 70% is awesome.
Speaker 3:  You can also heat a small village. Yeah. You can fry one egg.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be great. You, can I do like
Speaker 5:  The idea of, of both turning my oven on and charging my phone at the same
Speaker 5:  time?
Speaker 4:  No, I think you'll blow a circuit breaker if you do that.
Speaker 5:  No, it's like a, it's like a hot plate and a phone charger all in one little,
Speaker 5:  little gizmo on my table. Just
Speaker 3:  This is great. The, the street, the street lights from miles around dim when
Speaker 3:  David plugs in his phone.
Speaker 3:  I'm excited. I'm just looking at this photo, this guy smiling at the words
Speaker 3:  320 watt supersonic charge and I think more of the tech industry should be
Speaker 3:  like this. Yeah. Yeah. That's what I
Speaker 5:  Have for you. I will take a pocket Canon.
Speaker 5:  I feel like I probably, Tim and
Speaker 4:  I live just to guy
Speaker 5:  Smiling to live on a podcast, but yeah, here we are. Alright. Right. I have
Speaker 5:  two, the first one, I actually should have brought this up, up at the top
Speaker 5:  where we were talking about all the AI image processing stuff, but
Speaker 5:  Allied a very good camera app for iPhones and iPads
Speaker 5:  launched a thing this week called Process Zero that is basically just
Speaker 5:  a setting inside of their app that instead of running every photo you take
Speaker 5:  through either apple's, I think they offer Apple's standard
Speaker 5:  image processing, the pro raw processing and then a thing they call
Speaker 5:  reduced, which is just kind of a light version of Apple's processing, runs
Speaker 5:  it through no processing. So you get, you get what is supposed to be as close
Speaker 5:  to like a film camera experience as possible. You just get the light, it
Speaker 5:  collects the end. A super cool feature.
Speaker 5:  It got a lot of people very excited. This idea that like we, we can actually
Speaker 5:  choose to go another way. It's gonna make some of your photos meaningfully
Speaker 5:  worse. It's gonna change them in certain ways. But I think that idea
Speaker 5:  of like, not only do I get to pick like where I am in the photo, which is
Speaker 5:  weird, but like I have actual real control over what is
Speaker 5:  happening to my photo every time I capture it is very cool.
Speaker 5:  Also, just the idea that a camera on your
Speaker 5:  phone can have that kind of access is very
Speaker 5:  cool. And not a thing I really understood until I started writing about this
Speaker 5:  thing that like, it's, it again, it's just collecting sensor data.
Speaker 5:  And. if you give apps like allied access to that sensor data, there's all
Speaker 5:  kinds of interesting stuff they're gonna be able to do with it. And I just
Speaker 5:  think that's very cool and a sort of rich vein that at least to my
Speaker 5:  knowledge, nobody has really explored. And I think that's really cool.
Speaker 4:  If you don't know a lot about photography, don't use that feature. All your,
Speaker 4:  your photos are gonna look like trash
Speaker 3:  Disagree. I just do it. This you learn a lot about photography that
Speaker 4:  Don't use
Speaker 3:  The feature
Speaker 4:  I, I'm assuming of like the the 70-year-old who listens to The Verge
Speaker 4:  cast. and it is like, you know what, I wanna, this sounds cool. I wanna,
Speaker 4:  I wanna put this on my phone.
Speaker 3:  No, that person, what are you doing with your time? It's my mom. Get up there,
Speaker 3:  take Oh, I see. Got it. Understood.
Speaker 3:  So just Alex's mom, don't do it. Everyone else I've hung
Speaker 3:  out with your mom before Alex I'll, I'll teach her about, about, about digital
Speaker 3:  photography.
Speaker 4:  You say that now that'll be a great four hour VERGE cast
Speaker 3:  It. I think people would listen to talk about a Patreon, just me and your
Speaker 3:  mom. There you go.
Speaker 3:  But what's really interesting here is pocket point and shoot digital
Speaker 3:  cameras are making a tiny blip of a comeback. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Particularly with younger folks because they see how bad
Speaker 3:  the processing on their phones has gotten and they don't want to be always
Speaker 3:  connected. Like my nieces and nephews are all carrying around Power
Speaker 3:  shot elfs and I'm like, I made a lot of mistakes with those cameras. Don't
Speaker 3:  do what I did. But it's fasting to see that little comeback.
Speaker 3:  Is it meaningful? Is it the threat to smartphone? No, none of that.
Speaker 3:  But it is a pushback on how process the photos are getting. Right. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I think, you know, an app, putting some of those photos
Speaker 3:  into the phone might push the default cameras back
Speaker 3:  towards sanity. And I'm kind of hoping Apple takes the hint,
Speaker 3:  right? That there's, you've they've overdone it. Samsung has overdone
Speaker 3:  it for years. Google has been inching towards overdoing it. I think
Speaker 3:  it's, apple has taken kind of the most aggressive step from
Speaker 3:  I, you know, the 12 or the 13 to now where it's just like, oh, this,
Speaker 3:  these photos just look bananas. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I like the photos less on my iPhone 15 than I have
Speaker 5:  in a long time. Yeah. From the iPhone. Like they, I think in a certain way
Speaker 5:  they're like technically better photos. I I like them less.
Speaker 5:  Like my photos don't look like, I feel like they should anymore
Speaker 5:  on the, on most smartphones. But the iPhone I think held out a long time,
Speaker 5:  but that has kind of gone away. What
Speaker 4:  Is it that that, that I guess because I I maybe don't see it as much. What
Speaker 4:  is it that that, that you guys are seeing when you do that? Is it like, is
Speaker 4:  it the color, is it the, the, the dynamic range? All of it.
Speaker 3:  It's all of it. The the things for me, and I'm curious David, since you have
Speaker 3:  the same opinion, if you're seeing something different for me it's the,
Speaker 3:  the iPhone is now just completely allergic to shadows. Just takes
Speaker 3:  away, it loves the sky. Like nothing
Speaker 3:  loves the sky. Like the iPhone camera loves the sky. So just like more
Speaker 3:  sky
Speaker 5:  But not the sky as it is. Like what if the sky was the best it has ever been
Speaker 5:  in history all the time. Every time you take a photo,
Speaker 3:  Oh my god, sky. Oh, turn up that sky knob. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're like, oh no, it's gray out today. And the iPhone's like the fuck it
Speaker 5:  is, let's go.
Speaker 3:  And then those things combined, if you're outside in
Speaker 3:  a bright scene, it can actually make your photos gray. Yeah, right.
Speaker 3:  So I was thinking about dynamics like in, if you're a music
Speaker 3:  person, you know, dynamics are quite and loud. Like there's dynamics and
Speaker 3:  photographs too. And so everything is bright. The
Speaker 3:  perceived brightness of the whole image drops. Yeah. And so the iPhone, by
Speaker 3:  getting rid of shadows and pumping up the sky and then over like bringing
Speaker 3:  everything up actually makes the photo look di Yeah. And I've seen
Speaker 3:  influencers like complain about their iPhone cameras
Speaker 3:  and they're like, why is this camera so gray? Like I think Alex Earl has
Speaker 3:  made a video about why her camera appears to be gray. Right? And like that's
Speaker 3:  bad. Like you don't wanna be there right. When you are the,
Speaker 3:  the, the hardware of the entire creator economy, having the
Speaker 3:  creators being like, why is my phone gray? And it's not because they're less
Speaker 3:  bright. It's because if you destroy all the shadows and you make everything
Speaker 3:  bright, actually everything looks di and that's just kind of a weird
Speaker 3:  spot Apple has gone into. I dunno, David, is that what you're seeing too?
Speaker 3:  Or is it something else?
Speaker 5:  No, that's, that's basically right. And the, the other thing I keep noticing,
Speaker 5:  and in the the highlight story I wrote, there's a really interesting
Speaker 5:  comparison shot where what Apple does by
Speaker 5:  getting rid of shadows wherever it can and hyping up the
Speaker 5:  brightness everywhere You can is it just, it just flattens it all too. So
Speaker 5:  there's a, there's a version of the shot that is like, it's a, it's the front
Speaker 5:  of a flower shop. And so you see all this sort of, the flowers in the pots
Speaker 5:  in the front and the photo is like crisper and brighter than the one that
Speaker 5:  you got with the process. Zero thing that Haled is doing. But it's also
Speaker 5:  much less like dynamic. The photo itself, there's no,
Speaker 5:  there's no sense of sort of ups and downs. You get the sense the whole curve
Speaker 5:  is just like bright. Yeah. and it makes the whole thing look really flat.
Speaker 5:  Kinda like you're talking about Neil. and it just, it makes all the photos
Speaker 5:  less interesting in a way. Like they're brighter and cooler and less
Speaker 5:  interesting to me in, in so many ways. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And there's other stuff there's doing, there's like weird sharpening when
Speaker 3:  you get in the low light iPhones just start freaking out. Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  And like, not in a bad way. They're not like making bad, technically bad
Speaker 3:  photos. I think this is what you're getting at David. They're just trying
Speaker 3:  so hard to make a great photo that you lose the character of it. And then
Speaker 3:  there's tons and tons and tons in processing like Right.
Speaker 5:  And I think what you're seeing a lot of coming back with the, the point and
Speaker 5:  shoots and the process zero stuff. Like this whole idea is like,
Speaker 5:  I, people should be allowed to take bad photos. You know what I mean? And
Speaker 5:  it's like there's something too, if I'm standing in a dark room and I take
Speaker 5:  a picture, maybe it's actually okay that the picture is dark. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 5:  maybe, maybe that's okay. And, and sometimes that's what I want. And
Speaker 5:  increasingly with these devices, you are not allowed to take a dark
Speaker 5:  photo. And I think that's just weird.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna say a sentence that a small number of people
Speaker 3:  will understand the significance of Charlie XCX
Speaker 3:  invited the Cobra Snake to her birthday party.
Speaker 3:  That that's a real thing. And, if you were in your twenties in the early
Speaker 3:  two thousands, you're like, oh, it's back. It's just fully back.
Speaker 3:  We're we're just doing it again. Whole. That whole aesthetic is back and
Speaker 3:  like we're we're just gonna do flash photos with drunk people and like let's
Speaker 3:  do it. The iPhone can't do that shit. Yeah. No one wants that.
Speaker 3:  No.
Speaker 5:  A bunch of squinting people with a flash on. That's, that's what we're looking
Speaker 5:  for. Oh,
Speaker 3:  They're not SST sing. Those eyes are dilated my friend.
Speaker 3:  Fair
Speaker 5:  Enough. Two. Alright. My other one, and then Neli, we should get to you and
Speaker 5:  then we should get out of here is Flipboard, which is, we've been
Speaker 5:  sort of chronicling flip board's, like relentless quest to figure out the
Speaker 5:  Fedi verse, which I continue to find very interesting. Turned on a thing
Speaker 5:  that I think is actually very instructive in understanding how all of this
Speaker 5:  is supposed to work, which is just that now You can follow Fedi verse accounts.
Speaker 5:  So like people from Mastodon or Pixel Fed or even on threads
Speaker 5:  from inside of Flipboard. Right. And it's like if you, if you wanna understand
Speaker 5:  the way the Fedi verse is supposed to work, it's that where you make posts
Speaker 5:  and where you read posts can be different and that anybody can decide how
Speaker 5:  those posts are supposed to look and how they're supposed to work and in
Speaker 5:  order they show up. And so, like the idea that You can do Mastodon
Speaker 5:  inside of Flipboard is both like mind bending and exactly the point.
Speaker 5:  And so if you've like, wanted to understand how the Fedi verse works, go
Speaker 5:  to Flipboard and like mess around with a bunch of Mastodon stuff. They've
Speaker 5:  put together some lists. I think one that includes you and Eli because you're
Speaker 5:  just a tremendously huge deal on the fedi verse.
Speaker 5:  But like that, I think this is the closest thing I have seen to like
Speaker 5:  telling the whole story of like, here is, here is what you get
Speaker 5:  when all you have is just this massive content that You can either build
Speaker 5:  something that adds to or build something that reads from however you want.
Speaker 5:  So I think that was very cool. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's awesome. Flipboard is way ahead of this curve, right? Yeah. They've
Speaker 3:  like re-architected their app or the way they're thinking about their app
Speaker 3:  around activity pub and these open protocols and you kind of have
Speaker 3:  it, you know, in the broadest sense, like the future of a browser.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But
Speaker 3:  It's bi-directional. Like you take content in and you get to read it and
Speaker 3:  You can like reply to it and it goes right back to the person who made it.
Speaker 3:  And it's pretty powerful. It like
Speaker 3:  nothing works with it yet, right. Like, which is a problem.
Speaker 3:  But You can just see there's like glimmers here of a new kind of web.
Speaker 3:  I am the one who keeps babbling on about how we're gonna federate our site.
Speaker 3:  You can see how our site would play with something like that.
Speaker 3:  Right. Very quickly. But then you start to build it and we're trying to build
Speaker 3:  it and it's like, oh, there's a million problems to solve here. Yeah. Like
Speaker 3:  big hairy technical problems that mo no one has ever really tried to solve
Speaker 3:  before, which is why, you know, threads is federating and they are
Speaker 3:  doing it in like drip by drip. Like they're solving one little problem at
Speaker 3:  a time. They, they let you know that someone in the fedi verse had liked
Speaker 3:  one of your posts. Right? Sure. That was just a problem to
Speaker 3:  solve. They now they now they let you see those posts, but you can't reply
Speaker 3:  to them Now they let you like those posts, but You can't reply to 'em, obviously
Speaker 3:  reply to this coming next. And all of that is just like, where does the data
Speaker 3:  go? If you want to delete something, how do you delete
Speaker 3:  it across all of these servers that have now ingested it? Maybe you
Speaker 3:  can't. Yeah. Weird. Right? If someone rep to
Speaker 3:  me on another server with another kind of moderation policy and puts something
Speaker 3:  bad in my replies on, on my site or in mass, like how
Speaker 3:  do I moderate that? Big questions like huge
Speaker 3:  earth shattering questions like that obviously have made the process slow
Speaker 3:  for everyone, but you're like, oh, these are new problems. Like, I'm in the
Speaker 3:  market for new problems. Totally. Like, we've never thought about these problems
Speaker 3:  before. Fun. Like, this is great. So I'm very excited to just like see
Speaker 3:  everyone making slow progress here. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just have a question, which is the bigger platform shift G and I live
Speaker 4:  or Flipboard,
Speaker 3:  You know, I you, you know, I believe it's the Fed verse. I I i, in my heart
Speaker 3:  of heart, I believe it's the Fed verse.
Speaker 4:  I I just really wanted to hear us all say Flipboard is the platform shift
Speaker 4:  this week. Watch.
Speaker 3:  Look, I like Flipboard. I think they do really interesting. I don't know
Speaker 3:  if Flipboard is a platform shift. I think it is part of the platform shift
Speaker 3:  about how information moves around the internet. Mm. That,
Speaker 3:  you know, if, if you are gonna break something like Google through regulatory
Speaker 3:  action or just Google killing stuff.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Go Google. End of life Google search seems
Speaker 3:  like a, a likely outcome. It's more likely than not. You know, like giving
Speaker 3:  Google's history. If all that stuff is breaking down
Speaker 3:  and all, you know, the photo based networks are flooded with synthetic images,
Speaker 3:  no one can trust you need to make something else. Yep. and it seems like
Speaker 3:  everyone has bet on open interoperable networks this time.
Speaker 3:  And I do think that is fundamentally a bigger shift that more people will
Speaker 3:  feel than Gemini. Maybe in the long term, obviously.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I will like do all the things and none of us will have to work and
Speaker 3:  the robots will just bring us pina coladas. But right now I think it's
Speaker 3:  the social web.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I agree. All right. Neela, what's yours before we get outta here?
Speaker 3:  What is mine? This is what happens when you're in a sidekick chair. You,
Speaker 3:  you're not prepared. You're just here to
Speaker 4:  Hype.
Speaker 3:  Yo. Good point.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So mine is actually related to ai. So Eric Schmidt used to be the CEO
Speaker 3:  of Google.
Speaker 3:  He gave a talk recently. He got dinged for a lot of stuff he gave in this
Speaker 3:  talk. And then he asked for the talk to be taken off of YouTube.
Speaker 3:  He not a great cycle, right? He give a talk at
Speaker 3:  Stanford, you're like, oh no, you're quoting my talk. Please remove it from
Speaker 3:  YouTube first. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wasn't a moment in it where he, he's like, this is off the record and the
Speaker 5:  person he's talking to like points at the camera.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Whatcha doing? It's a tough look. It's brutal. So the thing he got
Speaker 3:  in trouble for, he asked for the talk to be taken down was, he said Google
Speaker 3:  was behind an ai 'cause the workers prioritized working from home and
Speaker 3:  snacks as opposed to being competitive. Mm. This from the former
Speaker 3:  CEO of Google, this did not go well. Like just, what are you talking about?
Speaker 3:  It's also
Speaker 5:  Just a bad take. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's a million reasons. And I don't think it's the people who work
Speaker 3:  at Google who made the strategic errors, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But whatever. And also Google is, you know, this is coming on the heels of
Speaker 3:  like The Pixel event where Google is like doing huge
Speaker 3:  muscular AI stuff. Yeah. Whatever. So he got in trouble for that.
Speaker 3:  Alex Heath wrote a quick post about it. He was like, here's this thing that
Speaker 3:  happened. The video got taken down and then Alex got a transcript of the
Speaker 3:  thing and you actually watched part of the other video. And Schmidt said
Speaker 3:  something else that I think is very fascinating, very telling,
Speaker 3:  and I think very important to understanding not
Speaker 3:  just Silicon Valley, but Google and Google's place in the world. So he
Speaker 3:  said to this room full of like Stanford students, a lot
Speaker 3:  of, you're gonna be tech people. I hope a lot of your tech startups. What
Speaker 3:  I would do right now, if TikTok was banned, I propose each and quote, I propose
Speaker 3:  each and every one of you say to your LLM the following, make me a copy
Speaker 3:  of TikTok, steal all the users, steal all the music, put my
Speaker 3:  preferences in it, produce this program in the next 30 seconds, release it.
Speaker 3:  And in one hour, if it hasn't gone viral, do something different. Along the
Speaker 3:  same lines, what what LLMM using. So first of all,
Speaker 3:  yeah, I don't know what kind of magic lm like at best you're gonna be like,
Speaker 3:  do you wanna bang this iPad? Like that's what he, he's using the the rabbit
Speaker 3:  we all expect it to see. Yeah. Seriously. Right. So for, but I, you understand
Speaker 3:  what he's saying? He's like, if TikTok is banned, just clone it. Just take
Speaker 3:  it. Yeah. Take the music, take the users, take the content. Just make it
Speaker 3:  clone of TikTok and stand it up and people will start using it if they don't
Speaker 3:  do it again. And his point was the quote,
Speaker 3:  the example I gave of the TikTok competitor is that's what you would do if
Speaker 3:  you were a Silicon Valley entrepreneur, which hopefully all of you'll be,
Speaker 3:  if it took off, you would hire a whole bunch of lawyers to go clean up the
Speaker 3:  mess. But if nobody uses your product, it doesn't matter that you stole all
Speaker 3:  the content. Wait, wait, wait. What's, what's the next line? And do not quote
Speaker 3:  me. Yeah. Whoopsies.
Speaker 3:  Oops. So. anyway, my, my point of this is Eric Schmitt ran Google in the
Speaker 3:  early period, right? He was famously the adult they hired to run Google.
Speaker 3:  Well, I know Larry and Sergei were growing up or whatever they were doing,
Speaker 3:  finding, learning whether or not toe shoes were for them. Eric is
Speaker 3:  the adult in the room. This is what Google did.
Speaker 3:  And not in a small way, in a big open way.
Speaker 3:  They just built a company on copyright infringement they hired a bunch of
Speaker 3:  lawyers and they clean up the mess. And they were a friendly company with
Speaker 3:  two lovable goofballs as their founders. They were providing
Speaker 3:  an enormously valuable service at the time. Google search was enormously
Speaker 3:  valuable. Google Book search, copyright lawsuit, enormously valuable,
Speaker 3:  YouTube enormously valuable, built on copier infringement,
Speaker 3:  particularly against Viacom. So valuable that Viacom lost its copier
Speaker 3:  infringement case because of Viacom's own. People kept uploading the content
Speaker 3:  to YouTube
Speaker 3:  like ridiculous. But this, this is how Google worked in
Speaker 3:  the beginning. It is the attitude we're gonna make the thing, it's gonna
Speaker 3:  be so useful, people are gonna love it. And then when the copyright infringement
Speaker 3:  cases or whatever other lawsuits come, we will have enough money to pay lawyers
Speaker 3:  to make it go away. And Google did it. That actually
Speaker 3:  worked. It was a successful strategy at the time. It was successful
Speaker 3:  for other companies like Uber or whatever it is, right? We are at a point
Speaker 3:  now where the AI companies kinda wanna run the same playbook. Google wants
Speaker 3:  to run the same playbook with AI and training, and they're not
Speaker 3:  lovable goofballs anymore. Yeah. And so when Eric Schmidt is at Stanford
Speaker 3:  complaining that, you know, the kids aren't working hard enough anymore,
Speaker 3:  and then on top of it being like, just steal this stuff and figure it out
Speaker 3:  later, the attitude that he's say that the,
Speaker 3:  like, the world's attitude and response to that is nowhere near
Speaker 3:  as friendly as it was when they were building Google. And I, I think it's
Speaker 3:  actually kind of fascinating to see that shift. Like, I don't know,
Speaker 3:  like Alexis Hanian, like wrote the book that was like, ask for
Speaker 3:  permission, not forgiveness. Right? And that was like the whole
Speaker 3:  industry's attitude. And that worked. Like I,
Speaker 5:  are just like trying to make cool stuff together. Like that is not how
Speaker 5:  those people are perceived. And enough of them see themselves that way,
Speaker 5:  that that's why they're like, oh, we're, we're just the contrarians and
Speaker 5:  it's why you see this like crazy push away from woke him and all that stuff.
Speaker 5:  And like, I don't wanna get into the political side of it, but it comes from
Speaker 5:  the same impulse that it is. Like we are the renegades. And it's like, no,
Speaker 5:  you're not, dude. Like you are the most establishment of the
Speaker 5:  establishment and yeah. You, you don't get the
Speaker 5:  leeway that you once got and maybe you never should have.
Speaker 4:  The thing is also, they were never the renegades, like, like Silicon Valley
Speaker 4:  was built on like military funds and stuff. Yeah. Right. Like
Speaker 4:  they, they were never that. It was a very conscious
Speaker 4:  PR move. And they decided at some point, we are too big to need to do that
Speaker 4:  PR move. But actually you can't keep running your playbook and do that because
Speaker 4:  then you just look like a hearse or something. You just look like all of
Speaker 4:  the kind of like people who are always the villains in period films.
Speaker 4:  That's not a great look. No. And we're seeing the apple, like Apple doing
Speaker 4:  the 30% you're just seeing over and over again. It's like, no, you guys forgot,
Speaker 4:  like, you forgot the PR part of this. That, that actually is really important.
Speaker 4:  You do have to market this. You market yourselves, And. if you stop
Speaker 4:  doing that, we are gonna all eventually
Speaker 5:  alive during the whole process. And he learned a lot about kind of the history
Speaker 5:  and future of cars and everything. and it was an awesome, and he's alive.
Speaker 5:  It was an awesome story and he made it out. So it's a happy hunting.
Speaker 3:  All right, well that's coming up on Tuesday. Escape from Hydrogen Cars pretty
Speaker 3:  much today on the Calibrators. That's it. That's our chest rock and
Speaker 3:  roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.