# Transcript
ID: 23db5c07-cfb7-46a9-8cdc-1baa27455ede
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/434036981777114548/1777972915800737291/s93290-US-6292s-1727432530.mp3
Description: The Verge's Alex Heath joins Nilay, Alex, and David to talk about all the announcements coming out of Meta Connect: the impressive (and expensive) Orion glasses, the new features for the Ray-Ban Smart Glasses, and lots and lots of new AI. Then they discuss the latest executive departures at OpenAI, as the industry's foremost AI company undergoes a huge shift. In the lightning round, it's time for more AI gadgets, the PS5 Pro... and then some more AI gadgets.
Speaker 3:  of wearable stuff. I don't wanna start with a swear word, but
Speaker 3:  If. you know, there it's usually a swear word. Hi, I'm your friend. Neli.
Speaker 3:  Alex. Kran here.
Speaker 5:  I'm also wearing my augmented reality glasses right now
Speaker 3:  Because they pass light through them. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They pass light through them and everything is augmented now. I can see
Speaker 3:  It's been augmented into focus. Yeah, I got you. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hello?
Speaker 3:  And Alex Heath is here. Alex, are you actually wearing a face computer?
Speaker 7:  I am, but you'll never know.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's Big week in Tech News. Quite a lot going on. It was Meta, Connect.
Speaker 3:  Alex was there, along with Kylie Robinson and j Peters.
Speaker 3:  Alex. You wore the Orion AR glasses, the demo you interviewed Zuckerberg.
Speaker 3:  We gotta talk all about that. There's tons of other news outta Meta Connect
Speaker 3:  and then there's chaos at Open ai, which a company
Speaker 3:  for being as successful as it is remains mired in, in nothing but
Speaker 3:  pure chaos. We
Speaker 6:  Could just snip that and play it every single week on the first cast. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  just that thing you just said is like a, it's just a universally true statement
Speaker 6:  at this point.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, we, we have to talk about that. And then
Speaker 3:  we have a lightning round unsponsored
Speaker 5:  Still.
Speaker 3:  I have walked into rooms at this company. Yeah. Demanded why the lightning
Speaker 3:  round is unsponsored.
Speaker 5:  Was anybody else in the room?
Speaker 3:  No one else was in the rooms. This is the, I'm getting, I'm working
Speaker 3:  up to the, the final result. But you walk into a
Speaker 3:  room, you know where Eater is having a staff meeting demanding the lightning
Speaker 3:  round be sponsored and they're like, I don't, we're doing a roundup on cakes.
Speaker 3:  Like get outta here. I'm working on it every day. Closer
Speaker 3:  to the, the goal. Okay, let's start with Meta. Alex.
Speaker 3:  You wore the Orion. We, I think the Orion is the thing to talk about. They've
Speaker 3:  been working on this for 10 years at Reality Labs burning billions of dollars
Speaker 3:  a year. They did it. They made AR glasses, but you can't buy them and they
Speaker 3:  cost $10,000
Speaker 7:  Kind of. Yeah, you can't buy them. So they are glasses
Speaker 7:  in the sense that you could put them on and they work to a degree.
Speaker 7:  I wrote this in the story and I had a hard time writing about this because
Speaker 7:  I've been getting a lot of almost products put on my face
Speaker 7:  recently. Like just coming off of Snap.
Speaker 3:  We do have a series of photos of you that is incredible right now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I need to make like a, like a photo book to just have at
Speaker 7:  home and look at it and go like, that's a cry for help
Speaker 7:  Me wearing all these face computers.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's, it's a really impressive demo.
Speaker 7:  I think Meta is doing the demos
Speaker 7:  because it knows it's impressive, but it's not a product. So
Speaker 7:  I mean, I wrote this in the story. It's, it's not vaporware. Like it's very
Speaker 7:  real and it's not a simulation, it's not totally on
Speaker 7:  rails. I used it for probably a total of two and a half hours between
Speaker 7:  the two days we were shooting. And I had enough opportunity
Speaker 7:  to go off of the beaten path a little bit and make sure I wasn't just
Speaker 7:  getting piped in a complete simulation. And it's, it's a real
Speaker 7:  working piece of kit but it's not a product.
Speaker 7:  And that says a lot about the state of AR and these glasses.
Speaker 7:  And at the same time I finally
Speaker 7:  feel like I've been running about this for so long, banging my head against
Speaker 7:  the wall and being like, what am I doing? This is never gonna happen.
Speaker 7:  And I finally feel after this week that AR glasses
Speaker 7:  I may actually want to use are not a pipe dream.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I wanna argue with you about the definition of the word vaporware,
Speaker 3:  which is very important to me personally.
Speaker 7:  And holograms.
Speaker 3:  And holograms. So let's start, that's, and Alex and I got into a real fight
Speaker 3:  about what ho the word holograms means this week. We'll get into all this
Speaker 3:  I promise, but let's start with what it is, right? Because AR glasses
Speaker 3:  you are correct. The industry has been talking about them for a long time.
Speaker 3:  Magic Leap promised AR glasses years ago, if
Speaker 3:  you'll remember, their founder claimed that he could hack the
Speaker 3:  GPU of your brain. This is a real thing that, and that was
Speaker 3:  in reference to a display technology because this is the challenge. How do
Speaker 3:  we build a display that you can look through that can augment reality, have
Speaker 3:  the processing power to see reality and augment it, have connectivity, have
Speaker 3:  a battery that, and no one can solve these problems. Most
Speaker 3:  of all the display. Yeah. The, the thing doesn't
Speaker 3:  exist. The thing that you look through to perceive the world and then layer
Speaker 3:  information over stuff you could maybe solve battery and processing
Speaker 3:  and all this stuff in, in, you're wearing a backpack, but the actual display
Speaker 3:  technology to make it good is more or less not
Speaker 3:  existed in any realistic way. And Magic Leap had to give up on their
Speaker 3:  idea and they tried another thing. And HoloLens was another thing with a
Speaker 3:  tiny field of view. And there's a long list of things with bad fields of
Speaker 3:  view. and it seems like that's the thing Meta solved most of all
Speaker 3:  here.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. As quote that really stuck out to me from the
Speaker 7:  product lead when I was getting my demo, was that the display
Speaker 7:  was a scientific breakthrough problem they had to solve.
Speaker 7:  And now they're in the engineering problem solving phase of making these
Speaker 7:  glasses work at a price point that people can actually buy. And
Speaker 7:  that really stuck with me. I you're right that the display is the hardest
Speaker 7:  part. The distinction between ar glasses like these in the
Speaker 7:  Vision Pro or the Meta quest is that yes, you can do mixed
Speaker 7:  reality in the pro and the quest in the vision and the quest, but
Speaker 7:  what they're doing is fully enclosing your face in a computer piping
Speaker 7:  video in and mixing all that in the displays. These are literally
Speaker 7:  just these glasses. Orion are letting light in their actual glasses. And
Speaker 7:  so the, the challenge there is, is much different
Speaker 7:  and Meta has a lot of good ideas here
Speaker 7:  and they also I think realized that the
Speaker 7:  specific optical stack that they went with for Orion was just
Speaker 7:  inex like inexplicably hard to manufacture.
Speaker 7:  And it's, these lenses are made of silicon carbide,
Speaker 7:  which is also used in like space.
Speaker 7:  It's used in EVs, it's, it's used
Speaker 5:  In like Dremels. It's, it's like the, what you use for cutting tools, it's
Speaker 5:  primarily,
Speaker 7:  It's literally like a giant crystal. And so yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's also used for wedding rings sometimes. So basically it's like having
Speaker 5:  two fake diamonds on your face.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And they were talking to me about this in this like challenge of the
Speaker 7:  yields on this. It's like, yeah, you, you have to cut the crystal perfectly.
Speaker 7:  He's like, and there's not enough of it in the world. So we're, we're growing
Speaker 7:  crystals we're growing like big ass silicon carbide
Speaker 3:  Rocks. I'm sorry the, the image of Mark Zuckerberg walking into the basement
Speaker 3:  of his layer looking at his like crystal farm in a haze of like purple
Speaker 3:  smoke and being like, I will conquer the world.
Speaker 3:  Fuck. I mean like I'm go get it Mark. You know? Yeah. Like yeah.
Speaker 5:  Very distinct image.
Speaker 3:  But but you have to be that person to do this I think. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. And that's another thing of all this that we'll get into this
Speaker 7:  is like, I think this is a device that only Meta could have built in a way
Speaker 7:  that they can show to the world because for a lot of reasons
Speaker 7:  that are very,
Speaker 5:  'cause everybody else would expect it to ship.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like everybody else does hardware more often. So we'd be like, okay, but
Speaker 5:  when
Speaker 7:  I think if Meta was not a founder mode company
Speaker 7:  to the fullest extent, this thing would've been killed a long time ago.
Speaker 3:  So can I read you, I just wanna read you a quote from Ben Thompson
Speaker 3:  who writes a newsletter called Trek. He tried on Hawaiian and he just said
Speaker 3:  this thing that it just made me start laughing a
Speaker 3:  lot and I'll explain why it made me laugh so hard. Here's the quote, the
Speaker 3:  difference from the quest. And he is him talking about Orion,
Speaker 3:  the obvious limitations of display, particularly low resolution, felt immaterial.
Speaker 3:  The difference from the Quest or Vision Pro is that actually looking at reality
Speaker 3:  is so dramatically different from even best in class pass
Speaker 3:  through that holographic video quality doesn't really matter. Even the highest
Speaker 3:  quality presentation layer will pale in comparison to reality.
Speaker 3:  Hmm. Yeah dude, I mean this is very funny. He's presenting this as like a
Speaker 3:  right and it's Ben and that's how he writes and that's fun. But If, you'll
Speaker 3:  recall my review of the Vision Pro was looking at display
Speaker 3:  sucks. Like this is the end of the road for video pass through
Speaker 3:  If. you want to put a screen in front of your head in a VR headset and then
Speaker 3:  do camera based pass through. This is as good as it will ever be. and it
Speaker 3:  is nowhere near good enough. At the time. Many people
Speaker 3:  disagreed with me. I believe that I have been proven to be correct about
Speaker 3:  the value of the Vision Pro over time. Still not pleased with
Speaker 3:  myself that I gave it a seven, seven outta 10. So, so,
Speaker 3:  but like this is the thing, right? Meta built the displays that grew the
Speaker 3:  crystals. Zuckerberg is like, I'm spending the money, I can't be fired because
Speaker 3:  I own super voting shares of this company. Here's here
Speaker 3:  it's, I made the displays.
Speaker 3:  When you say it's not a product, did he make the rest of it? Like does the,
Speaker 3:  is the software good?
Speaker 7:  There is an os, right? So I. Guess I'll just quickly explain like how
Speaker 7:  we got to where we are. They started developing this about 10 years ago.
Speaker 7:  This is like Zuckerberg's big bet to maybe control the
Speaker 7:  next computing platform. If, you buy into the idea that face computers are
Speaker 7:  maybe that in 2022 it became everything
Speaker 7:  everyone remembers the year of efficiency, Meta stock was in
Speaker 7:  was not doing as well. They were cutting back budgets and they decided
Speaker 7:  looking at how expensive it was gonna be to create Orion.
Speaker 7:  I'm told that the cost to build is somewhere around $10,000 per pair.
Speaker 7:  And that the display stack, especially the lenses, the silicon carbide was
Speaker 7:  just not something that would scale. They decided to make it a
Speaker 7:  prototype internally. And then there was debate after that of, okay, do we
Speaker 7:  show it to the world at all? Is it good enough? And I mean
Speaker 7:  the thing that stuck out to me that Boz, the CTO told me was like, we just,
Speaker 7:  we just didn't think this was gonna work at all. We, when we set out to build
Speaker 7:  this, we thought maybe a 10% chance we actually get to a working device.
Speaker 7:  and it, I think he literally said, I was just like, holy shit,
Speaker 7:  it works.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I think they were amazed that it works. And so they started in
Speaker 7:  earnest on the software stack like three months ago deciding that they were
Speaker 7:  gonna show it off at Connect. So it does have an os
Speaker 7:  you know, they have pretty concrete ideas, especially on the interaction
Speaker 7:  elements of it, which we'll get into the software is is bare bones.
Speaker 7:  They've got some demo apps. They had Instagram, you and I did a call over
Speaker 7:  Messenger neli, they've got a web browser. But
Speaker 7:  these are like the early primitives of how you would bring
Speaker 7:  2D experiences into 3D space. It's like a float A, it's like Vision Pro.
Speaker 7:  It's like a floating pain. Yeah. I think the work they're doing now that
Speaker 7:  they have a working kit is in the next couple of years, how do you actually
Speaker 7:  make uniquely 3D
Speaker 7:  augmented type interfaces? Which is like, you just have to
Speaker 7:  have the thing on your face. You have to be able to use it. And for the longest
Speaker 7:  time, this hasn't been something that even resembles an actual pair of
Speaker 7:  glasses. Like the, the thing they showed me that it was even like in 2022,
Speaker 7:  it had like a backpack. I mean it was just the, the iteration they've done
Speaker 7:  even in just the last couple years is is pretty remarkable. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  yeah, I, the software had enough ideas
Speaker 7:  in it to where I went, okay, they have ideas of where this
Speaker 7:  is going. Still super rough, but like the AI
Speaker 7:  stuff especially, it's compelling the idea that what all did
Speaker 3:  You get to actually do in the headset?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We did, you know, web browsing, video calling,
Speaker 7:  basic kind of Instagram stuff, calling in a
Speaker 7:  2D HD pane, which like, NELI beamed him that way. And I could see him,
Speaker 7:  he couldn't see me. 'cause they, there's all these things in Orion that they
Speaker 7:  just turned off because they decided to not make it a product. Like there's,
Speaker 7:  they have inward facing cameras that could potentially map your face to an
Speaker 7:  avatar to show someone and they just haven't turned off. 'cause like they're
Speaker 7:  not, that's not being used for that now. Yeah. But they could
Speaker 5:  Also just look like garbage.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So we did that. Some Meta employees came in as
Speaker 7:  avatars, like floating, like think of the horizon quest avatar style. But
Speaker 3:  Like legs or no legs,
Speaker 7:  Legs, legs and like full body scale across the
Speaker 3:  World. $10,000 a leg is what I'm told. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And then we did like a code. They have their hyper realistic kind of unca,
Speaker 7:  uncanny Valley Kodak avatars, someone called in as one of those as well.
Speaker 7:  And then there were some games. And the games were actually, you know, I've
Speaker 7:  done a lot of really kind of I would say just gimmicky ar
Speaker 7:  games in my career. And the games were actually decent, like the interactions
Speaker 7:  because they've nailed a lot of the interaction elements and input
Speaker 7:  elements of the glasses. The game experience was, was
Speaker 7:  actually surprisingly good. And they have some connected ones where like
Speaker 7:  you scan a QR code, you're in this pong game immediately with someone else
Speaker 7:  wearing the glasses who just scanned it. And that's how I did it with Zuckerberg.
Speaker 7:  And the video, you can see on all of the verges channels. He,
Speaker 7:  he beat me of course in Palm,
Speaker 5:  Did they have a laser tag game? I just, that's my AR dream.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that would be cool. They had this kind of space invaders esque game
Speaker 7:  where your head was move the ship. And the band, which we'll talk about was,
Speaker 7:  was the, was the lasers for the ship.
Speaker 3:  So here's what I'm curious about the Yeah, they've built a lot of stuff
Speaker 3:  in the Quest, right? Like they've taken Android, they've built an entire
Speaker 3:  operating system, they have a store. A lot of
Speaker 3:  that is complete. And I've always assumed based on what Mark and others have
Speaker 3:  said is that they're doing all that work there in that form
Speaker 3:  factor. And that lets them build the software experiences and then
Speaker 3:  they're building the ray bands and the other form factor. And then, you
Speaker 3:  know, Orion is like the goal. Are they using
Speaker 3:  any of the stuff from the Quest? Like any of the, the user
Speaker 3:  interface gestures, any of the, is it Android? Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's, it's Android based. It's a similar kind of app launcher ui.
Speaker 7:  The thing with the app launcher though that's different is like, it's, it's
Speaker 7:  much more minimal and your finger gesture brings it up and then when, and
Speaker 7:  then takes it away just as quickly. It, they're very different
Speaker 7:  products. I mean the app, the avatar was the same as what you would see on
Speaker 7:  like a Quest game.
Speaker 3:  But I'm just getting at, you know, like Zuck has laid out the idea that like
Speaker 3:  the Meta ray bands are on one side of the spectrum
Speaker 3:  and the headset is on the other side where it, it, this is not
Speaker 3:  the right form factor, but I can do everything in it and the raybans are
Speaker 3:  the right form factor. I can't do anything in them hardly. And in the middle
Speaker 3:  are these glasses right? And they're, these products are gonna converge towards
Speaker 3:  the glasses So. I'm just, it just seems interesting to me that they haven't
Speaker 3:  used all the stuff from the Quest. 'cause that was the plan that they sort
Speaker 3:  of articulated.
Speaker 7:  Well like I said, they started doing the software for this like three months
Speaker 7:  ago. Sure. And I will say the coolest thing, David, to your earlier
Speaker 7:  question that we did was this Meta AI thing where they laid out all these
Speaker 7:  ingredients for a smoothie on a table. They gave me the prompt,
Speaker 7:  which means they tuned it a little bit. Right? But there's
Speaker 3:  Just a guy in the background being like,
Speaker 7:  No, I messed around with it to know that it was actually, it was a model
Speaker 7:  running, but
Speaker 3:  It wasn't Tom Brady being like, all right, smoothie
Speaker 7:  Go. Yeah. But it was like I asked it to make a smoothie outta the ingredients
Speaker 7:  and it popped up like a recipe pane above me with, I could like click through
Speaker 7:  the different steps.
Speaker 6:  Can I just quickly be the, the turd in the punch bowl on this particular
Speaker 6:  demo? Because I've seen a bunch of people talking about this particular demo
Speaker 6:  and I am so spectacularly unimpressed with that demo. And I, I would
Speaker 6:  like you to tell me why I'm wrong. So first of all, If, you go look at
Speaker 6:  that demo. Every single thing on that table says what it is with Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Big ass letters. That's true. And you know, it's a really, really easy thing
Speaker 6:  to do. It does. The bag of dates says dates in big ass letters and the ba
Speaker 6:  the box of matcha says matcha in big ass letters. Like those
Speaker 6:  are not hard computer problems to solve
Speaker 7:  It. Recognize that if
Speaker 3:  You're listen to this in your car, I want you to know that right now, Alex
Speaker 3:  Heath is scrolling through a picture to confirm or deny that the
Speaker 3:  bag of dates says dates on it.
Speaker 6:  There are two things on the table that don't say in words what
Speaker 6:  they are on the box. It's the banana and it's the pineapple banana and it
Speaker 6:  identifies the banana, which is again a really easy thing for a computer
Speaker 6:  to do. and it misses the pineapple entirely.
Speaker 3:  Again, I'm just, I'm just putting this out there. If you're listening, you
Speaker 3:  know, when you're on a Google meet call with someone and their face instantly
Speaker 3:  goes to I'm browsing the web face. Yeah, yeah. I've never seen anyone
Speaker 3:  move to, I'm browsing the web face as fast as Alex did when
Speaker 3:  David said everything had a label.
Speaker 7:  Well, okay, you're right. So David, a big
Speaker 6:  Box that says dates on it is not a hard computer problem to
Speaker 7:  Solve, David. So the pineapple it missed in the video
Speaker 7:  I did was zuck it Got it right the first day I did it.
Speaker 6:  Okay, that's good. That's
Speaker 7:  Encouraging. So you still
Speaker 6:  Picked the two most distinctive fruits that you could have possibly picked.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying this demo is the easiest possible version of this demo. And
Speaker 6:  still it gives you a recipe that involves not everything on the table
Speaker 6:  and a bunch of stuff you don't have on the table. So, I, I, I get to the
Speaker 6:  end of that demo and I'm like, what problem did we just solve?
Speaker 7:  David? I fully agree with your, your big point like yes
Speaker 7:  there's a lot of smoke and mirrors here. The bar is also low.
Speaker 7:  The what they were trying to communicate is like, oh, what happens when you
Speaker 7:  have the visual AI in the ray bands with a display? And so what I'm talking
Speaker 7:  about is not the fact that it recognized everything right or wrong, it's
Speaker 7:  just this idea of like that visual AI with
Speaker 7:  a display and then, oh I can actually, like, I don't have to like just listen
Speaker 7:  to the recipe. I can see it and I can move it around and I can make it it
Speaker 7:  big and
Speaker 6:  I can edit it. That was cool. Edit the thing in the demo where it popped
Speaker 6:  up above it. Yeah. Saying what each thing was. I actually thought was like,
Speaker 6:  that's a really cool little bit of ui that it was like this is the cacao.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Nevermind that there was a box that said cacao right underneath the
Speaker 6:  label. But still, like I-I-I-I-I actually thought the UI was
Speaker 6:  very cool for what amounted to a not particularly impressive problem.
Speaker 6:  So looking at it as like, here is how you do this, I think is actually very
Speaker 6:  clever. I just was so like there so many people were like, oh my god,
Speaker 6:  the smoothie thing. And it's like, did we actually do anything here
Speaker 3:  Also to make a smoothie? You just dump everything. I was gonna say like,
Speaker 3:  push the button. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  That's, it's blender
Speaker 3:  It in, it'll
Speaker 6:  Be fine.
Speaker 3:  There's a technique here that the AI is gonna walk you through. You hit pulse
Speaker 3:  a couple times and then you hit plants. Yeah. Should've showed us you'd make
Speaker 3:  bread.
Speaker 7:  So on the smoothie thing, just really quick, I kind of freaked out not
Speaker 7:  because of how crazy I thought it was that it correctly identified a
Speaker 7:  pineapple the first time. David, they had been doing all these little Easter
Speaker 7:  eggs for me throughout my, I I spent like a full day at Meta and I'd done
Speaker 7:  a bunch of other demos before this and they were like dropping little things
Speaker 7:  all throughout my demos. Like the text that came up in the glasses was
Speaker 7:  like an employee being like, Hey, I've got the scoop for you on the next
Speaker 7:  ar glasses. Like I need to go like step out the room to like not get caught.
Speaker 7:  And then they, by the time I got to the smoothie I do,
Speaker 7:  I make smoothies every morning. And so by the, I thought I was like, did
Speaker 7:  they, they do they have cameras in my house. Like I, I got
Speaker 7:  to the point I just turned around to the room 'cause there's like 12 people
Speaker 7:  in the room and I'm just like, are you guys like watching me at home?
Speaker 7:  Are
Speaker 3:  You listening to me on my phone? Just say yes or no. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. It was the smoothie thing felt special and So I was actually
Speaker 7:  very disappointed to see that everyone got the smoothie demo, but
Speaker 3:  That's okay. So I wanna come back to whether the demo
Speaker 3:  is real or fake and the debate about what the word vaporware means. But you
Speaker 3:  talked about the control Yeah. Band the wristband several times. Yes. Let's
Speaker 3:  explain that real quick first. 'cause I, there's a part of this
Speaker 3:  where the, the neural wristband is the most
Speaker 3:  ready to go product, which is fascinating in and of itself. It's kind of
Speaker 3:  the coolest I think. Yeah. I mean it's done. It's, it's one part of the dream
Speaker 3:  for sure.
Speaker 7:  It's very clear that the band is done. I also know this because they're releasing
Speaker 7:  a pair of glasses with a very small heads up display. It's not full ar
Speaker 7:  that will use the band. I'm pretty sure next year it was very
Speaker 7:  clear that the band is done. And that's why I spent more time in the story
Speaker 7:  than I originally thought writing about the band. Also because it was genuinely,
Speaker 7:  I mean, I think I said this in the video, it was one of the coolest experiences
Speaker 7:  with a new piece of technology I've ever had because
Speaker 7:  there's no calibration. You just, you put it on you, you go through the
Speaker 7:  gestures and it has this haptic feedback in the
Speaker 7:  band that kind of reinforces when you're doing it correctly. I did that for
Speaker 7:  like 10 seconds and I was just flying through the thing
Speaker 7:  and to the point where I had to take them off at one point and put them
Speaker 7:  back on and like go back through the setup and I didn't even, I just did
Speaker 7:  it on my own and like, it, it just clicked so fast and it's so
Speaker 7:  precise and yeah, I'll, it uses EMG
Speaker 7:  electromyography and it, it's not reading your thoughts, but it's
Speaker 7:  interpreting neural signals through the movements of your wrist and
Speaker 7:  translating those into input in the glasses and Meta Meta
Speaker 7:  botta startup that we have covered extensively. I believe Addie
Speaker 7:  covered this even before they sold to, to Facebook. This was like in
Speaker 7:  2019 Control labs and it's this tech and
Speaker 7:  it's really powerful. I think they've stumbled onto something here that
Speaker 7:  I haven't seen for headsets, which is how do you control 'em without
Speaker 7:  putting your hands out in front of you? You know, like I use the spectacles
Speaker 7:  which rely on just hand tracking the week before.
Speaker 7:  And I was thinking when I was like flying to Meta
Speaker 7:  the next week, like in my airplane seat, it's like you're not gonna stick
Speaker 7:  your hands out like in an airplane seat to control your glasses.
Speaker 5:  Well North Glasses did that too, right? They had, they had like a ring that
Speaker 5:  would that they used to control it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It was like a joystick on a ring. Yeah, it was just
Speaker 7:  Weird. Yeah, it wasn't but it was cool. Yeah. But this
Speaker 5:  Is like, yeah, it wasn't like moving your hands out in front of you. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  This is like hyper precise click like
Speaker 7:  input that you can do with very, very small hand
Speaker 7:  gestures in your pocket or behind your back. And
Speaker 7:  I just, I mean I like audibly gasped when I started using it. Well
Speaker 5:  This is like cool technology we've seen for ages, right? Like,
Speaker 6:  Well Control labs has been around but
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah, like Control labs. We, we saw, we've, we've seen like horrible
Speaker 5:  products from small startups using this stuff before, but it's also like
Speaker 5:  just regularly used in prosthetics now, particularly like hand
Speaker 5:  prosthetics and arm prosthetics to, to give that movement. So it's like,
Speaker 5:  it's really cool to see it come to consumer products.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I've never seen EMG in a consumer products.
Speaker 7:  So it was, it was really
Speaker 5:  Cool. There's one in 2014 it was called like the Frog or something. Does
Speaker 5:  nobody remember this? No, no. I like, I swear
Speaker 6:  That there was a real, you know, face when everyone immediately started Googling.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We were all like, that's my face right now.
Speaker 6:  No, but Alex the thing you said in your story that most got me was
Speaker 6:  the, the moment where you your, like you had your hands in your jacket pockets
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And you're controlling the thing and that's the moment where you're
Speaker 6:  like, oh this is obviously the correct answer for this. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 6:  I'm fascinated by the whole kind of kit that they put together where it's
Speaker 6:  the, it's the glasses, there's the wireless compute puck that
Speaker 6:  feels like you put it in like your jacket pocket or your backpack or your
Speaker 6:  back pocket or whatever and then it's the band. Yep. And I think
Speaker 6:  at least for now, that strikes me as like
Speaker 6:  the exact Right. Three parts in the right way. Yeah. I think like
Speaker 6:  the Vision pros cable thing is, is wrong. The
Speaker 6:  only hand motions that the cameras can see in front of your face is wrong.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I honestly believe Meta got that part of this thing
Speaker 6:  like Exactly. Correct. and it just feels like you instantly are like using
Speaker 6:  it in a way that feels way more natural. Yes. Than even like
Speaker 6:  Eli's experience with the Vision Pro where you, like you, you still have
Speaker 6:  to sort of keep your hands on like the front plane of your body and in view
Speaker 6:  and that is just an amount of thinking that you don't have to do with this
Speaker 6:  and that feels much better.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I totally agree. I wanna talk about the puck. Just I guess on the
Speaker 7:  band though too, what Meta hopes is that over time the band
Speaker 7:  becomes its own platform and that it interfaces with
Speaker 7:  appliances, it interfaces with your car, other gadgets.
Speaker 7:  And the idea is like this is probably a 10 to 15 year out thing honestly
Speaker 7:  for it to really, you know,
Speaker 3:  It interfaces with your car.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So the idea is like you're walking around with these glasses, you look
Speaker 7:  at your car and you want to start the engine as you're walking
Speaker 7:  up to it, you do a little tap because it sees that you're looking at your
Speaker 7:  car, the band is connected, there's an API, you're logged in and you
Speaker 7:  turn your AC on or you turn your, this is the
Speaker 3:  Idea of a man who can grow crystals in the basement of his mansion.
Speaker 7:  Well it's honestly, it's it's, there's several leaps to get there. It's not
Speaker 7:  like the ecosystem of it all will be tough to develop until there's scale
Speaker 7:  with these glasses. But it's pretty obvious to think about, okay, if I'm
Speaker 7:  wearing contextually, you know, spatially wear glasses at all times and
Speaker 7:  I'm walking around my house and I look at my thermostat and I want to change
Speaker 7:  the setting, why can my band not, because it's
Speaker 7:  all connected. Why can my band not adjust the thermostat? Right. And that,
Speaker 7:  that's, that's the idea they have. I think it's a really cool
Speaker 3:  Idea. Why can't I turn reality into a bitmap display with windows and a mouse?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  With, with a camera and a controller and good enough
Speaker 6:  processing. You can get a pretty long way towards that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So people will see the band soon like,
Speaker 7:  like next year and, and I'm big excited. I
Speaker 5:  Gotta of I got an update real fast. Yeah. I found the band. Oh wow. It was
Speaker 5:  called the Mayo. It cost $200. They
Speaker 5:  first started reporting on it in 2013, came out in 2016 and you wore it
Speaker 5:  like on the middle of your for Oh sure, yeah. To control your, your laptop
Speaker 5:  and your,
Speaker 3:  And also keep this sweat away from me while you play tennis. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No it's so ugly.
Speaker 6:  And it use, I remember this thing, I tried
Speaker 3:  This thing thing. The thing looks like a ball bangle.
Speaker 6:  It really does.
Speaker 7:  And it uses EMG Kranz.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Used EMG like, like that particular technology, the E
Speaker 5:  mg technology has been around a while and we've seen it in other stuff but
Speaker 5:  it's always like been kind of, nobody's gotten the software part of it. Right.
Speaker 5:  And there's interactions
Speaker 7:  And the form factor it looks like the fit and it. Yeah. Yeah. Like this thing
Speaker 7:  is not bulky and it and it just sits
Speaker 3:  On your wrist. Yeah. This is cool. Did you have to wear it tightly around
Speaker 3:  your wrist?
Speaker 7:  It's tight but it's not like, like there, there are sensors that indent a
Speaker 7:  little bit into your skin but it wasn't like uncomfortable. I wore it, I
Speaker 7:  left the, the demo room with it still on to go interview Zuckerberg and like
Speaker 7:  they came running after me and we were like, you still got the band on?
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 7:  Keep running. Please let us keep that. So if we're talking about, you know,
Speaker 7:  the three parts of this I guess on the puck, I just like,
Speaker 7:  David, I agree with you that this feels like the right combination for now.
Speaker 7:  They obviously don't want the puck to be in the picture long term.
Speaker 7:  Sure.
Speaker 3:  But I think we're a long way away
Speaker 7:  From that. Yeah. They made the decision, which I think is the correct call,
Speaker 7:  is that they want the glasses to be as light as possible and to not burn
Speaker 7:  your face. Which is, you know what I've experienced a lot. Not literally
Speaker 7:  burning but just they get really hot and so they'd
Speaker 7:  made the decision to offload most of the app logic onto the puck. They
Speaker 7:  invented their own wifi protocol and it has to be 12 to
Speaker 7:  13 feet max away at all times. Or the glasses just don't work. And
Speaker 5:  Why do we call it a puck and not a computer?
Speaker 7:  I mean why do they call 'em glasses and not a computer? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh yeah. But like the,
Speaker 3:  Is it a circle?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's like, it looks like one of the big like
Speaker 7:  iPhone brick chargers you could like put on the back of the iPhone with
Speaker 7:  like MagSafe, like a big ass anchor. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It looks like you could put it in your back pocket but you wanna wear a belt.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  You could, I could put it in my back pocket 'cause I have huge back pockets.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, I mean the, the idea
Speaker 3:  Is like are you wearing JCOs? Did we just learn something about Flex? Alright.
Speaker 3:  Yeah I know you live in LA but like how bad is it gotten over there? It's
Speaker 7:  Pretty bad.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So the puck is the right trade
Speaker 7:  off to make because these glasses only weigh 98 grams.
Speaker 7:  Right. Whereas the Vision Pro is like five, six x that
Speaker 7:  and I, like I said, I wore them for two hours and I, I never felt
Speaker 7:  like uncomfortable. And a funny thing about the two hours I was
Speaker 7:  informed as we were wrapping, like you know there, there's a bunch of met
Speaker 7:  employees in the room. I'm, I think I was the second journalist ever to try
Speaker 7:  them. I've also written about these extensively. So they, they were really
Speaker 7:  like on edge and they, towards the end, like
Speaker 7:  I took them off and they, I could just hear everyone like breathe a sigh
Speaker 7:  of relief and like they were like, you just broke the demo, the record for
Speaker 7:  longest demo. Oh actually longest continuous wear of them at two
Speaker 7:  hours. We were like yeah we thought they would just like crap out by now.
Speaker 3:  That's what's up. So that was,
Speaker 5:  Was there a battery indicator or anything?
Speaker 7:  No. No there wasn't. And they didn't swap them out or anything. That's cool.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How, okay. You wear glasses. Yeah. How heavy versus
Speaker 5:  the ones you're wearing now, which seem fairly lightweight
Speaker 7:  Like you notice but like I have a pair of chunky LA
Speaker 7:  glasses that honestly felt in the same ballpark. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Like it wasn't, it wasn't too heavy because like it was on the ears. It was
Speaker 5:  just those ear pieces
Speaker 7:  Are so no pressure on the ears. I mean if anything it's a little in the front
Speaker 7:  of your face but, and the thing that struck me was, you know, they told me
Speaker 7:  definitively like the frames will be half as thick in the consumer version,
Speaker 7:  which means that
Speaker 3:  Okay so okay wait, that's it. That's my cue to Are you fromwhere There go.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So just describe the product that we, you saw, which is a very impressive
Speaker 3:  demo, right? Yeah. Lots of people saw the demo. Everyone is suitably impressed.
Speaker 3:  Great. The thing that they accomplished that no one else has
Speaker 3:  been able to accomplish is getting that display to work in that form
Speaker 3:  factor 98 grams on your face, two hours of battery life. You can
Speaker 3:  look at reality through the lenses and it will put, from what I understand,
Speaker 3:  labels above boxes of cocoa. Yeah. That's wonderful. Mark, Zuckerberg can
Speaker 3:  play pong with you. They had right, they, they've iterated it and a and
Speaker 3:  developed the existing EMG control band.
Speaker 3:  We put a computer in a giant battery and are sending signals from it
Speaker 3:  wirelessly to something else challenging 'cause they gotta do it in real
Speaker 3:  time but Right. A a thing that existed,
Speaker 3:  we put it all together in a product and we sell it far, far away. Right.
Speaker 3:  Like I'm giving them credit for a bunch of stuff. Some stuff they iterated
Speaker 3:  some stuff, they bought some stuff they had to build from scratch and spend
Speaker 3:  billions of dollars that basically no one else has managed to crack yet.
Speaker 3:  All great. It's a long way from here to there three years.
Speaker 3:  So that's their promise. And so like, you know the thing I would say is like
Speaker 3:  it's a vapor till it ships and Meta has the
Speaker 3:  extraordinarily opportunity to show a thing that isn't shipping.
Speaker 3:  Right. Like I, they're all proud of it. Yeah. You can see they're bursting
Speaker 3:  with pride. They in particular built a
Speaker 3:  display technology they can demo for two hours with a variety of people doing
Speaker 3:  stuff that no one else has been able to do. Magic
Speaker 3:  leap hacking GPU of your brain I think is the closest to this. And
Speaker 3:  they had people sitting down next to a box the size of a refrigerator
Speaker 3:  and they couldn't ship it.
Speaker 3:  What is the the, and Meta doesn't have to do that, right? They have,
Speaker 3:  they're selling the quest. They make a bunch of money selling ads. They got
Speaker 3:  Kristen Bell being an AI voice that they have a whole business that's running
Speaker 3:  that can subsidize this thing.
Speaker 3:  W it's still vapor in my opinion. Like they have to ship it. They're just
Speaker 3:  able to be confident that they've gotten this far.
Speaker 3:  But it's unclear to me what this actually looks like as a product because
Speaker 3:  I sincerely doubt it will have a wireless compute puck and like
Speaker 3:  once they start shipping the neural wristband, it won't take on a life
Speaker 3:  of its own in some other way and it will be completely divorced from the
Speaker 3:  Quest ecosystem there. It just like, there's a set of
Speaker 3:  unanswered questions here that I think it's very tempting to pres answer
Speaker 3:  or imagine. And that honestly is the fun part and I'm excited to do some
Speaker 3:  of that with all of you. But it's also like three years is a long time. A
Speaker 3:  lot of things can change in three years and a lot of other things have to
Speaker 3:  go right. Like the lenses in your story, they're planning to ship
Speaker 3:  regular lenses, right? They're gonna go from silicon carbide
Speaker 3:  to glass.
Speaker 7:  Well they wouldn't tell me the material and the truth is that they're
Speaker 7:  parallel pathing like four or five different options. So they're Right. But
Speaker 3:  If your big innovation is the display and you're like
Speaker 3:  we have four options to bring this display to mar, you actually haven't picked,
Speaker 3:  I think
Speaker 7:  You're being simplistic when you say display 'cause the display is the
Speaker 7:  projectors, the wave guides and the lenses. The lenses
Speaker 7:  specifically are what they can't manufacture in a cheap enough way at scale.
Speaker 7:  So the lenses will be different. The projectors are on the
Speaker 7:  path of what I saw going to be the same kind of technology. They invented
Speaker 7:  them, you know, from scratch. The wave guide's the same.
Speaker 7:  They wouldn't tell me what the lenses are. Not because they don't think,
Speaker 7:  they don't know necessarily, but because they haven't fully decided
Speaker 7:  because they're locking these things in on like a timeline
Speaker 7:  that is aggressive. But also they don't want to speak
Speaker 7:  before they, like if they would've said, you know,
Speaker 7:  lemme back up like they decided to not ship Orion two
Speaker 7:  years ago. So the timeline for this hardware stuff is farther out. They,
Speaker 7:  when they, when they say, you know, this is coming in a few years,
Speaker 7:  it's not like we have not set anything up for this to happen in three years.
Speaker 7:  They have, they're on a believe me heads will roll if there is not a
Speaker 7:  consumer version of these error classes in a few years. Well sure. But those
Speaker 7:  are
Speaker 3:  The stakes. The stakes are, we are either, we're all double clicking on cars,
Speaker 3:  you know, to see what happens or heads will roll. Like I, I
Speaker 3:  don't want to shy away from the stakes. Yeah. But I, the part of me that
Speaker 3:  says it's great to imagine how these products might work, especially
Speaker 3:  products that are meant to deliver AI is a new platform that replace
Speaker 3:  smartphones on balance. I don't believe you
Speaker 3:  and it probably doesn't work is like the right answer. And the fact that
Speaker 3:  they got the display to work, which no one else has ever achieved as far
Speaker 3:  as I can tell is incredible.
Speaker 3:  Now comes like an incredible hard part. Okay. But let's
Speaker 5:  Talk about these lenses though because like the lenses is part of the magic
Speaker 5:  of these things, right? Like they, they went with this really expensive product
Speaker 5:  to do this, to have the best light refraction and stuff. And that's
Speaker 5:  because that material exists in the wor I mean it doesn't, very little of
Speaker 5:  it exists in the world. They usually make it all. But like they have to do
Speaker 5:  all of that now they're gonna have to go to a whole different thing which
Speaker 5:  presumably would have a lower price, but similar
Speaker 5:  qualities. And that seems not like an engineering but like
Speaker 5:  a science problem. And that seems like a big science problem
Speaker 5:  for them to have.
Speaker 7:  I don't think they see it that way. I think the Yeah, I'm
Speaker 5:  Sure they don't. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I, I kind of agree with you. I mean look, here's what they told me. The
Speaker 7:  consumer version will be, the frames will be about a half as thick projector
Speaker 7:  technology will, the projector technology will be very similar, will be in
Speaker 7:  line with what I saw the wave guides will, the field of view which was 70
Speaker 7:  degrees, which is super wide, will be slightly smaller
Speaker 7:  but not like dramatically.
Speaker 7:  And the puck will exist. The band will exist.
Speaker 7:  Like it's just the lenses that they I think are looking
Speaker 7:  at a few options and they don't have to make the call right now. So they're
Speaker 7:  not committing to it. And on the why they're not using
Speaker 7:  silicon carbide and why they did it in the first place is they told me
Speaker 7:  they had hoped that the rest of the industry, whether it was other companies
Speaker 7:  doing AR headsets or even the EV industry for example, which hasn't grown
Speaker 7:  in the last five years, I think as everyone thought it would maybe
Speaker 7:  five years ago, which is when they began the MA manufacturing of Orion and
Speaker 7:  Earnest, they thought the rest of the industry would go to silicon
Speaker 7:  carbide and build up Oh interesting. Economies of scale with
Speaker 7:  them and they ended up being the only company that was trying to do
Speaker 7:  this.
Speaker 3:  So that's like a really interesting bet, right? You think Apple and Google
Speaker 3:  and Samsung are all gonna go forward, invest in a technology Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And you'll just be able to catch the tailwind and that didn't happen. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They thought economies of scale would make silicon carbide more efficient
Speaker 7:  and less costly to produce. And that didn't happen. I mean Bos told me
Speaker 7:  90% of the cost is the lenses. So Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause it's like having two diamond rings on your face.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. But I'm just, I'm coming back to the thing no
Speaker 3:  one has solved is the displays. So whether the lenses are the
Speaker 3:  key element of the displays or just they happen to have bought a lot of
Speaker 3:  silicon carbide and they use them this time. Like I don't, I I
Speaker 3:  I'm curious to know like how much of the thing that they
Speaker 3:  demoed is down to that lens because everybody's vision
Speaker 3:  is the same, right? We're gonna, we're gonna put glasses in your face, you're
Speaker 3:  gonna look at the world, we're gonna layer digital information over the world
Speaker 3:  and then you're gonna be able to take action on it. This is Apple's vision
Speaker 3:  and they couldn't build it. So they built the vision pro. And if
Speaker 3:  Apple is like we can't make it good enough on a timeline to sell,
Speaker 3:  here's a VR headset that fakes it. Meta doesn't have to
Speaker 3:  do that. Right. Meta's business is good enough to keep funneling money into
Speaker 3:  this r and d project. I think that, I think I'm curious for you to read on
Speaker 3:  Zuck wanting to show it. Yeah. 'cause I think he, he was just having
Speaker 3:  the time of his life yesterday at Meta Connect. Yeah. Like showing up all
Speaker 3:  the toys that he's built and like how far ahead of both Apple and Google
Speaker 3:  in various ways. There were a lot of shots at Apple and Google in that. Well
Speaker 6:  Wait, NELI y you and I have paid a lot of attention to these companies this
Speaker 6:  year and have talked about this. Would you bet for or against
Speaker 6:  Apple having something that looks and works an awful lot like Orion and is
Speaker 6:  just as expensive to make in existence in their offices right now,
Speaker 3:  I would say they probably have 500
Speaker 3:  variations of something that looks and works exactly like Orion and Apple
Speaker 3:  is not the kind of company that shows off science projects like this at
Speaker 3:  all. They just won't do it. They've talked about it, right? I mean
Speaker 3:  like Tim Cook in the lead up to the Vision Pro. Before the Vision Pro existed,
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook was like, I'm making glasses. Like I'm gonna, everything that he
Speaker 3:  ever described was Orion, So, I. Think Zuck loves the
Speaker 3:  fact that he showed off the thing that Apple has been describing for years,
Speaker 3:  well before Apple was ready to do it. I do wonder
Speaker 3:  like when Apple's like we need chips, they
Speaker 3:  go to TSMC and they're like, we're gonna buy all the chips, we're gonna build
Speaker 3:  you a factory Corning, but it's your, we don't want to own it, we
Speaker 3:  just want to build it for you so we have the capacity for it. You you run
Speaker 3:  it. We're not putting that on our books. Like that's the level that Apple
Speaker 3:  makes investments at. And I, I don't think they were able to pull off
Speaker 3:  this form factor. And even with the Vision Pro, the form factor
Speaker 3:  compromises are like now in retrospect like ludicrous,
Speaker 3:  right? Like the battery pa like all the stuff right, the hand tracking,
Speaker 3:  I'm actually, you know, even the Orion, right? That uses your eyes to the
Speaker 3:  pointers still feels like a miss to me. That's still overloading an input
Speaker 3:  within output.
Speaker 7:  I disagree because of the band, the eyes when they're your drag and not your
Speaker 7:  click it's and the click is not sticking hands up.
Speaker 7:  It works pretty well. Like I I I thought the same thing with the Vision Pro.
Speaker 7:  When you If you try Orion at some point. I'd be curious to hear how you
Speaker 7:  think when you try it because the eye tracking was, was
Speaker 7:  surprisingly good with the band.
Speaker 5:  When you were having like the conversation with Neli, were you able to also
Speaker 5:  do other stuff at the same time? Like Yeah, because I'm just curious like
Speaker 5:  how that works if you're like looking at him and then you need to move something
Speaker 5:  over here and that means you have to drag it so you have to kind of like
Speaker 5:  look away from him in a potentially awkward way.
Speaker 7:  You could stick your hand out and pinch it and drag it or you could glance
Speaker 7:  at it really quick. Tap your fingers together to to
Speaker 3:  Oh 'cause it does hand tracking too.
Speaker 7:  It does hand tracking and it will merge hand tracking with all of it anytime
Speaker 7:  you put your hands up.
Speaker 3:  That's smart. Yeah, well the, the reason I brought brought all this up is
Speaker 3:  like Apple, a Apple punted on the big problem on
Speaker 3:  the display problem and then tried to solve a bunch of the other problems
Speaker 3:  or at least show you what a bunch of the other problems could look like if
Speaker 3:  they were solved. Like hand tracking like windows and space, spatial compute,
Speaker 3:  all this stuff. But they couldn't solve the display problem so that you end
Speaker 3:  up with a Vision Pro. Even in the compromise state of the Vision Pro form
Speaker 3:  factor, Meta has solved the display problem, at least
Speaker 3:  we think in a way that costs $10,000 and we have yet to see how they will
Speaker 3:  solve the rest of the problems. And that is kind of just an interesting place.
Speaker 7:  I agree. Here's the
Speaker 3:  Company that could not solve the display but they shipped the product like
Speaker 3:  the operating system and the app model and the blah blah blah. And then here's
Speaker 3:  the company that solved the display but can't ship it 'cause it's too expensive.
Speaker 3:  Eventually it seems like the answer is gonna be someone will get to the right
Speaker 3:  answer in the middle first.
Speaker 6:  But again, I keep coming back to like Heath last year
Speaker 6:  when Meta tried to front run the Vision Pro, one of the things that
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg basically said was, we could have done something
Speaker 6:  as good as the Vision Pro, but it would've been as expensive as the Vision
Speaker 6:  Pro. and we don't wanna do that. I think it is perfectly plausible that at
Speaker 6:  a bunch of other companies in the tech industry right now, there is a thing
Speaker 6:  that looks and works and costs just like Orion and
Speaker 3:  Then there's whatever Snap has, which is well, and
Speaker 6:  I was gonna say the difference is there are only two companies willing to
Speaker 6:  show it to people and of those two Meta is just absolutely
Speaker 6:  kicking Snap's ass. But in a certain way kudos to Meta
Speaker 6:  for being the ones who are actually willing to be out in public sort of showing
Speaker 6:  the state of the art on what they're working on. But I, I genuinely
Speaker 6:  wonder how far ahead it actually is because the
Speaker 6:  gap between, we've made a thousand of these and they cost $10,000 each
Speaker 6:  and we can make millions of them at a reasonable price is so much bigger
Speaker 6:  than anybody ever makes it out to be, including experienced hardware companies.
Speaker 6:  Like the gap between I can make one and I can make a thousand is huge
Speaker 6:  and like kudos to Meta they're there, but thousands to millions is a completely
Speaker 6:  different thing.
Speaker 5:  Wait, wait, wait. But have we seen people wearing, is there an increased
Speaker 5:  use of glassware in like at Google at at
Speaker 5:  Apple? Like does it just seem like more people have bad vision in thick glasses?
Speaker 6:  I mean Google's been showing off the, the, there, there are the prototype
Speaker 6:  glasses in a bunch of Google videos recently. Like they're, that kind of
Speaker 6:  look like the size and shape of Orion. Like this stuff is
Speaker 6:  just out there. I
Speaker 7:  I just as the verges foremost phase computer expert, again this is a cry
Speaker 7:  for help. This is not a brag.
Speaker 7:  I actually will push back on you guys. I do not think anyone has anything
Speaker 7:  working in this form factor as a standalone kit that is not
Speaker 7:  completely on rails or something on a desk that you look through.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I don't think that actually exists.
Speaker 3:  Can I just for the sake of our own comments, can I just say a bunch of nouns
Speaker 3:  so that people
Speaker 7:  What
Speaker 3:  HoloLens X reel two Pro Air or whatever it's called,
Speaker 3:  HTC, other companies? Yes. I know other companies have
Speaker 3:  made glasses before. I know that the Hol Alex and I have both changed
Speaker 3:  Spark plugs wearing a HoloLens like the, the form
Speaker 3:  factor innovation here is real. Yeah, like, like getting it down in glasses.
Speaker 3:  I I'm not trying to take away from that. I'm, I'm just pointing at like it's
Speaker 3:  vapor till it ships. Like it's one of our rules, right? And the,
Speaker 3:  the distance from what we see today to a product.
Speaker 3:  All of the questions I have to answer in the middle, this is what I was asking
Speaker 3:  about. The quest is like they've answered a bunch of these questions with
Speaker 3:  the Quest. I suspect they think that some of those answers are the wrong
Speaker 3:  answers actually and they need to go in a different way to enable some of
Speaker 3:  the things they want with true AR glasses.
Speaker 7:  I think that's right. I also just think that before this week
Speaker 7:  I honestly did it no where they were at
Speaker 7:  with this in terms of how they were going to do it. And I feel like
Speaker 7:  after this week they actually have the right approach of how they're going
Speaker 7:  about it, which is just relentlessly focusing on the
Speaker 7:  form factor, which Meta has made a lot of hardware mistakes
Speaker 7:  over the years and has, I think just not had the right priorities
Speaker 7:  in terms of what they're building and what it's for or even
Speaker 7:  understanding what it's for. It took them 10 years really to understand that
Speaker 7:  the quest is really just a gaming device even still. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  How much do you think that's the RayBan lesson? That's
Speaker 7:  Part of it, but I just, I think, I think there's clarity here
Speaker 7:  about why people would want these and like something
Speaker 7:  Zuckerberg told me was I thought pretty illustrative of this
Speaker 7:  is like, we want them to be just as good when they're off because we know
Speaker 7:  that you're not going to have the AR on maybe most of the day.
Speaker 7:  And so focusing on that first and letting
Speaker 7:  the technology then kind of fill in, I think is the right approach versus
Speaker 7:  just how they've approached hardware so far, which is like, let's just put
Speaker 7:  as much technology in something as we can and see how
Speaker 7:  people will use it. And here they're like, no, we know how people will use
Speaker 7:  this. It's utility. It's like heads up lightweight interactions,
Speaker 7:  video calling and AI and
Speaker 7:  but the form factor is, is primary. And that's what like,
Speaker 7:  that's the intro of the piece. Like I walk in and I'm looking at
Speaker 7:  them, you know, I'm probably four feet away and I you can't tell, you can't
Speaker 7:  tell that they're AR glasses and it's like even that and as a
Speaker 7:  prototype and I struggle with this 'cause yeah, NELI is is vapor until it
Speaker 7:  ships but it's, it's also not like it's somewhere between a
Speaker 7:  mirage and a product. Like it's, it is real. Like I touched it, I used it
Speaker 7:  but it's not, it's not productized. So seeing that and going
Speaker 7:  wow like the form like and it's gonna be half as thick in a few years. Like
Speaker 7:  okay, I finally see where this is going, especially with the band and I feel
Speaker 7:  like before this week even I, as someone who's been reporting on this a lot,
Speaker 7:  couldn't really see where they were going and I think they feel so
Speaker 7:  confident in where they're going and the clarity of what they're gonna do
Speaker 7:  that that's why they shut it off this week. And also I think Zuck just thinks
Speaker 7:  it's really cool.
Speaker 3:  Yeah and he's right. It is really cool. No one else has done, I, again, I'm
Speaker 3:  just not taking anything away from him. No one else has pulled off the display
Speaker 3:  like hundreds
Speaker 7:  Of, with the form factor,
Speaker 3:  Millions of dollars if not billions of dollars have been thrown at this
Speaker 3:  problem of can I put lenses in front of your face that can convincingly in
Speaker 3:  3D augment reality. Not just show you a TV like the X
Speaker 3:  reel glasses do and not require you to wear a hollow lens and still
Speaker 3:  have no field of view. Like billions upon billions of dollars in this
Speaker 3:  industry been thrown out this problem and only Meta has allowed people to
Speaker 3:  wear it for two
Speaker 7:  Hours. And it's not an overestimation to say that they have probably
Speaker 7:  spent snap's market cap on Orion in the last
Speaker 7:  10 years. And it's like no other company would do this like, like
Speaker 7:  Apple killed the car project 'cause it's like we don't see a
Speaker 7:  realistic timeline to shipping. We're not even sure what it is. Like this
Speaker 7:  is a uniquely Meta thing and it's, it's like a personal thing for
Speaker 7:  Zuckerberg, which is just like screw Apple and Google. I'm never going through
Speaker 7:  this shit again on mobile. You know that he's gone through
Speaker 3:  Actually hold right there. Alex, I wanna talk about Zuck versus Apple and
Speaker 3:  Google and I wanna talk about the Ray bands a bit, but we gotta take a break.
Speaker 3:  So let's take a break and then come back and then we can talk about Zucks
Speaker 3:  War with Tim Cook. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. Keith, right before the break we're talking about
Speaker 3:  Zuck and you said he doesn't want to go through this shit again, which is
Speaker 3:  you, you just interviewed him for quite a long time. You saw him on stage
Speaker 3:  at Meta Connect. I mean, he is, I mean the hair's flowing. The,
Speaker 3:  the Latin T-shirts are in Latin. He's feeling himself chain. He's bringing
Speaker 3:  out chain. He's got a chain. He's bringing out MMA fighters for Meta,
Speaker 3:  RayBan demos just for the hell of it at this point. Take mine out. He's like,
Speaker 3:  I can produce in the MMA lightweight champion of the world. It will, like
Speaker 3:  here he is, get outta here. Like it's
Speaker 3:  great. It's, it's all good. But the, the thing that strikes me about that
Speaker 3:  is
Speaker 3:  yes, there's a politics of it, which maybe we should talk about a little
Speaker 3:  bit, but he really thinks that these glasses are the
Speaker 3:  next great computing platform and he
Speaker 3:  wants to win that fight more than anything. And
Speaker 3:  he probably perceives that he's ahead, but put that in context of
Speaker 3:  why he does not want to lose to Apple and Google.
Speaker 7:  There's so many reasons. Do you guys remember when all of Facebook's
Speaker 7:  internal apps went down for like a full day in the entire company? Like
Speaker 7:  ground to a halt? Yeah. Yeah. Because Apple revoked its developer license.
Speaker 3:  I do.
Speaker 7:  That's just one example. There's, there's app tracking transparency. I
Speaker 7:  don't want it to get into a moral debate about that, but like it objectively
Speaker 7:  like killed billions of dollars of meta's ad revenue.
Speaker 7:  There's all of the app store policies that he is talked about for a very
Speaker 7:  long time.
Speaker 7:  Like people think of Meta as just an app developer and they are really in
Speaker 7:  terms of their business. But they came up, you know, 20 years ago they
Speaker 7:  watched mobile happen. They tried to do a phone, failed at it.
Speaker 7:  Zuckerberg has always wanted to be in control of a platform. And
Speaker 7:  this is something that I think like companies that were born in the mobile
Speaker 7:  era don't even really like think is possible. 'cause it's like you just come
Speaker 7:  into the reality you're in. But he knows what the reality was before Mobile
Speaker 7:  when he was building Facebook early on. And I think
Speaker 7:  they really feel that, you know, if Apple does glasses and the vision pro
Speaker 7:  people start using it and they ship a cheaper one and these
Speaker 7:  become, you know, they start selling, maybe they
Speaker 7:  don't let METAS apps on there at all. And there's this just real tension
Speaker 7:  there of who has the distribution control.
Speaker 7:  It's why Google pays billions of dollars to Apple to have search in
Speaker 7:  Safari. Whoever controls how you access your thing ultimately has
Speaker 7:  leverage over you. And Zuckerberg's been feeling that pretty acutely for
Speaker 7:  10 plus years. And so yeah, this is like a, this is a
Speaker 7:  as much about like inventing the future as it is Correct. In the past. And
Speaker 7:  I don't think any company without that unique context would be doing this.
Speaker 7:  And I think that, so that's a uniquely Meta thing.
Speaker 6:  Can I just read a quote from the interview that I thought was, was very telling
Speaker 6:  you, you, you guys spent a long time talking about basically what
Speaker 6:  AR and AI are gonna do to the next generation of gadgets. And then he, what
Speaker 6:  he says is, for what it's worth, I also think that all the AI work is gonna
Speaker 6:  make phones a lot more exciting. You know, blah blah blah. AI is cool. If
Speaker 6:  I were at any of the other companies trying to design what the next few versions
Speaker 6:  of iPhone or Google's phones should be, I think that there's a long and interesting
Speaker 6:  roadmap of things that they can do with AI that as an app developer, we can't.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like to me that's the whole thing, right? Yeah. He's like, if, if I
Speaker 6:  am convinced that if Meta had its way, the puck
Speaker 6:  wouldn't exist on Orion, the puck would be your phone. Yes. Yep. That's
Speaker 6:  what those companies want. And they just can't do it because the only companies
Speaker 6:  that are ever gonna be allowed to do it are Google and Apple and and like,
Speaker 6:  and so if I'm Mark, I'm like, oh, a gigantic part of what I am
Speaker 6:  doing should be tethered to this thing that I'm just not allowed to touch
Speaker 6:  and that would piss me off.
Speaker 7:  They're so mad that they can't automatically sync photos off your Ray
Speaker 7:  bands into your iPhone Camera roll. Yes. Yes. They can do it on Android.
Speaker 5:  It's super annoying.
Speaker 3:  It's so dumb.
Speaker 7:  They can do it on Android because the APIs are there. Android's a little
Speaker 7:  looser. iOS No, like the reason the first ones,
Speaker 7:  the first Ray bands also had a lot of issues. They had a lot of Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  pairing issues and like limitations with what they could do with Apple. And
Speaker 7:  Apple is because of the EU gradually being forced to open up its
Speaker 7:  APIs. But yeah, they're like, they're pissed. They can't sync photos to
Speaker 7:  a camera rolls.
Speaker 5:  But why doesn't Meta complain more? I guess like, like
Speaker 5:  we saw this, they complain Epic all the time. No, no, but they complain all
Speaker 5:  the time. We saw Epic put their, their money where their mouth is like, does
Speaker 5:  does Meta do that? It doesn't seem like they do.
Speaker 3:  Well Meta's also Monopolistically.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I was like, I was like, is it because they know that like Lena will
Speaker 5:  be like, yeah. Yeah, that's true. We are. I mean,
Speaker 3:  And this is what I mean by the politics of it all. And yeah, Alex in your
Speaker 3:  talk like Mark, just like, there's just hard
Speaker 3:  shots. The EU like throughout your interview where he is like, they should
Speaker 3:  figure out what they want and it's like, dude, what they want is like slightly
Speaker 3:  better Bluetooth than iPhone, right? They want to open
Speaker 3:  interop between messaging platforms and so that is bad for
Speaker 3:  WhatsApp. Like straight up. I think they're trapped between,
Speaker 3:  we would love for you to kick open the doors on iOS but also
Speaker 3:  don't do that to any of our platforms that have the same kind of restrictions.
Speaker 7:  Well that's, I mean they're being forced to do interop with WhatsApp like
Speaker 7:  we just wrote about. Yeah. You're gonna be able to message people outside
Speaker 7:  of WhatsApp. Yeah, I, yes, there's truth to what
Speaker 7:  you're saying. I would argue like Apple is still super locks down
Speaker 7:  and it's opening up over time, but I don't think they think Apple will
Speaker 7:  open up
Speaker 7:  soon enough. And so it's like we need to just invent the next thing.
Speaker 6:  Well, and I think my read of this is that if you're Meta,
Speaker 6:  the easiest way to get where you're going would be to start
Speaker 6:  all of this cool ar stuff as an accessory to your phone, right? And the reason
Speaker 6:  that the Ray bands have worked is that they are an accessory to your phone.
Speaker 6:  They're, they're vastly underpowered accessory to your
Speaker 6:  phone just because of what they're allowed to do, but also the restrictions
Speaker 6:  of the technology and stuff. But like the 1.5 step of this transition,
Speaker 6:  you would want to be your, your phone becomes the computer
Speaker 6:  and then you, you have a bunch of new wearable accessories that you use.
Speaker 6:  You're just not allowed to build that. And so what all these companies have
Speaker 6:  to do is basically like engineer a giant societal shift out of
Speaker 6:  nowhere because the like gradual change that actually would make
Speaker 6:  this make sense is just walled off to all but two companies on the planet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And if I were anybody but one of those two companies, I would be really
Speaker 6:  pissed about that.
Speaker 7:  So what has Zuckerberg done? He has gone and linked up with
Speaker 7:  the Italians and the French 'cause it's technically right. Ellisor
Speaker 7:  Luxottica, the parent company of RayBan is French and Italian. But
Speaker 7:  what did you think Neli of his comment? So they've just done
Speaker 7:  a 10 year deal with Ellisor Luxottica. The idea is that Meta's tech stack
Speaker 7:  is something Ellisor will be able to put into any of its lines. It owns
Speaker 7:  a ton of brands. Oakley, Raven,
Speaker 5:  It's a monopoly.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 5:  Wear. You and I are both wearing glasses made by them right now, presumably.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. Pull over in your car, look at your glasses.
Speaker 3:  Probably made by s
Speaker 7:  They just bought Supreme. So Supreme glasses. He
Speaker 7:  confirmed in our interview that they're buying a stake in Ellisor Luxottica,
Speaker 7:  which was news. But his comment about he
Speaker 7:  thinks that Ellisor will be for Europe and smart glasses, what
Speaker 7:  Samsung was for Korea and phones. Incredible.
Speaker 3:  What you think about that, Nina? Oh, interesting. It's a good line. It's
Speaker 3:  a great line. It is extraordinarily presumptuous
Speaker 3:  in the best possible way. Yeah. Like if you're at Samsung,
Speaker 3:  you're like, yo, we were Samsung before
Speaker 10:  We make ships like,
Speaker 3:  Like our nuclear reactor division is doing just fine.
Speaker 3:  So that is confusing. But what he means is
Speaker 3:  Android is the operating system enabled Samsung to enter the mobile
Speaker 3:  phone market. Samsung is now even more Samsung than it was before.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I would point out by the way, a Saturday Samsung alert If, you are
Speaker 3:  over a chess listener, know that Samsung required all of its executives to
Speaker 3:  work six days in the office to, in a sense insert
Speaker 3:  a sense of urgency and crisis into the company. They don't make anything.
Speaker 3:  So all they can do is come up with deals. They cut the price of one of their
Speaker 3:  gaming monitors by 50% and gave you not one but two TVs for free. If, you
Speaker 3:  buy one. Incredible. It's on the website. Saturday Samsung. Everybody,
Speaker 3:  you had
Speaker 7:  To go on that tangent. You had to.
Speaker 3:  It's it's just incredible. Yeah. Every part of every part of Saturday Samsung
Speaker 3:  it is better than less. Makes me happy. But wait, what he's saying is
Speaker 3:  there was a hardware vendor in Samsung and Android came along
Speaker 3:  provided at the operating system and the opportunity to go address the world
Speaker 3:  market. And now they are Samsung. Yeah. Again, extraordinarily presumptuous
Speaker 3:  in the best way. Are you saying that Esor Luxottica is a hardware maker
Speaker 3:  and are something, is the operating system that will let you
Speaker 3:  go become Samsung? Well, you're missing some key components, right?
Speaker 3:  Es Asada doesn't make chips. Samsung makes fucking dram. Like
Speaker 3:  they're like the hardware maker. They make ole displays and
Speaker 3:  chips. The first ch the first processor in they made batteries was
Speaker 3:  a Samsung arm processor. Right? So like the industry was built on top
Speaker 3:  of Samsung from the jump.
Speaker 7:  I'm pretty sure I'm looking at these new transparent ray bands. They announced,
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry, Tom Warren translucent, translucent ray
Speaker 3:  Bands. He's really ran into like, I work with a bunch of nerds this week
Speaker 3:  piece and
Speaker 7:  I think it's a Qualcomm chip inside actually,
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying like all of that, like Samsung's latent capabilities
Speaker 3:  were brought together because Google provided them a, an
Speaker 3:  operating system that let them become dominant in phones. Yeah. Maybe Microsoft
Speaker 3:  could have provided an operating system. You remember Samsung made a bunch
Speaker 3:  of weaker Windows phones in in the early days. Mm.
Speaker 3:  I But does Luxottica have chips
Speaker 3:  and Ram or does it just have design chops and retail distribution? I think
Speaker 3:  that whole comment was basically another like
Speaker 3:  shot at the eu because the big criticism of all the EU regulatory
Speaker 3:  stuff is we, the United States,
Speaker 3:  deeply weird libertarian, unregulated United States makes the tech
Speaker 3:  companies and you make the taxes and all you have is Spotify, which
Speaker 3:  only ever complains about not having access to iOS. And that
Speaker 3:  basically is the, the shape of the complaint. and we have European
Speaker 3:  listeners are gonna argue with me about something or the other. It's fine.
Speaker 3:  But that is the shape of the complaint from Silicon Valley. And I think Mark
Speaker 3:  is saying, look, I'll take one of your companies and I'll turn 'em into Samsung
Speaker 3:  just to get the hell outta my way. And I don't know that that comparison
Speaker 3:  holds up because again, Luxottica does own everything. Yeah. But instead
Speaker 3:  of dram fabs they own Supreme. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like it's just a very different Yeah. Thing. But
Speaker 6:  But potentially like as the, as the proprietor of the Eli's
Speaker 6:  insane theory of wearable bullshit.
Speaker 3:  I'm ready, I'm ready for this. You have to acknowledge if you're opening
Speaker 3:  this door, I'm, I'm walking right in. No,
Speaker 6:  You, you have to acknowledge that making the DRAM and owning Supreme might
Speaker 6:  be equally important in this. Like, oh,
Speaker 3:  They are,
Speaker 7:  They think that it doesn't,
Speaker 6:  You can't sit here and tell me that fids and value
Speaker 6:  are opposing things unless you agree that looking good on your face is
Speaker 6:  important. And there there are a small number of companies that are very,
Speaker 6:  very good at making things that people like wearing on their face. And
Speaker 6:  I, I think you could argue that a lot of companies in tech have tried to
Speaker 6:  like, acquire or develop that capability and can't do it.
Speaker 7:  There's no way Meta would've made these, there's no way they would look anything
Speaker 7:  like these.
Speaker 6:  It honestly, it might be easier to learn how to make DRAM as a company than
Speaker 6:  to learn how to be cool.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I was like, okay, well can we just clip that, that line and
Speaker 3:  just put it on TikTok and just let it live its own life. I sincerely believe
Speaker 3:  that. But like the hundred years,
Speaker 6:  The history of technology said that is
Speaker 3:  Probably true. Easier to make dram than glasses to look good.
Speaker 5:  It's, I mean the, the ones that they wear, like they got just a little right,
Speaker 5:  the Orion's because they look like Buddy Holly glasses from the fifties,
Speaker 7:  Which are actually kind of coming back. Like that was another thing. That
Speaker 7:  was another thing Zuckerberg said is like, it's kind of nice that chunky
Speaker 7:  glasses are back in style.
Speaker 3:  Like this is like a Zuckerberg long game, right? Like Yeah, he, he, he
Speaker 3:  bought off a bunch of fashion houses in the background. I was like, make
Speaker 3:  the glasses bigger and like, and you know, it's like that scene from Devil
Speaker 3:  Horse product.
Speaker 6:  He turned all the knobs on Instagram to make vintage cool again and now it's
Speaker 3:  Back.
Speaker 7:  I mean he's he's right, he's right. I was at the Snap event the week before
Speaker 7:  and I saw someone wearing what I thought were the new spectacles and they
Speaker 7:  were Prada glasses.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying Ian was picked in this room for you. Alex.
Speaker 3:  That's what's happening here.
Speaker 3:  No, but like the, I look, I'm saying I, I, I agree. I'm very
Speaker 3:  excited to get my clear Raybans on Monday. They
Speaker 6:  Look so good.
Speaker 3:  They're pretty cool. They only make them in this small size. And I have a
Speaker 3:  huge head and I'm furious about this.
Speaker 7:  You're 49 or 50 or 52,
Speaker 3:  Whatever. What's the bigger go? Bigger. Bigger. Number
Speaker 7:  52 is like you
Speaker 3:  60. Good. Just as big
Speaker 7:  As they
Speaker 3:  Can be. No,
Speaker 7:  52 is like, most brands are like, sorry, like Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I know. Which is why I can't. So
Speaker 7:  You're probably a 50. I'm like a 49 50. These are comfortable.
Speaker 3:  Stop measuring my head first of all. Like
Speaker 7:  I've just been enough with you in person to kind of, you know, map it in
Speaker 7:  my
Speaker 3:  Mind. I I have a side hobby of head measurement. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's not problematic at all.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying as big as they can get. And I know Boz has an equally sized
Speaker 3:  noggin that's, I know that he should have built the bigger ones 'cause it,
Speaker 3:  the regular ones come two sizes and these only come in medium. But I'm getting
Speaker 3:  'em on Monday. I'm very excited. It's the first time I've got them. I think
Speaker 3:  the clear ones look sick. I'm excited to do all this stuff with them.
Speaker 3:  The, the jump that I'm curious about, right? 'cause now Meta AI is
Speaker 3:  more conversational. It can remember things. It can, they've added some capability
Speaker 3:  to it. That's all running in their
Speaker 3:  cloud still. Right? Like you talk to the glasses, it talks to your
Speaker 3:  phone, it uses your phone's connection.
Speaker 7:  They've got a decent amount that's on device now.
Speaker 3:  On the glasses on device. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Because they're, they're doing with llama these super fine tuned distilled
Speaker 7:  models. So the latency on these is like pretty incredible
Speaker 7:  in terms of how quick the AI is. It's not humane pin. Wait a minute to
Speaker 7:  set a timer. Yeah. It's like answer something in like
Speaker 7:  a second. Right. Or like, tell me what's in this photo and it does
Speaker 7:  it in a couple seconds. And I got the demo of the new
Speaker 7:  AI stuff that they're adding to the Ray bands. So did Kylie, so did Jay.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, wow, okay. They're, they're understanding this form factor
Speaker 7:  and what's unique about it. So being able to like look at a phone number
Speaker 7:  and say, call that phone number and it just calls it and the call comes in
Speaker 7:  on your glasses because it's paired to your phone or scan that QR
Speaker 7:  code like you're looking at a menu, the webpage for the menu just gets
Speaker 7:  sent to your phone. Like breaking down some of the
Speaker 7:  interactions you would do with a phone that require extra steps and like,
Speaker 7:  just like taking a step away is like an kind of an aha
Speaker 7:  moment when you do it. You're like, oh, like this is where it's going.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it's the first time that I feel like AI makes
Speaker 7:  sense in a wearable And did, did
Speaker 7:  you guys watch the keynote in the live translation demo that Zuck did? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  that's
Speaker 3:  When he brought the MMA fighter. Yeah. Yeah. He said yell some words at me
Speaker 3:  in Spanish. That is
Speaker 7:  Wild. That is wild. That is like, that is like Putin's earpiece
Speaker 7:  on stage like at scale, you know, for like anyone.
Speaker 7:  and it works. And
Speaker 5:  I mean it was a thing like Google promised a couple of years ago, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think that the really interesting part of this is these
Speaker 3:  ideas are all just the ideas. Like these are the demos
Speaker 3:  we have been hearing about or promised for a decade if not more,
Speaker 3:  right. Live translation. Like Apple has live translation on your iPhone.
Speaker 3:  You should open the app and it'll do it. Google can do it. It's the form
Speaker 3:  factor like you're saying Alex that like, okay we've put this in glasses,
Speaker 3:  your phone is away, there's no screen, there's just an ambient
Speaker 3:  computer. Another thing that has been promised for a billion years and it's
Speaker 3:  just paying attention and helping you out as you go through your day. Does
Speaker 3:  that ambient computer require sending an awful lot of data to Meta? It
Speaker 3:  sure does, right? It just really, really does. But that's the
Speaker 3:  trade off all the way down to one day. I'm guessing Orion will have
Speaker 3:  my dream feature, which is I will look at someone and it will tell me their
Speaker 3:  name. Yes. And that will absolutely require Meta searching.
Speaker 3:  Its gigantic worldwide surveillance database of names and faces,
Speaker 3:  but like they're gonna build, that's the technical
Speaker 7:  Name. I was waiting for you to bring this up in my Orion demo.
Speaker 7:  The VP of wearables at Meta said we're excited
Speaker 7:  about name tags. Yeah it
Speaker 3:  Is. It's it is the feature If. you can do name tags, it doesn't matter. I
Speaker 3:  will wear the backpack. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 3:  Like all day long. Everybody
Speaker 5:  At CES. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I wanna double click on what you said, like that the phones have live translation.
Speaker 7:  Because I think this is important when we're talking about like these form
Speaker 7:  factors. Yes they do. Like, especially iOS 18, it's really easy to just do
Speaker 7:  like live language translation from the action button and from the action
Speaker 7:  button. There's something about not having your phone out though
Speaker 7:  that feels like, oh I would actually use this. I like think about like talking
Speaker 7:  to someone in another language and holding your phone between you. It's
Speaker 7:  like an interview. Like it's just awkward, but it's like, oh wait, when this
Speaker 7:  isn't a form factor where like they can't even hear that what they're saying
Speaker 7:  is being translated to me in my language and I'm not even pulling a device
Speaker 7:  out. Like all of a sudden these features make sense as like something
Speaker 7:  you would use in the world. And I think that's what these mean, like these,
Speaker 7:  it's like taking all these concepts and like putting in a device that like,
Speaker 7:  oh, like you'd actually do this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause they are cuter than the pixel buds. They're no disrespect,
Speaker 3:  They're Well, so here these are, they're just, again the ideas,
Speaker 3:  the end state, the goals very familiar. Everybody
Speaker 3:  shares them. The demos as described very familiar.
Speaker 3:  Everybody has the same ones. It's really down to
Speaker 3:  where is the form factor? How fast can we get there? Can we ship it at scale?
Speaker 3:  Are the phone makers, the operating system vendors gonna get in our way?
Speaker 3:  Which is a big deal. And you're kind of like, okay, well the closest Apple
Speaker 3:  is fundamentally is AirPods. Yeah. Right. Like
Speaker 3:  fundamentally the closest they are to this kind of idea is AirPods or they
Speaker 3:  haven't put glasses on their face yet. They have an Apple watch but doesn't
Speaker 3:  really do any AR stuff. Yeah. They have pinchy pinch. You can, you
Speaker 5:  Can do, I mean honestly, every
Speaker 3:  Time time you tap away with an Apple watch,
Speaker 5:  I wear my Meta ray bands. The, the number one feeling I have is, boy I
Speaker 5:  wish this actually tied in with my phone. Yeah. So, I could use Siri because
Speaker 5:  then I would have access to all my stuff.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Siri could just like, you know, like text the wrong person at
Speaker 7:  any point
Speaker 5:  I could just play my music because
Speaker 3:  I don't, okay. So that's that. So it's AirPods for Apple, it, it Alex you
Speaker 3:  were just bringing up the pixel buds. Yeah, that is Google's. Although does
Speaker 3:  Google remember that it made the pixel buds and it made,
Speaker 5:  It made the pixel buds too, which
Speaker 3:  Sure Neli.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The review came up the same time. Yeah. The metal event.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So Neli AirPods, great example with my AirPods. I can say, Hey
Speaker 7:  remind me about whatever. I can say whatever I want it to remind me about
Speaker 7:  at a certain time. Right. And I'll get the notification and the reminders
Speaker 7:  app with the Ray bands you can say, Hey look at this and remind me about
Speaker 7:  it at whatever time. Right?
Speaker 3:  'cause it can
Speaker 7:  See, yeah, that's like, that's wildly useful to me. I
Speaker 7:  cannot tell you how many times throughout the day. I just wanna have a snapshot
Speaker 7:  of whatever I'm looking at and go back to it later. And like those
Speaker 7:  ideas, because you had literally have a camera on your face. You can't do
Speaker 7:  that with AirPods. And so you're right, like the closest we have are these
Speaker 7:  earbuds that are internet connected and can hear our voice. There's
Speaker 7:  something about adding the cameras though. That's
Speaker 3:  Big. So you know the the prevailing theory of why the camera control
Speaker 3:  button is not just on the pro phone but also on the regular 16 is that Apple
Speaker 3:  add visual intelligence and then you'll be able to quickly access the camera
Speaker 3:  and look at stuff and Well,
Speaker 6:  When, when you say theory, you mean Apple just said that out loud in that
Speaker 6:  Benet words,
Speaker 3:  Well they haven't shipped yet, is vapor till ships. Like,
Speaker 6:  No, but I mean that is, it's, whether it's good or not is a question, but
Speaker 6:  like that is, that is clearly that is half the purpose of the thing. Like
Speaker 6:  they have just said as much
Speaker 3:  At this point, my theory, like whether Apple has its own unified
Speaker 3:  theory of what it's doing. It's like sure, I've used control center
Speaker 3:  and iOS a t enough to be like, did anybody pay attention to this?
Speaker 3:  Like,
Speaker 6:  But also there are, there are increasingly convincing and well sourced rumors
Speaker 6:  about things like AirPods with a camera, which, what would that look like?
Speaker 6:  And an Apple watch with a camera because I, I agree with you Heath. Like
Speaker 6:  the the camera is the thing. Yeah, both. Both as the input and
Speaker 6:  as like the activity, right? Like I hear from people all the time for
Speaker 6:  whom the reason to have the smart glasses is to take pictures of your kids
Speaker 6:  like, or your pets or whoever. Like I'm convinced my dog knows when I take
Speaker 6:  out my phone to take a picture of her, I'm a hundred percent sure. And she
Speaker 6:  runs away and now she doesn't anymore. And I can take pictures of her. It's
Speaker 6:  awesome.
Speaker 3:  I can't wait to get these glasses. Did you buy the glasses too, David?
Speaker 6:  I already have two pairs. Okay. I don't have a great answer for why
Speaker 6:  I have two pairs.
Speaker 3:  What do you have like the large size or the small size? 'cause If you don't
Speaker 3:  need the large size. I'm in the market.
Speaker 6:  I have, I don't know. I I also have a big head. So We'll, we'll, we'll have
Speaker 6:  to figure this out together.
Speaker 3:  Alex, how big do you think David said is, what do you think? 49 50?
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna guess he's like a 48, 47.
Speaker 6:  Neil has like a 65. Yeah, I'm saying
Speaker 3:  Bigger than better. I, it's not insulting to me. 80. Let's go the big the
Speaker 3:  better.
Speaker 3:  All right, let's we we this, so we talked a lot about the Meta stuff. I wanna
Speaker 3:  make sure we talk about two other pieces of Meta Connect that are
Speaker 3:  important and then spend a little time in OpenAI before we
Speaker 3:  go to light around. The other piece of Meta Connect that I think is deeply
Speaker 3:  fascinating is you guys did talk about AI a lot and
Speaker 3:  how it'll be expressed. It seems like they're chasing a big distribution
Speaker 3:  advantage with glasses that maybe other people will catch up to. But then
Speaker 3:  there's like training data and open source models.
Speaker 3:  Zuckerberg said, and I think this is one of the shots at Google, like I think
Speaker 3:  all of the, we're doing live demos. We shots at Apple for doing infomercials.
Speaker 3:  I think when he says things like we are the Linux of open source
Speaker 3:  because llama's like that's a shot at Google, right? Yeah. We're just gonna
Speaker 3:  have more distribution, we're gonna have more development, we're gonna be
Speaker 3:  better at everybody else. Be is open always piece closed, which is usually
Speaker 3:  Google's model. And that's just not how Google's doing it.
Speaker 3:  They had to suck up a lot of training data and you asked about people wanting
Speaker 3:  to opt out. There's all the celebrities on Instagram right now
Speaker 3:  saying, opt me out of this. His answer, explain his answer
Speaker 3:  and then we, we should talk about it a little bit 'cause it was really interesting.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, he said the quiet part out loud, which is that
Speaker 7:  everyone thinks their data is more valuable than it actually is for these
Speaker 7:  models In aggregate it's valuable. But
Speaker 7:  when you're some, when you're a company like Meta and it's like the entire
Speaker 7:  world is your corpus of information in the internet at large.
Speaker 7:  What exactly do you have to have? And I think, you know,
Speaker 7:  we were talking a lot about publishers and about how Meta has basically thrown
Speaker 7:  its hands up on news and you know, Rupert Murdoch is in Australia
Speaker 7:  saying pay me or I'm gonna take your news off and Zuckerberg's like fine,
Speaker 7:  like whatever. Like people don't even like this.
Speaker 7:  So we, we were talking a lot about publishers but I think he's
Speaker 7:  kind of just saying that look like yes, you
Speaker 7:  know, people have feelings about their data being
Speaker 7:  used to train these models
Speaker 7:  and yes we're all doing it but we also like
Speaker 7:  If you, you know, If, you don't like it like go away. Like
Speaker 7:  whatever. It's like it's, so it's
Speaker 3:  Really interesting to me about this is that's the line to the publishers.
Speaker 3:  Like we will deran your news and we won't have news on threads. However you
Speaker 3:  want to interpret all of the many things Adam Saria said about that
Speaker 3:  there's no opt out for any user of these services unless you're in
Speaker 3:  the EU from having your stuff trained on.
Speaker 7:  And guess where Meta AI is not available in the eu.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. And so, and he did say I remain what eternally
Speaker 3:  confident that we'll launch this in the eu, something like that on stage.
Speaker 3:  But there's just, I would just draw a connection. It, I think it is very
Speaker 3:  funny to dunk on people posting what amounts to chain letters
Speaker 3:  on their Instagram stories being like, dear Zuckerberg, by the
Speaker 3:  statute of Rome, I command you from not,
Speaker 7:  We were doing this on our Facebook walls like 15 years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This keeps happening.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is a chain letter. Like that's what it is. Yeah. And it's like
Speaker 3:  people think the law is magic words, you know, If, you just like
Speaker 3:  issue an incantation to the internet. Like someone has to do what you say
Speaker 3:  and it's like
Speaker 5:  Usually chain letters have a lot more like promising death than then than
Speaker 5:  these. Yeah. Yeah. And I really miss that. I wish if it was like send this
Speaker 5:  to 12 of your friends or Zuckerberg will appear in your house in his Latin
Speaker 5:  shirt and beat the shit outta you, that would be great.
Speaker 3:  Have you ever fallen down the hole of courtroom video? So people
Speaker 3:  invoking the sovereign citizen defense. Oh Lord, yes. In like local courtrooms
Speaker 3:  and
Speaker 5:  Then they're like,
Speaker 3:  Shut up. And the judges are like that, that doesn't mean anything. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 5:  You're going to jail.
Speaker 3:  Shh. They're like by what authority? And the judges always like, because
Speaker 3:  I'm the judge and it is just like that, that's happening on in. and it is
Speaker 3:  very funny.
Speaker 6:  It's Michael Scott on the office yelling, I declare bankruptcy. It is. Exactly.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 6:  Then somebody pulls 'em aside and says that's nothing. And he goes, I didn't
Speaker 6:  say it, I declared it. That's what these people are doing.
Speaker 3:  So it is very funny. And I and Tom Brady, who has a Meta
Speaker 3:  deal to use his face for a chatbot has done it. He did. He did.
Speaker 3:  He did it. He did. They killed, they canceled the deal because that idea
Speaker 3:  was bad. Yeah. And they came up with a better idea of what if we just used
Speaker 3:  the celebrities voices and said they were the celebrities instead of pretending
Speaker 3:  they were other characters. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It was Tom Brady as like Barry your workout partner or something.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it was very confus confusing. Not great, but it was his face. And then
Speaker 3:  Kristen Bell, you can just chat with Kristen Bell. She put up one of these
Speaker 3:  that Kylie noticed 'cause she's Kristen Bell fan. And so she's like, you
Speaker 3:  have a deal with Meta AI and you have an Instagram post saying don't use
Speaker 3:  my stuff for Meta AI
Speaker 7:  Ship sales. Well that was before she saw the zeros on the check.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Money, money is cool.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They're paying for these celebrity voices,
Speaker 3:  Great reporting, paying, paying millions of dollars for the rest of us. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So here's what I will just say about that thing. The
Speaker 3:  idea that you can negotiate with Meta feels
Speaker 3:  intuitive to everyone, right? Or any platform.
Speaker 3:  I'm posting my stuff here, I should be able to tell you how I want you to
Speaker 3:  use it, but you don't. And the answer is, well you already signed the terms
Speaker 3:  of service and you go away. You didn't, but everyone knows nobody reads that
Speaker 3:  shit
Speaker 3:  when half of your users are like collectively
Speaker 3:  trying to renegotiate the terms of their agreement with you.
Speaker 3:  That means there's a problem. Like kind
Speaker 7:  Of they're doing it on your platform though, that's the thing. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 7:  well
Speaker 3:  That's fine, but like you can't, there's, there's so other
Speaker 3:  things in the world where like you don't get to
Speaker 3:  negotiate on this level except for weird internet terms of service that
Speaker 3:  everyone agrees. No one reads, right? Like and I would just say
Speaker 3:  like If, you are one of the many, many, many young staffers
Speaker 3:  in DC who listens to the show, which is a weird audience that we have. And
Speaker 3:  I love you. I'm glad that we're making the commute to your basement office
Speaker 3:  in the capitol better. You should look at all the people
Speaker 3:  posting. I don't want you to train on my data on Meta's
Speaker 3:  own platform and the basic response of, yeah, go fuck
Speaker 3:  yourself and be like, oh this is actually what regulations are for,
Speaker 3:  right? Like the people are expressing that they do not like that
Speaker 3:  the terms of this arrangement are not in their favor
Speaker 3:  and no one is an individual has enough power
Speaker 3:  to change it. And Mark Zuckerberg is like everyone overvalues the,
Speaker 3:  their work in this context, So I don't have to pay attention to it. Like
Speaker 3:  that is actually the problem that like, it doesn't matter if you're a
Speaker 3:  Republican or a Democrat or a libertarian or whatever. That thing is
Speaker 3:  the problem that governments are meant to equalize.
Speaker 7:  How is this any different from using data for ad targeting? Think about when
Speaker 7:  we copy and pasted protest messages on Facebook 15 years ago, what was it
Speaker 7:  about? It was,
Speaker 3:  I'm I'm putting this all in the same line, right? This is all the same line
Speaker 3:  of thing. My point is when everyone is like, I signed this agreement, I didn't
Speaker 3:  read it right and now I've handed over whatever leverage I might have had
Speaker 3:  because I signed this agreement that I didn't read. And the second I'm made
Speaker 3:  aware that I that by saying abracadabra,
Speaker 3:  this is like go back in my favor, I will just happily start yelling
Speaker 3:  abracadabra as loudly as I can. Like that is, that's the
Speaker 3:  problem.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But that's also just like no one reads EULAs and that's that's
Speaker 3:  But like, so who should read the EULA for you? Should we all hire and you
Speaker 3:  can't do ai? And then, and then what are you, do you, do you have bargaining
Speaker 3:  power If you disagree with the terms? No. If the uses
Speaker 3:  it's terms of service and ships it to you, are you like, you know, Tim,
Speaker 3:  paragraph five, a couple of notes. Are you
Speaker 7:  Saying that social media needs to unionize?
Speaker 3:  I am saying terms of service agreements should be illegal like flatly
Speaker 3:  because there are con Kristen Bell for president, they are contracts. No
Speaker 3:  one reads and it's these moments. I I just have a lot of empathy.
Speaker 3:  I have written the, don't believe the Instagram
Speaker 3:  meme story five times in my career. Yeah. And one time I got a call
Speaker 3:  from Instagram, they're like, thank you so much. And I was like, I I don't
Speaker 3:  like this because it happens over and over again for a
Speaker 3:  reason, which is whenever you offer somebody back the
Speaker 3:  mechanism of control over their own information, they're like, yeah, I'd
Speaker 3:  like that back please. Yeah. It universally, yep. And
Speaker 3:  no one reads the agreements. The the agreements change all the time. The
Speaker 3:  agreements always change in, in favor of the platform using your data for
Speaker 3:  more and more and more things. And then you get Zuckerberg saying, everyone
Speaker 3:  overestimates the value of their individual data. And it's like, who, how,
Speaker 3:  what is the mechanism that you would ba rebalance this equation with?
Speaker 3:  There isn't one.
Speaker 7:  There isn't one. And I think Zuckerberg's also thinking, yeah, guess what?
Speaker 7:  You're using Instagram and you're gonna keep using
Speaker 5:  Instagram. Well he's not incentivized to say actually yeah we
Speaker 3:  Should deliver more value to you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like he doesn't care. He's like, yeah, give me all of your data for
Speaker 5:  free. So I can make lots of money and afford my cool shirts. Like of course
Speaker 5:  he is. Look,
Speaker 3:  I'm not saying we all shouldn't dunk on a bunch of people posting advocate
Speaker 3:  AB to Instagram. Like we absolutely should. We should abs It
Speaker 3:  is one of the funniest repeat memes that can possibly exist
Speaker 3:  is people basically doing sovereign citizen on Instagram. Like very
Speaker 3:  funny. But If, you just, I'm just tr one step back from a place of empathy.
Speaker 3:  It's a bunch of people communicating that they don't like the terms of the
Speaker 3:  agreement and there's no mechanism to channel that into any change.
Speaker 3:  That agreement is not changing.
Speaker 7:  I fully agree with you and I, that's how I frame it to him. I'm like, do
Speaker 7:  you sympathize with this icky feeling people have about this trade off and
Speaker 7:  the sense that value is not flowing back to them? And he said the thing about
Speaker 7:  how everyone overvalues their data.
Speaker 3:  Well
Speaker 7:  There's also a sense of yeah, If, you feel this way, stop using the product.
Speaker 7:  We were doing this about ad targeting and our data being used for
Speaker 7:  ad targeting 15 years ago and copy paste messages on
Speaker 7:  Facebook. Everyone's still using, well not everyone, 3 billion people
Speaker 7:  apparently are still on Facebook. So for them it's
Speaker 7:  like the platforms, they don't see any data
Speaker 7:  to suggest that this value exchange is actually unfair because in their mind
Speaker 7:  we would stop using the services. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that just presumes that people have that power and and what do you mean
Speaker 5:  can afford
Speaker 7:  To do that? You can delete Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I would say these things are businesses for a lot of people, right?
Speaker 5:  Like this is a way they advertise their businesses. Sure. This is a way they,
Speaker 5:  they advertise themselves if, if they're influencers. Like,
Speaker 7:  But like most people in the vers newsroom are no longer posting on X.
Speaker 7:  Like people can make decisions about that. People can
Speaker 5:  On people. And I think even when
Speaker 7:  They have career implications,
Speaker 5:  I think there's also a lot of journalists who are still on XI mean, I think
Speaker 5:  there is a power imbalance there that, that neli is speaking to of like,
Speaker 5:  these people have no power in this relationship. It is gone. It is If.
Speaker 5:  you wanna use this, suck it up. And I think people slowly get tired of that,
Speaker 3:  Right? I think, I think it's just that there are very few other
Speaker 3:  relationships you have If you are a creator and creators
Speaker 3:  are mostly just business people at this point. Yeah. They're all running
Speaker 3:  content businesses on the terms of the platforms. If you're a celebrity,
Speaker 3:  you're just a content business on the platform. Which is why I think the
Speaker 3:  celebrities are so fast to be like, don't use my stuff. Like they know they
Speaker 3:  do not want their voice and likeness to use without payment. And I'm just,
Speaker 3:  all I'm saying is from a place of empathy, one step back, there's no
Speaker 3:  mechanism to channel this frustration into anything. And
Speaker 3:  that is actually like, again, it's, I I I don't think you have to be very
Speaker 3:  political on either side of the spectrum to be like, oh this is actually
Speaker 3:  the thing we should, this is what it's for. Right? Like a lot of people,
Speaker 3:  like most people on the society would like to renegotiate the terms of their
Speaker 3:  agreement with the large platforms that is called the privacy law,
Speaker 3:  right? Where we're just gonna reset the floor of the agreement. A lot of
Speaker 3:  people wanna reset the terms of how train, how their content can be used
Speaker 3:  for training. That's just a AI training law like
Speaker 3:  that it's just very simple and like, I don't know what those laws should
Speaker 3:  do or how they should read or whether you are a
Speaker 3:  conservative and you think the answer is like, I don't know, some
Speaker 3:  weird public private partnership that the Heritage Foundation runs. Like
Speaker 3:  tho those are those ideas. Or you're a hardcore liberal and you're like,
Speaker 3:  I will start a government commission and we will, the government will set
Speaker 3:  the rates, which is what we do in copyright law. Like there's a million solutions
Speaker 3:  to this. I don't think that's a very liberal solution. Copper, I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  there are government entities that set rates in other parts of this world.
Speaker 3:  But it's just, I would just point like we're talking about AI and
Speaker 3:  distributing it and who has the power, where the models run and how powerful
Speaker 3:  the, the experiences can be that you had Alex and
Speaker 3:  underneath it all is like, Hey, did do all of these people
Speaker 3:  feel ripped off? Like is that, is that okay? And like
Speaker 3:  Zuckerberg's answer is Zuckerberg's answer. I asked Sundar Phai this about
Speaker 3:  YouTube I in the same kind of framework of a question, how do you feel about
Speaker 3:  open AI training on YouTube? And he was like, I think that would be inappropriate.
Speaker 3:  And it's like, do you understand why all of your creators think that's
Speaker 3:  inappropriate? And he just like sided me and I, I suspect something
Speaker 3:  else is gonna happen there. Like some set of lawsuits
Speaker 3:  or some Scarlet Johansson open AI situation
Speaker 3:  where it just becomes less and less tenable to be this this
Speaker 3:  Blythe about it. I we,
Speaker 6:  We should get off this point 'cause we could do this for hours and we'll
Speaker 6:  end up talking about the Fedi verse and it'll be a whole thing. Oh my God,
Speaker 3:  Let's do it. But
Speaker 6:  The thing is no one has any reason to believe that
Speaker 6:  any of what you just said is true. And what's actually happening is everybody
Speaker 6:  is now saying the quiet part out loud. Eric Schmidt is out here being like,
Speaker 6:  oh you want data from the internet? Just steal it. Mustafa Suleman was like,
Speaker 6:  oh it's all free. It's on the internet. You can just have it. Like this is
Speaker 6:  what everybody thinks and there has been absolutely nothing
Speaker 6:  to convince them otherwise so far. So if I'm Mark Zuckerberg, why I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  look around and be like, oh I'm gonna be the good guy here and it's gonna
Speaker 6:  cost me in this race to AI that is suddenly the only thing anyone
Speaker 6:  cares about. Like no, of course he's not gonna do that. Right? He's gonna
Speaker 6:  say, oh you like Instagram, keep using Instagram.
Speaker 3:  We, we can do this for another hour. But also his new attitude, which is
Speaker 3:  like, I no longer apologize for everything. Apologizing was a 20 year mistake
Speaker 3:  that I'm not gonna make anymore.
Speaker 11:  No
Speaker 3:  Dude, you grow the hair out, you get a little older, you know, like I'm thinking
Speaker 3:  about growing my hair out. I watched that interview, I was like, oh I could,
Speaker 3:  I could get the, is it the cauliflower hair? Is that what they call it? Look
Speaker 3:  when every, every 12-year-old and boy is gifted a gold chain and you have
Speaker 3:  to make a decision. And I made one decision and I'm saying I could remake
Speaker 3:  that decision. You could.
Speaker 7:  The hair is getting long. You could, yeah. I feel like you're like you're
Speaker 7:  a few months away from curls.
Speaker 3:  Oh this hair is very curly. I could tomorrow we're not talking about this
Speaker 3:  right now. We are changing the subject. Mila's hair is so French and we need
Speaker 3:  to go to a break. Yeah, yeah. Can we just before we go to break, I do wanna
Speaker 3:  talk about OpenAI. Oh yeah it it God seems
Speaker 3:  like chaos over there. What is going on over there? Alex,
Speaker 7:  Did you guys know that OpenAI is a nonprofit?
Speaker 3:  Do they know that?
Speaker 7:  I'm not sure they do. I think they're finding out and that's what's going
Speaker 7:  on honestly like at a very high level.
Speaker 3:  But everyone's leaving like Mira Dy, the CTO is leaving Greg
Speaker 3:  Brockman, the president just apparently just vanished.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there's this great photo of all of the like execs,
Speaker 7:  Aliyah, Greg, Mira and Sam together for this big New York Times
Speaker 7:  profile. This was like right before the boardroom boardroom coup, which Neli
Speaker 7:  was almost a year ago when you were at Disney. No way. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Isn't that crazy? You were at Disney not getting to ride the rides
Speaker 7:  almost a year ago. 'cause we were reporting on this, which is yeah nuts to
Speaker 7:  me. But there's this photo of him and all these execs and now they've just
Speaker 7:  photoshopped out everyone except Sam Altman who's the only one left. And
Speaker 7:  what's happening is that OpenAI just raised the largest round of funding
Speaker 7:  of all time. I think they just went above Elon's mega round for Xai
Speaker 7:  which was I think 6 billion on purpose. Of course optics,
Speaker 7:  they're valued at $150 billion, which is more than the market cap of Goldman
Speaker 7:  Sachs. Guess what? OpenAI is legally still a nonprofit.
Speaker 7:  They get tax breaks in the state of
Speaker 7:  California as a nonprofit. They make billions of dollars
Speaker 7:  a year. And so what's happening is this very chaotic fast
Speaker 7:  transition from what was a
Speaker 7:  research lab. We're gonna invent a GI all the IUs stuff
Speaker 7:  to in the last year when Sam won the board coup,
Speaker 7:  no we are a large commercial for-profit
Speaker 7:  next big mega tech company and they hired A CFO,
Speaker 7:  they hired a CPO who used to run product at Instagram, not the
Speaker 7:  other one who used to run product at Instagram. He's philanthropic and
Speaker 7:  they're very chaotically turning into a real big company.
Speaker 7:  And I think what you're seeing is a lot of the previous era
Speaker 7:  being abruptly managed out quitting
Speaker 7:  what have you and it's the Altman show and he
Speaker 7:  famously does not have equity in OpenAI has been doing a ton
Speaker 7:  of interesting dealings with other startups and investments
Speaker 7:  around OpenAI. It is now reportedly gonna be getting a large stake
Speaker 7:  in this new for-profit company that they're creating. I
Speaker 7:  will love to see how, what the tax implications are of this transition
Speaker 7:  more to come on that. And the state of California really
Speaker 7:  doesn't like when nonprofits become for-profits. It's a very, very
Speaker 7:  contested thing and yeah, I think that's what's happening
Speaker 7:  at high level. So Mira, the CTO is out who was
Speaker 7:  MeMed with her reaction to, did you use YouTube to train Sora? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  They were very unhappy about that from what I understand.
Speaker 7:  And then they're head of research who literally just did an interview about
Speaker 7:  the new reasoning model with Kylie a couple weeks ago
Speaker 7:  who won out against Ilya in the research kind of group battle a
Speaker 7:  year ago. So yeah, it's just like stuff's happening very fast and yeah big
Speaker 7:  picture. This is open AI entering a decidedly commercial
Speaker 7:  big tech company phase. They are speed running.
Speaker 5:  Should that be terrifying for us given that they were supposed to be the
Speaker 5:  safeguards of ai?
Speaker 7:  Well yeah, now Eli is doing, Ilia is doing super safe
Speaker 7:  whatever ai, so it's gonna be super safe.
Speaker 5:  But you didn't have the money raised
Speaker 3:  Billion. He raised a bunch of money. Yeah
Speaker 7:  He raised a bunch of money but not
Speaker 3:  As much. No, not as, yeah
Speaker 7:  Not as much. But
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. We are so over.
Speaker 3:  We are often asked how long the show is supposed to be and the answer is
Speaker 3:  not this long. Six and a half minutes but we're never gonna tell you how
Speaker 3:  long it's supposed
Speaker 5:  To be. Actually a 92nd show.
Speaker 3:  We've gotten some incoming lightning around sponsorships. Again, I don't
Speaker 3:  make the deals, I just walk around Vox Media demanding why the deals aren't
Speaker 3:  made, which has proven to be ineffective. So
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna try some new strategies. But today we remain unsponsored,
Speaker 3:  which is a personal failure. I, for somebody who complains
Speaker 3:  about creator like influence and brand deals as much as I do, I'm horrible
Speaker 3:  at this. I should makes that money anyway. The lightning round is available
Speaker 3:  to sponsor I I might say your company's name, If. you give us a bunch
Speaker 3:  of money or I might not because of ethics policy you won't know until you
Speaker 3:  pay me money. That's lightning round. All right Alex, let's start with you
Speaker 3:  'cause I think you've, you've got the most relevant lightning round item
Speaker 3:  after that previous conversation.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Trip Mickel, the New York Times has this great story about what
Speaker 7:  Johnny Ive has been up to post Apple and this design firm he founded
Speaker 7:  called Love from lots of nuggets in here. I thought it was very
Speaker 7:  interesting that he says in the story he interviewed I in June
Speaker 7:  and this came out the week of iPhone 16.
Speaker 7:  The timing was interesting
Speaker 7:  but yeah, Johnny's, he's working, I think the Time's kind of buried the lead
Speaker 7:  here. He's
Speaker 3:  Literally, it's like the last paragraph of the story. Yeah, it's very, very
Speaker 3:  end.
Speaker 7:  He confirms that he's working on some kind of AI device with open ai. It
Speaker 7:  sounds like they haven't quite nailed down what it will be. It was the first
Speaker 7:  time he confirmed it on the record. My understanding is that love from
Speaker 7:  is super small. It's like 40 ish, 50 people and there's
Speaker 7:  only
Speaker 5:  10 people working on this project I
Speaker 7:  Think. Yeah. And a wild detail in this story is is
Speaker 7:  as Mr Ive climbed a wooden staircase to the studio second floor that morning.
Speaker 7:  And by the way he bought like a whole block, a city block of downtown San
Speaker 7:  Francisco for their office.
Speaker 7:  He said he spoke about love firm's clients love firm's clients which
Speaker 7:  pay the firm as much as $200 million annually. That's very
Speaker 7:  good. And that includes like Airbnb, Ferrari, he just designed a
Speaker 7:  $3,000 Ja jacket with Montclair Love firm is like
Speaker 7:  50 people. So how much money are they making
Speaker 3:  Johnny? Ive
Speaker 5:  Bought a whole block in San Francisco. Like they're doing good.
Speaker 7:  Brian Chesky is paying him $200 million a year to
Speaker 7:  like riff on what the Airbnb logo should
Speaker 3:  Be. Can I, can I just tell you a story about the Airbnb Johnny Ive connection?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which, because I was reading this and it says what he worked on, like
Speaker 3:  they did the experiences where you can like live in a pineapple house or
Speaker 3:  something. What whatever 200 million nonsense is happening. Right.
Speaker 3:  Airbnb last year, the year before after the
Speaker 3:  Johnny Ive stuff was out
Speaker 3:  like announced a bunch of redesign stuff and like an app redesign and all
Speaker 3:  this stuff and we emailed them and we're like, was this the stuff Johnny
Speaker 3:  I've worked on? Because obviously that is very relevant and interesting detail
Speaker 3:  and they're like yeah, yeah. And then we like publish and they like freaked
Speaker 3:  out at us and they're like, that's not wrong. Everyone's like take it down.
Speaker 3:  We're like, but you said okay and we like adjusted the story. You can like
Speaker 3:  read it. There's all these like back and forth corrections in it because
Speaker 3:  Airbnb's trying to clarify this and I was like, what is the point of Jo spending
Speaker 3:  all this money and Johnny I If you don't want say that he worked on this
Speaker 3:  stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's worth easily a hundred of the 200 million is just to be able
Speaker 6:  to put Johnny Ive in your press release,
Speaker 3:  Check out the new Airbnb app designed by Johnny Ive, I
Speaker 3:  dunno, Brian Chassis's coming on decoder in a little bit. I'm gonna ask you
Speaker 3:  about it in addition to talking about founder mode, which he's excited to
Speaker 3:  talk about but it's, I read this profile and I was like,
Speaker 3:  yeah we tried to write the story about him designing this
Speaker 3:  app and they were like not into it. They were like pushed back on this idea
Speaker 3:  that he had done it super
Speaker 7:  Hard. He's like the Wizard of Oz, he just needs to be in the background.
Speaker 7:  There's also a
Speaker 3:  Part did he, he, there's a part in the story that I loved where he designed
Speaker 3:  a steering wheel for like an EV Ferrari and he's like, he completely rethought
Speaker 3:  what a steering wheel should be. I'm like, it's a circle.
Speaker 7:  Oh he didn't do a yoke.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's definitely a circle. I've famously a car guy.
Speaker 3:  It's very good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, So I. Just think it's like Ive is clearly gearing up and I think
Speaker 7:  there's a lot of pressure on him if this AI device is gonna be
Speaker 7:  real, like that is a, that is your Johnny Ive like, this thing has to work.
Speaker 7:  It has to not be the humane pin. And he's, he's got Evans hanky who
Speaker 7:  succeeded him at Apple leading design at love from working on this device
Speaker 7:  with him. So it's, it's a bunch of OG apple people that invented all of
Speaker 7:  like the original Apple stuff with him. So that's a really
Speaker 7:  interesting situation to watch.
Speaker 6:  We've seen one company with a very similar description to that make
Speaker 6:  AI hardware and it didn't go super great so we'll we'll see.
Speaker 6:  Gosh.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You know like he doesn't have, for example, Apple's famed antenna team,
Speaker 3:  which once had to save his ass from his own designs
Speaker 3:  wireless product.
Speaker 6:  It'll be super thin. Whatever it is, you can, you can bet it will be thin
Speaker 3:  25 minutes of battery life.
Speaker 5:  Five.
Speaker 3:  I'm very curious. I mean he, after we just had this whole conversation about
Speaker 3:  Meta, they have all of the same pro, like Apple is not gonna give him hooks
Speaker 3:  into iOS
Speaker 3:  presumably. Or the reason that chat BT got announced
Speaker 3:  as integrated iOS A 18 is when this device comes out. Tim Cook can be like,
Speaker 3:  it's mine now.
Speaker 7:  I just have a feeling whatever it is, it's gonna be so deeply, deeply weird
Speaker 7:  that it's gonna be awesome. Like I have the longer, he's away from Apple,
Speaker 7:  he just is doing weirder and weirder stuff and so
Speaker 7:  some kind of AI device from him is like, yes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I I
Speaker 6:  Want it. Yeah. I'm excited about it. Yeah, I agree. It's gonna be insane
Speaker 6:  and I love
Speaker 5:  It. Altman probably isn't gonna be excited about it 'cause he wants something
Speaker 5:  that he can sell and make lots of money. What do
Speaker 7:  You mean he open AI's working with him?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I know but like, is that the guy you hire If, you wanna make something
Speaker 5:  really commercial and sell and make lots of money. I mean
Speaker 7:  You argue
Speaker 5:  Have 10 Johnny people on their
Speaker 7:  Staff already done okay with that. He's done.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah, he did
Speaker 3:  Great. He the iPhone, he made the
Speaker 7:  IPhone iPod, apple
Speaker 3:  IPod did decent.
Speaker 5:  This is a design firm. Decent.
Speaker 3:  That's true. Yeah. I will say there's a picture of him in that profile where
Speaker 3:  he's just holding his iPhone in like a regular blue apple rubber case.
Speaker 3:  And I'm like, that's not weird enough for Shaw. I've and my God. But he made
Speaker 3:  the iPhone, he puts his feet no gold Apple watch either. Gosh. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was upsetting. He put his feet on the couch. That was the part that got
Speaker 5:  me like these gorgeous white couches and he had his shoes on them.
Speaker 5:  I was like, oh
Speaker 3:  Hurts. He can just get new ones. All right. Yeah. Kranz, what's your lightning
Speaker 3:  around Adam?
Speaker 5:  Sean got a hands-on with the PS five pro and If. you like to
Speaker 5:  pixel peep. It's gonna rule. I do. It's it's apparently
Speaker 5:  it's, it, it, he, he says it really like lives up to the hype as far as
Speaker 5:  like things just look a lot clearer. They're a lot prettier. It's
Speaker 5:  awesome in that way, but also it is still so much
Speaker 5:  money and, and you can, there's a lot of photos
Speaker 5:  in his piece where you can go and look and try to see the differences.
Speaker 5:  and it is sort of like playing highlights as a kid. You can
Speaker 5:  see them, but you gotta, you gotta look for 'em. So I would say
Speaker 5:  If, you don't have a giant monitor that you sit like two feet
Speaker 5:  from, you're probably Okay. But otherwise this is cool.
Speaker 3:  I will say that I was in the queue to buy the, the PS
Speaker 3:  five Pro 30th anniversary edition. And then I forgot I was in the q and o,
Speaker 3:  my place in line.
Speaker 5:  The the one to really look at is in, and David Ma and me before
Speaker 5:  we recorded it, 'cause I pointed this out, is the ratchet and clank rift
Speaker 5:  apart. You can really see the ray tracing working. It's, it's, it's, it's
Speaker 5:  beautiful.
Speaker 6:  Thank God. I've always said that's the main thing missing from ratchet
Speaker 6:  and clank rift apart is is ray tracing. That's the thing.
Speaker 6:  Preventing me from enjoying ratchet and clink rift apart.
Speaker 3:  There's a very funny line in Sean's hands on where he, he notes that all
Speaker 3:  the controllers were wired so they couldn't get far away from the screen
Speaker 3:  and not see the ray tracing anymore. Yeah. Choice. It's beautiful.
Speaker 6:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 3:  Alright, David, what's, what's yours
Speaker 6:  While you're over here? Neil denigrating Google's headphones.
Speaker 6:  Chris Welch published our view of the Google Pixel Buds Pro two,
Speaker 6:  which is a name that I have never said correctly until just now. So I.
Speaker 5:  I'm very proud of you. They're
Speaker 6:  Awesome. They're, they're smaller. They sound better, they're a little more
Speaker 6:  expensive. Seem great. But the thing I just wanna point out is that
Speaker 6:  Google absolutely crushed this hardware cycle, like in a, in a way
Speaker 6:  that Google Yeah. Never has before. The, the TV streamer is great. The
Speaker 6:  buds are great, the watches is great, the phones are great. The foldable
Speaker 6:  phones are great. Like Google just like did the whole thing this year.
Speaker 6:  And that is sort of wild to me. Do
Speaker 3:  You think that's Rick Oslo now runs the whole thing? It's
Speaker 5:  Dieter, it's all here. It's
Speaker 6:  No, I think whatever.
Speaker 3:  And Dan, don't forget Dan. Yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  Dieter and Dan. They did it. Thank you guys.
Speaker 6:  I think there's a certain amount of this that is like that compound interest
Speaker 6:  phenomenon, right? It's just like, Google's been at this a while and like,
Speaker 6:  Hey Google, if you're listening, this is why it's good to stick
Speaker 6:  to things because you can make them better over time and then they're good
Speaker 6:  and people like them. Yeah. Like that's a concept. Try
Speaker 6:  it with other things. But at any rate, like what Google did
Speaker 6:  here is not like reinvent the wheel as it is prone to do all the time.
Speaker 6:  It just made all of its products better. and it did that a bunch of years
Speaker 6:  in a row. And I think that the thing Rick Oslo gets credit for
Speaker 6:  is he has, he has made a plan and stuck to it. Like I talked to him years
Speaker 6:  ago at the very beginning and I was like, why on earth would anyone believe
Speaker 6:  you that you're gonna care about this for a long time? And he's like, I you
Speaker 6:  shouldn't, I don't know why you would, but we are going to, like, we're we're,
Speaker 6:  we're bought into this. And this feels like the first time that Google is
Speaker 6:  like really, truly playing hardware offense
Speaker 6:  in like it's, it's up there with everybody. We gave the TV streamer a nine,
Speaker 6:  Chris gave the Pixel Buds Pro two a nine. Like these are some of the best
Speaker 6:  products you can buy in their class. And I don't think that has ever been
Speaker 6:  true of Google products before. Yeah. So. I. Just think that's very cool.
Speaker 3:  I haven't, I didn't put this in the iPhone review 'cause I, I think
Speaker 3:  it's unfair to say this until Apple Intelligence comes out and we can use
Speaker 3:  the features, but I spent a lot of time using a pixel line pro camera
Speaker 3:  stuff while I was doing that review to compare the cameras. And every time
Speaker 3:  I picked up a pixel, I was like, this phone is a lot more fun than iOS right
Speaker 3:  now. Yeah. Yeah. Like it's just like bursting with ideas. The chaotic,
Speaker 3:  weird clippy level ideas about what every
Speaker 6:  Time you breathe it's like Gemini.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Should be Gemini. Do you want a Gemini? It's, it's, it's, it's, it's,
Speaker 3:  it's a little nuts, but it's fun because it's just like
Speaker 3:  ideas, like new ideas for what a phone could do or should do or why it should
Speaker 3:  do anything at all. And Apple is like, all the icons are
Speaker 3:  brown. Huh? You've been asking for big
Speaker 3:  brown icons and now you can have 'em.
Speaker 3:  Can I just say one more thing about the iPhone and then I'll do my lighting
Speaker 3:  round item control center. Total
Speaker 3:  total chaos. Like a mess. And they should just let
Speaker 3:  me edit it on my Mac.
Speaker 6:  I feel that way about my home screen.
Speaker 3:  Let me, yeah, let me do the home screen and control center on my Mac. I know
Speaker 3:  you can do phone mirror and you click direct. No, no, no. I want like full
Speaker 3:  like old school Adobe PageMaker print layout,
Speaker 3:  you know, like all the tools, the mirror, the, the
Speaker 3:  rulers and just let, just, this is, we're we're past
Speaker 3:  being able to do this on the phone
Speaker 6:  Control center is like the, once you get it set up, it's pretty great. But
Speaker 6:  the thing is like, and I feel the same way about the home screen. Like if
Speaker 6:  I drag an icon somewhere into a page that is already largely
Speaker 6:  full of icons, it takes a, it takes a PhD to figure out where
Speaker 6:  all those icons are gonna go. Yeah. Yeah. Like it is, it is just a mystery
Speaker 6:  every single time
Speaker 3:  The fastest, most capable, most efficient processors
Speaker 3:  humankind has ever created. And it's like, I don't know what's going on with
Speaker 3:  these icons. Like too much for me man. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 3:  yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right Mila, what's yours? We
Speaker 3:  Have to end here because we've been talking about AI gadgets the
Speaker 3:  whole time. Only 5,000 people use the Rabbit R
Speaker 3:  one every day. According to c said, how many people own it? He gave
Speaker 3:  an interview at some conference and the number is 5,000 daily active users
Speaker 3:  of the rabbit. That's more than I thought.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I was like, I'm surprised that many people have found a good use for
Speaker 6:  the rabbit.
Speaker 3:  The other thing to note is If, you, you cannot recycle or resell a humane
Speaker 3:  AI pin, but you can just return it to the company for full price,
Speaker 6:  Which kudos good to that. Good for them. Send it back. That is the correct
Speaker 6:  thing to do. It's just my bad. Wait, I, I am curious. I've spent a lot of
Speaker 6:  time trying
Speaker 3:  To, so it's 5% of buyers. Five, 5,000 people is 5% of the rabbit R one buyers.
Speaker 6:  Well that's, that's a hundred thousand is the biggest number we heard. I
Speaker 6:  actually think it's probably true that more people bought it than that. That's
Speaker 6:  just the last number we heard. Is that higher or lower than you
Speaker 6:  would've guessed. Like reasonably knowing way higher that at least a hundred
Speaker 6:  thousand people bought the thing. Most people buy gadgets intending to use
Speaker 6:  them. You think 5,000 is is higher than you would've expected.
Speaker 3:  Do you use yours every
Speaker 6:  Day? No, it's sitting right here. The battery's been dead since, I dunno,
Speaker 6:  April.
Speaker 6:  I am gonna fire it back up though. Do
Speaker 3:  You podcast from like a pile of dead useless gadgets?
Speaker 6:  I do everything from a pile of dead useless gadgets. Yes. That's, that's
Speaker 6:  what my job is. I've lived my life. You know, everything you
Speaker 6:  can't see in this maybe fake background of mine, it's just a pile of dead
Speaker 6:  useless gadgets. It's
Speaker 3:  Just slowly swelling. Batterie. I
Speaker 6:  Also, I have the, the humane pin right here. Oh good. It's been, it's
Speaker 6:  been six months since these things came out. Almost. I believe it was
Speaker 6:  April 11th. We're a couple weeks away from the six month anniversary and
Speaker 6:  I promised when I did them that in six months I would come back. So God help
Speaker 6:  me. I have to fire these devices back up and see how it's going. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think, I think it's substantially higher than I expected. I expected the
Speaker 3:  people who work at the company to use this thing every day and everything
Speaker 3:  else. We'll see, I'll say
Speaker 6:  Daily is, daily is a lot. I think I is a lot. I would guess the number was
Speaker 6:  higher than this for like people who still turn it on sometimes. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  daily is a lot.
Speaker 3:  Jesse Lou, the C of Rabbit has told us he's
Speaker 3:  coming on decoder. I'll let you know when that happens, but he
Speaker 3:  is, he's, we are booked. I have the, the, it's on my calendar. I'm
Speaker 3:  dying to ask him questions. So let me know what your questions are and
Speaker 3:  we'll see if we can get some answers about the rabbit.
Speaker 6:  I will say too, rabbits credit, they have like continued to post through
Speaker 6:  it. Like they, they are not shy about the stuff they've been dealing with.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  No, he's out there. I mean he's obviously on a media tour, right? Yeah. He's
Speaker 3:  at this conference. He, he wants to be on decoder. We're, we're gonna do
Speaker 3:  it. I'm very curious like many of the things we talked about
Speaker 3:  with Meta, can you get past the phone operating system or do you have to
Speaker 3:  build your own hardware? Rabbit is an answer to that question. Yep. But then
Speaker 3:  you have to do all the rest of it. We'll see. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Alright. I we're way over. We gotta wrap this thing up. Does anybody else
Speaker 3:  have any last minute Zuckerberg style dunks on the whole
Speaker 3:  industry issue? No. All right. Let us know. You can get a hold of us.
Speaker 3:  There's quite a lot to talk about so we welcome your feedback. Leave us your
Speaker 3:  voicemails. You can send David a text to his rabbit R one I believe.
Speaker 3:  I'm
Speaker 6:  Trying to figure out
Speaker 12:  Vergecast everybody. We'll be back next week. Rock and roll.