# Transcript
ID: ebada7fc-2487-4f19-aebc-045a94565229
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1525801070238127863/-4763628833108192602/s93290-US-4714s-1731419117.mp3
Description: On today's show: sleep gadgets, AI DJs, and sneaky TVs. Victoria Song joins the show to talk about her experiences with the Eight Sleep mattress pad, the Oura Ring 4, and other sleep gadgets. Can you really measure your way to a better night of sleep? After that, Allison Johnson gives us her take on Spotify's AI DJ, and we wonder exactly how an AI tool is supposed to help us find and listen to music. Finally, Nilay Patel comes on to answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline about the Samsung Frame TVs — and how to figure out whether you need a TV at all.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Quantified REM
Speaker 2:  Cycles. I'm my friend David Pierce and I am playing
Speaker 2:  Batman AUM Shadow on the Quest three.
Speaker 2:  I tend to always have one game that I like to play on the Quest,
Speaker 2:  usually for just like 15 or 20 minutes at a time in between
Speaker 2:  meetings or at night just to kind of move around. I like this better than,
Speaker 2:  you know, sitting on the couch playing video games, even though frankly I
Speaker 2:  do a lot of that too. This at least kind of gets the blood going in a way
Speaker 2:  that I really like. For a long time it was super hot vr then it was
Speaker 2:  supernatural when I was feeling like exercise. Then there was a tennis
Speaker 2:  simulator that I got strangely into, but I kept hitting the ceiling
Speaker 2:  trying to do serves, so that didn't last. And now I'm playing AUM
Speaker 2:  shadow. I have loved all of the AUM games over the years. They're
Speaker 2:  like the perfect mix for me of lots to do, but pretty
Speaker 2:  straightforward and they don't require me to just wander aimlessly for hours.
Speaker 2:  Very much my kind of game. By the way, there's a decent chance you've heard
Speaker 2:  ads for this game on this podcast. I've gotten some
Speaker 2:  complaints from people who were like too many meta ads in a row and I can
Speaker 2:  only assume they're for ACOM shadow. So trust me, this is
Speaker 2:  not one of those ads. I'm happy to tell you all of the things I hate about
Speaker 2:  both this game and the quest in general, but this game's pretty
Speaker 2:  great. I'm having a nice time. Anyway, that is not what we're here to talk
Speaker 2:  about today. We are here to do two things on the show. First,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk to V Song about kind of a year of experiments
Speaker 2:  in Quantified sleep that she's been doing. She's tried some gadgets,
Speaker 2:  she's tried some more expensive gadgets, she's tried some really expensive
Speaker 2:  gadgets and we're gonna talk about whether any of them are
Speaker 2:  actually worth it and have made her sleep better. Then we're gonna talk to
Speaker 2:  Alison Johnson about the AI DJ on Spotify and what it means
Speaker 2:  to have a computer decide what is good and what you should listen
Speaker 2:  to. She wrote a really great piece about it. I have some thoughts. I actually
Speaker 2:  disagree with her in some ways, so we're gonna get into it. We also have
Speaker 2:  a question from the hotline to do lots of fun stuff coming up on this episode.
Speaker 2:  But first we'll get to that, but I have to go beat up some
Speaker 2:  bad guys on the streets of Gotham. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So we talk a lot on this show about the
Speaker 2:  idea of tracking yourself and using wearables
Speaker 2:  to get data about your biometrics and the whole idea of the quantified
Speaker 2:  self, which to be honest is a phrase that I really hate, but
Speaker 2:  it just means tracking something in order to be able to do it better.
Speaker 2:  The thing we don't talk about as much with that I think is sleep.
Speaker 2:  We talk a lot about exercise, we talk some about food and things like that
Speaker 2:  and all that stuff is good, but I think If, you wanted to make everyone's
Speaker 2:  lives better immediately. Getting everybody better sleep
Speaker 2:  would be the way. So V Song on our team has been testing
Speaker 2:  a bunch of sleep related gadgets. She's actually been doing this for a long
Speaker 2:  time, both as part of testing lots of wearables, but
Speaker 2:  also just because like the rest of us she'd like to get more sleep.
Speaker 2:  So I figured now would be a super fun time to have her on the show and talk
Speaker 2:  through all of this. She's tried some cheap stuff, she's tried some
Speaker 2:  absurdly expensive stuff and we're gonna see if any of it is actually worth
Speaker 2:  the money and actually helps you sleep. V song. Hello.
Speaker 4:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so a few weeks ago you were here on the show and I said
Speaker 2:  something about how I think sleep tracking is stupid. I don't think I said
Speaker 2:  those exact words, but I said something like those exact words and I would
Speaker 2:  say A surprising number of people have had feelings at
Speaker 2:  me about that feeling and have told me that I'm wrong. And
Speaker 2:  it turns out that you, without even telling me at
Speaker 2:  that moment when you could have told me, have been doing all kinds of interesting
Speaker 2:  sleep tracking research over the last several months, So I wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  it and I wanna talk especially about the, the thing
Speaker 2:  that you tried to do where you tried to convince people that it's not insane
Speaker 2:  to spend many thousands of dollars on your bed. But before we get to
Speaker 2:  all of that, I wanna talk about sleep maxing you.
Speaker 2:  You brought up in one of your recent stories, this thing that I find really
Speaker 2:  fascinating, which is that sleep tracking has become the
Speaker 2:  thing in a, in a way that I can't remember
Speaker 2:  this sort of quantified self trend being
Speaker 2:  mainstream quite like this maybe ever, or at least
Speaker 2:  since the like get 10,000 steps craze, right? Sort of took
Speaker 2:  over everybody. Like sleep is, it's such a thing, it's
Speaker 2:  having such a moment and I'm curious what you make
Speaker 2:  of that. Like how, why do you think sleep has gone viral in the way that
Speaker 2:  it has?
Speaker 4:  So, I think that we all feel a lot of existential dread
Speaker 4:  and there are so many things that are externally out of our control
Speaker 4:  at the same time, like you have a lot of really health conscious people at
Speaker 4:  this point in time. I attribute that in like my little bubble to
Speaker 4:  like all of these devices that Apple Samsung Google say will save your
Speaker 4:  life. And you know, these are things you can by and large control,
Speaker 4:  sleep, you know, talk to any doctor, they're gonna tell you get a
Speaker 4:  good night's worth of sleep, sleep, eat nutrient dense
Speaker 4:  foods, exercise. Every single health professional is gonna tell you
Speaker 4:  that If, you can master these three things, your life will be better. Like
Speaker 4:  they, you know, and I think that message really does kind
Speaker 4:  of just solidify when you hit your thirties and things
Speaker 4:  start creaking and you have disposable income and you
Speaker 4:  just realize, oh man, like sleep actually is pretty
Speaker 4:  important. These doctors, they're actually not lying. If my
Speaker 4:  sleep is bad, I feel bad. If my sleep is good, I feel good.
Speaker 4:  So it's a very easy way to just
Speaker 4:  dramatically improve the things that you can control. Like your anxiety will
Speaker 4:  go down If, you sleep well, your health will
Speaker 4:  improve. If, you sleep well, it'll be easier for you to lose weight. If,
Speaker 4:  you sleep well, it'll be easier for you to build muscle If, you sleep well,
Speaker 4:  it'll be easier for you to just do literally anything and have better mental
Speaker 4:  health. If, you sleep well. So, I think that's kind of where this
Speaker 4:  intensity around sleep maxing comes from. And you know, like what
Speaker 4:  is sleep maxing? Sleep maxing is literally just buying
Speaker 4:  several products to try and hack your sleep, right? So it's,
Speaker 4:  it's like really a convergence of late stage capitalism
Speaker 4:  and existential dread shaking hands like that meme in your
Speaker 4:  TikTok shop to tell you like If, you just do this one thing, you might
Speaker 4:  sleep a little bit better and feel better while you deal with a bunch
Speaker 4:  of other crap. And So I think that's honestly where it
Speaker 4:  comes from and they're not wrong is is the thing I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  say.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think it's true. I mean it, it strikes me as you explain those
Speaker 2:  three things that eat better, exercise more and sleep more essentially
Speaker 2:  sleep better is by far the least
Speaker 2:  costly of those three things. Like eating better is hard.
Speaker 2:  It like yes, all the tasty foods are bad for you. It's just,
Speaker 2:  it's just a fact of the universe.
Speaker 4:  It's hard. It's a thing I struggle with the most.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's more expensive, it's more complicated. Like it's very hard to
Speaker 2:  eat well, it's also hard to exercise a lot. It just
Speaker 2:  requires a lot of commitment and dedication and the opportunity cost is high
Speaker 2:  because I could be sitting on my couch watching television and I'm not
Speaker 2:  also
Speaker 4:  It's painful. Yeah, it sucks. It's painful. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And kudos to you who you get up and do it anyway.
Speaker 2:  Sleep has in theory none of those costs.
Speaker 2:  Like if I can, I'm going to lie in bed for eight hours at night
Speaker 2:  if I can make those eight hours more efficient, that is all upside,
Speaker 2:  right? Like it's the only one of those three that in that if getting
Speaker 2:  better sleep has zero downsides,
Speaker 4:  It's also enjoyable. Getting a good night's sleep is
Speaker 4:  really great. It's the most enjoyable of these three things that you can
Speaker 4:  fix your life,
Speaker 2:  Right? It would be one thing if like the activity of going to sleep really
Speaker 2:  sucked, but like going to sleep is great,
Speaker 4:  It's so good.
Speaker 2:  It's not like exercise that way where you feel really good at the end but
Speaker 2:  not during sleep is just awesome the whole time.
Speaker 4:  It's just great. The whole, like whenever you see someone going to bed and
Speaker 4:  they're sleeping you, so they're always like sleeping with a little smile
Speaker 4:  on their face, a sleeping baby, good vibes. And like you
Speaker 4:  look at insomniacs, they have bags under their eyes. They generally don't
Speaker 4:  look good. So like just culturally speaking, sleep is by far
Speaker 4:  the easiest thing you can do and it's, you know,
Speaker 4:  in terms of like effort put into results immediately seen,
Speaker 4:  you will immediately feel the effects of good sleep. Whereas you will not
Speaker 4:  immediately feel the effects of sticking to a nutritious diet or
Speaker 4:  exercising over a long period of time. Like those, those things are all
Speaker 4:  like I, you know, you should do them, they're gonna suck while you do them
Speaker 4:  and you have to have delayed gratification. There's none of that
Speaker 4:  complicatedness with sleep. Sleep instant gratification.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it'll feel good literally in hours and you won't have to
Speaker 4:  do anything at all.
Speaker 2:  It's pretty great. Yeah. So it seems like in in that
Speaker 2:  vein of trying to do better with sleep a, there's a lot of snake oil.
Speaker 2:  I mostly don't wanna talk about the snake oil, but I think by and large If
Speaker 2:  you see a thing on TikTok in the TikTok shop, you should assume it's nonsense.
Speaker 2:  I think that's true of everything definitely including sleep maxing
Speaker 4:  Mouth tape. I legitimately that makes me angry.
Speaker 4:  Mouth tape. Yeah. But yeah. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  We're just gonna leave that as aside. But it seems to me there are sort of
Speaker 2:  two separate things that the tech
Speaker 2:  industry has to figure out here. One is how to
Speaker 2:  successfully tell how you're sleeping, right? Like the, and
Speaker 2:  the sleep tracking thing has been happening for forever. The reason we were
Speaker 2:  talking about this a few weeks ago is we were talking about the Oura Ring,
Speaker 2:  like the idea of using some device or another to track
Speaker 2:  your sleep goes back a long ways. So I would assume
Speaker 2:  we're pretty good at that. Now are we pretty good at that now?
Speaker 4:  We are okay at that now. Okay. So what we are really
Speaker 4:  good at is telling when you go to sleep and when you wake
Speaker 4:  up the sleep stages, so like the REM sleep, the
Speaker 4:  deep sleep, the light sleep dubious,
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that stuff is really important.
Speaker 4:  That stuff is important. If, you wanna get more granular or if
Speaker 4:  you're having sleep problems and you're trying to self like figure out like
Speaker 4:  what's going on,
Speaker 4:  you know, so aura, they put a lot of research into it, but
Speaker 4:  even there only, like our algorithm is like, I think it's 70 to
Speaker 4:  80% in agreement with the gold standard,
Speaker 4:  which is polysomnography. And that's when you go into a little
Speaker 4:  clinic and they put stuff on you and you sleep there for a night and the
Speaker 4:  scientists watch you and measure your brainwaves. So that's the clinical
Speaker 4:  gold standard. And most consumer grade sleep trackers that are out there
Speaker 4:  on the market, we're at best we are getting around
Speaker 4:  70%, 70 to 80% in, in that range. Okay. So
Speaker 4:  you know, like eh, so we're, we're much better than we used to be. But
Speaker 4:  in the grand scheme of things, you do have to really take it as a
Speaker 4:  very unsatisfying, oh this is my baseline.
Speaker 4:  I probably will know when I have a crappy night of sleep. Yeah. Right?
Speaker 4:  But you can from that BA baseline view trends like, oh
Speaker 4:  you have a lot of breathing disturbances, maybe you have sleep
Speaker 4:  apnea and you should go to a doctor and maybe get
Speaker 4:  A-C-P-A-P and see how that
Speaker 4:  improves your sleep quality. So like that's kind of the real
Speaker 4:  thought process behind sleep tracking as well as like
Speaker 4:  another really valuable thing is having a sleep routine. So
Speaker 4:  something that a sleep tracker can do is help you build that sleep routine
Speaker 4:  by going, you regularly go to sleep at this time and wake up at this time.
Speaker 4:  Good job buddy. You are super consistent with that, right? Or
Speaker 4:  you know, if you're just really having crappy sleep and you see that you
Speaker 4:  wake up a ton of times in the night and you go, aha, that is the 3:00 AM
Speaker 4:  cat is angry at standard time and that kibble
Speaker 4:  is not coming at the time that they are used to. So they screamed and woke
Speaker 4:  me up. Like you can view patterns and trends kind of easily in that way.
Speaker 4:  It just, it's not super automatic, right? Because you have to tag
Speaker 4:  like Angry Cat, like some of my sleep tracking devices, it's
Speaker 4:  literally got an angry cat tag. And I can tell you they wake
Speaker 4:  me up quite frequently because they're angry. But I don't need a sleep tracker
Speaker 4:  for that. 'cause obviously the cat is hitting me in the face and whatnot.
Speaker 4:  So,
Speaker 2:  Well So I, that's been the challenge with me with sleep tracking for forever,
Speaker 2:  right? Which is, I think the idea that it tells you when you went
Speaker 2:  to bed and when you woke up is nothing
Speaker 2:  like I know that I don't, it's, it's like, it's like if
Speaker 2:  the only thing a fitness tracker could tell me was that I went for a walk,
Speaker 2:  like I don't need that. That's, that's not helpful. But I will
Speaker 2:  say to the credit of these devices, I think the thing you just said about
Speaker 2:  these kind of macro trends that it can give back to you.
Speaker 2:  One thing that happened to me very recently was my wife and I got a sleep
Speaker 2:  number bed a few years ago. We went from trying to
Speaker 2:  perpetually compromise on firmness to just being like, we need a bed
Speaker 2:  with two different firmness. So we got a sleep number bed, it's fine, we
Speaker 2:  got like the cheapest crappiest one, it's fine, but it does the thing we
Speaker 2:  need it to do and it gives me like a sleep score every morning. And I think
Speaker 2:  the sleep score is mostly meaningless generally speaking. But one thing it
Speaker 2:  did for me over time was it said, Hey David, just
Speaker 2:  FYI your sleep scores tend to be the best when you go to bed about 11 and
Speaker 2:  you wake up about six 30. And it was just like that, just that one thing.
Speaker 2:  It was like, okay, this seven and a half hour window of sleep
Speaker 2:  seems to be what you need in order to be successful. And that
Speaker 2:  was, so it was one of those things I like never really paid attention to,
Speaker 2:  but was so helpful that like a, that's about the amount of sleep I need
Speaker 2:  to be a successful functioning adult, but also this
Speaker 2:  window actually kind of works was very helpful. And I'm
Speaker 2:  like that that alone is like, okay, we've now you've done something for me
Speaker 2:  that I would not have done on my own.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's, that's honestly the thing about self quantification is that
Speaker 4:  it takes a really long time to tell you something useful. Yeah, that's so
Speaker 4:  true. And sometimes the stuff that it points out to
Speaker 4:  you is gonna be super obvious to everyone else, but to yourself you're like,
Speaker 4:  oh, I never really thought about that. Oh, I never really paid attention
Speaker 4:  to that. So on the surface it's all really dumb,
Speaker 4:  but one thing that they show time and time again is that logging these things
Speaker 4:  will make you more aware of them. So like, I personally
Speaker 4:  hate calorie tracking, I hate logging food. I
Speaker 4:  also have learned a lot about logging my food over time. Like I am just
Speaker 4:  like, oh, I was extremely protein deficient. I thought I was getting enough
Speaker 4:  protein. No I wasn't. Hmm. Oh, I tend to like
Speaker 4:  stress eat. Oh wow. That like when you have to log all the things that you're
Speaker 4:  stress eating, you will be more aware of those habits. So that's
Speaker 4:  primarily the benefit of sleep tracking. Even if on the surface you
Speaker 4:  look at it and you're just like, well, duh.
Speaker 2:  Like yeah. I had one the other night where my, my sleep score was 14
Speaker 2:  because I, I went to bed and I got up
Speaker 2:  at two o'clock with a toddler who didn't wanna go back to sleep and I spent
Speaker 2:  the whole rest of the night in his room and it's like, yeah, thanks bed.
Speaker 2:  I got a notification that I got a 14. Like that's how that thank you. Great.
Speaker 2:  Cool. Helpful. Which brings me to the second thing that I think is,
Speaker 2:  is complicated and interesting in this space right now is step one
Speaker 2:  is like figure out how you're doing, right? And step two is make it better.
Speaker 2:  And I think the challenge with a lot of these devices, all these
Speaker 2:  wearables, and this is the thing we've talked about many times is the the
Speaker 2:  so what the, like what do I do about this thing? Right? And like
Speaker 2:  you've seen this on the Apple watch where it'll like prompt you to go for
Speaker 2:  a walk at the end of the night to hit your goals. And sometimes that's good
Speaker 2:  and sometimes I'm like, shut up. I don't wanna go for a 61 minute walk at
Speaker 2:  10:00 PM to hit my goals A BRI walk. Yeah. Like, I'm good. Thank you Apple.
Speaker 2:  But I think the, the trick with sleep is figuring out how to make
Speaker 2:  things better. And I think this is what brings us to v's.
Speaker 2:  Adventures in $5,000 mattresses. Let's just, just
Speaker 2:  explain this thing to me that you've been sleeping on for the last few months.
Speaker 4:  I've been sleeping on the Eight Sleep Pod four Ultra. I have
Speaker 4:  previously tested the Eight Sleep Pod two Pro cover. And
Speaker 4:  basically this is a smart mattress cover.
Speaker 4:  It's not even the mattress. The mattress is my mattress that I spent
Speaker 4:  a good amount of money on because I really do think
Speaker 4:  you should invest in sleep. Oh, I agree. Clearly
Speaker 2:  A good couch and a good mattress are like the two grownup purchases
Speaker 2:  I think are worth all of the outrageous amounts of dollars you will spend
Speaker 2:  on them.
Speaker 4:  I I, I personally spent seven years in Japan sleeping on
Speaker 4:  a really cheap futon. And I actually got several
Speaker 4:  musculoskeletal like pain to the point where my doctor sat me down
Speaker 4:  in Japan and in Japanese was just like, Victoria Sun, you need
Speaker 4:  to buy an actual mattress.
Speaker 2:  So,
Speaker 4:  You know, that was a huge life lessons for me. So take
Speaker 4:  this into context that when I was saying, you know, I was willing to
Speaker 4:  test and seriously consider a
Speaker 4:  $4,700 mattress for
Speaker 4:  not mattress but mattress cover.
Speaker 2:  Right? Not even a
Speaker 4:  Mattress. Not even a mattress, a cover with a, a base
Speaker 4:  at the bottom so the base will elevate. So you can use that
Speaker 4:  manually and be like, hey, I feel like being comfy while I read. And so it'll
Speaker 4:  elevate you in that way. But the more like sleep maxing bits of it is that
Speaker 4:  there is like a special position where it slightly elevates
Speaker 4:  your feet
Speaker 4:  for sleep position and supposedly the AI in this
Speaker 4:  thing will adjust the position of the bed while you're sleeping to minimize
Speaker 4:  snoring. I have woken up while it's been moving the bed.
Speaker 4:  Oh no. To make my spouse stop snoring. I was
Speaker 2:  Just about to say, who's the snorer in the bed, which is, it's
Speaker 4:  Not me. I have quantifiable proof in our marriage that I am not the one
Speaker 4:  snoring. Okay. So haha. So you know, you know, this can be great fodder
Speaker 4:  or not in your marriage to be like, I am not
Speaker 4:  the snore, you sir are the snore. But you know, I have
Speaker 4:  actually woken up while this bed has been adjusting and watched
Speaker 4:  as they're snoring dramatically lessened. And just like in a sleep adult
Speaker 4:  state going like, oh, you mean I don't have
Speaker 4:  to like smack you and be like, wake up, you're snoring. It's woken me up.
Speaker 4:  I can just go like, oh, this is a fever dream going back to sleep and whatnot.
Speaker 4:  So that is one thing that it does. But the thing that they're most famous
Speaker 4:  for doing, I certainly buried the s lead, is that it adjusts
Speaker 4:  the temperature, right? So there's tubing inside of this
Speaker 4:  smart mattress and water runs through it from this hub. And
Speaker 4:  I am perpetually cold So I like to crank it
Speaker 4:  up and it's warm and it's toasty and I fall asleep so quickly.
Speaker 4:  Normally I like tossing and turning. Wait. All
Speaker 2:  Right, let's just confession time here on The Vergecast left to your own
Speaker 2:  devices. What's the thermostat at when you're sleeping
Speaker 4:  Warm, like in the winter? Minimum 75.
Speaker 4:  Wow. Oh my God. I I I need to be
Speaker 4:  toasty. I need to be warm. I need a heavy blanket year round.
Speaker 4:  Like I get cold so easily and if I'm cold, I don't fall asleep.
Speaker 4:  So, I need to be toasty.
Speaker 2:  I'm the opposite. I used to get in trouble when I was a kid because I would
Speaker 2:  sleep with a window open in like the dead of winter
Speaker 2:  because for me it's like cold face, giant blanket.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's the life that's where I want to be. But then getting out of
Speaker 2:  bed is awful. These like
Speaker 4:  The worst. Yeah, no, no, I, I don't, I don't, I don't mess around with
Speaker 4:  cold stuff. I like to be warm. Toasty, snug is a bug in the fetal
Speaker 4:  position. That's me, my, my spouse. However, like this summer,
Speaker 4:  like, I think the max cold setting you can go on this bed is negative 10
Speaker 4:  and they were just like negative 10. I wanna
Speaker 4:  sleep on a slab of ice. I'm living this penguin life.
Speaker 4:  And honestly they can do that on their side of the bed. I can be
Speaker 4:  in toasty heaven and they can be in ice cold hell. and we
Speaker 4:  can both be super happy about that.
Speaker 2:  Wait, but there, there's something interesting in that though because I think
Speaker 2:  on the one hand we have lots of science at this point about like
Speaker 2:  optimal temperatures for getting good sleep and things you mentioned like
Speaker 2:  the the position your body should be at to not snore, So I can imagine
Speaker 2:  in some world that like what this mattress pad ought to do for you is
Speaker 2:  optimize all of it automatically and be like, no, trust me, I un I know what
Speaker 2:  is required to get it does. Oh it does do that. Okay. Because I was gonna
Speaker 2:  say, giving you a lot of buttons and knobs might actually not be helpful,
Speaker 2:  but it will attempt to solve these problems for you.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. No, it has this AI feature which is locked behind a subscription,
Speaker 4:  which is why everyone's like, are you crazy? And yes, actually
Speaker 2:  To be fair, I do think a subscription mattress is just in principle
Speaker 2:  ridiculous. Even though I, I sort of understand why it exists. It is in principle,
Speaker 2:  it's ridiculous
Speaker 4:  In principle, subscribing to your mattress is ludicrous.
Speaker 4:  And I think I wrote that in my review. It is absolutely batshit insane,
Speaker 4:  ludicrous, but you're not even subscribing to the mattress, you're subscribing
Speaker 4:  to the mattress cover. So it's absolutely bonkers,
Speaker 4:  honky tonk insane. But at the same time, I cannot
Speaker 4:  lie, I have been sleeping so well. Even when
Speaker 4:  external circumstances in this world are crazy, I sleep
Speaker 4:  like a baby that's
Speaker 2:  So If. you have that mode on it, it will attempt to balance all the temperature
Speaker 2:  and, and space and adjustments of the positioning.
Speaker 2:  It'll try to just do all that for you.
Speaker 4:  It does all of that for you. And then when you look it up in the app in the
Speaker 4:  morning, it's so proud. It's like autopilot made four adjustments last
Speaker 4:  night to help you sleep longer. So like I, I look at it and it's like these
Speaker 4:  micro adjustments to temperature So I need to be very toasty to fall asleep,
Speaker 4:  but to stay asleep, I apparently need to sleep cooler. Mm. So
Speaker 4:  it'll do that. It'll adjust during the middle of the night to the temperature
Speaker 4:  to help me stay asleep. And the longer you test
Speaker 4:  this stuff, the better it gets. And to the point where I'm just like,
Speaker 4:  this is a joke. My god. Like all my other corroborating sleep
Speaker 4:  tracker data has basically set my sleep has been
Speaker 4:  spectacular for the last six months. And I am putting on
Speaker 4:  muscle, I am losing fat at, at the same time. It is just, it's,
Speaker 4:  I wake up like I wake up at 4:30 AM
Speaker 4:  now feeling completely rested because I go to bed at like
Speaker 4:  an insane grandpa time, like
Speaker 4:  9 39, 9 30 or whatever. And I'm
Speaker 4:  out here. I just pop out of bed in the mornings a lot of times just like,
Speaker 4:  hi, I'm super rested. Time to go on a run, which I
Speaker 4:  never thought was possible for me. It's like I am, I
Speaker 4:  have a history of insomnia. I don't fall asleep easily.
Speaker 4:  I previously in the past and I have the data to back it up, I have had really
Speaker 4:  crappy sleep scores. So it's, it's just
Speaker 4:  wild to see that and to feel the improvement in my life and
Speaker 4:  then think this is
Speaker 4:  $4,799 and comes with
Speaker 4:  a $300 per year subscription or something along those
Speaker 4:  lines. So really testing this, my whole thing has just been
Speaker 4:  like, how much is a good night's
Speaker 4:  sleep worth? How much is the best night's sleep worth to me?
Speaker 2:  Well, so let, let's actually separate those questions, right, because I think
Speaker 2:  If, you look at the eight sleep thing as kind of the very
Speaker 2:  end of a spectrum, right? Which is like, it is, it is doing the most and
Speaker 2:  it is charging the most,
Speaker 4:  It's actually doing the middle sleep number has like
Speaker 4:  $10,000 beds. Do they really? So this being they do, oh my god. So this being
Speaker 4:  modular and fitting on your existing mattress is actually kind of like
Speaker 4:  mid high spectrum. Okay. If not the, the craziest end of the spectrum.
Speaker 2:  All right. So we'll put that at like a seven out of 10 sleep number. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I can't even fathom with, I don't EI don't wanna know because I can't afford
Speaker 2:  it and I don't wanna know. But I'm curious, like I, I remember, I don't even
Speaker 2:  know if these are still really a thing, but there was this run of like sleep
Speaker 2:  tracking apps and there were the gadgets that would sit on your bedside table
Speaker 2:  that would try to do this. And have we gotten anywhere with those? Like are
Speaker 2:  can these approximate some of the stuff you're talking about?
Speaker 4:  Some of them can, like I actually really liked the Amazon halo
Speaker 4:  rise, which is rare for me because all of the Amazon Halo products I hated
Speaker 4:  with like a burning passion.
Speaker 2:  You and everybody else that turns out,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, me and every, that was not special. That was not a hot tank. But that
Speaker 4:  I, I liked this bedside lamp that gently woke you up with
Speaker 4:  light because that's actually quite effective. I've tested a bunch of these.
Speaker 4:  It's really effective to wake up with light. So smart light's
Speaker 4:  really great If, you hate alarms, they just come on, you wake up kind of
Speaker 4:  naturally. 'cause that's just how circadian rhythms and your brain works.
Speaker 4:  I actually liked that. It's sleep tracking. My cat got in
Speaker 4:  the way. So, I got a lot of really inaccurate results. So when you have these
Speaker 4:  non-invasive, non-invasive in, in the sense that they're not on
Speaker 4:  your body in any way on the nightstand, they can be very
Speaker 4:  hit or miss. They, they can be great If, you sleep alone,
Speaker 4:  don't have pets, don't have a bed partner. That can be
Speaker 4:  cool I guess, right? But you know, there this is an option. It's
Speaker 4:  there. I've tested the Withing sleep, which is like a little
Speaker 4:  mattress that you stick under your mattress. So it's like a little pad that
Speaker 4:  you stick under your mattress. Oh right.
Speaker 2:  It looks like a little heating pad kind of deal, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Speaker 2:  yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Super affordable. I think that's a really great budget option. If, you want
Speaker 4:  to track your sleep, but you are like, these
Speaker 4:  people are crazy. I'm not spending thousands of dollars on this
Speaker 4:  mattress that does all of these things and which is totally valid. I think
Speaker 4:  you are probably fiscally very responsible if that's your reaction,
Speaker 2:  But every morning you wake up feeling a little smug about your decisions.
Speaker 4:  I, yeah, I feel so good waking up on this mattress.
Speaker 4:  Let me tell you, I I hate that nobody hates this more than me.
Speaker 4:  I hate this the most. For me personally,
Speaker 2:  I think this goes on the list of like never try the really expensive thing
Speaker 2:  because once you know
Speaker 4:  You can't go back,
Speaker 2:  It's you can't go back. It's like, it's the recommendation I always give
Speaker 2:  with headphones. Like If, you don't wanna buy a really nice pair of headphones,
Speaker 2:  don't ever try a really nice pair of headphones. Don't 'cause it will ruin
Speaker 2:  everything else for you. And I feel like this is the same thing.
Speaker 4:  You can't miss what you don't know. A hundred percent. That's a hundred percent
Speaker 4:  it. There's, yeah, so there are
Speaker 4:  cheaper versions of those things. I actually think the smart home
Speaker 4:  is really great If. you want to just hack it and have stuff that is
Speaker 4:  multifunctional. Because the other problem with a lot of the stuff is it's
Speaker 4:  very one, one dimensional, one function. It does one thing.
Speaker 4:  Smart lights, you can program them so you can wake up naturally that way.
Speaker 4:  That's great. It can really help with you setting a routine
Speaker 4:  smart thermostat. You can, it is not gonna stop your
Speaker 4:  marital problems and, and fights over what temperature of the thermostat
Speaker 4:  is, but you can schedule it so you know that that can help
Speaker 4:  create a much more inviting sleep environment for you.
Speaker 4:  So those, those are all much more affordable hacks that have
Speaker 4:  multifunctional purposes that I personally have used and
Speaker 4:  found to be good.
Speaker 4:  Does it beat this expensive bed? No. No it does not.
Speaker 4:  But at the same time it is really about what
Speaker 4:  is it worth to you and how good
Speaker 4:  do you want to feel after your night of sleep. Totally. And you know,
Speaker 4:  I, I have sleep problems so it means a lot to me. But If
Speaker 4:  you are someone who sleeps like the dead on the crappiest Ikea
Speaker 4:  mattress. You don't need this stuff. You're good. You're Gucci, right? Like
Speaker 4:  So I it, it is, I I definitely understand the
Speaker 4:  criticism and I'm just sitting there alongside you nodding my head
Speaker 4:  and going, yes, yes you are, you are completely correct. I agree with you
Speaker 4:  a hundred percent. At the
Speaker 2:  Same time though, yeah, if you're listening to this and you are desperately
Speaker 2:  looking for a reason to buy this, here it is.
Speaker 2:  This is not like buying a really fancy pair of running shoes
Speaker 2:  you might never have. Or like over-investing in workout
Speaker 2:  equipment that you're never gonna use. This'll work. This is like, you just
Speaker 2:  put this on your bed and it will start doing things in the same way that
Speaker 2:  sleep has that it's, it's happening anyway. Like
Speaker 2:  adding something like this into the repertoire
Speaker 2:  just helps. It's just, it's just gonna help. This is why like the,
Speaker 2:  I want the version of this that is like 60% is good and 20% of the
Speaker 2:  price because it's like same. That's the one that it's like, just give me
Speaker 2:  the magic pillow and everything will be fine. You know what I mean? Like
Speaker 2:  that's the dream.
Speaker 4:  Oh, speaking of magic pillows, many, many, many years ago I tested
Speaker 4:  a smart pillow, which was the most insane thing because it
Speaker 4:  had a speaker inside of the pillow. No. So it would track your sleeping
Speaker 4:  and your snoring 'cause there's a microphone in there and then it would
Speaker 4:  wake you up to your music inside the pillow. It was one of the most
Speaker 4:  ridiculous pieces of sleep tech I've ever tested. But yeah,
Speaker 4:  another thing I tested was the Oslo Sleep Buds was gonna ask you about that,
Speaker 4:  which is the Bose sleep buds resurrected. They had a lot of, a lot of people
Speaker 4:  who are fans of those. And it's really great
Speaker 4:  If, you have a noisy environment. 'cause that's the one thing that this
Speaker 4:  bed can't solve, right? It can't solve If. you live
Speaker 4:  in a city and your neighbor upstairs loves to practice
Speaker 4:  salsa at 3:00 AM in the morning. Or in my case, if
Speaker 4:  Hackensack loves to send garbage trucks outside of your house
Speaker 4:  at exactly 5:00 AM and you're just like, oh,
Speaker 4:  I'm awake now having these buds in your ear,
Speaker 4:  can it, it can muffle a lot of the noise. So I. I used to be
Speaker 4:  a religious user of that. My, my spouse is a religious user of not the,
Speaker 4:  not the PO ones 'cause those once again very expensive or the
Speaker 4:  Oslo ones are expensive, but he has the cheaper anchor sound core,
Speaker 4:  which allows them to play their true crime podcast, which
Speaker 4:  why you wanna go to bed. Listening to murder is a thing I don't necessarily
Speaker 4:  understand, but it works for them. So they do that,
Speaker 4:  they love it, it falls out of their ear, which we
Speaker 4:  don't love. But the Bose design is very good for side
Speaker 4:  sleepers. I don't feel discomfort. They don't fall out of my ear
Speaker 4:  pretty great. Okay. Those will apparently come with sleep tracking
Speaker 4:  sometime in 2025. So yeah, we're, we're out here, we're sleep
Speaker 4:  maxing, we're just sleep maxing and just trying to figure it out.
Speaker 2:  The earbuds are one that I have always felt like could be more
Speaker 2:  than they are. So I'm, I'm actually encouraged to hear that they're gonna
Speaker 2:  do some sleep tracking stuff with it. Because like, one thing you and I have
Speaker 2:  heard a lot of over the years is people saying like, the, the ears are a
Speaker 2:  really interesting place to do wearables stuff. And especially if you're
Speaker 2:  gonna start to think about like, how do I, you know, gently help you go to
Speaker 2:  sleep and gently help you wake up. Like that's a thing you can do with a
Speaker 2:  thing in your ears. Like, I dunno if it can help you not snore
Speaker 2:  or fix the temperature, probably not. But there's like little things
Speaker 2:  that if you're just doing like a tracker you probably can't do.
Speaker 2:  But If, you have this device that is just gonna sit in your ears all night.
Speaker 2:  It feels like there's more you could do. So maybe there's, maybe there is
Speaker 2:  a roadmap of interesting stuff to come there.
Speaker 4:  Especially for like helping you fall asleep because I think that's
Speaker 4:  something that a lot of people have issues with is just falling asleep,
Speaker 4:  figuring out ways to fall asleep. So staying asleep,
Speaker 4:  it's a, it's a valuable thing because I have tried the smart
Speaker 4:  alarm clocks. I've tried the Hatch Restore that
Speaker 4:  TikTok made me try it. It's on my nightstand. And that,
Speaker 4:  you know, just having a sleep partner doesn't really work out well
Speaker 4:  for me. Yeah. Like the, the light. Great. Love that. Waking
Speaker 4:  up. How
Speaker 2:  Does it feel to know that you and my 1-year-old son have the same alarm clock?
Speaker 2:  Is that, is that good? Is that cool? He loves, yeah, it works great for him.
Speaker 4:  He sleeps like a baby. So honestly,
Speaker 4:  honestly, I'm, I'm trying to, I'm trying to live that life, so it
Speaker 4:  makes me feel great.
Speaker 2:  That's good. All right, before we let you go, any other, any other sleep
Speaker 2:  gadgets on your mind? Anything else you've been looking at or trying or hoping
Speaker 2:  to try?
Speaker 4:  Honestly, I'm just going to reiterate one last time that
Speaker 4:  you should invest in your sleep in, in whatever way
Speaker 4:  and don't cheap out on it.
Speaker 4:  Sometimes the right decision is to buy a $5,000
Speaker 4:  mattress cover. Sometimes that is the right decision.
Speaker 2:  This is where we were gonna land because the verges editorial policies
Speaker 2:  dictate that you don't get to keep this thing at some point.
Speaker 2:  This beautiful device that has changed your life is going to leave your house.
Speaker 2:  What happens then? Can you go back?
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna buy it. Yeah, but I, it's, it's either gonna be a long-term
Speaker 4:  sleep testing control device so that I can test it for sleep trackers,
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 2:  For journalism, everyone,
Speaker 4:  For journalism purpose, for journalism, for journalism purposes, or
Speaker 4:  you know, just have to buy the thing because I can't go
Speaker 4:  back and you know, like if it was just a simple matter of
Speaker 4:  also returning it and knowing that that's what it was gonna be, that'd be
Speaker 4:  cool. But because this has my biological material
Speaker 4:  on it, they will not necessarily return it. Right. They will destroy it.
Speaker 4:  And then that just feels like e-waste. So
Speaker 4:  I'll figure out a way, I'll figure out financing.
Speaker 4:  I will do long-term test tracking. But this is one of the things
Speaker 4:  where, yeah, I'm just gonna have to buy it honestly,
Speaker 4:  if it comes, comes down to it. And that's just,
Speaker 4:  it has a huge impact on my life. Yeah. My, my sleep quality is so much better.
Speaker 4:  You can think I'm crazy. All you like, I'll figure it out.
Speaker 4:  I I'll figure it out. My husband does not agree with me, but I'll figure
Speaker 4:  it out.
Speaker 2:  So that's their problem, not
Speaker 4:  Yours. That's their problem, not mine. I will be figuring this out and I
Speaker 4:  will be paying a absurd subscription. So
Speaker 2:  That's how they get, you don't test it unless you're willing to buy it. People,
Speaker 2:  I'm
Speaker 4:  Not, those are the rules proud of my life choices, but they are mine.
Speaker 2:  These are the things we do for our audience. V we spend outrageous amounts
Speaker 2:  of money on beautiful nights of sleep.
Speaker 4:  You know, I'm winning. So there you go.
Speaker 2:  All right v thank you as always.
Speaker 4:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about music. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back If. you use Spotify, I'm sure you know
Speaker 2:  the DJ feature. You click on it, it has this AI
Speaker 2:  generated voice that greets you and then it plays you music. And
Speaker 2:  that's the idea. It is supposed to be a, a sort of constantly updated
Speaker 2:  AI curated playlist of music that you'd like.
Speaker 2:  I love this feature. I listen to it all the time. I think the voice bit
Speaker 2:  is kind of weird, but I think the idea that I can just
Speaker 2:  sit down and essentially press play and have something play music for me
Speaker 2:  that I'm going to like, is very powerful. Alison Johnson
Speaker 2:  on our team feels slightly differently. She has also been testing
Speaker 2:  ai, DJ stuff, has a lot of thoughts and I figured
Speaker 2:  it, it, we just need to hash this out. I'm also working on a big story about
Speaker 2:  what the best music app is because I'm sort of over Spotify and
Speaker 2:  trying to find something else and finding something else is a challenge.
Speaker 2:  So I'm hoping Allison can help me talk through this one piece of it
Speaker 2:  and try to make sense of things. Let's just get into it. Alison, hello.
Speaker 5:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  I should tell everybody that I'm interrupting a day off for you to do this
Speaker 2:  So I and everyone listening owe you a great debt of gratitude.
Speaker 5:  I'm happy to be here. I get to talk to another adult before a
Speaker 5:  little bit before I go to the Children's Museum. So
Speaker 2:  This is, I'm I'm happy to, I'm happy to do it. So real
Speaker 2:  quick, I wanna talk about AI DJs But. first, I want know kind of
Speaker 2:  your theory of the case about Spotify's AI
Speaker 2:  DJ in particular. This is very clearly a thing you have been thinking about
Speaker 2:  a lot and there's a lot of interesting context, but you've, you've come to
Speaker 2:  a conclusion about these things and I wanna know what that is.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so Spotify, like every other
Speaker 5:  tech company with an app has been shoving
Speaker 5:  AI into everything over the past year. And
Speaker 5:  the one that caught my eye recently is this AI dj, which is
Speaker 5:  not actually new, it's been around like a year, but it just kind of
Speaker 5:  popped up in my feed and I was like, sure, I'll try this
Speaker 5:  weird thing. And, and right outta the gate, it's just so strange.
Speaker 5:  'cause it, it talks to you, it goes, Hey Allison,
Speaker 5:  blah, blah, blah. They kinda launch into a like DJ
Speaker 5:  spiel about what they're gonna play
Speaker 5:  and then, you know, it gets into the music and not surprisingly
Speaker 5:  in any way, it's all stuff that I really like
Speaker 5:  because what company has more data about what
Speaker 5:  music I like to listen to than Spotify. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I was just kinda like, what is this? And I try, I listened to it, I like
Speaker 5:  kept with it for a day and like off
Speaker 5:  and on throughout a week just to be like, what is going on
Speaker 5:  here?
Speaker 2:  But you don't like that you just described such a good thing what you just,
Speaker 2:  and this, this is why I think this is so interesting and why I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about it, what you just said. I just, I'm just gonna say it back to you is
Speaker 2:  you, you clicked on a thing that greeted you by name and then played a bunch
Speaker 2:  of music in a row that you really like and this feels like a problem.
Speaker 5:  Terrible. Yeah, no. So here here's the thing,
Speaker 5:  kind of the, the flip side is that we have a local radio
Speaker 5:  station in Seattle, K-K-E-X-P that
Speaker 5:  I've, I've listened to forever, since before I moved to Seattle.
Speaker 5:  And it's just kind of like a daily habit. It's on
Speaker 5:  in the background all the time. It's on in the car. And
Speaker 5:  I don't know if it's a Seattle thing or a me thing or what it is, but
Speaker 5:  the osmosis of like, you, you get, you have these like
Speaker 5:  parasocial relationships with the DJs that kind of start you like
Speaker 5:  have your favorite DJs. And then the weird thing in Seattle is like,
Speaker 5:  I'll be out on the bike path and I'll see Kevin Cole going
Speaker 5:  the other direction after his show. I'm like, oh, they're, they're real
Speaker 5:  humans. They're out here just like we are.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like in, in Seattle, like a very musicy town that counts as like
Speaker 2:  an actual celebrity setting. Like that's, that's legit.
Speaker 5:  Oh, for sure. Yeah. Yeah. The whole rest of my bike ride, I was like, oh
Speaker 5:  my God, Kevin Gold was going on the bike.
Speaker 5:  So that's, that's kind of like the background where I,
Speaker 5:  maybe I bring a little more skepticism to it where I'm like,
Speaker 5:  you know, I, to me a a radio DJ is like
Speaker 5:  a real person and I have favorite radio DJs
Speaker 5:  and yeah, hearing, hearing this, which is just an
Speaker 5:  imitation of that, just like maybe I
Speaker 5:  was just not gonna like it right out of the gate. But
Speaker 5:  that's my bias I brought to it, I guess.
Speaker 2:  So I, this is part of why I wanted to talk about this because I think
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out what feels wrong about the AI
Speaker 2:  DJ actually feels like a really useful sort of metaphor for all
Speaker 2:  of ai. And I think this is a lot of what you were getting at in this piece.
Speaker 2:  And I think why it struck me too, there's this question of, okay, is it
Speaker 2:  a bad thing that it is pretty much exclusively playing music? I
Speaker 2:  definitely for sure am going to like, like for me, I was listening to my
Speaker 2:  DJ all morning and I mean, it is just down the middle
Speaker 2:  David Bait, right? Yeah. One of it was like, there, there was this guy I
Speaker 2:  found who was doing like punk rock covers of old songs on
Speaker 2:  TikTok. And then I listened to a bunch of his stuff on Spotify and it was
Speaker 2:  just like, what if we just played nine of his songs in a row? I was like,
Speaker 2:  great, I'm in, let's do it. Yeah, Let's go. And then, and then there was
Speaker 2:  a bunch of like Cynthia eighties pop
Speaker 2:  music, which Spotify like you said, has immense knowledge of the
Speaker 2:  fact that that is music I'm always gonna like, and so it, it was like
Speaker 2:  a no skips playlist for an hour and a half and I got to the end and I was
Speaker 2:  like, was did I, did I get anything out of any of that? Like could I tell
Speaker 2:  you what songs it played? It was just sort of music. So there's the question
Speaker 2:  of like, is that the right thing? And then there's the question of like,
Speaker 2:  is this, is this product even a good idea? And that goes back to
Speaker 2:  the, like, it's a, it's a person quote unquote talking
Speaker 2:  to you, quote unquote as it goes. And there, there is
Speaker 2:  this thing about this, this thing is obviously trying to
Speaker 2:  seem like a person. And I think one of the things we're seeing about AI
Speaker 2:  a lot is AI that is trying to seem like a person. And, and I
Speaker 2:  think in some ways this is just the most sort of n
Speaker 2:  nakedly straightforward version of that. And it rubs
Speaker 2:  me the wrong way too. And I can't figure out if it's just because it's not
Speaker 2:  very good or if it's because it's the wrong idea.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's, I mean, it's pretty convincing. Like, it,
Speaker 5:  it just sounds like a person talking to you.
Speaker 5:  And I think, like I, to me it just
Speaker 5:  feels like this is not somewhere I need ai. Like
Speaker 5:  I am good with Spotify putting together a playlist for me.
Speaker 5:  You know, I use the playlist feature, the AI
Speaker 5:  playlist feature quite a bit where I'm like, I wanna hear
Speaker 5:  upbeat jazz. There can't be any lyrics because I'm writing
Speaker 5:  a blog, you know? And like it spits out a playlist and it's great.
Speaker 2:  Which is also AI by the way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That is,
Speaker 2:  It's, it's a different flavor of it that is still very much ai
Speaker 5:  And, and I'm totally good with that. I am like, do not
Speaker 5:  try to insert a human into this interaction, you know? Right.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's a very like, transactional, like this is fine.
Speaker 5:  So that's where, where I think I am just weirded out by the DJs.
Speaker 5:  Like we have human DJs, we have people
Speaker 5:  If, you wanna listen to the radio, you can do that. Like why, who
Speaker 5:  is asking for this? It feels, I put it in the box of who was asking for this.
Speaker 2:  No, I I think that's totally right. And I think I made a lot of fun of Apple
Speaker 2:  music when Apple Music came out and they had, you know, beats won and
Speaker 2:  all of these celebrity driven radio stations
Speaker 2:  essentially is like, and and my theory then was like, who
Speaker 2:  wants this? Right? Like in a, I have a library full of
Speaker 2:  infinite music, why am I gonna spend two
Speaker 2:  hours a week listening to like whatever John Mayer feels like playing?
Speaker 2:  I was wrong about that for, I think exactly the reason
Speaker 2:  you're describing that there is a lot of time
Speaker 2:  that I just want what I want. Right.
Speaker 2:  Which is like a giant library full of music and I'm gonna go in and I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  be like, I would like to listen to the Wicked soundtrack, please. Yeah, go
Speaker 2:  listen to the Wicked soundtrack. Great. Right. That, that is better than
Speaker 2:  the radio. And then there's all the way on the other side there is the like,
Speaker 2:  just expand my brain a little bit. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think that AI is not doing
Speaker 2:  successfully at all. Yeah. And, and, and this goes back to the like, is it
Speaker 2:  right to just play me songs that I like a bunch of times in a row? I think
Speaker 2:  that that is such an easy win if your goal is to just get people
Speaker 2:  to keep listening, but it doesn't feel good. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like in, in a way that, like you, you, you talked about, you know, some of
Speaker 2:  the stuff you've gotten from KEX exp as like meaningful stuff and you
Speaker 2:  like remember the experience and it feels cool and you feel like part of
Speaker 2:  community. I don't think it's possible to get any of that from this AI stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's exactly it. And the, the
Speaker 5:  metaphor I landed on is like, listening to Kxp
Speaker 5:  is sort of like a well-rounded meal. Like there's stuff I really like,
Speaker 5:  there's stuff I am sort of into, there's stuff I, I just straight
Speaker 5:  up do not like, but it's, it feels like
Speaker 5:  a balanced experience. And the AI DJ is
Speaker 5:  just straight up feeding me like all this stuff I like, I'm like,
Speaker 5:  I love M and mss. I don't want to eat m and MSS all day long. You know, like,
Speaker 5:  like you, you get a stomach ache eventually that,
Speaker 5:  and that's just kind of how it feels to me. And there is like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  it, it just, it hits different, there's like, I hear
Speaker 5:  tears for fears come on in the grocery store and I'm like,
Speaker 5:  well they know that a woman in her late thirties
Speaker 5:  is probably shopping is gonna love this and they're right.
Speaker 5:  But then my, you know, favorite DJ plays it on KXP
Speaker 5:  'cause she really loves it. I'm like, oh, this is, it just, it, it's
Speaker 5:  more meaningful I think.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The one part of it I have trouble with is the, is
Speaker 2:  it good to play me stuff that I hate side of things. Right. Because I
Speaker 2:  think, and you made this case a little bit in your piece and I think it,
Speaker 2:  it's been a thing for you of like the, the percentage of
Speaker 2:  things that I hear from these DJs or whatever that I actively don't like
Speaker 2:  is good and important and yeah, there's part of me that sort of intellectually
Speaker 2:  understands that, but then part of me that's like, well a,
Speaker 2:  that's the time when I turn off the radio. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Or,
Speaker 2:  Or b what if it just only played things that
Speaker 2:  I liked and then I'm back to the a i DJ thing that it's like, again,
Speaker 2:  you can see how you get there, right? Where it's like if we just keep playing
Speaker 2:  songs that you like, you're, you, you won't turn the thing off.
Speaker 2:  And so what responsibility does it have to
Speaker 2:  just inject randomness into your life
Speaker 2:  in even on the grand likelihood that you're gonna hate it. And
Speaker 2:  in a weird way, I feel like this is something we're not dealing with at all
Speaker 2:  in the rest of ai, but it's the kind of question we're gonna have to have
Speaker 2:  all the time when we get to things like all of these sort of information
Speaker 2:  retrieval services and the way that we think about generating images and
Speaker 2:  texts. Like should it write you a bad email one out of 10 times just to like
Speaker 2:  keep you on your, just to feel
Speaker 5:  I don't wear reel. Yeah. Yeah. There's a weird like
Speaker 5:  personalization echo chamber I think that you can get into
Speaker 5:  and it's, I don't know, maybe like, there's times
Speaker 5:  when I'm like, yeah, I wanna be in the echo chamber of music. I like,
Speaker 5:  I don't feel like, you know, eating my
Speaker 5:  vegetables today, I just wanna hear the stuff I like.
Speaker 5:  But I think it's like, that's probably different for every person and I think
Speaker 5:  there's a different limit of like, when do I feel like, okay,
Speaker 5:  I've, I should probably listen to something else and like
Speaker 5:  get, get something else mixed in here and then I don't
Speaker 5:  know, then when I go back to listening to washed out or whatever I'm doing,
Speaker 5:  it's like, it sounds great. I'm like, yeah, I I love this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I like the m and m's analogy a lot, right? It's like, it's good to
Speaker 2:  have comfort food. Yeah. But If you only eat comfort food. Like comfort food
Speaker 2:  is comfort food because you don't eat it all the time. That is kind of the
Speaker 2:  point. Right,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that's something AI can get better at? Like is there someone
Speaker 2:  at Spotify who can tweak that algorithm to make that work?
Speaker 5:  I think it, I mean it probably could, but some, you know,
Speaker 5:  someone commented on the article and it
Speaker 5:  really resonated with me that when a human plays
Speaker 5:  something that you don't like, they like it, like they have
Speaker 5:  a reason for playing it and you kind of like weigh it differently in
Speaker 5:  your head and you kind of give it a chance maybe more than, than if this
Speaker 5:  robot, like, I'm, I'm like more offended when the robot plays something I
Speaker 5:  don't like, I'm like, excuse me, where
Speaker 5:  did you come up with this?
Speaker 2:  That's so true. Yeah. Well and there's a sense of like, you, the robot
Speaker 2:  should know. Yeah, yeah. Right. Like you, you dumb ass Spotify
Speaker 2:  dj. Yeah. You know everything about what I like, why are you
Speaker 2:  playing me
Speaker 5:  This? Yeah. Get out of here with this. It tried to do that. There was, I
Speaker 5:  turned it on the other day and it was like, here are some songs that are
Speaker 5:  shaping rock music right now. And I was like, absolutely not.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm good. Just, just play the stuff I wanna hear.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it is, I don't know, again, I keep coming back to this question of
Speaker 2:  like, can we can better AI get closer to
Speaker 2:  these things? I think I'm just so stuck on this question of like what is
Speaker 2:  necessary for humans to do and, and I
Speaker 2:  think that the point our comments was making about having someone say
Speaker 2:  that they like this to you is really powerful. I mean, we talk to people
Speaker 2:  all the time about like recommendation systems and, and like we,
Speaker 2:  we think about this with like buying guides and all this stuff, right? Like
Speaker 2:  someone you trust liking something is an incredibly
Speaker 2:  good predictor of whether you're going to like that thing because you're
Speaker 2:  more likely to like that thing because you like the person who recommended
Speaker 2:  it. Like there there is some wild human nature thing
Speaker 2:  inside of that that I think you just can't replicate with a computer.
Speaker 2:  And it's true of like the Netflix algorithm and everything else, right? Even
Speaker 2:  if it puts the perfect thing at the top, I'm still probably
Speaker 2:  more likely to like the thing that you told me to watch than the thing that
Speaker 2:  Netflix told me to watch. Even if statistically Netflix is right. You know
Speaker 2:  what I mean? Yeah. And So I, I wonder to some extent
Speaker 2:  if it's a matter of Spotify and everyone else doing this
Speaker 2:  kind of thing, just totally barking up the wrong tree. Or if it's like,
Speaker 2:  maybe if the voice was 10% more convincing, I wouldn't even
Speaker 2:  know. Yeah. And it would start to feel like a person. I feel
Speaker 5:  Like there's a, you feel the intention behind it
Speaker 5:  a little bit. Like when I hear something on the radio,
Speaker 5:  it's maybe something I don't like, like the there's a person playing it,
Speaker 5:  it's their job to curate music and, and they
Speaker 5:  like it. The intention behind the Spotify
Speaker 5:  ai DJ is a little murkier where it's like, I think
Speaker 5:  you just want me to keep using Spotify. You know? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Or it's like, I, I just can't shake that feeling of like, this is
Speaker 5:  a, this a robot, it's a convincing robot. You are
Speaker 5:  basically like the voice of, I don't know, a corporate
Speaker 5:  entity like that. Like that's not at the front of my
Speaker 5:  mind when I'm listening to it, but I think it's somewhere in the back where
Speaker 5:  I'm sort of like, I don't quite trust the
Speaker 5:  intentions, like when it's trying to introduce me to, but whatever's coming
Speaker 5:  next in rock music, I'm like, well, are they
Speaker 5:  sponsored or are they just like,
Speaker 5:  did a human pick these? Like, I, I just don't know where it's coming from.
Speaker 5:  It, it feels a little, yeah, it feels murkier, I think.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then ironically, I think there are probably similar questions worth
Speaker 2:  asking about a lot of radio DJs. True. But it, it feels different
Speaker 2:  even when it's not Right. And I think that that thing is really
Speaker 2:  important. And like for Spotify, I think If, you rewind a bunch
Speaker 2:  of years. Spotify and everybody else always talked about we
Speaker 2:  need this sort of human computer combo to do this stuff
Speaker 2:  really well. And I think my experience at least was,
Speaker 2:  there was a long time where Spotify's curated playlists were
Speaker 2:  where I did the vast majority of my listing. Oh yeah. And it was, it
Speaker 2:  was a mix of like, you know, rap Caviar was like the biggest playlist
Speaker 2:  on Planet Earth, and it was, it was a person, they had a ton of machine help.
Speaker 2:  They get all kinds of listening data. They get all kinds of like, you know,
Speaker 2:  quantitative and qualitative data about the songs themselves. And, but ultimately
Speaker 2:  they're putting the thing together. And I feel like
Speaker 2:  Spotify probably most of all, but to some extent kind of all of these
Speaker 2:  media services of any kind have just leaned further and further and further
Speaker 2:  into the machine. And maybe the
Speaker 2:  right answer is just like a human face on the machine. Like Right.
Speaker 2:  The cynical answer is they hire a DJ to just say the
Speaker 2:  words to you instead of Yeah. A machine saying the words to you.
Speaker 2:  But it, it does feel like that combination is
Speaker 2:  being lost. And I think part of the reason I wanted to talk to you about
Speaker 2:  this is, I, I'm curious about your own music habits, because I was thinking
Speaker 2:  about my own after reading your story, and I spend a shocking amount of my
Speaker 2:  time in the, like, daily mixes that Spotify
Speaker 2:  does. It has like six of them. One of mine is always country. One of mine
Speaker 2:  is always like movie soundtracks, which is awesome. 'cause that's why I listen
Speaker 2:  during work all day. Like it rips, it's great. But I spend a lot of time
Speaker 2:  in those. And that's ai. There's no person involved in that. That is the
Speaker 2:  computer curating music for me. But that's not like I get to
Speaker 2:  the end of those playlists and I couldn't tell you anything about them. They're
Speaker 2:  just kind of the noise I have on during the day. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  reading your article, I was like, oh, I need to go back to listening to the
Speaker 2:  radio in the car just as like a new kind of sensory
Speaker 2:  experience for music because I had all, all music is background noise
Speaker 2:  to me now in a way that I kind of hate. And I think Spotify has done that
Speaker 2:  to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. That's, it's funny because like, I feel like that's a big
Speaker 5:  reason why we all signed up for Spotify was like,
Speaker 5:  whoa, the algorithm is really good and you're gonna find stuff that
Speaker 5:  you actually like. And that was like kind of a, in a
Speaker 5:  groundbreaking concept at the time. And I, I do
Speaker 5:  find a lot of music I like through recommended stuff on Spotify,
Speaker 5:  but yeah, it is, it is a different, like, you, you do get
Speaker 5:  into
Speaker 5:  the too many m and ms situation, or at least I do pretty
Speaker 5:  quickly because I will just happily keep
Speaker 5:  listening to my Yeah. Eighties inspired
Speaker 5:  since pop like bands. And then,
Speaker 5:  yeah, it, it, it feels good to like, there, there's a couple of
Speaker 5:  DJs I I like a lot on KXP and I think one,
Speaker 5:  one of the things they do is play the songs that I didn't
Speaker 5:  realize I wanted to hear, and they feel kind of out of left field.
Speaker 5:  And there's like, love the Spotify algorithm
Speaker 5:  for what it does, but then I do want it, it's
Speaker 5:  like gratifying when I hear something, I'm like, I had no idea
Speaker 5:  that I needed to hear Stevie Wonder like as much
Speaker 5:  as I did. And, and you hear it on the radio, it's like, that was perfect.
Speaker 5:  I, I feel like it just, it just comes down to feeling like
Speaker 5:  there is something there with ai and there Spotify's had a
Speaker 5:  lot of success with it. I think they're kind of leaning
Speaker 5:  into that, is getting to a point of like,
Speaker 5:  well, yeah, the AI was good, but I didn't wanna like talk
Speaker 5:  to the ai. Like, it wasn't the AI that I was here for.
Speaker 5:  I was here because the AI was helping me get to good music
Speaker 5:  that I like. It's not the entity I wanna be
Speaker 5:  interacting with. And I don't, it's, it's like such a cringey moment
Speaker 5:  right now where everybody's like, you know, you log on Instagram,
Speaker 5:  it's like, do you wanna interact with ai? And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  no. I wanna see what my friends are doing.
Speaker 2:  I know, I, I have come to the point where I'm like, I think we, we need to
Speaker 2:  get to the point where we think of ai. Like we think of, you know, TCP
Speaker 2:  ip, like crucial infrastructure to how all of this
Speaker 2:  works. And if it works correctly, you should never, ever, for one second
Speaker 2:  have to think about it. Right. Like, yeah. I, I don't, I don't spend
Speaker 2:  time thinking about packet loss on the internet anymore because it works
Speaker 2:  now. Yeah. But that's not the point of any of it. All of it enables other
Speaker 2:  stuff. And I, I think right now we are, we are at a moment where
Speaker 2:  AI is like the main character and what, what it should be is like the
Speaker 2:  camera. You know what I mean? Yeah, exactly. It's, I don't know, it's a bad
Speaker 2:  metaphor, but I I am, I'm, I'm totally with you. So now that you've been
Speaker 2:  messing with this way of music consumption, what do you feel like is the
Speaker 2:  right answer? How are you gonna do your own music to make sure you're getting
Speaker 2:  the right kind of diet?
Speaker 5:  I feel like I have a pretty, I mean, our, our use case is
Speaker 5:  kind of weird in that like, I can't listen to songs with lyrics during
Speaker 5:  the day fair. And when I'm writing So, I have a movie,
Speaker 2:  Soundtracks, it's the only way movie
Speaker 5:  Soundtracks is good. I like
Speaker 2:  That The Pirates of the Caribbean soundtrack for like five years was all
Speaker 2:  I wrote too. Oh God.
Speaker 5:  It's amazing. Oh my God, if everything I start writing sounds is like super
Speaker 5:  epic and like, you'll know I've been putting on the parts
Speaker 5:  of the Caribbean
Speaker 2:  Cannot recommend it
Speaker 5:  Enough. Yeah, yeah. So, I have like kind of my,
Speaker 5:  my genre for when I'm writing and working during the day. I think probably
Speaker 5:  in there there's even a little room to experiment. Like I've listened to
Speaker 5:  the same like coffee table jazz playlist
Speaker 5:  probably a hundred times.
Speaker 5:  But then, yeah, it's like when the working day is over, I kind of like,
Speaker 5:  I like having KXP on while I'm doing the dishes and while I'm in
Speaker 5:  the car picking up my kid. And yeah. It doesn't feel
Speaker 5:  as like, I don't need everything to be a banger. I don't know,
Speaker 5:  like maybe in different situations I'm a little more like, okay,
Speaker 5:  I wanna listen to whatever it is right now, but
Speaker 5:  sort of feels like a nice way to unplug from the day
Speaker 5:  and, and hear a person hear some, probably a lot of songs I'll
Speaker 5:  like.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think there's something to the kind of
Speaker 2:  unoptimized ness of that that is really,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, encouraging and, and compelling in
Speaker 2:  a way that listening to a playlist of things that are sort of ruthlessly
Speaker 2:  constructed for your oral pleasure is like,
Speaker 2:  eh, you do, you get to the point where you're like, okay, this is, these
Speaker 2:  are great songs and I'm, I'm kind of over it. Yeah. But then the, the like
Speaker 2:  the peaks and valleys of like, oh my God, I love that song.
Speaker 2:  Versus what is this trash that they're playing for me for the next three
Speaker 2:  minutes Is it's, it is, it's just so hard to replicate. And I think we're
Speaker 2:  gonna see a lot of companies and products try to emulate that.
Speaker 2:  I'm not sure it's possible, I just don't know. If, you can do that with computers
Speaker 2:  in a way that people doing people things is Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Gonna keep working like that. So should everyone listen to KEX exp, like,
Speaker 2:  is the move here? Find your own local radio station or just get into KEX
Speaker 2:  exp and it'll solve all your problems.
Speaker 5:  I think it is. IKXP is streaming worldwide
Speaker 5:  online.
Speaker 5:  I am not a paid spokesperson for KX exp. I just really like it.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, no, I, that was the really amazing thing about this
Speaker 5:  comments on this article are people chiming in like, yeah, I have this station
Speaker 5:  and you know, shout out to the station in Milwaukee
Speaker 5:  or wherever you are. And they're, they're out there. It was, it was really
Speaker 5:  gratifying to hear that people have their favorite indie
Speaker 5:  radio stations in, in our super
Speaker 5:  optimized super Spotify time. So
Speaker 5:  that was great to hear. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I will say the one other thing I would add in, in terms of like places
Speaker 2:  to go for this kind of thing is YouTube is a surprisingly
Speaker 2:  rich place for people basically just doing radio.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like, I think a lot of people know lo-Fi Girl and stuff like that,
Speaker 2:  which is a thing I really like for sort of the, the
Speaker 2:  right vibe. But new music, I, I use it sort of
Speaker 2:  as a mood setting thing, which I'm very happy to outsource. Like
Speaker 2:  I don't need to know what the songs are called. I just want, I trust them
Speaker 2:  to sort of make me feel the way that I'm looking for. But there are also
Speaker 2:  lots of people out there doing really interesting mixes of like
Speaker 2:  different kinds of genres and doing all kinds of really long
Speaker 2:  radio DJ sets essentially. And there's tons of great
Speaker 2:  radio to do there. But I also would encourage people to go poke
Speaker 2:  around on the sort of endlessly streaming YouTube stations. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  'cause there's, there's some very cool stuff out there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Awesome.
Speaker 2:  I think we, we all need a little more of the like weird random discovery
Speaker 2:  in our lives. It's
Speaker 5:  Good. Eat your vegetables. Don't eat m and ms all day. As much
Speaker 2:  As I hate to say it, John Mayer's Apple Music radio station is very good.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. It's like I, I like
Speaker 2:  John Mayer a lot against my will, but here we're, this is just,
Speaker 2:  this is just what happened. He
Speaker 5:  Is a good musician. It's he he is like undeniable. However you feel
Speaker 5:  about him. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, exactly. You this, this is, this is where I've landed. All right. Give
Speaker 2:  us a music recommendation then. I'm gonna let you leave. We're, while we're
Speaker 2:  telling people to listen, what should everybody go listen to? Oh
Speaker 5:  Gosh.
Speaker 5:  I just heard, oh, Sudan archives. I
Speaker 5:  saw her at a festival. I hear her on KXP all the time.
Speaker 5:  She's a Cincinnati girl like I am. Check her out.
Speaker 5:  I, I love everything she's doing.
Speaker 2:  Love that. I have been listening to Casey Musgraves nonstop for like two
Speaker 2:  weeks. So it's probably good for me to go and branch equipment.
Speaker 5:  This will be good. Let's switch it up
Speaker 2:  Allison, go have fun at the Children's Museum. Thank you as always.
Speaker 5:  Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  take a question from The Verge cast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. We love all of your questions and we try to answer at least one
Speaker 2:  on the show every week. Thank you to everybody who has reached out with thoughts
Speaker 2:  about how we should be covering politics and the next Trump
Speaker 2:  administration and just the next four years of life in America.
Speaker 2:  We have a lot to think about. It's been really great to hear your thoughts
Speaker 2:  on what you do and don't want us to talk about and do and don't care about
Speaker 2:  yourselves and how we as The Verge can make this stuff
Speaker 2:  make sense both kind of in our world but in a broader world. Thank you to
Speaker 2:  everybody who's reached out. But this week we do not have a question about
Speaker 2:  that. We have a question about one of the true central
Speaker 2:  tenants of The Vergecast and that is the Frame tv.
Speaker 2:  Let's hear it.
Speaker 6:  It is Pete from North Carolina. I need some advice on the frame tv.
Speaker 6:  I'm probably not a normal TV buyer in that I'm almost 40 and I've never bought
Speaker 6:  a tv. The only reason I'm in the market now is that we had some inclement
Speaker 6:  weather out here recently and our old TV that was going on like 20 years
Speaker 6:  old got a piece of a window throw in. So what I'm looking at is
Speaker 6:  the only place in our house for a TV is the main room up on the mantle
Speaker 6:  place. It's pretty central and I hate the idea of having a big
Speaker 6:  empty black void staring at the room, especially with our little kids 'cause
Speaker 6:  they're just gonna demand that some sort of cartoon is played on it. It's
Speaker 6:  also well used to be next to a big window that is getting
Speaker 6:  repaired. And so it gets a lot of light and
Speaker 6:  between that, it kind of seemed like the Frame TV or
Speaker 6:  something like it would be a good fit so that it's not getting too much glare
Speaker 6:  and when it's off it's not just begging for something to be
Speaker 6:  turned on.
Speaker 6:  So that being said, I see
Speaker 6:  50 55 inch TVs on Best Buy
Speaker 6:  for like 200 to $300 while the frame TV
Speaker 6:  is over a thousand. Can I justify paying that much
Speaker 6:  for something that hopefully will look nice?
Speaker 6:  Is that a good trade off? Is the Frame TV actually what I want in the middle
Speaker 6:  of my main room that I'm gonna be looking at all the time? I
Speaker 6:  would love any advice you can gimme. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  When someone asks the question, is the frame TV actually what I want? There
Speaker 2:  is only one person to bring in and a Snee Patel. Hi Neli.
Speaker 7:  I'm just gonna answer that question
Speaker 7:  with a statement which is that Hollywood is doomed
Speaker 7:  embedded in that question. If, you listen to it carefully is
Speaker 7:  the complete destruction of the film and TV industry as we know it.
Speaker 2:  Say more,
Speaker 7:  Pete, you don't want a tv, you're 40 years old, you've gone your entire
Speaker 7:  life without purchasing a TV and I'm yours
Speaker 7:  got broken. And you're like, I should have a TV in this space because you
Speaker 7:  think you need a TV and maybe you watch it sometimes and you don't want your
Speaker 7:  kids to watch cartoons on tv. So you're gonna buy something else
Speaker 7:  out of obligation to cultural norms.
Speaker 7:  And you're actively looking to spend money on a TV
Speaker 7:  whose picture quality sucks to prioritize how
Speaker 7:  it looks when it's turned off. It is just
Speaker 7:  a little, it's a little hop from there to not having a
Speaker 7:  tv. I don't know how more clearly I can say this, Hollywood is doomed.
Speaker 7:  People don't wanna watch the TVs, they wanna watch TikTok.
Speaker 2:  I mean it is, it is true in a way that I had never really thought about
Speaker 2:  until you said that, that you are just assumed to have a television.
Speaker 2:  Like we watch a lot of HGTV in our house and one of the things that drives
Speaker 2:  me the most crazy is whenever they stage the houses at the
Speaker 2:  end, they're always beautiful and perfect and well set up. And you always
Speaker 2:  sit there and go, well where's the TV gonna go? They're gonna have to flip
Speaker 2:  all this around 'cause they're gonna have to have a TV because you have to
Speaker 2:  have a tv.
Speaker 7:  I it, I'm the, the fact that people will spend money, I'll answer the
Speaker 7:  actual question with the Frame tv, but I'm just embedded in this question,
Speaker 7:  in this thought process is the end of the assumption
Speaker 7:  that everyone's gonna watch TV and once you break that assumption,
Speaker 7:  everything goes to hell. The
Speaker 2:  Description is kind of, I have a space on a wall where I'm supposed to put
Speaker 2:  a tv, not I want a tv. That is kind of the premise of this question.
Speaker 2:  You're right.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Put up, hang up a picture,
Speaker 7:  you're gonna,
Speaker 2:  But what If, you bought a thousand dollars TV that let you hang up all the
Speaker 2:  pictures,
Speaker 7:  Right? Can I? You sure may. Maybe that's what you want and you should spend
Speaker 7:  the money on that. Right? But if what you want
Speaker 7:  is to sometimes watch tv,
Speaker 7:  you should spend $200 on a 55 inch TV and put it on a roller stand
Speaker 7:  and roll it into the garage and then roll it back out when you wanna
Speaker 7:  watch tv. Like, and you will quickly find that maybe you never wanted to
Speaker 7:  watch TV at all. And I, I just as a person who has
Speaker 7:  giant expensive TVs and wants to watch movies on them,
Speaker 7:  I every single day think, boy this TV
Speaker 7:  is off most of the time. Like we don't have it on all the time.
Speaker 7:  I have friends and family that keep their TVs on 24 7.
Speaker 7:  Fine. That's another way to go. But it doesn't sound like that's what Pete
Speaker 7:  wants to do. No, the reason I'm always ranting and raving about the Frame
Speaker 7:  TV is that the TV of it is
Speaker 7:  pretty compromised, right? It's a, it's a very old panel. It doesn't have
Speaker 7:  local dimming backlight. It's not Samsung's latest l CD tech.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't have Dolby vision, which is a Samsung choice.
Speaker 7:  It Prince Tieszen like I I'm just sorry. Yeah. Right. Like it's all, it's
Speaker 7:  all this stuff, but it has the matte finish and it has
Speaker 7:  the art store and you can put a frame on it and you can hang it on the wall
Speaker 7:  and people prioritize how it looks way over the picture
Speaker 7:  quality. Right. Or the how the TV of it works.
Speaker 7:  And that's, and that's fine. I'm just saying it's just a short hop to the
Speaker 7:  next thing. So Pete, what I recommend is you really feel like you need to
Speaker 7:  have a Mac finished TV showing a picture. There are now much cheaper
Speaker 7:  rifts on a Frame TV from a bunch of companies.
Speaker 7:  TCL has one, ENS has one, right? Like everyone knows
Speaker 7:  this is the market and I think the the prices will come down the Frame TV
Speaker 7:  itself is whatever, like the Art store, same thing has done a great job with
Speaker 7:  the art store. They have spent a lot of time and energy
Speaker 7:  making the deals and getting the licenses and da da da. But are you gonna
Speaker 7:  pay $50 a month for the art store If? You're not. Then you should just get
Speaker 7:  another matte finished TV that can be framed of which now there are several
Speaker 7:  and put up a picture of your family or something.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Ironically, Pete I think is coming into this thinking. He's, he's kind
Speaker 2:  of like really trying to decide which is the best TV to buy, which like would
Speaker 2:  make him Neli people. He's actually my people. He's like, I I don't care
Speaker 2:  about my tv, I just need to have one. Right. Like I think if you're starting
Speaker 2:  from a 20-year-old tv, frankly the Frame TV is probably gonna
Speaker 2:  look great. The the 20-year-old panel you had on your wall, it's probably
Speaker 2:  a big upgrade to even the Frame tv. But I do think you're right that clearly
Speaker 2:  the, the goal is not I want the best television. Is it the Frame tv?
Speaker 2:  Like I don't think anyone is arguing that it's that, and that's not what
Speaker 2:  Pete wants either. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  If, you wanna spend a thousand dollars on a TV at So Crate you should buy
Speaker 7:  a 55 inch ole.
Speaker 2:  Right. But I think if, if, if the question is like, how do I solve this specific
Speaker 2:  problem that I have, it seems like the cheapest riff on the frame TV
Speaker 2:  is probably what you're after
Speaker 7:  Or get What's that? Samsung's easel tv. These are all expensive. Hell Oh
Speaker 7:  yeah. Get that LG Suitcase tv. I'm not
Speaker 7:  kidding. That's actually, you don't want a tv.
Speaker 2:  That might be the Solve It,
Speaker 7:  Buy the TV that goes in a suitcase and put it on the kitchen table once a
Speaker 7:  month when you wanna watch a movie. Like yeah, there are, there are just
Speaker 7:  many, many more ways to solve the problem of sometimes
Speaker 7:  we all want to sit around a screen, get a projector and
Speaker 7:  hang up a Bedsheet
Speaker 2:  So I had the projector thought, but I think the place it sits in
Speaker 2:  Pete's house where it's like a space that gets a lot of light and is kind
Speaker 2:  of screwy. That might be, that might undo the projector, but, but I
Speaker 2:  think the, the TV you can put away theory here in some
Speaker 2:  way is actually maybe the solution.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I looked it up, I'd forgotten what it's called. It's the LG Stand By
Speaker 7:  Me Go.
Speaker 7:  It's a 27 inch tv. It's in a, you know, it's something like a, one of those
Speaker 7:  like James Bond metal briefcases. It's expensive, it lists
Speaker 7:  it over a thousand, I bet on Black Friday. It gets really cheap.
Speaker 7:  Buy a Smart Monitor. I have a 40 inch Samsung smart
Speaker 7:  monitor that I bought for $300. Throw that in a closet. Like,
Speaker 7:  I'm just saying, there are many, many more ways to solve this problem
Speaker 7:  or buy a cheap frame tv. But I, I've just, every time I get this question
Speaker 7:  out, I hear from people who are like, I want a TV
Speaker 7:  that looks good when it's off and I'm constantly coming back to it is
Speaker 7:  just a tiny jump to I don't need this at all.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. I mean, it makes me think, do you remember that CESA
Speaker 2:  few years ago where LG had that rollable TV that you like pulled up out of
Speaker 2:  a case? Like that's the kind of thing we all need
Speaker 2:  is like, I just, I wanna be able to hide that behind a bunch of books and
Speaker 2:  then pull it out, unroll it and watch a movie and then put it away. And I
Speaker 2:  think like that's the sort of thing that would be great. And I think
Speaker 2:  the, the thing about Pete's question I keep thinking about is, is if I put
Speaker 2:  this TV here, my kids will want something on it. And like, I'm sure
Speaker 2:  you feel that, but like, oh God, do I feel that I would love to be
Speaker 2:  able to, I hide the remote now because if he can't find the remote,
Speaker 2:  I'm like, oh, sorry, I can't find the remote. But he, he goes, he just points
Speaker 2:  at the tv, which is at his eye level and is like, put it on
Speaker 7:  And it would be,
Speaker 2:  It's, I, there there is more and more appeal to putting the TV away
Speaker 2:  than ever. For
Speaker 7:  Me it's all, it's all fun and games until they get iPads,
Speaker 7:  that problem instantly resolves the second the iPad or the Chromebook is
Speaker 7:  delivered. Right. For better and for worse. Even things that I've tried to
Speaker 7:  turn into, like this is a a TV thing,
Speaker 7:  the ERAS tour, we're gonna watch this on the tv. She instantly figured out
Speaker 7:  how to get it on Disney Plus, right? Like everything moved yesterday. I walked
Speaker 7:  into our kitchen and she was listening to music on her iPad speakers
Speaker 7:  in a house where she's surrounded by speakers can just
Speaker 7:  speak into the void to ask a music service to start playing
Speaker 7:  and knows how to use airplay. I've taught my 6-year-old how to use airplay,
Speaker 7:  still listening to music on her iPad speakers. What are we gonna do about
Speaker 7:  this? Yeah, I,
Speaker 2:  I bought a whole Sonos system and my wife listens to podcasts out of the
Speaker 2:  speaker on her phone and it will never, ever stop making me crazy. Mine
Speaker 7:  As well. I'm just saying, Pete, buy what you buy, what you want, buy what
Speaker 7:  fits your budget, buy most people just prioritize size.
Speaker 7:  All TVs are bright. I'm gonna call out Casey Newton here. Casey asked me
Speaker 7:  on TV to buy and I told him and then he bought a Frame TV and I said, how's
Speaker 7:  the picture? And he was like, it's so bright. And that was the end of that
Speaker 7:  conversation.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that, that's, that's
Speaker 2:  Fine. Casey is also my people when it comes to
Speaker 7:  TVs. Yeah. We're talking about this in early November, so we're just a few
Speaker 7:  days away from Black Friday so that the Frame TV will go on. Huge sale always
Speaker 7:  does Last year's frame tv, which is fine. They're
Speaker 7:  Samsung spends no money developing these. It's the same TV every year and
Speaker 7:  they just collect huge margins on them last year's Frame TV will
Speaker 7:  go on even deeper sale. And then you've got the new class of
Speaker 7:  competitors, right? You've got the High Sense Canvas tv,
Speaker 7:  the T-C-L-N-X-T, frame tv, the next frame tv.
Speaker 7:  Amazon has the, the Fire TV Omni, which has adaptive
Speaker 7:  brightness and art. There's just a lot of these and they're all gonna go
Speaker 7:  on sale on Black Friday and it's, it's worth just looking at them and
Speaker 7:  thinking, will this solve my problem of it's there.
Speaker 7:  That's the problem you're trying to solve.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I just looked it up. By the way, the 55 inch Omni TV currently on sale
Speaker 2:  for $369, like this is, this is a cheaper
Speaker 2:  problem to solve than a thousand dollars for mtv. However you choose to solve
Speaker 2:  it, you can do it for less than a thousand dollars for mtv. I feel pretty
Speaker 2:  good about that
Speaker 7:  And I'm a hundred percent confident that they'll be even cheaper on
Speaker 7:  Black Friday.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there we go. That's just the way it goes. Awesome. All right, I hope
Speaker 2:  this helps Pete. Let us know what you end up doing and send us pictures of
Speaker 2:  your setup. I'm very curious, NELI, thank you as always.
Speaker 7:  You're dead to me.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who came
Speaker 2:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about at The Verge dot com v's. Review of the eight Sleep thing
Speaker 2:  is great. Allison's story about a AI DJs, all of our
Speaker 2:  many, many, too many frankly, stories about frame TV's,
Speaker 2:  all of it on the website. I'll put some links in the show notes. But as always,
Speaker 2:  read The Verge dot com. It's a good website. I like it. And as
Speaker 2:  always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other televisions
Speaker 2:  that you'd like to spend too much money on. You can always email us at Vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com or like I said, call the hotline. Eight six six VERGE
Speaker 2:  one, one. we love hearing from you the slack room that all the questions
Speaker 2:  get pumped into is bumping my friends. It's great times in there. Thank
Speaker 2:  you to everybody who calls and thank you to everybody who emails. This show's
Speaker 2:  produced by Liam James, Wil Poor and Eric Gomez. Vergecast is VERGE production
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. neli and I'll be back on
Speaker 2:  Friday to talk about all the AI news, some more Mac
Speaker 2:  stuff. Just a whole lot going on right now. We'll see you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll