# Transcript
ID: ab8cdb20-0829-4ddf-937c-78719d560e98
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8793600971836145754/2913271150673695885/s93290-US-2262s-1716767988.mp3
Description: On this episode of The Vergecast, the fourth and final installment of our series on the five senses of video games, we asked Polygon’s Charlie Hall to help us make sense of the current state of the art in flight simulation. Hall, who once spent more than four months in VR mapping the edge of the Milky Way galaxy in Elite: Dangerous, has more experience in a virtual cockpit than most. We wanted to know how the pros set up their simulators to get the most realistic experience and why it’s so complicated to make a virtual world look like the real one.
Speaker 3:  so excited we get to like, have you on instead of just
Speaker 3:  you were like all up about wanting to do a whole thing about televisions.
Speaker 1:  I did. I am a huge display nerd. I find new
Speaker 1:  tandem ole screens to just be, to me, that's my sports,
Speaker 1:  but David wouldn't let me do that. Listener lucky for you.
Speaker 3:  Nothing makes great audio like deep dives into display
Speaker 3:  technology. That's, that's kinda how I feel.
Speaker 1:  Agree to disagree, agree to disagree. But yeah, the, the journey
Speaker 1:  took me back to my childhood, which was a very big surprise. And it turns
Speaker 1:  out the thing that was the the most advanced, most
Speaker 1:  spectacular visual experience you could have back when I was a kid
Speaker 1:  is arguably still the same thing. And that's flight simulators. Mm.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Back when I was a kid, flight simulator was the thing I wanted to try
Speaker 1:  but couldn't, didn't have the computing power. So I, I just kind of admired
Speaker 1:  it from afar and stopped paying attention to it once I got a little older.
Speaker 1:  But fast forward to this episode and, and looking around at what
Speaker 1:  the visual landscape is in gaming and I was blown away
Speaker 1:  by what you can recreate in a flight simulator today. It's
Speaker 1:  just astonishing. So I reached out to Polygon, I said, who's the
Speaker 1:  flight sim person that I should be speaking to about this? And of course
Speaker 1:  they partnered me up with Charlie Hall, who I had a great conversation with
Speaker 1:  about all this. But what I really wanted to find out was
Speaker 1:  in 2024, what is the best way to experience a flight
Speaker 1:  simulator? Is it creating a wall of monitors? Is it
Speaker 1:  strapping a VR headset on? Is it something in between?
Speaker 1:  And the answer was not as obvious as I thought it would be. And Charlie really
Speaker 1:  helped me understand what is a gimmick and what is actually useful when you're
Speaker 1:  trying to fly a virtual airplane. Okay.
Speaker 3:  So before we get into it, just give me the like super high level,
Speaker 3:  what is it about Flight Simulator that is so sort of uniquely
Speaker 3:  visual? Like when I think of really visual games, you think about the sort
Speaker 3:  of big huge open world like No Man Sky kind of games with like
Speaker 3:  beautiful graphics and it's always in space and everything is happening.
Speaker 3:  Flight Simulator seems otherwise like, it's just like a bunch of buttons
Speaker 3:  and you're in a cockpit. Like what, what is it about Flight Simulator that
Speaker 3:  felt so like specifically visual to you?
Speaker 1:  Absolutely. The more fantasy like games,
Speaker 1:  in fact even flight simulators that take place in space are actually a lot
Speaker 1:  easier for us to create because they're not based on something in real life
Speaker 1:  that we can compare it to. Whereas in a flight simulator, like for instance,
Speaker 1:  Microsoft, Flight Simulator, you've got models of real planes at real
Speaker 1:  airports. You're actually flying a real life
Speaker 1:  recreation of planet Earth. You can literally fly
Speaker 1:  all the way around the earth and If, you were to look at a bird's eye view
Speaker 1:  of what you're seeing. It is one to one exact to
Speaker 1:  satellite imagery that Microsoft has been building over many, many years.
Speaker 3:  And if I'm not mistaken, there are a lot of people on the internet who like
Speaker 3:  make it their job to find when that is wrong. And
Speaker 3:  that like the stakes for screwing up the length of a runway at the airport
Speaker 3:  in flight simulator are actually like pretty high.
Speaker 1:  Very high, yes. Okay. Everything from the hat switches to the
Speaker 1:  airports to the airplane reflections on the outside. They, they try for
Speaker 1:  the most accurate representation as you can get. And that's a lot harder
Speaker 1:  than just creating some wacky looking spaceship that you'd
Speaker 1:  see in in a Sci-fi movie.
Speaker 3:  Got it. Fair enough. All right, well, before we get into it, I should say
Speaker 3:  I haven't really been a flight simulator guy and still I'm sitting here looking
Speaker 3:  at my one measly 24 inch monitor and I feel like this episode is about to
Speaker 3:  cost me a tremendous amount of money. So with that as a warning to everybody,
Speaker 3:  here's Liam and Charlie.
Speaker 1:  Charlie Hall, Welcome To, The Vergecast. Glad to be here. So I
Speaker 1:  was lucky enough to be the producer chosen to do the Vision
Speaker 1:  episode for this gaming series that we've been running the last three
Speaker 1:  Sundays. I couldn't help myself. I went back to being an
Speaker 1:  8-year-old kid with Packard Bell 46 computer
Speaker 1:  wanting to play video games. And the one I wanted
Speaker 1:  to play the most but couldn't actually run on my machine was
Speaker 1:  Microsoft Flight Simulator.
Speaker 4:  Yes, yes, yes. Yeah. The, the original like
Speaker 4:  crisis for PC gaming, right. Does it run Flight
Speaker 4:  Simulator?
Speaker 1:  Absolutely. This was 1993 or 1994. And yeah,
Speaker 1:  I just, I couldn't run Flight Simulator and probably because of that,
Speaker 1:  right? I wanted to play it so badly, even though as
Speaker 1:  you know, a third grade kid, I probably wouldn't have had the
Speaker 1:  patience to sit through the pre-flight checks and actually get a plane off
Speaker 1:  the ground in Flight Simulator. Didn't matter. I wanted to play that game
Speaker 1:  because it just felt like something above and
Speaker 1:  beyond a normal video game that you were flying in the air, but it also
Speaker 1:  felt as close to real in 19 93, 19 94
Speaker 1:  graphics that you could get.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely.
Speaker 1:  So fast forward to today, working adult with a salary.
Speaker 1:  I could actually afford things like a gaming PC that could run Flight Simulator.
Speaker 1:  I wanted to see what does Flight Simulator feel like and look like
Speaker 1:  today, and quite a bit has changed in Flight Simulator in
Speaker 1:  30 years.
Speaker 4:  It has.
Speaker 1:  So maybe you could tell me a little bit about your experience with Flight
Speaker 1:  Simulator. I know that Microsoft's been doing this for quite some
Speaker 1:  time, but you know, there was some time in between where there was
Speaker 1:  a dearth of flight simulators out there. What's the deal with Microsoft?
Speaker 1:  Flight Simulator? Well,
Speaker 4:  Much like you, I started playing Microsoft Flight Simulator in
Speaker 4:  like the, the late eighties, early nineties. My
Speaker 4:  dad actually worked at Bell Laboratories here in, in northern
Speaker 4:  Illinois. So he was able to bring home kind of is almost like
Speaker 4:  company surplus, these fairly high-end
Speaker 4:  switching terminals, basically. So I had a PC
Speaker 4:  sixty three hundred and eighty eighty six board. And so I was playing an
Speaker 4:  old version of Microsoft Flight Simulator. I had the ad lib sound card, right?
Speaker 4:  So I had all the good stuff and I had my gravis joystick
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 1:  Oh wow. You had a gravis.
Speaker 4:  I did, but it, it didn't have the twist rudder, right? So I had to do rudder
Speaker 4:  with the keyboard anyway. And so I was able to take off and get
Speaker 4:  up and going from MIGS field, you know, back when there was a MIGS field
Speaker 4:  before Mayor Daley put a couple of exes through it. And that really
Speaker 4:  gave birth to this kind of life long gaming
Speaker 4:  obsession with flight for me. I went deep on flight
Speaker 4:  simulator, I got all the mods as they were going up for clearance at Toys
Speaker 4:  Ross. Right? I remember a science fair project that I did
Speaker 4:  in eighth grade where I combined Sim City and
Speaker 4:  Microsoft Flight Simulator and took the teacher on a tour
Speaker 4:  of my sim city that I had rebuilt in
Speaker 4:  Microsoft Flight Simulator. Like I was way into it as a kid.
Speaker 1:  I just need to pause, I just need to pause for a moment to just tell the
Speaker 1:  listener the, the face I just had on was in of, of
Speaker 1:  complete awe. I mean, those were the games of my childhood sim
Speaker 1:  city flight simulator that, that was so impressed, so impressed. Go on. I
Speaker 1:  I apologize for interrupting.
Speaker 4:  But the way that Microsoft Flight Simulator was built
Speaker 4:  back in the day was entirely by hand. The, the
Speaker 4:  John Hancock building, the Prudential building, all of those
Speaker 4:  famous buildings in the Chicago skyline were built
Speaker 4:  by hand. So If you, If you went too long on your approach and you
Speaker 4:  hit the Adler Planetarium there at the end of MIGS Field. Like somebody put
Speaker 4:  that there to impeach your progress in the game. But that is not
Speaker 4:  necessarily the case in the modern version of
Speaker 4:  Microsoft Flight Simulator. And we can, we can certainly get to the modern
Speaker 4:  version of Microsoft Flight Simulator. But you know, for a while there
Speaker 4:  Microsoft kind of kept the heartbeat going,
Speaker 4:  right? And then kind of some new competitors came into the space.
Speaker 4:  XPLAN is another really popular platform that kind of
Speaker 4:  grew up during the, the early two thousands and kind of came
Speaker 4:  of age and kind of the 20 teams. But then there was this
Speaker 4:  big surge of space flight simulation as well.
Speaker 4:  This Chris Roberts, one of the co-creators of the
Speaker 4:  Wing Commander franchise, kind of brought that back to life with Star Citizen,
Speaker 4:  this massive ongoing decade long project to,
Speaker 4:  to recreate kind of the nineties dream of Wing
Speaker 4:  commander inside that game. And then of course, elite
Speaker 4:  came into its own with a brand new version called Elite Dangerous.
Speaker 4:  And I've, I've also had the experience in both of those. But after
Speaker 4:  both of those products came to market, that's when Microsoft came
Speaker 4:  back to it basically with this new vision for
Speaker 4:  Microsoft Flight Simulator. Which while there are some things in the game
Speaker 4:  that are kind of made and rendered and and done by hand,
Speaker 4:  the vast majority of the game is, is not done by hand. It's actually done
Speaker 4:  with a very sophisticated, almost kind of
Speaker 4:  photogrammetry, which we can discuss too.
Speaker 1:  So yeah, 2020 rolls around and Microsoft releases what
Speaker 1:  to a layman's eyes like mine looks like
Speaker 1:  photorealistic flight simulation. How do they pull that off? Have GPUs
Speaker 1:  just gotten so good? What's, what is it that's making this look
Speaker 1:  so pretty?
Speaker 4:  Well, you gotta remember that Microsoft is, well it's a, it's a very
Speaker 4:  large company, Liam. And in addition to
Speaker 4:  having in its portfolio Microsoft Flight
Speaker 4:  Simulator, which I don't know if you're aware, is its oldest
Speaker 4:  piece of published software. It's older even than Windows.
Speaker 4:  In addition to owning Microsoft, Flight Simulator, well it
Speaker 4:  also owns this little thing called Bing. And Bing
Speaker 4:  is, in addition to being a very capable search engine, it is
Speaker 4:  also a entire suite of mapping tools. So just
Speaker 4:  so you can go to Google Maps, you can go to Bing Maps and you can find
Speaker 4:  your way around. But Bing has done something a little bit more
Speaker 4:  aggressively than Google has and that is capturing
Speaker 4:  satellite information of the entire world.
Speaker 4:  And so what Microsoft and its partners at a Sobo
Speaker 4:  studio, a French studio that actually did a lot of the heavy lifting on Microsoft
Speaker 4:  Flight Simulator, what they were able to do is take,
Speaker 4:  I dunno if it's two or four or five petabytes
Speaker 4:  of this satellite data that it's getting
Speaker 4:  that Microsoft owns effectively as part of Bing Maps. And
Speaker 4:  then it bolted Microsoft Flight Simulator to this data.
Speaker 4:  So when folks received Microsoft Flight Simulator in the
Speaker 4:  mail, or when they downloaded the client, they were really only downloading
Speaker 4:  a tiny fraction of what they needed to run the game.
Speaker 4:  You get the, the app outlet, you get the client, you get, you get it started
Speaker 4:  up and then it starts downloading, I think it was
Speaker 4:  120 gigabytes on launch day. It was one of the largest
Speaker 4:  downloads on launch day that I had ever received. And
Speaker 4:  that was just the basic information. After you get that
Speaker 4:  120 gigabytes, then it starts streaming data directly
Speaker 4:  from Bing. So If you go, like, I went to Egypt to
Speaker 4:  be parked, you know, 2000 feet over the great pyramid at Giza.
Speaker 4:  It's streaming in satellite data,
Speaker 4:  photogrammetry information, all of this sophisticated information
Speaker 4:  from Bing Maps and putting it directly on the screen
Speaker 4:  in front of you using all kinds of technological
Speaker 4:  wizardry. And it's literally applying that satellite data
Speaker 4:  to other data sets that it's pulling in. It has
Speaker 4:  topographical information that it literally skins the
Speaker 4:  ground with satellite information at launch. It was really
Speaker 4:  weird. It looked kinda like there were rivers that were kinda crawling up
Speaker 4:  the sides of mountains. They hadn't quite gotten it dialed in
Speaker 4:  quite perfectly as the game has progressed since 2020.
Speaker 4:  That resolution, the, the difference between the topographical map
Speaker 4:  and the satellite data has become even better. You're literally
Speaker 4:  able to fly over the entire surface of the entire world.
Speaker 4:  And it looks like it does in bing maps.
Speaker 4:  It, it actually looks better because it's, it's putting in trees,
Speaker 4:  it's putting in houses, it's put, it's putting color on the
Speaker 4:  roofs of these houses and it's doing all of it automatically without really
Speaker 4:  any human intervention on that landscape. It's, it's really remarkable.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, I have wondered a couple times why the, the map companies,
Speaker 1:  the Google maps, the Apple Maps being don't just copy Flight Simulator
Speaker 1:  because it is that much just prettier looking
Speaker 1:  and more realistic than the 3D maps we get now. They
Speaker 4:  Go further than that though. They bring in real world air traffic. So
Speaker 4:  you are flying in the sky next to other planes that are
Speaker 4:  really in the real sky. They bring in real weather
Speaker 4:  data from actual weather data in real time. You
Speaker 4:  can actually bring in other players as well to act as like air traffic
Speaker 4:  controllers so that they can control the airports that you're flying around.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's an incredible multilayered
Speaker 4:  multiplayer simulation.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, simulation is truly the only word for it.
Speaker 1:  Okay, I want to get into flight simulator peripherals, but first we're gonna
Speaker 1:  take a quick break to listen to some ads.
Speaker 1:  what maybe a, a typical gamer has with a 16 by nine
Speaker 1:  computer screen in front of them. What are some of the things that you've
Speaker 1:  heard about or maybe you've even personally tried to kind of
Speaker 1:  go beyond the 16 by nine box that
Speaker 1:  constraints a normal flight sim experience.
Speaker 4:  The most easy and frankly the most popular
Speaker 4:  next step is to go with multiple monitors. Some folks
Speaker 4:  will do two, but then you have that bezel kind of right in front of you there.
Speaker 4:  So the kind of the standard is three monitors. And so there
Speaker 4:  are companies that will make triple monitor arms
Speaker 4:  with the intent being that you tell the program, be
Speaker 4:  it Microsoft, Flight Simulator or xplan or star citizen, whatever you're
Speaker 4:  using, I have three monitors and then you kind of calibrate it in and
Speaker 4:  you've got a view out the front of the canopy on your middle monitor to
Speaker 4:  whatever degree works for you. A view out the left side of the canopy and
Speaker 4:  the right side of the canopy. And at its most fundamental, this lets
Speaker 4:  you do things like line up your approach when you're landing, when you're
Speaker 4:  making that final turn, you can see the runway, you can
Speaker 4:  time that turn appropriately without doing any crazy stuff with a hat, switch
Speaker 4:  your keyboard. So that is kind of the most typical
Speaker 4:  adaptation. The next step up from there is actually
Speaker 4:  my preferred way to fly and that's what something called the track IR
Speaker 4:  or track infrared. So If, you remember the we right?
Speaker 4:  The dearly departed Nintendo we, it had that remote control
Speaker 4:  and there was infrared emitter on the front of the remote control. Then
Speaker 4:  you'd put that bar up on the top of your TV and the bar would
Speaker 4:  track where you're pointing the we mode, right? Sure. Track IR works
Speaker 4:  basically the same way. You get three little
Speaker 4:  IR emitters, you clip those to your headset or you clip it to
Speaker 4:  your hat, you just make sure it's on your head. And then there is
Speaker 4:  a receiving panel that you put on the top of your middle monitor
Speaker 4:  and it just kind of sits there. And yeah, as you move your
Speaker 4:  head, the panel on your monitor can see how
Speaker 4:  those three points of light move in space and it interprets that
Speaker 4:  as head movement inside the game. So when I'm using
Speaker 4:  my track ir, I can just look ever so slightly to my left
Speaker 4:  in the calibration of the track ir it will accelerate my head
Speaker 4:  movement inside the game. So even though I'm still looking at my middle monitor
Speaker 4:  on the screen, what I'll be seeing is fully behind me. Very cool.
Speaker 4:  And so you can calibrate this to meet your needs for a number of
Speaker 4:  different games. I use it also for arm three. I used to use it for
Speaker 4:  Daisy and it gave me a neck, which is not something that you get in most
Speaker 4:  first person shooters. Tremendously helpful when you're looking down a gun
Speaker 4:  site to be able to look to the left, look to the right without taking that
Speaker 4:  gun off your shoulder. But in a flight simulator it's just
Speaker 4:  situational awareness and it's increasingly important when you're doing any
Speaker 4:  type of combat flying. So when I'm playing in elite
Speaker 4:  dangerous, it's very easy to lose my quarry to lose
Speaker 4:  my bogey, lose the thing that I'm trying to shoot at. And I can look around
Speaker 4:  really with my actual head and the view changes on
Speaker 4:  my screen and it is delightful an alternative
Speaker 4:  solution to that. And it's something that I've had less success with. It's
Speaker 4:  eye tracking technology. A company called Tobe does that, or
Speaker 4:  Tobi, I don't know how to pronounce that company correctly, but
Speaker 4:  it's more in line with the, the form factor of the old
Speaker 4:  we, it kind of sits on the bottom or the top of your monitor and it literally
Speaker 4:  looks at your eyes and as you move your eyes it changes the view
Speaker 4:  for you.
Speaker 1:  So it seems like Charlie peripheral vision in flight is
Speaker 1:  essential, right? Absolutely. So, you know, casual gamer like
Speaker 1:  myself, I can't help wondering why not just throw a VR headset on
Speaker 1:  your, on your face. Have you tried that at all?
Speaker 4:  I have. I have actually in Elite Dangerous, I traveled
Speaker 4:  from the bubble, which is the area right around the Saul system in
Speaker 4:  the unfashionable Western spiral arm of our Milky Way galaxy.
Speaker 4:  And I went all the way across 65,000 plus light years to
Speaker 4:  Beagle Point, one of the furthest reaches in that game. And I spent four
Speaker 4:  months nightly making that trip and I did it all
Speaker 4:  in virtual reality with kind of, I think it was a launch Oculus,
Speaker 4:  if I remember correctly.
Speaker 1:  So you have a lot of experience in VR and I would imagine a very strong neck.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah, it was, it was daunting man. Probably by two to four hours
Speaker 4:  per week night. Yeah, it was a lot of travel. I was doing probably like 80
Speaker 4:  jumps a night to try and get where I was going. Anybody who's played elite
Speaker 4:  knows that that's a lot of, a lot of, yeah, a lot of push in the throttle
Speaker 4:  back and forth. But I've also done it in Microsoft, Flight Simulator. I've
Speaker 4:  done it in, I've tried to do it in Star Citizen and I've done it in a few
Speaker 4:  other flight simulators as well.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah, I mean a, as an apartment dweller, I'm looking around at my space
Speaker 1:  thinking, hmm, two or three screens that's that that'd be hard to fit on
Speaker 1:  my desk. But a VR headset seems, at least at first
Speaker 1:  thought to be the perfect solution for this. If I move my head up or
Speaker 1:  down left or right, it's, it's gonna show me what I would be
Speaker 1:  looking at in a cockpit. But there have to be some downsides of
Speaker 1:  it than the cost. Tell me about your, that four months in
Speaker 1:  vr, what was it like?
Speaker 4:  I mean, elite dangerous is a real pleasure
Speaker 4:  in VR and there's a reason for that. You're often
Speaker 4:  not looking at very much, it's, it's space Liam, there's a
Speaker 4:  planet, right? It's very far away. Looks like a star. There's a couple
Speaker 4:  thousand of those and, and that's it for the majority of your trip.
Speaker 4:  Now you get closer to a single celestial body, it's, it's very easy
Speaker 4:  for that, you know, circa 2014 client
Speaker 4:  to get the, the visuals right as you're coming closer to it.
Speaker 4:  So rarely do I have issues with frame rate in elite dangerous
Speaker 4:  Microsoft Flight Simulator is real hard though. And we're talking about,
Speaker 4:  I think I had an I seven or an I 9 32 gigs of Ram
Speaker 4:  2060 card I was working with and Microsoft Flight Simulator was
Speaker 4:  still very challenging frame rate wise.
Speaker 4:  And when you are flying, you do not want to
Speaker 4:  have a delay in your frame rates. You need to know where that
Speaker 4:  airplane is relative to air traffic around you relative to the ground, relative
Speaker 4:  to the runway at all times. So aside from just, you know,
Speaker 4:  the nausea that can be induced by the frames, lock it up
Speaker 4:  or skipping, not having that situational awareness is, is gonna end your
Speaker 4:  play through very quickly. But the other big issue that I had
Speaker 4:  on my trip to Beagle Point Elite Dangerous was, well I couldn't see the
Speaker 4:  keyboard and Elite Dangerous is unique. They actually
Speaker 4:  model the ctech X 52
Speaker 4:  joystick into the game. And so it was a partnership
Speaker 4:  between Cytech recently purchased by Logitech and
Speaker 4:  Frontier Developments to put their product in the game. So I looked down
Speaker 4:  in real life at the CYTECH X 52, same controller I'm using in the game,
Speaker 4:  but it doesn't move the same way all the time because I have my
Speaker 4:  bindings set differently than the game is expecting me to have my
Speaker 4:  binding sets. So when I use the rudder it shows my hand twisting. But
Speaker 4:  no, my feet are moving 'cause I have rudder pedals, so that's not one-to-one,
Speaker 4:  but there's a lot of buttons in the cockpit and I need this keyboard in front
Speaker 4:  of me in order to hit those buttons. And so that
Speaker 4:  required a lot of remapping of the controller. I was able to
Speaker 4:  remap what I needed to do all those lightspeed jumps to do all the
Speaker 4:  landing, to do all the maneuvering to the
Speaker 4:  buttons on my warthog throttle and the buttons on
Speaker 4:  my wart hog. I think it's an F 16
Speaker 4:  stick that I swapped out for the traditional warthog stick. But I was
Speaker 4:  able to do everything I needed to do using the buttons on the
Speaker 4:  joystick, including reset the center of my vr. But I
Speaker 4:  couldn't shut down the game, I couldn't pause the game for that.
Speaker 4:  I had to take off the helmet, I had to look down at my keyboard and it, it
Speaker 4:  takes you out of the experience a little bit, but mostly it's a performance
Speaker 4:  issue. Like if those frames are not where you need them to be, it's a very
Speaker 4:  uncomfortable experience and it's, it's not productive frankly. It's
Speaker 4:  better I feel to have the higher frame rate to have it on a monitor
Speaker 4:  in front of you. And I prefer to use track IR over VR because
Speaker 4:  of that.
Speaker 1:  Well it seems like the community agrees with you. I watched
Speaker 1:  many, many hours of people excitedly trying out
Speaker 1:  headsets from the MedQuest three, the valve index
Speaker 1:  of course the HT C vi and one in particular stood
Speaker 1:  out to me that a lot of flight sim enthusiasts were excited about
Speaker 1:  last year, which was the ax crystal. And it seems like
Speaker 1:  a very similar story to what we're seeing with even the Apple
Speaker 1:  Vision Pro, the kind of consumer focused version of one of these
Speaker 1:  VR headsets and that, you know, there's, there's a huge amount of
Speaker 1:  anticipation and excitement and then of course you get the thing and
Speaker 1:  you try it on and you, you see all the edge cases and
Speaker 1:  issues with it and you've now have this very expensive
Speaker 1:  device that you can strap to your head but you don't want to anymore. It
Speaker 1:  seems like, from what I'm gathering from the Flight sim
Speaker 1:  YouTube community is that a lot of people have tried these, these VR headsets
Speaker 1:  and gone back to that three monitor setup that you're talking about because
Speaker 1:  in the end that just still provides a better
Speaker 1:  experience. Is that, would you agree with that?
Speaker 4:  I would agree with that. It's absolutely been my experience. It's been my
Speaker 4:  experience in, you know, high-end flight sim YouTubers that
Speaker 4:  I follow. The folks like the Grim Reapers, the majority of
Speaker 4:  of their team I think does the, the one or two or three monitors set up
Speaker 4:  and so do the ground training centers for the F 35
Speaker 4:  and the F 22. Like when you look at the
Speaker 4:  military training regime for those latest generation fighters,
Speaker 4:  you know, it's a tactile experience for them. They
Speaker 4:  need to know that the buttons in the cockpit
Speaker 4:  are where the buttons are gonna be in the actual cockpit. And that's the
Speaker 4:  majority I think of what they're training to. I need to hit this switch
Speaker 4:  without even looking at it. That's the work. And they should already know
Speaker 4:  how to fly the airplane by that point. But yeah,
Speaker 4:  technologically it, it seems to be a better experience just working with
Speaker 4:  screens.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're gonna take another quick break then we'll get into whether VR
Speaker 1:  will ever be the future of flight simulators. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  simulators. And like the drawbacks to the human
Speaker 4:  physiology are real. I spent a lot of time,
Speaker 4:  for instance, reviewing Medal of Honor above and beyond, which was,
Speaker 4:  you know, the, the re-imagining of EAs classic first
Speaker 4:  person shooter. But for the Oculus Rift and review situations can be
Speaker 4:  stressful. And so I had to spend about six, eight hours reviewing
Speaker 4:  this game under a time crunch for embargo. And Liam, I
Speaker 4:  was laid out for the rest of the week. Oh, I bet it had a
Speaker 4:  deep, deeply bad thing happen to my inner
Speaker 4:  ear and all of the things that kept me upright. And it was no low level
Speaker 4:  nausea that I was stuck with for like the better part of three days.
Speaker 4:  So I don't enjoy first person shooter
Speaker 4:  games, I don't enjoy Minecraft in vr. I, I was there at that press
Speaker 4:  event as well for Minecraft vr and it was not a pleasurable experience, but
Speaker 4:  flight simulators, they work for me. And
Speaker 4:  I'll tell you why. Elite in particular has a
Speaker 4:  permanent horizon line in front of you. It is this transparent
Speaker 4:  dashboard piece that sits on the screen in front of you and it's a similar
Speaker 4:  thing with a flight simul. You've got that top of the cockpit
Speaker 4:  dashboard right there in front of you and it eases a lot of that motion
Speaker 4:  sickness for me. And that may not be true of everybody,
Speaker 4:  but actually having it on your head for more than an hour or
Speaker 4:  two does get to be taxing. I would come out
Speaker 4:  of my office after my trip to Beagle Point and the kids would make fun of
Speaker 4:  me because I'd have this trench down my bushy hair
Speaker 4:  on the top of my head. I'd have goggle marks on my face.
Speaker 4:  The tip of my nose would be red. 'cause I'm a six and a half foot tall human.
Speaker 4:  And all of me doesn't quite fit inside of most VR helmets because of
Speaker 4:  that. But also, especially with something like, I've had a
Speaker 4:  lot of experience with the HTC Vive very heavy
Speaker 4:  on the front. When you're using the wireless set, there's a
Speaker 4:  battery that you have to wear on your waist to get truly untethered
Speaker 4:  access to that platform. And it's just a lot of stuff that weighs you
Speaker 4:  down and yeah, there's some fatigue on your neck. So I don't know,
Speaker 4:  it's, some headsets are better than others in my opinion,
Speaker 4:  but I mean, it's, it's certainly nothing like wearing a, a
Speaker 4:  military style helmet for a long period of time. That is a weight
Speaker 4:  on your head, but it's, it's not the most comfortable thing either.
Speaker 4:  Microsoft Flighting leader does something really clever in this regard. You
Speaker 4:  can actually accelerate your flight, like you do the takeoff part, you can
Speaker 4:  do the landing part and you just hit a couple of buttons and it takes that
Speaker 4:  whole middle part and just compresses it down to a couple of seconds. So
Speaker 4:  you're, you're doing the most active, the most engaging parts of the flight
Speaker 4:  during your time in vr and you don't have to, you know, do the Overland autopilot
Speaker 4:  section for four hours to get to la
Speaker 1:  Oh, that's very cool. I didn't know they they had that feature. That's nice.
Speaker 1:  So Charlie, as Microsoft continues to push the boundaries of
Speaker 1:  what's possible with Flight Simulator making it feel
Speaker 1:  more and more realistic to what you'd experience in a real cockpit,
Speaker 1:  do you think that VR may come back into the fold? Or do you
Speaker 1:  think that the visual experience is best represented
Speaker 1:  by a wall of monitors kind of making you feel like you're inside a cockpit?
Speaker 4:  I am really excited about the
Speaker 4:  mixed reality work that I'm seeing out of the Apple VR
Speaker 4:  in particular. And here's why. When Microsoft
Speaker 4:  set out to make Flight Simulator and Flight Simulator 2024, the
Speaker 4:  latest edition of it, they worked very closely
Speaker 4:  with aircraft manufacturers, with Boeing, with
Speaker 4:  Airbus, with folks like Icon. And what they've done is
Speaker 4:  they've actually baked into the game pre-flight
Speaker 4:  checklists and If, you go down those pre-flight checklists.
Speaker 4:  Well, lo and behold, you can actually interact with all of
Speaker 4:  the gauges and dials and buttons and switches in the aircraft.
Speaker 4:  It is a hot dashboard in front of you. You
Speaker 4:  need merely point your face down with your track ir use
Speaker 4:  your mouse to reach out and click those switches. But I look
Speaker 4:  forward to a day where there's some kind of mixed reality
Speaker 4:  in front of me where I can see my hand or a vision of my hand
Speaker 4:  and I can reach that hand out and I can touch this virtual
Speaker 4:  dashboard in front of me and change the altitude setting and
Speaker 4:  switch to the other gas tank and I can lower the
Speaker 4:  landing gear really with my hands virtually rather than using
Speaker 4:  the keyboard. But I don't have a good
Speaker 4:  expectation that that is gonna happen anytime soon
Speaker 4:  because there are better cheaper solutions
Speaker 4:  like monitors and keyboards out there. I don't know that there is enough
Speaker 4:  desire, enough of an audience really to make that happen,
Speaker 4:  but I, I can see how it could work. Does that make sense?
Speaker 1:  That makes perfect sense And, and honestly, mixed reality is
Speaker 1:  probably the perfect technology. It's exciting to see some of, some of the
Speaker 1:  things we can do now with them. But what I'm really excited about is,
Speaker 1:  is where, you know, of course it's the joke that right VR is just a few years
Speaker 1:  away or you know, this is the year of Linux on the
Speaker 1:  desktop. So many of those in, in the technology world. But it really does
Speaker 1:  feel like we've gotten to a point now where we can comfortably
Speaker 1:  say mixed reality will eventually get to a point that can
Speaker 1:  offer us some experiences that we just, we can't pull off right now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And just like they have the capacity to stream in new satellite
Speaker 4:  data or new weather data, I'm confident that a OBO and, and
Speaker 4:  Microsoft have the capability to, to add that in there too because
Speaker 4:  they've got those dashboards, those cockpits that, that really do have working
Speaker 4:  switches really do work like the real thing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Ooh, it's very exciting. My third grade
Speaker 1:  self, just hoping and wishing for a computer to one day run flight
Speaker 1:  sim has been reignited I'm very excited about, about this future.
Speaker 1:  So we'll have to have you back to try those, those new things when they,
Speaker 1:  when they finally come out.
Speaker 4:  I can't wait. I will be there and ready to fly. Let's do it.
Speaker 1:  Charlie, thank you so much for coming on the show. Thank you
Speaker 4:  Liam. This was a blast.
Speaker 3:  Thank you Liam. Thank you Charlie, thank you to everybody who listened to
Speaker 3:  this show. That is it for The. Vergecast for today. I honestly
Speaker 3:  believe I'm about to go buy a bunch of new monitors. I don't even really
Speaker 3:  know that I'm a flight simulator guy. I've dabbled with it in the past.
Speaker 3:  I also at one point got very excited about a Formula one simulator.
Speaker 3:  That's a whole thing. But at some point in this episode, I just looked at
Speaker 3:  my one monitor and I'm like, this isn't enough. It's time. Anyway,
Speaker 3:  thank you as always for listening. This is the last episode in our Five
Speaker 3:  Senses of Gaming series, but we will be back with more special content for
Speaker 3:  you really soon. We have some more fun series coming up between now and the
Speaker 3:  end of the year. It's gonna be great. As always. There is lots more to read
Speaker 3:  on gaming and everything going on in tech at The Verge dot com. It's a
Speaker 3:  website, we like it a bunch. This show is produced by Liam James Wil Pour
Speaker 3:  and Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the
Speaker 3:  Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back on Tuesday to talk about Microsoft
Speaker 3:  PCs, the Smart Home, and a whole bunch of other stuff. We'll see you then.
Speaker 3:  Rock and roll