# Transcript
ID: d8e24299-ab44-4bca-9765-4b4c09dd5f47
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4105530968187231613/4149795874993533850/s93290-US-2591s-1729424736.mp3
Description: For the last eight months, David Cogen has been living a double life. By day: a YouTuber and creator, the face of the TheUnlockr channel, reviewing phones and testing ebikes and explaining how food smokers really work. By night and morning and every single other available in-between moment: a coffee shop entrepreneur, working to get a Brooklyn spot called Coffee Check up and running. In this episode, the second in the two-part miniseries that we’re calling How To Make It In The Future, Cogen tells the story of how a YouTuber becomes a coffee shop owner — and how to bring those two things together without ruining them both.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Robot Baristas.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend, David Pierce, and I am sitting here doing cold brew research.
Speaker 2:  So about a year ago, I started making overnight oats a lot. I really like
Speaker 2:  the idea of being able to right before I go to bed, basically make my breakfast
Speaker 2:  ticket in the fridge, and then it's ready for me when I get up in the morning.
Speaker 2:  It's really helpful having a kid around in the house who also needs breakfast
Speaker 2:  and likes to just run in circles, starting at 5:00 AM But it also just
Speaker 2:  feels nice. It's like one less decision I have to make when I first wake
Speaker 2:  up in the morning. So I've started trying to do the same thing with coffee,
Speaker 2:  making cold brew. I drink iced coffee of some kind, basically
Speaker 2:  365 days a year. But I also like the
Speaker 2:  idea of being able to do it the night before and then wake up and the thing
Speaker 2:  is ready for me and I just pour it and start the day that seems nicer than
Speaker 2:  what I do now, which is like a 10 minute process of weighing things
Speaker 2:  on a scale and gently pouring in concentric circles. It's just
Speaker 2:  too much. But boy, did I not realize
Speaker 2:  how deep the rabbit hole of cold brew is. The ratios, the
Speaker 2:  amount of time you're supposed to do it for, the thing you put the cold brew
Speaker 2:  in, it's supposed to be really simple. You put in beans, you pour in water,
Speaker 2:  the end time happens and then you have coffee.
Speaker 2:  Nope. Turns out like all coffee things. It is super complicated.
Speaker 2:  But luckily for me, this is what we're doing on The Vergecast today is
Speaker 2:  we're talking about coffee for this episode, which is the second episode
Speaker 2:  in our mini series that we've been calling How to Make It in the Future.
Speaker 2:  I'm talking to a guy named David Cogan, who you might know as the
Speaker 2:  Unlocker on YouTube. He's been a tech creator for a really long time
Speaker 2:  doing lots of reporting and lots of cool camera test videos
Speaker 2:  recently, and he's been a creator on YouTube since like 2009. He's been around
Speaker 2:  this for a long time, and very recently he opened a coffee shop,
Speaker 2:  just a full left turn pivot
Speaker 2:  in his career. He's still a YouTuber. He still wants to be a creator.
Speaker 2:  He's still trying to make all that work, but he also opened a coffee shop
Speaker 2:  in Brooklyn, and I have a lot of questions about that. I think this question
Speaker 2:  of what does it mean to marry those two things and
Speaker 2:  can you be both a small business owner and a content creator
Speaker 2:  without those things blurring together. I had a really
Speaker 2:  fun time talking to him, and I think you're gonna enjoy this conversation
Speaker 2:  too. He had a lot of thoughts about what it means to be a creator, what it
Speaker 2:  means to be a coffee shop owner, how the grind
Speaker 2:  of YouTube changes the way that you think about your career and
Speaker 2:  what you want out of your life. Why making YouTube videos and
Speaker 2:  being a creator is so intoxicating in the first place. It was incredibly
Speaker 2:  fun. I had a really good time hanging out with him in his coffee shop
Speaker 2:  in Brooklyn. We're gonna get to all of that But first. Apparently
Speaker 2:  I have to do cold brew 24 hours ahead of time, so I'm gonna go do that.
Speaker 2:  Then I'll come back. Then we'll get into it. This is The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right back.
Speaker 2:  assumed I was on the wrong block or had overshot and turned around,
Speaker 2:  but I wasn't. I was in the right place. I found the shop with this white
Speaker 2:  coffee emoji light and a green check mark emoji light on the front,
Speaker 2:  and otherwise no sign whatsoever that this is a coffee
Speaker 2:  shop, which means it's a very like cool hipster coffee shop. That's how you
Speaker 2:  know they're doing it. Found the place, went inside and found
Speaker 2:  a spot to sit. So I ordered a bacon, egg
Speaker 2:  and cheese personal pie. Not a hundred percent sure what
Speaker 2:  that means, but we're about to find out and I got a large coffee that I'm
Speaker 2:  very excited to try. It looks like the coffee here is called Founder's Blend,
Speaker 2:  which is extremely on brand. I approve now.
Speaker 2:  The plan is just to sit here, try to get some work done,
Speaker 2:  have aggressively judgy thoughts about the wifi and all the coffee gear
Speaker 2:  they're using here, and then wait for David to show up.
Speaker 2:  Let's do this. I found out later, by the way, that David himself
Speaker 2:  had made that pie. It was very good. One of those like hand pie
Speaker 2:  size things that comes in a little personal Tin Delicious, no notes.
Speaker 2:  The wifi in there was also extremely fast. There were so many
Speaker 2:  outlets in the room that it actually kind of made me laugh, trying to count
Speaker 2:  them all. And the coffee year was also pretty on point. I had
Speaker 2:  annoyingly few complaints in my first couple of hours at Coffee Check
Speaker 2:  At about 10 30. David himself showed up. He'd been out filming for the
Speaker 2:  morning, but he came in, stopped at the counter, said hi to the baristas,
Speaker 2:  checked in to see how things were going, and then came over and said hi to
Speaker 2:  me. He gave me a quick tour of the place, the shop in the front, the
Speaker 2:  production studio in the back. We walked around the kitchen. He was very
Speaker 2:  excited about an outlet thing that you could press on the counter and it
Speaker 2:  would pop up. He showed me all the USBC ports. He was very excited
Speaker 2:  about that. There were a bunch of e-bikes just sitting around. There was
Speaker 2:  a gigantic Samsung TV that he'd been sent to review. It all felt very familiar
Speaker 2:  to me as a person who has too many gadgets and loves
Speaker 2:  USBC. And then at the end of our tour, we sat down in this
Speaker 2:  huge podcast booth that he got from Finland at a huge
Speaker 2:  discount in exchange for letting the company use it for occasional demos
Speaker 2:  and sales tours. It's so big they like didn't have a place to put it.
Speaker 2:  So his studio is now also the sales
Speaker 2:  floor for this podcast booth. It's wild, but it seems to work.
Speaker 2:  It fits four people and three cameras in it all at once, just in
Speaker 2:  this little booth. And so while the coffee shop continued to
Speaker 2:  operate around us, David and I sat down and recorded this episode. I
Speaker 2:  asked him to begin with just to tell me his story and to start with the
Speaker 2:  story of how coffee became part of his whole persona and brand
Speaker 2:  in the first place. So I started doing these videos
Speaker 2:  occasionally where I would do like a battery test or a camera comparison.
Speaker 2:  And I, I was just kind of interested in vlogging and that kind of style,
Speaker 2:  but I wasn't doing that on the channel because I was a tech channel. And
Speaker 2:  So I started kind of making these battery tests and these camera
Speaker 2:  tests while kind of bouncing around and like filming them in a very vlog
Speaker 2:  esque style for those
Speaker 4:  Not familiar, a complete walkthrough on those channels where I try to go
Speaker 4:  through every single feature on a new device that I possibly can so you guys
Speaker 4:  are better prepared should you be in the market to actually go buy one. Now
Speaker 4:  with that said, there is a lot to go through.
Speaker 2:  And then I just kinda like somewhere between like Casey and I Stat and Marquez
Speaker 2:  Brownley was like, sure, stylistically, like Dead center was where you were
Speaker 2:  in Sidious with like, yeah, with like, yeah, that's, let's go with that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, because it was like not, not terribly technical, but not, but also
Speaker 2:  just kind of like running around and showing you things. Yeah, yeah, right.
Speaker 2:  And then editing it to a beat. So yeah, so that happened a bit
Speaker 2:  and then pandemic happened and during that I was filming in my apartment,
Speaker 2:  like everywhere other CRA was doing it. And I like kind of lost my
Speaker 2:  mind as we all did and as soon as like we were allowed really to kind of
Speaker 2:  go outside again, I was like, screw, I'm filming this outside now because
Speaker 2:  I've just done however many videos, literally in on the same coffee table
Speaker 2:  and So I went outside and just naturally went and got a coffee
Speaker 2:  in the beginning of the video and sat down and got my coffee and I went Coffee
Speaker 2:  Check. Like I got a coffee, right? Coffee Check. And then
Speaker 2:  I, then I would talk about the phone a little bit and then I kinda bounced
Speaker 2:  around and I did that. And then the, I posted that and, and I even,
Speaker 2:  I think even talked about like history in the first one. I like kind of just
Speaker 2:  went off the rails a little bit 'cause I was losing my mind. Sure. And but
Speaker 2:  you didn't do that going like, I have just invented a catchphrase. No. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Not at all. I literally just naturally went Coffee Check, like I got
Speaker 2:  it. That was it. Yeah. And then I went away and then posted that people were
Speaker 2:  stoked and they were just like, this is so different and fun and whatever.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, oh, you like this too? Oh great. 'cause I
Speaker 2:  enjoy this. And so then I started doing more and more of that and I did a
Speaker 2:  few, and I got comments. They were like, where's the coffee?
Speaker 2:  And I was like, oh, oh, this is a thing now. And I
Speaker 2:  didn't realize, okay. And then in the next video I went Coffee Check and
Speaker 2:  like got the coffee. Like there was a few videos that didn't have coffee.
Speaker 2:  And I mean, people were upset. So people told you it was a bit
Speaker 2:  before you realized it was a bit correct. It was, it was the audience that
Speaker 2:  told me interest that I had to do a bit. That's so funny. And that just became
Speaker 2:  a thing. So do you then take that thing and you're like, okay,
Speaker 2:  coffee is now part of what I do here.
Speaker 2:  How can I blow this out? Right. Like I, there there's a,
Speaker 2:  there's a particularly like ruthless thing you could do in that moment
Speaker 2:  that's like, okay, coffee's part of my thing now who's gonna be my coffee
Speaker 2:  sponsor? Hmm. I'm gonna start selling a coffee mug as merch. Like
Speaker 2:  there, there's a, there's a very simple, like, how do I monetize this road
Speaker 2:  that you can go down in that moment? Correct. Did you start going down that
Speaker 2:  road? I think in my head I was like, oh, wouldn't it be really cool if I
Speaker 2:  had a coffee sponsor? Okay. But I never, there was never any, anything beyond
Speaker 2:  that. I was never like, oh, I'm gonna go find one. But if we're honest, that's
Speaker 2:  also because I don't generally reach out to sponsors. Like, and
Speaker 2:  I'm very fortunate in that way that like most sponsors have come to me and
Speaker 2:  then I kind of decide whether I wanna work with them or not. And it just
Speaker 2:  happened to be, there wasn't any conference sponsors that had come and I,
Speaker 2:  I think I did, I did one, which I was very excited about to this point, Apress
Speaker 2:  came out and did a, an integration in a video where I made an arrow press
Speaker 2:  with, you know, the S 24 alter or whatever it was at the time. And so that
Speaker 2:  was, that was really neat. But it was never like a, I wasn't trying to go
Speaker 2:  do that. It just felt like, oh, wouldn't it be, it'd be great fit if someone
Speaker 2:  reached out and did that. Right. I've been watching David's videos
Speaker 2:  on the Unlocker for a long time, and it's honestly sort of shocking to me
Speaker 2:  that he doesn't have more coffee content. So many of his
Speaker 2:  videos start with a quick intro to the video, like, what's about to happen?
Speaker 2:  And then he just barrels the camera and goes, first things first, and
Speaker 2:  then there's a long montage of him getting coffee at some cool place around
Speaker 2:  New York. And then he goes, Coffee, Check. And then the video starts. That's,
Speaker 2:  that's the thing. It's a good bit. But like lots of people drink
Speaker 2:  coffee, you know what I mean? And I've always wondered whether he was
Speaker 2:  really into coffee this way or if that ends up being just a useful
Speaker 2:  construct to set up a lot of these videos. Like I've filmed camera tests
Speaker 2:  before. I know how hard it is to find interesting stuff to film and
Speaker 2:  photograph on a camera to show on video. But then again, to be fair,
Speaker 2:  we're sitting recording in his coffee shop. So this fact
Speaker 2:  should not surprise you. I was a coffee snob. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I'd like to admit that here. That was the word I was trying to not accuse
Speaker 2:  you of, but it's fine. I'm glad. No, it's totally fine. I, I've accepted
Speaker 2:  it. Anyway, all that coffee love went from
Speaker 2:  intros and arrow press into something very different last year.
Speaker 2:  That was when David's lease was up. He had this space that he'd shared with
Speaker 2:  a couple of other creators just a few blocks away in Brooklyn. And
Speaker 2:  when their lease was ending, he started looking for a new space and
Speaker 2:  a new project. Initially, my idea was to try to make something for
Speaker 2:  creators. I wanted to make, like, I wanted a larger space that could then
Speaker 2:  have some sort sort of community. I was just kind of craving that I think
Speaker 2:  like a bigger community of, of creators to like, you know, inspire each other
Speaker 2:  and do other things. And then I was like, okay, cool. Like I, I went looking
Speaker 2:  for a space, I found the space that we are currently in and I loved it. And
Speaker 2:  then I did the math on, you know, how viable was this
Speaker 2:  business model of like, creators coming in and like, cool, we all, you know,
Speaker 2:  can use this space and film it and whatever. So you're describing like WeWork
Speaker 2:  for creators essentially that. And I literally would've said those at some
Speaker 2:  point to someone I'm sure. So we were for creators and the problem is
Speaker 2:  I realized quickly after finding the space and doing the math was that you
Speaker 2:  have to limit the number of creators that join because, you know, people
Speaker 2:  have to be able to film in here and you can't all be in here at the same
Speaker 2:  time when someone's filming. Sure. And so inherently it limits the number
Speaker 2:  of members you can have, which means you have to charge a lot more. New York
Speaker 2:  rent is not cheap. It just made zero sense. And I'm went Cool, great. Done.
Speaker 2:  Glad I figured that out before I started. And then I was literally in the
Speaker 2:  space and be like, what else can I do with this? 'cause I just really liked
Speaker 2:  it. And originally when I walked in, I I, I immediately thought, okay, a
Speaker 2:  roastery, I would love to have a roastery one. I would love to do something
Speaker 2:  with my hands. I've just been a creative for so long. They like, I feel like
Speaker 2:  we all crave that to some degree at some point. And I love coffee. It was
Speaker 2:  already part of the brand. I was like, okay, well now this also makes a little
Speaker 2:  bit more sense. So maybe I could start a roastery. I could roast my own coffee
Speaker 2:  and, and that could be my merch. I could then sell that to the audience.
Speaker 2:  I can sell that to wherever, maybe other stores. You become your own coffee
Speaker 2:  sponsor. I become my own coffee sponsor in every video was definitely part
Speaker 2:  of that. Okay. Right. Like, and I, and I've been doing that the last few
Speaker 2:  videos. I'm sorry to anyone who's listening, been watching my videos. I'm
Speaker 2:  so sorry. I'm keep doing it for a little bit longer. So your thought was
Speaker 2:  like, maybe I'll just do this myself. Like this will be a, a
Speaker 2:  something. It's, it seems like a side project. Is that,
Speaker 2:  is it, is it, is it the side project or is YouTube No, the side. No, I'm
Speaker 2:  just kidding. We're gonna get to that. Yeah. Yeah. I would say, yeah, it
Speaker 2:  was, it was kind of just like a, hey, this felt like a good, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  like
Speaker 2:  a side project, let's just call it side project. But that's what it was.
Speaker 2:  It was felt like a good cyber project that also though had a lot of ties
Speaker 2:  in with what I was already doing, which is another reason why I did it. For
Speaker 2:  sure. 'cause if it didn't have that, it wouldn't have made as much sense.
Speaker 2:  It was just like, cool, let me, you know, I already have no time. Like I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm as busy as it was with YouTube, right. Asking anyone that knows me. They're
Speaker 2:  like, yep, David's always busy. Yeah. So like, then I was like, cool, lemme
Speaker 2:  start another business was probably not the best idea, but it's okay. So
Speaker 2:  wait, but on that front, actually, like in those first moments,
Speaker 2:  like if, if the spectrum of ambition is like
Speaker 2:  guy brewing beer in his basement all the way to
Speaker 2:  like, I wanna start Starbucks, where,
Speaker 2:  where would you say your ambition was? Way closer to the guy in the basement.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah. No, I, 'cause like, I don't, and and it's funny 'cause even people
Speaker 2:  have said stuff to me about like, oh, when you can open your next one and
Speaker 2:  do, you know, like, I'm like, oh, I'm, no, I'm never, it's not gonna happen
Speaker 2:  because like, it's so much work for just one. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  I, and I kind of like the idea of it being a smaller thing. The point wasn't
Speaker 2:  to make an empire out of this thing, it was just to do something good. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Right. Something that like, felt good for me, generates revenue. Sure. But
Speaker 2:  I mean, you know, more So I right now. I just care that it has its own bills.
Speaker 2:  Like that's all I really hope for. That's right. And, and it just was
Speaker 2:  something that like, yeah, I was something I, it something felt good about
Speaker 2:  the idea and it wasn't necessarily like building an empire.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we have to take a break, but when we get back, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  how you actually do all of this. Because it's one thing to say,
Speaker 2:  oh, I'd love to open a coffee shop. Honestly, I feel like lots of
Speaker 2:  people have at one point had that specific dream. You know what I mean?
Speaker 2:  Mine personally is not a coffee shop. It's to like, throw all this
Speaker 2:  away and go open a divy sports bar somewhere.
Speaker 2:  It's even another thing to actually find and lease a
Speaker 2:  space and say, okay, I'll figure this out later. And
Speaker 2:  then to decide I'm gonna do a roastery and then I'm gonna do a coffee
Speaker 2:  shop because there's a door. You, you start to go down this road. But
Speaker 2:  actually pulling all of that off and doing it well and
Speaker 2:  do it without turning it into the exact thing and
Speaker 2:  grind and lifestyle that you're trying to get away from in the first place,
Speaker 2:  that's all way harder. We're gonna talk about how all of
Speaker 2:  that went for David. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from AWS. With the power
Speaker 3:  of AWS generative AI teams can get relevant fast
Speaker 3:  answers to pressing questions and use data to drive real results,
Speaker 3:  power your business and generate real impact with the most
Speaker 3:  experienced cloud.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So just to reset here, we have David Cogan
Speaker 2:  longtime YouTube creator, tech reporter. Apparently according to his
Speaker 2:  is healthy. We'll have a lot of questions about coffee shopping all way.
Speaker 2:  We can talk about Yeah, we can talk about that. I might need my laptop. We
Speaker 2:  can talk about that. But yeah, like how did I
Speaker 2:  go about starting it? So, well first off, so when I did that there roastery
Speaker 2:  idea, I realized that there was frontage, which is essentially just like
Speaker 2:  a term for, there's street access from a door. The street. There's a door.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So, I might as I might as well. Because if we're gonna be roasting
Speaker 2:  beans in here, there might as well be something in the front where people
Speaker 2:  can just buy them and hang out and sit. And so that's where the coffee shop
Speaker 2:  then came from that. And then this back production space, which is what we're
Speaker 2:  in now, just kind of made sense for what I was on YouTube
Speaker 2:  and everything else. Do you think about past, you now thinking about it like
Speaker 2:  that? Like, oh, there's space. I might as well do a coffee shop. And you're
Speaker 2:  like, that moron had no idea what he was saying. He was meeting up for he's
Speaker 2:  Nope, nope. Yep. Question that every day. Okay. Yep. Just confused. I I will
Speaker 2:  say actually like that's the most like casually I've ever heard someone decide
Speaker 2:  to open a coffee shop. Yeah. So I. It's funny because I went from like thinking
Speaker 2:  about this to signing a lease in about three months. Oh wow. And so like
Speaker 2:  I look back at that now, one, it was dumb, but, but also there was a blessing
Speaker 2:  because I didn't have time to sit, sit there and question all of the things
Speaker 2:  For sure. And like then now it's like, oh, it's too late. Cool. I'll just
Speaker 2:  figure it out. First thing I did was I started to learn as much as I possibly
Speaker 2:  could. I went to coffee events, I went to coffee conventions. I started seeing
Speaker 2:  coffee classes, roasting classes, barista classes. I'm like certified in
Speaker 2:  certain things. Like, because I just like, I just, I think a lot of us do
Speaker 2:  this, especially like most people I know that are in tech stuff. Like if
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do something, we obsess about it. Yeah. Until we're good at it.
Speaker 2:  And So, I started that process first. Okay. Well signed the lease and then
Speaker 2:  went, cool, now I've gotta start this process. Sure. And then the lease wasn't,
Speaker 2:  you know, it took a few months for that to actually start. So this is like,
Speaker 2:  and then during those three months was just as all this is happening. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Correct. So it was like So, I. Think I signed the lease in December. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Ish. Yeah. And so like December, January, February, like, and then started
Speaker 2:  starting construction in here. But, so while all of that process was happening,
Speaker 2:  I would fly off to, I think Chicago, I went to the SCA Coffee
Speaker 2:  Expo, which is like one of the biggest ones. Took us all of the free classes.
Speaker 2:  They offered as many as I could. Nice. That would fit in my schedule. Went
Speaker 2:  to Javits Center, had one recently I did. Went and did that. Started
Speaker 2:  taking coffee classes at another coffee roastery nearby. Like just
Speaker 2:  obsessed as you do. Yeah. Right. And so that is step one. It's like
Speaker 2:  I felt like I needed to know enough that I could obviously do this thing
Speaker 2:  once. And then throughout that process though, it was getting built. So then
Speaker 2:  it just took a long time. Took about eight months before it finally,
Speaker 2:  you know, became looking like a coffee shop. Funny about that. And not just
Speaker 2:  a warehouse. You know what's fascinating about that, by the way, and I've
Speaker 2:  been thinking about this ever since we talked in YouTube time, eight months
Speaker 2:  is like an eternity. If, you work for eight months on a single project.
Speaker 2:  YouTube's algorithm will almost certainly have forgotten you exist by the
Speaker 2:  time you reappear. You just cannot work on that kind of
Speaker 2:  timeline. But in building terms, like physical, putting up
Speaker 2:  buildings eight months isn't bad. And I think one of the reasons it felt
Speaker 2:  so long to David was that he was actually trying to live in both
Speaker 2:  of those timelines simultaneously. To both be a creator
Speaker 2:  at the pace of the internet demands, but also do this deliberately
Speaker 2:  slower and more personal and more thoughtful thing at
Speaker 2:  the same time. It seems like it might be a healthy balance,
Speaker 2:  but it also seems like it might just tear your brain completely to shreds
Speaker 2:  trying to do both at the same time. For David, I think it was a little bit
Speaker 2:  of both, but mostly the second one, I knew it,
Speaker 2:  I knew what I was doing and I did it anyway. Which maybe that was the mistake.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But it was having running two businesses at once, like the YouTube
Speaker 2:  is a full-time business. Like, I don't know anyone knows, but like it's a
Speaker 2:  lot. Yeah. And it's a constant grind and it's very draining. Everybody
Speaker 2:  burns out. Right. It's a very normal thing. Were you burned out on it?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think I get burnt out every three months. It just like comes and
Speaker 2:  goes, you know, it's like a cycle. I'm just used to it now. Yeah. But I mean,
Speaker 2:  I wonder like you, you, there's a, there's everyone I know what definite
Speaker 2:  I can, there's a definite like armchair psychology thing I could do to you
Speaker 2:  that it is like Yeah. What a lot of people who burn out
Speaker 2:  on YouTube do is like make the why I hate YouTube
Speaker 2:  video. Yes. Or they like, go make a product or
Speaker 2:  something just as kind of a, a reset to use a different part of your brain
Speaker 2:  Sure. And try to like diversify. And maybe this is what I'm doing is I think
Speaker 2:  you're, what I wonder is like if, if I wanted to really try and like
Speaker 2:  psychoanalyze you, maybe maybe that's a reaction to it where you're like
Speaker 2:  the the grind gets everybody Yes. Like it does, you're absolutely right.
Speaker 2:  For sure. And I can see why it would feel like
Speaker 2:  romantic and exciting to do something so sort of diametrically opposite
Speaker 2:  Totally. Of grind on YouTube every day. Yes. And I think, and again think,
Speaker 2:  I think that's like that, you know, people wanting to do stuff with their
Speaker 2:  hands when they work on the internet, all right's, everybody got sourdough.
Speaker 2:  Correct. Yes. Yeah. You just, I missed that actually. You just went, I wish
Speaker 2:  I got on the sourdough. You went way harder on that. I went, yeah. This is
Speaker 2:  my sourdough. You're Yeah, yeah, that's exactly. Please
Speaker 2:  come in and try my sourdough. No, it's, it's, yeah, I, I, I totally agree
Speaker 2:  with that. I think that's, that's definitely a part of it. Even if that was
Speaker 2:  a little more subconscious than like a conscious effort. It was definitely
Speaker 2:  a part of it. Okay. But you also kept the YouTubing this
Speaker 2:  of this space. Like there's a I would say what, 60%
Speaker 2:  of the square footage in here? Maybe half 50%. Yeah. Let's say 50 is
Speaker 2:  designed, designed to be like a production space. Correct. Was that part
Speaker 2:  of the plan from the beginning? So I always wanted to have that for a number
Speaker 2:  of reasons. Just as a business person was like, I need to differentiate as
Speaker 2:  much as I can in this space 'cause I just gotta pay rent. Sure. And I dunno
Speaker 2:  how long the coffee shop's gonna take. I dunno how long the roastery is gonna
Speaker 2:  take, et cetera. So what's something else that I have some experience in,
Speaker 2:  obviously and was like, that could maybe also help just pay the bills for
Speaker 2:  a bit. And I did research on peer space and started to look at all the
Speaker 2:  other like rental studio spaces around here. Realized none of them had a
Speaker 2:  kitchen. And so that was my choice for building the kitchen. It was like
Speaker 2:  cool differentiator kitchen. You know what else? They don't have a podcast
Speaker 2:  booth, which we are in right now. So got that as well. So it's just trying
Speaker 2:  to like create a separate, another business obviously, but another part of
Speaker 2:  this business that like could help pay the rent because that's all I cared
Speaker 2:  about and still do. And so yeah. So that, but,
Speaker 2:  but the truth is like, 'cause this isn't as a, as we were talking about at
Speaker 2:  some point, I don't, I don't need the backspace.
Speaker 2:  Like I film most of my videos outside now as, as we've discussed and So I
Speaker 2:  don't really need to have a space that I'm gonna film in. I
Speaker 2:  I, the bigger intent was for this to get rented out help pay rent. But
Speaker 2:  I do use it and I, I also kind of designed some things within here.
Speaker 2:  For example, the kitchen has a very standard width of the oven. That
Speaker 2:  way it can be swamped out so that maybe I can start doing appliance videos
Speaker 2:  and not just phones and laptops and bikes and whatever else I do that are
Speaker 2:  outside of the kitchen that are not as large. Can't do any of that in my
Speaker 2:  apartment because it's, I rent it. Right. They won't let me. Yeah. And then
Speaker 2:  I did the same thing for the fridge. The fridge is positioned in a way where
Speaker 2:  it's on the side where I could get a doubles size fridge and it would still
Speaker 2:  fit. And I tried to do those as many of the things as possible. Same thing
Speaker 2:  with the, I'm never gonna mount a TV in here because I wanna be able to
Speaker 2:  swap them out to do more TV reviews is something else. I would like So I
Speaker 2:  try to add some elements of the space to benefit my YouTube
Speaker 2:  channel in some way. But it was, it's, it's a small percentage of what the
Speaker 2:  space should be used for. Right. Really need to just rent it out. Okay. That
Speaker 2:  makes sense. So, and to that point actually more broadly, like how
Speaker 2:  did you think about sort of connecting the coffee
Speaker 2:  shop to the YouTube channel? There are a bunch of ways in
Speaker 2:  which they are very connected, including the name. Like, it's, it's Yes.
Speaker 2:  You, you said Coffee Check in a lot of your videos you open a coffee shop
Speaker 2:  called Coffee Check. Yes. Which is dumb to anyone who doesn't know the YouTube
Speaker 2:  channel, but it's fine. There's a, there's an easy thing you could have done
Speaker 2:  right. Back to the like, how do I monetize this thing on my channel question?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Where you make this whole thing
Speaker 2:  kind of about your YouTube channel, right. And you have a TV that's always
Speaker 2:  playing your videos terrible and hate that so much. And you're, and it's
Speaker 2:  the background of all of your videos and you try to make these things sort
Speaker 2:  of symbiotic. Yeah. My sense is you have like
Speaker 2:  deliberately run the other direction Yes. Of that except for the little
Speaker 2:  touches of the name. Like why, why not push these two things closer together?
Speaker 2:  So to me, I think I wanted to make sure that I could do a good coffee shop
Speaker 2:  and that it stood on its own for that. I didn't want it to have anything
Speaker 2:  to do with the YouTube channel as far as like, you know, you know, I dread
Speaker 2:  those, those headlines that are influencer opens coffee
Speaker 2:  shop. Right. And then, which are inevitable sometimes a lot of the people
Speaker 2:  go to those coffee shops though. Yeah. Which is, which is great. But like,
Speaker 2:  there's, there's an implied, like a lot of people don't like that word. A
Speaker 2:  lot of people don't sure don't know what an influencer does or, you know,
Speaker 2:  and I don't, I don't think I would ever call myself an influencer, but, you
Speaker 2:  know, media marketing company call me that. So it's fine, you know, but it's
Speaker 2:  like there's a connotation there that I think that is
Speaker 2:  negative in a lot of people's minds. And I didn't want that. Firstly, I also
Speaker 2:  just, again, I wanted this to be, to live on its own. I wanted it to kind
Speaker 2:  of be Easter eggs for people that know, like the Coffee Check symbol, like
Speaker 2:  the name. Right. But everything else is just, oh, it's just the local coffee
Speaker 2:  shop that we enjoy and we like, and it's just, you know, whatever. That's
Speaker 2:  it. I didn't want it. I, I think on the YouTube channel, I don't mind doing
Speaker 2:  the other way around. Right. Because for me to, on YouTube to be like, Hey,
Speaker 2:  here's the coffee shop that I made. And like, come check it out. And like,
Speaker 2:  here it is and filming in it, I feel like there's less of a, like,
Speaker 2:  it's, it's less weird to me that people on YouTube know I have a coffee shop.
Speaker 2:  It's more weird to me that the people in the coffee shop know I have a YouTube
Speaker 2:  channel. Interesting. Yeah. Does that make sense? Yes. And yet
Speaker 2:  I feel like every time you bring it up on your channel, you apologize for
Speaker 2:  bringing it up. Absolutely. Why? Because I'm annoying.
Speaker 2:  I'm, because a big part of it is that I keep bringing it up
Speaker 2:  and I'm, I'm doing that partially because I need to like, get word out about
Speaker 2:  the coffee shop to some degree. And, and like, and so it's almost like, feels
Speaker 2:  like a bit of an ad to myself. Right? So I don't want, you know, so I'm apologizing
Speaker 2:  for that and, but, and everyone has been very sweet, which I, I very much
Speaker 2:  appreciate all the comments have been like, dude, don't apologize. Like,
Speaker 2:  amazing. Like, so glad you're like, you know, living a dream, whatever. And
Speaker 2:  it's very, very, very sweet. So I, So I do appreciate that. I, this is the
Speaker 2:  thing. I still feel like I'm gonna apologize, so it's fine. But this is the
Speaker 2:  weird thing about being a, a creator in this moment, I think Right. Where
Speaker 2:  like, you could, your point about Influencer Opens coffee shop
Speaker 2:  is like, I I tend to agree with you that it feels sort of gross. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  like, a lot of people will go to that coffee shop because for
Speaker 2:  whatever reason they feel attached to that person. Sure. And that's a thing
Speaker 2:  you can you to for evil or for good.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah, true. But If you use it for, we've seen it used both by many
Speaker 2:  people. Right, right. And, but I think If, you use it for good. There's not,
Speaker 2:  there's nothing inherently wrong with it. Right. And I think like even what
Speaker 2:  your original story about how Coffee Check became a thing,
Speaker 2:  it's like that that's people being connected to you as a person and like
Speaker 2:  they want to know what you're up to and they wanna know where you're going
Speaker 2:  and you're traveling and their Yeah. Where am I getting the coffee? Right.
Speaker 2:  And so you you get to a point where it's like, okay, actually what I'm doing
Speaker 2:  is I'm bringing you along on this ride with me. Correct. And
Speaker 2:  that, that would've just required a very different approach. Like to some
Speaker 2:  extent, it's surprising to me that you didn't make eight months of videos
Speaker 2:  out of building the coffee shop. Seriously. Like a lot of creators would've
Speaker 2:  done that. Yeah. I dunno if it's pride. It's something there's like, I want
Speaker 2:  this to stand on its own, I want to do a good job at this. Right.
Speaker 2:  You want it to work because it's good. Not because theoretically Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  want have, I, I don't want that to influence it in any way. Interesting.
Speaker 2:  I want it to just do well. I want to have this coffee shop do well the roastery
Speaker 2:  do well because they merit such things, not because
Speaker 2:  of some other outside influencer marketing or whatever else. Right. So, I
Speaker 2:  mean. So I've seen enough creators hawk the things that they're doing
Speaker 2:  and kind of being like, Hey, yeah, I'll do, I'm doing, I made this thing
Speaker 2:  and like, you know, I wanted to actually do something with my hands. Like
Speaker 2:  be in the space. Like, not just like white label something, like actually
Speaker 2:  make it do the things and that, and like, I dunno, I think there's,
Speaker 2:  I think I start to also a good way to put it too. Right? I think I start
Speaker 2:  to skew my own data when I introduce those other things. If I want to make
Speaker 2:  sure that this does well on its own, I need to not kind of push all of those
Speaker 2:  other things into it because then I won't know what helped it do. Well I
Speaker 2:  have a very long lease. Right. I did that on purpose. I want this to be a
Speaker 2:  thing that doesn't just like get a bump of traffic because of influencer
Speaker 2:  word and then dies. Hmm. Right. So it needs to be something that literally
Speaker 2:  just can like, be a part of the neighborhood and be a good thing and grow
Speaker 2:  with the neighborhood and, and outlast my YouTube channel. Right. This is
Speaker 2:  the retirement plan, man. Okay.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take one more break and then we will be back with the
Speaker 2:  rest of my conversation with David. Cogan
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. Now we're kind of back to the present in our story.
Speaker 2:  David just spent eight months creating a coffee shop from scratch while
Speaker 2:  still kind of sort of maintaining
Speaker 2:  mix of the two worlds every day. Is the context searching of that
Speaker 2:  brutal? Yes. Are, are, are, are you gonna survive
Speaker 2:  that? No. To be determined. Okay. No, it's been,
Speaker 2:  it's, I've, I've been feeling pretty burnt out to be honest. But like, but
Speaker 2:  there's something, it's a different burnout. Sure. Right. There's, there's,
Speaker 2:  because, and I'm sure some of it's just, it's novel, right? The coffee shop
Speaker 2:  is new. It is a different thing. It is very to what we already talked about.
Speaker 2:  It's very different than the YouTube channel. And So, I enjoy it a lot, even
Speaker 2:  if it's stressful and there's things going wrong and everything else. There's,
Speaker 2:  there's something about it that is just so enjoyable that it kind of tempers
Speaker 2:  the burnout from all the things that are happening. And I, and I can see
Speaker 2:  a light at the end of the tunnel. I think, you know, I feel like there's,
Speaker 2:  there is a world where this, where I, I'm here less and less.
Speaker 2:  I can, you know, not have to worry about doing certain things. I'm trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out inventory, for example. Right? Like, how do I make sure that
Speaker 2:  the inventory I can project in a certain way that I don't have to order every
Speaker 2:  time things get low, obviously. Right. So it's a goal you have to get to
Speaker 2:  getting there. So like, that's helpful. Is that the goal?
Speaker 2:  Like, is the, is the goal to spend
Speaker 2:  less time on this so you can go back to making videos? I,
Speaker 2:  yeah. I, mm, questionable. I, I wanna do both. Okay. I enjoy both
Speaker 2:  to some degree. I think I enjoy the coffee shop more than YouTube at this
Speaker 2:  point. But again, I think that's something to do with it being novel and
Speaker 2:  it's with your hands and everything. And I've been doing the other thing
Speaker 2:  for 13 years, but I, you know,
Speaker 2:  YouTube is still the thing I've been doing for however long. Right.
Speaker 2:  I can't, it's also, I assume the business, it's like it's paying for everything.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely. Yeah. This is just losing money. This is just a very expensive
Speaker 2:  hobby. Sure. So yes, YouTube is paying the bills and it is, it is kind of
Speaker 2:  the thing that I've, I've built over all this time. I can't throw the baby
Speaker 2:  out with the bath water fair. Not that I would, I still enjoy YouTube, but
Speaker 2:  like, you know what I mean? So, I. I've now just, I'm trying to just
Speaker 2:  get back to a, a better cadence of making the YouTube videos
Speaker 2:  while still being involved in the coffee shop. Okay. And I think that's the
Speaker 2:  goal. It's not necessarily like step completely away from the coffee shop
Speaker 2:  and then just run YouTube. Like I was, I think there, there's an
Speaker 2:  element of like, if I could figure out more things to, to hand off in YouTube
Speaker 2:  and make that a little more efficient, make the coffee shop more efficient.
Speaker 2:  There's a, there's some, and maybe this isn't real, but there's some ideal
Speaker 2:  world where I can kind of do both in a, in a healthy balance and still have
Speaker 2:  a social life somehow. Then I'll figure that part out later because Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Details, details. I think one of the things people burn out on YouTube
Speaker 2:  and really kind of creator life in general is just that it asks so
Speaker 2:  much of you in so many different directions all the time. Right. Like, I
Speaker 2:  hear from creators all the time who are like, I started making videos because
Speaker 2:  I like making videos. They were fun. Either the thing in the video is fun
Speaker 2:  or the process of making the video is fun or something. And then all of a
Speaker 2:  sudden you're like, oh my God, I'm spending all my day essentially doing
Speaker 2:  data analysis. Like, that's actually not a good time. Right. Right. And then,
Speaker 2:  and then your option is either grind until it burns you out. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Not worry about it so much and kind of limit your cap of success
Speaker 2:  on the platform. Sure. Or basically try to
Speaker 2:  systematize. Right. And like hire people. Yep. Outsource some of that stuff.
Speaker 2:  Make it no longer your problem and you just get to do the parts of it that
Speaker 2:  you like. Right. And, and sort of solve the rest around you. And it sounds
Speaker 2:  like that's the thing you're aiming for. I, after a long time of just grinding.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I look, I So I think, I think there's a couple things there. Like the,
Speaker 2:  I think that is the goal. I would like it, but, but not quite. Right. Like
Speaker 2:  I don't, I don't wanna be Marquez. Like, that's just never a goal for me.
Speaker 2:  Sure. I don't want to have like, or a Linus or, you know, whoever else which
Speaker 2:  are essentially media companies. Correct. I, that's never a goal. I don't
Speaker 2:  wanna do that. That sounds like more stress for me than I want to be honest.
Speaker 2:  But also like, I don't need to be that big. Right. I'm happy to like, you
Speaker 2:  know, I I, I just want to, I think I need to let go of more things. And this
Speaker 2:  coffee shop has proven is like, kind of forced me to do that. Not to the
Speaker 2:  point where it's like, I come in and I talk on camera for more four seconds
Speaker 2:  and I walk away and that's the end. I don't, and and also just the, just
Speaker 2:  the nature of my videos, it's very difficult as well. Right. Because I, I
Speaker 2:  enjoy having this, like, you're coming along with me very vlogger style.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. As soon as there's a cameraman holding that camera, it gets a very
Speaker 2:  different vibe, which I just don't want as a creative choice. I just don't
Speaker 2:  like that. Maybe it'll happen one day 'cause I wanna have a choice, but like,
Speaker 2:  sure. That's, you know, like, I kinda like bouncing around with, with the
Speaker 2:  audience and like, kind of, and I even enjoy making those videos where like,
Speaker 2:  it's literally me, like exploring places with you. I'm, I'm, a lot of these
Speaker 2:  places are new to me too. So I. Don't think I'm gonna let that go. So there's
Speaker 2:  somewhere else that, that I think I can hand things off, but still
Speaker 2:  be as involved as I can be without, you know, killing myself and
Speaker 2:  going insane. But I do. But I also think, like creators in general, we
Speaker 2:  have this issue too, which is the fact that like, in order to do what
Speaker 2:  we do, especially YouTube or Instagram or whatever social media, you,
Speaker 2:  you have to make everything formulaic. Right.
Speaker 2:  So in other words, like in order to churn out as many videos as I do, I have
Speaker 2:  to make everything so like, fit into a
Speaker 2:  box. Like, I'm gonna write the script, it's gonna be like this. Yeah. I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna get this shot like this. I'm gonna do, there's no area for creativity
Speaker 2:  at some point because the only way it'll get done is If. you make it as
Speaker 2:  efficient as possible. Yep. And that is where I think we all start to burn
Speaker 2:  out because then you're just like, I'm just a hamster on a wheel. Nothing
Speaker 2:  feels gratifying at that point. It's just cool making a video, putting it
Speaker 2:  out. Right. Especially around this time of year is even worse. But, but that's
Speaker 2:  what the audience demands of you, right? Correct. Yeah. That's, that's the
Speaker 2:  industry thing over and over and over and it over again. Yeah. That's what,
Speaker 2:  that's what the algorithm's like. Yep. That's what the audience expects.
Speaker 2:  And at some point it just becomes Yeah. Easier
Speaker 2:  and way less fulfilling Totally. To just deliver the thing. Correct. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And, and like yeah. And you need to, you need to do the optimization in order
Speaker 2:  to be able to do it. Right. And the only way you can, you know, keep up with
Speaker 2:  that cadence is to make things as smooth as possible, not as creative as
Speaker 2:  possible. Has that, yeah. Like, that's not transferred to the coffee shop.
Speaker 2:  Does it feel the same way? No. No, no. Which I think maybe
Speaker 2:  that's another reason why I enjoy it so much. Like there's, there is a lot
Speaker 2:  of, because we just opened, there's a lot of creating all these
Speaker 2:  processes and optimizing and I, I do enjoy a lot of that,
Speaker 2:  which is interesting. I enjoy it in this respect more so than like, I think
Speaker 2:  I enjoy trying to figure those things out with YouTube, but now that I've
Speaker 2:  figured them out Right. They're just building systems is much more fun than
Speaker 2:  living inside of them. Just living in them. Yeah. Correct. It's a hundred
Speaker 2:  percent. Yeah. That's a good way to put it. Yeah. But yeah, so like I'm building
Speaker 2:  those systems for the coffee shop and every day like I get feedback from
Speaker 2:  the baristas or I'm behind the counter with them sometimes I'm like, I see,
Speaker 2:  okay, there's a bottleneck. Like, let's figure that out. You know, Hey guys,
Speaker 2:  what do you think? You know, what is a better setup for this? Like, is what's
Speaker 2:  slowing you guys down? And like, that's fun. There's something I think hu
Speaker 2:  as humans, we like to solve things, especially when they're small problems,
Speaker 2:  like where the cups should go. Right. You know, like bigger problems.
Speaker 2:  Terrible. Right. But like, you know, these kinds of things are like, they're,
Speaker 2:  they're fulfilling. They give you like a, a nice, ah, I did that. I checked
Speaker 2:  the box. Right. And so there's a lot of those right now in the coffee shop
Speaker 2:  that are fun to do. So back to this like content coffee shop mix. I,
Speaker 2:  I can now imagine a world in which you become a coffee
Speaker 2:  content person. Mm. Like the, the roastery is gonna happen. Yep.
Speaker 2:  You already do a lot of filming of cups of coffee. As someone
Speaker 2:  who has watched your channel for a long time, I can, I can vouch for it.
Speaker 2:  Appreciate that there are hours of videos of coffee Yes. Correct. Coffee
Speaker 2:  cups on your channel. I don't even need to create new content. I can just
Speaker 2:  splice all that together. Boom. Exactly. It's a real, to reverse all the
Speaker 2:  questions I asked you at the beginning, right. You're like, oh, now I have
Speaker 2:  a room full of coffee equipment. Maybe I should just point a camera at it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. It, it occurs to me in, in, in the way a bad habit occurs to
Speaker 2:  you. Right. Like, I sit there and I'm like, should film this that make some
Speaker 2:  good content? Look at that. Yes. I think I always think that it's like a
Speaker 2:  junky thing. It's legit. Like, how do I make this content legit? It is legit
Speaker 2:  that it's like a and after a decade of YouTube Yeah. That's, you see the
Speaker 2:  world as content opportunities. It's real. You're for better and worse. No,
Speaker 2:  it's true, real. It's absolutely true. And So I have thought about it
Speaker 2:  and I think IIII think there is a world where maybe more coffee
Speaker 2:  stuff ends up on the channel or the audience, you know, if they, if they
Speaker 2:  want that, maybe I'll try it and let's just see how they feel about it would
Speaker 2:  be the way to do it. I mean, I did of course grab all of the social things
Speaker 2:  for the coffee shop just preemptively because I was like, well, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  have to start doing content here as well for sure. So I. I mean, I think,
Speaker 2:  but that's different. So like, I think, I think in the
Speaker 2:  world in which we exist, you are going to have to take pretty videos of your
Speaker 2:  espresso machine and put them on Instagram occasionally. And I think to some
Speaker 2:  extent, again, those things are symbiotic, right? Yeah. Like, it's, it's,
Speaker 2:  they, it brings people into the shop. Yep. People watch the thing. People
Speaker 2:  like the thing like it, that's all good. Yeah. But I also think it changes
Speaker 2:  the way you think about the thing when it becomes most
Speaker 2:  lucrative as a content opportunity. Right. And it would then become the thing
Speaker 2:  I hate. Exactly. And So I think for you as someone who is like, who, who
Speaker 2:  is in part this all appealed to Yeah. As a thing that is not
Speaker 2:  content Yeah. To then have that pull of what if I make content about this?
Speaker 2:  Yes. And, and what if the content could help the coffee shop, but then eventually
Speaker 2:  you get to a point where the coffee shop is just helping the content. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like how to pick all those things apart in your brain. Just strikes me. It's
Speaker 2:  very complicated. So So I think I've simplified it because
Speaker 2:  I'm just So I. So don't want that last part to happen. Okay. Right.
Speaker 2:  I don't want the coffee shop to ever be making more money from the content
Speaker 2:  than from the coffee shop. It, it becomes like a, a studio that happens to
Speaker 2:  serve real coffee, which I don't want. Right. Because then, because then
Speaker 2:  to the point, I would then just be doing the thing again that I'm sure. So
Speaker 2:  like, I don't, I won't ever let that happen. And so that, like, in the same
Speaker 2:  way that like, I don't want the influencer part of this. Like, and I just
Speaker 2:  want to have one coffee shop. I don't wanna have more. Like I think these
Speaker 2:  are ways to limit that chaos that would normally happen in my
Speaker 2:  head. Yeah. I've given myself this hard No, and,
Speaker 2:  and so like, I, I think we need to make content and we will, like right now
Speaker 2:  we're posting photos and stuff and like whatever, I, I'm terrible at writing
Speaker 2:  captions. I just have too much, too much to do though is the other problem.
Speaker 2:  Sure. Right. So in, if I was gonna try to make content in here and like
Speaker 2:  try to get back to my own channel like that, it's just, I'm, I'm burnt out
Speaker 2:  as it is, that's just gonna throw me over the edge. Yeah, that's right. So,
Speaker 2:  but I do, I do like the idea of doing some sort of coffee content. Maybe
Speaker 2:  when things start to settle and they start to get like, at least I get caught
Speaker 2:  up on all the tech tober stuff that I need to get caught up on. Yeah. I just
Speaker 2:  don't know actually in my head, if that's something that
Speaker 2:  maybe lives on its own channel and is kind of just the Coffee Check
Speaker 2:  channel and I host that maybe to some degree maybe someone else can host
Speaker 2:  it, maybe I can set that up in a way where it's not just me, because then
Speaker 2:  that would be more, be more scalable, easier for me to not have to be a part
Speaker 2:  of all the time. Whereas like YouTube tick the locker, I'm not, I can't do
Speaker 2:  that. Right. Right. If some other face showed up, it just would be a totally
Speaker 2:  different trend. Yeah. I just, again, I want this to be a good coffee shop
Speaker 2:  roastery, like known for the things that are, that are those things
Speaker 2:  and not tied to an algorithm and other things like that.
Speaker 2:  Alright. That is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to David for being
Speaker 2:  on the show and for lending me his podcast booth to do it. And thank you
Speaker 2:  as always for listening as ever. There's lots more on all of our
Speaker 2:  coverage of the Creator universe and YouTube and links to
Speaker 2:  David's channel at The Verge dot com. I'll put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 2:  but as always, read the website, a lot of stuff going on right now and If
Speaker 2:  you have thoughts, feelings, questions, or other places I can
Speaker 2:  record a podcast in the back of cool coffee shops. You can always email us
Speaker 2:  at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE
Speaker 2:  one one. we love hearing from you. Please keep all your questions coming.
Speaker 2:  It's the best. This show is produced by Liam James, will Poor and
Speaker 2:  Eric Gomez. Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of the Vox Media Podcast
Speaker 2:  network. We'll be back on Tuesday and Friday to talk about Smart
Speaker 2:  Rings, Kindles, and all the other news happening right now because
Speaker 2:  again, I know I say this every week, but there just continues to be a lot
Speaker 2:  of it. We'll see you then. Rock and roll