# Transcript
ID: 56c0e9fe-7eca-40c5-ba2c-0023e0b25848
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4101580840624704360/-4776706358472857885/s93290-US-4899s-1717977611.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss what they expect to see next week at Apple's WWDC, or "dub dub" as it's more affectionately known. But first, we take you through all the gadgets previewed at Computex.
Speaker 4:  the flagship podcast of a
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just thrilled to learn more about defense contractors who also
Speaker 5:  moonlight as game designers.
Speaker 4:  We, this is a real thing and I promise you're gonna talk. If you can already
Speaker 4:  guess what it is, God bless you because you are spending too much time on
Speaker 4:  the internet, which means you're our people. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hi.
Speaker 4:  How's it going buddy?
Speaker 6:  It's good to be here.
Speaker 4:  Are you excited to manage multiple devices in an enterprise environment?
Speaker 6:  Listen, I did choose one of the stories in here that
Speaker 6:  is about Windows app virtualization, and I am surprisingly excited to talk
Speaker 6:  about it. So I'm gonna say I'm a hard yes on that front today.
Speaker 4:  All right, so we're opening with a lightning round. Yeah. The gadget lightning
Speaker 4:  round. I have proposed that we do it a
Speaker 4:  little differently than normal. Usually when you have a lightning round,
Speaker 4:  we have a bunch of stuff and then we all pick one. Yep. Rest assured
Speaker 4:  that's how we're doing The third lightning round, the third
Speaker 5:  Second, I got my name next to my little thing. And
Speaker 4:  I feel like that is not how lightning runs work.
Speaker 4:  Like we have just made up an alternative to lightning runs. Really what we're
Speaker 4:  supposed to do is look at all the headlines and go through them as fast as
Speaker 4:  we can, and I suggest we do this. And then David,
Speaker 4:  David Poo-pooed me.
Speaker 6:  It's not so much that, it's just that you have many skills
Speaker 6:  in life and one of them is not doing several
Speaker 6:  things in a row quickly. And, and so
Speaker 6:  we have, we have, I would say, I don't know, probably 10 headlines here.
Speaker 6:  This is going to take us four and a half hours. We're gonna do it and everybody
Speaker 6:  should just buckle up for this.
Speaker 4:  People love buckling
Speaker 6:  Up. I'm not mad at it. I'm just, I just You claim to have a train to catch.
Speaker 4:  It's true. I do. You're
Speaker 6:  Supposed to
Speaker 4:  That train today. I'm just saying, I'm gonna quote our transportation
Speaker 4:  editor, Andy Hawkins, who every time he puts the phrase buckle up in a headline,
Speaker 4:  the story goes viral. That's true. And then he says, people love buckling
Speaker 4:  up. So buckle up. Buckle up. That's what I got for you.
Speaker 4:  Flaming round time. Alright, we're gonna go through this as fast as we can.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  Like speed. Run
Speaker 4:  'em. Yeah. It's compex week. This week Intel showed up
Speaker 4:  after Nvidia announced all of its new chips and announced something called
Speaker 4:  Lunar Lake. And the thing that I understand it from this Kranz is that
Speaker 4:  they're trying real hard, but they've also gotten rid of upgradable memory.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, so they, their, their typical way of building
Speaker 5:  chips wasn't working for 'em. So they, they've gone a whole new route. And
Speaker 5:  This is Lunar Lake. It is just for mobile devices. It's not gonna be in big
Speaker 5:  desktops and stuff like that.
Speaker 4:  Wait, wait. Laptop, mobile devices? Yes. Or phone mobile devices.
Speaker 5:  Laptops. LA Okay. Laptops.
Speaker 4:  Because Intel being like, we're doing phones again is
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 4:  That's a straight line down. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Straight line down. Like I would say maybe 80, 90% of what is
Speaker 5:  in this chip, like the little chips within the chip not made by
Speaker 5:  Intel. Like, like it's based on like a TS
Speaker 5:  mc node. Okay. So they, they just fully were like, yeah, we can't do it.
Speaker 5:  You do it. So there's all of that.
Speaker 5:  They then they've just changed it all up and one of their big things is like,
Speaker 5:  we need to be faster, so we're gonna put the RAM on the chip, which will
Speaker 5:  make it faster.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The app famously Apple's move. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  People like to upgrade the RAM on their devices, so we'll see how
Speaker 4:  Yeah. THEC market less
Speaker 4:  compliant than I think Mac users.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I, I I, we'll we'll see how it goes. They're, they're claiming 48
Speaker 5:  tops for their AI chip. The NPU specifically
Speaker 5:  48
Speaker 4:  Tops. Trillion operations per second.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Trillion operations per second. And this only matters because everybody
Speaker 5:  has decided that this is the way we're gonna calculate how good things are
Speaker 5:  at processing AI workloads.
Speaker 4:  Has anyone figured out what to do with AI on these
Speaker 4:  computers?
Speaker 6:  You can take a a thing in a photo and move it over here. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think that's about as far as we've gotten. And now you can do it very fast
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 5:  Some of 'em have like a little chat bot powered by chat GPT
Speaker 5:  and you can be like, Hey, it'll be like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  That one's in the cloud. That's not even, that's all, that's not even anything.
Speaker 6:  That's that's fine. But that's like over there. But it
Speaker 5:  Could one day
Speaker 6:  It could, it could one day. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Run on a laptop powered by literal lake. That's
Speaker 4:  What, when Oregon and Trail tries to bang you. That's happening in Azure.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm just putting, I'm just saying.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's no like local banging happening.
Speaker 4:  Intel, we got a new marketing message for you.
Speaker 5:  We helped
Speaker 4:  This computer will try to get it on with you. No internet required.
Speaker 6:  Local dimming is out, local banging is in.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying so far the, the biggest consumer success of the AI industry
Speaker 4:  ha. Has been the fact that it's a little bit horny. Fine.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Okay. Do we think lunar based on
Speaker 4:  what we saw from Qualcomm in, in Windows
Speaker 4:  and then Nvidia. Nvidia was not a Compex or event, it was just
Speaker 4:  before they announced like 500 new chips, like a whole roadmap.
Speaker 4:  And they said we're doing this every year. It was very aggressive. Jensen
Speaker 4:  Wong looks very proud of himself. Is is this
Speaker 4:  competitive from Intel or No,
Speaker 5:  This is different. So this is not like in Nvidia and Intel
Speaker 5:  don't compete in this space.
Speaker 4:  No, I meant with Qualcomm, like we're seeing, oh, Qualcomm, yeah. We're,
Speaker 4:  this thing happen with
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm. Definitely.
Speaker 4:  Right? Qualcomm, like Microsoft wants to say, these new
Speaker 4:  Qualcomm windows laptops are faster than the MacBook error. They're better
Speaker 4:  than the MacBook error. They've, they've got AI built into them and then
Speaker 4:  our data centers full of Nvidia chips are rocketing into the future
Speaker 4:  and none of that has intelligent.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, and yeah, this is, this is definitely their, their attempt to like
Speaker 5:  catch up with everybody else because I think they just got bodied by
Speaker 5:  Apple for a long time in, in this space, in this laptop
Speaker 5:  CPU space. And so this is their, like, they've just changed their whole strategy.
Speaker 5:  It's all about power efficiency first, soldering the RAM
Speaker 5:  directly onto the chip so it'll go even faster. Everything is about how can
Speaker 5:  we get every single like piece of power out of this thing
Speaker 5:  while also keeping it as energy efficient as possible. And their,
Speaker 5:  their claims are really big. Like Right. Like they're saying like 50% better
Speaker 5:  GPU performance. They're saying 60% better battery life, which is
Speaker 5:  huge if true. Yeah. But it's also if true, we
Speaker 5:  still have to see these chips. We still have to see 'em in a laptop. We still
Speaker 5:  have to test them. There's a lot more to come. Intel always likes to make
Speaker 5:  huge claims and then it's like, okay, but what is reality?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Intel has even less credibility
Speaker 6:  for making some of these claims right now than Qualcomm does, which is tough
Speaker 6:  because we're still in the, you know, let's
Speaker 6:  see if it's real phase for what Qualcomm just launched. And
Speaker 6:  Microsoft also at that event was like, we have stuff coming from a MD and
Speaker 6:  Intel too. This copilot plus P thing, PC thing is gonna be real. Everything's
Speaker 6:  gonna be great. I found myself reading about all of this from Intel
Speaker 6:  going like, yeah, okay, sure. And I hope it's great. Like I really do.
Speaker 6:  And I think Intel is right to do it this way. And I think the overlap of
Speaker 6:  people for whom this chip would be useful and people who upgrade their ram
Speaker 6:  is like zero. So I think that's actually fine, but
Speaker 6:  I just, I think Intel is, is lying
Speaker 6:  until proven, truthful in a pretty real way about some of its chips right
Speaker 6:  now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I also want to know what I can do with 40 tops that I can't
Speaker 4:  do with 25 or two.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah.
Speaker 4:  What, what is it? Is it something, because we
Speaker 4:  seem to be in a spec war over nothing and I love a spec war, don't
Speaker 4:  get me wrong. You want to take me from 12 to 14 megapixels. I will talk to
Speaker 4:  you all day about that. You wanna go from HDMI 2.1 to 2.1 a,
Speaker 4:  we'll give you an hour. That's what we do here. I just,
Speaker 4:  what is it like, like I, I
Speaker 4:  don't need generative fill in Photoshop to go that much faster
Speaker 4:  and on my computer anyway. That's CPU bound. It's not even GPU bound. So
Speaker 4:  like what is the thing? And I, I don't think
Speaker 4:  there's a great broad consumer answer to that question yet.
Speaker 5:  The, I I, yeah, I would say a hundred percent. You're correct. I think most
Speaker 5:  of the, the answers are for like engineers and stuff
Speaker 5:  like that. They'll probably see some advantage from this.
Speaker 4:  By the way, not generated Phil a ID noise in Lightroom. That's the one
Speaker 4:  and my computer anyway. That, that's a good ones. CPU bound. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Surprisingly good too. That works. It's really good. Like remarkably, well,
Speaker 6:  every time I use it, every
Speaker 4:  Time I do it, I realize I'm committing like, like heresy against what is
Speaker 4:  a photo. I'm like, the Pope should come to my house and bless me,
Speaker 4:  but it's
Speaker 6:  Only like gentle heresy, you know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's a little
Speaker 6:  Goodhearted, heresy.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Fine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I have, we we should keep going. We're already, this is
Speaker 4:  Thing can see we're, we're gonna
Speaker 5:  Crack down.
Speaker 4:  Alright. Like, who knows? Question mark. Number two,
Speaker 4:  Humane is trying to sell itself to HP for a billion dollars. This is perfect.
Speaker 4:  David, the reporting from CBC says there's also at least
Speaker 4:  one telecom company in the mix.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So one of the things that Humane needed really early on
Speaker 6:  was telecom support. And it has been working with
Speaker 6:  different telecoms sell around the world. I think it made a deal in Japan
Speaker 6:  fairly recently to launch the device over there. Like getting the AI
Speaker 6:  pin on these networks is crucial to it working so in a certain way, like
Speaker 6:  if you're Verizon, you're like, oh, all we do
Speaker 6:  is sell other people stuff. We are desperate to be more than a dumb pipe.
Speaker 6:  Like you can see how you have that meeting. Right. And I think
Speaker 4:  This not Verizon ended up buying blue jeans. That's what I
Speaker 6:  Mean. And like they will keep,
Speaker 4:  This is ended up
Speaker 6:  Startups until morale improves. You know what I mean? This, this is just
Speaker 6:  what they do. So I would not be, I would not be shocked by that at all. The
Speaker 6:  HP one seems very strange to me.
Speaker 5:  IHP
Speaker 6:  Just can't do this and seems to have finally understood that being
Speaker 6:  cool is not HP's thing. And that's fine.
Speaker 6:  And yet here we are. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know what? You never like, as you get older, you, you always
Speaker 5:  have those moments where you're like, yeah, I can pull that off. Right? Like,
Speaker 4:  No, HP already had that moment. I wanna be very clear about
Speaker 5:  It's, we all have that moment. I, I thought I
Speaker 4:  Could pull,
Speaker 5:  Pull off a leather hat. I couldn't do that.
Speaker 4:  When did you think you could pull off a leather hat?
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 5:  Was like three months ago. Too long ago. Yeah, it was like last week, Tuesday
Speaker 5:  last week. Right. I, I thought I could pull off skinny jeans.
Speaker 5:  Like, like, like you always have these moments. Like, so
Speaker 4:  I just wanna point out in, in this comparison very directly
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm comparing buying Humane to buying skinny
Speaker 4:  Jeans and That's great. I'm I'm running with you. Yes. I'm just saying HP
Speaker 4:  went through its skinny jeans phase when it bought palm
Speaker 4:  and had an entire event that I went to in San Francisco on the water. It
Speaker 4:  was beautiful. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No, this is like
Speaker 4:  Where they were like, here's the HP Touchpad, our web os tablet
Speaker 4:  that will compete with the iPod. Jimmy Iovine was there and
Speaker 4:  he got on stage and was apparently so blown away with the level of
Speaker 4:  innovation on display that he just went off script for like 10 minutes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Paul Jacobs, who's the CEO of Qualcomm spoke right before this is a real,
Speaker 4:  I want you to go watch this video. I remember he was like, Dr. Paul Jacobs
Speaker 4:  was incredible. I was supposed to say something about music, but you know
Speaker 4:  what's beats we don't make chips. Like it was nuts. Nuts.
Speaker 4:  And then they canceled the touch pad. No, this is like, no one has one except
Speaker 4:  for Dieter and I don't think he's allowed to admit it anymore. 'cause he
Speaker 4:  works at Google. Now.
Speaker 5:  I I would say that this is like,
Speaker 4:  That those were the skinny jeans.
Speaker 5:  These are Yeah. That's skinny jeans. This is like when you hit like your
Speaker 5:  sixties. Okay. And you get the motorcycle and you're like, I'm gonna be a
Speaker 5:  guy that does motorcycling. See on the weekends they're gonna be a company
Speaker 5:  that does Humane. This
Speaker 6:  Is the midlife crisis. This isn't the the cool kids phase. This is the midlife
Speaker 6:  crisis.
Speaker 4:  No, that's the skinny jeans. Skinny jeans were midlife was the midlife crisis.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's fair. This is your retirement. It depends on when you think you're,
Speaker 4:  the sixties are, it's fair. I I would say it's midlife now that I'm in my
Speaker 4:  forties. This is, you're saying this is the the Harley with a windshield.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's Humane. Yeah. In this context for hp.
Speaker 4:  I understand. Totally nailed it. Understood. Harley with a
Speaker 4:  windshield. I grew up in Wisconsin. There were a lot of Harleys with a windshield.
Speaker 5:  It's like, look at that lawyer go, he bought that Harley last
Speaker 4:  Week. If you're a Harley person, you have a windshield. I want it's America.
Speaker 4:  You know, live your life.
Speaker 5:  You go real fast.
Speaker 4:  I'm a sports star person. Okay.
Speaker 4:  They also Humane the gift that keeps on giving
Speaker 4:  recall their, their battery cases this week.
Speaker 6:  It's a really tough week for Humane and it's, it's actually Humane has
Speaker 6:  entered that rare phase where everyone has gone from making fun of them to
Speaker 6:  feeling bad for them. And it is, it's a tough time at
Speaker 6:  Humane. But yeah, they had what sounds like one incident with a
Speaker 6:  charging case, which is a, a little like egg shaped thing that they ship
Speaker 6:  with the AI pin because the battery life is awful. And
Speaker 6:  because of that one incident, they are getting rid of that supplier and giving
Speaker 6:  all of the ai pin owners two extra months of service.
Speaker 6:  What they're not saying is whether they're going to replace anybody's charging
Speaker 6:  case, how they're doing better with the charging case. Like it just
Speaker 6:  seems like this company is scrambling in a really bad way and
Speaker 6:  I think correctly realized like, oh, something bad happened, it could happen
Speaker 6:  again. We have to stop it from happening. And did that before it made any
Speaker 6:  other plan. Because I don't think there is another plan because I think they're
Speaker 6:  just trying to sell as fast as they can and get out. Yeah. Yeah. It's just
Speaker 6:  bad times all around.
Speaker 4:  There is a very long times article about the inside of
Speaker 4:  Humane during this period and there's a lot of people saying, this isn't
Speaker 4:  as good as we think. Should we launch it now? And apparently being shut down
Speaker 4:  one slash
Speaker 6:  Slash
Speaker 4:  Fired slash fired. Yeah. Fired. Yeah. In one case being fired. Go read that.
Speaker 4:  But we'll see. I will say the idea of
Speaker 4:  either of the founders of Humane working for Verizon,
Speaker 4:  very funny, very funny. Or at and t and I I will say
Speaker 4:  just, I know we have to move on 'cause it's lightning around. I will say
Speaker 4:  once again, a workable antitrust policy for the United States
Speaker 4:  is to prevent at and t from buying anything.
Speaker 5:  That's what
Speaker 6:  You mean. It's like an anti-monopoly. 'cause it will just drag it down into
Speaker 6:  the muck.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's fine. That would work. You could, Joe, if you're listening
Speaker 4:  Donald, you know, you're in the mix. Propel, let's see what happens. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  let's get after it. You didn't, you didn't want them to buy Time Warner and
Speaker 4:  you were right my friend. Do you think Donald Trump has ever watched the
Speaker 4:  four three Senator Grace he
Speaker 5:  Hundred percent dead on.
Speaker 6:  Wait, before, before we do move on, I I'm just curious. The, the number in
Speaker 6:  the time story was that Humane has sold 10,000 AI pins. They were hoping
Speaker 6:  to sell a hundred, but they have 10. And my question for the two of you,
Speaker 6:  is that more or less than you would've guessed?
Speaker 5:  More
Speaker 4:  More.
Speaker 6:  Same actually, I, I I I, what I wonder is how many of those were
Speaker 6:  pre-orders and how many of those came after the reviews and after the thing
Speaker 6:  shipped? And I, I would be shocked if a thousand people have bought that
Speaker 6:  thing since
Speaker 4:  It shipped. What wasn't 10,000 number of rabbits too?
Speaker 6:  No, they sold, they sold like a hundred thousand rabbits. Oh.
Speaker 4:  'cause they were cheap. Yeah, I was I think you said on the show
Speaker 4:  when we heard the rabbit number the first time, like you could probably sell
Speaker 4:  that number of $300. Anything. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I really believe that. Yeah. It's orange. Like
Speaker 6:  it's
Speaker 4:  True. Speaking of extremely odd AI news, someone just
Speaker 4:  explained this to me. Raspberry Pi is getting AI features.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're getting a, I believe they're, they're gonna have a little a
Speaker 5:  like add-on accelerator that's gonna give you 13
Speaker 5:  tops.
Speaker 4:  Again, someone tell me what to do with one top Wait, no,
Speaker 6:  But, but Neli, the thing that's great about this is now every other chip
Speaker 6:  maker on earth is going to have to convince you that they can do more than
Speaker 6:  your raspberry pie. This is perfect. Raspberry pie is now it's the
Speaker 6:  thing is $70 floor and this is the bar now, like in order for
Speaker 6:  me to buy your thing, you have to be more compelling than a raspberry pie.
Speaker 6:  Which I
Speaker 5:  Love. I I love this because if anyone can figure out why
Speaker 5:  tops matter, it's, it's people using like raspberry pies for stuff.
Speaker 4:  All that's gonna happen is a bunch of people are gonna like hook a raspberry
Speaker 4:  pie up to their video doorbells and that. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 4:  unhinged LLM horny responses from video doorbells will happen.
Speaker 5:  What or what if like pie hole gets better? What if like pie hole can do
Speaker 5:  something with ai? With ai?
Speaker 5:  I don't know what, what I don't like, I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  What if the routing on your network was a little bit less reliable than it
Speaker 4:  was today?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just gonna start making stuff up. It's gonna be like, eat the
Speaker 5:  cheese Alex. It's got glue in it.
Speaker 4:  Like it's at the network level. It's telling lies. I'm into it.
Speaker 4:  It does feel like the $70 for raspberry pie is expensive. That's not where
Speaker 4:  they started. Yeah. And so it feels like this push is
Speaker 4:  just, it's making everything more expensive. I'm just begging for one.
Speaker 4:  What's it 18 tops.
Speaker 6:  13
Speaker 4:  Thir 13. Just just tell me what 13 tops are
Speaker 4:  for if you wanna max out in a, in a raspberry pie
Speaker 4:  compute environment. 13 tops.
Speaker 5:  I mean I do know what 13 tops are for, but it's a different time of tops.
Speaker 4:  Wait, the the trading cards are actual spinning tops. We'll keep going.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Keep
Speaker 6:  Going. Moving on.
Speaker 5:  Liam's gonna love
Speaker 4:  That. This is maybe a perfect VERGE scoop. I'm very happy
Speaker 4:  Jen Tui got this scoop. Yes. When I think, when I think of reasons
Speaker 4:  The Verge exists,
Speaker 4:  we found a secret thread radio in every Mac. Right. It's right at the top
Speaker 4:  of the list. Like we had to manufacture the reasons people
Speaker 4:  care about this, but Jen noticed in a bunch of
Speaker 4:  FCC documents that there are in fact thread radios
Speaker 4:  in a bunch of max and iPads. This follows on Apple announcing a thread
Speaker 4:  radio in the iPhone 15 in 15 Pro, which they've never
Speaker 4:  done anything with as far as we can tell. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Or even explained why it would be there.
Speaker 4:  Well, well no, what they said about the iPhone was this is for future home
Speaker 4:  app integrations. Right. Cool. Cool. Sure.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This sort of like makes sense like in the world of chip design
Speaker 4:  at Apple scale, maybe you just bought a bunch of wifi chips and they have
Speaker 4:  thread radios. You might as well have them. But they've said nothing. They,
Speaker 4:  they tested them, which means they can be used. They're not just like
Speaker 4:  dark on the, on the chip die. But why
Speaker 4:  Apple said nothing to Jen. Jen ran around and asked everybody what it's for.
Speaker 4:  There's a bunch of reasons you could have faster setup. You could have a
Speaker 4:  low power thread network in your house.
Speaker 5:  That'd be
Speaker 4:  Cool. That'd be neat. And have the devices serve
Speaker 4:  as border routers between wifi and thread. Although you want that usually
Speaker 4:  to be stationary. Like having your thread border router leave your home with
Speaker 4:  your laptop or your iPad not great or your iPhone.
Speaker 4:  There's a bunch of other little like ideas people have that Apple hasn't
Speaker 4:  said anything. I'm kind of hoping we find out at WWC
Speaker 5:  That that's Jen's hope too.
Speaker 4:  We'll
Speaker 6:  See, I see it also, it it, there is like, we're gonna talk about this in
Speaker 6:  the next segment, but if you like, push this into the big, like
Speaker 6:  AI makes your life easier narrative of Apple, like
Speaker 6:  pushing into smart home stuff and like sensors and letting
Speaker 6:  your devices talk to each other makes a lot of sense. I still think the,
Speaker 6:  the like Occam's razor explanation here is that they got that chip for
Speaker 6:  free inside of these tri band chips that are in a lot of devices.
Speaker 6:  But I hope it's more cool. It's more interesting than that.
Speaker 5:  I was just trying to see if thread radios have tops in them
Speaker 5:  So far it seems, no,
Speaker 4:  Not even a single top. No
Speaker 5:  Tops. Well that I'm
Speaker 4:  Out. And also very few uses for thread that matter.
Speaker 4:  We're we have to create the conditions by which people care about these scoops.
Speaker 4:  But a perfect VERGE scoop from Jen, speaking of Apple, another
Speaker 4:  weird one. They misstated the core count the number of
Speaker 4:  GPUs on the M two iPad Air. They said it was 10. It's
Speaker 4:  actually nine. How, how do you make a mistake like
Speaker 4:  this?
Speaker 5:  Like Yeah. Yeah. That, that's just the thing. This was very surprising to
Speaker 5:  see from Apple because they have a whole marketing department a, a very good
Speaker 5:  one when it's not like crushing all of art.
Speaker 5:  So, so the like to screw up, which I think is fair to say
Speaker 5:  that's a screw up, is to put the wrong number of cores
Speaker 5:  on all of the marketing materials. That's a pretty big one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And you think that the engineers, the chip designer, I mean because
Speaker 4:  it, the way these work is they pixel bin the chips. Yeah. So they try to
Speaker 4:  make the chips the, the most number of cores, some of them don't get, don't,
Speaker 4:  don't work. And they pixel bin 'em and they cut down the number of cores
Speaker 4:  that are active to just the ones that work. And off you go. Every
Speaker 4:  manufacturer does this
Speaker 5:  Thing. Maybe someone just like forgot to be like, yo, we pixel bin that one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then it was up on the screen and they're like, oh dang, I forgot
Speaker 5:  to send that email last week.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then Apple's email system is like archaic. Yeah. And it just didn't
Speaker 4:  go through the approvals.
Speaker 6:  Yep. WebEx was down that day. And
Speaker 4:  They do use WebEx. I will say this is not in our show in nor Aaron. We had
Speaker 4:  the CEO of Zoom on decoder and he used to work at WebEx and I asked him if
Speaker 4:  he used WebEx in the past year and he was like, I don't, no.
Speaker 4:  Truly weird. They haven't said it. They're gonna make it Right because they
Speaker 4:  say the performance that they're offering is the same as what they said.
Speaker 4:  So you just got the number wrong. But the performance Right.
Speaker 6:  Well and even apparently the listed performance is right. So like
Speaker 6:  the only mistake that they made was a 10 instead of a nine. Which if that's
Speaker 6:  true, is like Yeah. Mostly it's just weird that it happened.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I do. Yeah. I, it's just like
Speaker 5:  I typos all the time.
Speaker 4:  This is what happens when you let the AI write your spec sheets for you.
Speaker 4:  You just made stuff up and I'm like, oh crap. See lightning round. This
Speaker 4:  is, this is all the more that needs to be said moving Right on. Samsung had
Speaker 4:  a leak, potentially a cheaper Galaxy watch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Samsung loves to leak things. They're not as bad as like Google,
Speaker 5:  but they're, they're, they're up there. So there's New Galaxy Watch. It's
Speaker 5:  gonna be like their founder's edition. So the FE edition
Speaker 5:  could cost about $200. Has a lot of really pretty colors.
Speaker 5:  Seems really neat if it's real and it probably is. So I think like Galaxy
Speaker 5:  unpacked is happening very, very soon. So we should know a lot more
Speaker 5:  very, very soon. But now we know a lot. It's gonna probably be
Speaker 5:  $199. It's got an EXOS W
Speaker 5:  nine 20 chip in it. 1.5 gigabytes of Ram
Speaker 5:  16 gigabytes of storage.
Speaker 4:  What do use with 16 gigabytes of storage on a smartwatch?
Speaker 5:  You put all only music. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I think that's the real answer
Speaker 5:  All the time. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like yeah. Download. You just download a bunch of playlists and you're off
Speaker 6:  running because
Speaker 5:  People need their, their like, that was always a weird thing when I was reviewing
Speaker 5:  watches years ago. People would always be like, yeah, how many songs can
Speaker 5:  I get on that
Speaker 4:  Watch? Yeah. 'cause you wanna go for a run without your phone,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. And I'm like, why are you running, what, why are you running
Speaker 5:  and then you're just gonna use your watch. That's not people do it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  A lot of people do it and I respect them for it. Sorry. Unpack.
Speaker 4:  This is why we have v on our staff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's why VV runs. Thank you V Yeah,
Speaker 6:  V begrudgingly runs, which is the correct way to review products, I think.
Speaker 6:  And I, I love that about v unpacked is usually what, like early
Speaker 6:  August, right? Yeah. I think it's gonna be a really interesting one. Like
Speaker 6:  the galaxy ring seems like it might be a pretty cool, this is coming, you
Speaker 6:  know, Samsung is going to have hundreds of thousands of weird ideas about
Speaker 6:  ai. Samsung will answer your tops questions. Neli, Samsung is going to
Speaker 6:  figure out what to do with tops. Will they be good ideas? I don't know. Will
Speaker 6:  they be branded milk? Like maybe. But they will, they will
Speaker 6:  use those tops and I I think it's gonna actually be really fun if I, this
Speaker 5:  Year I they're gonna have the most unhinged digital assistant. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like it's it's gonna have like a face
Speaker 4:  Big like bigby with a face.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's gonna talk to you. It's gonna make you feel very uncomfortable.
Speaker 5:  I am so excited.
Speaker 4:  I feel like this Wwc and we will talk about that next time when it we're
Speaker 4:  leading into what I have begun to think of as the, what is a photo
Speaker 4:  apocalypse because Apple's just gonna let people start. But like it's when
Speaker 4:  Samsung is like, this is what the tops are for. All
Speaker 4:  bets are off.
Speaker 5:  We just made a new moon. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just straight up like two moons. Fine. That's what the tops are for.
Speaker 5:  Each tops gives you another moon.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of ai, more ai, nothing. It has the phone three.
Speaker 4:  David, you looked at it apparently just AI apps for days.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Did you guys see this teaser that, that Carl pay the CEO of nothing
Speaker 6:  put up. He basically, it's like him sitting in an armchair being like, we
Speaker 6:  believe that smartphones are the future of ai. And it's like, cool Carl like
Speaker 6:  great job. But then they show off a couple of things they've been working
Speaker 6:  on and one of them is just like straight up like
Speaker 6:  GPT-4 oh rip like push the button, talk to the
Speaker 6:  assistant looks very cool. But they also had this prototype they've been
Speaker 6:  working on of a dynamic personalized home screen, I guess you'd call it.
Speaker 6:  It's like a little bit news feed, a little bit sort of live updating
Speaker 6:  widgets with all the information you care about. And Carl has
Speaker 6:  been saying for years, including on this show, I think almost exactly a year
Speaker 6:  ago, that their big idea is like, okay, smartphones are still
Speaker 6:  the thing, but the app model is wrong. And how do we start to push past
Speaker 6:  this idea that all of life is just siloed off into a million apps. And I
Speaker 6:  happen to agree with that more and more every day. And so I think
Speaker 6:  it was interesting to see what they were working on and he just sort of said,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna start working on this stuff on the phone three. Like not surprising
Speaker 6:  that there's going to be a thing called the phone three, but interesting
Speaker 6:  that he said it and presumably it's gonna be launched this summer. Very curious
Speaker 6:  to see what they do because they've been kind of like
Speaker 6:  forward looking in some of their designy stuff, but have mostly just made
Speaker 6:  like pretty straightforward cell phones and headphones. Like it's a, it's
Speaker 6:  a design around a pretty straightforward product. But if they're gonna start
Speaker 6:  doing this stuff, it might be more of a push into something different in
Speaker 6:  the Android world, which I think would be pretty cool.
Speaker 5:  Does it give you guys kind of like a Windows phone vibe?
Speaker 4:  Yes. I was gonna tell you, this is the episode of House where I brought up
Speaker 4:  the fact that I lived through the touch pad and now I have to be here being
Speaker 4:  like, this was the, this is Windows phone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like we're just, we're just doing and Gadget again. Yeah. I mean
Speaker 4:  this is how I spent my time back then.
Speaker 6:  A it is just 2004. Again, I would point that out. It just is,
Speaker 6:  but also like, it's really, it's long past due for us to
Speaker 6:  just admit that live tiles were a good idea and Microsoft should have stuck
Speaker 6:  to them because they
Speaker 4:  Were, they should have stuck to Windows. They
Speaker 6:  Should have stuck. No, no. They should have, they should have changed every
Speaker 6:  other thing about what they were doing except for Live tiles, which were
Speaker 6:  a good idea.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  A real like baby bath water situation. Like this
Speaker 5:  Is like less attractive life tiles.
Speaker 4:  There was a Microsoft event in Vegas where they announced like
Speaker 4:  the next version of the app model Windows phone. I'm just saying that's where
Speaker 4:  I fell in love with Teeter Bone. Aww, that's nice. Like we were, we were
Speaker 4:  there being like, are they
Speaker 5:  Say anything like eyes connected over the shitty
Speaker 4:  Phone Met we, we drank a lot. We we drank
Speaker 4:  a lot. And I was like, we will be friends now.
Speaker 4:  You you belong to me. We lasted a lot longer than Windows phone. I'm just
Speaker 4:  saying That's true. It's
Speaker 5:  Beautiful. It's true. It's true.
Speaker 4:  But the idea that Microsoft should have stuck to Windows phone because Carl
Speaker 4:  Pay is out here with nothing. Being like, what if we did this idea again?
Speaker 4:  What if we expose the apps to another interface on the home screen?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Man. I don't know. Like everyone wants to do this, but the app makers
Speaker 4:  don't wanna do it. They want you in their app. Right.
Speaker 6:  I mean it's, we've seen this even like, again, WWDC is gonna be interesting
Speaker 6:  in that respect. 'cause we spent a lot of time last year talking about these
Speaker 6:  live updating widgets and the interactive widgets and the dynamic island
Speaker 6:  and this idea that like, oh, you can pull information out of the apps and
Speaker 6:  onto the home screen of your phone. I think we've gotten to like a two
Speaker 6:  out of 10 on where that could have gone. And it's been a year and like, I
Speaker 6:  don't know how many live activities y'all interact with every day, but my
Speaker 6:  answer is pretty damn close to zero
Speaker 5:  Once a week when I get Uber Eats.
Speaker 4:  There you go. There's countdown timers for various things that are gonna
Speaker 4:  happen. Yeah. All very good. Yeah. But it's also kind of like, yeah, I, I'd
Speaker 4:  super know the plane is gonna land in 45 minutes.
Speaker 5:  I mean I like, like the Uber Eats one is great. I'm like, wings almost here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then sometimes it goes up and I'm like, wings took a wrong turn.
Speaker 5:  Come back Wings.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're gonna get through this whole thing. We're almost done. We're
Speaker 4:  almost there. We got two left. The ASE Rogue
Speaker 4:  Ally X
Speaker 4:  Sean looked at it. Alex, what do you think?
Speaker 5:  I love Sean's enthusiasm for this thing. 'cause he, he
Speaker 5:  went to look at it originally.
Speaker 4:  Rog or Rogue?
Speaker 5:  Rog. Rog. It's wrong.
Speaker 4:  It was, I know, I know, I
Speaker 5:  Know. It stands for Republic of Gamers. I'm aware of that. Which was a, which
Speaker 5:  was a gaming company that at a sous spot. 'cause all
Speaker 4:  All of this stuff is in my brain. It's just right next to Windows phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Windows phone was really
Speaker 4:  Loud then. Right? They gotta spin up the dress.
Speaker 5:  Just, just, just really loud. No, I, I like, I
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm really optimistic. I mean, we both talk about this a lot.
Speaker 5:  Like Sean and I's dms are just like more steam decks and more Steam deck
Speaker 5:  clones. Yeah. We've designed about four of our own.
Speaker 4:  This is how it starts.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Someone call us. We, we've got great ideas. This thing is
Speaker 5:  is is definitely still pretty heavy. It's, it's definitely
Speaker 5:  beefy in a way that I think people will not find always so
Speaker 5:  pleasing. But is is
Speaker 4:  The Steam deck still just the the the prototypical
Speaker 4:  one of these?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's, it's primarily because is it the one to be Yeah. 'cause most
Speaker 5:  of these run on Windows. Yeah. And that's not very
Speaker 5:  good for, for this, for this platform, right? Yeah. Like I think
Speaker 5:  that's the thing that Steam Deck has done really, really well, is they built
Speaker 5:  this really, really good platform so you can just pop in and start downloading
Speaker 5:  games and go. Whereas everybody else, you have to like futs with it.
Speaker 5:  You know, there's always something. This
Speaker 6:  Is like a sneakily exciting reason to be optimistic for all these new chips,
Speaker 6:  right? That if they, if they are as good as advertised, suddenly building
Speaker 6:  a device like this that is light and good and lasts a long time
Speaker 6:  and still does the stuff you want it to do, becomes a lot more plausible.
Speaker 6:  Whereas right now you basically have to just shove as much of
Speaker 6:  a gaming PC as possible into as small a box as possible. And that
Speaker 6:  is just physics. Yeah. And physics is hard, but I will say on this,
Speaker 4:  I all the while Microsoft is like, what if Windows just watched everything
Speaker 4:  you did and wrote it down in a plain text database
Speaker 4:  And it's like, I don't, it'll
Speaker 5:  Be
Speaker 4:  Fine. But that's one of the reasons that's the advantage Steam Deck has,
Speaker 4:  is they were able to cut down the, the operating system. Right.
Speaker 5:  And, and this one like assumes their, their way of doing it is like, well,
Speaker 5:  we're not gonna fix Windows,
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 5:  We're gonna make the battery a lot bigger. Yeah. There go. So, so that, that
Speaker 5:  could be really cool. Like, like this thing should have probably I think
Speaker 5:  the biggest battery of all of these kind of deals, but
Speaker 5:  We'll, we'll see. I like, I would love, every time I get one of these in
Speaker 5:  I'm like, oh, this is gonna be rad. And then I meet Windows and I'm having
Speaker 5:  to use a joystick to move a mouse around the screen and it
Speaker 5:  stops being rad real fast. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's end it where we need to end it with the promise we made
Speaker 4:  at the top of the show. There's a defense contractor who made a game. Boy,
Speaker 4:  it's Palmer lucky everybody. What a surprise. Of course.
Speaker 4:  If the, this is a long and twisted tail. Palmer. Lucky we met when he was
Speaker 4:  a literal child. Speaking of things that happened a million years ago, we
Speaker 4:  saw the first Oculus prototype in our
Speaker 4:  like trailer at CES
Speaker 6:  2012, right?
Speaker 4:  A hundred million years ago. It was a young
Speaker 4:  fresh-faced Palmer Lucky. Yeah. Showing us a thing, talking about OLED refresh
Speaker 4:  rates and how he'd built the thing in forums and met John Carmack in the
Speaker 4:  forums of the Ole Nerds. It was very vir. Many things
Speaker 4:  have happened to both Oculus and Palmer. Lucky in that time.
Speaker 4:  He
Speaker 5:  Grew a little mustache. He,
Speaker 4:  The facial hair is, we're gonna set it aside. You're allowed
Speaker 4:  to make whatever choices you want with your facial hair. It's true. If you
Speaker 4:  wanna make those, we will just note them and set them aside.
Speaker 4:  Meta bought Oculus, they turned into the Quest line.
Speaker 4:  They fired Palmer. Lucky for being kind of weird.
Speaker 4:  Palmer Lucky made a bunch of weird donations to the Trump campaign, mostly
Speaker 4:  in the form of inflammatory billboards, I believe. Yeah. This is all real.
Speaker 4:  This is like in the past. And then he started a defense contractor named
Speaker 4:  Andrew, which makes drones with guns on them.
Speaker 5:  And is also named after like a jk. No, not at
Speaker 5:  JK Rowing named after a JR Tolkien. Like
Speaker 4:  Oh, sure. He also has Cosplayed
Speaker 5:  And more of the Rings stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He's also cosplayed as quiet from Metal Gear series. One of the, a
Speaker 4:  real thing that you can go look at a photo of,
Speaker 6:  One of the great sightings of my life was in San Jose. I was at a bar with
Speaker 6:  my wife watching the NBA playoffs. And Palmer Lucky comes
Speaker 6:  walking in with a tail on and just sits down at the bar and orders a drink.
Speaker 6:  Just a delightful day.
Speaker 4:  He's been spiky with us. Whatever. This is all Palmer lucky stuff. And it's
Speaker 4:  in the, like, people arguing about the merits of spending money on Palmer
Speaker 4:  Lucky devices in our comments. But it is true
Speaker 4:  that he's made something called the Chromatic
Speaker 6:  And it looks sick. Which,
Speaker 4:  Which is rules $199 and apparently is just like, what if
Speaker 4:  you finished a Game Boy? Like what if you took a Game Boy to the
Speaker 4:  most Game Boy conclusion It could be.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What if you took all of the technology we have in 2024
Speaker 5:  and made a Game Boy from 1989
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 6:  Plays Game Boy cartridges for like, it's, it's, it is exactly what I
Speaker 6:  want it to be. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  Or excuse me, game boy color too.
Speaker 6:  You're right. Yeah. It has a, it has a color matched screen to the game
Speaker 6:  boy color. Right. Super bright, really good screen.
Speaker 6:  The colors look awesome. Like this, this thing. Yeah, you're right. All the
Speaker 6:  pedigree of it aside, this thing looks awesome and
Speaker 6:  it's 200 bucks. And I think like people love the stuff that analog makes
Speaker 6:  and, and at least from the little bit we've seen so far, this belongs like
Speaker 6:  right there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like analog I would say is for modern
Speaker 5:  nerds who wanna like get into retro gaming. This is for like you are
Speaker 5:  in retro gaming. Yeah. Because this is, this is like, what if we could make
Speaker 5:  it as accurate as possible, but modern, so like, like the pixels and everything,
Speaker 5:  you know, it's not a super high resolution display or anything like that.
Speaker 5:  It is meant to be the same resolution as the Game boy color,
Speaker 5:  which came out.
Speaker 4:  And then also it comes with a side of deep moral ambivalence. There
Speaker 5:  You go. And
Speaker 6:  Tetris, don't forget, Tetris
Speaker 5:  And Tetris
Speaker 4:  Very confusing product just all the way around. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I don't know that I'm gonna spend $200 on it. I know that
Speaker 4:  Boy would I love to spend $200 on something just like it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Deep moral ambivalence. That's, that's what I would say a defense contractor.
Speaker 4:  Although if Lockheed Martin was to make a 200 game, boy would we cover it.
Speaker 4:  I think the answer is surely yes. Yeah. Lockheed, you have your orders. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Agreed. I mean, it is interesting like Palmer lucky it is
Speaker 6:  documented as having been into this for a really, really long time. Like
Speaker 6:  I I, again, all of, all of the feelings about Palmer. Lucky aside, he's
Speaker 6:  actually a person you would think would probably do a very good job of this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's gonna be, it's gonna be really interesting to see. He's also apparently
Speaker 6:  about to launch some new headset like Palmer. He's just running around doing
Speaker 6:  stuff now is it's very odd. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Mean that defense contractor money really helps out. Yeah. Seriously. But
Speaker 5:  yeah. And that, that's the, that's the challenge of trying to wear as many
Speaker 5:  hats as he does, is that people don't like sell a lot of those
Speaker 4:  Hats. Ed one of those hats is reprehensible politics. Okay. That's the lightning
Speaker 4:  round. We finished it. We did it. I dunno how long. Mila,
Speaker 6:  I'm really proud of it took 45 minutes. You did a good job. It was so long
Speaker 6:  I only had to delete two things from the list. That was really good. We
Speaker 4:  As we went. All right. We have to take a quick break. We'll be back preview
Speaker 4:  of WDC and then a second traditional
Speaker 4:  lightning round for you traditionalists. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back.
Speaker 4:  which is really interesting. Traditionally we've seen
Speaker 4:  and you certainly don't want to tie that to the idea that you need
Speaker 4:  new hardware to do it. Right. The 'cause Apple has been on that
Speaker 4:  cadence in the past where they're like, here's a new iPhone.
Speaker 4:  We've gated some camera feature that you could definitely do on the old iPhone
Speaker 4:  to the new iPhone. But here, this is about the future of iOS. It's about
Speaker 4:  the future of Siri. It seems like you need all of the focus to be like
Speaker 4:  a great upgrade that's coming to everybody with a recent iPhone
Speaker 5:  Ai. Yeah. Apple does not wanna be talking about Tops. I mean, not just because
Speaker 5:  their, their processors have the fewest, but Yeah, they, that that's not
Speaker 5:  a thing. They wanna, they they
Speaker 4:  Never, I mean they never wanna talk about specs that way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They never wanna talk about the
Speaker 6:  Specs. But Alex, that's, that's true. And it isn't. Right, because the, the,
Speaker 6:  it is true that Apple is maybe losing the tops where it's also definitely
Speaker 6:  true that Apple is going to have the most
Speaker 6:  devices that this stuff can run on Yeah. By a million miles
Speaker 6:  on day one. And that is like, they don't, that's the Flex Apple is gonna
Speaker 6:  want here. Not we launched a new AI thing, but like we made all your things
Speaker 6:  AI things and if you're Apple and the world feels like you need to catch
Speaker 6:  up in ai, that's how you do it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I totally, totally agree. And I, and especially because as we, we
Speaker 5:  know, we, we have no idea what TOPS actually do so so they
Speaker 5:  don't need to care about it.
Speaker 4:  Well, so like what are Tops four a good question. Apple has an
Speaker 4:  opportunity to answer that question. Maybe not by saying Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We don't care
Speaker 4:  Tops. Yeah. But by saying like, here are a bunch of features in the operating
Speaker 4:  system. Apple very famously has so much
Speaker 4:  headroom in terms of performance that it can just
Speaker 4:  put out features. It can, it can waste cycles basically, again, to
Speaker 4:  just sound like an old band when os an Apple first announced OS
Speaker 4:  10 and it was like beautiful, it had extra animations. Everyone would
Speaker 4:  complain that they were just like running the processor all the time. And
Speaker 4:  Apple was like, yeah, it's pretty, that's what we do here.
Speaker 4:  It's delightful. Yeah. That's what, that's what the processors are for. And
Speaker 4:  now they have so much headroom they can do a bunch of stuff. So there, there's
Speaker 4:  just a bunch of stuff. There's AI
Speaker 4:  generated emojis. Yep. Rumored to be announced. There's AI
Speaker 4:  powered voice transcription in voice memos and in notes, which
Speaker 4:  sounds great.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Love it should put that in the operating system. Sorry, a bunch of India
Speaker 4:  apps that are offering that right now.
Speaker 4:  The idea that Siri will be able to just like go into your apps and do things.
Speaker 4:  An idea that we have talked about for a long time, programmatically with
Speaker 4:  Bixby, programmatically with Siri, with shortcuts
Speaker 4:  in implausible and ultimately fake ways with Rabbit in a
Speaker 4:  large action model. Like the idea that an assistant can just
Speaker 4:  use a computer for you, that is the dream. Apple can get
Speaker 4:  to somewhere farther than we are now with Sir on the phone.
Speaker 4:  That's a huge Yeah. Step
Speaker 5:  Forward if I can just go, 'cause I, I, we all have like, what,
Speaker 5:  four different music and podcasting and audio book apps on our phones.
Speaker 5:  And so when you're like, yeah, I just wanna listen to my book, it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, would you like to buy it from the Apple store? And you're like, no,
Speaker 5:  I have it in like Libby or LiRo FM or whatever. And to the idea to just be
Speaker 5:  like, Hey, play that. Go do it. Go do it. And it would just do it.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God, that would be incredible.
Speaker 4:  Will that actually happen Or will Apple still try to get you to buy a
Speaker 4:  book from the, from the iBook store?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I think, I think that's gonna be the real issue for or for,
Speaker 5:  for that particular use case.
Speaker 6:  But so I think the question is
Speaker 6:  exclusively what you just said, NELI, which I think is really fascinating,
Speaker 6:  right? Because until now there have been a million problems, right? One of
Speaker 6:  which is the like underlying machine learning technology is not very good.
Speaker 6:  One of which is that Siri is not historically very good at speech
Speaker 6:  recognition. One is that the processing stuff has not been as fast
Speaker 6:  as it needs to be to be useful for stuff. But the biggest one has just been
Speaker 6:  that Apple won't let developers do stuff. And if
Speaker 6:  you're Apple, the question now is like, what are we going to
Speaker 6:  expose to developers? Because the way it's been for a long time is developers
Speaker 6:  would've had to do all the work, right? So Apple just says like, here's what
Speaker 6:  Siri can do, plug it into your app however you'd like. But if this new AI
Speaker 6:  thing can work the way that it might, or at least that it's been reported
Speaker 6:  to work, all developers have to do is basically just like
Speaker 6:  expose their app to Siri in a way that could become very powerful in the
Speaker 6:  way that it's like, I don't know, Google search is a good example of this,
Speaker 6:  right? Like if you just write a recipe on your website in a certain way or
Speaker 6:  you structure the page a certain way, like Google can understand it and index
Speaker 6:  it and do stuff with it. And if Apple can say, Hey,
Speaker 6:  Spotify, Libby, whoever else, you want somebody to just be able to
Speaker 6:  listen to their podcasts in your app. Just turn these
Speaker 6:  three flags on that say, here's how you play a podcast in our app and we're
Speaker 6:  off and running. Like if everybody wants this to happen, it could happen.
Speaker 4:  But that's not the AI of it.
Speaker 6:  No, that's,
Speaker 4:  That's like, that exists sort of today. Like you can
Speaker 4:  kind of get there. My favorite example of this, I'm just going to
Speaker 4:  admit to being a dad who buys chicken nuggets in the McDonald's app all
Speaker 4:  the time. It's like a real thing that happens. I'm counting
Speaker 4:  those points. We're gonna get six free nuggets one of these days.
Speaker 4:  And every time I make this order it's like, do you wanna make a series shortcut
Speaker 4:  for this order? And I have like a total moral crisis about
Speaker 4:  voice ordering chicken nuggets. Like,
Speaker 4:  but it's like those flags already exist. No, but this
Speaker 6:  Is my point. Walk me through that process. Tell me, tell me every step you
Speaker 6:  take to do that,
Speaker 4:  You literally hit a button in the app that's like, just say this as a, as
Speaker 4:  a favorite. And then you can be like, Siri.
Speaker 6:  No, I mean to order Siri or to, oh wait, wait, you order
Speaker 6:  McDonald's and then it says, do you wanna order McDonald's with your voice?
Speaker 6:  And you can't bring yourself to be
Speaker 4:  That. If you make me open this app on this podcast, I would right now like
Speaker 4:  to.my
Speaker 6:  God. I would like you to do that very much. No, because one thing I, I should
Speaker 6:  have said this at the beginning, is there are gonna be a lot of people listening
Speaker 6:  to this who are like, shortcuts solved this. And no it doesn't. No it doesn't.
Speaker 6:  Shortcuts is a bad app that no one can figure out. And if you figured it
Speaker 6:  out, congratulations. And I'm proud of you. Shortcuts is not the solution
Speaker 6:  to this problem.
Speaker 5:  I would say shortcuts is the solution. If you're a programmer and you have
Speaker 5:  a really strong grasp of programming.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you wanna write code, you can solve a lot of your problems, including
Speaker 6:  in shortcuts.
Speaker 5:  Absolutely true. Yeah. I, I don't wanna write code if you know
Speaker 6:  What a callback URL is. Congratulations. You can use shortcuts.
Speaker 6:  Most people don't and that's fine.
Speaker 4:  I don't think you can set up Siri on the McDonald's app unless you order
Speaker 4:  McDonald's.
Speaker 4:  That's, but it is. That's how they get you. But, but it is true that you
Speaker 4:  can set up a Siri thing. It might use shortcuts in the background, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like the hooks for have Siri do stuff in the app
Speaker 4:  programmatically, semantically, like you're talking about with Google, they
Speaker 4:  exist. The opportunity for Apple is to say,
Speaker 4:  we control this operating system top to bottom. We control the app store
Speaker 4:  top to bottom in, at least in this country and
Speaker 4:  we can now use your phone for you. Right? Which is more or less the promise
Speaker 4:  Samsung made with Bixby a million years ago. and more or less the promise,
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is starting to make with Windows. Yeah, right. We just sit over
Speaker 4:  the top of everything and we'll click around for you.
Speaker 4:  And if Apple can get there, which I don't know if they can, but it's
Speaker 4:  certainly the promise that's been reported by Grim and others, they will
Speaker 4:  get there in their own apps that you'll just be able to talk to Siri and
Speaker 4:  it will take action in Apple's own apps. And there's obviously privacy and
Speaker 4:  security concerns and all this stuff, but if they can get even a little bit
Speaker 4:  farther there on the phone with ai, so it's not this like very
Speaker 4:  manual set the flags of what you're allowed to do and here's how it
Speaker 4:  works, but much more where the computer's gonna use the computer
Speaker 4:  for you. That's a huge deal. Oh, I agree. I don't know how much processing
Speaker 4:  power you need for that. I don't know if Well
Speaker 5:  You're, you're also gonna run into to Apple's like desire to have you
Speaker 5:  use their stuff so that they get money and Right.
Speaker 4:  And then and once you're, once, once you're using Apple stuff and Apple's
Speaker 4:  ecosystem, whether or not it even is AI like starts to
Speaker 4:  get fully obfuscated. 'cause you don't, you could just fake once you control
Speaker 4:  everything, you just like fake it more or less. Yeah. So there's a million
Speaker 4:  questions in there and then there's obviously the big problem of
Speaker 4:  how many tops do you need to pull that off? Can they run locally on the phone,
Speaker 4:  which is power constrained, network constrained, all this stuff. Heat, thermal
Speaker 4:  constrained.
Speaker 4:  Yikes. Yeah. And then do you want your phone watching everything you do like,
Speaker 4:  just like a series of escalating yikes problems. Yeah. I'm very curious
Speaker 4:  to see how Apple talks about this stuff. 'cause this sort of like
Speaker 4:  chat bot esque part Yeah. Where you're like, make a custom emoji for
Speaker 4:  me or like do a voice transcription. Like these familiar things
Speaker 4:  all make sense to do the part where they're like, we control everything and
Speaker 4:  we can do things that no one else can do. Wild. I'm
Speaker 5:  Also gonna be curious if they can even like roll it out as fast
Speaker 5:  as they want to. Right. Because I think technologically they can, but I'm
Speaker 5:  just thinking of what we've, what we've seen again and again and again is
Speaker 5:  that these companies are pushing these things out and not considering the
Speaker 5:  edge cases. Because I was just sitting here being like, oh man, I'm totally
Speaker 5:  gonna have it make an ugly Sonic the
Speaker 5:  hedgehog emoji that looks like Raccoon Girl.
Speaker 5:  Which is like, that is a whole thing that would
Speaker 5:  see, I think any AI would struggle with that. Siri would struggle with
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 4:  There's a red team at Apple right now listening to this podcast being like,
Speaker 4:  did we test Right?
Speaker 10:  I hope you guys did.
Speaker 4:  Please hire Alex Cranz for
Speaker 6:  All your Edge case Red team.
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  A service we can provide on this show. You
Speaker 10:  Know, the, the,
Speaker 5:  The glue thing happened because they were like, how do I get the cheese to
Speaker 5:  stick to the pizza?
Speaker 4:  Can I say the funniest thing about the glue thing?
Speaker 5:  What did you do
Speaker 4:  It? I have not. Katie and I policy said Insider did it. She said it was fine
Speaker 4:  but you know, it's all good. You need to trust her that it was fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So Google is manually deleting the bad results or Google
Speaker 4:  contractors and some other country are manually deleting the results as people
Speaker 4:  see them. But because so many people have now searched for
Speaker 4:  how to keep pizza, glue the cheese on pizza and then
Speaker 4:  proactively clicked on fuck Smith's comment
Speaker 4:  on Reddit about the glue, the regular Google search algorithm
Speaker 4:  now is like, that's the answer. So Google
Speaker 5:  Ai, Google bombed Google. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Like the, the, if you at least I have a screenshot of it, but it, when
Speaker 4:  I searched for it the other day, no AI result, but
Speaker 4:  straight up it was like, here's a Reddit answer from 11 years ago by user
Speaker 4:  named fuck Smith who's like put the glue on pizza. You got it, didn't you?
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  It just immediately got it. That was the first thing
Speaker 4:  I got. It's like we, the regular Google algorithm is now broken.
Speaker 10:  That brings me so much skill.
Speaker 4:  It's like whatcha gonna do with this man?
Speaker 5:  You can put the glue on the pizza.
Speaker 4:  And it's funny because with the Google leak that we were talking about last
Speaker 4:  week, we know it's because of the clicks. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We, we know that So many people have like clicked on this answer as a goof.
Speaker 4:  That regular Google got confused. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh it's beautiful. It's
Speaker 4:  Good. Anyway, back to Apple. I can Apple's brand sustain
Speaker 4:  that kind of error. It seems like they're not gonna do an open chat bot in
Speaker 4:  this way. Yeah. But that brings us to whatever this OpenAI partnership
Speaker 4:  is gonna be. I feel like I'm gonna disclose now that Fox Media has a
Speaker 4:  content deal with OpenAI. Yep. It's the first time we've done it in the
Speaker 4:  course of the show. Like in the flow quick,
Speaker 5:  Somebody bring up Netflix.
Speaker 4:  I made a Netflix show.
Speaker 10:  Hi
Speaker 4:  Hollywood Patel over here. It's called The Future of, it's a great show,
Speaker 4:  I encourage you to watch it. It was number one for five minutes and then
Speaker 4:  immediately other shows were number one.
Speaker 4:  Anyhow,
Speaker 4:  what are they gonna do with open ai? It feels like this is where Open AI
Speaker 4:  launches a search product or another
Speaker 4:  kind of integration. Who knows? David, do you have any inkling it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be a
Speaker 6:  Chatbot
Speaker 4:  Chat? You think it's just gonna be a chatbot
Speaker 6:  Bot? Well, no. So there's a bunch of things going on here. One is, is that
Speaker 6:  like no
Speaker 4:  Multimodal four oh
Speaker 6:  Search. So there's gonna be some of that. Right? And to your point about
Speaker 6:  how Apple does this on device Siri thing, there's this research paper
Speaker 6:  that Apple put out I think earlier this year. It was either very late last
Speaker 6:  year or early this year about this thing called Ferret, which is basically
Speaker 6:  the like academic version of some of what we're talking about. It's
Speaker 6:  basically how to teach a language model, how to understand what's on a screen.
Speaker 6:  And one of the things they say in that paper is that
Speaker 6:  GPT-4 is very good at sort of conceptually understanding
Speaker 6:  a page, right? Like you, you show it something and it says this is an image
Speaker 6:  of people on the beach, but if you zoom all the way in and
Speaker 6:  you're like, what's this little thing on the sand? GPT four's not good at
Speaker 6:  that. So what they built is this thing ferret that is very good in these
Speaker 6:  small spaces. And what they say in the paper is, this combination is going
Speaker 6:  to be very useful for us because we have this one simple system that can
Speaker 6:  just say, this is the Discover Weekly playlist on
Speaker 6:  Spotify. And then you have this thing ferret that can drill down and be like,
Speaker 6:  okay, that's the song that they're looking for. And so I think that is
Speaker 6:  probably more what you're gonna see that GPT-4 and this OpenAI
Speaker 6:  partnership is sort of the big broad strokes. Like
Speaker 6:  let's do the first 80% of the AI job with a lot of the stuff.
Speaker 6:  And then Apple's job underneath it is going to be to fix
Speaker 6:  all of the things that GPT-4 either can't do or doesn't do very well. Which
Speaker 6:  actually in a lot of ways is really smart because it, you don't need to
Speaker 6:  reinvent all the, you know, quote unquote easier stuff. Apple can just
Speaker 6:  like build features on top of it. It's like all the browsers building
Speaker 6:  out of chromium now it's like we don't, we, we've more or less finished the
Speaker 6:  job of like how to do the very small simple basics. All the
Speaker 6:  interesting stuff is like the interface and the last mile stuff. And so I
Speaker 6:  suspect that's what we'll see a lot of all over
Speaker 6:  iOS. But where
Speaker 4:  Is it gonna happen? Because if you're relying on GPT-4 oh to do some
Speaker 4:  aside, you have to go to the cloud, you probably have to go to Microsoft
Speaker 4:  servers, right? 'cause most of that runs in Azure.
Speaker 6:  Azure if you want the full model. Yeah. I also, I, I don't, I don't pretend
Speaker 6:  to have a ton of knowledge, but I'm, I'm confident that OpenAI is working
Speaker 6:  on smaller versions of, its stuff that works on device and
Speaker 6:  locally and all that stuff. But I think if you look at something like
Speaker 6:  what's a good example, voice transcription. We were just talking about why
Speaker 6:  on earth if you're Apple, would you try to rebuild Whisper when Whisper
Speaker 6:  is really good And OpenAI made it already. Whispers may be a
Speaker 6:  bad example 'cause it's actually open source and Apple could just take it.
Speaker 6:  But that's the sort of thing that's like OpenAI is sitting on a lot of very
Speaker 6:  good technology that is not being made into very good products.
Speaker 6:  And I think if I'm Apple, what I'm doing is looking at them and saying, I
Speaker 6:  know how to make products. I'm just gonna take your sort of
Speaker 6:  base level infrastructure technology and build on top of it. I do think
Speaker 6:  the what's going to happen on device versus what's gonna happen in the cloud
Speaker 6:  thing is gonna be messy for Apple at first and
Speaker 6:  has been messy with Siri over the years, right? Like for a long time, one
Speaker 6:  of the things that sucked about Siri was that it went to the cloud for basically
Speaker 6:  everything. And progressively over time, Siri has gotten to do more stuff
Speaker 6:  locally and has gotten better and faster as a result. And so I think we're
Speaker 6:  gonna see a lot of that sort of calibration of that sliding scale again from
Speaker 6:  Apple here.
Speaker 4:  But if they get to the point where they're sending what's happening on your
Speaker 4:  device to a cloud server,
Speaker 4:  especially one that Apple doesn't own, that's a, that is Apple
Speaker 4:  walking away from someone's privacy promises. They
Speaker 6:  Made a Google deal, dude. Like this is what happens.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I was like,
Speaker 4:  But I'm, if they do the, where you're like, play spot Discover weekly in
Speaker 4:  GPT-4 and an Azure server is looking at your screen and then locally
Speaker 4:  it's something else. Like no. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Like, I there's a level that there's a line that I don't think Apple will
Speaker 4:  cross.
Speaker 5:  I I think, I think we, we don't know the term, the full terms of the
Speaker 5:  open AI partnership, right? And Apple would be very, very, very, very,
Speaker 5:  very stupid to throw away that, that like privacy marketing
Speaker 5:  that they have. So I could totally see them be like, yeah, we're gonna, we
Speaker 5:  have open ai but we're gonna use it on our servers and it'll go through our
Speaker 5:  stuff and it's all gonna be through your iCloud and, and all of that stuff.
Speaker 6:  I think that's probably what it's, I think, I think this is going to be less
Speaker 6:  like we wanna run this stuff on the back of open AI's
Speaker 6:  server infrastructure, which is literally, as you said, Azure and more like,
Speaker 6:  we're going to take some of their technology and we're gonna run it on our
Speaker 6:  servers and it's just gonna be like a white label licensing deal. And
Speaker 5:  We've, we've heard rumors about Apple having like building their own
Speaker 5:  processors and stuff.
Speaker 4:  No, they're, they're putting M two ultras. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's it In Iraq. Yeah. And that's what it's for.
Speaker 4:  How many tops on M two Ultra?
Speaker 6:  Some,
Speaker 4:  Some, some to very, I mean, look, if, if there's, if there's one company
Speaker 4:  like you said David, that can say like, this is what all the headroom on
Speaker 4:  the phone is for
Speaker 5:  31.6 tops.
Speaker 6:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 4:  That's an amount of tops.
Speaker 5:  That's, that is more than a raspberry pie. If
Speaker 6:  You two and a half raspberry pies right there.
Speaker 4:  That's brutal. If you can tell us what incremental
Speaker 4:  tops are for, please leave us a note. But you can't be an AI
Speaker 4:  researcher. Like if you are building a consumer application where you're
Speaker 4:  like, oh man, when phones have at least 27
Speaker 4:  tops, like the world will like you let us know.
Speaker 4:  I'm dying to know the answer to question
Speaker 5:  Is writing you as we speak to be like, we can put, we can map
Speaker 5:  weird stuff to your face so well with more tops.
Speaker 4:  But if Evan Spiegel is like up at night because the average phone has 20
Speaker 4:  tops and he needs 27 like you, that's what I'm looking for. Evan
Speaker 4:  I.
Speaker 5:  Love it. This is such a good conversation for the beginning of Pride I. love
Speaker 5:  it so much.
Speaker 4:  My god. Alex,
Speaker 5:  I just had to
Speaker 4:  Say what's randomly horny or Alex? Cranz Renee.
Speaker 4:  Only
Speaker 5:  A top six. We'll find out that that's gonna be a ba a head to head on a later
Speaker 5:  VERGE cast.
Speaker 4:  Alright, what do we think is like the big thing that we're looking for from
Speaker 4:  WAC? Let's, let's, let's wrap it up this way. What, what's yours
Speaker 4:  like wishlist style? Ooh,
Speaker 5:  I don't even know because I like, as, as, as David well
Speaker 5:  knows, I started using Arc. Oh my God. And so now that's all I care about
Speaker 5:  on my Mac. So like, I'm like, yeah, I just want
Speaker 5:  it to like look nice. I want better control over my, the
Speaker 5:  appearance of my device. I would love if the AI would just, I'd be able to
Speaker 5:  be like, I want it to be like cool cyberpunk green. And it would just be
Speaker 5:  like, got you.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That's my wishlist.
Speaker 4:  Did a cyberpunk green.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I want, I want, I want Mac OS and Siri to make my
Speaker 5:  computer look as ugly as possible.
Speaker 4:  AI powered theming is an incredible, I'm not, I I don't think
Speaker 4:  it's Apple.
Speaker 5:  Give it to you. That was a Samsung. Yeah. Saturday day. There
Speaker 6:  Has been some reporting that Apple is going to like, really open up the
Speaker 6:  possibilities for what you can do with your home screen. Like they're going
Speaker 6:  to let you put app icons wherever you want, which like, oh my God, what
Speaker 6:  a, how did no one think of this before? It's unbelievable. Incredible.
Speaker 6:  But like, maybe we're not that far away from you just being
Speaker 6:  able to tell Siri like, just uug up my phone. It's no big deal and it'll
Speaker 6:  just happen. Yes, that'd
Speaker 5:  Be amazing. That's what I want. That's
Speaker 6:  The dream.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's Alex's David.
Speaker 6:  All of my stuff is Spotlight, which I would very much
Speaker 6:  like to, that's where I want all the AI stuff to go. I think
Speaker 6:  the like little AI features, voice transcription, all that stuff is gonna
Speaker 6:  be very cool for me. It's like if it can get very good at me
Speaker 6:  just being like, what was that picture of the sign
Speaker 6:  that I took a few days ago? And it'll just be like this one or like the,
Speaker 6:  the thing in Google Photos where you can just ask it about things in your
Speaker 6:  photos. Like, I want that locally on my phone. And also with access
Speaker 6:  to all of my stuff, right? Like Spotlight knows everything. It sees the
Speaker 6:  internet, it has all the stuff on your device. Oh man, it, there's been some
Speaker 6:  reporting I think from Mark Garman at Bloomberg that it's gonna be able to
Speaker 6:  do more stuff inside of files and with documents. And I just wanna be like,
Speaker 6:  I wanna just live my life inside of that spotlight search and just have it
Speaker 6:  understand everything on my phone all the time. Like that's, that
Speaker 5:  Would be cool too.
Speaker 6:  That's DAI job here as far as I
Speaker 4:  You want rewind
Speaker 6:  Basically, but, and it's just sitting here. This no reason. You're one, one
Speaker 4:  Of the people who's like, just do all
Speaker 6:  He already does Neli. It's already like, do you know what? Already knows
Speaker 6:  everything that's happening on my phone is my phone. Like,
Speaker 6:  just do it for me. And again, like I think the, the interesting
Speaker 6:  thing about the recall thing is that it's like the
Speaker 6:  worry is that somebody can get all the stuff on your device, right?
Speaker 6:  Malware exists on Windows that just lets somebody look at that plain text
Speaker 6:  database that is sitting on your device way less of a threat on the iPhone.
Speaker 6:  And so for me, like all my stuff is already here and if
Speaker 6:  you get my phone and my passcode, I'm screwed already. So I'm like,
Speaker 6:  let's at least make use of the fact that this device essentially contains
Speaker 6:  every piece of my life in existence and make it useful to me because I can't
Speaker 6:  help what it already is.
Speaker 5:  I love this because I have like a whole reservoir of horrible photos
Speaker 5:  and gifs and it would be real God, God, it would rule to just be like, Hey
Speaker 5:  Siri
Speaker 4:  Again, if Apple's red team is available, Alex
Speaker 5:  Got
Speaker 4:  You to Alex. Cranz is also also
Speaker 6:  Available. If I could just be like, like that. If I could just be like, where's
Speaker 6:  the Wilmer Valda Ramma gift where he does the I love you with his hands and
Speaker 6:  it just shows it to me like that's what I want. That's the dream. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's that. I I love this dream. Okay. I'm on board. I, I switched
Speaker 5:  mine to Davids,
Speaker 6:  But also I wanna make my phone ugly with one command. Yes. I I'm with Alex
Speaker 6:  too. Neli, what's your like Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I feel like the, the Hey don't share wilder wil
Speaker 4:  derra gifts anymore. Warning is something that you need from an AI
Speaker 4:  system in this context. Like, hey, you're a little outta date. There's been
Speaker 4:  some news
Speaker 4:  just helping you out there bud. Okay. Mine is very small.
Speaker 4:  It's not really a wishlist of a feature. Okay. I am
Speaker 4:  dying to see how Apple addresses adding RCS to messages. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  Is it an announcement? Is it a Bento box slide? Is it the world's smallest
Speaker 4:  type? Is it just cred, FII being like, we've added the letters
Speaker 4:  and just like moving on. Like it could go a million different
Speaker 4:  ways.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be bento, it
Speaker 4:  Could be a full thing. Like we've now added support for the standard
Speaker 4:  that everyone's been making for Right?
Speaker 5:  I figured it out. They're gonna talk about the emoji emojis are that they
Speaker 5:  can make with AI and then be like, and you can even send them to your friend
Speaker 5:  on Android because we've introduced R Cs. Right?
Speaker 4:  So a a any number of ways Will the, will they show green bubbles on that
Speaker 4:  stage?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Anything could happen.
Speaker 5:  Oh, it's
Speaker 4:  Gonna rule. And I'm just like, that's the thing that I'm, or or they could
Speaker 4:  do nothing.
Speaker 6:  I love this Alex, because like, do you remember a million years ago
Speaker 6:  when Paul Pierce sent that tweet where he tried to send an emoji but he actually
Speaker 6:  sent a picture like a jpeg of the rocketship emoji. That's what
Speaker 6:  it's gonna look like when you make a custom emoji on an iPhone and send it
Speaker 6:  to an Android person. And that is how Apple gets to support
Speaker 6:  RCS and still kind of knife all the Android users all at the same time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's good. These new features are for, for message users. Messages users.
Speaker 4:  And for Android users you get
Speaker 6:  Jpeg
Speaker 5:  You get a jpeg
Speaker 6:  I love it.
Speaker 4:  Like I've just, anything can happen like literally
Speaker 4:  anything from that like open cutting warfare
Speaker 4:  all the way down to, we've put three letters in like the tiniest box
Speaker 4:  of the other features in iOS. You know,
Speaker 6:  They might not even call it RCS like Right? Yeah. Just
Speaker 4:  Like rich messaging.
Speaker 6:  What did they call it on the Apple Home app? Like new architecture.
Speaker 6:  Maybe they'll just call it new architecture
Speaker 5:  Rich complex mess messaging. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So whatever, they'll just, they'll just literally anything is possible.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like, I cannot wait 'cause they've announced they're gonna do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And this is when they roll out the new operating systems. This is when
Speaker 4:  they might do it.
Speaker 5:  They just don't say anything.
Speaker 4:  I'm on pins and needles.
Speaker 6:  It is really interesting, by the way, how little we've heard about
Speaker 6:  non-AI stuff coming this year. Like Yeah, the
Speaker 6:  non-AI reporting so far is basically like new settings, menu
Speaker 6:  and some more native apps for the Vision Pro and all that stuff is well
Speaker 6:  and good, but there is surprisingly little,
Speaker 6:  at least from what we've heard so far, that is not going to be about ai.
Speaker 6:  And I think both for just how the presentation goes, but also what these
Speaker 6:  things are, it's gonna be really interesting to see if basically whatever,
Speaker 6:  12 months ago Craig Federighi was like, we only do AI
Speaker 6:  from now on. Or not like, it's just, it's,
Speaker 6:  I, that's the thing I'm gonna be watching the most for is like how much non-AI
Speaker 6:  stuff is there, which I think is very telling for how much Apple is gonna
Speaker 6:  feel like it has to do with ai.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm telling you it's gonna be RCS. All right, we gotta wrap this up.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna be at wwe C
Speaker 5:  He's so sad.
Speaker 11:  What? I was gonna get in there and
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. Wait. Liam's got one. Okay. All right. Liam, we we, bonus round.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 11:  This one has technically been announced already, but the thing I'm most
Speaker 11:  excited to try next week is the motion sickness feature.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 11:  I'm one of those people that like, when I'm in an Uber, I can't read my
Speaker 11:  phone for more than a few seconds 'cause I get horrible motion sickness.
Speaker 11:  Me too. So I really wanna try this if it's in beta and hopefully it works.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're gonna get Liam in a car just zooming around. I'll,
Speaker 5:  I'll drive.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 6:  Is the first that we should do. Liam and I are gonna get in the back. We're
Speaker 6:  gonna both look at our phones and we're gonna see who Pukes first. And that's,
Speaker 6:  that's
Speaker 4:  The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast. I'm just gonna be doing figure eights in a parking
Speaker 4:  Lot. That's also sponsorable. You considering
Speaker 6:  Bal
Speaker 4:  Who boots first.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's it. We're gonna be there next week. Sick house
Speaker 4:  again. I, I've been told there will be tacos. I'm not a hundred percent sure
Speaker 4:  how we're gonna work the tacos in the show. A lot of
Speaker 5:  Horses are gonna be
Speaker 5:  so
Speaker 4:  Right. But you're still just like, I'm gonna like HBO or Max, I'm sorry,
Speaker 4:  yeah. Is now just full of a bunch of weird discovery reality shows. Like
Speaker 4:  that's, that's the value for dollar there. Yeah. Is like, you wanna watch
Speaker 4:  House Hunters here, here it is. And that stuff is still super
Speaker 4:  available on a cable package. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And, and the cable package is probably gonna be a nicer
Speaker 5:  experience where it'll be easier to find the episode you wanna watch and
Speaker 5:  get started because the, the Max UI is still
Speaker 5:  hot, hot garbage.
Speaker 4:  So my max is still paid for because as you know, at
Speaker 4:  t it's a child at t bought. Because that's not why that would be incredible.
Speaker 4:  If everyone named Max got free Max, that would actually be great. Feels great.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It would justify the bad name. No, as you are aware,
Speaker 4:  at t bought Warner Brothers.
Speaker 5:  I I did know that. Yes.
Speaker 4:  A deal which led only to the release of the four three Snyder cut.
Speaker 4:  Sorry. But also a bunch of grandfathered plans. Yeah. And I have
Speaker 4:  one that is the same money as a new at t plan. It just
Speaker 4:  includes
Speaker 5:  Max,
Speaker 4:  But in 10 80 p
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's brutal.
Speaker 4:  And so I'm just like stuck with free 10 80 P max. Nope. Until
Speaker 4:  someone will notice this at at and t, which they never will.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They just want, they're just not gonna notice. Then
Speaker 5:  They're like, you enjoy 10 80.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, they're gonna be like a grandfather at at and t plan. You're not
Speaker 4:  churning You may have it forever. Yeah. Until you get a, until they get to
Speaker 4:  six G, that's when they churn you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you're done
Speaker 4:  Then. But I'm stuck with this horrible plan. I'm sorry, David. Are you, are
Speaker 4:  you paying 21 bucks a month
Speaker 6:  For No, I'm switching to ads over and over again. And it's just really,
Speaker 6:  it's just fine.
Speaker 6:  And the thing that I have realized increasingly is
Speaker 6:  that the idea that people are churning is less real than people
Speaker 6:  think. And I think these services are stickier than people give them credit
Speaker 6:  for. Like I was, I was reading something the other day about how one of
Speaker 6:  the big reasons these companies get sports is that people sign up to watch
Speaker 6:  one game and then like an overwhelmingly large percentage of those people
Speaker 6:  keep the service. Like it's actually the, this idea that people are coming,
Speaker 6:  watching the thing and then canceling until that thing comes back a year
Speaker 6:  later is largely not the behavior. And
Speaker 6:  as a result, once you're in, you're kind of
Speaker 6:  in, and I think these companies have figured out that a dollar at a time
Speaker 6:  is not terrifying. Like, I think if if Max suddenly went up $10
Speaker 6:  a month, people would freak out and leave. Right? Like I think I've been
Speaker 6:  watching Evernote for this. I dunno why this just came into my head, but
Speaker 6:  I've been watching Evernote over the last couple years. They basically just
Speaker 6:  doubled their subscription price. And we're very honestly like, this is the
Speaker 6:  only way. This is a sustainable business. Here we go. And people freaked
Speaker 6:  out. That's how you churn people. But a
Speaker 6:  dollar a month at a time, just there doesn't seem to be a lot
Speaker 6:  of evidence that that costs them anything and it gets them more money.
Speaker 6:  And also what they want is either for you to pay $50 a
Speaker 6:  month or get ads and they will, they will keep raising the price
Speaker 6:  until those are the only two options left. I really believe that.
Speaker 5:  I I, I totally agree with you. I mean, it's, it's just the frog and the,
Speaker 5:  the boiling pot, right? Like it's the water that
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm stuck with an at t plan. Turning up.
Speaker 5:  You're you're stuck with 10 p turning forever.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry.
Speaker 4:  Ah, all right. David, what's yours? Mine
Speaker 6:  Is maybe the wonkiest thing I've picked on
Speaker 6:  The Vergecast in a while. Google bought this company called Cameo
Speaker 6:  with a y not the cameo, where you can get famous people to like tell you
Speaker 6:  you're terrific. It's a, it's a company that does Windows app
Speaker 6:  virtualization on CMOs. And I
Speaker 6:  thought this was very funny because this happened this week after I had a
Speaker 6:  very like related cameo experience. My wife is in grad school
Speaker 6:  and she's taking like a statistics class right now. And
Speaker 6:  she had to download this unbelievably like
Speaker 6:  esoteric old app called our Studio. I
Speaker 6:  think that looks like it has not been updated since 1994.
Speaker 6:  Runs on Windows, Linux and Mac and not Chrome os. And she has a
Speaker 6:  Chromebook for her like personal use. And so
Speaker 6:  she spent, I would say the better part of a day trying to install
Speaker 6:  Linux on her Chromebook in order to do this. And was
Speaker 6:  she got like most of the way down, I was actually very impressed with how
Speaker 6:  far down the, like running a Linux distro on a Chromebook she got
Speaker 6:  and then eventually just gave up and was like, it's not worth it. Do a Windows
Speaker 6:  computer I can use. But the thing that we found was like, oh, the best answer
Speaker 6:  to this is this app called Cameo, which just lets you run Windows apps on
Speaker 6:  your Chromebook, but it's prohibitively expensive and like explicitly not
Speaker 6:  designed for just like regular people. But now as part of Google, I think
Speaker 6:  this is super interesting. It gives Google like a new inroad into businesses
Speaker 6:  with Chromebooks where it has traditionally had trouble. It gives
Speaker 6:  Chromebooks a lot more to do because if this works well, you could
Speaker 6:  start to just do more window stuff inside of Chromebooks. There's a lot left
Speaker 6:  to shake out here. This acquisition like just happened. But I actually think
Speaker 6:  it's super interesting and as like the one person on earth who still really,
Speaker 6:  really, really, really wants Chromebooks to be cool and succeed. This makes
Speaker 6:  me happy. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The the, the best thing I've ever bought for my mom is a Chromebook.
Speaker 5:  Really?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Because a regular computer or regular macro or Windows PC is like
Speaker 4:  55 different operating system metaphors all at once.
Speaker 4:  You're like, this is called Launchpad. Why? And you get a Chromebook, you're
Speaker 4:  like, use this browser. And they just use it and it's like, fine.
Speaker 5:  Does your mom know what, when you say
Speaker 4:  I wrote whole article about it ages ago,
Speaker 5:  Does she know like what the box is to where to type things in?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's just a browser. It's like, this is Chrome. You like Chrome, right?
Speaker 4:  Okay. Go to YouTube. Your mom is so much
Speaker 5:  More advanced than my mom.
Speaker 4:  But like now what I worry about with Chromes to say added Android apps, now
Speaker 4:  they're adding Cameo. They're getting the same place where you're like, oh,
Speaker 4:  there's multiple competing application metaphors at once. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But I still love a Chromebook. Oh, and Chromebook pluses
Speaker 4:  now have all the man. Yeah. It's like I just want a brow man.
Speaker 4:  That
Speaker 5:  Pixel book was such a good,
Speaker 6:  It was very fun watching everybody argue in our comments about sort of
Speaker 6:  the, the overall Chromebook thesis. And like, one of the things obviously
Speaker 6:  Chromebooks have done is they've been hugely successful in schools.
Speaker 6:  And there were a lot of people in our comments who were like, yeah, I had
Speaker 6:  a Chromebook in high school and it ensured that I will never ever buy myself
Speaker 6:  a Chromebook because it was a piece of junk. And it was like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  maybe at some point Google and others should have invested in making Chromebooks
Speaker 6:  good. And then people would want them. Like what a crazy idea that would
Speaker 6:  be. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They should put Arc on it.
Speaker 4:  I had a Chrome, I bought my mom a Chromebook Pixel, a thousand dollars Chrome
Speaker 4:  laptop. People thought I was nuts. It's still rocking. Yeah. 'cause it has
Speaker 4:  like 16 gigs of rain
Speaker 6:  Runs. Yeah. That had 10 times the power it needed.
Speaker 5:  It was such a good
Speaker 4:  Laptop, like an I seven. It was amazing. Still going 'cause it just runs
Speaker 4:  rules. Alright, mine is last minute game time
Speaker 4:  decision. We just put this story up. The chair
Speaker 4:  of the Tesla board is warning shareholders today
Speaker 4:  that if they don't approve Elon's $56 billion pay package,
Speaker 4:  he might leave Tesla. Oh no,
Speaker 4:  Alex.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's
Speaker 4:  Terrible. Elon is not a typical executive and Tesla's not
Speaker 4:  a typical company. He says in the letter, which was filed to the SEC. So
Speaker 4:  the typical way in which companies compensate key executives will not drive
Speaker 4:  results for Tesla motivating someone like Elon requires something different.
Speaker 4:  He says,
Speaker 6:  To be fair, I would also be very motivated by $56 billion.
Speaker 6:  Like, I dunno that that's different. That's the same
Speaker 4:  Somehow he says, and it's not about the money, it's like
Speaker 4:  following up. You gotta motivate Elon somehow. And then it's not about the
Speaker 4:  money when the letter is about approve the pay package. Didn't
Speaker 5:  He just like
Speaker 4:  Threaten the needle there buddy? Didn't
Speaker 5:  He just screw over Tesla by having a bunch of like
Speaker 5:  H one hundreds from Nvidia shipped?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. He sent them to X instead. X instead. This Matt Levine at Bloomberg
Speaker 6:  made what I thought was a very good point about this, which is that what
Speaker 6:  this, the, the initial read on that is like, oh, this is a
Speaker 6:  sign that Elon Musk is not paying attention to Tesla. Why would you give
Speaker 6:  him the money? The the Galaxy brain take is, oh, this
Speaker 6:  is a threat that if you don't give Elon Musk his money, he will stop paying
Speaker 6:  attention to Tesla. And this is what will happen. Yeah. And I think that
Speaker 6:  is a fun, like war games
Speaker 6:  version of this story that is just gonna keep getting worse. He's obviously
Speaker 6:  gonna get the money right? Like, oh
Speaker 4:  No, you don't think so? No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. I think he's gonna
Speaker 4:  get the money. No, this vote doesn't even guarantee that he gets money. You
Speaker 4:  could win this vote and still not get the money.
Speaker 6:  Okay, that's fair. I think he'll win the vote.
Speaker 4:  Maybe. I think I, I think they're worried. I don't think that Chairman of
Speaker 4:  your boards since the letter about how you have to motivate
Speaker 4:  Elon, which by the way is hilarious. That's a letter you send about like
Speaker 4:  a, like me in eighth grade. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Do you think $56 billion would've done it for you?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I don't know. I was not a typical eighth grader and
Speaker 4:  I did not respond to typical motivations.
Speaker 4:  Right. We have to challenge him. We gotta keep him involved. Otherwise
Speaker 4:  he's gonna light yet another classroom on fire. Like
Speaker 4:  I just, that's a crazy letter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it really is.
Speaker 5:  That's too much.
Speaker 4:  And I will point out, Chancery Daily has been in great work on this if you've
Speaker 4:  follow that. They've followed a lot of the Tesla and Twitter back and forth.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like the court in Delaware said this pay package was illegal.
Speaker 4:  Like this vote doesn't cure the problem.
Speaker 4:  Actually it's, it's like a weird dance. Who knows,
Speaker 4:  man. I just think he,
Speaker 4:  the need, the thing that caught my eye here is all this preamble
Speaker 4:  about how it takes something special to motivate Elon.
Speaker 4:  It's not money. And then it's like, and also vote for the money. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  very good. All right, we're gonna wwc, we gotta get outta
Speaker 4:  here. That vote by the way is June 13th where Andy and Liz are primed
Speaker 4:  to Co, as you can imagine, primed to cover it. It's gonna be, I think
Speaker 4:  it's gonna be wild. I think the future of Tesla and X and
Speaker 4:  SpaceX kind of all tied up in this one little very odd
Speaker 4:  moment. Yeah. So they'll be covering that next week while we are headed back
Speaker 4:  from dub dub. I think there's gonna be a lot of stuff to cover outta
Speaker 4:  dub dub. I was saying this to our team today. People have a lot of feelings
Speaker 4:  about ai. Yeah. And Apple putting AI all over its operating system.
Speaker 4:  If you just look at the response to that ad that Alex mentioned before, that
Speaker 4:  Crush ad, that crush ad, that ad was not about ai. That was just about
Speaker 4:  iPads. Yeah. You actually do the thing where the photo
Speaker 4:  editing gets easier or the copy is easier to write. I think people,
Speaker 4:  apple has a lot of creatives who care a lot about this company. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be a weird time next week I think. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I would agree.
Speaker 4:  So all that covered, that's why The Verge exists. Why do we exist? That's
Speaker 4:  why to figure out why we make art with computers. And the answer
Speaker 4:  according to all trans, is to do weird horny stuff. Yeah. That's it. That's
Speaker 4:  The Verge cast rock and roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 8:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is the
Speaker 8:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 8:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.