# Transcript
ID: bcb60977-d8c1-487b-810b-ccfc202f30e4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4867592338036987258/-5935121345743156612/s93290-US-6948s-1729248121.mp3
Description: Nilay and David talk about the week in gadget news, after scoring their predictions on last week's Tesla event. (Spoiler alert: nobody did very well.) They talk about the new iPad Mini, the new Sonos Ace Ultra soundbar, and the new Analogue N64 emulator. Then Amazon's Panos Panay joins the show to discuss this week's big Kindle news, and where he thinks the future of e-readers is headed. Finally, Nilay and David do a lightning round, with a lot of Google org chart news and just a little bit of Trump news.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast of knowing that you
Speaker 3:  should just always take the over on Tesla ship dates.
Speaker 3:  I'm not a betting person. That's not a thing that I do. I spend my money
Speaker 3:  in Vegas in limousines. Famous, famous personality trait of mine.
Speaker 3:  But if FanDuel ever offers bet on Tesla ship dates, I might get into it.
Speaker 3:  I'm the, I'm just putting it out there.
Speaker 4:  Listen, if I've learned one thing about the internet, it's that you can bet
Speaker 4:  on anything somewhere on poly market. You can bet on Elon Musk and the
Speaker 4:  cyber cab. I'm confident.
Speaker 3:  Do you think he's just taking the other side of that bet that that's his
Speaker 3:  plan to fund Twitter?
Speaker 4:  He just gets it coming and going, man.
Speaker 3:  Hi, I'm your friend Eli. That's David Pierce. Hey David. Hello. We've got
Speaker 3:  a good episode. We're gonna go over our bets from last week on the
Speaker 3:  Robo Taxii announcement. Apple announce New iPad
Speaker 3:  minis. There's some weird intel news to talk about.
Speaker 3:  There's a really cute Nintendo 64 emulator that I want to get into.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But also Amazon's Panos pane is on the show this week. There was
Speaker 3:  a Kindle event. David went to it, Panos came to the studio. We hung
Speaker 3:  out with him for a while. We tried to get him to say, what's going on for
Speaker 3:  Alexa? He declined and then we got a lightning round. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be amazing. It's the, it's The Vergecast. It's a, it's a good one. Let's
Speaker 3:  start, David, with our bets. So we
Speaker 3:  ran the gimmick last week where we were recording the show before Tesla's
Speaker 3:  robot taxi event and you and I made a bunch of predictions
Speaker 3:  and now we can see if we were correct.
Speaker 4:  You know what's weird is going back through and we'll, we'll, we'll go through
Speaker 4:  it, but I have two regrets that I would like to share. Yeah. Before
Speaker 4:  we get into it, one of my regrets is that I didn't push
Speaker 4:  harder on the, I think this is a thing you're gonna be able to buy. We talked
Speaker 4:  about it briefly and I asked like, wait, do you think that this roboto taxi,
Speaker 4:  they're about to launch is gonna be a thing you can buy? And you were just
Speaker 4:  like, absolutely not. That would be insane. Whoops, here we are.
Speaker 4:  That was not one of your predictions. Carefully, not one of your predictions.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But it should have been one of mine that it was gonna be something
Speaker 4:  you can buy.
Speaker 3:  I actually still stand by my prediction.
Speaker 4:  I,
Speaker 3:  I want be clear.
Speaker 4:  I mean fair. The problem is we're gonna have to redo who
Speaker 4:  won these predictions like every three months for the next 10 years until
Speaker 4:  these things actually launch and then we'll see who wins. So let me, let
Speaker 4:  me just quickly like run through the news and then we can run through our
Speaker 4:  predictions. And the news I would say was basically two
Speaker 4:  things right there is there was the, the cyber cab and the robo van.
Speaker 4:  There was a bunch of other like, I'm
Speaker 3:  Sorry David, it's pronounced Ovn. You think I'm
Speaker 3:  joking? Wait, listen to Elon pronounce it. No, he
Speaker 3:  says Ovn.
Speaker 4:  It's the Ovn.
Speaker 3:  Yes. And I'm pretty sure that is yet another horrible westward
Speaker 3:  reference that sounds like at the event you could take the robo taxii
Speaker 3:  between two different spots on the map at Warner
Speaker 3:  Brothers on the lot. And one of them was like New York City and one of them
Speaker 3:  was Westworld and If. you stuck it out long enough
Speaker 3:  through Westworld. One of the villains is whatever, it doesn't
Speaker 3:  matter. He said Ovn
Speaker 4:  Ovn is just like the last name of a Midwestern door to door salesman who
Speaker 4:  is just like Thomas Ovn. How you doing?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Or or it's the all seeing AI in
Speaker 4:  Westworld. Yeah. Or it's that. Well, no, it is not
Speaker 4:  Ovn. I will not acknowledge that it is the robo van.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. It's like when, when Apple was like, no, it's not the iPhone X,
Speaker 4:  it's the iPhone 10. They were wrong. It's the iPhone X and it is the robo
Speaker 4:  van. Wow.
Speaker 3:  Bold.
Speaker 4:  So there was the robo van, the, the robo van named
Speaker 4:  Robo
Speaker 4:  Rob, Rob Boon,
Speaker 3:  Rob ovo. That's great. I'll take that
Speaker 4:  In Europe. It's the Rob of
Speaker 3:  VI just want, again, and I just wanna underline this. All of these things
Speaker 3:  are fake.
Speaker 4:  Yes. They
Speaker 3:  Van, most of all yes. Is not a thing that
Speaker 3:  will occur.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And one of the things that you said was there, there might be a whiff
Speaker 4:  of,
Speaker 4:  you know, the, the, the supposedly autonomous truck that's actually just
Speaker 4:  rolling downhill.
Speaker 4:  I would not say I'm absolved of all of the, maybe this is not real vibes
Speaker 4:  from this event. But anyway, so those were basically the two things right
Speaker 4:  there was the, the cyber cab was the thing. It has bat
Speaker 4:  wings. It's a two seater car. Looks neat.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. It is supposedly going to be available in 2027.
Speaker 4:  It's supposedly gonna cost less than $30,000. It's just a
Speaker 4:  bunch of words that he said out loud and a
Speaker 4:  prototype.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's not nothing like, I wanna be clear, I'm not being dismissive. It's not
Speaker 4:  nothing, but it's not something either.
Speaker 3:  So I just wanna acknowledge this from the start. Our conversation about this
Speaker 3:  is happening in the context of SpaceX catching
Speaker 3:  the Starship booster on
Speaker 4:  The launch tower, which is sick as hell.
Speaker 3:  Which is awesome. Yeah, it is true that sometimes the things
Speaker 3:  happen. Yeah. That is a, a true thing you can say about Elon Musk companies,
Speaker 3:  but mostly about one of them, the one that he doesn't
Speaker 3:  run. Elon Musk companies usually accomplish their goals
Speaker 3:  is a thing you can mostly say about the company that Gwen Shotwell
Speaker 3:  runs. That's it. That's that one. Yes. Tesla
Speaker 3:  on the other hand, has been promising a lot of things for a long time and
Speaker 3:  most of those things don't arrive. And I think it's possible to split them
Speaker 3:  up. I don't think you can say, well, he landed the rocket or caught the
Speaker 3:  rocket in this case. So he will ship the cyber cab in full
Speaker 3:  self-driving. I tho I those things are fundamen like
Speaker 3:  the most deeply unrelated things I can think
Speaker 4:  Of. Totally.
Speaker 3:  For example, Tesla has furious competition.
Speaker 3:  SpaceX does not. In fact, SpaceX's competition is so
Speaker 3:  shit that there are astronauts in space right now. Yeah. The
Speaker 4:  Moment. Yeah. And and including like the government has largely
Speaker 4:  just given SpaceX, everything like that is that is
Speaker 4:  that's a whole different thing. I'm
Speaker 3:  Just saying I just wanted, that's contextually I the people I know and
Speaker 3:  like to read and people I think highly of have
Speaker 3:  conflated these two accomplishments and I I'm just pulling them
Speaker 3:  apart
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. And I think that's it's useful in another way, which is
Speaker 4:  like we, we always overrate for better and for worse
Speaker 4:  the extent to which A CEO is a company. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  the, the, he doesn't deserve all the blame for the mess of Tesla stuff
Speaker 4:  over the years and he doesn't deserve all of the credit for what SpaceX is
Speaker 4:  doing. Neither of those things is true. I think, I think he probably deserves
Speaker 4:  more blame than credit generally speaking. But like all this is
Speaker 4:  to say, like I actually, I I have found it very useful over the years to
Speaker 4:  think of each of his companies as completely separate things run by separate
Speaker 4:  people. Like
Speaker 4:  X and Tesla increasingly are aligned in ways that are
Speaker 4:  strange and odd
Speaker 3:  And XAI it's the ones he runs and Gwen Shotwell, I, that's it.
Speaker 3:  I mean that's fair. Those are the companies
Speaker 4:  That is, that is fair.
Speaker 3:  They're the companies that Elon runs and then there's Gwen Shotwell who runs
Speaker 3:  Face X and she is by all accounts trusted and visionary and great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Okay. But I just wanna separate because the two achievements,
Speaker 3:  it well achievements, the one achievement and the one launch
Speaker 3:  happened in the same timeframe. Right. So everyone thinks one is evidence
Speaker 3:  to the other and, and they're not. And so the cyber cab, which
Speaker 3:  is fine, like people watch this event and in real time
Speaker 3:  they're like, this is fake. Yeah's a guy controlling the car.
Speaker 3:  I dunno if that's true or not. I do know that a a prototype
Speaker 3:  car running around the back lot of a movie set
Speaker 3:  is a thing that we've had for a long time. Yes. Like you can
Speaker 3:  go to Universal Studios today and drive around
Speaker 3:  in a car that appears to be driving itself.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A hundred and like a a a humanoid seeming robot
Speaker 4:  that's being controlled by somebody else far away. Also a thing we've had
Speaker 4:  for a long time. Yeah. Also a thing that they try to get people very excited
Speaker 4:  about at this event. This is the thing I'm so torn between
Speaker 4:  like where on the spectrum of nothing to something this actually is.
Speaker 4:  Because on the one hand, the whole idea of the cyber
Speaker 4:  cab strikes me as completely ridiculous. Like a, a a
Speaker 4:  two-seater car already
Speaker 4:  vastly decreases the number of people who can use it.
Speaker 4:  I saw somebody point out that like, oh great, you made a cab whose doors
Speaker 4:  can't open in city traffic, which is a really excellent point.
Speaker 4:  Like, this thing just doesn't make any real world sense, but neither does
Speaker 4:  the cyber truck and like that eventually shipped. So who knows.
Speaker 3:  Oh, I mean they also announced inductive charging, which doesn't exist for
Speaker 3:  a car of this size yet. Right. That's cool. I would love to have that. It's
Speaker 3:  just not real. And then the math, they didn't announce any of the
Speaker 3:  mathematics, right? Like how will this work? I buy one of these things for
Speaker 3:  $30,000, I put it on the Robax
Speaker 3:  network or the robot network.
Speaker 3:  That one doesn't work nearly as well. And then Tesla just takes
Speaker 3:  some money while this thing drives around picking up customer. Am I liable
Speaker 3:  if it crashes? Do I have to clean it up? If someone pucks in it is
Speaker 3:  that Tesla's responsibility? Who, what are the splits?
Speaker 3:  Like if I buy a cyber cap for $30,000 and put it on the
Speaker 3:  Robax network, how long in a moderately busy city
Speaker 3:  until that investment is paid off and I'm making a profit on it?
Speaker 3:  If, you don't have that chart. You actually haven't announced anything in
Speaker 3:  the context of this service. Totally.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  At least a projection of that chart.
Speaker 4:  Well, and that's all the stuff that is the
Speaker 4:  stuff of self-driving, right? Like, like you said, a a a
Speaker 4:  car that can drive you around a movie lot without appearing to have a
Speaker 4:  driver. It's actually like, it, it's a huge technical achievement that we
Speaker 4:  are actually not near in the real world, but it, that is only
Speaker 4:  one tiny slice of what is going on here. And Andy Hawkins wrote a great thing,
Speaker 4:  just basically like writing the list of things left to solve
Speaker 4:  both by this whole industry and by Tesla in particular. And I think
Speaker 4:  the belief from Elon Musk and Tesla has been
Speaker 4:  that they can just like brute force their way through it and it'll work and
Speaker 4:  it just hasn't and it won't. And So I think again, even if
Speaker 4:  you've solved the can this thing drive safely by itself on the road problem,
Speaker 4:  which we, we haven't, no one has. Even if you've solved that, you've only
Speaker 4:  solved one tiny slice of the what does it take to actually roll this out
Speaker 4:  in the world problem. And the cyber cab to me is just like
Speaker 4:  one sort of bad idea about what that car might
Speaker 4:  look like. Yeah. That's as far as I am, like willing to grant it.
Speaker 3:  So two things about that. The, the promise for a lot of model
Speaker 3:  three and model Y buyers over the years has been you'll pay the extra money
Speaker 3:  for a full self-driving hardware and then one day overnight these things
Speaker 3:  will turn into robo taxis and they will start making you money while you
Speaker 3:  sleep. This is an explicit promise that Elon Musk and
Speaker 3:  Tesla have made to these buyers, prospective buyers. This is something that
Speaker 3:  people have bought these cars as an investment spending money they maybe
Speaker 3:  didn't have waiting to pay off. It's not here yet.
Speaker 3:  What version of the car will actually get support for this
Speaker 3:  is contested. And when I say contested, I mean
Speaker 3:  while Elon was speaking, speaking, someone was screaming hardware three
Speaker 3:  support at him and his response was, let's not get too nuanced.
Speaker 3:  Right? And then later, I think it was Franz von
Speaker 3:  Hoen, the head of design at Tesla who's giving an interview who said Te Hardware
Speaker 3:  three would be supported. Hmm. What what's the answer? Like, it's
Speaker 3:  unclear. But if you're buying a cyber cab
Speaker 3:  and you're immediately competing with thousands if not
Speaker 3:  millions of existing model threes, you're in a weird spot.
Speaker 3:  Like why would you make that investment? Because then you're buying a less
Speaker 3:  practical car also, presumably Tesla's gonna run its own. Right.
Speaker 3:  So again, I just think the math doesn't add up and then
Speaker 3:  the, the basics of like what Tesla has promised people for a long time
Speaker 3:  still isn't there.
Speaker 4:  Well and there's this sense at all of those events that
Speaker 4:  Tesla is still the company that has infinite demand,
Speaker 4:  right? That anything they do, people will buy because it's Tesla because
Speaker 4:  it's exciting and because it's cool. And to me the reaction
Speaker 4:  to the event was very telling in the sense that I think
Speaker 4:  Tesla has lost a lot of that shine, partly because there's a lot
Speaker 4:  of competition and partly for like Elon Musk reasons, but also
Speaker 4:  people just don't believe Tesla anymore. Yeah. There was a
Speaker 4:  sense for so long that it was like, okay, don't believe the price, don't
Speaker 4:  believe the ship date, but like this thing is going to happen and it's going
Speaker 4:  to be awesome. And that is just not how people react to this anymore.
Speaker 4:  There is no benefit of the doubt that this is a good idea. I just don't see
Speaker 4:  it yet anymore. And Tesla had that going for it for so long
Speaker 4:  and it just feels gone. But anyway, the the taxi thing is a good segue to
Speaker 4:  our predictions. So yeah, let's just, let's just do the scoreboard here very
Speaker 4:  quickly. I think unfortunately it's gonna look very bad for me very quickly.
Speaker 4:  So let's just run through this very fast and then never speak of it again.
Speaker 4:  Your three predictions were won't arrive until 2027. Ding.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Nailed that one again. We'll see. But he said
Speaker 4:  20, 27 many times I should
Speaker 3:  Take only in certain, I should have said 2029
Speaker 4:  Only in certain cities. What what's our ruling on that? That it,
Speaker 4:  it, like again, this is one we'll we will see someday,
Speaker 4:  but the pitch was like you can buy one and just have it and everything will
Speaker 4:  be like, I kind of wanna give you a push on that because he didn't say it
Speaker 4:  is that he didn't say it won't be that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's, that's, that's a nothing. Okay. I feel very confident that
Speaker 3:  that will be true. Okay. That you can only like the seven in one city at
Speaker 3:  a time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, I I suspect you're right about that.
Speaker 3:  For example, you have to build your vaporware inductive chargers first.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 3:  So you, you have to invent them, which is an important step one you have
Speaker 3:  to make sure they work at scale, a very important step two. And then you
Speaker 3:  have to put them in in cities.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Wait, can you explain that one to me actually? 'cause the didn't Tesla
Speaker 4:  like do this once successfully already and now everyone is adopting the
Speaker 4:  standard that Tesla did and we're actually like headed towards a good place
Speaker 4:  where all of this might work successfully. Why
Speaker 4:  blow this up with a new way of charging things?
Speaker 3:  Oh, I thought you meant that they invented an inductive charging standard.
Speaker 3:  I was like that would be amazing. No, no, I meant
Speaker 4:  They did charging charge. Yeah. Like we have the max charger got that's like,
Speaker 4:  that is, that is the thing that is going to enable these charging systems
Speaker 4:  to work around the world on a, in a standard way. And then Tesla is just
Speaker 4:  like, nevermind, we're gonna try this other thing that definitely won't work.
Speaker 4:  Like why? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well I mean it makes sense in the, in the way that catching the
Speaker 3:  rocket makes sense. Like, you know what I mean? Like it's, it's an
Speaker 3:  absurd If you idea be sick idea. Like if I can pull up this off, it will
Speaker 3:  be sick.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Right.
Speaker 3:  So you've got taxis, you don't want too many moving parts around
Speaker 3:  the taxis,
Speaker 3:  so to charge them, you don't wanna roll up to a bay where a robot arm opens
Speaker 3:  the door and sticks the charger into it. You just want it to roll up and
Speaker 3:  start charging. Sure. So If, you make it work that there's inductive charging,
Speaker 3:  which has been demoed by a handful of companies and a handful
Speaker 3:  of controlled settings. Tesla I think at one point demoed like
Speaker 3:  motorized battery changing from the underside of the car. But
Speaker 3:  there's lots of ideas on how to make like battery charging
Speaker 3:  faster. Sure. Or simpler or smoother require less moving parts.
Speaker 3:  The problem is that Elon was also showing off mocks of like, what if we got
Speaker 3:  rid of all the parking lots around the stadiums and they were just parked
Speaker 3:  Right? And it's like, well all the robotaxis are gonna drop off the a hundred
Speaker 3:  thousand people at the stadium. Where are they gonna go to charge
Speaker 3:  on these? So you just want fields of
Speaker 3:  inductive charging pads. That seems like
Speaker 3:  weird, that's a weird thing to wanna put somewhere. Every
Speaker 4:  Time somebody shows one of those. I just think of the traffic
Speaker 4:  data from New York where Uber and Lyft were like, we'll get everybody off
Speaker 4:  the roads. And actually what it is now is there are just like 50%
Speaker 4:  more cars because it's just Uber and Lyft driving around waiting for somebody
Speaker 4:  to get in the car. Yeah. Like we, we actually made it worse.
Speaker 4:  And, and yeah. If we have a bunch of robot taxis, they gotta go somewhere.
Speaker 3:  I once tried to explain the concept of induced
Speaker 3:  demand to my family, which is, that's the concept
Speaker 3:  that If you make the highway wider, more people will take the highway.
Speaker 4:  You're so fun at parties. I bet. Well
Speaker 3:  'cause they were like, we should make the highway bigger. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  no. The thing called induced demand, like, boy did that not make sense
Speaker 3:  to anyone. And I feel like this trade off
Speaker 3:  of, we'll put a park near soldier field instead of a parking lot
Speaker 3:  and then we're gonna need to build a field of
Speaker 3:  like inductive charging pads for all the cyber cabs
Speaker 3:  to go to, to charge while everyone's That's I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  one city at a time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's your problem. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No, I think, I think that's right. So we'll, we'll give you a push on that,
Speaker 4:  but again, we're gonna have to rescore this so many times. And then
Speaker 4:  your third one was existing Teslas will not be able to
Speaker 4:  turn into Robotaxis and I think you're taking a loss on that one.
Speaker 3:  I think this one's also a pushed, 'cause we don't know about hardware three.
Speaker 3:  We don't know if it's only the very newest ones or if the hardware three,
Speaker 3:  which has the, I mean they all, they all have like low resolution cameras,
Speaker 3:  but we don't know which ones. So this is also just up in the air.
Speaker 4:  Mm. I'm gonna give you like a, like a light loss on that one. It's like I'm
Speaker 4:  I'm taking some of your money, but not all. Yeah. Like I'm not taking
Speaker 4:  all your money, but I'm, I'm not happy with you. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Usually want me to be a little bit embarrassed. I got Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Mine.
Speaker 3:  Lemme do yours. Yours are worse.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, please hit me. Mine are worse.
Speaker 3:  You predicted that the cars would be driven by optimist Robots.
Speaker 4:  It's a push If. you
Speaker 3:  Don't know
Speaker 4:  There's two seats in the car.
Speaker 3:  Well, you were not what you were, what you should have predicted is the optimist,
Speaker 3:  robots would be driven by people.
Speaker 4:  Well, so this is where my second one really hits,
Speaker 4:  which is they, they were gonna do a demo that didn't work and Yep. They,
Speaker 4:  they,
Speaker 3:  Well the demo worked in that the people controlling the
Speaker 3:  Optimus robots fooled some other people. That's
Speaker 4:  Fair.
Speaker 3:  And like a lot of people were like, Optimus is the future. And once again,
Speaker 3:  I'll point out that Honda had those robots like a decade ago
Speaker 3:  that could like jump and flip. Yeah. Boston Robotics. I
Speaker 3:  mean they will sell you a lethally armed robot dog today and they are
Speaker 3:  desperate for customers. They've been trying to sell themselves for a long
Speaker 3:  time. Yeah. I mean if you're in the market for a robot dog with a gun on
Speaker 3:  its tail, make the call, you know, you never know what's gonna, the least
Speaker 3:  deals are out of control and then,
Speaker 3:  you know, Chuck E. Cheese exists.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean truly one of the funniest things about this whole event to me
Speaker 4:  was all the people like taking the videos and stuff of the robots being like,
Speaker 4:  whoa, this is so cool. And my reaction to all of these videos, which are
Speaker 4:  very impressive, like these robots are holding conversations, they're doing
Speaker 4:  really complicated gestures and motions, like all kinds of really
Speaker 4:  impressive stuff. One's like, I think running around doing card tricks or
Speaker 4:  something. If the robots were that good, there would be no
Speaker 4:  other story. Yeah. Like it would, that would've been the event. They
Speaker 4:  would've been like, oh my God, we fixed robots. Like we, we did it.
Speaker 3:  Wait, I need to correct myself. Boston Dynamics was purchased, they did complete
Speaker 3:  the purchase in 2021. Hyundai Motor Group bought Boston
Speaker 3:  Dynamics. So that means Hyundai and Kia have a more
Speaker 3:  advanced optimist than, than Tesla.
Speaker 4:  That also makes me, there's a Hyundai dealership literally down the street
Speaker 4:  from me that I would say four years ago was like
Speaker 4:  kind of dingy and gross. And they have now expanded to its two full blocks
Speaker 4:  long in our town and I now assume one of those is for
Speaker 4:  robot talk with guns. And Yeah. I fear for my life in this neighborhood now
Speaker 3:  The headline and I triple E Spectrum, which is a great magazine. Hyundai
Speaker 3:  buys Boston Dynamics for nearly $1 billion Now what, which is very
Speaker 3:  good.
Speaker 4:  Sounds about right.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, the, the robots was just like, if it had been even remotely
Speaker 4:  close to as good as those robots appeared and they were actually automated
Speaker 4:  and ai, that would've been the most incredible tech demo in
Speaker 4:  ever.
Speaker 3:  So I
Speaker 4:  Was like, no, of course there are people on the other side of this. Like
Speaker 4:  I think where it netted out was they were walking automatically. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  everything else was, was human assisted, which
Speaker 3:  Again, Honda pulled off a decade ago. Right. And also you can just roll
Speaker 3:  up to a Boston Dynamics robot and kick it and it's like, that's fine. I
Speaker 3:  I won't fall down. And no one was touching the Yeah, I I get
Speaker 3:  it. You you want optimists to exist. You want to prove that it's great. And
Speaker 3:  the videos I saw, I think Marque posted one, I saw a few others
Speaker 3:  where they were just talking to the optimist robots and they were just
Speaker 3:  talking back. They're like, are you an ai? And he is like, yo dude, I don't
Speaker 3:  know. It's like, that's a guy. Yeah. You ever
Speaker 3:  talked to Chad? Me? That's just a guy.
Speaker 3:  All right. And then your last prediction. So that's two L's.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Off drivers. That won't
Speaker 4:  Work. I'll take it. I should've, I should have gone with It's a thing you
Speaker 4:  can buy. I really should. I was, I was sitting there being like, this is
Speaker 4:  a thing you can buy. But then I was like, that doesn't make any sense that
Speaker 4:  it would be, and I should have stuck to my guns.
Speaker 3:  All right. And then you, you, you existing Teslas are taxis.
Speaker 3:  We basically, we took the opposite side of the bet. Yeah. And I think it's
Speaker 3:  a, it's a light l for both of us.
Speaker 4:  No, it's a light dub for me. It's a light L for you. Let's be, let's be honest
Speaker 4:  here. So it's
Speaker 3:  Some existing Teslas, but maybe not most of it. It's
Speaker 4:  Like, you know, we're like going into halftime and the score is tied, but
Speaker 4:  like, I'm playing much better than you. You know what I mean? Like that's
Speaker 4:  where we are. I have all the momentum, but the score is tied. That's what's
Speaker 4:  going on right now.
Speaker 3:  You're an optimist robot just shuffling your way towards the bar.
Speaker 4:  Exactly.
Speaker 3:  Fair. I'll, I'll, I'll I'll give it to you just because you know,
Speaker 3:  I want you to hit the heights. So the crash is that much sweeter for me
Speaker 3:  playing the long game here.
Speaker 4:  It's kind of you.
Speaker 3:  So that's the, that's the Robo Taxii event. Oh by the way, I need to, I just
Speaker 3:  need to say this about the robo van one more time.
Speaker 4:  Sorry, what? The the what? The robo
Speaker 3:  Van, he showed a picture of it. They showed some mocks of the
Speaker 3:  interior. Of all of the things. This
Speaker 3:  is the one that will not arrive. Which totally agree. The, the way
Speaker 3:  that it looks and operates and works, it's just not gonna
Speaker 3:  happen that way.
Speaker 4:  I mean we, we've seen basically this
Speaker 4:  idea in roughly this design a
Speaker 4:  billion times over the years. Yep. Like in, in so many ways. Nothing about
Speaker 4:  this concept is new at all.
Speaker 3:  That's where my confidence comes from.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  When they do, when, when, when Tesla or another Elon company does the
Speaker 3:  bonkers thing that no one else has tried. 'cause it's too hard. Alright,
Speaker 3:  let's give it catch the rocket. You know what I mean? Yeah. When you're like,
Speaker 3:  oh, well here it is again.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like that stuff in every city of the Future thing. This is
Speaker 4:  what buses look like. Yep. Ev every single one of them for 50 years, this
Speaker 4:  is what they look like and it just,
Speaker 3:  Oh, I figured it out. You know what the difference between SpaceX and Tesla
Speaker 3:  is? What's that? The fucking cyber truck wiper.
Speaker 3:  Like you have a grand plan to reinvent space flight.
Speaker 3:  Gwen Shotwell will get it done. You're like wipers
Speaker 3:  start at the drawing board.
Speaker 3:  No idea what to do.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Are there wipers on the rockets? I feel like they probably work.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The, you know, the gimbals on the thrusters, a lot of things on the
Speaker 3:  Rockets work
Speaker 3:  that's all doing it. And then over here we're like, what if one big
Speaker 3:  wiper, let's do it. And it's like that thing does not work at
Speaker 4:  All. No, it's so floppy.
Speaker 3:  It's, but it's a bad wiper. I'm saying taking the
Speaker 3:  solved problem and trying to resol it is very much the Tesla
Speaker 3:  mode right now. Yes. And that it's like
Speaker 3:  this van is the most solved problem. How do you move six people
Speaker 3:  around a city? It's called an Escalade. Just do it. Just
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Make an Escalade. It's gonna be fucked.
Speaker 4:  I mean we, we make fun of Waymo for just getting a bunch of like Chrysler
Speaker 4:  Pacificas. That's actually like It does, it does work. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It does do job. Actually a very funny thing, I was looking at a chart of
Speaker 3:  percentage of EV sales by car maker and Jaguar has
Speaker 3:  this like shockingly high percentage of EV
Speaker 4:  Sales because of Waymo.
Speaker 3:  Because of Waymo.
Speaker 4:  That's so funny
Speaker 3:  Because Waymo buys so many EVs. Yeah. So like they're,
Speaker 3:  they're taking platforms that work and making them
Speaker 3:  autonomous. And it is, it's like they're just moving along.
Speaker 3:  There are Waymo testing on the streets of New York right now and they're,
Speaker 3:  you know, they're just adding cities and moving along and making the progress
Speaker 3:  and then there's whatever this is in 2027.
Speaker 4:  Right. And Tesla's whole thing is like launch the
Speaker 4:  giant thing and then work backwards from it. And that worked enough
Speaker 4:  times that it gave them a lot of confidence. And I think there's very
Speaker 4:  little evidence it's gonna work this time or has worked the last couple,
Speaker 4:  but we should move on. We have other stuff to talk about
Speaker 3:  By the way. I think we were both one for three.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no,
Speaker 3:  Well yeah, it's a push for me and I'm
Speaker 4:  One Yeah, you you, you won.
Speaker 3:  Congratulations. Well, we'll, we'll, we'll it's, it's a
Speaker 4:  Provisional, I'll buy you, I'll buy you a cyber cab.
Speaker 3:  There's an asterisk by this one. I'll take the 30 grand.
Speaker 4:  No, I'll, I'll buy you a cyber cab. Damn it. I'll buy you a ovn when it comes
Speaker 4:  out.
Speaker 3:  All right. There's other news actually quite a lot of other news. Yeah, we
Speaker 3:  should start it. There's been a lot of rumors about Apple doing an October
Speaker 3:  event. We're obviously running out of October. A lot of rumors about M four
Speaker 3:  Max. Who knows what's gonna happen. We're waiting on Apple Intelligence
Speaker 3:  to hit that Feels very likely it will happen this month. But again, we're
Speaker 3:  running out of October. Yeah. And I think they just needed to announce the
Speaker 3:  new iPad mini with a new chip in it and then they just did
Speaker 3:  it. They just put out a press release and now there's a new iPad mini.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. At some point I have just given up
Speaker 4:  waiting for Apple to like really care about the iPad Mini
Speaker 4:  and it's not that it's not a good device. I think it's a very good device
Speaker 4:  and I think the new one is probably also very good, but it is so
Speaker 4:  clearly not interesting to Apple for, for whatever reason.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like there's a subset of people who really like it. The new one even
Speaker 4:  is clearly not impressive. Like it's fine, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be a very good iPad mini, but it has, it has this, it has last year's chip.
Speaker 3:  There's a pilot somewhere that just banked the plane super hard angrily while
Speaker 3:  they're listening to this.
Speaker 4:  Listen, I got a lot of posts, I
Speaker 4:  wrote the story and I put every pilot's favorite tablet in the deck
Speaker 4:  of our story. Like you can't own me harder than I own myself people,
Speaker 4:  but the like it's, it's just a spec upgrade. Right. Which is fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The the last one of these was three years ago and
Speaker 4:  total redesign, they did a bunch of cool stuff. They, they squared off the
Speaker 4:  edges. It got touch ID in the, in the power button. Like
Speaker 4:  all good stuff. It's a really good device. This one is just purely a spec
Speaker 4:  upgrade. Faster everything. Faster connections, faster processors.
Speaker 4:  But to me the thing that's the most telling is in a year where Apple upgraded
Speaker 4:  the iPad air to the M two and the iPad Pro to the M four and
Speaker 4:  and actually launched the M four with an iPad like that, that is a,
Speaker 4:  apple does not do that stuff by accident. That is like a statement of
Speaker 4:  this is what this device means in our lineup. This
Speaker 4:  thing got the A 17 Pro, which was in iPhones last year.
Speaker 3:  Do you think They just were like, well we got all these iPhone 15 pro parts.
Speaker 4:  Jason Snell wrote a really good thing at six Colors, basically positing that
Speaker 4:  that it's like this is a good chip. It's the least you need to
Speaker 4:  work on Apple intelligence. So Apple is, is just trying to pull people along
Speaker 4:  with not quite like garbage bin parts, but like stuff
Speaker 4:  it already had. Right. Yeah. This is the upgrade you can do without trying
Speaker 4:  very hard and, and it'll work like the the, I'm sure this mini will be very
Speaker 4:  good. No one I know had performance issues with the last mini.
Speaker 4:  This one will do fine, it's all gonna be fine. But I, every single
Speaker 4:  time one of these comes out, I hold out hope that Apple is going to do something
Speaker 4:  new for it. Like give me a keyboard case, come up with a new idea about how
Speaker 4:  people are gonna use this thing. We got Pencil Pro support, which is nice.
Speaker 4:  But the story of this is just, it is
Speaker 4:  slightly worse and smaller,
Speaker 3:  Slightly worse. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's not the M two. It's not the M four. Oh, I see. Not than before this
Speaker 4:  thing, this thing will feel old much sooner
Speaker 4:  than the other iPads that came out this year.
Speaker 3:  I thought you meant slightly worse in comparison to the old one. Like it's
Speaker 3:  an iPad mini but this one will hurt you in some way. Oh
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 3:  No. This like the glass is jagged.
Speaker 4:  This one it's an iPad mini but it pokes you once every eight
Speaker 4:  minutes and you never know when.
Speaker 3:  No, you mean in comparison to the rest of the iPad
Speaker 4:  In comparison to the rest of the iPad. Got it. Right. Okay. And like the
Speaker 4:  story, what you would want really is basically to have this one
Speaker 4:  be just as good and slightly smaller, right? Like this is what people want
Speaker 4:  from the iPhone mini. Like give me one that is just as good but slightly
Speaker 4:  smaller. And Apple is resolutely not doing that with any
Speaker 4:  of its products.
Speaker 3:  I wonder, I mean I wonder if there's thermal issues with sticking an N series
Speaker 3:  chip in a platform. It's possible small who, who knows the thing that gets
Speaker 3:  me, I believe it was Christopher Mims, your old colleague from the journal
Speaker 3:  who I think his post was just make it a phone.
Speaker 3:  Like If, you just called this the iPhone Ultra plus max people would buy
Speaker 3:  it because people love big phones. Yes. And it's so funny because even
Speaker 3:  If, you wanted to use an iPad mini as your phone. You could not
Speaker 3:  because it doesn't run iPhone apps.
Speaker 4:  Right? Well there is a,
Speaker 3:  The iPad OS is like in this weird tweener zone.
Speaker 4:  There is a real like what if I had an iPad and an
Speaker 4:  Apple watch And that was my computing setup that I think could
Speaker 4:  in theory be very compelling in, in the way that you're describing. But
Speaker 4:  Apple just won't do that. You're right. If this was a giant iPhone, I think
Speaker 4:  it would actually be more interesting as a device than as a tiny iPad.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But it's like, you know what, it doesn't run Instagram. Right?
Speaker 3:  Indefensibly So Yeah, it just doesn't run Instagram. Yeah. And it's,
Speaker 3:  it's not so much bigger than my iPhone 16 max like.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well, which is I think the strange thing, it's at this point, especially
Speaker 4:  as the phones have just continued to get bigger, I mean the, the 16 Pro Max
Speaker 4:  is 6.9 inches right now. The iPad
Speaker 4:  mini is 8.3 inches, which is a difference,
Speaker 4:  but it's not that huge a difference. Like
Speaker 4:  the only main user interface thing is A,
Speaker 4:  you can't run iPhone apps and B, you don't get the pencil
Speaker 4:  support on the iPhone. Right. So that's No I'm saying's
Speaker 3:  The trade. No, I'm saying the picture Apple's own press picture of the mini
Speaker 3:  is a hand holding it like a phone like this. Yeah. And like the
Speaker 3:  only difference is the fingers are out. Like that's a huge hand. I
Speaker 3:  have a big hand. It's a and like that is a big hand. We're gonna get there,
Speaker 3:  it's gonna happen one day and then the ghost of Steve Jobs is gonna be very
Speaker 3:  upset with everyone. It was, I was like being my old old
Speaker 3:  iPhone five, which was like the biggest, he would let it get and he was
Speaker 3:  like, your thumb has to hit the opposite iPad mini as a phone. Those were
Speaker 3:  the days. That's the future. Those were the days. Alright, can you explain
Speaker 3:  this next one to me because I don't understand
Speaker 3:  what's going on.
Speaker 4:  I was really hoping you
Speaker 3:  A MD Intel and a bunch of tech companies formed an alliance.
Speaker 3:  It's called the X 86 advisory group.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft, Google Meta Lenovo, and then truly
Speaker 3:  Intel and A MD which are ferocious rivals. Yeah. They formed the X
Speaker 3:  86 ecosystem advisory group. Pat Gelsinger announced
Speaker 3:  it on stage at Lenovo's Tech World
Speaker 3:  2024 conference, the hottest conference of the year. And
Speaker 3:  Gelsinger said X 86 said it's, we are alive and well.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. My, my we are alive and well. T-shirt is answering a lot of questions
Speaker 4:  raised by my world. Well
Speaker 4:  the only thing I can read into this is just
Speaker 4:  pure existential fear from these companies. Right? Like of
Speaker 4:  arm of arm. Yeah. And, and I think frankly with good
Speaker 4:  reason, apple has been
Speaker 4:  sort of, has completed its transition to its own ARM-based silicon
Speaker 4:  stuff and is just lapping everybody else
Speaker 4:  in, in like raw sort of everyday device performance. It is just
Speaker 4:  crushing the competition. Qualcomm I think for
Speaker 4:  like a decade made promises that it couldn't keep about
Speaker 4:  its arm performance and how it was gonna bring like all the efficiency of
Speaker 4:  mobile and all the power of desktops and put that together and it was gonna
Speaker 4:  be magic. And I think Intel and a MD and others
Speaker 4:  watched Qualcomm sort of try and fail to do that. And we were like, okay,
Speaker 4:  well they'll never get there. It's not gonna happen. And I think you could
Speaker 4:  argue with relative success that Qualcomm is there
Speaker 4:  now and I think it's very clear that Qualcomm is going to get there. Right?
Speaker 4:  Whether or not you believe it's a real X 86 competitor now
Speaker 4:  with the, the Snapdragon elite and all that stuff in the new copilot plus
Speaker 4:  PCs and all that stuff, it's either there or it's close. And
Speaker 4:  I think that leap was so big that all of these other companies
Speaker 4:  just panicked. I mean, and Intel is obviously like sort of
Speaker 4:  collapsing in on itself, like a dying star in, in
Speaker 4:  so many ways right now. And a MD is a, I think in a slightly
Speaker 3:  Less AMD is in
Speaker 4:  A better spot precarious position. Yeah. But it also would very
Speaker 4:  much like to not have Qualcomm become a dominant player and
Speaker 4:  the whole chip industry has just turned right. Like you have, you have what
Speaker 4:  Apple's doing, you have what Nvidia is doing and you have what Qualcomm is
Speaker 4:  doing and all these other chip makers are just out there being like, oh my
Speaker 4:  God, this happened so much faster than we expected. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I just, I don't know how to read it other than that
Speaker 3:  On the AI side of things, I So I actually I read this as a like a
Speaker 3:  data center announcement of all of the things that like interesting, even
Speaker 3:  though it's a Lenovo conference, X 86 is still doing well in
Speaker 3:  data centers. Sure. And then, you know, Nvidia I think gets a lot of the
Speaker 3:  shine for AI because it's selling so many of its GPUs to AI companies.
Speaker 3:  But like, you know, X 86 processors outperform the N series in
Speaker 3:  a bunch of AI tasks. Yeah. A MD has a pretty healthy business selling
Speaker 3:  GPUs there. There's just a whole thing there,
Speaker 3:  right? Where like you, if that is the big market,
Speaker 3:  you might as well put together the big competitor to 10
Speaker 3:  Nvidia and say like here's your other path because all these, all the big
Speaker 3:  companies would like not to be locked into Nvidia. I don't know about consumer
Speaker 3:  PCs at all. Like I, I truly don't. I guess they were on stage at the Lenovo
Speaker 3:  event, but they weren't like waving laptops around. That's true. And So.
Speaker 3:  I. Yeah. I just, it's weird and it's weird that Microsoft is like copilot
Speaker 3:  plus PCs and mostly arm ships and then also over here
Speaker 3:  on this other platform that we are tied to forever.
Speaker 4:  Right. Well and I think with a lot of that stuff
Speaker 4:  there is the, the arm advancement has
Speaker 4:  just happened so fast while I think X 86, particularly
Speaker 4:  with Intel, has just been like stuck in the mud for a long time
Speaker 4:  that Intel has kind of gone version after version of its chips without
Speaker 4:  sort of meaningful progress on some of the stuff that people really
Speaker 4:  care about. And I, I think in theory the idea of
Speaker 4:  banding together on this is like, okay, we can sort of rising tide lifts
Speaker 4:  all boats here by meshing together some of
Speaker 4:  the work these companies are doing and saying, okay, we're all gonna build
Speaker 4:  better chips, which is actually going to benefit all of us instead of
Speaker 4:  just, you know, sort of running in parallel and all trying to reinvent the
Speaker 4:  wheel on our own. Which I think is a good strategy. I just think they are
Speaker 4:  way too late in starting this move. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Let me just read you the list here to support my data
Speaker 3:  center claim. Broadcom, Dell, Google,
Speaker 3:  Hewlett Packard Enterprise as well as HP,
Speaker 3:  the Sure. The other one, Lenovo Meta, Microsoft,
Speaker 3:  Oracle and Red Hat. And then just for fun,
Speaker 3:  Linus Tova and Tim Sweeney. Sure.
Speaker 3:  You know guys, those are all people that run giant service.
Speaker 4:  I mean the picture at the top of the press release is a data center. Like
Speaker 4:  it's not, it's not unclear what they're doing here,
Speaker 4:  but No, I I think you're right and I think it, it's, that's all fine, right?
Speaker 4:  Like there, many of these companies have big businesses like did you mention
Speaker 4:  Google is in this? Yeah. And it's, it is because of Google Cloud, right.
Speaker 4:  Like we run data centers, we kind of need this to work
Speaker 4:  because otherwise we're hosed paying Nvidia every penny we have for
Speaker 4:  the rest of this.
Speaker 3:  But it's funny because all those companies are also building their own chips
Speaker 3:  on the side.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Right. Microsoft is building its own chips. They have a lot to say.
Speaker 3:  If you're Microsoft and you want Arm on Windows to work, you get to walk
Speaker 3:  in the Qualcomm's office and be like, do what we want. You're it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right. Or we're going back to Intel, which someone has to tell 'em
Speaker 3:  what to do. Yeah. So you just see it's, it's
Speaker 4:  Google's building TPUs like this is this. Yeah. Everybody is on this.
Speaker 3:  Well, we'll see. I just think something is happening in the world of X 86
Speaker 3:  trips and this is one of those things. That's what I got for you
Speaker 3:  right now. And I will say that If, you are, if you're ever in a position
Speaker 3:  to give a keynote and you're like, make the slide say we are alive and well
Speaker 3:  just take a beat. Just really, just really think about what
Speaker 3:  that means to everyone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean again, like it's it's them trying to
Speaker 4:  convince the world. Allison Johnson who wrote the story
Speaker 4:  made the point that this whole thing might have just been to convince
Speaker 4:  investors that like, yes, we are taking Arm seriously.
Speaker 4:  Might've been true. Really would've been a super good idea to do this in
Speaker 4:  like 2017.
Speaker 3:  Hmm. What If you face down the ferocious competitive
Speaker 3:  monster of Nvidia with a committee that works as well as the USB and
Speaker 3:  Influencers forum. Yeah. It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 4:  Give leather jackets to everyone on the committee. It's game over
Speaker 3:  A couple more bits of Gadget News. Sonos announced a
Speaker 3:  new Arc Ultra soundbar and Sub four, two pieces
Speaker 3:  here. I would say one, I think they've decided the app is good enough again,
Speaker 3:  like they had paused new releases because the app was so broken.
Speaker 3:  But they, you know, they, we've talked about this, they've like released
Speaker 3:  their plan to fix it. They've mostly fixed it. They're doing the
Speaker 3:  public Trello board with the feature updates to come, which is incredible.
Speaker 3:  You know, their Eddie Lazarus in their c-suite is, he has
Speaker 3:  given his media tour about what he found and his report,
Speaker 3:  which was we shouldn't have released a shitty app. Shocking
Speaker 3:  Revolution. But I think they think they're fine. They've, they've gotten
Speaker 3:  to where they need to be and it's time to start releasing products again.
Speaker 3:  So it's a thousand dollars Arc Ultra. It's more powerful than the
Speaker 3:  regular arc. And it's got new trans issues from a company called
Speaker 3:  Mate Mate, M-A-Y-H-T-I
Speaker 4:  Think it's mate Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Sun Product. This company in 2022. They're like specialized
Speaker 3:  speakers basically they call it sound motion. And the quote is
Speaker 3:  one of the most significant breakthroughs in audio engineering's in nearly
Speaker 3:  100 years that unlocks greater clarity, depth and
Speaker 3:  balance than ever before possible in a soundbar. The sleek
Speaker 3:  seven tweeters six mid wolfers a built-in
Speaker 3:  Wolfer and you get 9 1 4 from all from the one soundbar.
Speaker 4:  What do we know about sound motion? Like I I do feel like Sonos is not
Speaker 4:  typically prone to grandiose lies about its own sound
Speaker 4:  quality. So I'm, I'm more inclined than a lot of companies to believe them
Speaker 4:  when they say this is a big deal. But I also, it just seems like
Speaker 4:  a lot of words.
Speaker 3:  It's a, it's a, it's definitely a lot of audio processing.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  But like So I I food audio process, the original arc long time
Speaker 3:  ago and I tested it against my own 5 1 4 at with
Speaker 3:  actual speakers in the ceiling. And I thought the Arc did a great job actually,
Speaker 3:  but it was obviously more processed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like that was the trade off. Like very clearly the trade off was,
Speaker 3:  boy there's not as much stuff happening around me when I used my
Speaker 3:  actual system versus the arc. And the arc is like, boy there's a lot of stuff
Speaker 3:  happening around you and boy, it just sounds like more
Speaker 3:  audio processing is occurring to make it seem like a bunch of stuff is happening
Speaker 3:  all around you. I, yeah, I've never been happy with how these things sound
Speaker 3:  for music. I just think music and movies are two different things. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So I haven't heard this yet. I'm excited to hear it. I know Chris Welch is
Speaker 3:  excited to review it. But you know, the notable thing is
Speaker 3:  we're getting to the place where
Speaker 3:  9 1 4 out of a soundbar is possible. Yeah. For a thousand
Speaker 3:  dollars, which is, if all that works, that is incredible.
Speaker 3:  That is a system that would, you know, even If, you buy cheap speakers, a
Speaker 3:  receiver that can support 9 1 4, like you're, you're out for
Speaker 3:  thousands of dollars and then you gotta put 'em on the ceiling. So to do
Speaker 3:  it in a soundbar for a thousand bucks is pretty cool.
Speaker 4:  Well and that's, I I think that's been Sonos thing with Soundbars for
Speaker 4:  a minute now. Even what you're describing about the ace right. Is like, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's almost as good or like very
Speaker 4:  good if not as good with
Speaker 4:  essentially none of the effort. Right? Like it's, and and that's I
Speaker 4:  think the whole pitch of Soundbars in general. I have become a big believer
Speaker 4:  in Soundbars as somebody who is like, just not going to
Speaker 4:  put nine speakers in my house. It's just not gonna happen. I'd love to but
Speaker 4:  it's not gonna happen. But I think the idea that If, you If you
Speaker 4:  can use this processing to get even most of the way there
Speaker 4:  with just a thing I plant in front of my television. That's pretty powerful.
Speaker 4:  Like I, I think that's, that goes a really long way for an awful lot of people.
Speaker 3:  I just wanna be clear, 9 1 4 is not nine speakers, it's 13.
Speaker 4:  You're right. I apologize
Speaker 3:  That's that and that's bonkers. Like I have a, I'll
Speaker 4:  Put in nine, I'm not putting in 13 right?
Speaker 3:  I have a 5 1 4 system which is nine and that's a lot of speakers.
Speaker 3:  Like arguably too many
Speaker 3:  9 1 4 out of a soundbar is legitimately kind of cool if
Speaker 3:  it works. So I'm excited for that. By the way, the quote from CO Patrick Spence
Speaker 3:  is we have reached a level of quality in the app that gives us the confidence
Speaker 3:  to launch our extraordinary new products.
Speaker 3:  They have 90% of the previous apps features with the
Speaker 3:  forthcoming update and more on the way.
Speaker 4:  I think that's all fine. I also think at some point if you're Sonos, you
Speaker 4:  just have to start shipping stuff. Like you can, you, you can only sort of
Speaker 4:  sit there and apologize so many times and eventually you have to ship new
Speaker 4:  things and it's about to be the holidays. And I think like we just got to
Speaker 4:  the point where they're like, well it is what it's Yeah,
Speaker 4:  we're just gonna ship the thing, which I think is fine. Right? Like you,
Speaker 4:  how, I don't know how much longer they're supposed to sit and sort of beat
Speaker 4:  themselves up about the very bad app that they shipped.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I well I'm dying to listen to this thing. I'm dying to review it. I
Speaker 3:  will say one of the If, you have a regular sort of
Speaker 3:  5.1 system. The, the biggest, most noticeable
Speaker 3:  upgrade is front height.
Speaker 4:  Oh, interesting. So
Speaker 3:  You have your three speakers in front of you. The, the most immediate upgrade
Speaker 3:  is not over your head. It's in front of you and up.
Speaker 3:  Hmm. 'cause your ears are pointed to the front, some basic
Speaker 3:  biology. So you put the two speakers above your other speakers and they,
Speaker 3:  things are coming at you from above there. That's just a huge upgrade. If,
Speaker 3:  you can figure out how to get that upgrade today, you should do it. But a
Speaker 3:  sound bar or even the speakers you put on top of your speakers are sort of
Speaker 3:  necessarily reflecting from the middle.
Speaker 3:  'cause they can't make the sound come from straight up. So that's always
Speaker 3:  the thing I'm curious about. We'll see. Interesting. Revolutionary new transducers.
Speaker 3:  David,
Speaker 4:  Listen, I still listen to the audio out of my crappy TCL
Speaker 4:  Roku tv. I'm coming to your house, So I am I am looking forward to the day
Speaker 4:  that one of these feels worth buying.
Speaker 3:  I have my old five one system from college, like sitting in storage. I'm
Speaker 3:  just gonna drive to your house. It's not great.
Speaker 4:  Listen, every time I leave for work, I come home and Anna has like
Speaker 4:  rearranged one room in our house. I think next time she leaves you should
Speaker 4:  come over and we'll just set up speakers everywhere. It'll be awesome.
Speaker 3:  All right, last one. It's this four KN 64 from Analogue. I'm so
Speaker 3:  excited
Speaker 4:  About this thing. So this thing has been a year in the making maybe.
Speaker 4:  I think like we, we've been getting teases about this for an incredibly long
Speaker 4:  time. It's called the Analogue 3D. It just looks like a Nintendo
Speaker 4:  64. Actually the thing kinda looks like a Sega Genesis, but
Speaker 4:  it, it'll play 64 cartridges. It has a controller.
Speaker 4:  As somebody who grew up with the N 64, like the, the way I would date
Speaker 4:  my childhood is the Nintendo 64.
Speaker 4:  I'm so excited about this thing. And Analogue does a really great job of
Speaker 4:  emulating stuff and, and letting you play old cartridges with these things.
Speaker 4:  I have, I have every confidence that this thing is actually gonna
Speaker 4:  work really well. The N 64 is notoriously hard to emulator and
Speaker 4:  Analogue seems to feel very good about having pulled it off, which I'm excited
Speaker 4:  about.
Speaker 3:  They changed the controller to now have the weird third thing in the middle,
Speaker 3:  which I think
Speaker 4:  Is, which is a bummer to be honest. Like I I love the stupid controller.
Speaker 4:  It never made any sense because you only ever held the middle one and the
Speaker 4:  right one.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because you're not, you don't have three hands. But it does still
Speaker 4:  have the, the ports on the front for plugging in
Speaker 4:  an N 64 controller, which I love. I don't know if it actually even
Speaker 4:  works, but as it just as the way it looks, I'm into it.
Speaker 3:  Let me ask you a really dumb question. This only takes cartridges or you
Speaker 3:  can play off cards like SD cards.
Speaker 3:  I think it only takes cartridges.
Speaker 4:  So No, it, it takes, it has two USB ports and an SD card slot. So
Speaker 4:  you'll you'll in theory be able to, you'll be able to put other stuff onto
Speaker 4:  it. But the, the thing is, and I wonder how true this is, I think there
Speaker 4:  are probably a lot of people out there who still have a box full of n 64
Speaker 3:  Cartridges. I mean, I intend to only play on my legally acquired n 64 cartridges.
Speaker 3:  I don't
Speaker 4:  Know what you're talking about. Yeah, I'm gonna, I'm gonna dump them as I
Speaker 4:  always do and always have, which is how I play goldeneye now.
Speaker 4:  It's it's totally fine. I bought
Speaker 3:  One of those Amber Nick game boys.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 4:  So the one that just ships with like 6,000 games on it from Amazon. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  great.
Speaker 3:  And we had friends over and someone was like, what's this and the other,
Speaker 3:  just without missing
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. So Amazon introduced new Kindles this week. David,
Speaker 3:  you were at the event. I was, which very notably
Speaker 3:  was the first event at Amazon for Panos Penne who first house
Speaker 3:  listeners almost certainly remember from his time at Microsoft when he ran
Speaker 3:  Windows and Surface. How was that event?
Speaker 4:  Really interesting. So I think they, they did it in a very unusual way. It
Speaker 4:  was like a, it was an embargoed event. So the whole existence of
Speaker 4:  the thing was not public. It was basically just like a media
Speaker 4:  briefing. But they framed it in his event upon us, like got up on stage and
Speaker 4:  gave a whole speech very clearly what's going on is
Speaker 4:  whenever they do a big public thing, it is going to have to be the future
Speaker 4:  of Alexa. But they wanted to like give the Kindle its moment,
Speaker 4:  right? And they launched four Kindles at once, which I think has never happened
Speaker 4:  in the history of the Kindle. That it was like, it's a full line reset. And
Speaker 4:  it was fun. Like the, the, this team loves Kindles. I always forget how
Speaker 4:  many people love Kindles. Like the, the traffic to our website on the
Speaker 4:  day. It suggests that a lot of people really care about Kindles
Speaker 4:  and the, the team has been making stuff. Ponos has been there for like almost
Speaker 4:  exactly a year and has done a lot of stuff with the Kindle team since he's
Speaker 4:  been there. So it was cool to actually just get to like live
Speaker 4:  in Kindle universe for a minute. Normally they just like update the website
Speaker 4:  and it's like, here's some new Kindles. And this was like, this was much
Speaker 4:  bigger than that.
Speaker 3:  So what are the new ones? So
Speaker 4:  There's four and I, I'll go from cheapest to most expensive. So the
Speaker 4:  cheapest is just the regular Kindle, which has some, you know,
Speaker 4:  speck improvements. It's a little brighter. It comes in a really cool new
Speaker 4:  matcha color that I like a lot. But it's still just the base
Speaker 4:  Kindle. The new Paperweight has a bigger screen,
Speaker 4:  brighter screen, faster processing. They like redesigned it a little bit.
Speaker 4:  It has some really nice, like vibrant colors. One thing I heard a bunch from
Speaker 4:  folks at Amazon was the whole sort of book talk movement and the thing where
Speaker 4:  people are like bedazzling their Kindles has really changed the way they
Speaker 4:  think about the device. So they're leaning into sort of making it more fun.
Speaker 4:  The Paperweight is the Kindle right in like a very real way. It is, it is
Speaker 4:  the biggest, most important Kindle in the lineup. New one seems to be
Speaker 4:  very good. There's the Kindle scribe, which is the, the biggest
Speaker 4:  one that you can take notes on. They made lots of changes to that, including
Speaker 4:  some gen AI stuff where you can write your notes and then have
Speaker 4:  the scribe either summarize them or just like neatly format them and fix
Speaker 4:  your handwriting so you can share them and find them more easily.
Speaker 4:  But that's still described. And then the big announcement was the, the Kindle
Speaker 4:  Color Soft, which is the first color Kindle. And basically it's a paper white
Speaker 4:  with a color display. And they've done some really interesting like
Speaker 4:  display stack work to make that work. It's very expensive, but
Speaker 4:  it is like the one that they were like, this is sort of
Speaker 4:  the moment for a new Kindle looks really
Speaker 4:  great. I like you look at color and it's like, what do I need from color
Speaker 4:  in a reading device? But then just looking at it on a table,
Speaker 4:  seeing the book cover and now it's in color. It's just instantly like, oh,
Speaker 4:  this is great. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I was, I played with the new paper, right, you had in the office and it's
Speaker 3:  very fast. That's
Speaker 4:  Awesome. Super fast. Yeah, that's a good advice.
Speaker 3:  I, the only other thing I'll say is I asked back if she wanted to call her
Speaker 3:  Kindle and she just looked at me and said, stop trying to buy me Kindles.
Speaker 3:  This is the problem. You're in here. We're gonna talk about it right now
Speaker 3:  with Panus Penne. And once we're done with that, we're gonna go to an ad.
Speaker 3:  We'll be back with the lightning round. Here's Kindles with Panos Pane.
Speaker 4:  Panos Pane, Welcome, To, The Vergecast. What's
Speaker 6:  Going on guys? Have
Speaker 4:  You been on The Vergecast before? Yeah. Okay. Yeah. But not in your current
Speaker 4:  iteration, new Anos.
Speaker 3:  Do you feel like a different person? No.
Speaker 7:  I mean, you guys come right out swinging it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Unbelievable. We gotta do this for
Speaker 6:  30 minutes. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We're just getting started.
Speaker 7:  We got lot to do. So
Speaker 4:  I. Feel
Speaker 6:  Like good to see you guys. It's good to see you guys.
Speaker 4:  We've got a lot of news to talk about. You launched several thousand new
Speaker 4:  Kindles that we have to talk about.
Speaker 6:  It is the most, it is the most Kindle's been launched, I think, in history
Speaker 6:  of Kindle,
Speaker 4:  Which is kind of fascinating and it's part of what we should talk about.
Speaker 4:  But the, let's just start with you. I think our audience
Speaker 4:  knows you well over the years. You've, you've launched a lot of things. You've
Speaker 4:  been a product guy for a really long time. Why? Why'd you go to Amazon?
Speaker 4:  Tell us the, the p transition,
Speaker 3:  The audience does know, but you were Microsoft for the longest time. You
Speaker 3:  did all the surface stuff there, and then it was kind of a surprise, right?
Speaker 3:  You left Microsoft to go to Amazon.
Speaker 3:  That was a surprise. I think people are very curious why, why the move? I
Speaker 3:  feel like you had a ring camera and you were maybe had a bug and you're like,
Speaker 3:  I'm going to Amazon. There
Speaker 6:  Were a few details I wanted to get. I wanted to
Speaker 7:  Get, is
Speaker 6:  Enough of this enough?
Speaker 7:  Fix this right now. You know what? I'm just gonna go somewhere
Speaker 7:  new to fix it. Yeah. Yeah. I
Speaker 6:  Don't think it was exactly that, but there is a, there's a, there's a little
Speaker 6:  bit, there's a little bit to that. You know, when you think about the array
Speaker 6:  of products between Ring, blink, arrow, fire, tv, fire
Speaker 6:  tablets, Alexa, echo, Kindle,
Speaker 6:  satellites, zoos. Like, you just look at that and you go, what, what could
Speaker 6:  you do? And when this technological pipe,
Speaker 6:  you know, of AI that's coming, which eventually ends up being a red thread
Speaker 6:  between all these things, how they all connect and you can change people's
Speaker 6:  lives. Like yeah, it's not a bug. It's just
Speaker 6:  a, it's just awesome. Like awesome. And so, you know, it
Speaker 6:  energized me. Plus, you know,
Speaker 6:  it, it's, it's like a, another chapters is a great thing. It's a
Speaker 6:  cool thing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Is there a, is there an underlying AI bet
Speaker 4:  underneath all of that? Like when you came in, 'cause I think you, you
Speaker 4:  were making this move, right? Kind of at the
Speaker 4:  beginning of the Holy crap. AI is going to change everything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Moment. And we've been talking to people now for, you know, two years
Speaker 4:  who are like, everything that you can see or touch or imagine,
Speaker 4:  it's a platform shift. AI is right. It's a platform shift. Like, is that,
Speaker 4:  is that your
Speaker 6:  It's a real one too. Like it's very real. Yeah, it's a hundred percent that.
Speaker 6:  And so when you ask the question like, why did you go to Amazon? Like
Speaker 6:  first it's an amazing company.
Speaker 6:  Second, the values are crazy cool, you know,
Speaker 6:  but third,
Speaker 6:  wow. Like that shift is real.
Speaker 6:  And I think what you can do, especially in the consumer space,
Speaker 6:  what you can do for people in their everyday lives is off the charts. So
Speaker 6:  If, you combine it, you know, it gets a pretty easy answer.
Speaker 6:  Not simple, you know, challenging as a human, you know,
Speaker 6:  emotional and on every way. No question.
Speaker 3:  Let me just ask you this. You, you said there, you, you named all the things.
Speaker 3:  Zoox is the autonomous taxis, KU
Speaker 6:  Robax.
Speaker 3:  Robotaxis. Yeah. Think
Speaker 6:  About it that way.
Speaker 3:  Kuper is the satellites. What is the connection between Kindle and the
Speaker 3:  satellites?
Speaker 6:  You don't, you don't need to stretch. Okay. You don't need to stretch everything
Speaker 6:  and pull 'em together. That's not the goal. Okay. It's just the, you know,
Speaker 6:  how you impact people's lives is different in those things. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I was just wondering
Speaker 6:  'cause you getting broadband to everybody versus, and let's just think about
Speaker 6:  the impact that has on people. Like, and for, for me, like, it's like a dream.
Speaker 6:  You have, you know, helping people read, learn, create.
Speaker 6:  That's one side on a Kindle. And so game
Speaker 6:  changing for life to make sure, you know, you're reading, learning, getting
Speaker 6:  into a book, disappearing into it. And that's one, that's one way to think
Speaker 6:  about like, it's just positive everywhere. And then
Speaker 6:  satellites are distributing broadband to the world where everybody needs
Speaker 6:  it. Like same like impact. Both are massive, but very different ways.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, very different ways.
Speaker 3:  One of the things that could connect a bunch of these products is Alexa,
Speaker 3:  obviously you're talking about ai. Yeah. The opportunity for Alexa
Speaker 3:  to be a smarter kind of AI product. I think a lot of people can see it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Is that happening? You, you working
Speaker 6:  On that? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  we are working on it. You know, I'm not necessarily here to talk about it.
Speaker 6:  I think I'll be back soon to talk about it. So another way to say it. I mean,
Speaker 6:  if you'll have me back. Yeah, we'll see. 'cause so far I'm frustrated with
Speaker 6:  both of you, so we'll see how this goes. Like how it ends.
Speaker 4:  No, that's right. It'll stay like that. Yeah, that's what we keep doing here.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna keep this carefully
Speaker 4:  Calibrated. Yeah, it goes fine. Like
Speaker 3:  Right at, should I leave?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like, just start right away. I'm sorry. Why did you go to off? Like
Speaker 6:  what? Come on man. You
Speaker 3:  People, I mean, you were the face of products people love for a long time.
Speaker 3:  I mean, you just had an event. You, David, I think you were at the Kindle
Speaker 3:  launch event and I got an immediate text from David that's like, I missed
Speaker 3:  a Panos pane presentation. Like did
Speaker 4:  You I did. I really did that text. I sent him that text. You did? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. It was a little, it was, it was a less of a tech presentation
Speaker 6:  yesterday. Yeah. Little bit, little bit different. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I just, that was, Microsoft also has a big platform and has a lot of
Speaker 3:  products that you can connect in different kinds of narratives. Sure. You
Speaker 3:  were great at that. I I was just curious like the, the jump from one
Speaker 3:  big company's ecosystem to another big company's ecosystem, trying to
Speaker 3:  pull them together. It seems like the same challenge, but it sounds very
Speaker 3:  much like you think of the opportunities as as different. They're
Speaker 6:  Very different. You know, they're very different. And, and the way I look
Speaker 6:  at it at Amazon, like the amount of consumers you connect around the world
Speaker 6:  with the technology shift, you know, it seems like buzzword at this point
Speaker 6:  to say ai, I can't, it's so hard for me to, and with ai,
Speaker 6:  What we're gonna be able to do with Alexa just to connect people. I,
Speaker 6:  I'm not talking about it in detail today, but man, this is gonna be transformative
Speaker 6:  and how it connects throughout your life with all the devices that we just
Speaker 6:  talked about, all the brands that are coming together, both in the home and
Speaker 6:  outside of the home. It's just, it's off the, it's so, it's,
Speaker 6:  it's so energizing. There's another side to it too, though. You, you, like,
Speaker 6:  the leadership principles at Amazon are surreal. They're fully
Speaker 6:  aligned with the way I love running teams.
Speaker 6:  You know, connecting people and what it means to focus on a customer.
Speaker 4:  All right. Well before this becomes a full decoder episode that you're, you're
Speaker 4:  gonna do at some point, I have lots of questions about leadership principles
Speaker 4:  that you guys will get to some other time. Let's talk about gadgets. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I'd love that. We can talk about leadership principles all day. Those are,
Speaker 6:  they're just, they're awesome. But if you're not gonna let me, that's
Speaker 3:  The other show. I think that's,
Speaker 4:  That's the other show. There's time for that. We'll do that, we'll do that
Speaker 4:  somewhere else but Kindles. So yeah, the, I'm, I'm fascinated
Speaker 4:  by just the scope of this launch. Like you said, it was four Kindles at once,
Speaker 4:  which I think Amazon has never, ever done. And I feel like
Speaker 4:  that's either like an accident of technological development or
Speaker 4:  like a very much on purpose. Kindles were
Speaker 4:  so back kind of moment. Which one of those
Speaker 4:  things is it?
Speaker 6:  I mean, seriously, come on. It is not gonna be an accident as, you know,
Speaker 6:  Kindle's one of these products that kind of transcended other products in
Speaker 6:  a sense of, it's a brand and it's a thing and it's identified as
Speaker 6:  e-readers. And it's all about reading all this connection to it
Speaker 6:  is so powerful. But it all all reflects back on the people making it.
Speaker 6:  I joined Amazon about a year ago. One of the first couple of meetings I had
Speaker 6:  was on Kindle. And I was inspired to see like, where are we at?
Speaker 6:  And you had a team with a bunch of stuff in the vault, basically. Like,
Speaker 6:  we're, we're close. We're thinking, what do you think? What do you think?
Speaker 6:  and we, you know, we sat down, we looked at it all true story, you know,
Speaker 6:  in on the Color Soft. We looked at it and I said,
Speaker 6:  if the color's great, won't, let's not compromise any
Speaker 6:  experience. You know, there is some limitations with e 'cause it's challenging,
Speaker 6:  you know, there's flashing and other small challenges and how bright it'll
Speaker 6:  be. And you always compare it to an ole and what that means. And you have
Speaker 6:  this team that's just obsessed about the detail in which of course, near
Speaker 6:  and dear to my heart. And so about a year ago, you know, we looked at the
Speaker 6:  full lineup and we made, we made the investment that said, let's get
Speaker 6:  after these products. Let's launch 'em All breeding has
Speaker 6:  momentum.
Speaker 6:  Literally. I mean, the Kindle brand product
Speaker 6:  line is growing
Speaker 6:  and there's a whole new generation of readers.
Speaker 4:  I think, what was the stat that 60% of people who bought a Kindle last year
Speaker 4:  were first time Kindle buyers? First time buyers. I find that, that was so
Speaker 4:  surprising to me.
Speaker 6:  So awesome. Because you also have this up into the right reading trend.
Speaker 6:  And so
Speaker 6:  you're, when you put those two things together, it basically says,
Speaker 6:  people who have always read are still reading. And there's a whole new cohort
Speaker 6:  coming in reading and it's
Speaker 6:  happening right now. I love it because you have Gen Z and millennials who
Speaker 6:  are, are diving into the power of like disappearing into a book
Speaker 6:  and If you on, you know, TikTok, you'll find book talk and there's a lot
Speaker 6:  of energy. People are bedazzling. There are Kindles right now. That's, that's
Speaker 6:  always a signal or a sign. That's cool. But a year ago when we sat in a room,
Speaker 6:  you mean these are can be very personal, passionate. That's what I should
Speaker 6:  close that. But a year ago when we sat in that room, yeah, it was very, let
Speaker 6:  me answer the question. Super conscious like next year Kindle
Speaker 6:  will be the year of Kindle. Let's go. We'll bring color, we'll bring it where
Speaker 6:  it belongs. We'll bring a new level of ink, it's a writing,
Speaker 6:  and then we'll refresh the products that you know are just what, what you
Speaker 6:  would call products that people already love.
Speaker 4:  I'm super fascinated by that moment because I feel like the Kindle's a really
Speaker 4:  unusual kind of device in that it just won
Speaker 4:  so long ago that there has been, I think you,
Speaker 4:  you can perceive Kindle as both like a giant success and
Speaker 4:  as kind of a slow moving product line. Over time there was a sense
Speaker 4:  of like, we, we did the thing, right? Like 10 years ago, just here's
Speaker 4:  the paper white, it's great. You're never gonna buy another one again because
Speaker 4:  you're not gonna have to. And in a certain way it was like victory for the
Speaker 4:  Kindle, right? And So I think there were people who were like, that's a great
Speaker 4:  thing. But on the other hand, also, there's other stuff happening. There
Speaker 4:  are other companies out there doing interesting things with ein and building
Speaker 4:  new kinds of things. We have, we've, we have people who like import
Speaker 4:  weird ein devices from China just to like, try what it looks like to
Speaker 4:  run Android on them. Like there's a, there's a whole
Speaker 4:  David's talking about himself. I am talking about myself, my book's. Palmer
Speaker 4:  is just outside of this room. And I, and I have a lot of questions for you.
Speaker 4:  You about it. Bring
Speaker 6:  It in here. Let me, let me evaluate. Let's do that off camera.
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. I'll take a look.
Speaker 6:  I'll help you.
Speaker 4:  But I'm curious, like in that moment you're like, okay, the Kindle is in
Speaker 4:  most ways a gigantic success for what it is. Right? Like it, it
Speaker 4:  won the thing. It was trying to win. How do we move this
Speaker 4:  along? Strikes me as kind of a complicated question. And it
Speaker 4:  also feels like, especially with something like the Scribe, you have given
Speaker 4:  the Kindle a new job to do for the first time in a really long time. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But a very focused job. Okay. A very focused job. And I think that's part
Speaker 6:  of what Kindle is. Like Kindle's all about reading and now it's about reading
Speaker 6:  and writing. And it's that simple. These are both very innate
Speaker 6:  behaviors in humans. And just stay that focused,
Speaker 6:  distraction free, create while you write, create while you read. These are
Speaker 6:  big things for me, for the team.
Speaker 6:  I'm not sure what how to think about it other than I, when you say it, I
Speaker 6:  go, you know, Kindle Kindle is a fantastic brand. I don't think it's even
Speaker 6:  near its peak.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Not even close. Not, I mean, not even close. Kendall's
Speaker 6:  also a very humble brand. I mean maybe that's why you say, oh, it
Speaker 6:  had its state. No, it's, it's, it's so meaningful to me. That's why I call
Speaker 6:  it a humble brand. So means a lot to people for sure. It it's made a difference
Speaker 6:  in their lives and still does. But here's a great example. Like If, you had
Speaker 6:  a paper wipe from four years ago. I mean, you'd love that paper White.
Speaker 6:  You do. Yeah. People love their Kindles like
Speaker 3:  Love. Yeah. But I think this would, like my wife loves her Kindle. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I'm like, do you want a new one? And her answer is basically why.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Until, and on the one
Speaker 4:  Hand you can read that is huge success. But also Absolutely.
Speaker 6:  It's rad. Yeah. Like, come on. If they're, if people are reading, let's take
Speaker 6:  it. That's a, that's a win. And why? It means it's a
Speaker 6:  robust and meaningful device and it's doing the job it was meant to do.
Speaker 6:  However, as an example, I'll challenge like, do this for me. Go
Speaker 6:  hand the new Paperweight.
Speaker 3:  I think if I hand the color one, then we'll have a different conversation.
Speaker 3:  Try both.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, try both. I think color changes the emotion.
Speaker 3:  Buy two Kindles. I I'm understanding my
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Keep buying instruction. Keep buying Kindles. No, no. Well,
Speaker 3:  But can I ask you actually a, a different variation on that question? 'cause
Speaker 3:  I, I think the answer So I think what you'll say will come out in the answer
Speaker 3:  to this question
Speaker 3:  I look at.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I don't think David actually asked a question. I think he just made
Speaker 6:  a bunch of statements there. David is like, challenge me. Is that right?
Speaker 6:  Well,
Speaker 3:  The question is, does Kindle have a lot of competition and is there an ecosystem
Speaker 3:  of things, other devices using like ing screens to drive
Speaker 3:  that technology forward? Because there hasn't been a lot of action
Speaker 3:  like Ola displays, there's a lot of action in OLA displays that technology
Speaker 3:  is relentlessly moving forward. And you can build new kinds of products around
Speaker 3:  whatever those displays can do. Kindle is like the, it's the
Speaker 3:  main product in its category. Yeah. Do you think it has a bunch of con competition
Speaker 3:  that drives it forward? Do you think that the underlying ecosystem,
Speaker 6:  I think competition's always a great thing. You have to start there. I think
Speaker 6:  it's always been, it always will be like, just makes everybody better. It's
Speaker 6:  gotta be a good thing. But I would also say like, yeah, I don't think,
Speaker 6:  you know, the, the tech is not done. It's not even close. I think there's
Speaker 6:  another level that that comes. And it's actually purposeful.
Speaker 6:  I've had had several of these arguments in the past, but you know,
Speaker 6:  LCDs have its purpose. OLED has its purpose. That line blurs quite a bit.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know, where the, what that delta might be, what the purpose is
Speaker 6:  between each and so super close.
Speaker 6:  But when you get down to ink displays and just the softer feel,
Speaker 6:  softer on the eyes, what you're getting from it, and there is something about
Speaker 6:  it that is just, is romantic.
Speaker 6:  It, they, it will, they'll stay that Delta's critical. You know, this is
Speaker 6:  for, these are noisier, this is simple. But that
Speaker 6:  simplicity doesn't mean there isn't an innovation to be had. Yeah. There's
Speaker 6:  a ton of it left. You know, and you start, you can start getting into color,
Speaker 6:  you can start getting into ink. You can start getting into speeds.
Speaker 6:  All of it is important, but it doesn't need
Speaker 6:  knee light when you're making products. You don't need these
Speaker 6:  massive leaps to change people's lives.
Speaker 6:  Sometimes it's like the most subtle difference
Speaker 6:  has the, it's like just massive impact. So let's say, let's go back
Speaker 6:  to, let's just go back to reading.
Speaker 6:  We'll use your wife as the example since you, you put it on the table. She
Speaker 6:  loves her paper white. Yeah. Is that right?
Speaker 6:  Hand her the new paper. White color's a leap. You know, there's a different
Speaker 6:  level of emotion. So it's easy to understand, hey, this is the book. This
Speaker 6:  is how the author intends you to see the cover. Or you like reading
Speaker 6:  comics or take Trevor's new book or whatever. It's a color, it's a color
Speaker 6:  book. You just, you know, read through it. It's very cool. But If, you
Speaker 6:  If you take it just to its most simple level and you hand her
Speaker 6:  the new paper white and just have her use it. I think you'll experience
Speaker 6:  something. It's just back to this point of it's a very subtle change. It's
Speaker 6:  massive change really technically. But it's a subtle change to the
Speaker 6:  user, which is basically speed of page turns. It's the first thing I noticed
Speaker 6:  when I picked up the one David has. Dude, it doesn't, it's crazy. You
Speaker 6:  hand somebody who had a 4-year-old paperweight, the new one first.
Speaker 6:  They're like, I don't need it.
Speaker 6:  And then they turn a page and they're like, don't touch this.
Speaker 6:  It's mine. Yeah. I believe it. The emotion is, it's
Speaker 6:  not because there was color, it's not because it's huge leap. It's not because
Speaker 6:  you saw it. It's subtle, but you feel it. And when
Speaker 6:  you feel it, you know this like, it's so critical. Now
Speaker 6:  all of a sudden it's like, this feels better. And while it's a massive
Speaker 6:  technology shift in the product itself under the covers on,
Speaker 6:  in many ways, it's just totally different display stack. But you're now in
Speaker 6:  this place of
Speaker 6:  Wow. The user just felt it. And I think, I don't think she
Speaker 6:  gives it back. Yeah. Especially because all your books are there. Your
Speaker 6:  content came with you, you didn't lose anything. You're not starting over.
Speaker 6:  It's very seamless. And so now you're just back into the book you were in.
Speaker 6:  Now it's just faster. And it's not like people are gonna read faster.
Speaker 6:  You just feel better. And so when you're reading and you feel great, you
Speaker 6:  you read, you just, it's better. Well
Speaker 4:  It goes back to what's so interesting about the Kindle as a product for me
Speaker 4:  is that like, from the very beginning, the Kindle was always sort
Speaker 4:  of not about itself. Like the, the less you spent thinking about your
Speaker 4:  Kindle. Yeah. The more you, it's
Speaker 6:  Like the truth in a product that disappears into the background. No,
Speaker 3:  It, hold on, I'm just gonna disagree with David. That first Kindle really
Speaker 3:  wanted you to think about
Speaker 4:  It. It did. That's fair.
Speaker 3:  That thing was like, it's remarkable
Speaker 4:  Piece. It had a joystick was a whole
Speaker 3:  Wheel though.
Speaker 6:  It was a lot going on. It a
Speaker 3:  Arrived
Speaker 3:  it
Speaker 6:  Brilliant.
Speaker 3:  First one was a little out of control. Stick to the facts.
Speaker 4:  Physical keyboard was sick though.
Speaker 6:  Stick to the facts man.
Speaker 4:  Keyboard is awesome what you're talking about. Alright, fair
Speaker 4:  enough. Once like,
Speaker 6:  Like split keyboards are are one of my favorite things on the planet.
Speaker 4:  Once somebody other than Jeff was in charge of the Kindle design, it, it,
Speaker 4:  it hit a point where, and you know, we heard this from people for a
Speaker 4:  decade that like the goal is pen and paper, right? Like that is that that
Speaker 4:  was the north star of like, it should feel like that it should crumple like
Speaker 4:  that. It should have all the properties of a thing that you don't
Speaker 4:  think about or worry about as technology. And that's I think a good
Speaker 4:  and admirable goal in a lot of ways, but also makes building the product
Speaker 4:  really hard because you're like, okay, every cool thing we build
Speaker 4:  calls more attention to this device designed to not call attention to itself.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, if the goal is to just get people reading
Speaker 4:  anything that you do that isn't open your book faster and turn the pages
Speaker 4:  faster is both an upgrade and a downgrade in the
Speaker 4:  experience. Yeah. And that just strike me as a really complicated tension
Speaker 4:  to sort through with a device
Speaker 6:  Like this. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Here's what it comes down to. Since people love the product so much, you
Speaker 6:  just have to listen to what they love. Like they love it.
Speaker 4:  Which is different than listening to what they're asking for. Correct. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Listen to what they love. And you know,
Speaker 6:  with paper white just, just listen. And at the end of the day it is, they
Speaker 6:  don't, this isn't about thinking about the Kindle, it's about thinking about
Speaker 6:  what they're reading and disappearing into it. And then you start
Speaker 6:  getting into the nuance. Like, so what do you love? Like, I just like the
Speaker 6:  way it feels. I like the way it, how much it weighs. I like what I can lean
Speaker 6:  in any posture like that I can lay by the beach.
Speaker 6:  I like that I could spill my coffee on it. Like they don't say those words,
Speaker 6:  but you start listening like, I don't know, but one time I spilled my coffee
Speaker 6:  and then I just wiped it and I kept reading and I'm like, so you like
Speaker 6:  waterproof? You know what I mean? Yeah. And I'm laying at the beach like,
Speaker 6:  you know, that we test it with salt water, you know, that you can drop this
Speaker 6:  thing in the pool. Like what? You may not know it, but that's what you love
Speaker 6:  where you can do it. And now, but the real trick is the comfort that the
Speaker 6:  product brings when you're reading. So it's not in your way. And then it
Speaker 6:  disappears. Take the new paper white, like this screen
Speaker 6:  just got subtly bigger. It's up to seven inches now, but the footprint of
Speaker 6:  the device just barely grew.
Speaker 6:  Which means you still have that perfect center of gravity when you're holding
Speaker 6:  it. You still don't think about the weight. It feels like a feather, you
Speaker 6:  know, when you're holding it and reading it disappears lighter than a book.
Speaker 6:  And you're like, you get to this point of,
Speaker 6:  I've given, you've got, you know, team's given the user more real
Speaker 6:  estate, subtle back to one of those things. And now you just, you
Speaker 6:  see more very simple. The page is turning faster,
Speaker 6:  feels pretty good and, but you haven't taken away anything they love.
Speaker 6:  You just added to it. And I think critical. But it is
Speaker 6:  a product that I think disappears into the background sans 17 years ago.
Speaker 6:  I'm not gonna, I'm not, I'm not gonna comment, bring
Speaker 3:  Back the transf reflective scroll bar on the side of the display. Let's go.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 6:  Don't know. I'm not exactly sure. But it's all about reading and it works.
Speaker 6:  It works really well now.
Speaker 3:  So there's two parts of the Kindle. David mentioned the BS Palmer, which
Speaker 3:  I believe he caused the highest spike in their sales ever.
Speaker 3:  PE people like that device, they like other ink devices 'cause of what you're
Speaker 3:  talking about, right? Younger people especially know that their phones are
Speaker 3:  distracting. They're drawn to a cheaper e ink device that offers
Speaker 3:  a more focused experience or just a black and white experience to cut down
Speaker 3:  on distraction and noise. We can't, there's a dumb phone movement out in
Speaker 3:  the world. Like there's this idea that we should just not use our phones
Speaker 3:  for everything. I see that the Palma is
Speaker 3:  a fine piece of hardware. It's like a commodity e screen. The Kindle is like
Speaker 3:  integrated, right? It's hardware, software, there's a service behind it.
Speaker 3:  When I hear people complain the most about the Kindle, it's, I am locked
Speaker 3:  into the Kindle ecosystem. I can't go to other bookstores.
Speaker 3:  PDF on this device is messy. It's hard.
Speaker 3:  Am there's not like an app store for Kindles to let you extend the capabilities
Speaker 3:  of the device. There is a little bit of a back and forth there, right? Where
Speaker 3:  they love this device. It, it offers one very singular experience that might
Speaker 3:  bring people into an ecosystem. They might love it. And then to make it do
Speaker 3:  all the rest of things you might wanna do. Like the scribe, you have to let
Speaker 3:  it go be a computer.
Speaker 6:  You gotta let it be a writing device.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  You gotta let it be a writing device. I think you got, it's a very slippery
Speaker 6:  slope though. Like once you try and get kind of too cute with features
Speaker 6:  or go too far, you start getting away from what I'm,
Speaker 6:  what we really want. Which is the analogous, you know, moving from
Speaker 6:  the Analogue to the digital and just writing on paper. It's very
Speaker 6:  dangerous. You know, once you start introducing more by the way, you can,
Speaker 6:  it's why like we added a couple of gene AI features to it. But,
Speaker 6:  but two very simple. We have a list that we have such a long list. I think
Speaker 6:  I was telling David yesterday, like the amount of features we could,
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  But I don't, I don't think it's right to con to confuse this scenario.
Speaker 6:  If, you can create some ands great. But the end of the day what you need
Speaker 6:  is fundamentally put your pen down and start writing
Speaker 6:  and as if it was paper. and we
Speaker 6:  also introduced writing on a book as If. you were writing on a book. And
Speaker 6:  so that translation's also challenging. But I think we're getting pretty,
Speaker 6:  I think we're there. I think we're close,
Speaker 3:  But you're a unique person to talk about this with because if I, I was like,
Speaker 3:  who knows the most about running a full operating system with
Speaker 3:  a pen on a piece of custom hardware.
Speaker 6:  I gotta find that person.
Speaker 3:  And then it's like, and then you've got this other thing way at the other
Speaker 3:  end of the spectrum where like you can write on a book.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Those experiences are kind of headed towards each other
Speaker 6:  A little bit. I I mean, or
Speaker 3:  The, at least with the Kindle scribe, the, the more you add capability
Speaker 3:  to it to do anything else, even if the capability is just as simple as
Speaker 3:  you can access PDFs and write on them and get your notes
Speaker 3:  out. Well now you, now you're like, here's the file system,
Speaker 6:  Which you can, which you can right now. Right? But it with the new scribe,
Speaker 3:  But not, it's still like within the Kindle world, right?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely.
Speaker 3:  There's still, there's still a bunch of abstractions there that make it
Speaker 6:  Not, and the feeling you're not gonna get the extra distractions. There's
Speaker 6:  nothing better than when you go to attach a file to an email and you're like,
Speaker 6:  oh, but let me check the web right now. Oh, let me see. I'm reading about,
Speaker 6:  I'm reading about The Verge. Oh, let's see. Like,
Speaker 3:  And that's my goal actually. Then
Speaker 6:  You're down this,
Speaker 3:  How do I get The Verge on the kennel screen? But
Speaker 4:  I think, I think that's, that's
Speaker 3:  But all the way to a surface with a pen. Yeah. Right. That's, you're, you're
Speaker 3:  on the same spectrum
Speaker 4:  Somewhere between a device that exists only for reading books and nothing
Speaker 4:  else. And
Speaker 3:  A com, like a full and
Speaker 6:  Windows purpose-built matters. Let me just say that that's what you're saying.
Speaker 6:  It does man. It does.
Speaker 4:  Do you buy that for Kindle specifically or
Speaker 6:  Specifically for Kindle? Kindle, like be careful. Like this is one of the
Speaker 6:  beautiful things. Like there's so many different things that can come together
Speaker 6:  and make magic, don't get me wrong. And how they come together makes a difference.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I agree. But I think but but in, in specifically in this space,
Speaker 6:  like
Speaker 6:  of course like don't, of course you can, you should be able to write on your
Speaker 6:  iPad or a PC or a Surface or whatever it is. Of course you should. Of
Speaker 6:  course. You know, there's things to accomplish and things to do. There might
Speaker 6:  be a job to be done.
Speaker 6:  This is purpose driven. You don't need
Speaker 6:  your paper to browse the web. You just don't. As a matter of
Speaker 6:  fact, when you're writing, that's what you need to be doing. Sometimes. If
Speaker 6:  not all the time when I'm in a meeting, I take all my notes on my
Speaker 6:  scribe. Now
Speaker 6:  it, it can't imagine trying to do it on you just don't.
Speaker 6:  It's either that or a notebook. Yeah. But it's definitely not
Speaker 6:  a full functioning computer because it just
Speaker 6:  distracts me right out.
Speaker 3:  It's impossible. So that, that part where you take all your notes on the
Speaker 3:  scribe. Yeah. And then
Speaker 6:  I also do all my morning writing on the scribe. Like I, it's why we
Speaker 6:  brought this summarized feature together. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So that's gotta go out my notes, right? I mean this is the service aspect
Speaker 3:  of it that Scribe is running some Kindle operating system.
Speaker 3:  It's running some set of gen AI features that helps you summarize and takes
Speaker 3:  the notes out. Those go up to a cloud service and then
Speaker 6:  Encrypted secure and sends it back to
Speaker 3:  Device and then they land encrypts
Speaker 6:  It on the device
Speaker 3:  Is text that you can use anywhere else. Yeah. They land
Speaker 6:  In. Yeah. So you, let's say in this case in the summarized feature, the gene
Speaker 6:  AI feature. You can, I have, I have, I don't know
Speaker 6:  so many notebooks now, but they're named by people. They're named by products.
Speaker 6:  They're named by meetings. You know, they're also, I have my morning
Speaker 6:  notes and generally it falls into one of those buckets. Unless there's a
Speaker 6:  creation bucket or an invention bucket. You know, I've got a few different
Speaker 6:  ways I laid out. But let's say there's 20 pages in a book,
Speaker 6:  one of my notebooks. Right. Those 20 pages
Speaker 6:  of notes. That's a lot. And by the way, there's something emotional about
Speaker 6:  writing. Yeah. 'cause there's recall, I remember I wrote this note right
Speaker 6:  here on this piece of paper. I know how I wrote it, I know why I wrote it.
Speaker 6:  But once you send this to the cloud, my 20 pages, it's gonna summarize
Speaker 6:  all 20. Send it back into a very simple format. Yeah. Think OCR handwriting
Speaker 6:  recognition. Sure. Take it. Look at the 20 pages, summarize,
Speaker 6:  bring it back in kind of a beautification form. Like pick the font you
Speaker 6:  wanna put it in. We got a number of them. You can make it longer or
Speaker 6:  shorter, whatever. But in very simplest form, it's two clicks comes down.
Speaker 6:  Here's a summary of all my notes. I've got a page of notes from 20 pages
Speaker 6:  written, which is powerful.
Speaker 3:  I'm just getting to, let's say AI is the platform shift. And now
Speaker 3:  instead of having one converged device on the phone, I have three devices.
Speaker 3:  I've got a paper to write on. I've got, I don't know, one of the many, many
Speaker 3:  microphone pins that David is constantly being forced to review
Speaker 3:  that he can, he can talk to all day long. And maybe, maybe I do have a phone
Speaker 3:  that is mostly a camera. Yeah. At some point I want all those things to talk
Speaker 3:  to each other. And the idea that my AI
Speaker 3:  pin does not know about the notes I took on my Amazon scribe
Speaker 3:  does not know about a email I read on my
Speaker 3:  laptop actually creates like the
Speaker 3:  desire for me to have more lock in. Right. So like fine, I'm just gonna buy
Speaker 3:  it all from one vendor. My phone already my, the phone company is already
Speaker 3:  selling me everything. How do you break that? Like do you, is it more
Speaker 3:  interoperability? Is it extending the Kindle operating system
Speaker 3:  to do more and more things?
Speaker 6:  No, I don't think it's that. I think, I think there's, I think interoperability
Speaker 6:  is a great thing. Yeah. And you, you know, you, you can find it, you can
Speaker 6:  find you can remove seams. Yeah. Between different oss for sure.
Speaker 6:  I don't really lose a lot of sleep over it. I also know that within the device
Speaker 6:  family that Amazon builds, like that'll all
Speaker 6:  continue because of AI become more seamless. Yeah. Back to 0.1, like the
Speaker 6:  opportunities off the charts. But I don't think you wanna lock it all in.
Speaker 6:  I think you still need the interoperability as well. So they're, I think
Speaker 6:  they both matter
Speaker 6:  and I think it's different for every person. Like you're gonna end up in
Speaker 6:  a place where you love a certain set of devices. I
Speaker 6:  don't think you're gonna have five in your bag, but if there's a purpose-built
Speaker 6:  device that you do need, you're gonna take it with you man. Makes a difference.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You're gonna need that connectivity. But don't, don't be confused.
Speaker 6:  All your notes on your Kindle today show up on your iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Like on the Kindle app. It's right there. Yeah. Seamless. That integration's
Speaker 6:  pretty awesome. And eventually you'll have editing those docs on your iPhone
Speaker 6:  too, I'm sure. But so like, not to give away the future roadmap, but I, I
Speaker 6:  don't think there's a limit to that. So I don't, when you say it, it doesn't
Speaker 6:  resonate as much for me because we do believe in interoperability. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We do wanna see it, you know, we see our products on all the other platforms
Speaker 6:  and in a way that's useful for customers where it matters to them. Not just
Speaker 6:  to do it or to check a box, but that it matters. I
Speaker 4:  Have one more question then we actually do need to let you go 'cause you
Speaker 4:  have other things to
Speaker 6:  Do. I do. It turns out you,
Speaker 4:  You were talking about the the sort of dedicated device
Speaker 4:  and the
Speaker 6:  Isn't it at some point, doesn't my team, doesn't our team save me at some
Speaker 6:  point
Speaker 4:  We're in this moment of like the supposed
Speaker 4:  disintermediation of the smartphone, right? There's like, we for years now,
Speaker 4:  companies are like, what is the thing that comes after phones and like digital
Speaker 4:  cameras are making a comeback. Everybody's buying cool pys from 20 years
Speaker 4:  ago again. Are they big trend? That's cool. You've been through
Speaker 4:  like, you've been making products through the whole rise and
Speaker 4:  sort of dominance of the smartphone. And you mentioned, you know, the Kindle
Speaker 4:  is a distraction for you device. It's been that thing for a long time. It's
Speaker 4:  been successful for a long time. Do you buy the like, big picture
Speaker 4:  trend here that we we shoved everything into a phone
Speaker 4:  and the next phase is like pulling it all back out again?
Speaker 6:  No, no. I don't buy that all.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I didn't know that was the big picture trend. There
Speaker 4:  Are a lot of people who would like you to believe that it is. I'm not sure
Speaker 4:  there they do any of them are everybody who
Speaker 6:  Wants to make, tell me, are they really important people? 'cause
Speaker 4:  Anybody who's not Google and Apple would really like that to be the case.
Speaker 4:  'cause that's a really great way for them to get around app store taxes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I mean I, I think If, you believe AI is a platform shift and you,
Speaker 6:  AI is a platform shift. There's no question.
Speaker 3:  But then, so then you can control and you kind of use your interface, right?
Speaker 3:  I mean, that's the heart of it. Sure. And then maybe you can get people to
Speaker 3:  stop using
Speaker 6:  Their phone. Yeah. But I don't think the phone's going away. Yeah. Like all,
Speaker 6:  everything you said was right. I think the and then part was odd.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, look, phone's a
Speaker 6:  incredible utility in the product you have in your pocket right now. Probably
Speaker 6:  is probably a great product. I, and it has its purpose and form.
Speaker 6:  I do think jobs are gonna move off the phone,
Speaker 6:  but I don't think the phone goes away. I think we can make some magical
Speaker 6:  products that have literally nothing to do with the phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And we're going to, I mean that's, that's why I'm here at Amazon.
Speaker 6:  Like, go back to your first question. That is why I'm here at Amazon.
Speaker 6:  Like, no question. Like we can, the
Speaker 6:  opportunity to make magic with the through line of ai, as you said earlier,
Speaker 6:  that's not fake. Yeah. That is a platform shift. But to get a silly
Speaker 6:  to say, you know, I remember 12 years ago when
Speaker 6:  13, so years ago when I, we had started surface. Lemme just give you an analogy.
Speaker 6:  Not that I wanna go back there. There were so many
Speaker 6:  people that told me the laptop is dead.
Speaker 6:  I mean, what are you doing? It's over. The phone has replaced it. That's,
Speaker 6:  that was the meme 13 years ago. And
Speaker 6:  that's not what was happening. Now what was happening is certain jobs were
Speaker 6:  moving to the phone, just shopping's great on the phone.
Speaker 6:  Social media is incredible on the phone, taking photos off the phone, pretty
Speaker 6:  damn good. Texting, communicating.
Speaker 6:  But then the jobs on the laptop just got stronger, which is
Speaker 6:  interesting. The jobs that had to be done on it, you know, walk into
Speaker 6:  any meeting and everybody opens their laptop. It's just what they do.
Speaker 6:  And in many places you can do a lot on your phone. But
Speaker 6:  what it's not that the PC was dying in. It's analogous now.
Speaker 6:  So take that analogy.
Speaker 6:  Same thing now. I think jobs are gonna move off the phone.
Speaker 6:  I think there's probably better products and I know there is that are coming,
Speaker 6:  you know, products that will bring more seamless,
Speaker 6:  more seamlessness for ai, make it more useful for people.
Speaker 6:  I mean I, you know, I might be working on some of those products right now
Speaker 6:  if it turns out, you know, where we started. I, I believe that.
Speaker 6:  I don't only believe it. I know it's, and I, and I know it's right for customers,
Speaker 6:  like for people, but to say it's going away. Come on. That's just,
Speaker 6:  that's silly. It just, I think jobs do move though. Does that analogy make
Speaker 6:  sense? Like the phone's aren't going away. Yeah. That screen in your pocket,
Speaker 6:  that's not the point. However, will they, will certain jobs move and be
Speaker 6:  better somewhere else? I think yeah, for sure. Now is
Speaker 6:  there a world where everyone has a hundred devices in their back? No, no,
Speaker 6:  no, no. But you know, some jobs move to your wrist and they're better
Speaker 6:  there. Some jobs stay in your pocket and they're better there. Some jobs
Speaker 6:  will be on your eyes. They're better there. And you know,
Speaker 6:  once that back to your seamless operations, like a
Speaker 6:  lot of things will be ambient devices where voice is powerful.
Speaker 6:  You know, I know a few of those things. We got over a hundred million people
Speaker 6:  using 'em right now. Like, jobs are gonna move there and they're gonna be
Speaker 6:  awesome. And by the way, unbelievably powerful jobs.
Speaker 6:  And you're gonna see it on devices that my team's building. Like literally,
Speaker 6:  I'm not supposed to talk about it. I gotta see my team's like, oh, don't
Speaker 6:  talk about it, don't you? Hold on, slow down on your, you know, I'm
Speaker 6:  so, stop hinting at Echo and Alexa, stop it. Like, but let's be clear. Like
Speaker 6:  there's reality between bringing together all these things. It's why I'm
Speaker 6:  here working with this amazing team at Amazon, man. Like, and I'm telling
Speaker 6:  you that product makers at Amazon are so good.
Speaker 6:  And so you, you just, there's this opportunity to pull, to
Speaker 6:  pull a lot of things together. But then go back to your original point. I'm
Speaker 6:  not, I'm not sitting here as a, you know,
Speaker 6:  as part of this industry saying yes. And the phone is going away. Like,
Speaker 6:  no, come on. Silly. Yeah, silly. Couldn't get me to say that about
Speaker 6:  technologies that matter every day in our lives. I, I might be wrong. Maybe
Speaker 6:  be happy to be proven wrong. It's fine by me. You know, we got other options.
Speaker 6:  But
Speaker 3:  Do you think AI
Speaker 3:  Yeah, this
Speaker 6:  Is great. Thanks guys. It was a lot of fun.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back The lightning round.
Speaker 3:  This, this week. I sent Slacks about getting the lightning round
Speaker 3:  sponsored.
Speaker 4:  Whoa, did they accomplish anything? How rich are we now?
Speaker 3:  I will say we, there were some very creative ideas that are still not
Speaker 3:  the idea of just having us say the lightning round is sponsor. Mm.
Speaker 3:  If you've got a company with the word lightning in it, boy do they want to
Speaker 3:  talk to you?
Speaker 4:  Sure.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's a lot. We're working on it. Again, I have no
Speaker 3:  ability or sophistication or experience in selling ads,
Speaker 3:  so I'm just, my job is to just say it every week. It's just
Speaker 3:  speak
Speaker 4:  Advertising into existence is
Speaker 3:  Definitely our works. Someone else with some money show up and someone here,
Speaker 3:  we'll figure it out.
Speaker 4:  I hope it's like the Tampa Bay Lightning, the, the NHL team that eventually
Speaker 4:  sponsors the lightning round. Cool. That,
Speaker 3:  That's, that's basically where we're at. And I was like, I don't, it doesn't
Speaker 3:  have to, to be that complicated, like sponsored by George I think would
Speaker 3:  work at this point.
Speaker 4:  I like that. George,
Speaker 3:  Your name is George and you can write a check. Call us up. It's some number.
Speaker 3:  I don't know how it works. I don't know. If, you can call us up to buy an
Speaker 3:  ad. Anyway, there's kind of a lot in this lightning round.
Speaker 4:  There is,
Speaker 3:  You take the first one.
Speaker 4:  All right, so this happened today, Thursday, as we're recording,
Speaker 4:  Google announced some pretty big org chart
Speaker 4:  shifts. And this is the thing we've kind of been tracking all year. Google
Speaker 4:  has been pretty aggressively changing the way the company
Speaker 4:  works, partly in order to just Ai I
Speaker 4:  everything. But I think partly because Google has changed a lot as
Speaker 4:  a company. And you have a lot of people who've been there a long time who
Speaker 4:  maybe don't wanna be there anymore or are just tapped out on what
Speaker 4:  they've been doing for a long time. And so like, it's just changing a lot.
Speaker 4:  And the new one that happened on Thursday was that
Speaker 4:  PBA Raghavan who has run search ads,
Speaker 4:  several other things, but mostly he, he is I would say the single most important
Speaker 4:  person in terms of how Google makes money and has been for a very long time,
Speaker 4:  is now stepping down from that role and is becoming Google's, I think the
Speaker 4:  title is chief technologist.
Speaker 4:  What's the nice way to say this? That title doesn't mean anything. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's like, this is what I mean, we, we went through this with Hiroshi
Speaker 4:  Lockheimer, right? Who was like, I'm not leaving Google, I'm just gonna go
Speaker 4:  take on other roles. And that's all fine and good. They're going to continue
Speaker 4:  to be interesting, important people inside of Google. But like the way
Speaker 4:  that Google works is If, you don't run a thing. You don't run a thing. You
Speaker 4:  know what I mean? And, and So I think the idea of being chief technologist,
Speaker 4:  it will be big and interesting and he'll like show up at conferences every
Speaker 4:  once in a while. But like, it is, it is super meaningful that he's leaving
Speaker 4:  the search team, which is
Speaker 3:  The team, the most important team under the most pressure,
Speaker 3:  right? Both from regulators and open ai, whatever.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it is, it is the thing. And to that point, actually, the person who
Speaker 4:  is taking over that job is Nick Fox, who has been
Speaker 4:  at Google for like forever. And a thing
Speaker 4:  that I've heard internally over the years is that Nick is one of a very small
Speaker 4:  number of people who Sundar Pache believes are like his fixers.
Speaker 4:  He is the person who is tapped to like make a thing work. He had
Speaker 4:  to do it with messaging, which I, I'm David,
Speaker 3:  I would, I would just say your evidence does not support your claim.
Speaker 4:  No, but so yes, except RCS has
Speaker 4:  worked. Google Messages is now everywhere. Like to the extent
Speaker 4:  that Nick Fox had to solve an impossible problem, he actually did a pretty
Speaker 4:  good job. He ran assistant for a long time. He has, he
Speaker 4:  I think was one of the, who launched Google Phi, like
Speaker 4:  hits and misses. But, but he is a guy who has been tapped to do some of
Speaker 4:  Google's most important, most ambitious things at various times.
Speaker 4:  And So I think it's telling that he is showing up as the one,
Speaker 4:  he's not like a grizzled search executive, right? Like there are lots of
Speaker 4:  people inside of search who've been working inside of search for a long time.
Speaker 4:  He is a guy coming from another part of the company to presumably
Speaker 4:  change the way that search operates, which I think is very interesting. Then
Speaker 4:  the other big change is that the whole Gemini
Speaker 4:  division is now going under DeepMind DeepMind and Demi
Speaker 4:  Ava who runs DeepMind is just ruthlessly consolidating
Speaker 4:  AI power inside of Google. Demis just won a Nobel prize,
Speaker 4:  which is bananas. Like kudos to them for some of the
Speaker 4:  protein stuff that they've been doing. It's really cool. But like
Speaker 4:  piece by piece, every AI thing Google has been doing
Speaker 4:  has come under Demis and DeepMind and
Speaker 3:  Except for Google Assistant, which is going to platforms and devices,
Speaker 3:  which
Speaker 4:  Is I think a sign that Google Assistant is dying, right? Like Google Assistant
Speaker 4:  is going to be how you turn Bluetooth on and off on your phone and everything
Speaker 4:  else is gonna be Gemini. Like, that's, that's so clear where that's going
Speaker 4:  to be.
Speaker 3:  So that's the Rick Oslo group, that's the Pixel group and the Android group.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's right. That is that group.
Speaker 3:  So that is just fascinating.
Speaker 4:  I that I, I actually think that makes perfect sense, right? That means that
Speaker 4:  becomes a, a feature of Android, not an AI thing
Speaker 3:  Or the home hub stuff.
Speaker 4:  Sure. It's a, it's a way to turn things on and off on your devices, which
Speaker 4:  is fine. Like you actually don't need AI to, but
Speaker 3:  Isn't the future of Google Assistant the future of Gemini, aren't they the
Speaker 3:  same thing?
Speaker 4:  No. Which is what's super annoying about using Android right now, because
Speaker 4:  Gemini can't do the things on your phone. Oh, oh yeah, but this is Google.
Speaker 4:  Like, come on. I mean, give it a minute and it'll all get rolled under Demis
Speaker 4:  at they'll this point anyway.
Speaker 3:  So what I take from this is actually no one knows how to organize these companies,
Speaker 3:  right? You're announcing a new chief technologist at your company. What is
Speaker 3:  the most important technology in the future of Google?
Speaker 3:  It's ai. Yeah. Is your new chief technologist gonna No, he's gonna
Speaker 3:  run right into your CEO of ai, the guy who just won a Nobel Prize.
Speaker 4:  Well, this is the problem with ai, right? Like If, you believe AI is,
Speaker 4:  is the future. It AI is everything. It's your infrastructure, it's
Speaker 4:  products, it's the like InBetween stuff that enables all this stuff.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's everything. AI is the whole stack, and
Speaker 4:  all these companies are putting someone in charge of ai, which is like, not
Speaker 4:  the same as making them the CEO of the company, but it's also not that different.
Speaker 3:  Well, So I mean, I would just compare and contrast to Microsoft, which has
Speaker 3:  now largely the same structure. Google has moved itself to the same
Speaker 3:  kind of structure as Microsoft. So Microsoft had Kevin Scott,
Speaker 3:  who's a CTO, famously still the person at Microsoft. He told me this
Speaker 3:  on decoder. Kevin Scott owns the GPU budget at Microsoft. Mm.
Speaker 3:  If you wanna buy a GPU, you gotta call Kevin. What? How do you
Speaker 3:  make yourself the most powerful person in the company?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's that's
Speaker 3:  Real. So he was the CTO, he was the one who did
Speaker 3:  a bunch of the opening, like early work to do the opening ideal. He was like,
Speaker 3:  figured it out. But then Microsoft, all the open
Speaker 3:  AI drama happened and Microsoft went out and sort of like just acquired
Speaker 3:  the talent from inflection. And now Mustafa Soliman is the CEO of AI at
Speaker 3:  Microsoft, and they have a CTO in Kevin Scottsdale that is just a complicated
Speaker 3:  org chart and it looks exactly like this.
Speaker 4:  Yep. A hundred percent.
Speaker 3:  And so you're just ending, these companies are starting to, they're trying
Speaker 3:  to figure out how to structure themselves to make all this work. And
Speaker 3:  the, the only difference to me is that Google's
Speaker 3:  business is under such regulatory threat that a bunch of people
Speaker 3:  are, I think are kind of choosing to bail instead of taking
Speaker 3:  the next turn.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, and again, even If, you think Google might come out of all
Speaker 4:  this regulatory stuff unscathed, it's gonna take so long. And
Speaker 4:  if I'm provocate raghavan, like, do you wanna sit and twiddle your
Speaker 4:  thumbs for the better part of the decade until all this antitrust stuff gets
Speaker 4:  sorted out? Or do you just wanna like dip and go work on other problems?
Speaker 4:  I kind of get it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They, they did all that consolidation. Android, Android and Google
Speaker 3:  is filing emergency motions with the court in the Epic case today to
Speaker 3:  delay opening up Android to other stores. Do you wanna do that or do you
Speaker 3:  just wanna wander the earth,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah. All right. What's yours?
Speaker 3:  Weird. I actually have more Google stuff. Oh, do you? But it's also Trump
Speaker 3:  stuff, and I, I apologize. Oh no, it's election season. Oh God. Trump
Speaker 3:  is talking a lot
Speaker 3:  And people are mad at us for covering this stuff, but, you know, there's
Speaker 3:  a, a meaningful chance he, he could win. And I would just point out
Speaker 3:  that we, we, we live through the tech policy of a first Trump administration,
Speaker 3:  which was bananas. I I've been made to
Speaker 3:  remember it recently, which I'm very upset about. Do you remember when I
Speaker 3:  just counted days since Trump announced Google would build a website for
Speaker 3:  Coronavirus testing like every week? Like that's where we're at again.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Only this time he hates the tech companies
Speaker 3:  like JD Vance's answer to, did Donald Trump lose the election
Speaker 3:  is not yes or no, it's big tech interfered with the Hunter Biden
Speaker 3:  laptop story. Right? Which is not an answer,
Speaker 4:  But they're pro TikTok now,
Speaker 3:  But they're pro So none of this makes any sense, by the way, that's not an
Speaker 3:  answer. Like, you can be upset that people did or did not have
Speaker 3:  information. That does not mean that their votes don't count.
Speaker 3:  Right? Like I think a lot of people who voted for Hillary Clinton are pretty
Speaker 3:  mad that New York Times chose to make the word emails
Speaker 3:  incredibly relevant to everyone, such that The Verge dot com sells a
Speaker 3:  T-shirt that just says emails on it. But that doesn't mean their votes
Speaker 3:  didn't count. Yep. And so that whole Vance line of attack is nonsensical.
Speaker 3:  But it, what it's pointed at is we're, we're all mad at tech companies. So
Speaker 3:  Trump is on stage
Speaker 3:  at the Economic club of Chicago, being interviewed by John
Speaker 3:  Michelate, who's the editor-in-chief of Bloomberg News. John Michel, wait
Speaker 3:  is a very proper British man. He used to be the editor-in-Chief of the Economist.
Speaker 3:  He is not a guff taking
Speaker 3:  kind of dude. No. Do you
Speaker 4:  Know what I mean? Yeah. He's not, he's not a, a shenanigans kind of guy.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I, you know, I know a lot of EICs.
Speaker 3:  This isn't the one that is having a party on the boat, you know, I'm just
Speaker 3:  putting out. But there are other ones that are, I'm not gonna say who they
Speaker 3:  are, but if you're on my list, you're on my list. You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 3:  Okay. So John Michel Way is interviewing Donald Trump
Speaker 3:  and he says the Department of Justice wants to break up Google, what do you
Speaker 3:  think? And then Trump just says some
Speaker 3:  stuff
Speaker 3:  and all of it adds up to I wanna do some speech regulations.
Speaker 3:  Lemme just, I'm just gonna read it to you. Trump says, yeah, look,
Speaker 3:  Google's got a lot of power. They're very bad to me, very, very bad to me.
Speaker 3:  I can speak from that standpoint. They only have bad stories.
Speaker 3:  In other words, I have 20 good stories and 20 bad stories. Everyone's entitled
Speaker 3:  to that. You only see the 20 bad stories. I called the head of Google
Speaker 3:  the other day and I said I'm getting a lot of good stories lately, but you
Speaker 3:  don't find them in Google. I think it's a whole rigged deal. I think
Speaker 3:  Google's rigged just like our government's rigged all over the place.
Speaker 3:  Confusing. Yeah. So I. Think what he's talking about is if
Speaker 3:  there are 20 stories about good stuff Trump has done and 20 stories about
Speaker 3:  bad stuff Trump has done and you search for Donald Trump's name in Google
Speaker 3:  News, you only get the negative stories.
Speaker 3:  Presu, presumably. That is,
Speaker 4:  I believe that is what he's talking about.
Speaker 3:  And he called up, presumably Sundar Phai, and complained about this.
Speaker 3:  That is just core First Amendment activity. Maybe he
Speaker 4:  Called PBA and Bakker was like, I'm done with this. I'm out. Nevermind.
Speaker 3:  I don't know man. That is just, that is just straightforward. First amendment
Speaker 3:  protected activity. Yeah. We're gonna rank some stories.
Speaker 3:  You're gonna type in a search term and we're gonna show you a list of them.
Speaker 3:  And maybe you think Google should be more neutral, but
Speaker 3:  If, you wanna do something about it. You're gonna, you in this country
Speaker 3:  will run straight into the First Amendment and these companies have won
Speaker 3:  multiple cases asserting their first memo, right? Yep. So
Speaker 3:  then he pivots this conversation with Google to China and he says, I do something.
Speaker 3:  But you have to give them a lot of credit. They've become such a power, such
Speaker 3:  a power. You have to give 'em credit. How they became a power is really a
Speaker 3:  discussion. Is that an antitrust argument? I don't know. And then he says,
Speaker 3:  at the same time, it's a very dangerous thing because we want have great
Speaker 3:  companies. We don't want China to have these companies. Right now China
Speaker 3:  is afraid of Google. And then, and
Speaker 3:  then he says China is a very powerful, very smart group of
Speaker 3:  people.
Speaker 4:  I'm really glad you read that part. I was gonna make you read that part.
Speaker 4:  If you didn't otherwise, which
Speaker 3:  Is a great way to describe a country. Yeah. What is a country
Speaker 3:  So, I don't know man. Like is China
Speaker 3:  afraid of Google? A company that doesn't operate in China? I is he
Speaker 3:  talking about ai? I, I tru I, I've like
Speaker 3:  been trying to parse this for some time. So then Michel wait says, well if
Speaker 3:  you're afraid of China, China, you wanted to ban TikTok and now you're
Speaker 3:  gonna let TikTok operate in this country. And
Speaker 3:  I don't know, Trump just kind of just pivoted this
Speaker 3:  conversation. 'cause Michael Fright said, is TikTok a threat? And
Speaker 3:  Trump goes, I think it is a threat. Frankly. I think everything is a threat.
Speaker 3:  There's nothing that's not a threat.
Speaker 4:  We should put that on a T-shirt.
Speaker 3:  But sometimes you fight through the threats like Google, I'm not a fan of
Speaker 3:  Google. They treat me badly. But are you gonna destroy the company by doing
Speaker 3:  that If, you do that. Are you gonna destroy the com company? What you can
Speaker 3:  do without breaking it up is make sure it's more
Speaker 3:  fair. And then he ends with,
Speaker 3:  and it's only bad because of fake news because the news is really fake. That's
Speaker 3:  the one thing we have to straighten out. We have to straighten out the press
Speaker 3:  because we have a corrupt press
Speaker 3:  that all of that is speech regulations. Yeah. I want to make Google
Speaker 3:  more fair. That's a content moderation law. And we're gonna pass
Speaker 3:  a law insisting that Google is fair. I don't know how you do that. And then
Speaker 3:  we're gonna straighten out the press
Speaker 3:  how write the, like if you're mad at me for saying those, you
Speaker 3:  write, go ahead, write the law. Right? That straightens out the press put
Speaker 3:  in, involve the government in that process. Just
Speaker 4:  In the course of that, he drills all the way down to, actually the problem
Speaker 4:  is not fix Google, it's fix the people who are writing
Speaker 4:  the stories about Google or about me that get posted on
Speaker 4:  Google. Like it just, I don't know, If, you think
Speaker 4:  too hard about it. Your brain sort of explodes. But the, these are things
Speaker 4:  he said out loud.
Speaker 3:  And apparently he's Colin, CEO. So then the other story is
Speaker 3:  today he said Tim Cook called him.
Speaker 3:  So I'm just gonna read you this quote. He's on one of the many, many bro
Speaker 3:  podcasts that he's been going on lately. Like this man's on YouTube. Like
Speaker 3:  who's on YouTube? It's Mr. Beast. Logan Paul. It's Donald Trump. Like he's
Speaker 3:  just real. If you've got a YouTube bro podcast, call him up. He's ready to
Speaker 3:  go. So he is on one today, the PBD podcast. Please don't get mad at
Speaker 3:  me if you're like some huge YouTube fan of this podcast. I've never heard
Speaker 3:  of it before. This is what I'm telling you. And I'm looking at the thumbnail
Speaker 3:  here and I'm describing it as I'm describing it. He's on this podcast today
Speaker 3:  and he says, two hours ago, three hours ago, he cook called me. He
Speaker 3:  said, the European Union has just fined us $15 billion. On top of that, they
Speaker 3:  got fined by the European Union, another $2 billion, which is
Speaker 3:  true in March, the EU find Apple 2 billion
Speaker 3:  after finding that Apple was restricting music apps in some way.
Speaker 3:  And then they basically said, apple, it needs to pay 14.4 billion in
Speaker 3:  unpaid taxes. Totally different things. Yeah, totally different fines. And
Speaker 3:  then Trump goes on to say he cook said something that was interesting. He
Speaker 3:  said, they're using that to run their enterprise, meaning Europe is their
Speaker 3:  enterprise. And then he said, that's a lot, Tim, but I have to get elected
Speaker 3:  first, but I won't let them take advantage of our companies. That won't be
Speaker 3:  happening.
Speaker 4:  What?
Speaker 3:  Okay, first of all, I love the idea that either Tim Cook or Donald Trump
Speaker 3:  thinks that it costs $15 billion to run the eu.
Speaker 3:  I'm like, very good. The most efficient government in world history. That
Speaker 3:  would be great.
Speaker 3:  Unclear how any us politician
Speaker 3:  can negotiate tax rates in other
Speaker 3:  countries. That's just a, that's just a thing. Like if
Speaker 3:  Germany showed up on our doorstep and it was like, we've got some ideas about
Speaker 3:  your tax. Like we wouldn't, we wish wouldn't do it. I
Speaker 3:  don't know. I'd be like, go away Germany,
Speaker 3:  American flag. Like, get outta here. So, I.
Speaker 3:  That's confusing. Yeah. Maybe, maybe there's something the president can
Speaker 3:  do. In that case,
Speaker 3:  the weirder thing is, he just said it. He said,
Speaker 3:  you know, in the Google case, he said, I called the head of Google and I
Speaker 3:  said, some outlandish nonsense. Okay. We, we asked Google, they didn't say
Speaker 3:  anything. But that's Trump's claim that he called, and maybe he's lying in
Speaker 3:  this one. He says, cook called him to complain about EU
Speaker 3:  regulations, which is a very interesting thing to, for Tim Cook to have done.
Speaker 3:  He put a timeframe on it. He said three hours ago he called me. So
Speaker 3:  we know approximately when that's today as we're speaking.
Speaker 3:  And so we asked Apple about this. Apple flatly doesn't respond.
Speaker 3:  I will tell you, we talk to Apple a lot. We send a lot of notes to a lot
Speaker 3:  of companies. Hey, did this happen? Hey, we need a statement. Hey, here's
Speaker 3:  this thing. Hey, I have a lot of thoughts about your iPhone camera. We
Speaker 3:  we talk to these companies a lot. Yeah. Dead silence. I don't know what it
Speaker 3:  means. I I can't, I'm not gonna interpret it. I'm just saying it is, there's
Speaker 3:  not, I don't have to like go to a magistrate judge and file a form
Speaker 3:  in triplicate to get a comment from a big tech company, right? Like, this
Speaker 3:  is the thing that we do all the way. So they just didn't respond.
Speaker 3:  I don't, I I don't know how to interpret this one.
Speaker 4:  I don't either. It's very, it's very odd. I mean, I think to some
Speaker 4:  extent the idea that a lot of tech CEOs
Speaker 4:  are somewhere between actively
Speaker 4:  rooting for a Trump presidency and hedging their bets in case he
Speaker 4:  wins by, you know, sucking up to him in various
Speaker 4:  ways. That's real. That's it happened the last time he was
Speaker 4:  president. It, it seems pretty clearly it's happening now. Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook is not the like jump on stage at a rally. Tim
Speaker 3:  Cook opened a fake factory for Donald Trump. Do you remember this?
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean. Like this is not,
Speaker 3:  He was like, they're making iPhones and Macs in America again, right? And
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook was like, we've sure come to this factory where we've been doing
Speaker 3:  it for some time. This
Speaker 4:  Is what I mean, right? So like it's, it wouldn't be
Speaker 4:  completely out of character for Tim Cook to have done that essentially as
Speaker 4:  like a make the man feel good, right? Like it, that is the, the
Speaker 4:  overwhelming advice on how to get things out of Donald Trump
Speaker 4:  is, is flatter him. And so to call him and be like, Donald,
Speaker 4:  WTF, you're up. Am I right? It is like, I can see why you would make that
Speaker 4:  phone call if you're, if you're Tim Cook. I also can see a
Speaker 4:  series of ways in which this story is not true and why Apple
Speaker 4:  would decide that there is literally no upside to responding at all. So again,
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm in a, I'm in the same place of like, I don't know what to make of
Speaker 4:  this all the way on the spectrum from none of this happened to, this happened
Speaker 4:  exactly the way that he describes. I don't know how to interpret any of the
Speaker 4:  possible outcomes. It's bananas.
Speaker 3:  I do love the idea that Tim Cook was like, they run Europe on my taxes.
Speaker 3:  And it's like, well first of all, they're mad at you because you haven't
Speaker 3:  paid them. Right?
Speaker 4:  They actually don't. And that's the problem.
Speaker 3:  To be clear,
Speaker 3:  So I, I don't think that's enough to run Europe. I, you know, I've never
Speaker 3:  run Europe before. I've imagined it as all children in the Midwest do.
Speaker 3:  And it just, I, my budget was higher as I, when I was working out in high
Speaker 3:  school in Wisconsin. I was like, I think it's gonna take like one or two
Speaker 3:  trail to run Europe.
Speaker 3:  Again, not an economist. I didn't have any formal training at the time. I
Speaker 3:  just think it's more than 14.4. We'll, see, we asked all these companies
Speaker 3:  to respond to this. I will say that, that the two comments
Speaker 3:  run right into each other, right? If you're Apple and you're mad at Europe,
Speaker 3:  you're probably also mad at the United States Department of Justice for filing
Speaker 3:  an antitrust case against you. And Donald Trump is here
Speaker 3:  saying something has to be done about Google, which just lost its big
Speaker 3:  antitrust case at the United States Department of Justice. The main
Speaker 3:  result of which is that Google's gonna stop paying Apple the money to be
Speaker 3:  the default search provider on the iPhone. So
Speaker 3:  it's just kind of all the same problem. And
Speaker 3:  Trump is Trump and he, I think he likes Tim Cook and is mad at
Speaker 3:  Google search.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Two easy things to be right now if you're, if you're Donald Trump,
Speaker 4:  you know what I mean?
Speaker 3:  And really that man is searching for the simplest one. All right,
Speaker 3:  let's end with, let's end with Anthropic and ai. 'cause I think we should
Speaker 3:  end with a vision of utopia. What's going on with this one?
Speaker 4:  Okay, so, so Dario Am who is the, the CEO of Anthropic
Speaker 4:  wrote, I think it's, it's, it's either 13,000 or 14,000
Speaker 4:  words. It's so many words. My man wrote like a short book
Speaker 4:  basically making the case for ai.
Speaker 4:  And I think it, it's particularly interesting that he's doing this because
Speaker 4:  a Sam Altman recently wrote his sort of opus about why
Speaker 4:  AI is gonna make everything wonderful. And Anthropic in a lot of ways has
Speaker 4:  been kind of a, a tonal counter to open
Speaker 4:  ai that they've been much quieter about what they're building. They've
Speaker 4:  been much less utopian, they've been much more concerned with security. They've
Speaker 4:  talked a much more like realistic game about what they're doing.
Speaker 4:  But as, as Kylie Robinson on our team pointed out, they
Speaker 4:  also need to raise astounding amounts of money in order to do
Speaker 4:  any of the stuff that they want to do. And it's much harder to raise money
Speaker 4:  on like a careful case for why this stuff might be interesting than it is
Speaker 4:  to just say out loud, I am building God. Right? Like Kylie has just been
Speaker 4:  running around the newsroom being like, this is why they're doing this. And
Speaker 4:  I think she's right. And so what Dario did here basically was,
Speaker 4:  right, a more reasoned
Speaker 4:  but still like wildly outrageously optimistic
Speaker 4:  vision for what AI can be. And I think, and
Speaker 4:  I think a lot of it is about the stuff that doesn't get talked
Speaker 4:  about a lot when we talk about ai, which I actually really appreciate. People
Speaker 4:  should read this. It's, it's this and Steven
Speaker 4:  Wolfram's thing about how chat GPT works from like two years ago are two
Speaker 4:  very instructive primers on like what is going on in this space. And I think
Speaker 4:  everybody should read both of them. They're both incredibly long, but they're
Speaker 4:  very good. And he just, I'll just read you the five things that he
Speaker 4:  says are the categories he's most excited about. It's biology and physical
Speaker 4:  health, neuroscience and mental health, economic development and poverty,
Speaker 4:  peace and governance work. And meaning first of all, that's everything.
Speaker 4:  It's all the things. It's
Speaker 3:  Just, that's, that's Europe and If. you have If,
Speaker 4:  You Europe pays
Speaker 3:  14.4. You too can,
Speaker 4:  But he makes a bunch of interesting cases and I think does a good job of
Speaker 4:  explaining like, here is what it's gonna take to get to
Speaker 4:  this. That we need AI that is sufficiently powerful and has
Speaker 4:  lots of different interfaces. And you can poke holes in all of this because
Speaker 4:  none of it exists. Most of it is going to be wildly difficult. And
Speaker 4:  he just says there's a line where he just says in it, it has all the interfaces
Speaker 4:  available to a human working virtually as if that's just like a, like a feature
Speaker 4:  you can ship tomorrow. So I. I take this less as
Speaker 4:  a real roadmap towards anything and more just like an actually really
Speaker 4:  thoughtful idea about what AI could be in the
Speaker 4:  absolute best case. And in that way it's a, it's a really good
Speaker 4:  read. He talks a lot about what it could mean for medicine and what it could
Speaker 4:  mean for how we interact with each other and with technology. And we've talked
Speaker 4:  a lot about like the relationships people are building with AI characters.
Speaker 4:  He mentions that kind of stuff. There's a lot of stuff in here and you get
Speaker 4:  to the end and you're like, hell yeah, ai, let's go. And then it's like,
Speaker 4:  oh, there's, there's other things. And also none of this exists or
Speaker 4:  probably will anytime soon. And that's where we land. And the thing I've
Speaker 4:  seen most people say about this is like, even if he's right about all of
Speaker 4:  this, his timelines are off by orders of magnitude and So, I think If, you
Speaker 4:  go into it thinking with that perspective. I actually think this is a super
Speaker 4:  fun read.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's funny. 'cause right next to it is the New York Times warning
Speaker 3:  perplexity to stop using its content, right? And it's like kind of all of
Speaker 3:  this is built on just like taking everything. Yeah. Like all of the
Speaker 3:  electricity and all of the content,
Speaker 3:  all of the money. And it's like you had, I guess you in
Speaker 3:  return you have to promise digital God.
Speaker 4:  I mean, and and to
Speaker 3:  Be clear, but what is worth all of that taking? And it's
Speaker 4:  Like what this does promise is digital God. He doesn't say it in as
Speaker 4:  many words. And he's actually, he's very careful to not say a GI,
Speaker 4:  which is what has become the synonym for digital God. I think he just calls
Speaker 4:  it powerful ai, which doesn't sound less
Speaker 4:  alarming, it's just different alarming I guess. But yeah, it is, it,
Speaker 4:  this is the size of the promise you have to make if you're one of these
Speaker 4:  companies in order to do everything you need to do to get there. And like
Speaker 4:  this is as neat and reasoned a summation of
Speaker 4:  that stance as I've seen yet. Yeah. Like he might be wrong about everything,
Speaker 4:  but it's, it's like If, you want to get inside the rational brain of
Speaker 4:  the AI industry right now. This is about as close as I've seen.
Speaker 3:  And and they have to take everything,
Speaker 4:  Right? It's like it takes 14,000 words to explain.
Speaker 3:  It's just like, and one lawsuit from Sarah Silverman could bring this all
Speaker 3:  to a grinding.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. Yeah. You put this next to, was
Speaker 4:  it Mark Andreessen who was like, you, you can't force us to pay for this
Speaker 4:  because then we won't be able to do it. Yeah. Like take those two statements
Speaker 4:  next to each other and it becomes very hard to know where any of this is
Speaker 4:  gonna go. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And that, by the way, was it Mark Andreessen said that in a filing to the
Speaker 3:  United States
Speaker 3:  making this go and it's very good. So go click on all the links, we'll put
Speaker 3:  them there. That's, that's happening. And then thanks to Panas for coming
Speaker 3:  on the show. We're gonna have them back when it's Alexa time. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I, I think that, I think, I think we can say that. Alright, that's it. That's
Speaker 3:  Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Wil Pour and Eric Gomez. And that's it. We'll see
Speaker 1:  you next week.