# Transcript
ID: d1a6255c-eb19-4205-9f31-35804975dc37
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5111220222872133655/818653159107941639/s93290-US-6221s-1714348639.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss President Biden signing the TikTok ban bill, Apple's May 7th iPad event, Tesla's flop era, and more.
Speaker 1:  state Farm is there. Talk to
Speaker 3:  anniversary Tour Captivating thousands of fans at each and every show.
Speaker 3:  Stream art beats and lyrics, Now on Hulu, please drink
Speaker 3:  responsibly. Whiskey specialty, 35% Alcohol by Valium Jack, Daniels
Speaker 3:  Distillery Lynchburg Tennessee Jack Daniels and Tennessee Honey are registered
Speaker 3:  trademarks 2024 Jack Daniels All Rights
Speaker 3:  Reserve.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And Welcome To, the Rich House, the flagship podcast of saying, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  burn your house down unless you sell it. That's the metaphor
Speaker 4:  everyone's using at TikTok.
Speaker 5:  If you don't listen to The Vergecast, we will burn your house down.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's, those are your choices. You can sell your house, or Crans will
Speaker 4:  come to it and torch it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I, I've got a lighter and everything.
Speaker 4:  Hi, I'm your friend Eli. I'm, I'm good. Crans is here. Alex Kranz
Speaker 4:  is here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm here to hear all the scorching takes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. She's got a lighter and she's not afraid to use it. David Pierce is
Speaker 4:  here.
Speaker 5:  Hello. We were all so close to being in the same city for
Speaker 5:  like 10 minutes yesterday. Yeah. And we managed to not record a VERGE cast,
Speaker 5:  and it was very upsetting. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's funny that we've, we've gone 180, like usually at least two of us are
Speaker 4:  together. We were all very close to all three of us being together, and now
Speaker 4:  we're all three of us remote, but it's for good
Speaker 4:  reason. David has the Rabbit R one in
Speaker 4:  hand. I do. I can't tell you how much I wanna talk about the Rabbit
Speaker 4:  R one and all the things it can or mostly cannot do. So that's very exciting.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna talk about that. We gotta talk about the electric gwa. That's
Speaker 4:  another hour of The Vergecast. Apple announced new iPads. Tesla
Speaker 4:  had earnings. Elon threatened once again to turn every Tesla on the road
Speaker 4:  into some sort of distributed AWS situation. Very weird. We got a lightning
Speaker 4:  round at the end. But we have to start, we have to start with breaking
Speaker 4:  news. Joe Biden to just before we began recording
Speaker 4:  today on Wednesday, signed the bill
Speaker 4:  that would force TikTok to either divest itself to sell itself to
Speaker 4:  some other company in the United States, or shut down. Those are the two
Speaker 4:  choices it passed as part of an aid package
Speaker 4:  to Ukraine, Israel. There's some humanitarian aid for Gaza in that
Speaker 4:  package. The house passed it as part of that aid bill. They extended
Speaker 4:  the timeline and the divestiture, which was the big holdup in the Senate
Speaker 4:  before. So now there's, now TikTok has nine months to, to
Speaker 4:  figure out a sale process. And if they're making progress, whoever is the
Speaker 4:  president has, can add three months per the president's
Speaker 4:  discretion, bringing the total to a year. So by chance, basically has a year
Speaker 4:  to figure this out. The clock is now ticking. The the bill is signed.
Speaker 4:  It's the law, and no one knows what's gonna happen next.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I like, there's so many strange
Speaker 5:  unknowns about this. Things like, who is going to be president when we hit
Speaker 5:  the nine month gap? Like it's, it's, it's so obvious to me that a big part
Speaker 5:  of the sticking point was to move this past the election, right. That whatever
Speaker 5:  is going to happen should have to happen after election day, and it'll either
Speaker 5:  be our problem after we've been reelected if you're the Democrats,
Speaker 5:  or it'll be their problem. Yeah. If you're the Republicans, right. Like that
Speaker 6:  Was in Lauren's reporting too, is is that a lot of these senators
Speaker 6:  signed on to, to approve this bill because it pushed it
Speaker 6:  past the deadline because they gave him a little bit more space to do it.
Speaker 6:  So, yeah.
Speaker 5:  No, I I think it's, it's, it, it's such an easy maneuver at such
Speaker 5:  an odd moment. And we've talked so much about the politics of this,
Speaker 5:  especially among young people in the United States and all the weird ways
Speaker 5:  that's gonna go. And all of the stuff I've been reading recently has been
Speaker 5:  very strange that like intellectually overwhelmingly, it seems like if you
Speaker 5:  ask people, is TikTok sort of bad in whatever, like
Speaker 5:  mysterious way you wanna define bad people say yes. Like all of the
Speaker 5:  polls are basically like, yes, most people believe TikTok is a net
Speaker 5:  bad. But then I think the, the reality of like
Speaker 5:  waking up in TikTok suddenly being gone is a, is a thing in
Speaker 5:  an election season that nobody actually wants to deal with. Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  very strange. I also don't think that part is ever actually going to happen.
Speaker 5:  But we we can talk about that.
Speaker 4:  Look, I love eating handfuls of m MSS at midnight, which is a thing I
Speaker 4:  love. I know it's bad. I know I shouldn't do that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, super do it all the time. I,
Speaker 4:  that feels like our relationship to social media is a country right now,
Speaker 4:  and maybe TikTok in particular, but in general, our relationship to social
Speaker 4:  media is like, eh, this making us feel bad. And and maybe it's measurable
Speaker 4:  or maybe it's not. Or maybe this guy's just a grifter trying to sell a book,
Speaker 4:  whatever it is, some ambient sense of, eh, I shouldn't eat m and ms at
Speaker 4:  midnight. Is there, and then everyone's just like, give them to me.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like, let me have him, the thing that's really interesting, right?
Speaker 4:  It, it just got signed today. It was inev, it felt inevitable all week that
Speaker 4:  this would get signed. That was the momentum was there. Lauren
Speaker 4:  finer, her reporting suggested the deadlines were coming ever faster.
Speaker 4:  Like usually with bills, there's delays and last minute changed and this
Speaker 4:  was just happening and it actually happened, I think, a little faster than
Speaker 4:  we anticipated it would happen, like a day faster. Now it's done.
Speaker 4:  There's no more argument whether you should ban on TikTok. Like they, they
Speaker 4:  did it. They passed the bill. Joe Biden signed it. It's the law.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I, I do think you, you could ask the
Speaker 5:  question of I is what Joe Biden signed,
Speaker 5:  intended to be a ban of TikTok. Like it's not nothing to me that
Speaker 5:  in, in his statement about signing the bill and his excitement and enthusiasm
Speaker 5:  for the fact that this got done after all this time, didn't mention TikTok
Speaker 5:  once or any of this stuff once it's buried like
Speaker 5:  halfway down this long bill after I, I
Speaker 5:  forget the exact heading of the thing, but it's like miscellaneous
Speaker 5:  and then TikTok like this is not the point of the bill. Yeah. Right. which
Speaker 5:  I think is, is a strange thing that is going to play out potentially in some
Speaker 5:  interesting ways as we go through the inevitable chaos of the next nine months.
Speaker 5:  This got passed in service of passing something
Speaker 5:  else. And I think what everybody decided along this process is passing
Speaker 5:  this other thing is so important that sure will ban TikTok. And
Speaker 5:  so I think, I don't know if that changes anything about the way this actually
Speaker 5:  plays out. I think that the bill is still law, like, it, it did happen, but
Speaker 5:  it's a strange way that we got here that makes me wonder,
Speaker 5:  like, does Joe Biden actually want to ban
Speaker 5:  TikTok or is that just a price everyone is willing to pay in order to get
Speaker 5:  this important aid bill? Oh,
Speaker 6:  It's a hundred percent of price everybody was willing to pay. Right. Like,
Speaker 6:  like this was a really, this, the whole bill was hard, was a hard fought
Speaker 6:  battle for everybody involved. And, and this was just like, you know
Speaker 6:  what? We just need to get this bill out the door. If somebody wants to put
Speaker 6:  this. And this is like, so, so at the back of most of our list, it's
Speaker 6:  fine. which I thought was really, really interesting to go from like
Speaker 6:  TikTok being like this huge center of discussion for everybody to being
Speaker 6:  like a f essentially a footnote and a much larger bill.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, they did have, the house did have the up down vote on the standalone
Speaker 4:  TikTok bill, which had a much shorter timeline. And I think a lot of people
Speaker 4:  had problems with that shorter timeline, and that just sort of arrived in
Speaker 4:  the Senate with nothing. So at least one part of our government had
Speaker 4:  the straight up down vote. That's true. Right. And after the house voted
Speaker 4:  to pass that version of the Bill, Biden said, I'm gonna sign it. Like I'll
Speaker 4:  sign it. Did you get it to me? And I'll sign it. Whether or not they skirted
Speaker 4:  it through the Senate by attaching it to a bill that everyone
Speaker 4:  wanted to get done. Yeah. I mean like on the margins. But that's like how
Speaker 4:  so many things get done. Totally. But I think you have, you had
Speaker 4:  the house, just the straight uptown vote and you had Biden saying, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  sign it. So the motivations I think are clear whether
Speaker 4:  or not Biden wants to run around crowing that he banned TikTok I think is
Speaker 4:  very different, like politically very different. The White House, for example,
Speaker 4:  announced today that's gonna keep campaigning on
Speaker 4:  TikTok. They're just gonna, they're gonna be
Speaker 4:  like, I don't know if anyone's ready for that ratio that is gonna, in the
Speaker 4:  history of ratios on the internet, every post, the White House now
Speaker 4:  makes, every post Joe Biden now makes on TikTok is gonna get
Speaker 4:  Ratioed to Helen back and it's gonna be delightful. And that's
Speaker 4:  fine.
Speaker 5:  I was actually thinking about that as sort of, it's like a perfect microcosm
Speaker 5:  of this whole thing. And I think the, the thing that I have come around
Speaker 5:  to is in, in the months that we've been talking about this, I
Speaker 5:  think at the beginning of all these conversations, I underrated how
Speaker 5:  important TikTok is as an information source, particularly to young people.
Speaker 5:  But now you see the stats that are like, it is a, it is a growing search
Speaker 5:  engine. It's a, it's a huge source of news, particularly for like Gen
Speaker 5:  Z and younger. It matters a lot. And so for the White
Speaker 5:  House to a wanna ban TikTok but also understand that if we wanna
Speaker 5:  reach people, this is the literal only way is actually like a
Speaker 5:  perfect summation of the TikTok problem. Right. TikTok is so
Speaker 5:  important that you can ban it and yet you have to use it.
Speaker 5:  It's so strange. But that is like, that is where we are with
Speaker 5:  what TikTok means to people. Right
Speaker 4:  Now, somewhere in the TikTok office, there's the knob that just throttles
Speaker 4:  you and like shows each you the CEO of TikTok is just like Biden Harris
Speaker 4:  hq
Speaker 5:  Goodbye. Yeah. Their engagement's gonna go way up.
Speaker 4:  No, from orbit. Good night everybody. So it's done right, that the
Speaker 4:  point I'm trying to make is it's done. There are only three options now.
Speaker 4:  TikTok has said it's gonna sue, it's gonna file some sort of
Speaker 4:  legal complaint to say, this is not allowed. We
Speaker 4:  don't know what that looks like. They showed Chu actually put up a TikTok
Speaker 4:  himself saying, make no mistake, this is a ban, which is interesting. We'll
Speaker 4:  come back to that and then we're gonna go to court and wanna fight for your
Speaker 4:  rights as Americans under the Constitution because you can't be silenced.
Speaker 4:  Also a very interesting thing to say. And then he said,
Speaker 4:  don't worry TikTok, we'll continue as before like we're, we'll keep running
Speaker 4:  TikTok, we're gonna keep investing in TikTok. Yeah. You just hold tight.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna go defend the Constitution against the United States government.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's super funny to see the guy who made
Speaker 6:  like unli a word because you're not allowed to say dead on
Speaker 6:  TikTok. The, the bastion of free speech. Like that's a really weird
Speaker 6:  stance for him to take because it's not, it's, it's PG
Speaker 6:  rated social media, right? Yeah. Like, like it's, it's social media for kids,
Speaker 6:  which is why the kids use it and why part of
Speaker 6:  the reason people don't want the kids using it. Like, come on dude,
Speaker 4:  I'm never gonna look at a corner emoji the same way Right after being on
Speaker 4:  OnOne. That's, you went from very, very innocent to very weird very
Speaker 4:  quickly. So there's that element. There's also the fact that it's not the
Speaker 4:  user's speech that is being regulated here, right? It's TikTok, the company
Speaker 4:  that distributes the speech of users and the notion that
Speaker 4:  its control of the AL algorithm presents some sort of national security risk.
Speaker 4:  That there is some longstanding issue with having foreign powers
Speaker 4:  control a significant part of our media. That's a very old policy issue.
Speaker 4:  There's some issue with concentration of media ownership. So you just
Speaker 4:  look at option one, we're gonna file a lawsuit, we're gonna win pure
Speaker 4:  coin flip. We just don't know how that's gonna go. We don't know what tiktoks
Speaker 4:  lawsuit is gonna be. It could hinge all on free speech or it could just hinge
Speaker 4:  on like a technical drafting error where the government did
Speaker 4:  not point to the correct statutory
Speaker 4:  authority from 1805 to enact. We don't, like, we
Speaker 4:  have to see it. So that's option one. We're gonna fight a lawsuit and win.
Speaker 4:  Option two is they shut down and leave. They could do that. That's
Speaker 4:  the ban, right? We, we've exhausted our other options and we are, we're outta
Speaker 4:  here. Goodbye. You ban TikTok. Weird. I I think that, I
Speaker 4:  think that is that that is a choice that by chance has to make under
Speaker 4:  duress. Yeah. Right. That's the, we're gonna burn your house down unless
Speaker 4:  you sell it. And they could be like, ah, we lit the, we lit the match. Look,
Speaker 4:  see you later. We shut it down Option two, option three is that they sell
Speaker 4:  it and you know, they got a year to figure it out. And option three has a
Speaker 4:  bunch of weirdness in it because most of the companies that would want to
Speaker 4:  buy TikTok, it feels like our own DOJ would prevent them from doing it
Speaker 4:  for antitrust reasons. So that's option three. So it, it's not
Speaker 4:  an easy road from here at all. I don't know what the
Speaker 4:  creators are gonna do. The creators have a year to figure out how much they
Speaker 4:  want to trust TikTok while TikTok is trying to turn itself into the home
Speaker 4:  shopping network anyway. And like it's not, and you know, universal music
Speaker 4:  isn't on there anymore. Like there's a whole bunch of stuff over there that
Speaker 4:  creators are gonna have to react to. I, I think we're in for just a whole
Speaker 4:  bucket of changes much in the same way that when, you know, Elon bought
Speaker 4:  Twitter and started making changes over there, the social media landscape
Speaker 4:  just started refracting around it. Like things started changing all around
Speaker 4:  that energy. I think we're gonna see the same thing with, with TikTok,
Speaker 4:  but though there's only three options. They fight and win a lawsuit, which
Speaker 4:  we haven't seen. And we don't know what that lawsuit will be based on. So
Speaker 4:  we, we don't know. They leave or they sell it.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 5:  It. Okay. I just wanna float a fourth option. Yeah. Which is they
Speaker 5:  stay and the app stores pay a fine, which in case you're
Speaker 5:  wondering, I calculated it would be $850 billion.
Speaker 5:  So that's an option. Just throwing it out there. Apple can do
Speaker 4:  That. That's 8.5 car projects for Apple.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like, not even a big deal. It's fine. That's fine. But I
Speaker 5:  think to me the, the strange thing that's gonna happen in the middle of
Speaker 5:  all of that is just uncertainty. Right? And I've, I've been reading and talking
Speaker 5:  to folks about this just in the last few hours and there is this
Speaker 5:  overwhelming sense from a lot of people that TikTok
Speaker 5:  is sort of screwed no matter what happens because this is like, it just
Speaker 5:  got completely thrown up in the air, everything about TikTok
Speaker 5:  and there is no indication it's going to
Speaker 5:  settle down quickly. Right. And like even if it gets a new owner, there will
Speaker 5:  be lots of changes. If it disappears,
Speaker 5:  obviously it'll be gone. And if it fights a lawsuit, that's gonna take a
Speaker 5:  long time. And so if you're a creator, if you're an advertiser, if you're
Speaker 5:  anyone who has any kind of investment in this platform,
Speaker 5:  the simplest thing to do is going to be immediately start investing your
Speaker 5:  time and energy and money somewhere else. Yep. And that is just going to
Speaker 5:  bleed TikTok so fast. And to the
Speaker 5:  point where even if a year from now TikTok sells to
Speaker 5:  Oracle, like what are we sure TikTok is going to still be
Speaker 5:  TikTok in a year because it's, I I like this stuff moves fast,
Speaker 4:  Right? And then the, the actual mechanism of sale is
Speaker 4:  confusing 'cause it appears by ance would not sell the
Speaker 4:  algorithm that underlies TikTok. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. Well, by dance has been pretty clear this whole time that it has no
Speaker 5:  interest in selling. Like I, the, if if you believe
Speaker 5:  ance divesting is not an option.
Speaker 6:  Well yeah. 'cause then we have to see if TikTok actually makes money,
Speaker 4:  Right? I mean like Yeah. Do they want a bunch of American tech companies
Speaker 4:  poking around the books of TikTok? Like they certainly do not. Do they have
Speaker 4:  to say just as a negotiating tactic, we will never sell in order
Speaker 4:  to ward off a ban? They sure do. But if you're just a responsible
Speaker 4:  executive and now you're here and you have the three choices or
Speaker 4:  choice four to be fair to David, which is ask Apple to pay $850 billion
Speaker 4:  a year in fines for having TikTok remain in the app
Speaker 4:  store. Yeah. I dunno. Like I, it it feels like you, you gotta run down two
Speaker 4:  of them, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean at some point your option is either $0 or a hundred billion
Speaker 5:  dollars. Yeah. And you just, you sort of have no choice but to take that.
Speaker 5:  But if that is the game that you're playing, you have to play that
Speaker 5:  basically until the very last minute.
Speaker 4:  Look, the millionaire Chinese teens buying GWAS all over Los
Speaker 4:  Angeles, it's gotta come from somewhere, you know?
Speaker 4:  Exactly like the children of the ccp, they need their gwas. That's all
Speaker 4:  I'm saying. I'm just put, I'm just putting that out there somewhere and like
Speaker 4:  money, money talks and like that's real. And I think having some dollars
Speaker 4:  is better than no dollars. Whether or not it's fair that the price is
Speaker 4:  depressed because the thing has to be sold. Good
Speaker 4:  question. There's just not a world in which the
Speaker 4:  evaluation doesn't come down to, are we gonna be successful in court?
Speaker 4:  What number can we get? Because that middle road of, we pulled out
Speaker 4:  of the United States market and now we have nothing to show for all of our
Speaker 4:  investment in building the TikTok user base. It just seems it's some, that's
Speaker 4:  a lawsuit too.
Speaker 5:  It's also just straight up bad business. Like that is just straightforwardly
Speaker 5:  like a stupid capitalism decision at some point.
Speaker 4:  Notably the Chinese government not so capitalist putting that out there.
Speaker 5:  Well, and again, like there are the question of who ultimately makes
Speaker 5:  this decision on that side very hard to
Speaker 5:  know, would tell you a lot about Yeah. How this will turn out,
Speaker 5:  right? Like if, if Chuchu, the CEO of TikTok is the person who ultimately
Speaker 5:  makes the decision, that will be very different than if TikTok
Speaker 5:  is connected to ance, is connected to the Chinese Communist Party, which
Speaker 5:  ultimately means the Chinese Communist Party makes that decision, that would
Speaker 5:  go very differently. Like there's so many things we don't know
Speaker 5:  still.
Speaker 6:  It's an exciting time, honestly. Like I love when a social media platform
Speaker 6:  changes hands or has this big moment because then you see, see
Speaker 6:  things like Adam Ari today was it on Instagram neli, I think you you
Speaker 6:  you clocked the video of him just explaining to creators how to get
Speaker 6:  engagement Yeah. On the platform. And it's like that probably wouldn't have
Speaker 6:  happened if there wasn't a TikTok
Speaker 4:  Adam and Sarah being like, so okay, you're at work. I'm gonna set some goals
Speaker 4:  for you. We're gonna check in in six months to see how they're going and
Speaker 4:  you know, we'll see how it's going. And it's like, dude, why does this all
Speaker 4:  feel like work? Yeah. Like I actually think that's like the bigger story.
Speaker 4:  Here's like, this feels like a work for an awful lot of people across all
Speaker 4:  of these platforms. Yeah. And like maybe some people are gonna be like, I
Speaker 4:  don't wanna work for TikTok anymore 'cause it came to nothing. And that will
Speaker 4:  just create energy somewhere else. We'll see
Speaker 5:  One of the funniest memes to me on Instagram is all the people who are
Speaker 5:  like, oh, I had a call with Meta and we talked about, you know, strategies
Speaker 5:  for how to succeed and it like, it has become a meme of people making jokes
Speaker 5:  about it. But it started as a real thing and it's like, it's a big win to
Speaker 5:  have a business call with meta executives about your Instagram presence.
Speaker 5:  Wait,
Speaker 6:  Wait. Did social media become the new Mary Kay?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Oh it's been there for a long time. I don't
Speaker 6:  Realize, have you seen the
Speaker 4:  People, the Hydrow water bottles? Yes. The
Speaker 4:  bottles just have a blue LED in the bottom and they're like, this adds hydrogen
Speaker 4:  to your water. That's a lie. It's very
Speaker 4:  bad. And if you don't understand why it's bad, I'm just telling you that
Speaker 4:  water is made of hydrogen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's already in there. It's
Speaker 4:  Don't need more. There's two of 'em for every oxygen
Speaker 4:  famously you get, you get two of
Speaker 4:  them double your hydrogens.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, what are you doing? Like how is this happening on this platform?
Speaker 4:  And they're all selling 'em a TikTok shop. And I just think that platform,
Speaker 4:  the revenue pressure on all the social platforms is so high, but
Speaker 4:  all these companies need to make money. They show profitability, they're
Speaker 4:  doing layoffs and they're just turning the screws. I'm like, can we, how
Speaker 4:  do we make money? And they just landed on the home shopping network. I think
Speaker 4:  it was headed towards a cliff anyway. Like there was a bubble in Video Creator
Speaker 4:  economy. Taylor Lawrence has actually talked about
Speaker 4:  it. And you can just see like to me the Hydrow
Speaker 4:  water bottle is like, oh that bubble's getting pretty big. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  it's, it's not good. All right, so here's the exercise. I wanna
Speaker 4:  do three options, right? Lawsuit
Speaker 4:  succeeds by chance, burns it down, or they get
Speaker 4:  sold. TikTok is a prize, right? It is the thing that
Speaker 4:  no one can get. It is a scaled social network with an active user base of
Speaker 4:  young people. That's what everybody wants. It's really hard to get the way
Speaker 4:  that TikTok got it right? They acquired Musically and then by dance started
Speaker 4:  spending billions upon billions of dollars on Facebook and Instagram ads
Speaker 4:  to convert people into downloading the app. You can't really do that. You
Speaker 4:  can't even run that playbook anymore because of Apple's app tracking transparency.
Speaker 4:  Like they made the ad changes. And so the market for app install ads
Speaker 4:  is basically gone. You have to pay Apple for them in the app store. Now a
Speaker 4:  different conversation. But the point is you can't just run the playbook
Speaker 4:  by Chance did. And they ran that playbook to the tune of billions upon billions
Speaker 4:  of dollars. Right? So here's this thing that was really hard to
Speaker 4:  do that the conditions under which Ance did it have
Speaker 4:  dramatically changed and it was very expensive even when they could do it.
Speaker 4:  It's what everybody wants. It will be expensive, right? This
Speaker 4:  isn't, this isn't like Twitter fire sale and even that was expensive
Speaker 4:  as we've all discovered. Like that was overpriced. This is the thing, like
Speaker 4:  it is a scaled video advertising platform with a bunch of young people on
Speaker 4:  it that love it, that defines the culture all the time. So who
Speaker 4:  can afford it? I just looked up the list of the largest American companies
Speaker 4:  by market cap, all of the ones that are measured in trillions or tech
Speaker 4:  companies. So I figured we could just go down that list and then we can go
Speaker 4:  to the companies that are measured in billions, which are much more amusing
Speaker 4:  to think about as owners of by ance. But that is very fun. I think we should,
Speaker 4:  we should start with the tech companies. 'cause they seem like the most likely
Speaker 4:  group to at least have some interest
Speaker 5:  Clarifying question. How much should we
Speaker 5:  think TikTok is worth? I have an idea in mind, but I'm curious if,
Speaker 5:  if there is a like assumed number that I have not heard for what
Speaker 5:  TikTok is valued at, do we know?
Speaker 4:  So the number that's I have just picked out of the blue is a hundred billion
Speaker 4:  dollars. Okay. 'cause that is more than double what Twitter was worth. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And it's a huge, I'm good with that. It's a huge number. Most companies can't
Speaker 4:  just do that.
Speaker 5:  Right? I would've actually gone a little higher. Yeah. Like the, there was
Speaker 5:  the, the estimate recently that YouTube is worth $400 billion on its
Speaker 5:  own. So I was gonna say like 200, let's go. Once
Speaker 4:  You're out here, it's just like whatever number you want another a hundred
Speaker 4:  bill
Speaker 5:  Like that. I'm good with a hundred bill. Oh no,
Speaker 6:  I'm good. TikTok doesn't, doesn't have like the numbers of YouTube though,
Speaker 6:  right? Like I'm, I'm at
Speaker 5:  50 or the money or the Yeah, no, you're right. I I'm good with a hundred
Speaker 5:  billion. This works
Speaker 4:  By the way. And I'm picking that number just 'cause it, it is this, it's
Speaker 4:  a small hard number. Yeah, right. Like 44 billion for Twitter
Speaker 4:  was like overpriced, but not even then a lot of companies can just like do
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 5:  I don't think there's any world in which TikTok is in a, in a
Speaker 5:  regular pure market sense worth less than a hundred billion.
Speaker 5:  So I feel, I feel pretty good about this
Speaker 4:  And I'll, I'll just for some comparison. As of December,
Speaker 4:  2023, apple had $73 billion in cash on hand, which is an
Speaker 4:  insane amount of cash. Like Apple's one of the most cash rich companies out
Speaker 4:  there and that's how much, so I, I picked a hundred 'cause it's, it would
Speaker 4:  be hard even for an Apple to pull off. Yeah, yeah. Anyway, here's the
Speaker 4:  list. Apple and Microsoft jockeying back and forth
Speaker 4:  for biggest market cap. So we'll start with
Speaker 4:  Microsoft today. Microsoft, I actually
Speaker 4:  feels like Microsoft should be in the running for TikTok. They have been
Speaker 4:  in the running before when Trump tried to ban
Speaker 4:  TikTok. Ella got pulled into those conversations. He has
Speaker 4:  repeatedly described it as some of the weirdest business dealings he's ever
Speaker 4:  been a part of. Then it just went away and we got Project Texas
Speaker 4:  where Oracle took over the data, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Which case
Speaker 4:  nothing appears to have been mostly a, a front
Speaker 5:  Convinced no one of anything.
Speaker 4:  No, no one cares about Project Texas
Speaker 5:  And Microsoft has been desperate for like a true consumer
Speaker 5:  play for a long time. I mean, it it wasn't it Microsoft that
Speaker 5:  sniffed around discord in a pretty big way. Yep. Like it wants something
Speaker 5:  like this very badly.
Speaker 6:  I I disagree. This is, this is like a big old hot potato
Speaker 6:  Microsoft wants no, part of like the big power of Microsoft nowadays is that
Speaker 6:  we don't talk about Microsoft that often. And, and that
Speaker 6:  would change immediately with TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A good question for all this is does your CEO want to get hauled in
Speaker 4:  front of Congress to talk about content moderation, right? Yeah. And mi
Speaker 4:  Microsoft No. The answer appears to be no. That said, there is
Speaker 4:  a lot of scrutiny around Microsoft Steel with open ai like a
Speaker 4:  lot of antitrust scrutiny. And this is gonna come up, the idea of antitrust
Speaker 4:  scrutiny is gonna come up as we go through this list. And there's, I think
Speaker 4:  Microsoft could run a play where they say, look, here's what we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do. We're gonna do a partnership with like snap, which can definitely Snap
Speaker 4:  is not on the list of biggest American companies by any, by any
Speaker 4:  means. Like not even in the top 100. Like, no, it's not even sniffing
Speaker 4:  this, but you could say Microsoft. But you could see Microsoft say, okay,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna do this weird kind of partnership with Snap, where they will
Speaker 4:  fund them buying TikTok will like be their backend provider. They'll run
Speaker 4:  AI and Azure for recommendations and it'll be the same kind of structure
Speaker 4:  as ai. And if that's fine over here, 'cause it solves a big problem. I bet
Speaker 4:  it's fine over here with OpenAI.
Speaker 6:  Lena Kahn will drop, kick that deal
Speaker 4:  Right out the door. I mean, but this is the, this is the game, right? Right.
Speaker 4:  All these companies are, it's an op, this is a problem that needs to get
Speaker 4:  solved. So I'm gonna ask to buy this thing. And if Lena Khan is like,
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna let anyone buy it, then it is a ban. And so you have to at
Speaker 4:  least run the process and you have to create some leverage somewhere.
Speaker 5:  I think Microsoft has like three meetings but ultimately walks
Speaker 5:  away
Speaker 4:  Again, they came close before. Also, Microsoft doesn't have a dead on antitrust
Speaker 4:  problem because it doesn't run any social networks that's said from Xbox
Speaker 4:  Live. And so it, you know, they, they could just buy
Speaker 4:  it. I dunno if they'd want to, but I, I think using it as leverage
Speaker 4:  to turn down the heat on open AI might be interesting. That's Microsoft
Speaker 4:  Apple one or two, the biggest companies in the world. Microsoft and Apple
Speaker 4:  always going back and forth. Apple no way is my answer to this
Speaker 4:  question. 0%. Then Timco wants to sit in front of Congress and talk about
Speaker 4:  content moderation. Ever.
Speaker 5:  The funniest possible outcome of this whole thing is that Apple buys
Speaker 5:  TikTok and makes it a feature of Apple TV plus. That is the, that
Speaker 5:  is the single best thing that could possibly happen. That this is, this
Speaker 5:  is their content play for Apple TV plus.
Speaker 6:  Oh it would be, it would be Apple Music.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, apple Music, right. Apple runs a music service. TikTok is huge in music.
Speaker 4:  They have great relationships with all the labels because they're the big
Speaker 4:  hedging against Spotify. Apple importantly has an incredible
Speaker 4:  relationship with the Chinese government that is extremely well managed by
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook. So they're, they're a known partner that would
Speaker 4:  find a way to blah, blah, blah interoperate, you know,
Speaker 4:  with ance globally, you, you could see the arguments. I'm just saying,
Speaker 4:  I don't think Tim Cook wants to sit in front of Congress and talk about content
Speaker 4:  moderation. I
Speaker 6:  I think Neli, they're gonna use that exact quote you just said. When
Speaker 6:  they pull Tim Cook in front of Congress for buying
Speaker 6:  TikTok,
Speaker 5:  You have a good relationship with the Chinese government is precisely the
Speaker 5:  reason not to buy TikTok. If you're Tim Cook,
Speaker 4:  All right, moving on. IIII think we can all, it would be the shock of all
Speaker 4:  shocks of Apple buys TikTok, Nvidia, third biggest market cap in the country
Speaker 4:  right now. It feels a bit a field.
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. Jenssen's. Like he's a smart
Speaker 6:  dude, right? Like he, he started that company from the ground up. He's still
Speaker 6:  running it now. He made his big bet on ai.
Speaker 6:  He, like, they think very measured over there. Like everything
Speaker 6:  they do has a purpose and a point even when it's a screw up. So I'd be
Speaker 6:  like very surprised.
Speaker 5:  Okay, allow me to make the counter case. Yeah. I love it. I'm Jensen Wong.
Speaker 5:  I have somewhat intentionally, somewhat
Speaker 5:  accidentally stumbled into a, just an unbelievable gold
Speaker 5:  mine that is the AI revolution. This will not last forever.
Speaker 5:  Other people are going to figure out how to make GPUs as good as mine. And
Speaker 5:  I'm not going to be able to sell H one hundreds for however much money I
Speaker 5:  want to whoever I want forever. I need another
Speaker 5:  move. That other move is
Speaker 5:  TikTok.
Speaker 4:  I want, I want that someone is writing that memo at Nvidia right now. Yes.
Speaker 4:  And then at the end of it, it's like question mark, question mark, question
Speaker 4:  mark, profit. You know, like, this is the move that's
Speaker 4:  as big as H 100. It's like, ah, I dunno about that. No.
Speaker 5:  The, the other, the other reason is there, there is a real version of
Speaker 5:  this that is TikTok as training data.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. which I think is, is not worth a hundred billion dollars, but is
Speaker 5:  also not worth nothing. And I think one reason a lot of these companies will
Speaker 5:  take a good hard look at TikTok is not because they want to operate a social
Speaker 5:  network forever, but because operating a social network gets them
Speaker 5:  basically an infinite supply of good training data for AI
Speaker 5:  systems
Speaker 6:  For now. Very. Right.
Speaker 5:  That's just what it is. I mean, this is what Mark Zuckerberg has been talking
Speaker 5:  about with Facebook. Like, they're, they're touting the fact that they have
Speaker 5:  this vast supply of stuff that people,
Speaker 4:  All right, so Jensen swoops in and he is like, look, I'm already in the middle
Speaker 4:  of geopolitical hot zones. Yeah. 'cause I'm, you know, I'm
Speaker 4:  building ships with TSMC in Taiwan and the whole universe is organized
Speaker 4:  around H one H 100 production in Taiwan. What if I had a little TikTok to
Speaker 4:  the mix, I could do it all right. That's, that's Nvidia. I I I'm putting
Speaker 4:  that sub 50%
Speaker 5:  Way sub 50, but
Speaker 4:  I sub 10. But we made the argument alphabet
Speaker 4:  or as the people know it, Google,
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think that no one wants them to buy it.
Speaker 4:  Don't, if you wanna ban TikTok, you let Google buy it and just
Speaker 4:  slowly kill it until they shut it down.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like, like that's what'll happen. That that is effectively a
Speaker 6:  ban. So no.
Speaker 4:  Do you think they're having a conversation?
Speaker 6:  I think Google's totally having that conversation though. Like they, they
Speaker 6:  love a social media platform that they kill a few years later. This is
Speaker 6:  just like
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but so to David's point, this is a rich source of training data for
Speaker 4:  Google. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think that's why they're, they're actually
Speaker 4:  Talking. It is a long time ago when I asked Sundar about the
Speaker 4:  web and what SEO has done to the web and where you would start a new thing
Speaker 4:  if you were a new creator. He said, well, we have, we have YouTube, right?
Speaker 4:  So they know that all the sort of organic content that is made by
Speaker 4:  human beings is happening on video platforms. This is a rich source of that.
Speaker 4:  They're already searching TikTok. You can search for tiktoks and Google search.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Don't forget, Google has been saying loudly for two years now that
Speaker 5:  one of the biggest threats to Google search is TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  Which is again, why they're not gonna
Speaker 4:  Buy this is the real Lena Con hands on hips one, right? Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 5:  No Alphabet would do this. I, I believe Absolutely. Yes. Alphabet would do
Speaker 5:  this. It would be sued to death
Speaker 5:  once Lean Kahn is like already standing outside of the Google plex
Speaker 5:  and Mountain View with a lawsuit and just ready to like huck
Speaker 5:  it into soon Aisha's office the minute this happens. I like if
Speaker 5:  I'm, if I'm student hai, I would do this in one
Speaker 5:  second, but there's absolutely no chance that they will.
Speaker 4:  Alright, so that's Google and the next one is really
Speaker 4:  interesting. Amazon, I think
Speaker 4:  Amazon looks at TikTok slowly turning into the home shopping
Speaker 4:  network and moving an awful lot of records and
Speaker 4:  is like this, we, this is what we want. This is the future of shopping.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yep. Amazon has been gently trying to do this on
Speaker 5:  Amazon properties for a while. Yeah. They've had
Speaker 5:  creator brand things that they've done, they've brought people in, they've
Speaker 5:  done video stuff. None of it has really worked. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  I, I think, I think Amazon of these is the one that makes the most sense
Speaker 5:  and also probably the one that is most likely to be plausible.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I don't think, they don't run a social platform now in way, shape,
Speaker 4:  or form. So the antitrust issues don't seem so bad. That said, you know,
Speaker 4:  the Europeans just blocked Amazon from buying iRobot because they were worried
Speaker 4:  about concentration on the robotic vacuum market. And Annie Jesse looked
Speaker 4:  furious when he was talking about that on CBC. Just
Speaker 4:  so mad. Yeah. He's like, we're well beyond the law now. Like are
Speaker 4:  we, I dunno, it sounds like
Speaker 6:  You were right by the law,
Speaker 4:  But they don't, but they don't have a social platform. And TikTok really
Speaker 4:  is a big advertising play and Amazon is actually one of the biggest advertisers
Speaker 4:  out there. I could see it. I think this would probably turn TikTok into something
Speaker 4:  worse.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, yeah. This is like Google where you don't want, if you're a TikTok
Speaker 6:  Yu you don't want this purchase. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like where can you imagine if you just combine Amazon alphabet soup
Speaker 4:  brands with TikTok shops, just general
Speaker 6:  Aesthetics. Oh my. Got Amazon Basics just nonstop
Speaker 6:  in your feed.
Speaker 4:  I would 100% calling, start calling that group of TikTok creators Amazon
Speaker 4:  Basics. You, you know who I'm talking about? Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like the Amazon basics. It would be bad for
Speaker 4:  America. Okay. So that's Amazon. That feels very
Speaker 4:  likely of this list. So far, Microsoft and Amazon feel like the, the most
Speaker 4:  likely to, to at least try. Then there's Meta, which feels like a
Speaker 4:  immediate hard no. Yeah, yeah. And I think the TikTok user base would
Speaker 4:  revolt and leave if they tried
Speaker 5:  Meta would do it. It wouldn't be allowed to do it.
Speaker 4:  Oh, sure. What? Mark Zuckerberg's a killer. Yeah. He'd be like a hundred
Speaker 4:  million dollars. Like how many people do I have to kill? I'll just, it's
Speaker 4:  it's done. It's been done.
Speaker 5:  And then at that point, I think Meadow would own the five most popular apps
Speaker 5:  in existence.
Speaker 4:  And also the regulators have a really good argument from Meta right now,
Speaker 4:  which, hey, you just made threads from scratch and it's doing great
Speaker 4:  by some, you know, fake accounting. It's bigger than
Speaker 4:  Twitter. And I only say fake because Twitter's numbers are fake. And then
Speaker 4:  it's like sensor tower numbers, which are weird. Like
Speaker 6:  No one's numbers are real. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You just, you just mash together a bunch of very truthy feeling numbers,
Speaker 4:  you know, like Threads is bigger than Twitter. Fine. But the argument would
Speaker 4:  be, well, you can do it on your own. You don't need, you don't need this.
Speaker 4:  So we'll see. So that's okay. That's all the companies with valuations in
Speaker 4:  the Ts. Notably, they're all tech companies. Then you
Speaker 4:  slide down one notch, you go from six to seven, the valuations are
Speaker 4:  now in the bees and the billions. And I would just say these are much
Speaker 4:  funnier companies to consider Berkshire Hathaway.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yes. That's the most likely, honestly.
Speaker 4:  Warren Buffet,
Speaker 6:  Warren Buffet, Warren Buffet's, like social media, Warren
Speaker 5:  Buffet, let's go out Warren Buffet, like Warren Buffet buying TikTok so that
Speaker 5:  he could become like the ultimate TikTok in the way that Elon Musk bought
Speaker 5:  Twitter. So he could just be the tweeter. Yeah. Like perfect.
Speaker 4:  When I think of Warren Buffet, I love for, I think of the phrase burnout
Speaker 4:  not fade away and buying TikTok. Really
Speaker 4:  just light of fire, baby. Just get out there. You got guy you
Speaker 5:  Got driving his old car to McDonald's every morning. Just vlogging on TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Are you kidding? Come on.
Speaker 4:  It would be great. I could see it. It, I don't know how it fits in the, in
Speaker 4:  the portfolio. It would be good.
Speaker 4:  Eli Lilly. It feels like a no
Speaker 4:  Visa.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  JP Morgan Chase. Why not have a bank owned
Speaker 4:  TikTok? What
Speaker 5:  If TikTok was just payments processing
Speaker 4:  At the end of the day? Tesla is here at number 12 on market cap list. Although
Speaker 4:  that valuation fluctuating wildly with every breath Elon
Speaker 4:  takes. That feels like an obvious No. Although the man does
Speaker 4:  love a social network. So I mean,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Is is Elon Musk himself a totally
Speaker 5:  bonkers poss
Speaker 4:  Here? Elon, I will say Elon, you know, he's doing whatever. He is doing Twitter
Speaker 4:  and he is got Linda out there being like, Twitter's a video first platform.
Speaker 4:  And then Elon is the most text forward person in the entire world. That's
Speaker 4:  it. I don't think so. Yeah, he's
Speaker 6:  Sent you a
Speaker 4:  TikTok. This one's interesting. Walmart, which actually tried
Speaker 4:  to enter the TikTok sweepstakes long ago. That's great. On, on the list.
Speaker 4:  A huge American company would be fascinating. I think for the same reasons
Speaker 4:  as Amazon, right? Can we, can we build a new kind of
Speaker 4:  shopping distribution? I don't know. It doesn't, it does not seem likely.
Speaker 4:  It does not seem like that's what America
Speaker 6:  Wants. They, they have so many ambitions and a lot of money, but like
Speaker 6:  Amazon, I don't want it.
Speaker 4:  All right. I'm just gonna read the, the, the next five and as an exercise
Speaker 4:  for the reader, just like silently consider them and send us an email over
Speaker 4:  which ones you think should buy TikTok of
Speaker 4:  this list. ExxonMobil? Yes.
Speaker 4:  MasterCard, Proctor and Gamble. Home
Speaker 4:  Depot. Costco, bank of America.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Costco is something.
Speaker 6:  Costco. There
Speaker 5:  We go. I just wanna pause on Costco for one second. You know, what is a
Speaker 5:  brand that everybody loves?
Speaker 4:  Cost. Yeah. People love Costco, but if
Speaker 6:  They have to start paying influencers, a living wage
Speaker 6:  like they do with their, their regular staff. No, that's,
Speaker 6:  that's too much
Speaker 4:  Money. Yeah. Costco is like, well, you know, it's a well run company in that
Speaker 4:  way. Then there's the two tech companies I skipped over here, Oracle, which
Speaker 4:  is already in the mix. You could see it, right? They're already in the mix
Speaker 4:  for a reason. And then Salesforce, which I, I think we should end
Speaker 4:  with Salesforce. Oh. Because that is the darkest outcome for
Speaker 4:  TikTok.
Speaker 5:  So, so Salesforce buys TikTok and tries to turn it
Speaker 5:  into what LinkedIn became for Microsoft, basically. Yeah. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  Salesforce just goes all in on like business
Speaker 5:  TikTok,
Speaker 4:  Why not? This is the future of American small businesses happening on
Speaker 4:  TikTok. Small business. TikTok is still my favorite thing. They're pressure
Speaker 4:  washer guys out there today. I mean, like, it's spring baby light it up and
Speaker 4:  then they're immediately making TikTok shop content where they're trying
Speaker 4:  to convince me to buy an extremely obviously cheap surface
Speaker 4:  cleaner where like they plug it in and you see the whole thing dent in as
Speaker 4:  they plug in the w I'm like, what are we doing here? Anyway, sorry. I have
Speaker 4:  a lot of feelings about TikTok right now.
Speaker 5:  You you might watch too many ads on TikTok. I just, the
Speaker 4:  Whole thing is
Speaker 5:  You just scroll past them, you know that, right? Like you just scroll past
Speaker 5:  them. I'm just saying, I just scroll until I get bloopers from the office.
Speaker 5:  So I don't even know what you're talking about.
Speaker 4:  Have you started seeing they're, they're doing like the shimmer effect across
Speaker 4:  it to prevent the, the content id. It's very good. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  TikTok, honestly, Disney should buy TikTok because TikTok
Speaker 4:  is the most impressive laboratory of copyright infringement that
Speaker 4:  exists in the world today. And, and maybe in world history.
Speaker 5:  So I was actually gonna bring up Disney as a, as a wild card here. I don't
Speaker 5:  think Disney can afford to do this, but I think like Disney kicked the tires
Speaker 5:  on Twitter a bunch of years ago. Disney is interested in
Speaker 5:  a new media startup in a really big
Speaker 5:  way. I think TikTok is probably too big to be that thing for Disney. Yes.
Speaker 5:  But I, I, if I'm Bob Iger, like I bet, I bet there is a
Speaker 5:  memo in that boardroom.
Speaker 6:  Is Disney still interested? 'cause I think when they kicked the tires
Speaker 6:  on Twitter, that was also around the same time they launched Fusion, which
Speaker 6:  was like their, their digital media play. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That was the wasting money of in Disney era.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I think they're beyond this point now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. IDI don't think so. I think Disney is in the business of
Speaker 5:  getting young people to watch its stuff. And that the answer
Speaker 5:  to that is TikTok.
Speaker 4:  I want everyone pull over in a car and just imagine with a TikTok
Speaker 4:  themed part of Walt Disney World look like,
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 4:  My God, close that loop.
Speaker 5:  Every ride is 60 seconds long and you just leap
Speaker 4:  From somewhat unsatisfying unless you do it a hundred times in a
Speaker 4:  row. I don't think Bob Iger wants to talk about content moderation
Speaker 4:  in front of Congress. I think that destroys Disney's brand right? To be anywhere
Speaker 4:  close to there is evidence that teenage girls are feeling
Speaker 4:  depressed because of our product. Not, not Disney Zone,
Speaker 4:  but it's inter it's interesting to consider because it is where, you know,
Speaker 4:  like Disney missed out on Coco Melon, which is a YouTube phenomenon and it's
Speaker 4:  now a Netflix phenomenon. They, they don't have a pipeline for that stuff.
Speaker 4:  And TikTok might be that pipeline. I just, I don't think they have the money
Speaker 4:  and I don't think they have the, the mental stamina based
Speaker 4:  on all the other things. They're going Disney. All right, that's the list.
Speaker 4:  There's other stuff you can talk about a MD and Pepsi and Netflix, but I
Speaker 4:  feel like that's the list and you gotta end with Salesforce. 'cause I, I
Speaker 4:  just want everyone to consider the darkest timeline. We'll see what
Speaker 4:  happens. You know, a bunch of forge reporters are out in the world
Speaker 4:  pounding the pavement to see who wants to buy things. What Alex, he told
Speaker 4:  me yesterday when I, when I was like, Hey, let's go through your list. He's
Speaker 4:  like, it's crickets. 'cause they're all afraid of Lean Con. And I think that
Speaker 4:  is, that was how they were talking before Biden signed the
Speaker 4:  bill. And I think that will change in the weeks to come, but there's gonna
Speaker 4:  be a lawsuit. We'll see how it goes. Kind of a wild time though. I like
Speaker 4:  I if you've been paying attention to the rich chest, you know that we, we
Speaker 4:  generally think like all of social media and the internet, it's being like
Speaker 4:  table flipped upheaval and like things are shaken out in different ways.
Speaker 4:  This is one pretty big table flip.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think it's, it's gonna be really interesting to see how
Speaker 5:  this radiates outward too, because like there's been a lot of talk in the
Speaker 5:  last couple of days about what this is gonna mean for Instagram and for
Speaker 5:  YouTube shorts and for Snap and there's this sense
Speaker 5:  of a handful of companies in the US that really stand to benefit from the
Speaker 5:  downfall of TikTok. And I think where people go
Speaker 5:  if they go and how those platforms start to change is going
Speaker 5:  to yet again upend the rest of everything. Like, if, if
Speaker 5:  TikTok suddenly floods into YouTube, it will
Speaker 5:  change YouTube completely. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Oh, there's gonna be a land grab. A hundred percent. Yeah. Between like the
Speaker 6:  QVC nature of TikTok and this all those like
Speaker 6:  Edge case people, the people who aren't really really into it are gonna be
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, I'll just, I'll go somewhere else. 'cause at least I'm, it's,
Speaker 6:  I'm not getting sold to.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean and this is
Speaker 1:  neighbor. State Farm is
Speaker 1:  there.
Speaker 4:  We are back. I just wanna say if at and t bought
Speaker 4:  TikTok, imagine what Zach Snyder would get up to.
Speaker 5:  Well it would immediately be spun off into some other, David Zaslav would
Speaker 5:  own it six months later, so would be, it would be fine.
Speaker 4:  Four three grayscale tiktoks for everyone. Extremely dark.
Speaker 5:  We've been talking a lot about terrible movies on this podcast recently.
Speaker 5:  Should we talk about Rebel Moon?
Speaker 4:  I refuse. I That one's like very bad. Like it's, it's so
Speaker 4:  obviously
Speaker 6:  Bad. Yeah, I haven't even looked at it.
Speaker 4:  I saw, I don't think this is a spoiler. I saw a screenshot of one of the
Speaker 4:  final scenes where the ship is revealed to be a woman who was hog tied. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Good stuff.
Speaker 4:  Doesn't seem like my bag
Speaker 5:  Also. That's almost certainly a spoiler. And I just don't care. So I'm sorry
Speaker 5:  to everyone who No,
Speaker 6:  I mean it does make me kind of wanna watch it, but just so I can be mad while
Speaker 6:  watching it.
Speaker 4:  That's how I felt about hard to be
Speaker 4:  clear. Just raise watch. All right. Enough enough of the Zach Steiner
Speaker 4:  talk. Yeah, look, the man took his bag from at and t and he made a square
Speaker 4:  movie in Grayscale where? Where Superman is super
Speaker 4:  weird.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you bring it up like three out of every four podcasts.
Speaker 4:  You know the thing, the policy thing that we're not about, we don't have
Speaker 4:  time to talk about is soon and net neutrality will become the law of land
Speaker 4:  again. And everyone's gonna talk about how net neutrality didn't mean anything,
Speaker 4:  blah blah. And I'm just gonna be like, justice League happened to you
Speaker 4:  because you repealed net neutrality. That's a real, that was a real
Speaker 4:  outcome of repealing net neutrality. You don't believe me, but it's a
Speaker 4:  hundred percent true. Alright, I, I wanna talk about the thing that I, I've
Speaker 4:  been most excited to talk about all week. I, David, you
Speaker 4:  went to a party at the TWA Hotel at JFK in New York, which is
Speaker 4:  a wild place to have a gadget launch. You
Speaker 4:  saw Rabbit happen, there was a demo on stage, which we
Speaker 4:  should talk about 'cause I have a lot of feelings about that demo. And now
Speaker 4:  you are holding a Rabbit R one. You have a review
Speaker 5:  Can show it. I have it right here. It's just so orange. It's mine. I bought
Speaker 5:  this with my own money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh that's yours. It's our
Speaker 5:  Own unit. It's not, they didn't do review units, huh? This was, so what I
Speaker 5:  went to was the, the pickup party for
Speaker 5:  the first, I think it was 300 R ones that came out.
Speaker 5:  So they, they invited a bunch of media but we had to buy our own in order
Speaker 5:  to get into the event, which is fine. That's very good. I should say to people
Speaker 5:  like for 200 bucks, don't know how this process normally works. Often for
Speaker 5:  reviews. People will ship us something and we'll test it and review it and
Speaker 5:  then we ship it back. That's usually how it works. Because if I had to buy
Speaker 5:  every single thing that I wrote about, I would be homeless.
Speaker 5:  So that's usually how it works. But in this case, we had to buy the thing.
Speaker 5:  So now I, I own this thing. Luckily it was only $200, but so we get to the
Speaker 5:  TWA hotel, which is amazing. I had never been, it's like it's
Speaker 5:  an a very old terminal at JFK that has since been
Speaker 5:  converted into this very swanky kind of old fashioned
Speaker 5:  hotel. It's awesome. Highly recommend. I had never been there before. I will
Speaker 5:  probably never go again, but it was super cool.
Speaker 6:  You should only go if you're having to fly in or out of
Speaker 6:  JFK.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh God. It took me two trains in an Uber to get there. Like I don't
Speaker 5:  recommend this plan otherwise. But yeah, so it
Speaker 5:  was, it was me and 300 or so other people along with a bunch of
Speaker 5:  rapid employees in this space. They had done lots of, you know,
Speaker 5:  work to overhaul it. It had a big stage in the middle. They had a 360 photo
Speaker 5:  booth and a speakeasy upstairs. There was a bar with signature drinks. They
Speaker 5:  were doing all kinds of merchy stuff. It was very much like
Speaker 5:  an old school tech party. Like I haven't been to one of those since before
Speaker 5:  the pandemic where it's just like a company with too much money that's just
Speaker 5:  like, what if we just blew a bunch of it on this large event
Speaker 5:  space. And then Jesse Lou, the founder and
Speaker 5:  CEO got up and spent like an hour basically just
Speaker 5:  doing demos. And he's been doing this for the last couple of
Speaker 5:  months, kind of with increasing frequency, showing off how this thing works
Speaker 5:  and what it can do and all this stuff. And he just sort of stood on stage
Speaker 5:  and did a bunch of demos that were ostensibly live and I have many questions
Speaker 5:  about all of them. And then
Speaker 5:  gave them out to the, that first group of, you know,
Speaker 5:  300 people. And so it was, everybody there had like literally bought
Speaker 5:  a thing to be there. So the room was very excited. Yeah. And there were a
Speaker 5:  lot of people who had been in the discord for months sort of reading about
Speaker 5:  the humane reviews and figuring out what was going on and trying to get
Speaker 5:  details on what this thing would do and how it would work. And lots of people,
Speaker 5:  it was very funny like being in line for a bar while people are behind me
Speaker 5:  debating how the large language model works. And there was a guy who was
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, every time you ask a question, you're eating into that $199
Speaker 5:  price. And I was just like, these are my people. It was great. I had, I had
Speaker 5:  a delightful time except that it was at 7:00 PM on a Tuesday night. And
Speaker 5:  I'm very old and I can't hang like that anymore.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. So you've got the thing, now
Speaker 5:  I have the thing, it's right here.
Speaker 4:  You've only had it for days day. I, I don't think this is a review. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But I was watching the demo that he'd done on stage and two things struck
Speaker 4:  me with that demo one, there was a little disclaimer on the stream
Speaker 4:  and he showed himself turning off the wifi. The entire demo was done over
Speaker 4:  4G LTE, not 5G. The one that is famously claimed to
Speaker 4:  have very low latency, a good old 4G LT, which is an
Speaker 4:  interesting choice, but that's 199 bucks. And then he kept pointing out how
Speaker 4:  fast everything was. At one point he took a picture and
Speaker 4:  you know, the thing did the thing where the AI told you it was in the picture.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, I don't, I don't think that uploaded over 4G
Speaker 4:  LT that fast. Like literally just the basics of it didn't seem like it
Speaker 4:  was making sense.
Speaker 5:  So two things on that one, none of it was
Speaker 5:  fast. Like go back and watch it again. He did a very good
Speaker 5:  job of sort of talking through his demos so that while it was waiting
Speaker 5:  for stuff to happen, it would work. And there were, there were a few times
Speaker 5:  where he would do something and it would pretty instantly do it. But what
Speaker 5:  it does very well is it, it it signposts as it's doing
Speaker 5:  stuff. So like you'll ask it a question and it'll respond and say, let me
Speaker 5:  go get that for you. And then it'll say, I'm gonna get that for you. And
Speaker 5:  then it gets it for you. And what you've, what it doesn't do is just sort
Speaker 5:  of leave you hanging in awkward silence for several seconds, which feels
Speaker 5:  like an eternity, but it does take a while to
Speaker 5:  do a lot of things. And with the photo having now tested
Speaker 5:  this a bunch, what it does when you like hold up the thing and say, you know,
Speaker 5:  look at this and tell me what you see, which is like the, the sort
Speaker 5:  of computer vision thing that a lot of these gadgets do. It's not taking
Speaker 5:  a good picture. It takes an awful picture. And I can show
Speaker 5:  you the awful pictures I've been taking, but it literally, it just uploads
Speaker 5:  just the tiniest little bit of data in order to be able to answer
Speaker 5:  the question, is there a crowd full of people
Speaker 5:  or like a begonia in front of you, right? Like that is the fidelity that
Speaker 5:  it needs and that is all of the fidelity that it gets. So I actually think
Speaker 5:  that particular one seems plausible to me.
Speaker 4:  I guess I, I do need to watch it again. 'cause I was just struck by the speed
Speaker 4:  at which things appeared to be happening over a
Speaker 4:  4G connection, not even a 5G connection over a 4G connection. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 4:  I'm not even putting this on rabbit. I'm just like, I've used LTE connections
Speaker 4:  before. They're not fast.
Speaker 4:  Especially now, right? Whenever all the bandwidth is being prioritized to
Speaker 4:  the 5G connections, all the spectrum is being prioritized over there. That
Speaker 4:  was one. And then there's the other thing that struck me was how much stuff
Speaker 4:  it can't do that we were shown at doing at the, at the first launch of
Speaker 4:  event N Cs, where that stuff is just nowhere close. Like everything.
Speaker 5:  It's weird. And even after being at that launch event where he got up
Speaker 5:  on stage, Jesse and said out loud, I am going to demo all of
Speaker 5:  the things that it can do from day one. And I have been testing those things
Speaker 5:  and it can't do some of them. So the, one of
Speaker 5:  the big things that Rabbit has been talking about is this thing called the
Speaker 5:  large action model, right? And the idea is that it can actually like learn
Speaker 5:  how to use apps on your behalf. That's like, that's its whole pitch. Not,
Speaker 5:  it's not just like a thing for chat GPT, it's a thing where you can say,
Speaker 5:  go do Spotify for me, right? Or like, go interact with
Speaker 5:  Photoshop. For me, that's literally one of the things they've talked about.
Speaker 5:  Like it, you can teach it how to use Photoshop for you. That
Speaker 5:  is not coming soon. It's not. It's, it's like a thing
Speaker 5:  that somebody had the idea to do. It's like when we talk about car renders,
Speaker 5:  right? It's like it's at the render stage as far as I can tell. And then
Speaker 5:  there's a bunch of stuff that seems very basic. Like I gave
Speaker 5:  humane a lot of crap for not supporting things
Speaker 5:  like alarms and reminders and these very basic things. And you know what
Speaker 5:  the Rabbit R one doesn't support is alarms and
Speaker 5:  reminders. And I, I ironically like
Speaker 5:  humane, like the deja vu of all of this is bananas for me. Like, like
Speaker 5:  Humane Jesse stood on stage and put up a big slide with here's
Speaker 5:  all the cool stuff we're shipping in summer of 2024. And it's things
Speaker 5:  like alarm, calendar, contacts, GPS, memory
Speaker 5:  recall, travel planning, Yelp,
Speaker 5:  like basic things. These are, these are, these are things that you should
Speaker 5:  have from the beginning and there's just not really
Speaker 5:  a good reason not to have it. So right now, again, I've been testing this
Speaker 5:  thing for a grand total of like 16 hours, some of which I
Speaker 5:  was asleep, right? Like I, none of this is final yet, but like a lot
Speaker 5:  of things about this device do not work very well. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it only has four apps, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I, I will say the, the biggest, most
Speaker 5:  complicated question about the rabbit is how this large action model
Speaker 5:  works and thus what you're giving it access to. So when you log into the
Speaker 5:  website, which is called Rabbit Hole, which I enjoy very much, the branding
Speaker 5:  on this thing is on point. They've done a very good job when you're playing
Speaker 5:  music, there's a little rabbit guy with headphones on, like it's
Speaker 5:  great, excellent branding exercise, well done. But you log
Speaker 5:  into Rabbit Hole and you go to, there's a tab called Connections and
Speaker 5:  it like lists all the apps you can connect to. And right now it's, it's four,
Speaker 5:  like you said, it's Spotify, DoorDash, Uber, and
Speaker 5:  Midjourney, which is a strange four, but
Speaker 5:  whatever. And then so you, you
Speaker 5:  click on the connect button and what it does is open up a virtual
Speaker 5:  machine on Rabbit servers through
Speaker 5:  which you just log into the Spotify web interface or the
Speaker 5:  DoorDash web interface. So like I click on the DoorDash button and literally
Speaker 5:  it opens the DoorDash website, just the homepage of
Speaker 5:  doordash.com on the thing. And then I had to go click sign in, I had to
Speaker 5:  enter in my credentials and then I clicked continue like I'm signing into
Speaker 5:  DoorDash normally. And then it closes that window because now it has stored
Speaker 5:  my credentials. And what Rabbit says is it doesn't store your credentials,
Speaker 5:  it just stores like an authentication token so that you stay logged in.
Speaker 5:  And to that, I say like, have you ever tried to stay logged in to a service
Speaker 5:  on the internet? Like it's not possible. You can't, the keep me logged in
Speaker 5:  button doesn't work. So there is something else going on here.
Speaker 5:  And there are a lot of people who are like, oh, what you're doing is you're
Speaker 5:  just exposing all of your login credentials to a virtual machine that's just
Speaker 5:  sitting on rabbit's, computer, computer. Like you're just uploading your
Speaker 5:  life to rabbit servers. That's stupid. Well,
Speaker 4:  There's also one step beyond that, which is you have now logged
Speaker 4:  into DoorDash on Rabbit servers and it's logged in,
Speaker 4:  right? So it doesn't matter if you have the credential or not you, well,
Speaker 4:  right. You have perfect logged in access to DoorDash.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And I think for me, I
Speaker 5:  like, I'm logging into all of these things because I have to test this thing,
Speaker 5:  but like even logging into Spotify felt strange. Like
Speaker 5:  this is like, this is actually kind of a lot of access to information
Speaker 5:  about me that you just have now. And that's
Speaker 5:  odd. But anyway, the interface for that sucks. The
Speaker 5:  system isn't very good. I have not yet successfully used DoorDash. Every
Speaker 5:  single time I try to do it, I like, I, you know, you press the button on
Speaker 5:  the side and you say, order me some food. And every single time it says DoorDash
Speaker 5:  may take a while to load on Rabbit os, which is very funny. And then it just
Speaker 5:  immediately fails every single time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So what's happening in the background there, from what I gather,
Speaker 4:  what the heart of the large action model is,
Speaker 4:  it's gonna click around on the DoorDash website for
Speaker 4:  you.
Speaker 5:  I believe that's correct. Yeah. I think the, the long term plan here is to
Speaker 5:  have more, let's say, robust
Speaker 5:  integrations that they can actually, like, there's way to you do that with
Speaker 5:  like structured data that you can get to some of that stuff. But, but
Speaker 4:  That's the old way, right? Like DoorDash has an API and we've built a weird
Speaker 4:  interface for DoorDash in our little orange square. You could, you
Speaker 4:  don't need a bunch of AI for that.
Speaker 5:  No, you don't. But it works. And right.
Speaker 4:  So, but this is like you're logged into DoorDash and we're gonna show you
Speaker 4:  pictures of the, we're gonna understand the DoorDash interface for you, and
Speaker 4:  then we're going to let, you're gonna say, buy me this food and we're just
Speaker 4:  gonna use the DoorDash website on your behalf. Like that's the, that that
Speaker 4:  is my understanding of what the large action model should do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, that, that's, that's exactly right. And part of the process that
Speaker 5:  they make, that they're in theory one day someday when this launch is gonna
Speaker 5:  make you go through is training the apps that you use. Like this
Speaker 5:  is where you click to do X and this is where you click to do Y and you
Speaker 5:  scroll down to get to the other thing. And that is, that is how you teach
Speaker 5:  these models how to do this stuff. And the reason they've worked with these
Speaker 5:  four apps now is because their people have done that training
Speaker 5:  with these four apps. So like literally
Speaker 4:  Do there have deals with the four apps, have deals with Spotify and, and
Speaker 4:  Uber and DoorDash, you know, Uber and DoorDash are competitors. Like Uber
Speaker 4:  Eats exists. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I, I don't agree about this. Don't, I don't know, but I sure doubt it. I
Speaker 5:  have
Speaker 6:  A more basic question. Okay. I, I know you've only spent what,
Speaker 6:  16 hours with it, but in that time,
Speaker 6:  have you had an experience with it where you're like, oh wow,
Speaker 6:  I would willingly train this model when I get more
Speaker 6:  access to it to have these kind of experience with another
Speaker 6:  app?
Speaker 5:  The Spotify integration is the one to me that I'm like, this is the thing
Speaker 5:  I really want to work. Does it? No,
Speaker 5:  it's awful. Oh, okay. It is so, so bad you guys. I can't, I
Speaker 5:  can't even tell you how bad it is. Like let me, I'll just give you a bunch
Speaker 5:  of examples. I say to the thing, play my Discover Weekly
Speaker 5:  playlist and it plays every single time a song called Can You Discover
Speaker 5:  by a Band's Discovery? That's good. I say
Speaker 5:  Play Beyonce's new album and it played like a, a lullaby
Speaker 5:  version of Crazy In Love. Yeah. And it's weird because it's not even
Speaker 5:  like, it's just searching and playing the first result. Because if you go
Speaker 5:  to Spotify and Search Discover Weekly, it shows you
Speaker 5:  your Discovery Weekly playlist. So in theory, that shouldn't be that hard
Speaker 5:  a problem. It's doing some weird thing that I can't figure out
Speaker 5:  yet and almost always does it wrong. So if I ask like a very basic
Speaker 5:  question like play Justin
Speaker 5:  Timberlake that works. It'll play a Justin Timberlake song. And I have
Speaker 5:  done that many, many times. But anything more
Speaker 5:  complicated, at least so far, it has fallen apart on me every single time.
Speaker 4:  See, this is why I don't understand about how it's working. If you're
Speaker 4:  saying you can go to Spotify's website and type in Crazy in
Speaker 4:  Love and it shows you the first result is correct,
Speaker 4:  theoretically that is all the large action model is doing on the backend,
Speaker 4:  right? It's looking at the web interface, it's identifying the search box,
Speaker 4:  it's entering the string. It's saying here's the first result and it's double
Speaker 4:  clicking on it. by the way, this is not some radically new idea,
Speaker 4:  right? Like big businesses deploy robotic process
Speaker 4:  automation to run their billing systems on Windows. $98 billion
Speaker 4:  companies exist to deploy this at the
Speaker 5:  Enterprise scale. And Rabbit has more or less acknowledged that that is what
Speaker 5:  it's doing. by the way, there was this weird thing, I don't know if you saw
Speaker 5:  that there somebody, it was called like Rabbit
Speaker 5:  scam on GitHub. GitHub sort of said they had found a bunch of
Speaker 5:  code showing that All Rabbit was doing was
Speaker 5:  just lifting Yeah. Stuff off of webpages and running the same systems
Speaker 5:  that everybody else runs in order to like understand what's going on on a
Speaker 5:  website. And they were like, this isn't as scary
Speaker 5:  as you think it is. Like yeah, that's, that's what we do. That's our public
Speaker 5:  code. So like they're acknowledging that this is what is going on and I think,
Speaker 4:  But it's not working like, yeah, no, if you were, again, if you're like some
Speaker 4:  midsize hospital system and you hire UiPath to show up and do
Speaker 4:  RPA and it's like we're doing the lullaby versions, you're like fire the
Speaker 4:  mid, it's like get rid of 'em, right? UiPath is a billion dollar company.
Speaker 4:  'cause it can do robotic process automation reliably at scale. Like
Speaker 4:  why Rabbit
Speaker 6:  Costs $200, well
Speaker 4:  It costs $200. But even the thing, like the basic thing, we entered a string
Speaker 4:  of text into a search box and we played the first result. Like
Speaker 4:  the industry, the robotic process automation industry knows
Speaker 4:  how to do that. So why can't it do that? Like it feels like it's doing
Speaker 4:  something else. Is
Speaker 6:  It like inserting a little clippy in there? It's like, is it
Speaker 6:  trying to like be smart for you?
Speaker 5:  It might be, it's also possible that it's doing something different with
Speaker 5:  Spotify because Spotify Yeah, like has an actual sort of
Speaker 5:  corpus of data that it lets other systems access.
Speaker 5:  So I can't speak to Spotify in particular, but at least from the demos that
Speaker 5:  I've seen, again, I haven't been able to get DoorDash to work once. But from
Speaker 5:  Jesse's demo of DoorDash, that seemed very clearly to
Speaker 5:  be the thing using the website because the way that he showed what was
Speaker 5:  working was he kept refreshing doordash.com on his
Speaker 5:  laptop and it would show that something had been added to the cart
Speaker 5:  on the website. That's not like a thing that happens if you use
Speaker 5:  like a third party API to do all of this stuff. That is just a thing using
Speaker 5:  the web app for you.
Speaker 4:  So I, this is the part that I'm just like most interested in because DoorDash
Speaker 4:  is the slowest one and they said it's the slowest one. And there comes a
Speaker 4:  point at which all this like just horsepower through the interface with
Speaker 4:  computer vision, it just hits the wall of like, what if you
Speaker 4:  just had an API? Right? What if you could just, instead of trying to
Speaker 4:  have a robot figure out what's happening on an interface made for
Speaker 4:  humans, what if you just let the robot talk to the application directly using
Speaker 4:  actual API commands the example that I'll give people, one of
Speaker 4:  my favorite companies that I I wished had succeeded was Cavo, the universal
Speaker 4:  remote company that I hyped up on the show over and over again. They were
Speaker 4:  doing exactly this to build a universal remote. You plugged all of your devices
Speaker 4:  into the cavo and the CAVO is doing computer vision to watch your Apple TV
Speaker 4:  interface or whatever and click around on your behalf. So you could just
Speaker 4:  say the name of a show and the name of a service and it would just like bang
Speaker 4:  around your TV and use it for you. And this shit was awesome when it
Speaker 4:  worked. It was very slow and it was extraordinarily
Speaker 4:  brittle when it broke.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It never worked. Like the win is very generous.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It, it sometimes it worked, you know,
Speaker 6:  And it was cool. It was very cool in those moments it worked, but most of
Speaker 6:  the time it didn't.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then the thing that like really got you was it wouldn't even show
Speaker 4:  you the clicking around. Like it would put up the Cavo screen and you would
Speaker 4:  hear it like booping in the background. You'd be like, can I just see if
Speaker 4:  you're getting this right? I would love to check your work. And then you'd
Speaker 4:  be like, that is not what I wanted to happen at all. Or it would just error
Speaker 4:  out. But the idea that like you've got a bunch of devices plugged into a
Speaker 4:  central HDMI switcher and you're like, watch this show and it knows
Speaker 4:  that's the Apple tv and you're like, I wanna play PlayStation. And it switches
Speaker 4:  the input and bangs around play. Like all of that was awesome, but
Speaker 4:  it, it failed because fundamentally the approach is brittle,
Speaker 4:  right? It just, it there, there, there are known ways for it to break when
Speaker 4:  the computer cannot understand what's seeing it's
Speaker 4:  $199. Like yeah, can they overcome this problem or do they actually
Speaker 4:  just need to build a bunch of APIs? And then you've got something that looks
Speaker 4:  like a, I think you have in your piece that's just a mid-range. Android,
Speaker 4:  Android smartphone with weird apps.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The answer is ultimately both. Right. And I think, I
Speaker 5:  think Humane has said this about what it's working on. Rabbit has alluded
Speaker 5:  to this too. Like they eventually want to build
Speaker 5:  big enough systems that others will actually integrate with. 'cause the reason
Speaker 5:  to not rely on APIs is that you're a tiny startup and nobody cares about
Speaker 5:  you and nobody will make the deals with you. Yeah. So you do hacky computer
Speaker 5:  vision stuff so that you don't have to get the deals because
Speaker 5:  by and large, they can't really stop you from doing that. They can, they
Speaker 5:  can get mad and they have some ways, but like that's, it's a more winnable
Speaker 5:  game in that particular respect. But the way for them to do this, they all
Speaker 5:  acknowledge, is to eventually have those more
Speaker 5:  official partnerships that just give, give them access to the DoorDash API
Speaker 5:  and then like, this doesn't all have to be ai, right? Like
Speaker 5:  I, I actually think we, we like run into a trap when we assume that the only
Speaker 5:  way to do AI things is for all of it to be ai. Like some of it shouldn't
Speaker 5:  be, we've solved a lot of problems actually. Like we're, we're pretty good
Speaker 5:  at a lot of things that don't require pinging a large language models to
Speaker 5:  order McDonald's. Like that's like ordering McDonald's on the internet is
Speaker 5:  like a solved problem. We're very good at it now. And so I think we will
Speaker 5:  land there with a lot of stuff. But one nice thing you can do with these
Speaker 5:  models is you can hack together a kind of n
Speaker 5:  solution to a lot of those business deals without needing those business
Speaker 5:  deals. And I think that's what all of these companies are doing. At first,
Speaker 4:  The question is what DoorDash is gonna say, this is a legal scraping of our
Speaker 4:  website. Like there's another whole set of problems that you kind of walk,
Speaker 4:  walk
Speaker 5:  Into immediately. I mean the good news for DoorDash is DoorDash just wants
Speaker 5:  you to order McDonald's. Right? Like, I I, and, and I think that's the, the
Speaker 5:  assumption that they're making, right? Like Uber wants me and an Uber and
Speaker 5:  is very happy anything that happens that gets me in an Uber, same with DoorDash
Speaker 5:  and me or McDonald's.
Speaker 4:  Does Spotify wanna stream copyrighted music to an
Speaker 4:  orange rectangle?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, yeah it did. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  They did. But how are buttons list of things that are coming? It's Apple
Speaker 4:  music and it's like, is it, Is that one
Speaker 4:  coming? Have you met them? Like Yeah, they
Speaker 4:  don't like competitors. They're not, you know, even Apple Music, which is
Speaker 4:  theoretically the, you know, horizontal play across. Like have you tried
Speaker 4:  Apple Music on Android? You think your weird little robot is
Speaker 4:  gonna have to use Apple Music Web that way? I don't know. We'll see, I'm
Speaker 4:  very excited for you to review this thing. I think that that central question
Speaker 4:  of like at $199 with no recurring fee,
Speaker 4:  can you make this a business that needs to improve on
Speaker 4:  a, some of the core AI features that is reliant on, look at it this way.
Speaker 4:  The thing you're saying, the bunch of these are solved problems,
Speaker 4:  right? Okay, that's great. The, the things that are sort of easiest
Speaker 4:  to do or solve problems, order some food, call a ride plate
Speaker 4:  songs, all API stuff that means you're relying on the AI to
Speaker 4:  solve all of the edge cases. Go to
Speaker 4:  Photoshop and draw a cropping square around a thing
Speaker 4:  like that is not a solved problem. You
Speaker 4:  cannot API your way into doing that in a Photoshop in the general case, you
Speaker 4:  can do it maybe in some specialized ways. Okay, you're now,
Speaker 4:  it's $199. No, no recurring revenue. Can you make an
Speaker 4:  AI that can solve for the general case of using a computer is the question
Speaker 4:  that this thing is asking. And I just like, dunno the answer.
Speaker 6:  I feel the answer answer's probably no. But David, I just need you to do
Speaker 6:  one thing for me. Can you hold it up to the mic and like click one of the
Speaker 6:  buttons? I just need to know how cliquey they are.
Speaker 4:  Kranz, like do some ASMR shit.
Speaker 5:  It's pretty quiet. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's so
Speaker 4:  Quiet. That's nothing. Yeah, that's it's clicking right now. Pull over in
Speaker 4:  your car, turn off the engine, roll up the windows. Click,
Speaker 5:  Click, click. That's what it sounds like that
Speaker 4:  Was No, do it without the clicks. They're they're pulled over now. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Ah, that sounds so bad. Yeah, the people in the electric cars are like, what
Speaker 4:  Engine?
Speaker 5:  No, but to me the thing is like the, the big open question for me with both
Speaker 5:  the humane pin and this was like, what is like the one
Speaker 5:  thing that this is actually for, and I keep hoping it's gonna be music and
Speaker 5:  Humane almost got there except for all the ways it was
Speaker 5:  awful. And this, like, I was excited because it's Spotify and Spotify
Speaker 5:  is what I and hundreds of millions of other people use to listen to
Speaker 5:  music just not there. But so far
Speaker 5:  it's a pretty good like, question and answer machine, which I'm happy about.
Speaker 5:  Rabbit has a big integration with perplexity, the AI search
Speaker 5:  engine. So for like relatively real
Speaker 5:  time questions like the, the NFL draft is tomorrow as
Speaker 5:  we're recording this. And I was asking it a bunch of questions about like
Speaker 5:  who is likely to go where in the NFL draft and it had good UpToDate
Speaker 5:  information about the NFL draft. Like that's cool. Cue
Speaker 5:  all the people saying, why can't I just do it on my smartphone? Like, you
Speaker 5:  super duper can. But what's weird to me about this so far, and
Speaker 5:  again I have a lot of testing and stuff left to do, is like this little thing,
Speaker 5:  the gadget itself feels right for this moment
Speaker 5:  in ai. Like it's pretty cheap. It's not that ambitious. It's sort of silly
Speaker 5:  and fun. It's like worst case scenario, it's just
Speaker 5:  like, will look cool on my desk. Yeah. People pay a lot more for
Speaker 5:  cool things on their desk, right? But
Speaker 5:  they're also at the same time talking about this
Speaker 5:  massive world changing vision for where it will all go. And
Speaker 5:  Jesse, to his credit, is constantly sort of tamping that down
Speaker 5:  saying we're just at the, at the very beginning, we haven't solved most of
Speaker 5:  these problems. He said something at the beginning of his speech last night
Speaker 5:  that was like, I'm gonna try all these demos and if
Speaker 5:  they don't work, I'll try 'em again. And if they still don't work, we'll
Speaker 5:  fix it. And I was like, what a, what a perfect summation of like the time
Speaker 5:  we're in for ai. And so I think all of that is right and I, I
Speaker 5:  appreciate kind of the like realism of what Rabbit is doing
Speaker 5:  as opposed to like humane, which is like, you know, sort of yeah. Brought
Speaker 5:  from the earth fully formed. We have solved this, but
Speaker 5:  then there's still like wildly overstating what this thing can actually do
Speaker 5:  in a way that I find very frustrating.
Speaker 4:  There's a bunch of comments on your hands on posts, like why are you being
Speaker 4:  nice to this inhumane? And it's like, well one, it's not actually the review
Speaker 4:  yet important note, like we're just holding the thing and two, it's
Speaker 4:  like it's $200. Yeah. Yeah. And that's just different. But
Speaker 4:  I I I am very curious to see as you go through this three review process,
Speaker 4:  how much it needs to lean on the computer
Speaker 4:  revision piece. Because the more it has to do that,
Speaker 4:  which is the AI of it all the worse it's gonna be. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I I feel that very keenly. All right. Some more things we should talk about
Speaker 4:  in this section. Apple announced a May 7th event for new iPads. Two
Speaker 4:  things about this one, it's just an infomercial. There's just like tune in
Speaker 4:  to watch their stream. No one's going anywhere. Yeah. And then they sp they,
Speaker 4:  they're calling it let it loose. And our friend Joanna Stern pointed this
Speaker 4:  out, the s in loose looks like a G so it's let it luge, which
Speaker 4:  is, if you want to think about what that means in the context of new
Speaker 4:  iPads, I welcome you. I personally believe Apple is announcing
Speaker 4:  luge oriented
Speaker 6:  IPad.
Speaker 4:  It's very weird.
Speaker 5:  It's an i it's a huge like boogie board size, iPad's,
Speaker 4:  IPad. It's a cursive capital S so it's like weird. And so like in context
Speaker 4:  it looks like a lowercase G. Very good. It's
Speaker 4:  pretty, it feels like we're gonna get an noad iPad.
Speaker 4:  Right? That's the rumor. It feels like they'll just chip, bump everything
Speaker 4:  else. I'm trying very hard not to buy an noad iPad.
Speaker 6:  Mm. But you're gonna
Speaker 4:  I why? Like I don't use the one I have
Speaker 6:  So that I'm not the only one. Like I need, I need other people making bad
Speaker 6:  person. We're
Speaker 4:  Gonna do, do a group buy. We're gonna call Tim Cook and we're like, we get
Speaker 4:  a group rate on Ill-conceived
Speaker 4:  iPads. It, it just feels like this.
Speaker 4:  What they actually need to do is announce new software for the iPad, not
Speaker 4:  new hardware.
Speaker 5:  There were a bunch of people talking about this that I really enjoyed. That
Speaker 5:  was like, after this came out everybody was like, relax the real iPad
Speaker 5:  event is ww DC in June. Like this, this doesn't matter. Right. And I think
Speaker 5:  that's probably true. Like the strangest thing about the iPad is
Speaker 5:  the hardware has been really good for a really long time. I
Speaker 5:  would say other than please move the camera from the bad spot to the
Speaker 5:  good spot. I have very few issues with the iPad's hardware
Speaker 5:  and have not had issues for a long time. I have a million issues
Speaker 5:  with what it's like to actually use the damn thing.
Speaker 6:  That's why I'm kind of curious about, one of the big rumors is that they're
Speaker 6:  gonna do a new magic keyboard that's like aluminum or
Speaker 6:  something. It's more like a just a laptop case.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. With a bigger track pad. Like that would be cool.
Speaker 4:  David, I'm pointing out the 10th gen iPad moved. They moved the camera.
Speaker 5:  I know, but they haven't, they haven't on the other ones. Move it on all
Speaker 5:  the other places.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna probably do it on, on the pro in the air this time around.
Speaker 4:  At some point they're, they have to admit that the pro is just a weird laptop.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Maybe this is the time.
Speaker 4:  Look, I've been, I've been using my ancient now 11 inch iPad Pro is
Speaker 4:  like a tablet. Like this is dumb. Like it's just laptop all the time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I want to use it as tablet. Boy do I wanna read stereo review
Speaker 4:  in p in PDF form on my iPad as God
Speaker 4:  intended. But it's just like the, the thing,
Speaker 4:  it's just like yearns to be in. Its its laptop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You're also, you I I've noticed you started sending a lot of Apple
Speaker 5:  News plus links around, which makes me think you, you are becoming more of
Speaker 5:  an iPad user.
Speaker 4:  I'm just a boomer now. I'm a dad. I live in the suburbs. Sold
Speaker 4:  my truck. I haven't sold the truck yet. It's heartbreaking. It's selling
Speaker 4:  my stupid truck. It's, this is just me trying to not use Twitter
Speaker 4:  and Wall Street Journal and Conde NAS publications are Apple News plus I
Speaker 4:  got suckered in the deal. Great, fine.
Speaker 4:  Right. But do I love it? Do I
Speaker 4:  think Apple News? I just, I'm not gonna pass any judgments on Apple News
Speaker 4:  plus I'm just gonna ask anybody who has the product go and look at the list
Speaker 4:  of trending stories and be like, who do we think this audience
Speaker 4:  is? You just make that
Speaker 4:  distinction all in your I don't, I'm not gonna pass any judgment, but I'm
Speaker 4:  like that they're not getting younger, is it what I would
Speaker 4:  say it doesn't appear that they're getting younger with
Speaker 4:  time. But anyway, I I, yeah, I'm trying to use the iPad as a
Speaker 4:  consumption device and the iPad Pro in particular, it, it kind
Speaker 4:  of yearns to be in the keyboard case and I hope they just go for it. Be like,
Speaker 4:  we have a weird mini laptop, it's fine. You know, but they,
Speaker 4:  the software has to change. So that's, that's coming very soon. May 7th,
Speaker 4:  a couple weeks from now, The Ray Band, meta Smart Glasses got a big update.
Speaker 4:  They have multimodal AI now they announced some new colors and it's in various
Speaker 4:  three designs that they have. I feel like I'm like about to buy one of these.
Speaker 4:  You should. A meta also announced that it's making headsets with other
Speaker 4:  people. An attempt to make sort of Quest os the Open VR
Speaker 4:  headset, which Zuckerberg has talked about a lot. They're gonna make an
Speaker 4:  Xbox VR headset. It's a limited edition Meta Quest. So you can see
Speaker 4:  Zuckerberg is like, we're gonna be the Android of vr. Well, Apple's doing
Speaker 4:  whatever it's doing over here. Can
Speaker 6:  We, we call out the fact that it is so funny to watch Microsoft go from being
Speaker 6:  like, we are gonna create the VR head
Speaker 6:  like the VR space. We are, we're gonna do it all. Mixed
Speaker 6:  reality. We're gonna own this place to, we're gonna do a
Speaker 6:  rebranded Meta Quest three.
Speaker 4:  I mean if you're Microsoft and you're out there being like the future is
Speaker 4:  Xbox Game streaming, you might as well look an ab it and run. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  I it's the Quest is basically like an Android phone right on your face.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Take the free ads. I mean, and the, the way they described it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  it's a journey is so funny. It's like, it's a, it's a Quest three inspired
Speaker 5:  by Xbox or something, which just makes me think like somebody
Speaker 5:  at Microsoft like sent over the hex codes for the Xbox Green and
Speaker 5:  we're like, do whatever you want. Leave us alone.
Speaker 6:  I hope it is like just huge. I hope it is so chunky. Like the
Speaker 6:  original Xbox,
Speaker 5:  It's just a full on like master
Speaker 6:  Helmet. I it OG Xbox Controller. That'd be so, yeah. Yeah, just over the
Speaker 6:  top.
Speaker 4:  So the os the question s is being
Speaker 4:  rebranded I guess to Meta Horizon os which is just a lot of
Speaker 5:  Words. Yeah. Yeah. It's weird. There was was like Horizon
Speaker 5:  Worlds and then there was Horizon Work Rooms. So that was kind
Speaker 5:  of always gonna be their thing. But now they're trying to make it even bigger.
Speaker 5:  I will say Horizon. Great name for an operating system. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Great job. The names are insane.
Speaker 4:  It's just a lot of words. So H Horizon os runs on the Quest hardware and
Speaker 4:  Xbox is making it Xbox inspired. That's a
Speaker 4:  lot good news though. More
Speaker 4:  companies that are known for their good names will be participating in this
Speaker 4:  ecosystem, including Ass Republic of Gamers. Very excited
Speaker 4:  for the names to come from them. Lenovo will make
Speaker 4:  something that will be, it'll
Speaker 6:  Have Legion in it somewhere.
Speaker 4:  A a word salad. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Lenovo Legion Quest Flip 13.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And, and then all of these are gonna run on Qualcomm chips.
Speaker 4:  Qualcomm also well known for stretching the boundaries of
Speaker 4:  tracking beyond all human recognition. So that's interesting. We'll see how
Speaker 4:  that goes. Right. They're the players. They have the momentum, the Quest,
Speaker 4:  quest three itself got an update where the pass through videos of higher
Speaker 4:  quality and looks better when you look at phones. There's momentum over
Speaker 4:  there. I want to come back actually to the The Ray band
Speaker 4:  glasses, which are a hit. Like they feel like a quiet hit. I
Speaker 4:  know a lot of people who have them. Our friend Joanna Stern says she doesn't
Speaker 4:  travel or go on field video shoots without them anymore.
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  They're really good. I've got a pair. I, I should wear mine more. I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm legit thinking about going and getting prescription lenses put in it.
Speaker 6:  'cause I, I always have to put my contacts in and it's like that friction's
Speaker 6:  too much. But every time I wear 'em I'm like, why don't I wear my contacts
Speaker 6:  more often? These like are awesome.
Speaker 4:  They're cheap, they're 300 bucks. I've got a friend who in the pandemic,
Speaker 4:  she just became one of those people who doesn't live anywhere. She's just
Speaker 4:  like, literally last week she's like, I'm working from a boat. And I was
Speaker 4:  like, I hate you. You seem great. All of her photos are from the Meta quest
Speaker 4:  now on
Speaker 5:  Instagram. Well and or The Ray band. The thing meta got really right, was
Speaker 5:  it, it went the correct direction in terms of saying like,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna pick a very small number of things for this device to do
Speaker 5:  and it's gonna do them pretty well. And then we're going to slowly
Speaker 5:  add things that it can do. Like it, when it started it was like, okay,
Speaker 5:  it's a pretty good speaker system if you like wanna listen to music
Speaker 5:  or podcast or whatever. That's mostly what I use it for. It's become like,
Speaker 5:  when I'm out on a walk or whatever, I wear it instead I wear the glasses
Speaker 5:  instead of headphones now, which is awesome. Pretty good
Speaker 5:  Camera people really like taking photos and videos that way. And now they're
Speaker 5:  adding on, they're like, okay, now we can do, they had the, you could like
Speaker 5:  ask meta AI questions, but now they're adding the multimodal stuff and so
Speaker 5:  they're like, they're sequencing this stuff really smartly instead of
Speaker 5:  like promising the world from the very beginning and then not
Speaker 5:  meeting people's expectations, which I think is really the key. These are
Speaker 5:  better than people expected them to be, which is so, so, so
Speaker 5:  rare in this moment with hardware. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And again, the first thing they just had to be was some nice looking Ray
Speaker 4:  bands. Yeah. And it's like, all right, you get a pair of Wayfairs, you get
Speaker 4:  these other two designs. Like people just like those designs. Whether or
Speaker 4:  not the battery lasts the camera works is like, oh no, there's just a pair
Speaker 4:  of Wayfairs. Like maybe it'll be cool. And now they're deciding all this
Speaker 4:  cool stuff. Well
Speaker 5:  It's like that old Mitch Hedberg joke, right? That like when an escalator,
Speaker 5:  an escalator doesn't break, it just becomes stairs. Like that's, that's these
Speaker 5:  glasses. Right. Like the worst case scenario is you just have a nice pair
Speaker 5:  of sunglasses.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And, and honestly 300 bucks for a pay pair of ribands is like a little
Speaker 4:  bit of a premium, but it's not crazy. No. And now the multimodal ai, you
Speaker 4:  can do the thing, what am I looking at? And it tells you Right, right. That's
Speaker 4:  the big trick. That's the, it's emerging as the party trick of these AI
Speaker 4:  devices
Speaker 5:  And it's as messy as anything else. Like V Song did a bunch of testing with
Speaker 5:  it and it was like hilariously wrong about cars and all that stuff. And it's
Speaker 5:  always like all these systems, it's very confident and just lies to your
Speaker 5:  face.
Speaker 4:  I actually, I'm, I'm starting to be of the mind that we need to push
Speaker 4:  back strongly against calling any of this ai. We just need to call them what
Speaker 4:  language models. 'cause they just make up words.
Speaker 4:  There's no intelligence artificial or otherwise happening here.
Speaker 4:  That's gonna be a hard fight. I don't think we're gonna, I'm not gonna win
Speaker 4:  that fight. There's a lot of fights I've won. I'm not gonna win that fight.
Speaker 4:  Support you. But the conflation of can you talk with, are you smart? Is in
Speaker 4:  a real weird moment on the internet right now. Turns out you talk
Speaker 4:  maybe less smart. You're the, I talk a lot that just, I'm
Speaker 4:  not trying to burn anybody just putting that out there. Fascinating
Speaker 4:  to me though. Put just add all this up, right? You've got meta doing this
Speaker 4:  sort of open stuff with Lenovo and all these other companies. You've got
Speaker 4:  the glasses which are sort of a sneaky hit that people like
Speaker 4:  next to, okay. Analyst reports the vision Pro demand is
Speaker 4:  suffering. Right. And it's like, did Apple just get outgunned by a pair
Speaker 4:  of Raybans? Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  That's crazy.
Speaker 5:  It's nuts.
Speaker 6:  It's not crazy though. It was a $3,500 bet against a
Speaker 6:  $300 bed.
Speaker 5:  I don't even think it's that. I think Apple just miscalculated. Like I, the,
Speaker 5:  the longer I use these devices, the more I can't
Speaker 5:  believe Apple didn't make the smart glasses. Like I I if in
Speaker 5:  the thing that Apple has traditionally done, which is like build a thing
Speaker 5:  and then build the more complicated thing and then build the more complicated.
Speaker 5:  Like Apple is actually very good at laddering that stuff up over time. And
Speaker 5:  in this case, just way overshot it was like, it, it it was like
Speaker 5:  building four generations too soon and trying
Speaker 5:  to convince people to buy it. And what if, if they had just built like the
Speaker 5:  iPod version of it, which is just like a nice thing for listening to music
Speaker 5:  and talking to an assistant. People would've gone nuts for it. And it is
Speaker 5:  like, it, it continues to blow my mind that Apple just, I think picked
Speaker 5:  wrong.
Speaker 6:  They could still do it. We could still get the Apple vision Air.
Speaker 5:  Oh I'm sure we will. I I'm, I'm sure that's where it's headed. But like I,
Speaker 5:  the, what the Humane folks told me is they were like, okay, well when we
Speaker 5:  built this, we decided to build the hardest thing first based on the idea
Speaker 5:  that then it's much easier to sort of ratchet our ambition down and sell
Speaker 5:  cheaper, simpler versions of the thing. But it turns out if you blow the
Speaker 5:  expensive one, you don't get the chance to do the next things. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  I think Apple has kind of dug itself a hole here by so aggressively
Speaker 5:  overshooting. I also like all these supply chain numbers
Speaker 5:  should be taken with like a giant heap of salt all the time. But I will say
Speaker 5:  anecdotally nobody talks about the Vision Pro anymore.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It has totally faded.
Speaker 4:  I spend a lot of time looking in the subreddit and it
Speaker 4:  is, a lot of people are like, what are, what are we using this thing for?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, and then there's like one app comes out and it's a hit and
Speaker 4:  people really like it, but it's a little little dire in
Speaker 4:  there. I'm just gonna say, I was writing in the review. Yep. Let's putting
Speaker 4:  that out there. It took a lot of heat for that one.
Speaker 5:  It's better out here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's better. Right. The question is like, is it worth putting it on?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And there isn't anything that makes it worth putting on. There's a
Speaker 4:  few things sometimes, but even Mark Gerberman in his newsletter where he
Speaker 4:  was talking about some of these results, he's like, I'm wearing this thing
Speaker 4:  less and less like it's lonely. Like he's like, I don't wanna watch basketball.
Speaker 4:  And I it is weird. It's just like a weird moment in hardware.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Where the big expensive stuff didn't go and the the sort of cheap stuff
Speaker 4:  that's making small promises. It's gaining a new kind of momentum. I think
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna buy 'em, I I don't know why I have too many glasses. I lose them.
Speaker 4:  It, I have a rule to not buy glasses that are more than 50 bucks. Not buy
Speaker 4:  sunglasses are more than 50 bucks. 'cause they're gone. That's good. I might
Speaker 4:  as well flush the $50 down the toilet. You know what I mean? But there's
Speaker 4:  a part it's like what if
Speaker 5:  The good news is these, these ones are very heavy so
Speaker 5:  it will be hard to lose them. They did like,
Speaker 6:  And the the charging case is really nice. So you're gonna be like,
Speaker 6:  oh I can't lose my charging case because it's so nice. And then you'll never
Speaker 6:  lose your glasses,
Speaker 4:  Alex, you've never underestimate
Speaker 6:  I'm just, I'm filled with optimism today. Yeah. Just
Speaker 6:  all optimism.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're gonna take a break. I'm gonna look on the meta website and
Speaker 4:  see
Speaker 4:  one. Just to recap, Tesla has laid off more than 10% of its workforce, like
Speaker 4:  14,000 people. Bunch of executives are leaving, including
Speaker 4:  the guy who was in charge of the powertrain and energy division. And then
Speaker 4:  the head of policy who's the guy who gets autonomy like approved also
Speaker 4:  gone a lot going on with Tesla, right? There's a rumor that they're gonna
Speaker 4:  cancel the cheap EV and then they kind of said they weren't gonna cancel
Speaker 4:  it. But it also sounds like what they're really gonna do is make the model
Speaker 4:  Y cheaper. They've, they've recalled all
Speaker 4:  3,800 cyber trucks, 3,878 cyber
Speaker 4:  trucks. But they talked, Elon said
Speaker 4:  optimist would be a fully sentient robot that would quote
Speaker 4:  expand the economy, the world economy infinitely. Oh
Speaker 5:  Sick.
Speaker 4:  They'll be selling that at the end of next year. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  So a classic Elon bump there. I
Speaker 5:  Think he even said in that announce in that like in that sentence I think
Speaker 5:  he said, but I'm just guessing. It's like alright
Speaker 4:  Cool. Yeah
Speaker 5:  Great investor call,
Speaker 4:  There's a new model three performance. Great. But they
Speaker 4:  don't have his new cars. There's not really a plan to have new cars. They're
Speaker 4:  gonna announce some robax plan on August 8th. And then there's this
Speaker 4:  thing that they've been talking about, which he brought up again on the earnings
Speaker 4:  call today, which I just wanna talk about for five seconds 'cause it is bonkers
Speaker 4:  to me. He was talking about how many H one hundreds Tesla has, he went on
Speaker 4:  his very funny side about how he doesn't like calling them GPUs because they
Speaker 4:  don't have any graphics but whatever it's, and you can hear the investors
Speaker 4:  being like, what? And then he got to, we
Speaker 4:  have all these H one hundreds and we are doing inference AI inference
Speaker 4:  more efficiently 'cause we had to learn how to do it in the car which is
Speaker 4:  constrained. Great. That makes sense. It's a good argument. Why not? You
Speaker 4:  can measure it whether that makes sense. And then he is like, we've got this
Speaker 4:  like AWS play, which they've hinted at before, but he was like, what we're
Speaker 4:  gonna do is run it on all the Teslas that are just sitting around.
Speaker 4:  So quote, if you can imagine in the future perhaps there's a fleet of 100
Speaker 4:  million Teslas and on average they've gotten like maybe a kilowatt of inference
Speaker 4:  compute that's a hundred gigawatts of inference compute distributed all
Speaker 4:  around the world. It's pretty hard to put together a hundred gigawatts of
Speaker 4:  AI compute. So, and perhaps maybe instead of using the car 10
Speaker 4:  hours a week, we use it 50 hours a week while it's sitting there. That leaves
Speaker 4:  over a hundred hours a week where the car inference computer can be doing
Speaker 4:  something else and it seems like it would be a waste to not use it. My man
Speaker 4:  is describing set at home for Teslas.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. What do those terms of service look like,
Speaker 4:  Right? It's just like you do you wanna run compute models on your car
Speaker 4:  while it's like sitting in the driveway your car, which by the way famously
Speaker 4:  runs on electricity
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 4:  Like where's that electricity, where's that power bill coming from? Are you
Speaker 4:  gonna get it cheaper? She buy a car and now Elon can use it to do whatever
Speaker 4:  inference to run whatever robax fleet that he thinks he's gonna need to run
Speaker 4:  it. Also, I dunno if you know about AWS, they like knowing where the computers
Speaker 4:  are
Speaker 5:  And and typically those computers are not driving somewhere between 20 and
Speaker 5:  a hundred miles an hour while they're being
Speaker 4:  Used. Yeah's like, you know, I've interviewed the C of a Wix. I I would say
Speaker 4:  a a core assumption of that conversation was that he knew where the servers
Speaker 4:  were and they were not ever at risk of crashing into
Speaker 4:  other servers.
Speaker 5:  This feels like such a classic Elon Musk thing. 'cause even as you were reading
Speaker 5:  that it's like okay, this sort of makes sense like
Speaker 5:  big fleet, lots of compute sitting around, what if we use the compute and
Speaker 5:  then it's like you raise your hand and you go like how is any of that gonna
Speaker 5:  work? And it's like, ah, don't worry about that. Like
Speaker 4:  It's fine.
Speaker 6:  He's doing it at the same time that like Chevy is is
Speaker 6:  getting a lot of flack because they've been using their computers to spy
Speaker 6:  on people and report it to their insurance companies. Yeah. Like maybe not
Speaker 6:  the time to be like, yeah we you've got a computer in there and I want to
Speaker 6:  use it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like it's mine now. Yeah. I just think this is the one where it's
Speaker 4:  like what what Elon is searching for is arguments that Tesla
Speaker 4:  will have massive margins, right? Software company style margins instead
Speaker 4:  of car company margins. Right. And the thing that's hammering Tesla right
Speaker 4:  now is they have absolutely car company margins again. 'cause they dropped
Speaker 4:  the price so much and they don't have any new cars. So the competition is
Speaker 4:  here and you can see the sales fell like 55%. Like they, they're just not
Speaker 4:  doing it anymore. And so he is, he's concocting these arguments
Speaker 4:  where a sentient optimist robot will expand the
Speaker 4:  world economy by infinity. That's a pretty good margin. Yeah, that's
Speaker 5:  Good.
Speaker 4:  It's, I mean if you know more power to you if you pull that off and then
Speaker 4:  he is like, and I'm gonna build this like distributed data center so I now
Speaker 4:  I'm running AWS instead of having to build a data center in Texas or wherever
Speaker 4:  you might need to build it and it's like this is the, the truth
Speaker 4:  is outing here, right? Like it is very hard to get
Speaker 4:  from here to, I'm running a distributed AI supercomputer
Speaker 4:  in every Tesla in the world. It's like, is this
Speaker 4:  very hard?
Speaker 6:  It kind of feels a little like a peloton moment for
Speaker 6:  him. You know, where Peloton, everybody and everybody got a Peloton
Speaker 6:  because they wanted one and it feels like maybe everyone who wanted the Tesla
Speaker 6:  got one.
Speaker 4:  Well lemme just ask you this question about this distributed difference computer.
Speaker 4:  What happens at rush hour?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. The, the total capacity of the computer just like blunts like, like
Speaker 4:  hour by hour. Like it's always five o'clock somewhere like every hour. There's
Speaker 4:  just like huge dip in capacity like starts and it comes, starts coming back
Speaker 4:  online at 7:00 PM like literally the sun sets on Tesla's
Speaker 4:  compute capacity across the United States every single day. Like it's very
Speaker 4:  hard to, to pull this through. I think. I think that Tesla
Speaker 4:  is in a like fascinating moment.
Speaker 5:  They,
Speaker 4:  I am not sure it five years from now it looks anything like this company.
Speaker 5:  No. Yeah. It, it seems hard to imagine. I mean I think
Speaker 5:  this company has already gone through so many weirder iterations than
Speaker 5:  anybody would've expected and continues to sort of chug
Speaker 5:  along. Like Tesla feels very much like a cockroach at this point. That sort
Speaker 5:  of nothing could happen to Tesla that would surprise me. And also it will
Speaker 5:  be the last company that exists on planet earth.
Speaker 6:  Oh I disagree but I I I like it feels like it's
Speaker 6:  going to crap.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Even like a bunch of Tesla fans were like, I dunno about this anymore.
Speaker 5:  Well that's, I mean that, that's one of the big questions to me. I was talking
Speaker 5:  about this with Andy Hawkins yesterday. Like thi this
Speaker 5:  question of kind of the Elon Musk effect that
Speaker 5:  the people who are predisposed to want
Speaker 5:  Teslas for a lot of the reasons that Tesla promotes them being good for the
Speaker 5:  world and all that are also people who are likely to not be psyched
Speaker 5:  about Elon Musk's shenanigans, particularly as he
Speaker 5:  runs X. And so trying to figure out how to
Speaker 5:  quantify how much of this is about the, the challenges in
Speaker 5:  the EV market, how much this is about plugin hybrids, which I thought was
Speaker 5:  a really interesting thing that Mus said during the earnings call. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  He blamed a lot of the struggle on the rise in plugin
Speaker 5:  hybrids and how much of this is just
Speaker 5:  people voting with their dollars and voting against Elon Musk is
Speaker 5:  really hard to know. And I think it's gonna be super obvious in retrospect
Speaker 5:  and I'm very curious how it's gonna shake out.
Speaker 6:  There's also the fact that if you're just going to buy a car and
Speaker 6:  you're going out in the world and you're like, I'm gonna buy a car and you
Speaker 6:  don't buy a car based on I, then you go and you look and
Speaker 6:  you say, okay, Teslas have really bad reliability.
Speaker 6:  They're really hard to repair, they're really hard to just get an appointment.
Speaker 6:  And oftentimes that appointment's horrible. The build quality is crap
Speaker 6:  to the point that like they keep having to do recalls on the cyber truck.
Speaker 6:  Like those are all just signs of a badly run company. And I think,
Speaker 6:  I think this company had a lot of advantage 'cause it was first mover and
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk is an incredible salesman but now like the bloom is off that
Speaker 6:  rose Twitter x, whatever you wanna call it, ripped that right off.
Speaker 6:  And now it's like okay, we see that this guy is just a really good salesman
Speaker 6:  and he pulls it all out of his butt and he is not some genius. And actually
Speaker 6:  he's not running a very good company because he is running 12 at once and
Speaker 6:  no one can do that. Even Elon Musk.
Speaker 4:  Alex is Alex Crans. The Verge with a K. Yeah, just email
Speaker 4:  that hit me up. I'm
Speaker 6:  Doing you a favor. I'm here to debate you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, debate Alex with a K please. It's gonna be great. Connie
Speaker 4:  potty Tesla trolls. I don't think you're
Speaker 4:  wrong. I just think, I think the fundamentals of the auto business, he has
Speaker 4:  to not be a car company and it, the thing that is happening is it's getting
Speaker 4:  sucked into being a car company
Speaker 5:  Because it is one and
Speaker 4:  Because it, yeah, because it is one you make cars and the blaming the hybrid
Speaker 4:  thing is super funny to me. Like yes, I own a hybrid, but like you're basically
Speaker 4:  telling your customers they're wrong. Right? And how do you get
Speaker 4:  across, how do you get past the market making a decision? I'm regulate the
Speaker 4:  market. Joe Biden, will you make hybrids illegal is like kind of the only
Speaker 4:  answer to that. Or you can yell at everyone that they're wrong and like yelling
Speaker 4:  at the market that it's wrong is like not great. That
Speaker 6:  That always famously works for everyone who does it.
Speaker 4:  This is famously why Betamax beat VHS. Yeah. Everyone
Speaker 4:  knows it. I don't think hybrid. I think hybrid's, everyone I know who has
Speaker 4:  hybrid knows it's like some short term solution to the infrastructure not
Speaker 4:  being there. Yeah. And they, like everyone prefers to drive around in the
Speaker 4:  battery.
Speaker 5:  My dad just, you're all wrong, recently bought a Prius after spending
Speaker 5:  months looking for an EV because he just like, they just
Speaker 5:  couldn't find one that made sense and decided that in their lives at this
Speaker 5:  point, like the next car should be an electric car.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The car right now should not be, and I think a lot of people are making
Speaker 5:  that decision.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Also the new Prius, it doesn't look like an angry robot anymore.
Speaker 5:  No, it kind, it's kind of great.
Speaker 4:  It kind kinda looks great. Yeah. We'll see. All right.
Speaker 4:  Lightning round. What you got David?
Speaker 5:  So while we're talking about Apple TV plus soon to be augmented
Speaker 5:  by the purchase of TikTok, there was, there was a report
Speaker 5:  this week that Apple has been negotiating with
Speaker 5:  fifa, which is the, the governing body of soccer around the
Speaker 5:  world to do a new
Speaker 5:  global tournament exclusively on Apple tv.
Speaker 5:  Plus I find this fascinating for a bunch of reasons. One,
Speaker 5:  apple is like increasingly deep into the sports world. They have this
Speaker 5:  thing with Major League soccer that's going very well it seems in part because,
Speaker 5:  you know, lion O Messi decided to play for the MLS but the numbers
Speaker 5:  that have been thrown around are upwards of a billion dollars from
Speaker 5:  Apple to be the one to stream this tournament. Which is
Speaker 5:  like, we've spent a lot of time talking about Apple TV plus as kind of
Speaker 5:  a somewhere between sort of a
Speaker 5:  lark and a side project that it was never going to be really material to
Speaker 5:  Apple. It was just kind of a thing it did on the side in order to sell more
Speaker 5:  subscriptions to iCloud, right? Like that was always the play. This seems
Speaker 5:  to me to be the sort of thing that you only do if you're actually serious
Speaker 5:  about turning this into a real thing. And Apple is
Speaker 5:  just further and further and further into sports in a way that I
Speaker 5:  continue to find surprising and sort of fascinating. And they wanna
Speaker 5:  invent a completely new thing with some of the biggest
Speaker 5:  soccer clubs in the world, which would be huge and is immediately
Speaker 5:  the kind of thing that would draw potentially millions of new people to Apple
Speaker 5:  TV plus. But this is like there, there's no
Speaker 5:  indication, I think it was a New York Times story that first reported this,
Speaker 5:  that this is like a done deal, but they wanna do it next summer, which
Speaker 5:  means like, this is a big thing that could happen very quickly. And
Speaker 5:  like, I, I don't know, apple TV plus just continues to
Speaker 5:  be a bigger thing than I think I've given it credit for.
Speaker 6:  I think it kind of makes sense though right now for Apple to do it
Speaker 6:  because Hollywood is in a state of flux, right? Like, like
Speaker 6:  streaming is completely changing the game there. Everybody's trying to
Speaker 6:  figure out where the revenue streams are and the tech companies are
Speaker 6:  kind of leading the forefront. The tech Kuo companies are running Hollywood
Speaker 6:  in a way they haven't previously. And Apple is doing
Speaker 6:  it really, really well. It's a smaller play than everybody else, but it's
Speaker 6:  it's doing it intelligently and it's like, yeah, this, this makes sense for
Speaker 6:  them to go in and just like, take a couple of streaming services
Speaker 6:  out. Yeah. Just body a few with money and, and
Speaker 6:  then buy, snap up the, the dregs of that later, right?
Speaker 6:  Like make a deal with Skydance or whatever. But
Speaker 5:  If that's the play, apple could just walk into the offices of any
Speaker 5:  streaming service it wanted to and just write a check for its valuation
Speaker 5:  and then some. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But they don't wanna do that. They wanna buy like they want, they want cheap
Speaker 6:  licenses and stuff like that. That's what runs these services. But
Speaker 5:  This is what I'm saying, a billion dollars to create a new soccer tournament
Speaker 5:  is not that thing. Like the MLS thing. I understood. That's a relatively
Speaker 5:  small, relatively safe bet. And they got to essentially take
Speaker 5:  over that whole project. This is a mu this is like negotiating for
Speaker 5:  NFL rights, which Apple like famously has not one because it became
Speaker 4:  Close for Sunday ticket.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it wanted, what has been reported is that it wanted like complete
Speaker 5:  control over this thing. And you're not getting that from the NFL and you're
Speaker 5:  not getting it from fifa and they're still willing to throw billions of dollars
Speaker 5:  at it. It's fascinating.
Speaker 6:  But this would drive subscriptions in a way.
Speaker 4:  Oh, for short
Speaker 5:  Is stick. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Eddie Hugs smart. He's also huge sports
Speaker 5:  Fan. Yeah, he
Speaker 4:  Is. And he knows sports sort the stickiest thing. We'll, see, I
Speaker 4:  I'm, I I think Apple has to get good at broadcasting sports.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If they're not great at it right now. Yeah. So the, the more they get
Speaker 4:  into it, the more they have to com. Does app, like, does Tim Cook want to
Speaker 4:  sit in Congress and talk about content moderation? I don't know. Does Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook wanna sit in front of a bunch of soccer fans and talk about penalties?
Speaker 4:  Like, I don't know about
Speaker 6:  Leader, he's
Speaker 5:  Issue for that. But does Tim Cook want to go like sit in a box at the World
Speaker 5:  Cup, like Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 4:  That's true. All right. Crans. What? You got
Speaker 6:  Qualcomm. They're back baby. We'll see,
Speaker 4:  We
Speaker 12:  Say that immediate every once in while. Undercut Just immediate, immediate.
Speaker 6:  Undercut. Undercut. Just immediate. Yeah. So Qualcomm has announced,
Speaker 6:  they previously announced some new processors
Speaker 6:  and these are their kind of responses to the X 86
Speaker 6:  processors from Intel and a MD. This is meant to go in Windows
Speaker 6:  machines meant to compete with Apple. They're saying they're as
Speaker 6:  fast as the M three and it's gonna blow it out of the water.
Speaker 6:  Joanna Nees are our new laptop reviewer. Went and checked
Speaker 6:  some of them out in some very, very, very, very
Speaker 6:  controlled demos. And she was like, there could be something there. She
Speaker 6:  was saying it was slower than the M three in some cases faster in
Speaker 6:  others.
Speaker 5:  I mean, if it's even in the ballpark of the M three, that's a huge deal.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's a huge deal. Right. And I think there's, there's some really interesting
Speaker 6:  stuff, particularly around architecture. They're not doing the big little
Speaker 6:  core deal that everybody else does, where they're like, these are performance
Speaker 6:  cores, these are efficiency cores. They're like, yeah, these are all performance
Speaker 6:  cores. Sure. 'cause they're just that efficient. Oh God, that was me doing
Speaker 6:  a Qualcomm impressions. Sorry. So
Speaker 6:  it's the, the Snapdragon X Elite was the ones previously announced
Speaker 6:  and now we have the Snapdragon X plus.
Speaker 4:  Oh good.
Speaker 6:  Which is slower the, because it's not elite.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna throw a premium in there. No one's gonna know what's going
Speaker 4:  on. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Nobody will know.
Speaker 5:  I appreciate that. When you, when you try to match Apple's performance, you
Speaker 5:  also try to match Apple's Insane name scheme. This is good.
Speaker 6:  And it's, it's all bad. They're all, they're all the names are bad, but we
Speaker 6:  don't know when. These are probably gonna come this year. We'll probably
Speaker 6:  start seeing 'em in some Windows devices this year. And I am really,
Speaker 6:  really curious to see it because like if Arm and Windows can work for
Speaker 6:  once, that would be huge. Yeah. But they famously kinda like
Speaker 6:  screwed it up the last time.
Speaker 5:  So, and the time before that. And the time before that. And
Speaker 6:  The time before that. Yeah, the time
Speaker 5:  Before that.
Speaker 6:  That's why I immediately undercut Qualcomm's like back at it again
Speaker 6:  at the Krispy Kreme.
Speaker 5:  The Microsoft event is May 20th or 21st or something. And they're gonna
Speaker 5:  announce new surfaces that we think by all indications
Speaker 5:  are going to run these things. So we're gonna, we're gonna see this sooner
Speaker 5:  rather than later. But Tom's been reporting about how excited Microsoft
Speaker 5:  is. Qualcomm seems very excited. This could be something.
Speaker 5:  Well,
Speaker 6:  We've got Compex coming in. That's May 31st. Oh yeah, my birthday.
Speaker 6:  Hey.
Speaker 5:  Oh, it's gonna be like laptop explosion here. That's gonna be
Speaker 6:  Great. Yeah. So, so we're gonna get a lot of laptops soon. Yeah. And I suspect
Speaker 6:  a lot of them are gonna have these, these new processors in them. Will these
Speaker 6:  processors be good?
Speaker 4:  It's a big move away from Intel if there's a lot of laptops with these weird
Speaker 4:  tracking and chips in 'em. We'll see. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well, we'll also have to see. 'cause historically the laptop makers don't
Speaker 6:  like to ship the, the stuff besides Intel be
Speaker 6:  to, to reviewers to check out because they want you to check out the thing
Speaker 6:  that people actually buy. And that's usually the Intel products. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  it's, it's gonna be a fun one.
Speaker 4:  All right. Mine is very simple. So now has a new app. Looks
Speaker 4:  very good on mobile. They've sort of gotten rid of all the tabs and it's
Speaker 4:  just all just widgets. It's cool. They said it's gonna be faster. It's coming
Speaker 4:  out May 7th. We'll see if the mobile app is faster. This is not the thing
Speaker 4:  I actually wanna talk about. They are getting rid of their desktop apps,
Speaker 4:  which they've had forever. Oh wow. On Mac and Windows. And they're going
Speaker 4:  all to web apps and you can now, because it's web app, you can control your
Speaker 4:  Sonos from anywhere, which is interesting. I'm just pointing out that the
Speaker 4:  move to distribute applications on desktop computers to the
Speaker 4:  web instead of in native binaries is like
Speaker 4:  full speed ahead. Like it's over like, you know,
Speaker 4:  Dylan Field, the CO of Figma was like, why would you distribute an app on
Speaker 4:  an desktop computer any other way except the web. And like yeah, there's
Speaker 4:  electronic and some other stuff where you package it up and it like looks
Speaker 4:  native and da da da. But I saw this and I was like, oh, this is just ha
Speaker 4:  like this is a huge shift in computers that is like reaching
Speaker 4:  a point where it's, it's like no one even talks about it. Like
Speaker 4:  it just assumed that if you're gonna make a new app for desktop computers,
Speaker 4:  what you are actually shipping as a web app. Yeah. And I, the thing I point
Speaker 4:  to is the Vision Pro, the high end of computers, the cutting edge of
Speaker 4:  what a computer can be mounted directly to your face. All of the most
Speaker 4:  interesting apps was on the Vision Pro, the Netflix app, the YouTube app,
Speaker 4:  whatever are just custom web browsers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We really called that. by the way. I feel like we, we deserve credit
Speaker 5:  for saying over and over that the thing that the only thing that might save
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro is, is web apps. Yeah. That has been absolutely correct.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, I'm excited for the news thing. 'cause the old app is Indeed Slow.
Speaker 5:  Wasn't the old app supposed to fix the fact that the app before that
Speaker 5:  was slow and bad?
Speaker 4:  No. So they, this is like a long story. We had Patrick Spence on the show,
Speaker 4:  I think to explain himself to us when they did, I know
Speaker 5:  They had the
Speaker 4:  Old, old platform, which they now call S one. Right. Which was like
Speaker 4:  ancient. And they re-architected everything for the future and to support
Speaker 4:  Atmos and all this other stuff they wanted to do. And that's
Speaker 4:  called S two. So that was just an architecture update. It was not a,
Speaker 4:  we need to make it in faster
Speaker 5:  Update. Got it. So they kept their slow app but made it work on the new
Speaker 5:  architecture.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's a lot of arguments about like what the best way to run Sonos
Speaker 4:  is now. Like do you want run Sonos net, which is like a custom 2.4 gigs network.
Speaker 4:  You just wanna run everything on wifi, which Sonos says you should do good
Speaker 4:  times in these, in these subreddits.
Speaker 5:  I just use Spotify Connect and it works fine. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's fine.
Speaker 5:  I wish I had a more complicated, interesting idea. Not super works. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I never ever touched the Sonos app and I'm very happy about it. Air, I've
Speaker 4:  Used Airplay for years now. It's great. It works just fine. And you can group
Speaker 4:  things in airplay. You can group unlike Speakers in Airplay, which is a very
Speaker 4:  interesting, but I don't know, I still got a soft shot for it. All right.
Speaker 4:  That's, we are way over. We've touched on everything from web apps to
Speaker 4:  the future of Free Speech in America. Busy week to, to
Speaker 4:  whatever's going on with Tesla. It's a lot, it was a big, it was a busy week
Speaker 4:  and we got more of 'em coming. 'cause we are, we are head first into developer
Speaker 4:  conference season now. Yep. All right. I'm gonna start a GoFundMe for this
Speaker 4:  Oola iPad. You can hit me up. I'm so true.
Speaker 4:  Not
Speaker 5:  Tell Alex all your favorite things about your Tesla, if you have one. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  she'd love to hear 'em. Oh, I'm
Speaker 4:  Super excited. We need to say excited. Utterly forgot to say this because
Speaker 4:  we're so bad at this. We won Webby Awards. Thank you so much
Speaker 4:  for all the people who voted for us and the people's choice of the Vergecast.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. The judges who gave the, the same award to the Dakota
Speaker 4:  podcast. We, we really do appreciate it. It's, it's very cool that
Speaker 4:  we have been doing the show for as long as we're do doing it and people stroll
Speaker 4:  voting for us for these awards. I truly appreciate it. Sponsor
Speaker 7:  week.