# Transcript
ID: a510c0e4-5fa8-4de2-a36d-8ec4b8dfef5d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6850138001847277611/-5719303374909386537/s93290-US-6062s-1710497252.mp3
Description: The Verge 's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the US House of Representatives passing a bill that could ban TikTok, the streaming news of the week, a Dyson robot, and more.
Speaker 1:  Support for the show
Speaker 1:  recommendation of any stock or investment strategy.
Speaker 3:  combined with an AI code assistant and your preferred IDE for rapid
Speaker 3:  development all wrapped up in an auto maintain infrastructure.
Speaker 3:  Search Wix Studio today to explore the full range of features.
Speaker 2:  Hello, And Welcome to our cast flagship podcast of algorithmic warfare.
Speaker 1:  Good.
Speaker 2:  That's good. That's a good phrase.
Speaker 5:  That's a good like band name.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like If. you were in high school, you would for sure play bass in a band
Speaker 5:  called Algorithmic Warfare. Right now
Speaker 6:  NELI
Speaker 5:  NELI would for sure a hundred percent
Speaker 2:  Cadillac this week. This is a true story. Cadillac this week teased a new
Speaker 2:  concept called Opulent Velocity.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which is really good. Like really good. but it sounds like the name of one
Speaker 2:  of those clubs or restaurants in New York that's always empty but always
Speaker 2:  open. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And is bottle service.
Speaker 2:  But it, but no one's ever in there. No one fully staffed, no visitors.
Speaker 2:  Opulent velocity. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I love that. I would stand in line for that.
Speaker 2:  Algorithmic warfare is playing at opulent velocity.
Speaker 5:  Tickets are $8,000
Speaker 2:  To no one. Right? Yeah. If, you don't live in New York City. This is
Speaker 2:  like a hard thing to convey
Speaker 2:  or city has corruption in it and
Speaker 2:  sometimes the people have to launder the money. So every now and again,
Speaker 2:  you'll be in a neighborhood where there's just a fully staffed
Speaker 2:  empty restaurant. There used to be one right by our office in Midtown. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It was deeply confusing,
Speaker 6:  But No, I bet it would be like, great, how are the deals? How are, how are,
Speaker 6:  how are
Speaker 2:  The food? No, you would go in there and you'd be, first of all, you'd be
Speaker 2:  like, I should leave. Yeah. Like the vibes were immediately hostile. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You're not ordering. And then you would order food and they'd be like,
Speaker 2:  what? We don't know. We
Speaker 6:  Don't, but like we, we have to go to like the grocery store and get you some
Speaker 6:  chicken tenders. We'll be back
Speaker 2:  Opulent velocity.
Speaker 2:  All right. There's a lot happening this week. I'm your friend NELI. Alex.
Speaker 2:  Cranz is here in studio. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  We're
Speaker 2:  Back. I was gonna say it's been a minute. It's a minute. But we were just
Speaker 2:  together in Texas. Yeah. All three of us. But it's been a minute since you
Speaker 2:  and I were together in this studio. That's
Speaker 6:  True. It's nice. It's a good energy. I'm having
Speaker 2:  Fun. And then David Pierce is Vanish was basement once again. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Cool. Thanks. It's really nice to see
Speaker 2:  You guys
Speaker 6:  Feeling great.
Speaker 6:  How is it?
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's, it's a basement. I did nap over there earlier, so I'm feeling
Speaker 5:  great. Ooh, everything's, everything's going well today.
Speaker 6:  Hell yes.
Speaker 2:  My understanding is that we are soon to give you some sort of green screen
Speaker 2:  experience where you can be anywhere.
Speaker 5:  Liam is threatening to give me a background, but every time he threatens
Speaker 5:  the background, there's one more box involved. And So
Speaker 5:  I think we're, we're now at either two or three boxes plus a six foot
Speaker 5:  long green screen that lives under my couch. So
Speaker 5:  it's either gonna happen and really change my life in a big way
Speaker 5:  or I'm just going to refuse to engage in this process any longer. We'll see.
Speaker 2:  Look, I know Vergecast listeners have a relationship with our producer,
Speaker 2:  Liam, mostly because he's the person who makes us be on time, which we have
Speaker 2:  defeated. Liam, I just wanna be clear that listeners plus hosts have defeated
Speaker 2:  Liam, but the way you know he is the right producer for the show is that
Speaker 2:  when he's allowed to spend money in gadgets and gadget
Speaker 2:  related ideas, it's just outta control like the Oh, he goes all in
Speaker 2:  the studio that is being built at my house fully out of control.
Speaker 6:  It's sick.
Speaker 2:  It's it, it's great. And one day we'll make Liam do the video where he is
Speaker 2:  like, here's all the stuff I bought,
Speaker 5:  But it Studio tour. That's gonna happen. It it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  Great. Yeah. It's a lot of stuff. And then I have ideas.
Speaker 2:  It's not, it's not great. I would not say it's a cost effective studio, but
Speaker 2:  it's, it's just a lot of stuff. It's
Speaker 5:  Great. I like to imagine you just never get out of your chair and you just
Speaker 5:  sort of wheel from set to set all day depending on what you're doing.
Speaker 5:  You just
Speaker 2:  Kind of like, Liam bomb across li has threaten to automate the studio. So
Speaker 2:  you just push one button and like the shades go down and the lights turn
Speaker 2:  on. I don't know that we can get there. You,
Speaker 6:  You totally can. Home assistant, right, Liam? It's gonna be home assistant.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be sick.
Speaker 2:  I like how you just like try to get Liam to jump in. Come on
Speaker 6:  Liam, hop in. He's not doing it. He's like, no, he's
Speaker 2:  Hiding under the studio.
Speaker 6:  No, he's got, he's got ideas.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. He's not, I, we were waiting. He just didn't show up.
Speaker 6:  He'll not be bathed.
Speaker 2:  He's, he's very upset. That's right. I'm sorry. We love you Liam.
Speaker 6:  Liam is
Speaker 2:  Incredible. Everyone tweeted Liam. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Good things only now
Speaker 2:  That we're on the high vibes. Yeah, there's a lot to talk about this week.
Speaker 2:  There's the TikTok ban, which we gotta talk about a lot. There's a
Speaker 2:  bunch of streaming Wars news, there's Twitter now X
Speaker 2:  pivoting to video, which a real 2012 idea.
Speaker 2:  There's a new YouTube app and then we got a lightning round. There's all
Speaker 2:  kinds of stuff going on. Oh, Starship had its third launch, which appears
Speaker 2:  to be totally successful. That happened to only minutes before we started
Speaker 2:  recording. So I'm saying that, and we'll see
Speaker 2:  if it landed. By the time we get to talking about it,
Speaker 2:  it's gonna be great. But we should start with TikTok, which is undoubtedly
Speaker 2:  the news of the week. It is very confusing,
Speaker 2:  very stressful. And I have promised to have the hottest take of all. But
Speaker 2:  first, David, do you wanna tell us what's going on with TikTok?
Speaker 5:  Sure. So the very short version of what has now become a
Speaker 5:  very long story is that after in 2021 deciding not to ban
Speaker 5:  TikTok, Congress has decided once again that it, it would very much like
Speaker 5:  to ban TikTok. So there is this bill called the Protecting
Speaker 5:  Americans from Foreign Adversary Controlled Applications Act, which just
Speaker 5:  really rolls off the tongue. Hmm. And what it essentially does
Speaker 5:  is block app stores from hosting
Speaker 5:  TikTok and it blocks internet hosting providers from
Speaker 5:  hosting TikTok. And there are a million complications and nuances in that
Speaker 5:  that we should talk about. But the idea is essentially to either ban
Speaker 5:  TikTok outright or force it to be sold to
Speaker 5:  an American company or a company at least not owned by a foreign
Speaker 5:  adversary, which is a technical term that only a few countries qualify
Speaker 5:  under. So it went through committee, I believe it passed in a house
Speaker 5:  committee. 50 to zero.
Speaker 2:  50 to zero. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then it went to the broader house where it passed with like 80%. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Which was a huge ridiculous victory in a time where nothing
Speaker 5:  passes with numbers like that. So now this bill is sitting in front of the
Speaker 5:  Senate president Biden has said that if it is passed to him,
Speaker 5:  he will sign it into law. There is essentially now one
Speaker 5:  step remaining between us and a TikTok ban.
Speaker 5:  And it's a big step and there are lots of good reasons to believe it will
Speaker 5:  never surmount that step. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 6:  It's, it's Rand Paul, right? Like the step is Rand Paul,
Speaker 2:  Senator Rand Paul, the Senate overall. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's Rand Paul and it's Chuck Schumer. And there are, there are a lot of
Speaker 5:  people in the Senate who have reasons not to make this happen. Right. but
Speaker 5:  it is, we are much closer to a TikTok ban than we have ever been before
Speaker 5:  to the point where a lot of people inside TikTok and outside
Speaker 5:  TikTok think it's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  All right. So can I quibble with you on one thing please? And it is just
Speaker 2:  the most pedantic thing, but why are, why else we here? Yeah. The idea that
Speaker 2:  it's a ban on TikTok specifically like
Speaker 2:  conflates, too many ideas.
Speaker 5:  Can I read you the first sentence of the Bill Eli? Yeah. To protect the national
Speaker 5:  security of the United States from the threat posed by foreign adversary
Speaker 5:  controlled applications such as TikTok.
Speaker 5:  It's the only app they name in the bill. This is a TikTok
Speaker 2:  Ban. Sure. And it's the only app specified later in the bill. Right.
Speaker 2:  but it, but the mechanism by which it is accomplishing that goal
Speaker 2:  is not actually by banning TikTok. And I think that's, that's important.
Speaker 2:  If, you wanna understand the dynamics of this bill and the people arrayed
Speaker 2:  for and against it. What might actually happen with TikTok?
Speaker 2:  It's a bill that regulates app stores and internet service providers. Yes.
Speaker 2:  It does not regulate TikTok at all. Like nothing in this bill
Speaker 2:  requires TikTok to do anything. It requires a
Speaker 2:  bunch of other companies to do stuff that will make it impossible for
Speaker 2:  TikTok to do business here. And I think when we have all these
Speaker 2:  conversations about the 170 million Americans who use TikTok and free speech
Speaker 2:  and all these businesses, it's all is though the government is
Speaker 2:  regulating TikTok. but it is, but
Speaker 2:  very specifically and very mechanically in this bill, it is not doing
Speaker 2:  that. It is making it impossible for TikTok to do business in the United States.
Speaker 2:  And you might think that is the same thing. And you are, I'm sure people
Speaker 2:  have a lot of like feelings about what I'm saying, but it If, you just
Speaker 2:  read the language of the bill. The bill does not regulate.
Speaker 2:  It says TikTok and for political expediency,
Speaker 2:  but it doesn't actually regulate TikTok directly. It just says these
Speaker 2:  other companies cannot do business with TikTok. And I think that's actually
Speaker 2:  really important.
Speaker 5:  It's also the only way to do it. Like you, you can't argue that
Speaker 5:  TikTok is a company owned and run by China and then say the US
Speaker 5:  government can regulate it like that. You just can't have it both ways. This
Speaker 5:  is the only way to get to TikTok. If. you want to get to TikTok?
Speaker 2:  No, there are, there are other ways to do it. I some of those ways have succeeded
Speaker 2:  in the courts and some of them have failed. Like over time we are
Speaker 2:  capable of regulating how foreign companies do business in the United States.
Speaker 2:  For example, foreign companies are not really allowed
Speaker 2:  to own like broadcast licenses in the United States. So If, you want to set
Speaker 2:  up a CBS tower in New York City, you can't go get a bunch of Saudi
Speaker 2:  money to do it. We, we seem to be fine with that. I just, and I just wanna
Speaker 2:  put that out there. Like there are some very direct regulations that we have
Speaker 2:  over media ownership in this country. And then there there's this bill, which
Speaker 2:  is like Apple can't do business with TikTok and it's actually different.
Speaker 2:  And the reason I'm poking at that really hard is 'cause I think
Speaker 2:  the rhetoric on both sides of this has gotten one turn
Speaker 2:  too simplistic, right? On the, we should
Speaker 2:  ban it side. It's like this is a danger to the United States. And then you're
Speaker 2:  like, so what's it whatcha are gonna do about it? And they're like, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna tell Apple what to do. Weird. Weird. Just like
Speaker 2:  straightforwardly weird. And on the other side it's like you're infringing
Speaker 2:  our free speech rights by banning TikTok. And then you look at the thing
Speaker 2:  and it's like, oh, that is the third order outcome of this.
Speaker 2:  But if what you're really doing is regulating Apple or you're doing, there's
Speaker 2:  actually all these other outs, including you could sell TikTok,
Speaker 2:  which as you pointed out David in 2021, like, boy
Speaker 2:  haven't we been through this before? Like Microsoft was gonna buy TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Ella was like, this is the weirdest deal I've ever been a part of. Oracle
Speaker 2:  has Project Texas and they, no one cares.
Speaker 2:  Like the least Alex is from Texas. This is the least anything named Texas
Speaker 2:  has ever talked about itself. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's true. It's true. All the other Texans are really confused
Speaker 6:  what's happening. Like how I got to that. Yeah, I
Speaker 6:  do not, lemme take that back. Yeah, I, I keep
Speaker 6:  looking at this and it's, it's fundamentally just like the next step in the,
Speaker 6:  in the Chinese American trade war, right? Like this is just saying we
Speaker 6:  don't want apps created in China that are popular
Speaker 6:  functioning in the United States full stop and, and a few other
Speaker 6:  countries, but, but specifically China. And, and so this is just an extension
Speaker 6:  of that trade war. And I'm a little like
Speaker 6:  taken aback by it. It does feel like, like the TikTok stuff in particular
Speaker 6:  has always felt vaguely xenophobic. It's always felt a little like, oh, we
Speaker 6:  can't, we can't have the Chinese do things here because America
Speaker 6:  and, and, and, and, but we, we do also at the same time have this this quickly
Speaker 6:  accelerating trade war that, that was, it was like in the background and
Speaker 6:  then Trump was like, let me lob the, the trade equivalent of a
Speaker 6:  bomb into the mix. And and now this is, it's not quite nuclear, but
Speaker 6:  this is like a really significant moment in that trade
Speaker 6:  war. And, and they're just, everybody's so
Speaker 6:  focused on TikTok and ignoring the fact that you are fundamentally changing
Speaker 6:  how the internet works in the United States and saying,
Speaker 6:  no, we are actually gonna build a wall the way that China has a wall. The
Speaker 6:  United States is gonna have a wall and some of this stuff we've already said
Speaker 6:  it about a lot of the technology that's coming out of China. And now they're
Speaker 6:  gonna say, yeah. And, and also these apps and
Speaker 6:  you know, it worked when it was Huawei and it was phones and they didn't
Speaker 6:  have a huge market share in the United States. And so it was like, oh no,
Speaker 6:  we lost Huawei. And like, that sucks 'cause they have really good technology
Speaker 6:  in their devices and now we're like, they're going after
Speaker 6:  TikTok. And that's, and people suddenly care.
Speaker 2:  All right, here it is. You ready, I'm
Speaker 6:  Ready.
Speaker 2:  I think it makes total sense for the United States government to not want
Speaker 2:  Chinese ownership of a major media platform in this country. Like Yeah. It
Speaker 2:  it is sensible on its face. It was sensible on its face for us to not want
Speaker 2:  a bunch of Huawei technology in our communications networks. Yep.
Speaker 2:  And I, I I agree with you. I think most people didn't have like Strand brand
Speaker 2:  affinity for Huawei. So when we would have FCC commissioners
Speaker 2:  on the show, Jeffrey Starks was on the show being like, we gotta rip and
Speaker 2:  replace all the Huawei gear.
Speaker 2:  No creator said anything. Right. As far as I understand, like maybe
Speaker 2:  there was a Huawei powered creator campaign to be like,
Speaker 6:  Save us
Speaker 2:  As far as I can tell, I think some people may be around the phones. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean they had war with the phones, they had like the le it was Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It was
Speaker 5:  Cool. Meli. Sure. In order to make that statement, you have to believe
Speaker 5:  one of the two arguments that everybody makes against TikTok, which is either
Speaker 5:  it is this like crucially important vessel through which China is collecting
Speaker 5:  data about Americans, or it is how China is
Speaker 5:  disseminating propaganda and influencing US elections and making our children
Speaker 5:  idiots. Which of those do you believe
Speaker 2:  The second one?
Speaker 5:  Do you, do you really? Yeah. On what evidence?
Speaker 2:  None. I just to be clear, I I just,
Speaker 2:  just to be clear, just
Speaker 5:  To be a great podcast
Speaker 2:  And I, I don't wanna, I don't wanna like say I have a bunch of evidence.
Speaker 2:  I think actually one of the problems in this entire situation
Speaker 2:  is that the House select committee went into a secure
Speaker 2:  briefing. They saw whatever evidence there was,
Speaker 2:  and they walked outta that briefing and went and immediately to a vote and
Speaker 2:  voted 50 to zero to pass this bill that would either get
Speaker 2:  TikTok off the app stores or force them to sell
Speaker 2:  with no dissension, no controversy. I was at South by
Speaker 2:  Southwest. The, the, the, the vibe I
Speaker 2:  heard coming outta the briefing was Congress people saying, If, you
Speaker 2:  saw what we saw, you'd do it too. What did they see?
Speaker 2:  I think they should be made to present that evidence to the American people
Speaker 2:  and yet, and yet they have not. Right. And yet that evidence is also so
Speaker 2:  persuasive that they voted 3 83 to whatever to
Speaker 2:  pass the bill in the full house. And yet there's nothing, the evidence is
Speaker 2:  so persuasive that Joe Biden's like, I'll, I'll I'll sign it when it comes
Speaker 2:  to my desk. And yet no one has made the case.
Speaker 2:  The thing that I'm saying based on no evidence is you should not
Speaker 2:  let an adversary of the United States even have this
Speaker 2:  capability. We didn't know if Huawei was actually spying on our communications
Speaker 2:  networks by embedding hardware directly into the cell system.
Speaker 2:  No one wants to take the chance. Right? Like, that seems
Speaker 2:  silly.
Speaker 6:  The problem, the problem I think with, with the argument of
Speaker 6:  this is about protecting us from, from, from Chinese
Speaker 6:  interests is that meta still exists.
Speaker 6:  A ton of other algorithmically driven social media platforms that are
Speaker 6:  extraordinarily susceptible to propaganda still
Speaker 6:  exist Sure. In this country and function in this country. They're only going
Speaker 6:  after TikTok, which means like Russia
Speaker 6:  went and, and did a whole lot of stuff in 2016, and we have a whole lot of
Speaker 6:  proof of that and not a lot's changed on that front. Instead we were just
Speaker 6:  like, well, we're gonna get rid of, Facebook's gonna get rid of a newsfeed
Speaker 6:  and we're we're all gonna be fine. And, and, and Menal is allowed to exist
Speaker 6:  in the com country. So this is explicitly about
Speaker 6:  China, but feels like so wrongheaded in actually
Speaker 6:  solving the problem because right now, okay, you say we we
Speaker 6:  kill TikTok in the United States, it goes away. China can just
Speaker 6:  go to US data brokers and get all that same
Speaker 2:  Data. But that's the, that's the first thing that David is saying, the data
Speaker 2:  brokers thing. Right. So this is why I ask about the two things because I
Speaker 2:  I agree that, I think I specifically mean the second one, but I think
Speaker 6:  If, but on that second turn, again, they can just
Speaker 6:  go and send their, their propaganda like right now. Okay. They, it's cool.
Speaker 6:  They, they maybe just have a button on the algorithm and they can, they can
Speaker 6:  control the algorithm in a very direct way. Instead they can now just send
Speaker 6:  all of their, their people, their, their propaganda specialists and all of
Speaker 6:  those folks onto, to meta onto, onto threads,
Speaker 6:  onto Instagram, onto X for the four
Speaker 6:  people still there. They, they, they can all, they can send 'em all to all
Speaker 6:  those other places. And that doesn't solve the problem. It just
Speaker 6:  like, it makes their lives just a little bit diff more difficult
Speaker 6:  and Yeah. I I just, but
Speaker 2:  That wait, it makes their lives a lot more difficult. Vastly
Speaker 2:  more difficult. Okay. I do agree with that. For all of their, many,
Speaker 2:  many, many faults. Yeah. Mark
Speaker 2:  Zuckerberg and Sundar Petra and Elon Musk live in the United States.
Speaker 2:  They operate United States companies. Right. Their kids
Speaker 2:  live here. If the United States and China go to war,
Speaker 2:  their kids will be at risk. The United States government has direct
Speaker 2:  regulatory control over their companies. Their companies, again, you
Speaker 2:  can argue about the merits of this as much as you want
Speaker 2:  their companies comply with and often support the military
Speaker 2:  activities of the United States. Right.
Speaker 6:  I'm I'm saying I have a problem with the idea that we
Speaker 6:  are okay with algorithmically driven
Speaker 6:  propaganda machines only when they're American.
Speaker 2:  We are because of the fucking First Amendment. Yeah. Right. Like our
Speaker 2:  government would love to sit down and directly regulate the
Speaker 2:  algorithms of meta and YouTube. They would in a
Speaker 2:  heartbeat. They would do it in one second if they could, and the First Amendment
Speaker 2:  stands in their way. And that's for good
Speaker 2:  reason. Right. You, you tend to believe that Americans have the best interest
Speaker 2:  of America at at heart. And I don't even mean that in a directly
Speaker 2:  patriotic way, I just mean like a do you want the place where you live to
Speaker 2:  get bombed? Yeah. Very directly. Like Yeah.
Speaker 2:  There's just a, a very individualistic impulse that is sort of at the
Speaker 2:  heart of this.
Speaker 2:  China is not that China is, is an adversary to this country. It
Speaker 2:  would like to destabilize this country in some way if it could gain an advantage.
Speaker 2:  It does it militarily. It does it economically. We do it to them.
Speaker 2:  Yep. Straightforward. And I think
Speaker 2:  TikTok users tend to believe that their individual
Speaker 2:  experiences have no relation to that thing. Right. So I've watched
Speaker 2:  a million TikTok videos from TikTokers who are outraged the top They're making
Speaker 2:  the argument you're making. Yeah. Why, why would you regulate us when YouTube
Speaker 2:  still exists? Or
Speaker 6:  Medicines? I mean, I think they should all not exist. I think algorithm
Speaker 6:  algorithmically driven social feeds or it ps on
Speaker 6:  on our country. And and
Speaker 2:  Anybody who's heard me talk knows that I agree with you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And so that's where I'm at with it.
Speaker 2:  I I don't disagree. Yeah. Come directly to our website. It's The Verge dot
Speaker 2:  com. You have an in a personal relationship with me on that website
Speaker 2:  and then send us money. Sure. Why not? There should
Speaker 2:  be, we make it very hard to send this money. We'll figure it out one day.
Speaker 6:  Venmo NELI. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  This is all just a pain to Cash app. Me. I will make dance videos for you,
Speaker 2:  send me use Cash app.
Speaker 2:  But what I'm getting at is just think about something as dumb as Stanley
Speaker 2:  Cups. Stanley Cups are not a
Speaker 2:  organic trend. Right? The algorithmic fed a bunch of people, a bunch of Stanley
Speaker 2:  Cup content, and then more people were inspired to make Stanley Cup content
Speaker 2:  and then the world around us generated an infinite
Speaker 2:  supply of Stanley Cup explainers. So many of my friends car. And then that
Speaker 2:  trend just died.
Speaker 5:  You sound like somebody who like watched the great hack last night and is
Speaker 5:  like, there's somebody at a button saying, it's Stanley. I
Speaker 2:  I don't, there's somebody like, that's
Speaker 5:  Not how it works. It's just not how it works.
Speaker 2:  But that's not, that's not how Stanley Cup works. But why
Speaker 2:  would you give a foreign power that capability inside the United States
Speaker 2:  to even dream of having that button?
Speaker 5:  A TikTok would tell you that it absolutely has not given China
Speaker 5:  that power inside of the United States. B there's no evidence that it has.
Speaker 2:  Well, look, I'm the, I'm the one who said the government should show us that
Speaker 2:  evidence, but just abstractly. Why, why would you
Speaker 2:  allow that to happen? Look, I'm gonna read to you the Communications Act
Speaker 2:  of 1934. Foreign investors are limited to 20%
Speaker 2:  direct ownership of companies holding a broadcasting license and
Speaker 2:  25% ownership of a holding company. If, you have
Speaker 2:  multiple broadcast licenses. Why did we think it was important to limit the
Speaker 2:  ownership of the airwaves, the United States in 1934?
Speaker 2:  Because we did not want foreign companies controlling what was broadcast
Speaker 2:  to the majority of Americans. The impulse is exactly the same.
Speaker 2:  I get it. The United States should probably
Speaker 2:  explain why it's terrified of TikTok. I I really think this is a huge miss
Speaker 2:  on a part of the government. And if they cannot, they should back the hell
Speaker 2:  off. I agree. But I'm, I'm looking at okay,
Speaker 2:  just on its face, is it a problem that
Speaker 2:  so many Americans are buffeted by algorithms that we do not have
Speaker 2:  any transparency into? And at least one of them, one very important one
Speaker 2:  potentially has an enemy of the United States like
Speaker 2:  controlling it and all that stands in between that is like
Speaker 2:  Tim Cook. Tim Cook is like, iPhones are really important to everyone. Do
Speaker 2:  not do the, do not do a war. Right. And like, that's what got us
Speaker 2:  through the Trump trade war in a a real way. It's basically the
Speaker 2:  idea of the modern global piece is that we'll all be so economically tied
Speaker 2:  up with each other that war will be bad. I don't know, If, you looked around
Speaker 2:  recently, like
Speaker 2:  kind of shaky, like more shaky than it's been in
Speaker 2:  a long time. And I would just point out like
Speaker 2:  on either side, none of these cases are proven. TikTok saying we don't do
Speaker 2:  it great. You gotta prove a negative, very difficult. Hui
Speaker 6:  Also said that a lot and
Speaker 2:  Hui said a lot and you know, most Western companies are like, we just don't
Speaker 2:  want your hardware embedded in our networks. And I I, that to me always felt
Speaker 2:  like very obvious. Like, don't put their hardware in your networks. That's
Speaker 2:  where you get o ran from. By the way, this is like a whole thing. This, and
Speaker 2:  this was what led to pro project Gen five assist. Look, I'm not saying you
Speaker 2:  should ban air, you should
Speaker 2:  keep the app stores from having it. I, I don't know.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry. I'm still thinking about how like Chinese trade war led to
Speaker 6:  project Gen five
Speaker 2:  Straight line. Oh, it absolutely
Speaker 6:  Did. Yeah. I've seen the meme of the guy with like the
Speaker 2:  Legos, but I'm saying If, you are a TikTok user and you're outraged because
Speaker 2:  they're gonna do this. It's like, think about your experience on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  You are being shown things that you are not in control of their sequence
Speaker 2:  of their content. Like it just happens to you and the number of TikTok trends
Speaker 2:  that come and go because people on the app
Speaker 2:  decide to participate in them. And then our understanding of the culture
Speaker 2:  around us is absolutely, it
Speaker 2:  absolutely has the potential to be controlled by a foreign
Speaker 2:  party. Okay. That I I don't think that
Speaker 2:  that is the, I don't think the United States government has no business in
Speaker 2:  paying attention to that. Should they lay out the evidence, the American
Speaker 2:  people, that this is the only solu they, they should,
Speaker 2:  is the evidence strong enough such that 50 Democrats and Republicans in a
Speaker 2:  room saw it and walked out and voted unanimously?
Speaker 2:  That's weird. That doesn't happen a lot anymore. Like
Speaker 2:  it's just weird.
Speaker 5:  No, it doesn't. but it is also true that the only two things anyone agrees
Speaker 5:  on in politics right now are China is bad and we must protect the children
Speaker 5:  on the internet. And If you want to gin up a 50 to zero vote,
Speaker 5:  you would pick one of those two things. That's just what you would do. And,
Speaker 5:  and on anything you're like, oh, we love kids. Right? Like 50
Speaker 5:  to zero is pretty, it's not that hard to do on that front. Like this is just
Speaker 5:  where we're
Speaker 2:  At. Hey, I challenge you to go do it. It's even csa. Like
Speaker 2:  csa the most we protect the kids is not passing right now.
Speaker 2:  Right. The kids' online safety act is not
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because that involves actually doing things and, and Congress is
Speaker 5:  not big on actually doing things. But wait, but like I I am, I'm still hung
Speaker 5:  up on this thing where like, okay, Tencent a company that is also
Speaker 5:  headquartered in China and has, I would say much clearer ties
Speaker 5:  to the Chinese Communist Party than maybe not by
Speaker 5:  dance, but certainly TikTok. And I think the like is is TikTok bite dance
Speaker 5:  and is bite dance. TikTok is a very interesting and still sort of unanswered
Speaker 5:  question in a lot of ways that we should probably talk about. But 10 10 owns,
Speaker 5:  I think if not all, almost all of riot games, which makes League of Legends,
Speaker 5:  which is very popular game, including in the United States. It owns a significant
Speaker 5:  part of Epic which makes Fortnite. Can you convincingly
Speaker 5:  prove to me that there is a better chance of me seeing Chinese
Speaker 5:  propaganda on TikTok than in Fortnite?
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  How?
Speaker 2:  Fortnite doesn't have any news in it. Fortnite is not the main news source
Speaker 2:  for millions of young Americans in the middle of an election year.
Speaker 5:  I think, I mean, a, that assumes that millions of young Americans have a
Speaker 5:  news source or give one solitary shit about the news. And I don't think that
Speaker 5:  they do. And so, but like leaving that aside, there
Speaker 5:  is potential Sure in the absolute worst case scenario
Speaker 5:  that one can possibly imagine bad things can happen
Speaker 5:  on TikTok. Granted, in the absolute worst case scenario,
Speaker 5:  China already owns Yahoo News and we don't even know about it. Like
Speaker 5:  we're, we're arguing about these like insane hypotheticals and we don't know
Speaker 5:  anything and we're just mad at China. Like I I don't know how to make it
Speaker 5:  less simple than that.
Speaker 2:  Right. But I'm saying a majority of the members of the House of
Speaker 2:  Representatives took a bunch of phone calls from their constituents and still
Speaker 2:  voted to pass this bill because of whatever
Speaker 2:  they saw.
Speaker 5:  No disagree. They took a bunch of calls from their constituents and so as
Speaker 5:  a result voted the, the overwhelming takeaway from
Speaker 5:  members of Congress from this huge phone bank thing that TikTok has been
Speaker 5:  encouraging users to do is, see this proves our point. TikTok can make young
Speaker 5:  people do whatever they want, so we have to ban it. This thing has backfired
Speaker 5:  so spectacularly on TikTok in the funniest possible way.
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 5:  Was bad, it convinced young people to make phone calls and everybody was
Speaker 5:  like, oh my God, they can make young people make phone calls. They can do
Speaker 5:  anything.
Speaker 2:  Right. But
Speaker 5:  That's the only evidence of propaganda that we actually have from TikTok
Speaker 5:  is that they can make people make phone calls.
Speaker 2:  I wanna point out that is indeed very funny. Like it is very funny.
Speaker 2:  I think mostly 'cause TikTok didn't think anything would happen like this
Speaker 2:  and then they overplayed their hand. Yes. Weird. But the idea
Speaker 2:  that you can get a bunch of young people to take political action
Speaker 2:  in service of a company that is owned by the Chinese government
Speaker 2:  should not feel like a backfire when people are like, well that's bad.
Speaker 5:  You can't just say a service run by the Chinese government. Like it's a thing
Speaker 5:  that we know. You just, you just said that so nonchalantly
Speaker 2:  But by chance of the Chinese company has Chinese government not supported.
Speaker 2:  Right. It is just true. Like
Speaker 2:  companies in China are structured differently than the companies here and
Speaker 2:  the state interests are much stronger for those companies. And if they don't
Speaker 2:  like you, they just make you go away. Which is a thing that happens
Speaker 2:  to Chinese companies.
Speaker 6:  Poor fun binging. That's
Speaker 5:  True.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. Like Jack Ma like where'd that guy go? He just disappeared.
Speaker 2:  Like, that's weird. Like that is a different, like a, a
Speaker 2:  crucial difference between United States government and Chinese government.
Speaker 2:  Chinese government is a brutal dictatorship.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean this is, this is the, this is the thing we, we saw with Huawei
Speaker 6:  and, and we're seeing again in, in this case that I think isn't always entirely
Speaker 6:  articulated because racism gets in the way and xenophobia gets in the way,
Speaker 6:  which is that like
Speaker 6:  this, the problem isn't that it's China and China bad because that that's
Speaker 6:  just racism xenophobic. The problem is that the Chinese Communist Party,
Speaker 6:  the CCP has a very capable way
Speaker 6:  of making businesses that are in China, do what they want
Speaker 6:  and they can exert influence and they will exert influence and they have
Speaker 6:  exerted influence. And in tiktoks case, TikTok has gone again
Speaker 6:  and again and again and said they do not do that. We are not based there.
Speaker 6:  We, we, we, we work really, really hard to not have that
Speaker 6:  relationship. And effectively the United States government has said, we
Speaker 6:  don't believe you. Right.
Speaker 2:  Because you made up Project Texas. Yeah. And then when the chips are down,
Speaker 2:  no one is talking about Project Texas. Yep. They, they made up
Speaker 2:  this fake thing, which is like Oracle host the data
Speaker 2:  and there's a, we wrote about it, Alex Heath wrote about it. He visited the
Speaker 2:  Algorithmic Transparency Center, which is basically a children's museum for
Speaker 2:  content moderation where you stand in front of a giant TikTok screen and
Speaker 2:  you're like, ban this, don't ban. And then behind that is like a
Speaker 2:  wall with a data center behind it that you can gaze upon and you're like,
Speaker 2:  look at the data. It's here in the United States. And none of that has anything
Speaker 2:  to do with anything as, as near as we can tell.
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. I I think, I think TikTok is always, it, it's always
Speaker 6:  gonna face this battle because unfortunately it is owned by a company
Speaker 6:  that does, is based in China and therefore cannot
Speaker 6:  fully say we are totally independent company like by dance can just not do
Speaker 6:  that. It never can. It never will. As long as the CCP is is staying in its
Speaker 6:  current like regime. And, and so TikTok is always gonna face that
Speaker 6:  and they have, they've really struggled to, to
Speaker 6:  convince the, the government at every turn they've struggled. And part of
Speaker 6:  that is definitely the xenophobia and, and and, and the racism, which
Speaker 6:  is just like completely out of pocket and horrible. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Every
Speaker 2:  Single time. I fully agree there.
Speaker 6:  Horrible. And I just, I don't know that TikTok can ever say
Speaker 6:  anything that is going to make them believe them. Like even if they, if
Speaker 6:  even if Project Texas wasn't so stupidly,
Speaker 6:  transparently like TikTok propaganda to say like us,
Speaker 6:  I don't know what they could do to make the United States government like
Speaker 6:  them. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Can I say something? Can they do vastly more esoteric and philosophical just
Speaker 2:  to turn this Yeah, yeah, yeah. Somewhere else
Speaker 2:  as I've gotten older, I've realized the thing that the internet does is make
Speaker 2:  everyone believe that collective action problems do not exist,
Speaker 2:  which is If you If you just take that idea and apply it to whatever your
Speaker 2:  political leanings are. You'll quickly realize like this is your primary
Speaker 2:  frustration with other people. It's like some problems are easier to solve
Speaker 2:  if we all do them together, but getting everyone to do everything
Speaker 2:  at the same time is like a political nightmare. Yeah. And that's just life.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's the history of politics. Do collective action problems exist
Speaker 2:  or not? Is it, if I'm like the market will
Speaker 2:  provide fighter jets, it won't unless we all pay our taxes and the government
Speaker 2:  buy fighter jets and we need it. We think we should have fighter jets for
Speaker 2:  X, y and Z reason. And you personally might disagree with those reasons
Speaker 2:  and you personally might sue the government of the United States and say,
Speaker 2:  I do not want my taxes to pay for fighter jets, which is a real thing that
Speaker 2:  happens on the regular and the United States government says, no, you don't
Speaker 2:  get a choice because of collective act like we have to do this thing together.
Speaker 2:  And you might think to yourself, boy, I wish we would pull our taxes and
Speaker 2:  pay for healthcare. I very strongly believe we should pull our taxes and
Speaker 2:  pay for healthcare for people or better education or whatever it is that
Speaker 2:  you think would be better if we all paid a little bit. And we all got a lot.
Speaker 2:  Right. This is like the main thing and what is happening in this TikTok
Speaker 2:  situation is TikTok is a collective action problem.
Speaker 2:  Our government believes the security of the United States is threatened by
Speaker 2:  the existence of TikTok in some way. Our government says that
Speaker 2:  it believes it, it's taking the, the votes that it, it indicate its belief
Speaker 2:  in that problem. Sure.
Speaker 5:  I would remind you that you're the same NELI Patel who believes most of the
Speaker 5:  things that Congress does are like deeply disingenuous and not at all about
Speaker 5:  the thing that they say that they're about.
Speaker 2:  I, I cannot believe I'm the one making this case. I'm, I
Speaker 5:  Can't either. I'm just,
Speaker 2:  I'm like, I'm this now I'm losing
Speaker 5:  My mind. Right now
Speaker 2:  I have never, I just, the the 50 to o vote, I think just really
Speaker 2:  there's something about that. Like they saw the evidence, they walked out,
Speaker 2:  they all did the same thing at Sometimes. I
Speaker 5:  Do agree that that is the single most compelling piece of evidence.
Speaker 2:  I've just got evidence circled in my brain. Whatever happened there is a
Speaker 2:  big deal. I don't know what it is. And that is the problem. Yep. To
Speaker 2:  overcome the collective action problem they have, which is they're going
Speaker 2:  to make a bunch of individuals feel bad. Yep. A
Speaker 2:  bunch of individual businesses will lose their marketing channel. A bunch
Speaker 2:  of individual creators will lose their livelihoods. A bunch of
Speaker 2:  individual people will lose their ability to just see trucks jump over
Speaker 2:  shit on command. This will hurt me personally to overcome
Speaker 2:  the collective action problem. They have to lay out the case. but it is
Speaker 2:  clear that they think if we all endure that pain
Speaker 2:  collectively we will get some benefit. And the benefit will be freedom
Speaker 2:  from Chinese interference in our media. I don't like that's the case.
Speaker 2:  And when you take that and you're like, now I'll make the same case against
Speaker 2:  Facebook or the same case against YouTube, I would point out to you the
Speaker 2:  government has been trying to make that case. They haul these
Speaker 2:  CEOs in front of the government and say, why are your algorithms bad?
Speaker 2:  And the CEOs are like, yeah, I don't know. First Amendment
Speaker 2:  go away. Like they cannot overcome that. They have yet to come up with an
Speaker 2:  argument that is strong enough to overpower the First amendment and solve
Speaker 2:  that collective action problem. They have not yet figured it out. The closest
Speaker 2:  they've come is the kids stuff. That's why you have a kids'
Speaker 2:  online safety act. The closest they've come is sex trafficking. That's why
Speaker 2:  you get fossa and Cesta is carve outs to two 30.
Speaker 2:  That's it. The closest actually the the, the farthest they've gone
Speaker 2:  is copyright law. Right. Like that's why Disney
Speaker 2:  gets to take stuff down off the internet. 'cause we've decided as collectively
Speaker 2:  that's fine. And most people don't argue with that. In this case,
Speaker 2:  they have a different thing that they can't wield against the
Speaker 2:  Facebooks and the, and the YouTubes of the world, which is like national
Speaker 2:  security and they have to make the case. And I, they've had one
Speaker 2:  kind of sham hearing where they just asked like, that's your xenophobia.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. Where they just like, we're like, are you Singaporean?
Speaker 2:  He's like, I am Singapore. Yeah. They're like, that doesn't work. They
Speaker 2:  asked the dude if TikTok uses wifi.
Speaker 2:  Truly a horrible theory like that isn't the case. But
Speaker 2:  the some case was made to these people where they are
Speaker 2:  willing to take the representative democracy hit
Speaker 2:  right where their own constituents are calling them and they're interpreting
Speaker 2:  that as this is the problem and I'm gonna vote against what my constituents
Speaker 2:  are saying to me. Can I put on that? That happens in like very rarely.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  Think you might be underwriting the extent to which it's
Speaker 5:  a political win to be mad at China right now.
Speaker 2:  No, wait, I disagree. I think banning TikTok is a political loser for everyone.
Speaker 2:  Which is why Donald Trump is out there being like, no, I'll, I'll, I'll keep
Speaker 2:  TikTok kids vote for me. Donald Trump.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh, I totally agree with that. But there, there is a, a subset of people
Speaker 5:  who are older and don't use TikTok
Speaker 5:  and hate China, which is a lot of people in America who
Speaker 5:  are gonna be psyched about this. And so it's like, there there are
Speaker 5:  the, if if you're just taking this as like pure political calculus and like,
Speaker 5:  this is not the thing we should get hung up on, but If you're taking this
Speaker 5:  just pure political calculus. The TikTok users aren't gonna vote
Speaker 5:  anyway. The old people who hate China. Oh God. They love voting.
Speaker 5:  Like that's, and this is the thing that I
Speaker 2:  Can I, can I offer you one thing? This is Unsourced, it's half-assed.
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry. I definitely heard at Southwest Southwest that a significant number
Speaker 2:  of people making the phone calls were boomers who spend all day on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  The Boomers love TikTok. I I say that because I
Speaker 2:  They got nothing to, they got nothing to do. They're all retired Yeah. Sitting
Speaker 2:  on their bags of money that they have yet to pass on. I
Speaker 6:  I wanna point out, I think you guys are both focused really a lot on the,
Speaker 6:  the political side of this and, and not on the economic side of this. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which is TikTok goes away suddenly all those
Speaker 6:  American companies that are, are largely dominant in the social media space
Speaker 6:  across the world. Right. Like, you know, like you Mo I think I was reading
Speaker 6:  today that an enormous portion of the the famous people
Speaker 6:  on social media are, are based in America. 'cause they use American apps
Speaker 6:  like Yeah. YouTube and, and Instagram.
Speaker 6:  TikTok goes away. YouTube and Instagram immediately get more users. Like
Speaker 6:  there is real economic incentive to get rid of TikTok because
Speaker 6:  that puts money back into American companies. But they
Speaker 2:  Could sell it,
Speaker 6:  I think. And I think this is also part of like the lobbying that is
Speaker 6:  happening here. Like, like we're seeing, oh, they went and they, they all
Speaker 6:  got convinced in, in some hearing that we didn't all weren't privy to, but
Speaker 6:  they were also getting convinced by lobbyists from, from Meta and lobbyists,
Speaker 6:  from from Google saying, yeah, you wanna get rid of our com
Speaker 6:  competition, go for it. And, and we, we can
Speaker 6:  ignore that like the the economic part component of
Speaker 6:  this thing because it's huge.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I totally agree. And all these companies have had a big stock bump in
Speaker 5:  the last week since this started to happen. Like Snap is sitting there being
Speaker 5:  like, please, dear God man, TikTok, some people will come use Snap Discover
Speaker 5:  if
Speaker 2:  Snap was smart, they would buy it. That's what I'm saying. Like maybe
Speaker 2:  it go away. Yeah. But maybe Steve Mnuchin will put together
Speaker 2:  his band of investors and buy it. Who is the other name that got floated?
Speaker 6:  Bobby caught it. Bobby
Speaker 2:  Ick.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Activision's Back baby.
Speaker 2:  When I, when I think about responsible media ownership in the United States,
Speaker 2:  the
Speaker 5:  Way that Choosy two, the CEO of TikTok has talked about it, it that seems
Speaker 5:  like a total non-starter. Like I, I don't think there's any world in which
Speaker 5:  TikTok sells. He
Speaker 2:  Has to say that.
Speaker 5:  But also the, like, who literally who could afford it?
Speaker 5:  Like this is, this is probably a several hundred billion dollars company.
Speaker 6:  Microsoft's back at it.
Speaker 5:  You can't sell to any of the big companies for antitrust reasons.
Speaker 5:  Who else has the money? Snapchat doesn't have Mon, literally TikTok could
Speaker 5:  buy Snapchat. I
Speaker 2:  Don't know man. Elon put together 44 billion for
Speaker 2:  Twitter.
Speaker 5:  You think? Okay, Elon If. you buy TikTok and take it private
Speaker 5:  and rebrand TikTok as X videos. Now we're onto something.
Speaker 2:  I I understand it's a huge number. I just think that the
Speaker 2:  opportunity for a bunch of investors to
Speaker 2:  get that company and that advertising revenue and that influence,
Speaker 2:  it's not such a big number for the thing that it is.
Speaker 2:  Yes. It's a
Speaker 5:  Very big number. It's pretty big number.
Speaker 2:  Well, we don't know what the number is, but
Speaker 5:  Also that's the unknown. You're not okay with,
Speaker 2:  I just, I just think from, you're not gonna be like, we're open to a sale
Speaker 2:  while you're still trying to fend off the bill that would force you to sell
Speaker 2:  it. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Agreed.
Speaker 2:  And at some point there becomes a number. Like everything has a number. It's
Speaker 2:  a business. Yeah. Capitalism baby. Welcome to America.
Speaker 5:  I mean, and it is true that like we got a ways down this road
Speaker 5:  in 2020 based on an executive order that pretty much everybody
Speaker 5:  thought had no chance of holding up in court. And like that's
Speaker 5:  I think the thing that is different now. I think there, there is a real sense
Speaker 5:  that this is a thing that could happen and could stick. And so to the
Speaker 5:  extent that, you know, Oracle talked about it and Microsoft talked about
Speaker 5:  it and there were all of these weird machinations going on. I think everybody
Speaker 5:  kind of knew it was probably nothing. but it seems to be
Speaker 5:  much more likely to be something. And so we might get a real price tag
Speaker 5:  at some point here in The future.
Speaker 2:  Look, all I'm saying, I'm, I don't, I don't think it will end up getting
Speaker 2:  banned. I think it will end up getting sold.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I think the opposite. That's so fun. But
Speaker 2:  We'll see. I don't know. Yeah, that's a good, that's a good prop bet.
Speaker 6:  I think nothing will happen. I think Rand Paul, a few other senators,
Speaker 6:  I'll kill it because they can kill it. Right? Like, like you do need, it
Speaker 6:  was what 60 Senators have to all agree and Oh boy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I, I'm I'm with you. I think the massive like
Speaker 5:  betting favorite is nothing. We never hear from this bill again.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I fair enough. But I will say there are, and I have
Speaker 2:  a long history of producing work about the First
Speaker 2:  Amendment. You can go,
Speaker 5:  You're throwing it all away in one verse cast.
Speaker 2:  You can definitely go to it. I feel very strongly about the First Amendment.
Speaker 2:  There are a tiny handful of things that overcome the First
Speaker 2:  Amendment copyright law. As you may be aware,
Speaker 2:  based on my long body of work,
Speaker 2:  national security is one of those things. Foreign ownership of United States
Speaker 2:  media is historically one of those things. And I think that's gotten lost
Speaker 2:  in all this con this is why I'm so focused on like how mechanics of how the
Speaker 2:  bill actually works. Yeah. Because that thing is actually
Speaker 2:  important. Even If, you, even If you believe they're not using it now. Should
Speaker 2:  they have that capability has traditionally been so big of a deal
Speaker 2:  that we've stopped it before it could even happen. And in this case, we just
Speaker 2:  let it slide 'cause it's an app with dancing kids on it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I mean, and if If you believe that there
Speaker 5:  is a nefarious thing happening here that is the true genius of TikTok, right?
Speaker 5:  That like, like the, the Galaxy brain thing you hear is like all the kids
Speaker 5:  in China are seeing on Deion, which is like the Chinese version of TikTok.
Speaker 5:  They're seeing like stem and how to build robots and code and all this stuff.
Speaker 5:  And we're just seeing dance challenges because it's making us all stupid
Speaker 5:  and slow. And this is like a long con plan to make the Chinese kids smarter
Speaker 5:  than the American kids. Which like if true, incredible. Like
Speaker 5:  well played everybody,
Speaker 6:  My favorite concern,
Speaker 2:  That's why they added the STEM tab to TikTok by the way. I know like this.
Speaker 2:  And I just wanna point out, it's right behind shopping. First it's shopping,
Speaker 2:  then it's stem like, but I think
Speaker 5:  The one thing I'm hung up on, like just, I I agree with you about the 50
Speaker 5:  to zero thing. And I think the idea that there is a smoking
Speaker 5:  gun is very possible. And I'm so willing to be convinced
Speaker 5:  by Yeah. Any shred of evidence that says this is
Speaker 5:  happening. There are plans to make it happen. There is capability to do it
Speaker 5:  quickly. Like whatever. The flip side of it for me is,
Speaker 5:  we've been at this for four years now and we've never heard it. And
Speaker 5:  there are so, so many people with incentive
Speaker 5:  to talk about this publicly. Like so many people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, but why won't they? Well,
Speaker 6:  I don't know. They get it.
Speaker 2:  We won't talk. Have you met politicians? They they usually talk about it.
Speaker 2:  This
Speaker 5:  Is what I'm saying. So either it is something so
Speaker 5:  grave and incredible that we can't be trust. It's like, it's like some alien
Speaker 5:  shit where like, we can't know or else it would destroy our way of life
Speaker 5:  way. Or there's nothing to talk about. Like I, I don't know how to think.
Speaker 5:  It's not one of those people
Speaker 2:  Usually when there's nothing they make shit up. I just historically with
Speaker 2:  politicians, usually when there's, then there's nothing. you know, it's like
Speaker 2:  they pull off the sheet and the Scooby-Doo kids are like, it was bullshit
Speaker 2:  all along. Like, you know, like that's his,
Speaker 2:  I dunno, maybe that's it. Maybe I'm just over indexing on 50 to zero and
Speaker 2:  the fact that so many of them were convinced by this campaign and
Speaker 2:  there's something there that they won't say, what
Speaker 6:  If this is all viral marketing for three body problems.
Speaker 2:  Very good. Netflix
Speaker 6:  Just really going for it this year. Yeah. We could see Who knows.
Speaker 2:  Look, I I think I've been convinced through the course of the conversation
Speaker 2:  that most likely outcome is nothing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Exactly. That's what Netflix wants you to think.
Speaker 2:  And, and I, I really do think, and I can't say
Speaker 2:  this more clearly, the government needs to show us its evidence before it
Speaker 2:  takes this action. Yes. We have not seen it. That is If. you take away one
Speaker 2:  thing from this conversation. It's me saying the government needs to show
Speaker 2:  us this evidence before it takes the action.
Speaker 2:  But it's crazy that the evidence apparently exists. Right. Such that
Speaker 2:  they voted 50 to zero.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You seem more convinced than ever that there is evidence,
Speaker 5:  which I think is fair. Like what we've seen in the last seven days would
Speaker 5:  indicate that some people have seen some things. I think that's fair,
Speaker 5:  but I just am, I don't think we should take that on faith.
Speaker 2:  I think Americans should own American algorithms. That's it. I I think that,
Speaker 2:  I think that comes down to it like
Speaker 6:  No algorithms.
Speaker 2:  Well, I mean If you really ask me. Yeah. I think we should get rid of the
Speaker 2:  algorithmic media and go start bring back RSS Yeah. A bill to bring
Speaker 2:  back RSS the United States vote Patel.
Speaker 6:  That's what they should do.
Speaker 5:  Just put TikTok on the fedi verse. It solves all of our problems.
Speaker 2:  Everything will be fine. But barring that, I think it's pretty, it it is,
Speaker 2:  it just feels reasonable to me that what people see and
Speaker 2:  consume should be they, the,
Speaker 2:  the people who are accountable for that should be here
Speaker 2:  closer to you.
Speaker 5:  You know, who would agree with that argument is the Communist party of China.
Speaker 2:  And also most people, like, I
Speaker 2:  think most governments are very interested in making sure that their citizens
Speaker 2:  see something that comes from within that's pretty natural. And
Speaker 2:  again, this I think just comes back to everything we've been talking about,
Speaker 2:  which is do you, do you think
Speaker 2:  that you are like an individual and a sea of individuals or
Speaker 2:  that you are part of a collective? And I think the internet makes everybody
Speaker 2:  feel very alone in that particular way. And, and like almost every
Speaker 2:  political problem comes back to that.
Speaker 6:  I'm just thinking about what happens if we get like, everybody's like, oh
Speaker 6:  no, you're right. Like we need to own our own media and then we get like
Speaker 6:  the BBC version of TikTok and like the
Speaker 6:  NHK version of TikTok. Like the national broadcastings.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  For,
Speaker 6:  For company, for countries, but for TikTok.
Speaker 5:  I mean NPRI think has a TikTok account. Just imagine that.
Speaker 6:  I like, yeah. What's theirs? What's the NPR r social media app look like?
Speaker 6:  I wanna see it.
Speaker 2:  Well get
Speaker 6:  On it. Is it just podcast? Is it just the Apple podcast Now?
Speaker 2:  It's just that voice. Alright, we should take a break. Everyone can
Speaker 2:  yell at me in the comments. Also, just tell us what you think. We have a
Speaker 2:  hotline.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna say, I think it's, I actually think I do want people to reach
Speaker 5:  out. You should call the hotline. Eight six six Virg one one. You should
Speaker 5:  email us Vergecast at the virg.com. But if I had to bet, I think most people
Speaker 5:  are gonna agree with you, Eli. I think it is, it is just, my brain is so
Speaker 5:  broken by the fact that you were the one making this argument. I think it's
Speaker 5:  a perfectly fair argument. We're all sort of arguing based
Speaker 5:  on evidence that no one has. And fundamentally you have to trust somebody.
Speaker 5:  And I think ultimately saying the i I choose to not trust China is like not
Speaker 5:  an unreasonable place to be. I just can't believe you're the one saying all
Speaker 5:  of this. But I'll, I'll, I'll get there. I'll settle down. It'll be,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What, what's the, what's the line of foolish consistencies
Speaker 2:  little minds?
Speaker 2:  Sure. Whatever that quote is. I'm real smart is what I'm trying to say.
Speaker 2:  No, let us know. I look, I've been reading our own comments. I think most
Speaker 2:  of our commenters believe I'm like stridently opposed to this ban.
Speaker 2:  I dunno why. Probably 'cause I haven't said anything about it until now.
Speaker 2:  I think the United States governments owes us this evidence. That's like
Speaker 2:  the main thing I think. But apart from that, I think it's reasonable to say
Speaker 2:  it. Alright. Media ownership
Speaker 7:  outsourcing projects simple, quick, and
Speaker 7:  completed on time ready to scale smarter.
Speaker 11:  clickup.com to get started.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right. I want to tell Alex and David a story about the
Speaker 2:  studio as Lord. It's looking around in the break
Speaker 2:  and things have moved and I, I know why they've moved and it's very funny.
Speaker 2:  So The Verge is part of Vox Media. As you may know,
Speaker 2:  Vox Media has a podcast network called the Vox Media Podcast Network on the
Speaker 2:  Vox Media Podcast Network is a very good podcast called Point Forward with
Speaker 2:  Andre a Goodal and Evan Turner who are basketball players. I'm
Speaker 2:  assuming most people know that, but If you don't. They're basketball players.
Speaker 2:  Now I
Speaker 11:  Know they're very tall
Speaker 2:  And very famous. They do the podcast in the same studio we are in
Speaker 2:  and they, they redress it with their stuff. Are they
Speaker 5:  The reasons it smells like weed all the time. No different podcasts.
Speaker 6:  Does this explain why my seat sometimes changes height?
Speaker 2:  I think it, it explains the chair moving. I don't, they
Speaker 2:  record on Mondays and it would be incredible if on Thursdays,
Speaker 2:  so I'm just gonna say no to that one. Okay. Call
Speaker 6:  Me and If, you ever smoke that much weed? We'll hang out.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's different. But for the, so they
Speaker 2:  redressed the studio for their show, which makes sense. And then we
Speaker 2:  have to put our stuff back. But I think they didn't notice it for the first
Speaker 2:  few they did in here. So the Hena Cube Yay. Was behind them.
Speaker 5:  Why would they get rid of that?
Speaker 6:  It's so cool.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think we should play NBA. Well, it was before 2K,
Speaker 2:  like NBA 94 on the Hena Cube. I
Speaker 5:  Think Jam probably existed on the, on the Hyah Cube.
Speaker 2:  I don't think you did. Here's my official pitch for a Vox Media podcast network
Speaker 2:  crossover. I will play NBA Jam
Speaker 2:  on a Game Cube with Andre Kwa.
Speaker 5:  Sounds amazing.
Speaker 2:  We have a game cube. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Your move, Andre.
Speaker 2:  We have a long promise that we'll get together and do, and Dave and I'll
Speaker 2:  play Madden. And we just are never in the same place at the same time with
Speaker 2:  the Game Cube. Like we've been in the same place at the same time
Speaker 2:  without a game cube. Both of us have been in this room
Speaker 2:  with the Game Cube, but without the other person, we're gonna figure
Speaker 2:  out all three elements at the same time.
Speaker 6:  I think you need some more elements. Like a, A plug Yeah. Controller. A
Speaker 6:  controller.
Speaker 2:  A copy of Madden. Yes. It's critical elements. Some other
Speaker 6:  Stuff has to happen
Speaker 2:  Just once on on point forward. I want these NBA superstars to be like, is
Speaker 2:  that a Heineken game? He I've been searching for?
Speaker 6:  You're like,
Speaker 5:  Yes. It's like I'm on eBay all the time. Looking
Speaker 2:  For one of those. It's very good. That show's great. You should listen to
Speaker 2:  it. They just had Megan Rapinoe on it's south by with them, which was wonderful.
Speaker 2:  Nice. Hell yeah. All right. Speaking of media, huh? That is your segue.
Speaker 2:  Boy, there's a bunch of media streaming news this week.
Speaker 2:  One correction I have to issue for the audience in our streaming draft. This
Speaker 6:  Is true. I won.
Speaker 2:  I Okay. So. I have long since been claiming that I won. I think
Speaker 2:  given this piece of news, I definitively lost even that.
Speaker 2:  I think I had the best lineup. I think this is an instant dq.
Speaker 6:  What happened to MotorTrend?
Speaker 2:  I picked as my niche streaming service. So David set up the draft.
Speaker 2:  We had to pick player in every category 4K awards.
Speaker 2:  Alex has an expansive definition of what counts as award-winning, streaming
Speaker 2:  service. Correct.
Speaker 2:  Live all these things. And the last one was niche. And I
Speaker 2:  candidly blanked on stage and I was like, I dunno, I have enough. Like I
Speaker 2:  picked TikTok, I'm good. you know, like even that it's going get,
Speaker 2:  you know, banned from app stores. Like, I'll take it for now. I want
Speaker 5:  A ban TikTok. I'm gonna pick it first.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, exactly. The point is to be confounding. Never let him
Speaker 2:  know what's coming. So I blanked on stage and I picked
Speaker 2:  what my father-in-Law had been watching at my home before I left
Speaker 2:  for South by Southwest, which is MotorTrend tv. And we published
Speaker 2:  a streaming draft and YouTube commenters, like this shit went
Speaker 2:  92 weeks ago. Oh no. Like it was killed two weeks ago.
Speaker 2:  So first of all, MotorTrend TV was long gone. Yeah. It was called
Speaker 2:  MotorTrend Plus, there's a rebrand and now it's being
Speaker 2:  shuttered and being folded into Discovery Plus. Oh.
Speaker 2:  Which is where all of us learn about house flipping and going to
Speaker 2:  car auctions. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Have you checked on your father-in-Law? How's he holding up?
Speaker 2:  You know, we haven't brought it up. Just wasn't one of those things. Like
Speaker 2:  is he,
Speaker 5:  He's just watching like, cached videos on, on the
Speaker 2:  Tv. Yeah. you know, we're just gonna let
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You don't wanna, You don't wanna roll to a family member and be like, you
Speaker 2:  have to watch Discovery Plus now. Like
Speaker 6:  I be, the app still works for a while.
Speaker 2:  I think the app is still gonna work for a while. It's No, that's not
Speaker 2:  even right. It's closing in 14 days. Yeah. Super.
Speaker 2:  Super isn't gonna work for a while. Ooh.
Speaker 6:  He's got some time. He's he's got time. He can, he can record
Speaker 6:  it with his phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Episode. I'm just saying episodes. Look, I, I think overall
Speaker 2:  I had the best, the best Suite, but I do
Speaker 2:  think picking an already dead service, like an instant dq.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like If, you pick a thing that's got 90, you're at the draft.
Speaker 6:  Netflix is next, but yeah. Get it. Netflix.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That was the real takeaway is Netflix is super dead really soon. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Any minute now. Don't you worry, it's coming.
Speaker 2:  I do think my ability to pick a, an already dead streaming service
Speaker 2:  distracted from your bold prediction that Netflix would die soon.
Speaker 6:  It didn't. I had friends messaging me being like, I heard the podcast
Speaker 6:  Netflix, Alex, what the hell? And I'm like, look,
Speaker 5:  It's outta your mind.
Speaker 6:  I, I think, I think Paramount plus Netflix,
Speaker 2:  I don't actually be very clear.
Speaker 6:  Say,
Speaker 2:  Alright, let's, that's some news. RIP to Motor Trend tv.
Speaker 6:  Real one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Bitch and Rides. Where will you live? Now? That's a real show
Speaker 2:  by the way.
Speaker 6:  It'll live, it'll live on Discovery Plus.
Speaker 2:  It's true.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You, you'll be fine.
Speaker 5:  Which will then be part of Max, which will eventually be merged with Paramount
Speaker 5:  Plus.
Speaker 2:  Yes. One way or another. You're gonna watch Bitching Rides. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Coming for We'll find you. Don't you worry.
Speaker 2:  I have a lot to say about that show, but I think, I think it's a very limited
Speaker 2:  audience for criticism of Bitching Rides. I've watched a lot of it with my
Speaker 2:  father-in-Law. Okay. Actual news TV news. By the
Speaker 2:  way, here's the dis the disclosure. We'll just get 'em all the way. We mentioned
Speaker 2:  Netflix. I was at EP on a Netflix show called The. future of
Speaker 2:  NBC is an investor in our company. They run the Peacock service, which If
Speaker 2:  you believe Alex Will Far outlive Netflix.
Speaker 6:  I'm right, I'm right. Don't worry about it. I'm right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Our company makes Full Swing the golf show on Netflix. That's pretty
Speaker 2:  good. That's it. Those are disclosures today there. I'm sure there are more.
Speaker 2:  I believe Wired connections are better than wireless ones. RIP starlink.
Speaker 2:  That, that's just a fact. I say that because the starlink people think that
Speaker 2:  I'm in the pocket of big Comcast. Yeah, that's a real, I say that all the
Speaker 2:  time. It still comes up. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's what I thought.
Speaker 2:  They're like, he's in Big Ethernet's Pocket. All right.
Speaker 2:  Actual news. Yeah. YouTube is revamping its TV app, not YouTube
Speaker 2:  tv, but the YouTube app on TVs.
Speaker 6:  I have a question about this. Yeah, yeah. Who is not watching in
Speaker 6:  full screen? What, what people are like, eh, I wanna
Speaker 6:  watch like with the ads and crap all around it. Who are they?
Speaker 2:  This is everyone's dream is to make QVC. Well,
Speaker 5:  It's that, that is half of it. I firmly agree with that. That like,
Speaker 5:  the goal is to let you point at something on your television and it just
Speaker 5:  appears at your house the next day. Like that is literally what everyone
Speaker 5:  who makes TV stuff wants
Speaker 2:  The only dream that anyone has ever had.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Truly the other half of it is, YouTube
Speaker 5:  has been on this very long quest to get YouTube
Speaker 5:  onto televisions in like a more YouTubey way. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  YouTube has talked for years now about how the TV is the fastest
Speaker 5:  growing YouTube platform. Like it's, it's now to the point that I just
Speaker 5:  laugh whenever they put that in a press release because it's like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  it's been that way for like a decade now. But the problem with
Speaker 5:  that is there are lots of things about YouTube that people like that
Speaker 5:  are not just watching the video, right? Like, there's all this community
Speaker 5:  stuff. Comments are very important. Recommendations are very important. You
Speaker 5:  want to subscribe. Like it's harder to subscribe to a channel from your television
Speaker 5:  than it is from your phone or your computer. And that is actually a
Speaker 5:  threat to YouTube over time as its stuff gets bigger, right? So yeah, they've
Speaker 5:  been on this thing forever to figure out like, how do we let you use YouTube
Speaker 5:  while also watching something on your television. And their s For a long
Speaker 5:  time was to connect it better to your phone. Like, you know how they have
Speaker 5:  the thing now where you're watching YouTube on your TV and you open up YouTube
Speaker 5:  on your phone, that little thing pops up that's like, do you wanna connect
Speaker 5:  first of all that future rules and thank you to YouTube for doing it. But
Speaker 5:  that was their big plan, and I think that's how they thought they were gonna
Speaker 5:  solve it, right? Like, they were like, we're gonna be both the first and
Speaker 5:  the second screen simultaneously. This to me feels like them saying
Speaker 5:  that's not really working. And so actually what we need to do is put more
Speaker 5:  stuff more accessible on the big screen in front of you.
Speaker 5:  So they have this new thing where in it's full screen by default, I think.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But you can press a button and it will, the, the video will shrink,
Speaker 5:  and then on the right side you'll get some of the metadata, the
Speaker 5:  description and the comments. And like, you know, I said a list of the products
Speaker 5:  in the video, it'll look more like seeing YouTube in like a desktop
Speaker 5:  browser. To me that feels like a
Speaker 5:  Reasonable thing to do. And also like, yeah, the most
Speaker 5:  obvious thing, they're like, what if we just did YouTube on your television?
Speaker 5:  It's like, yeah, that's the one. but it does feel like they're saying
Speaker 5:  this thing where we're gonna connect it to your other devices and you're
Speaker 5:  gonna be able to do it all simultaneously maybe is not actually the answer.
Speaker 5:  The way they thought.
Speaker 6:  It kind of feels like they pulled a Vizio Oh God. And went,
Speaker 6:  oh, you know what? Actually people don't wanna control
Speaker 6:  their TV viewing experience from their phone. Visio was like, yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's what you meant. I was worried there any number of other bad things
Speaker 2:  I could
Speaker 6:  Maybe No, no, no. I'm, I'm thinking very clearly because I just, I have the
Speaker 6:  26 physio TV and I put it in the guest room and I have a, somebody staying
Speaker 6:  over and I was like, oh, I have to, like, where's the remote? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  This person, I had to give you an Android tablet
Speaker 6:  And I was like, you're just gonna have to use your regular phone. I'm sorry.
Speaker 6:  And, and it feels like, like, and
Speaker 2:  I refuse to buy a $29 Roku to solve this problem.
Speaker 6:  It's true. No, it's 'cause I couldn't find it. It's in another box, but I
Speaker 6:  don't know where anything is. But, but yeah, this just feels like the same
Speaker 6:  thing where, where people are starting to realize, wait, actually the phone
Speaker 6:  is not the best way to do this. And sometimes you just wanna watch this and
Speaker 6:  interact with it with a remote, because remotes are probably the best way
Speaker 6:  to control TV is because they've worked Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Forever. Yeah. And the idea that you'll own both a first and second
Speaker 2:  screen is like the dream. Like you'll watch up there and shop down here and
Speaker 2:  it's like, people do that all the time, but they don't. No. We
Speaker 6:  Watch up there and we TikTok down here for now.
Speaker 2:  I think this entire story is explained by one quote
Speaker 2:  from the blog post, just one and the
Speaker 2:  image that YouTube supplied in that blog post. So the quote from
Speaker 2:  the blog post, the design changes started with quote, the
Speaker 2:  idea of reducing the size of the video player and simplifying the
Speaker 2:  interactions.
Speaker 6:  I hate it.
Speaker 2:  That's just like, we're just gonna make the video player smaller because
Speaker 2:  we have, everyone has long thought that the TV is like the lean
Speaker 2:  back. You just put up the video and you're done and you're going. And now
Speaker 2:  they're realizing, oh, this is just an Android tablet in your wall. What
Speaker 2:  if we just let you control it like an Android tablet instead of saying all
Speaker 2:  the interactivity happens on your phone. Yeah. Which is what you're saying.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But that first one, we're just gonna make the video player smaller
Speaker 2:  that is now acceptable on our TVs.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  That's a sea change.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I I I fundamentally disagree with YouTube on this one.
Speaker 6:  Possibly. YouTube is small.
Speaker 2:  This is what I'm saying. The whole story is in that quote. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  No, I I No, I agree. 'cause you look at that and then you look at the picture
Speaker 6:  and it's her talking about products and then all the
Speaker 6:  products are down at the bottom of the video.
Speaker 2:  No, what there? Yes, that is true. Okay. That's not what you were talking
Speaker 2:  about. My point is, you pull over in your car and
Speaker 2:  actually look at this image and you're like, here's what YouTube thought
Speaker 2:  best represents their big idea. And you look at the
Speaker 2:  thumbnail and you look at the headline and you're like, oh, YouTube
Speaker 2:  has a quality problem. Because the headline is, I bought
Speaker 2:  in All co in all caps, many beauty products that actually work
Speaker 2:  because that is how you agro. And maybe this video is great. I, I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  not saying that quality of the video is wrong. I'm saying YouTube is, the
Speaker 2:  algorithm is actively cheapening the YouTube brand because it's a
Speaker 2:  YouTube thumbnail with like a YouTube face on it. It's a headline that has
Speaker 2:  all caps. It's shouting at you and then underneath it, what
Speaker 2:  you're supposed to do is buy some stuff. Yeah. And you're like, oh,
Speaker 2:  this, all this adds up to a less premium
Speaker 2:  good thing. Cute. you know what I mean? Like, it's, all of it is being in
Speaker 2:  the mall where everyone's yelling at you. I
Speaker 5:  Think you're old. Like, that's, that's what I mean,
Speaker 5:  not to put too fine a point on it, but like the idea that
Speaker 2:  I think this feels bad.
Speaker 5:  I I think because you think
Speaker 2:  I like cool things that are cool. I'm sorry, I didn't realize that was an
Speaker 2:  old guy thing.
Speaker 5:  No, I mean, like, if, if you're, if you're mad at this
Speaker 5:  particular video, fine. It has 2.8 million views, which I would
Speaker 5:  say is a, a reasonable sign that it's, it's pretty good and people like it.
Speaker 5:  But also
Speaker 2:  I'm saying they should revert control of this algorithm to me personally,
Speaker 2:  the President of America. Just
Speaker 5:  If this, if this thumbnail just had a jumping truck, would you
Speaker 5:  be less mad about it
Speaker 2:  And then underneath it was trucks you could buy? Yeah, probably. Right? No,
Speaker 2:  look, I, I have, I don't have anything to say about beauty product videos
Speaker 2:  or any this category video. I'm saying the presentation that
Speaker 2:  YouTube picked for what do we want you to do on televisions
Speaker 2:  is a shouty shopping video. Right. Like all
Speaker 2:  caps in the headline. Like they are trying to take the market
Speaker 2:  away from television. That's long been the goal
Speaker 2:  on TVs is where they are growing the most. And I,
Speaker 2:  I think there's a real clash between what works in the algorithmic YouTube
Speaker 2:  feed on phones and desktops and then this experience on a television.
Speaker 5:  This proves the opposite to me. Okay. What this says to me is that
Speaker 5:  YouTube thought for years that what people would do when they
Speaker 5:  sat down on their couch is they would YouTube like they television,
Speaker 5:  which is to say, put something on and sit for 30 minutes and look at it without
Speaker 5:  doing anything else. And YouTube has slowly discovered over time that not
Speaker 5:  only is that not what people wanna do, it's not even what they wanna do with
Speaker 5:  their remotes. That this thing where like fundamentally YouTube is
Speaker 5:  about the thing that you're watching, but only in part about the thing that
Speaker 5:  you're watching. It's also about who the creator is and what the
Speaker 5:  description is and looking at the products in the video, because a lot of
Speaker 5:  people do like to shop for this stuff and seeing the comments and, and finding
Speaker 5:  recommendations and going down these rabbit holes. Like to me what this says
Speaker 5:  is, oh, people actually use YouTube on their TV with their remote
Speaker 5:  Exactly the same way they use it on their phone. And so what we need to give
Speaker 5:  them is YouTube that looks like a desktop browser.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, I think I agree. I agree with you. And in that specific
Speaker 2:  way, I am saying that even If, you look at this headline,
Speaker 2:  for some reason the word bought is capitalized, but the words that actually
Speaker 2:  work are not,
Speaker 5:  And mini beauty products is all Cap All
Speaker 2:  Is all cap. Like they are very tiny. It's algorithmic. Like when you
Speaker 2:  take the algorithmic media and you just like make it this much bigger, I
Speaker 2:  think that stuff is gonna get highlighted in different ways. And maybe the
Speaker 2:  fight is between people don't care and people do care. But you just end up
Speaker 2:  in this place where all social media turns into QVC and
Speaker 2:  really the dream of all interactive TV has always been to be
Speaker 2:  QVC and YouTube turning itself into QVC,
Speaker 2:  like literally turning itself into QVC puts them right next to
Speaker 2:  real QVC.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is
Speaker 2:  Weird.
Speaker 5:  No, I, I, I totally agree with that. And that is very clearly where all of
Speaker 5:  this is going. They're like, look at some ads, pay us a bunch of money
Speaker 5:  and buy every single product that exists anywhere in this video. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that is how we went. But you know what's interesting is the, the way,
Speaker 5:  like our comments are picked up on this too, on the, the piece that we wrote,
Speaker 5:  what was it a few months ago now that TikTok changed the thing where now
Speaker 5:  when you swipe up to see the comments, instead of pulling the comments up
Speaker 5:  over the video, it shrinks the video just down to the top of the screen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So you can still see the whole video just not as big.
Speaker 5:  That's essentially what this is doing now too. Right? It's saying you wanna
Speaker 5:  get to the other part of the interface instead of pulling it up over top
Speaker 5:  of what you're seeing. We're just gonna shrink what you're seeing. And I
Speaker 5:  think you can argue about whether that's the
Speaker 5:  correct viewing experience or not. But I think that is very much the trend
Speaker 5:  of where we're headed is like we want you to see the whole picture. We're
Speaker 5:  just also gonna recognize that the rest of the interface is at least just
Speaker 5:  as important as the video
Speaker 2:  Or at least provides more opportunities to shop. Right?
Speaker 6:  Mm. That one, I mean it's just all
Speaker 2:  Oh, you're watching this video?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I've been watching the video this whole time. I'm sorry.
Speaker 6:  I wanted to see what beauty products actually work, but it's not, they
Speaker 2:  Are many. They
Speaker 6:  Are, they, they're very, very tiny. But it's, it's cheap stuff that I don't,
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna use this.
Speaker 2:  Well, they're many. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  But it's, but it's
Speaker 2:  Cheap. Well, you'd think it'd be good stuff, but cheaper not
Speaker 6:  It's cheap brands Got
Speaker 2:  You. Ice cold Alex.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm, I'm, I'm one of those bougie bitches when it comes to my Sephora
Speaker 6:  runs.
Speaker 2:  The last time I watched QVCI was in a hotel room in California
Speaker 2:  and it was, you know, it was the winter, it was just recently and
Speaker 2:  on QVC in California, someone was earnestly
Speaker 2:  trying to sell a corded snowblower and being like, this cord
Speaker 2:  is so convenient, you just plug in the snowblower. And I was like, this is
Speaker 2:  doomed. And somehow this is also The future of all media.
Speaker 6:  It is. Everybody wants
Speaker 2:  To just straightforwardly being like, what it is is a push snowblower, but
Speaker 2:  you want to just plug it right in. No batteries to worry about.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. 'cause then you then you get to use your, your extension cord also
Speaker 6:  purchased on QVC. Exactly.
Speaker 5:  It really is amazing how much of like the stuff you see on TikTok now even
Speaker 5:  seals some of the conventions of how people used to talk on QVC. Like the
Speaker 5:  thing where it's like, describe the problem somebody has in overly dramatic
Speaker 5:  turn and then big beautiful turn into what a cool world
Speaker 5:  you live in. Like that's now TikTok shop. And they're like, I can't believe
Speaker 5:  how expensive it is. It's on the TikTok shop. It's only gonna be Yeah, this
Speaker 5:  price for this long. Get it now. It's like you're, you're literally doing
Speaker 5:  a QVC bit. And I suspect most of these people probably
Speaker 5:  don't know what QVC is and have certainly never seen it, but
Speaker 5:  like, it just turns out that's the correct way to do a buy this thing
Speaker 5:  from me video.
Speaker 2:  It has just been optimized over time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's just like one evolutionary way Yeah. To tell someone to buy your
Speaker 5:  stupid cheap product. And
Speaker 6:  It's the Q Vvc way real, like big
Speaker 2:  Thinkers. I was just watching this, the, you know, it's like the classic
Speaker 2:  QVC, like yeah. Male host, female host. Like, wow,
Speaker 6:  What are you talking about today? How are you gonna cooking your kitchen
Speaker 2:  With and, and how do you power this snowblower? And I was like, I don't,
Speaker 2:  this is like obvious on its face. Like
Speaker 2:  it was very good. It was the most QVC I've watched in, in some time. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I, in the mid, it was 70 degrees in California. I was watching people try
Speaker 2:  to sell me a snowblower. I was like, I don't, maybe I travel too much for
Speaker 2:  work.
Speaker 6:  I can't watch QVC because one time in the nineties I watched an episode of
Speaker 6:  Mama's Family where she got addicted to QVC. That's bad. And,
Speaker 6:  and the family had to be like, you can't use QVC anymore. And for whatever
Speaker 6:  reason I was like, me too. Yeah. As like a five-year-old
Speaker 2:  The end. I will tell one more QVC related story. My dad was
Speaker 2:  the overnight doctor in the ER in Wisconsin. So he would
Speaker 2:  come, he wouldn't be able to sleep at night when he wasn't working right.
Speaker 2:  Because he was used to being up all night. Boy did we have a lot of stuff
Speaker 2:  in my house.
Speaker 2:  Boy did I grow up eating a lot of dehydrated apples. The
Speaker 6:  Only thing on TV at that time of night, like, what are you gonna watch? Oh,
Speaker 2:  I did it again six to eight weeks later in the eighties, we got a food
Speaker 2:  dehydrator. It was great.
Speaker 6:  The fruit leather is in incredible at
Speaker 2:  House. He was so proud of that food dehydrator. It was just a circle with
Speaker 2:  a fan. I just, I don't know If you ever actually looked at it? Nevermind.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I've seen
Speaker 2:  One. They're like, we took the hair dryer and now we've pointed it up. It's
Speaker 2:  a food dehydrator. You
Speaker 6:  Get fruit leather.
Speaker 2:  This is by the way, the Dyson story is they invented a fan and now they only
Speaker 2:  make fan related products. It's very good. Okay. Other news,
Speaker 2:  Spotify now has music videos.
Speaker 6:  I I don't subscribe.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 6:  My God. Sorry. I, I'm excited for you all. I'm excited for everyone who
Speaker 6:  subscribes and loves a music video. I just open YouTube
Speaker 6:  on my TV in a tiny box next to below a bunch of sales links
Speaker 6:  and, and watch my music videos that way. That's
Speaker 5:  True. You're gonna be able to buy all the cars and beers
Speaker 5:  and liquors and hats that you see in every music video for the
Speaker 5:  rest of your life. Alex, are you so excited?
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be really, really great for me.
Speaker 5:  No, I think the, the music that he was saying, like, it turns out that every
Speaker 5:  streaming story right now is kind of a TikTok story. Like, and
Speaker 5:  we've talked about it a bunch on this show in recent weeks, right? Like this
Speaker 5:  question of like, okay, Universal's in a big fight with TikTok, TikTok,
Speaker 5:  TikTok might be having an existential crisis, whether it's gonna continue
Speaker 5:  to exist, who is going to show up and say, oh, all the music
Speaker 5:  videos you wanna watch, which are a gigantic portion of what is
Speaker 5:  successful on the internet as a whole. And Spotify
Speaker 5:  is like, yeah, we'll do it. But Spotify is doing it in like the slowest,
Speaker 5:  weirdest way. They have like a tiny number of artists and a few videos and
Speaker 5:  it's like, guys, it's not actually that hard to put videos into your
Speaker 5:  app Spotify. Like, kudos for trying I
Speaker 5:  suppose, but like If, you, If you really wanted to do this, do it
Speaker 2:  Better. Also, apple has had music videos forever. It's not a great player,
Speaker 2:  it's not a cool experience. But if you're ever bored on your Apple TV and
Speaker 2:  your Apple Music subscriber, you can just be like, show me music videos and
Speaker 2:  we'll just play a playlist of music videos. Or you can open
Speaker 6:  The YouTube app and and do it there.
Speaker 5:  I do think though this thing where that, that YouTube music
Speaker 5:  does very well and no one else does very well. Where you can sort of seamlessly
Speaker 5:  switch from video to song is very cool. And I think that's what Spotify is
Speaker 5:  going for here too. But Spotify is just like desperate to be an app that
Speaker 5:  you look at more because they want you to subscribe, discover
Speaker 5:  more stuff, pay them money and like look at ads,
Speaker 5:  but they just aren't gonna get there. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like remember what was it like a year ago when they basically like redesigned
Speaker 5:  the whole app to be TikTok and everybody was like, no thanks. Like I just
Speaker 5:  wanna play a song and then put my phone away. And I think they just, they're,
Speaker 5:  I don't think they're ever gonna escape that. Honestly.
Speaker 6:  I think Spotify is gonna buy Paramount Plus that's who's gonna do it
Speaker 6:  Solves everything
Speaker 2:  Done after Netflix collapses
Speaker 2:  in other Spotify news. Yeah. Neil Young has returned to Spotify.
Speaker 2:  I'm pretty sure this is only on the list. So we can reference the time that
Speaker 2:  Neil Young was on The Vergecast and describes
Speaker 6:  With his little, with his little player
Speaker 2:  With the pono. And he described the MacBook to me as Fisher price
Speaker 2:  quality and said, your new engineer is Captain Kangaroo.
Speaker 2:  I think we can just run the clips, Andrew, I don't think we have to say anything
Speaker 2:  else about this. Okay. That man really cares about sound quality.
Speaker 2:  Very confused about how digital audio sampling works
Speaker 2:  refuses to acknowledge that. It's very hard to hear the difference at a
Speaker 2:  appropriate bit rate and thinks that, and I just
Speaker 2:  wanna say it, the Mac, he thinks the MacBook Pro is a piece of crap,
Speaker 2:  but an actual quote that we can run now it's
Speaker 12:  A piece of crap. Are you kidding? That's Fisher price quality.
Speaker 12:  That's like Captain Kangaroo your new engineer, the
Speaker 12:  MacBook Pro. What are you talking about? You can't, you can't get anything
Speaker 12:  out of that thing.
Speaker 2:  All right, there you go, everybody. Fantastic. That was Neil. Young. Thanks
Speaker 2:  Neil.
Speaker 5:  No notes. Neil Young.
Speaker 2:  Well even, even Neil has caved to Spotify. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Everyone does eventually. Well not me,
Speaker 5:  But it is, I I just appreciate the logic that like, he left, he
Speaker 5:  was the, the like loud protester to Joe Rogan, right? Right. When he
Speaker 5:  signed a huge deal at Spotify. Neil Young was like, I can't be on this platform.
Speaker 5:  And then Joe Rogan got an even bigger but now
Speaker 5:  non-exclusive deal. So he's now everywhere. And Neil
Speaker 5:  Young's like, well, shit, I gotta, I gotta sell music somewhere.
Speaker 6:  It's like, I do enjoy those royalties. Guess I'm stuck. Yeah, those
Speaker 6:  are nice.
Speaker 5:  Go beyond. Go beyond like title. I don't think they have podcasts.
Speaker 2:  Oh my god. Neil's young website. It's so bananas. It's, it's
Speaker 2:  amazing.
Speaker 6:  Incredible.
Speaker 2:  I wanted to read the blog post about his return to Spotify, but it
Speaker 2:  appears to be down. And also NELI Young's website is fully insane and
Speaker 2:  looks like an old time newspaper from the Wild West. It's so, so good. It's
Speaker 2:  incredible. It does have a full res audio player on it with a switch that
Speaker 2:  says Master. Yeah. Your choices are low res MP three or master
Speaker 2:  quality. I love it. It's very good. I, again, I love Neil Young. If we just,
Speaker 2:  you'll listen to episode of To Vergecast after these clips. All of it was
Speaker 2:  astounding. I'm rarely taken aback the way that Neil Young
Speaker 2:  took me aback when I was like, so computers exist and he was like, kill yourself.
Speaker 6:  Get this little music player.
Speaker 2:  All right. Last bit of video news. I'm just gonna say it. It's about Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Mm.
Speaker 6:  Or X You mean X? Yeah. X
Speaker 2:  Linda. Yaccarino. Everyone's favorite. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Composed Stable Media executive. That's wonderful. Continues to say
Speaker 2:  X is becoming a video first platform because
Speaker 6:  You get more money from ads.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, when I look around the social media industry and the media
Speaker 2:  industry, I can confidently say that the pivot to video has worked out
Speaker 2:  super great for everyone every time and all these companies are doing great
Speaker 2:  and not doing layoffs. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Totally. Very, very accurate thing you said. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Not, not the biggest companies in the world are super not doing layoffs because
Speaker 2:  video is totally great for them. And then
Speaker 2:  everyone's favorite Free Speech Warrior Elon Musk signed
Speaker 2:  Don Lemon to do a show on XI think he thought
Speaker 2:  Don Lemon would be sort of the, the counterpart to Tucker Carlson who does
Speaker 2:  a show on X Don Lemon said, okay, Elon, it'll be my first interview.
Speaker 2:  They did an interview. We, we saw a tiny little clip of the interview.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 6:  Couldn't finish watching the clip.
Speaker 2:  The clip is Don Lemon saying, don't you think you have to answer to reporters
Speaker 2:  for like hate speech on the platform? Yeah. And Elon saying, I don't have
Speaker 2:  to talk to reporters, I'm only talking to you because you're on the X platform,
Speaker 2:  which is very funny. Okay. Deal canceled. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  we talked about this I believe last week, but in classic Elon
Speaker 2:  Musk fashion, there was no actual contract. Mm. So now
Speaker 2:  Don Lemon is out there threatening to sue x
Speaker 2:  Yes. For a contract that doesn't exist. And I just want all
Speaker 2:  of these people, If, you are somewhere around Elon Musk. Just write some
Speaker 2:  stuff down and sign it on a napkin.
Speaker 2:  All right. In the notes app, have him take a sharpie to your phone and
Speaker 2:  sign your phone. After showing him the contract on a notes app,
Speaker 2:  anything is better than the current situation where people just vibe deal
Speaker 2:  with Elon.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Don't, don't vibe deal. No
Speaker 2:  Vibe. Please. I beg of you.
Speaker 6:  What about Handshake
Speaker 2:  Anyway? No, no, no. No Vibes. Handshakes are the ultimate vibes.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Sorry. I wanted to make sure, I wanted to like, I wanted to double
Speaker 6:  check. I felt that way. but I don, like I needed to check
Speaker 2:  In. Yeah. Handshakes. They should give that to you in law school. Okay. Handshakes
Speaker 2:  are the ultimate vibes. All
Speaker 6:  Right. That's a, that's a class actually. Like
Speaker 2:  No one really knows what's happening on the other side of that handshake.
Speaker 6:  Well, I mean, not a contract in, in Elon's case,
Speaker 2:  Never a contract. In Elon's case,
Speaker 5:  Handshakes are the ultimate vibes, by the way, is algorithmic warfare's first
Speaker 5:  album title. And it's like surf rock and a variant
Speaker 2:  Type.
Speaker 2:  Anyhow, it's very funny that Elon claims that he's a free speech absolutist
Speaker 2:  canceled the deal over the most minor of questions when you run
Speaker 2:  a giant platform with speech on it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That interview supposedly running on Monday.
Speaker 5:  I am going to watch as much of it as I can physically stomach.
Speaker 6:  I, I started it and, and
Speaker 2:  You started just that clip.
Speaker 6:  I started the clip. Don spoke Elon started to talk
Speaker 6:  and like everything about it, I was like, oh, I'm just cringing
Speaker 6:  so hard. I can't even finish hearing him. Like finish the sentence.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just the awkwardness alone is, is tough. It was, but we'll
Speaker 5:  see.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. I, here's one thing I'll say. Many people can have
Speaker 2:  many opinions of Don Lemon. Elon mostly signed all those deals with
Speaker 2:  journalists who treat him like he has all the answers. Tucker in his
Speaker 2:  interviews with Elon treats him like all the answers. Matt Taibbi treats
Speaker 2:  him like, you're letting me do this thing with all the answers. This is the
Speaker 2:  first time I think anyone's straight up been like, so there's a
Speaker 2:  lot of racism here. Are you accountable for it? And he just didn't know what
Speaker 2:  to do. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Elon does not like to be asked questions.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  End of sentence, end of
Speaker 6:  Sentence. He just, he he doesn't like to be pushed ever. Like do, do not
Speaker 6:  push him. That's a good way to have your, your vibes deal. Un
Speaker 6:  vibe.
Speaker 2:  Just sign contracts. If there's one thing I I just beg of you If you it,
Speaker 2:  it protects both parties. It's not, alright, we gotta take a break
Speaker 2:  here. There are form contracts available online. Alright.
Speaker 2:  Just those will be fine. Anything.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 13:  This episode
Speaker 15:  visit kia.com/nine to learn more. Ask your Kia
Speaker 15:  dealer for availability. No system, no matter how advanced can compensate
Speaker 15:  for all driver error and or driving conditions, always drive safely.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Lightning round. We gotta make this fact we are way
Speaker 2:  over. This has been a deep Vergecast. We did food
Speaker 2:  dehydrating, we did Elon Musk hour on the First Amendment.
Speaker 2:  Chinese interference. We talked about motor trend tv. I just wanna say
Speaker 2:  we've been everywhere. This is why you come here. Yeah. And now it's
Speaker 2:  lightning around. And David says he has a sponsor.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So at South by Southwest, a friend
Speaker 5:  of The Vergecast named Simon came and it was his birthday and his big
Speaker 5:  plan was when we said it was lightning round time to scream. It's my
Speaker 5:  birthday and I'm sponsoring The Vergecast. We didn't do a lightning round
Speaker 5:  and he came up to me like full devastated. Oh no, no. So Simon
Speaker 5:  today is sponsoring the lightning round.
Speaker 6:  Hell yeah. Simon,
Speaker 2:  Happy birthday Simon.
Speaker 5:  Simon. We love you. Happy birthday.
Speaker 2:  All right. For your lightning round, Cranz is gonna talk about the British
Speaker 2:  monarchy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Oh my God. You're welcome.
Speaker 5:  We're so long into the show to just be getting into this now.
Speaker 6:  Well, it's okay because this is gonna be I think the shortest, what is a
Speaker 6:  photo one we've ever had? NELI will not be talking. He
Speaker 6:  will simply be sighing loudly the get tired.
Speaker 2:  I hate the story so much.
Speaker 6:  It's so good. Yeah. So, so Kate Middleton
Speaker 6:  has been out of public view. Who she, she's she's just some, she's a lady
Speaker 6:  who gets a lot of money to live in England and look pretty very good
Speaker 6:  and, and she has been out of the public view and there's been a
Speaker 6:  lot of theories about it. And then a relatively recently
Speaker 6:  a Spanish journalist who at one point said
Speaker 6:  out of pocket things about Michael Jackson and how he was probably murdered.
Speaker 6:  Wow.
Speaker 5:  Where are we going with this? Yeah. Oh boy.
Speaker 6:  She said Kate Middleton is in a coma. And, and then, and then
Speaker 6:  the, the the, the royals came back and said she's not, and that's very
Speaker 6:  unusual 'cause they usually don't re respond to like absolutely insane stupid
Speaker 6:  stuff. And so everybody's like, where is she then? So they released
Speaker 6:  this photo and apparently Kate herself has claimed that she
Speaker 6:  did the Photoshop job, but someone did it and they did a piss
Speaker 6:  poor job.
Speaker 5:  Wait, can I ask when the first time either of you saw this photo and
Speaker 5:  NELI, I know you follow her on Instagram, so you saw it. She's in your close
Speaker 5:  friend circle. So I know You saw it very quickly.
Speaker 2:  I only pretend to not care about the British monarchy because Kate and I
Speaker 2:  have been involved for several years.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 5:  Very true. Everyone has seen this photo. I don't feel like I need to describe
Speaker 5:  it, but If, you If you haven't go, go to the internet, it will find
Speaker 2:  You. No. Continue living your life in peace. Under
Speaker 5:  No circumstances should you pull over your car and look for this image. But
Speaker 5:  did either of you clock this as like weird in any way?
Speaker 5:  Yes, a hundred percent. Did you Right away.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Like I looked at it and I was like, why does every like, they all look
Speaker 6:  like they have AI faces. Like they're all smiling the
Speaker 2:  Same weird day. Oh, interesting. You must, you went that far.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then I didn't like to get to like zoom in and everything and I
Speaker 6:  didn't realize it was a story 'cause I had to get on a flight and So I was
Speaker 6:  like, this is so stupid. And I sent it to all my friends who we talk sometimes
Speaker 6:  talk about royal stuff.
Speaker 2:  One of it's okay, it's just me. Every you are, it's okay. Other people are
Speaker 2:  allowed to care about royal.
Speaker 6:  I don't actually care that much. I have a lot of friends who do Sonos.
Speaker 2:  Like we have a lot of staffers who care about this the most. And
Speaker 6:  It's,
Speaker 5:  It's great. Ironically, none of our British staffers just a bunch
Speaker 6:  Ofs only Americans. It's only the
Speaker 2:  Ex. The farther away you live from England, the more it appears you care
Speaker 2:  about this. That's
Speaker 6:  True. True. Actually,
Speaker 2:  I wonder if it keeps that keeps going. So If, you circle around the Pacific
Speaker 2:  Ocean, you start caring about it less again. You
Speaker 5:  Get to Japan and everybody's like up in arms about Kate Middleton Could be.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, no, it was, it was clear to me like something was weird in the
Speaker 6:  photo. 'cause her head was enormous. I was like, why is her head so huge
Speaker 6:  in this picture? And and it turns out because the whole, most of
Speaker 6:  it was photoshopped. We don't know entirely how much Kate later
Speaker 6:  dropped like a, a thing being like, I just love to mess around with Photoshop.
Speaker 6:  Still no photo of her. The only photo we've seen is a picture of her husband
Speaker 6:  driving and there was a woman looking away when the photo was
Speaker 6:  taken and they said, that's Kate, that's good. And it's like, mm. It's it
Speaker 6:  so unclear where she is unclear she's alive.
Speaker 2:  Can I, can I answer the one question? Yeah. Not a photo.
Speaker 6:  Not a photo. You think so? Yeah. Yeah. 'cause a
Speaker 2:  Photoshop just straightforwardly. Not a moment in time. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It was, that was my big question is yeah, what is a photo? Is this a photo?
Speaker 6:  And it feels like No, and what's cool is
Speaker 6:  everyone else agrees, including all of like the, the, the, the press everybody
Speaker 6:  like AP Reuters, everybody said, yeah, we're not gonna carry this photo because
Speaker 6:  it's not a photo and it's been manipulated and, and so
Speaker 6:  yeah. Very definitive. Not a photo everybody clocked in. I love how
Speaker 6:  many people clocked in. I love how quickly like
Speaker 2:  And I will that the, the misinformation on the social media
Speaker 2:  platforms about what's been edited here is out of control. That's so the
Speaker 2:  number of people who think is AI is very high. The number of people who've
Speaker 2:  decided,
Speaker 2:  what's it like a magazine cover? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was a Vogue cover I think from years ago. And it's like,
Speaker 2:  You know, that's use the face, her
Speaker 6:  Face.
Speaker 2:  It's like it's nowhere close to being the same face. Yeah, no, it's,
Speaker 2:  it's just at an angle.
Speaker 5:  It is very funny. You see them side by side and it's, it's the same person
Speaker 5:  making what amounts to essentially two totally different faces. And everybody's
Speaker 5:  like, they swapped them and it's like, no, they super
Speaker 2:  Didn't. But the heart of the what is a photo debate? The the,
Speaker 2:  the heart of it is If. you take a long sequence of
Speaker 2:  photos over a period of time and synthesize one moment in time
Speaker 2:  that never happened. But con that contains all the other moments in time.
Speaker 2:  Is that a photo that's the heart of Yeah. The right, like
Speaker 2:  iPhone smart HDR or whatever they call it now, the photonic engine
Speaker 2:  takes, you know, eight frames and synthesizes one exposure
Speaker 2:  and
Speaker 6:  That's what Kate did.
Speaker 2:  But she, but the eight frames happened like over five years. you know, it's
Speaker 2:  like, like that's not the same thing.
Speaker 6:  Is that even her kids who can say
Speaker 2:  The reason you asked and I said I clocked it right away, is I have but one
Speaker 2:  child in getting her to look at the camera and smile is
Speaker 2:  very difficult. And I was like all three of them. No way. Like, just like
Speaker 2:  immediately I was like, this is in JC Penney shit. Like, no way. And
Speaker 6:  It's the same smile on all of them. They all look like they have that that's
Speaker 6:  the Yeah. The filter in TikTok or whatever that makes you smile. That's what
Speaker 6:  they, they all look like they do. It's horrible. I'm sorry I
Speaker 6:  had to write about it. I know a lot. We had a lot of
Speaker 2:  Commenters. I I don't think we should apologize for writing about it. Okay.
Speaker 6:  You yeah, because I was gonna say we had a lot of commenters say who gives
Speaker 6:  a
Speaker 2:  Shit? All those commenters clicked and commented on the story. This is the
Speaker 2:  top story on our site by a mile. People really care about this. I do not,
Speaker 2:  I wanna be very clear about this. I'm an Indian American. My people
Speaker 2:  have escaped the British Royal family twice. We literally kicked these people
Speaker 2:  out of, out of the countries that I'm from, twice, two different countries
Speaker 2:  we brought came together. Here I am.
Speaker 2:  Don't need you and your queen on my money. Get outta here. Like I not
Speaker 2:  for you. It's a king now. Sure. I didn't even remember that, but I
Speaker 2:  understand why it's important. Yeah. I understand why so many members of
Speaker 2:  our staff thinks it's important. I understand why people are reading the
Speaker 2:  shit out of it. 'cause
Speaker 6:  It's hysterical.
Speaker 2:  It just, I am from Westworld and I'm looking literally getting inside and
Speaker 2:  be like, doesn't look like anything to me. She's like moving on. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, I do think If, you want to like, there's a really interesting story
Speaker 5:  about like the media and information sharing
Speaker 5:  and how we understand what's true and like all of that is fine and good.
Speaker 5:  And like Liz Lipato I think is in the middle of writing what I assume will
Speaker 5:  be 35,000 words about the Daily Mail. That will be very good and I'm very
Speaker 5:  excited to read it. But like I'm with you. It's, it's absolutely
Speaker 5:  not an AI story and it is pretty much not at all a
Speaker 5:  what is a photo story because it's a just a hacky Photoshop job that
Speaker 2:  Somebody did. CNN did a heroic job of trying to make it a what is a p story
Speaker 5:  They did.
Speaker 2:  They're like this. And I admire the, this raises the question of what even
Speaker 2:  is a photo. And I was like, you guys,
Speaker 5:  And also thank you to everyone who got that push notification and immediately
Speaker 5:  sent it to us. This is how we know you're our people.
Speaker 2:  Anyhow. Well, I hope Kate's okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Who, who, who can say they may be weakened up burning?
Speaker 2:  She hasn't texted me back.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. What's up with that? Kate? Get to it. Come on. Eli's
Speaker 2:  Waiting. It's a love affair.
Speaker 2:  What can I say? This is why I have to pretend to discard,
Speaker 2:  to disregard the world. I this
Speaker 6:  Is one of the rumors is that, that he was cheating on her So I
Speaker 2:  Think the should be a
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like Kate and I, she got back at him with you. That's,
Speaker 2:  Wow. I can't even imagine how dismissive my wife will be of this idea.
Speaker 2:  My actual divorce lawyer wife would be like, nah, that's not true. No,
Speaker 6:  Shut it down.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's not the person I married. Okay. Secondhand line round.
Speaker 2:  I'll just go as promised while we have been recording Starship
Speaker 2:  II launched, went up to orbit. Okay. Opened some doors to
Speaker 2:  prove it could open some doors and then it was supposed to splash down.
Speaker 2:  Did, did not.
Speaker 5:  Well presumably it did. Just not in the way that everyone was
Speaker 5:  hoping for.
Speaker 2:  Well, no, the quote from SpaceX spokesperson that
Speaker 2:  we have in our story, we haven't heard from the ship up until
Speaker 2:  this point. And so the team has made the call that the ship has been lost.
Speaker 2:  So no splash down today. Oh,
Speaker 5:  You're right. I took that to mean like it's gonna come down. We just don't
Speaker 5:  know where. But actually what that means is it's still up there somewhere
Speaker 2:  Or it burned up in the atmosphere or Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Or it came down and they lost track of it
Speaker 2:  Or it exploded in some other way. Yeah. So any number of exciting opportunities
Speaker 2:  for Starship fans. So
Speaker 6:  As, as successes go,
Speaker 2:  Well, so much, much more successful
Speaker 2:  than before. Yeah. When it fully exploded. That's, that's, and then when
Speaker 2:  the booster exploded, that's fair. This one went all the way up. It did some
Speaker 2:  planned maneuvers, love and maneuver.
Speaker 6:  That's it.
Speaker 2:  And then quote remained in one piece until contact was lost.
Speaker 5:  I mean I think it's generally true in these cases that getting it down is
Speaker 5:  the part the Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's the part that they worked on the hardest for
Speaker 6:  The longest. That is the massive engineering problem with it. Yeah. We, we've
Speaker 6:  gotten really
Speaker 5:  Good at putting a test like this, like worry about that once you can get
Speaker 5:  the thing where it's going right. Like let's get it there and then we'll
Speaker 5:  worry about getting it back. And it seems like the getting it there, we're
Speaker 5:  getting there. Like that's cool. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's cool. And probably the guy who runs that company,
Speaker 2:  different guy should run that company. Maybe a thing
Speaker 5:  That I could, well it should be Don Lemon say
Speaker 6:  Why does he care if it comes back? He wants to go up and and stay up. So
Speaker 2:  Go to Mars Elon. Yeah, I think everyone would be happier. It'll be fine.
Speaker 6:  All right.
Speaker 5:  Okay. My around. I'm just gonna run away from that as fast I
Speaker 5:  can. Yeah, I just, I just wanna take you on like a brief emotional rollercoaster
Speaker 5:  that I went on earlier this week, which is when I read a headline
Speaker 5:  from Tom Warren, lovely reporter at The Verge who said Apple
Speaker 5:  to allow iOS app downloads direct from websites in the EU.
Speaker 5:  David wakes up to this news. Hell yeah. Sounds awesome.
Speaker 5:  Super exciting. Apple's gonna like let you properly side load
Speaker 5:  and then you scroll down away and Apple has done what it always does, which
Speaker 5:  is say a thing and then set up like a hilarious set of hoops you
Speaker 5:  have to jump through in order for this to be real, the hoops
Speaker 6:  You have to,
Speaker 5:  So in Apple's developer program, you have to be in good standing. You have
Speaker 5:  to have more than a million annual installs in the EU, which is actually
Speaker 5:  a huge number. You have to only offer apps from your
Speaker 5:  developer account. You have to be responsive to communications from Apple.
Speaker 5:  You have to publish your data. Like you basically have to do all
Speaker 5:  the things you have to do to be in the app store only harder. And then
Speaker 5:  you can have it from website.
Speaker 6:  Your website. Yeah. You have to like go on a dinner date with Tim Cook at
Speaker 6:  one point. Like, that was a really weird one. I didn't understand that one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You have to go to the house of everyone who wants to download your
Speaker 5:  app and do it for them. Yeah. So yeah, again, like this
Speaker 5:  is, this is just what Apple is doing here, right? Like they are,
Speaker 5:  they are allowing things, but making it so onerous that
Speaker 5:  I don't think anything real is actually gonna change for people, but just
Speaker 5:  the fact that this is a thing that technically exists, I still think is very
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The concept is cool. The execution is hot garbage.
Speaker 6:  Yes. I'm just like, how's this gonna work? The EU is absolutely like,
Speaker 6:  come on man.
Speaker 2:  They won't stop. They
Speaker 6:  Won't stop. They
Speaker 2:  Relentlessly European. Yeah. They will come to your house and then take a
Speaker 2:  nap or on 4:00 PM and they're gonna wake up and they're gonna regulate the
Speaker 2:  shit outta you. They
Speaker 6:  Will work six hours and they will get a lot done in that six hours.
Speaker 2:  They will. They are, I don't, I don't mean to denigrate our European
Speaker 6:  Friends. They're wonderful. No, because they are getting stuff done. And
Speaker 6:  I think, I think Europe is doing a much better job at legislating technology
Speaker 6:  than the United States. And
Speaker 2:  It's because they eat well and sleep right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There
Speaker 2:  We go. The walk a
Speaker 6:  Lot. Yeah, we figured it out. We solved it.
Speaker 2:  You do some walkable cities and then suddenly you're able to do tech regulation.
Speaker 2:  I think all this stuff, we've talked about this at length, is all gonna backfire
Speaker 2:  on Apple. Like this is political nightmare territory for Apple. These like
Speaker 2:  technical compliance measures that don't actually add up to anything real.
Speaker 2:  They're, they're just getting in trouble. All right. Cranz, do you wanna
Speaker 2:  do one more?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I got, I got one more. And that is our,
Speaker 6:  our European friends will already know about this. The Dyson 360
Speaker 6:  Vis Nav. What is that you ask With a name? With the
Speaker 6:  Dyson 360 Vis Nav. That is a, a robot
Speaker 6:  vacuum cleaner that uses visual navigation.
Speaker 5:  Wait, do you know what I just realized? Alex? What's that? Do you remember
Speaker 5:  when Dyson was building an Electric car? They
Speaker 5:  for sure had a thing called Vis Nav and we're like, oh crap, we gotta use
Speaker 5:  this name for something. We like bought the domain name. That's where this
Speaker 5:  came from. How
Speaker 6:  Was the car gonna go? Was he gonna like have a big fan on the bag?
Speaker 2:  I'm telling you, anytime Dyson tries to make something that isn't a fan-based
Speaker 2:  product couldn't work that either sucks or blows to
Speaker 2:  get to get nowhere.
Speaker 6:  This thing does apparently suck like that, that that's its
Speaker 6:  whole thing is it's supposed to be really good at it and it has the
Speaker 6:  most enormous fluffy brush. Like, like she said, it's got a really fluffy
Speaker 6:  brush. And I was like, that's a weird thing for you to say and I don't understand.
Speaker 6:  And then she like sent me a picture and I was like, no, it's awesome. Like
Speaker 6:  I wanna just reach through the photo and touch it. It just looks very
Speaker 6:  squeezable. But she's gonna be, she just got it in it's, it's finally
Speaker 6:  available in the United States or is about to be available in the United States.
Speaker 6:  She just got it in. She's gonna be spending a lot of time messing around
Speaker 6:  with it.
Speaker 5:  How stupidly expensive is it? It's so
Speaker 6:  Expensive.
Speaker 2:  It's over a thousand dollars. Ugh.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like, come on.
Speaker 2:  Can I just say the way it, David
Speaker 6:  Asked me that question. I mean
Speaker 5:  It's Dyson, So, I, assume whatever number. I think I should just double it.
Speaker 5:  And that's what Dyson costs.
Speaker 6:  This is not gonna fit under If. you have one of those cool platform beds
Speaker 6:  with like real low clearance to the ground. This
Speaker 6:  will not clean under it. It is, it is quite tall.
Speaker 2:  $1,200. Sorry.
Speaker 6:  Purple. Okay, cool.
Speaker 2:  It does look like one of those things in the Matrix that puts you back in
Speaker 2:  the power plant. Yeah. But like in a friendly way,
Speaker 6:  That's what it's doing to the dirt. That's how the dirt feels when it, when
Speaker 6:  it comes at it,
Speaker 2:  It's like, you know that scene, it's like I'll get my body back to the power
Speaker 2:  plant, but I don don't wanna know nothing. It's this thing comes to your
Speaker 2:  house and it's like, we'll get you back in there. But you have to trade
Speaker 2:  a neo. I have weird feelings about this vacuuming cleaner,
Speaker 6:  But it's so fluffy looking like Did you look at the
Speaker 2:  Look? It does look very fluffy. I
Speaker 6:  I don't know why I like both. Both Jen and I were both like, oh my
Speaker 6:  God, this brush, like we lost our minds over the brush, which
Speaker 6:  was very weird and fun for us. I'm excited to see what she does with it.
Speaker 6:  Does
Speaker 2:  Does it vacuum her house?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But she's got a lot of robax in there right now and I really want her
Speaker 6:  to put knives on all of them and have 'em fight and she told me no. So
Speaker 6:  I'll update you guys on that. We
Speaker 2:  Can, let's work on that together. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  We can work on that. I think we can do it.
Speaker 2:  All right. Dad, what's what? Do you have another one or is it just me again?
Speaker 5:  Mine's just really quick, which is that Microsoft Teams is now
Speaker 5:  attempting to become like an app that families use to talk to each other.
Speaker 5:  And Microsoft has been talking about this for a while as like a thing they
Speaker 5:  wanna do, but they're now like unifying the apps so you can have personal
Speaker 5:  and work accounts together. And I just feel very vindicated by the fact that
Speaker 5:  I've been saying Teams was the stupidest possible name for this product this
Speaker 5:  whole time. And I was right and I feel good about it.
Speaker 5:  Can you imagine like going home tonight and being like, okay, I'm gonna set
Speaker 5:  up the family teams and then we're, that's how we're gonna like, no, I'm
Speaker 5:  out. Pass abort teams. Get outta here.
Speaker 2:  I I'm proud of you for having feelings about Microsoft teams. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Most people I know who use teams including me, whenever I use it, I try to
Speaker 2:  use it on my computer. Something bad happens, I join the team meeting, the
Speaker 2:  audio's all messed up and I always say this thing, I have a very complex
Speaker 2:  relationship with Microsoft teams and then everyone in the room starts laughing.
Speaker 6:  It's a good joke
Speaker 2:  Because it's just,
Speaker 6:  It's just, it's good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Everyone knows what I'm talking about. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Whatever. It's, it's that, and Zoom has to update every single time. Use
Speaker 5:  it. That's the, those are the two facts of life
Speaker 2:  Now. It's very good. And then Google meet on my 2015 iMac.
Speaker 2:  Just talk about a Dyson fan
Speaker 2:  who that thing could power a car. you know what I'm saying? It's suck, right?
Speaker 2:  Gotta get a new Mac. Still working on it. Okay. Mine, my last one and
Speaker 2:  then we gotta wrap this up. Many people wrote in to ask about this.
Speaker 2:  Nikon is acquiring red. So red, the big famous
Speaker 2:  camera manufacturer, the,
Speaker 6:  I think you mean phone maker. Thank the
Speaker 2:  Phone maker. The the red hydrogen one. Famously one of the worst products
Speaker 2:  we've ever reviewed. Incredible. A review so bad they canceled the product.
Speaker 2:  It's only happened a few times in our history.
Speaker 6:  I was just, ugh. I loved that thing. I mean, I loved like
Speaker 6:  it's existence. I didn't love it.
Speaker 2:  What if we took the design language of a rugged hard drive and made you hold
Speaker 2:  it all the time?
Speaker 2:  Look at it ridiculous. It was very bad. Bad 3D screen as well.
Speaker 2:  That is not why they're selling to Nikon. Yeah. They weren't like, we're
Speaker 2:  so embarrassed. We gotta get out of this. There's been some patent battles
Speaker 2:  in the past between these two. If you're Nikon you
Speaker 2:  know that so much of the action to imaging is happening in video.
Speaker 2:  That it's driving a huge amount of the, just the sensor
Speaker 2:  technology that is happening. Just all the, the stuff is happening on the
Speaker 2:  video side
Speaker 6:  And that's not what Nikon's known for.
Speaker 2:  It's not what? Not even a little bit. Nope, not at all.
Speaker 2:  So you, you see the Canons and the Sonys of the world, like really lean into
Speaker 2:  video. There's just an explosion of digital video making happening everywhere.
Speaker 2:  Red obviously owns a big chunk of that. I'm not entirely sure how the shape
Speaker 2:  of this patent battle led to an acquisition. I just know strategically
Speaker 2:  Nikon was kind of outta moves. Yeah. And I think Red saw
Speaker 2:  a number and they took the number. I'm very curious to see if
Speaker 2:  Nikon cameras turned more into red cameras because
Speaker 2:  I don't think the people who use red cameras will accept them turning more
Speaker 2:  into Nikon cameras. No,
Speaker 6:  I feel like both ways, like neither, neither one of those crews
Speaker 6:  wanna use that product. The other product.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And yeah. Which
Speaker 6:  Is, but that's, that, that makes it a good deal for them is because then
Speaker 6:  they get both of those those
Speaker 5:  Audiences. Yeah. Maybe that's okay. Like May Red, that's fine. Is a good
Speaker 5:  brand with great products. Like maybe, maybe the best place to Land is just
Speaker 5:  like, oh, you need Nikon to have a video strategy. Like, here it is. It's
Speaker 5:  called Red
Speaker 6:  And it's got good glass. So it's like,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Nikon. Yeah. I mean, I'm a Nikon person. Famously, our video team is
Speaker 2:  deeply confused by this at all times. Yeah. But I love my icon
Speaker 2:  D 7,500 still going strong.
Speaker 2:  We'll just see. It is also, by the way, it is a good time in still cameras.
Speaker 2:  We haven't really talked about this, but Becca's been doing a lot of coverage
Speaker 2:  of like, very exciting still cameras from Fuji and Laika that are coming
Speaker 2:  out. That
Speaker 6:  Fuji film I like. I think about it a lot. Yeah. I'm like, I don't need that
Speaker 6:  camera, but what if, what if I got into photography again?
Speaker 6:  That's, that's what it like. That's a midlife crisis camera right there.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, yeah. Oh,
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Yeah. What if Max doesn't go to college?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, college is overrated.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What? What you want? Get a cool camera? Beautiful street photography.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Sorry kid. I took a picture of a dumpster.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that is, is it? That's The. Vergecast. We're gonna send her to college
Speaker 2:  one way or the other. We'll just see how many dumpster photos pay for it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If she wants to go, which she's gonna want to because I'm her
Speaker 2:  father. Okay. That's it. That's s Vergecast. We've gone way over. Thank you
Speaker 2:  for listening. Many things to give us feedback on this time. David,
Speaker 2:  tell us how they can get in contact with us.
Speaker 5:  You can email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. That goes to all of us.
Speaker 5:  Or you can call the hotline. Eight six. Six version one one. We got a
Speaker 5:  tweet from somebody the other day who thought it was very funny that we used
Speaker 5:  to tell everybody about Twitter. And then we told people about threads for
Speaker 5:  a minute, and now we want them to call our landline, which is objectively
Speaker 5:  very funny. We're all also on threads. You can find us there. And
Speaker 5:  also just like The Verge dot com, we make a website. It's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, come to it directly. Escape the algorithms. That should be our new
Speaker 2:  tagline. Escape from the algorithms. That's pretty good. The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  All right. That's it. Alright, roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 3:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The. Vergecast is a
Speaker 3:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network.