# Transcript
ID: 863582bf-0031-4714-9e2f-67aead7ebb25
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2054398409039753068/5726749866743361951/s93290-US-4225s-1724750126.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the native resonance of your smartphone:
02:32 -The Verge’s David Pierce tries to find out if those YouTube videos promising to remove water from your phone with sounds actually work.
32:42 - Then, David chats with The Verge’s Alex Heath about some AR glasses that are reportedly set to launch from Snap and Meta this fall.
59:16 - Later, David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about competition in the AI industry.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (47 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Native
Speaker 2:  Resonance of Your Smartphone. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am in our
Speaker 2:  studio. I mentioned on the show last week that we just got this new studio.
Speaker 2:  If you've been watching on YouTube, you've seen it. I'm very jealous. So
Speaker 2:  I got on the Amtrak, came all the way up and now I'm sitting in this like
Speaker 2:  chair in the corner that exists for reasons
Speaker 2:  as yet to be figured out. Anyway, I'm here because we have
Speaker 2:  podcasting to do today on the show we have a couple of really fun things
Speaker 2:  to talk about. We're gonna talk to Alex Heath about this like glut of
Speaker 2:  headsets that is coming up. We're gonna get stuff from Meta, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  get stuff from Snap. There's been some news about the stuff that we're getting
Speaker 2:  from Meta that's pretty interesting. But in general, the VR
Speaker 2:  ar headset craze continues and seems to be unstoppable
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna talk about it. We also have a story that I've been reporting
Speaker 2:  kind of for months now, all based on a YouTube video that
Speaker 2:  claims to get the water out of your phone. I have lots of questions and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna get answers. All of that is coming up in just a second, along
Speaker 2:  with an answer to your questions from The Vergecast hotline. But first,
Speaker 2:  there are lots of microphones in here and I have to go scream into the mall
Speaker 2:  and see what trouble I can get into. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  only a few hundred residents. I have no idea why we went there,
Speaker 2:  honestly. I think my mom just found a cool house on Airbnb for pretty
Speaker 2:  cheap and was like sick house on the river for the weekend. Out behind
Speaker 2:  that Airbnb, there was this little dock that stuck out into the water
Speaker 2:  and the day after we got there, my nephew went out onto the dock to fish.
Speaker 5:  I was sitting on this little bench they had at the, at the very end of the
Speaker 5:  dock and I got lazy So I put my feet up 'cause I was like, okay, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  relax. And then all of a sudden my phone, I feel this slip right out my pocket
Speaker 5:  and it falls and right into the water.
Speaker 2:  That's Chris, that's my nephew. And his phone is a Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 2:  S 24. Basically still brand new. So Chris
Speaker 2:  drops his phone.
Speaker 5:  I saw a fall like as soon as it went past the dock. I saw it and
Speaker 5:  then goes and it starts sinking down,
Speaker 5:  just down, down, down and down.
Speaker 2:  Did you think about jumping in
Speaker 5:  Immediately? But then I was like, that's a bad idea. I'm gonna go run back
Speaker 5:  and tell him what happened and I hopefully can help me out.
Speaker 2:  Chris comes running inside the house where I'm hanging out with a bunch of
Speaker 2:  our other family members and tells us what happens. We all immediately jump
Speaker 2:  up, go outside, grab all the nets and stuff we can find
Speaker 2:  and start scraping through the muck at the bottom of the river trying to
Speaker 2:  find his phone and miracle of miracles. We actually found it.
Speaker 2:  Caden, my other nephew, grabbed it in a big net and just pulled it up and
Speaker 2:  there it was. It was kind of amazing. At the end of it all the phone had
Speaker 2:  probably been underwater for 10, maybe 15 minutes
Speaker 2:  and when it came up in that net, the screen was actually on. So it seemed
Speaker 2:  like we might have avoided the worst, but still everyone was worried,
Speaker 2:  right? Wet phones are bad no matter what the screen is currently doing. And
Speaker 2:  the S 24 did have that warning notification that said water had
Speaker 2:  gotten inside.
Speaker 5:  We brought it inside. I believe we tried Dr. No, we didn't even try to dry
Speaker 5:  it out 'cause someone brought up an idea that he had and we tried it out
Speaker 5:  to where literally what he did because it was 'cause it was so little, little
Speaker 5:  water, it was still working properly. He opened up a YouTube video and started
Speaker 5:  playing this weird sound that like, like changed like the, I made the speakers
Speaker 5:  like do a whole bunch of weird sounds and like ended up I think pushing out
Speaker 5:  some of the water or at least losing it up.
Speaker 2:  This is where our story really begins. The somebody in question here
Speaker 2:  is Gabe, a friend who had come with us for the weekend. So we're all standing
Speaker 2:  in the kitchen trying to figure out what to do for Chris's phone and Gabe
Speaker 2:  is just like, oh, there's this YouTube video that gets all the water out
Speaker 2:  of your speakers. I have been thinking about that YouTube video ever since.
Speaker 2:  And actually it's not just one video but a whole genre of them and
Speaker 2:  they are shockingly popular. There's sound to remove water from
Speaker 2:  phone speaker, parentheses, all caps guaranteed which has 45 million
Speaker 2:  views, 45 million views. Water out of speaker
Speaker 2:  sound, iPhone parentheses a hundred percent fix, 3.9 million
Speaker 2:  views, 165 hertz test tone, pure sign, wave five
Speaker 2:  min remove water from phone. Best version 27 million views
Speaker 2:  on and on and on. Hundreds of millions of views on these videos
Speaker 2:  from all over the place. And the comments honestly are the best.
Speaker 2:  Part. One just says, I think this is the most important video on YouTube.
Speaker 2:  No matter how many years go through this vid will just keep getting more
Speaker 2:  views. And another one says, damn, we really the elite gang bringing our
Speaker 2:  phones in the showers another one at this point, this video is gonna show
Speaker 2:  up in my Spotify wrapped. That one actually made me laugh really hard. I'm
Speaker 2:  still going to bring my phone in the shower again. So see you guys tomorrow.
Speaker 2:  That's another one. But here's my favorite one and you actually see a lot
Speaker 2:  of these on these videos. Everyone saying how they dropped theirs in a
Speaker 2:  shower or a pool of water. I dropped mine in cereal edit two months later
Speaker 2:  and I'm back here again 'cause I did the same thing again. Edit two, can't
Speaker 2:  believe it's been a year since I've gotten some sort of liquid in my phone.
Speaker 2:  Well, time to reset the counter 'cause my phone magically landed into my
Speaker 2:  pool.
Speaker 2:  The point is, there are millions of people out here apparently just
Speaker 2:  cavalierly taking their phones into the shower, the pool, the
Speaker 2:  rain, whatever and trusting that a YouTube video will
Speaker 2:  fix it. Before we get too far, I just wanna play you a clip from one of
Speaker 2:  these videos. I'm only gonna play you a few seconds of it because it's not,
Speaker 2:  you know, pleasant audio. But just wanna give you the idea of what this
Speaker 2:  is doing. So without further ado, here are the lush sounds
Speaker 2:  of sound to remove water from phone charging. Port parentheses one hour
Speaker 2:  version.
Speaker 6:  Woo.
Speaker 2:  Like I said, it's not nice to listen to but it's not really supposed to be.
Speaker 2:  It's supposed to do a job and ever since that day trying to fix Chris's
Speaker 2:  phone, I've been wondering if it really works because on the one hand
Speaker 2:  lots of people are using these videos and clearly their phones keep working
Speaker 2:  so great. But on the other hand, maybe that's just because our phones
Speaker 2:  have gotten impressively waterproof and generally durable over the years.
Speaker 2:  So the big question is did we get the water out of Chris's phone or
Speaker 2:  did Samsung keep the water from ever getting in? I became obsessed with this
Speaker 2:  question I had to know. So the first thing I did was reach out to a bunch
Speaker 2:  of phone makers to see what they thought. I didn't get much from Google or
Speaker 2:  Samsung or Apple except for vague responses. Kind of along the lines of
Speaker 2:  seems like it might theoretically work. A few companies did point me to their
Speaker 2:  official support pages for liquid damage and what to do if your phone gets
Speaker 2:  wet. Apple's for instance says to tap it gently against your hand with the
Speaker 2:  lightning or USB port facing down and then leave it in a dry area.
Speaker 2:  That's roughly the advice you'll get from most of these companies. That doesn't
Speaker 2:  answer my question at all. The most compelling piece of evidence I had for
Speaker 2:  my specific question from the very beginning was actually the Apple Watch.
Speaker 2:  It has this feature for swimmers where You can turn the digital crown
Speaker 2:  to eject water out through the speakers. Some other smart watches like the
Speaker 2:  Samsung Galaxy Watch do something similar. This seems like in theory
Speaker 2:  the same sort of idea, but Apple presumably has access to all of the
Speaker 2:  tech inside the watch to do that stuff. So is it the same thing when
Speaker 2:  you just play a video on YouTube? Actually, to be honest, the more
Speaker 2:  I got into this and the more I researched and tried to figure out how all
Speaker 2:  of this works, the more I realized I don't even understand the basics
Speaker 2:  of what's happening here. So I called up this guy,
Speaker 7:  I'm Eric Freeman and I'm a senior director of research at Bose.
Speaker 2:  In addition to his day job, Eric literally teaches a class to Bose employees
Speaker 2:  about how speakers work and So I tried to get him to tell me how speakers
Speaker 2:  work, but I'm an idiot. So I made him start at the most basic place
Speaker 2:  possible. Like what is a speaker? I know what it's for, I
Speaker 2:  know what it does, but if you actually opened up a speaker, what would you
Speaker 2:  see inside?
Speaker 7:  So I'm gonna start from the back of kind of a conventional speaker,
Speaker 7:  which is the most common thing that you'll find. It's in, you know, the speakers
Speaker 7:  that are in your Bluetooth speakers or
Speaker 7:  your phone or even like pro audio equipment. It's all the same
Speaker 7:  technology for the most part it's just tiny versus
Speaker 7:  huge versus medium size. So if we start from the back,
Speaker 7:  we've got a magnet and the magnet has some steel parts around it and the
Speaker 7:  purpose of the steel parts is just to take the magnetic field
Speaker 7:  lines and put them in a very specific location. In
Speaker 7:  that specific location there's a coil of wire. So you have a coil of
Speaker 7:  wire sitting inside of some magnetic field lines
Speaker 7:  and it turns out that when you run electrical current through a wire, it
Speaker 7:  behaves like a magnetic, it creates a magnetic field. So just like
Speaker 7:  when you play with two magnets, you know You can stick them together or
Speaker 7:  have them repel each other. You can run current through a wire
Speaker 7:  and have it attract to the permanent magnet or push away from
Speaker 7:  the permanent magnet.
Speaker 2:  The long and short of it is this, you're using that magnetic field he's talking
Speaker 2:  about to essentially push and pull a little piston shaped thing really,
Speaker 2:  really, really fast. About 20 times per second all the way to about
Speaker 2:  20,000 times per second. The long and short of it is this, you're using
Speaker 2:  that magnetic field he's talking about to essentially push and pull a little
Speaker 2:  piston shaped thing really, really fast, somewhere between 20 and
Speaker 2:  20,000 times a second and every time you do it's moving air.
Speaker 7:  So 20 is the low frequency. So the base, so like you know, 20
Speaker 7:  up to, I don't know 150 or so is generally considered the base range.
Speaker 7:  And then as the frequency of vibration gets higher, you get into
Speaker 7:  higher tones. So above that is kind of like the vocal
Speaker 7:  range and where a lot of instruments sit, it's called the midrange. Like
Speaker 7:  a lot of people are probably familiar with the, there's a base control, a
Speaker 7:  midrange control and a treble control, right? And as you go higher and
Speaker 7:  higher and get into the thousands and tens of thousands of vibrations per
Speaker 7:  second, that's the treble
Speaker 2:  To change the tone of a sound. You change how fast that little
Speaker 2:  piston is moving back and forth and to change the volume, you change how
Speaker 2:  much that little piston moves. Thus the bigger the speaker, the more
Speaker 2:  space the piston has to move so the more air it pushes around. So the bigger
Speaker 2:  and louder it can be. Hypothetically Eric told me that if you want to get
Speaker 2:  your speaker to move as much air as aggressively as possible,
Speaker 2:  you'd want to generate really low tones at really high volumes.
Speaker 7:  The lowest tone that that speaker can reproduce at the
Speaker 7:  loudest level that it can play, that will create the most air motion
Speaker 7:  which will push on the water that's in trapped inside the phone.
Speaker 2:  So just super bassy music is just gonna move more air inside of
Speaker 2:  your device than anything else you would think of.
Speaker 7:  Yes, that's right. So those YouTube videos, if you listen to them,
Speaker 7:  it's not like really deep bass because your phone can't go super deep in
Speaker 7:  the bass, but it, it plays kind of in, in the low range of where a phone
Speaker 7:  is able to make sound. So it, it uses the range where the,
Speaker 7:  the phone can move its speaker the most.
Speaker 2:  So if you have something in your phone, you don't want to be in there, you
Speaker 2:  play the lowest tones possible as loud as possible, lots of air moves really
Speaker 2:  intensely and boom, you're done. The science kind of tracks.
Speaker 2:  When I asked Eric what he thought about my YouTube video question, he only
Speaker 2:  really had one addendum to my theory.
Speaker 7:  I think the one caveat is you would wanna hold your phone so that
Speaker 7:  gravity is your friend, right? You would want the speaker to be facing down
Speaker 7:  so the water that's trapped near the speaker would
Speaker 7:  go as low as possible and probably like puddle against that little
Speaker 7:  screen. And then you play that YouTube track with all that base in this and
Speaker 7:  the cone starts pumping. I imagine what happens is, you know, with the
Speaker 7:  pressure behind the water, it's pushed through the screen and it kind of
Speaker 7:  spits out through the, through the screen, right? And, if you do that long
Speaker 7:  enough, the water's gonna jump around and jiggle around and eventually most
Speaker 7:  of it's gonna get pushed through the screen and there's probably a little
Speaker 7:  residual amount that just needs to evaporate over time.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I'm almost certain an incredibly stupid question,
Speaker 2:  but would the better idea to be, to put your phone
Speaker 2:  right in front of or like inside of some much larger,
Speaker 2:  much more powerful speaker? 'cause if, if the goal is to push as much
Speaker 2:  air as forcefully as possible, should I do that Or, or at this point am I
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm putting like an aluminum back in the way and it, I'm just gonna
Speaker 2:  screw up the whole thing.
Speaker 7:  That's a really interesting idea and I think if you, if you were to stick
Speaker 7:  your phone into a, a sealed cavity that a big wooer
Speaker 7:  was pumping on, right and you develop all this pressure that's gonna push
Speaker 7:  air in and out of that screen for sure, right?
Speaker 7:  So I think you could get a setup like that to pump the water
Speaker 7:  out. The only danger is that really high pressure could damage the
Speaker 7:  little speaker inside of your phone. So it's much safer to use your
Speaker 7:  own speaker up to the limit of its capability.
Speaker 2:  So at this point I'm convinced that at least theoretically You can use a
Speaker 2:  YouTube video to get water out of your phone. But I'm still stuck on this
Speaker 2:  idea of whether these videos are a placebo or not. All these people
Speaker 2:  using their phones in the shower or at the pool or whatever, are they actually
Speaker 2:  fixing their phones this way or are they and my nephew Chris, just
Speaker 2:  really lucky that phones have gotten impressively waterproof over time.
Speaker 2:  The only way to figure this out is just to do some testing and luckily I
Speaker 2:  found some folks willing to help. I had first reached out to the team at
Speaker 2:  iFixit when I hit up the phone manufacturers basically just to ask, does
Speaker 2:  this theoretically make sense to you? I got an email back with a quote from
Speaker 2:  I fix it, repairability engineer Karsten Heim. He also made
Speaker 2:  the connection to the Apple Watch and said quote, it's just a specific oscillating
Speaker 2:  tone that pushes the water out of the speaker grills. Not sure how effective
Speaker 2:  the third party versions are for phones since they're probably not ideally
Speaker 2:  tuned. We could test that is music to my ears my friend.
Speaker 2:  So not long after that I got on the phone with Sharam Tari, the lead
Speaker 2:  tear down technician at I Fixit and he walked me through a theory he'd been
Speaker 2:  developing ever since I sent that first email. Turns out he'd gone down kind
Speaker 2:  of the same rabbit hole I had
Speaker 8:  At top of my notes here and I am absolutely shocked would never have occurred
Speaker 8:  to me. People are using their phones in the shower.
Speaker 2:  Sharam had been wrestling with a question that I hadn't even thought of.
Speaker 2:  If You can remove water from a phone using the speakers and if
Speaker 2:  Apple already has this feature built into the Apple watch, why
Speaker 2:  wouldn't it be built into the iPhone?
Speaker 8:  This is definitely not something we should present as fact, but the watches
Speaker 8:  are easier to waterproof and all of Apple's
Speaker 8:  terminology they say how they're water resistant and not waterproof, which
Speaker 8:  is technically accurate. It's also been designed and has far
Speaker 8:  fewer and limited cavities and holes in the watches than there are on
Speaker 8:  the phones, which allows them to design to push the water out
Speaker 8:  from those cavities. Whereas on the phone the speakers are located
Speaker 8:  at the bottom and the top of the phone, which means you can't get cavities
Speaker 8:  like the sim card slot. It's, it's just not possible to push
Speaker 8:  water out from those cavities. I think that's why they don't
Speaker 8:  include the same feature on the phones because it's just, it's not
Speaker 8:  gonna work perfectly as it should or as they would want it to.
Speaker 8:  And I, they don't want to mislead people into thinking hey your phone is
Speaker 8:  waterproof again, speculation and we'll do some testing on that to figure
Speaker 8:  it out.
Speaker 2:  Like basically everyone else I had been talking to Sharam bought the overall
Speaker 2:  theory that speakers can move water though he did say it can get
Speaker 2:  screwy if the speakers themselves are actually damaged by the water and
Speaker 2:  that was just the first of a bunch of new caveats he had.
Speaker 8:  Question of whether fresh water and salt water makes a difference
Speaker 8:  pops up in my mind, which is something I plan to investigate how long the
Speaker 8:  water's been sitting in your phone is definitely going to make a difference
Speaker 8:  because salt, water, mineral and salt deposits are going to
Speaker 8:  interfere with the function. Where is it not able to push the
Speaker 8:  water out? From which cavities are we going to have the most trouble? What
Speaker 8:  does the water damage on the inside look like and does
Speaker 8:  this give people a false sense of confidence in
Speaker 8:  the water resistance capabilities of both phones and watches?
Speaker 2:  That last bit there is one of the things I've been wondering about this whole
Speaker 2:  time. It's definitely true that phones are more durable in waterproof than
Speaker 2:  ever but it might actually be dangerous to trust that fact too much.
Speaker 2:  Your phone might survive a drop in the pool or the toilet or whatever,
Speaker 2:  but you still shouldn't drop your phone in the pool or the toilet or whatever
Speaker 2:  because lots of other things can go wrong. Phones also wear
Speaker 2:  over time and lose some of that durability and impenetrability.
Speaker 2:  So telling people your phone is waterproof so go nuts is actually
Speaker 2:  maybe not a good or helpful or even true thing.
Speaker 2:  Sharam at the end of our first conversation had a bunch of ideas for other
Speaker 2:  tests he wanted to do and he also looped in Chaan Ritter, a master's student
Speaker 2:  in electrical engineering who has been working with iFixit. He also
Speaker 2:  had lots of ideas.
Speaker 9:  I may be thinking ahead with like a te, I don't know, I just wanna throw
Speaker 9:  it out there. But a test that we could do is we could get a phone, we could
Speaker 9:  dunk it in a, have you seen a pressure tank? Like a diving Well we were just
Speaker 9:  talking about that we need to get one of those for some of the other ingress
Speaker 9:  test things we had planned. We we could do this for the, the test that you
Speaker 9:  could fill it with a UV reactive liquid like put some dye in the water,
Speaker 9:  put the phone in there, just dunk it and then take it out, maybe take it
Speaker 9:  apart after and then shine a light on it to see where you'd get water
Speaker 9:  in there. But that means you'd have to have like two phones and then brand
Speaker 9:  new phones you'd have to buy.
Speaker 2:  I Fixit has tons of phones lying around but they've all already been
Speaker 2:  opened up. That's I fix its thing. They're a company based on repairing
Speaker 2:  electronics so they get things to open them up and figure out how to repair
Speaker 2:  them and once you've pried a phone apart you've kind of compromised it.
Speaker 2:  So they just needed new phones to play with if this test was going to really
Speaker 2:  feel like the real world. Luckily I had a drawer full of phones
Speaker 2:  to play with. I get a lot of phones for various reasons and sometimes the
Speaker 2:  companies that ship them to us just don't want them back. Often we will
Speaker 2:  donate them or find another use for them but sometimes they just sit around
Speaker 2:  like forever. In this case I have a box full of
Speaker 2:  new and old phones that have just been moving around with me for years.
Speaker 2:  So I decided to donate a few devices to science and put four phones
Speaker 2:  in a box and ship them to I fixit for Sharam and Chaan to take apart.
Speaker 2:  The four phones by the way are not particularly representative of anything.
Speaker 2:  Just what I had around and available to send it was a Google Pixel seven
Speaker 2:  Pro, an iPhone 13, a Google Pixel three and a
Speaker 2:  Nokia 7.1 that I think is from 2018. So some old,
Speaker 2:  some new, some fancy, some less fancy. Just something to get us started.
Speaker 2:  A few weeks later I got an email from Sharam and Chatan saying they had some
Speaker 2:  answers for me so we got back on a call, we
Speaker 9:  Got the four phones that you sent us. I tested using a
Speaker 9:  UV bath and we made that just by buying some of these.
Speaker 9:  So we got, we got like several UV dyes. The original one we started with
Speaker 9:  didn't work out so open week. So we got these like boat, like sewage tank
Speaker 9:  things to like detect leaks if you're in the harbor and they were amazing.
Speaker 9:  It was, I I don't Do you watch Futurama at all?
Speaker 2:  A little bit, yeah.
Speaker 9:  Have you seen, do you know the the drink S slm?
Speaker 10:  I'm dying of thirst. Grab my feet and dunk my head in So. I can drink. No
Speaker 2:  That's moronic
Speaker 10:  Fine. I'll let go and swim around in the S SLM and drink as much as I want.
Speaker 9:  Oh, it ended up looking like this and I, I just thought it was hilarious
Speaker 9:  but these worked out great
Speaker 2:  In case you haven't watched Futurama s SLM and this UV bath are both of these
Speaker 2:  kind of toxic spill green looking liquids and in
Speaker 2:  ton's case the goal was to submerge a phone in the stuff. Leave it there
Speaker 2:  for about a minute and then take it out And. if you look at your phone, You
Speaker 2:  can probably guess where liquid is most likely to get in in that process.
Speaker 2:  It's around the power button, the volume keys, the port at the bottom and
Speaker 2:  the speakers up top and down below. That's where the phone is open and that's
Speaker 2:  where stuff can get in. So the idea was after a minute underwater chattan
Speaker 2:  would pick the phone out, gently tap it to get some of the water out, play
Speaker 2:  one of our water ejecting YouTube videos and then leave the phone
Speaker 2:  overnight. This is basically what you do if you just dropped your phone in
Speaker 2:  a river I think. So it felt like a pretty good test but the S SLM green
Speaker 2:  stuff would leave a trace of wherever it had lingered, which they'd then
Speaker 2:  be able to see under a UV light so you'd know where liquid had managed to
Speaker 2:  get inside the phone and stay there long enough to leave this residue.
Speaker 2:  Anything that came in and then immediately was expelled wouldn't leave much
Speaker 2:  trace I should say by the way, that liquid getting inside of your phone isn't
Speaker 2:  by definition the end of the world. There are lots of different ways of
Speaker 2:  waterproofing things and plenty of valid different approaches to keeping
Speaker 2:  the really sensitive bits of your device safe. All these companies will tell
Speaker 2:  you that the main goal is not to keep water out, it's to keep your phone
Speaker 2:  working no matter what happens. But if You can, you should probably
Speaker 2:  try to keep everything out entirely because sure your phone might be
Speaker 2:  safe from a few drops of pure fresh water getting inside, but
Speaker 2:  oftentimes that's not what happens in the real world.
Speaker 9:  I would assume if you left your phone a little longer in there or you weren't
Speaker 9:  as lucky, we wouldn't be in the same situation. Also
Speaker 8:  We're talking about taking this thing into the shower repeatedly. So one
Speaker 8:  of these days you will take it and then it will fail
Speaker 9:  Also you got, I don't know what what other stuff is in shampoo but it's probably
Speaker 9:  more conductive than just any liquid like water,
Speaker 2:  Right? That's the other part of this is like very rarely are you getting
Speaker 2:  what amounts to perfectly fresh water inside of your eye. iPhone at least
Speaker 2:  you'll,
Speaker 9:  It'll smell nice after. You know
Speaker 2:  One of Apple's official recommendations actually if you get your phone
Speaker 2:  submerged in liquid is to immediately rinse it with tap water and
Speaker 2:  it includes a picture of just shoving your phone under the kitchen faucet.
Speaker 2:  Samsung also suggests soaking your phone in tap water if something like that
Speaker 2:  happens. Which seems wild to think about doing but that's
Speaker 2:  actually the point. These modern devices do do a lot to keep liquid out
Speaker 2:  but if something gets in and it's corrosive or otherwise chemically
Speaker 2:  in some way, you're in much more trouble. Anyway, Chetan started
Speaker 2:  showing me all these pictures of the phones that he'd taken with the UV light
Speaker 2:  on. So you're just seeing basically the outline of the phone and these little
Speaker 2:  neon green splotches everywhere that there had been liquid. He started with
Speaker 2:  the iPhone 13
Speaker 9:  So this is the, the inside of the screen and You can clearly see around this
Speaker 9:  little hole there's a bunch of residue that was left behind. Now
Speaker 9:  on our speakers here, I was surprised that on the bottom speaker at least
Speaker 9:  there wasn't as much as I thought there was gonna be and I
Speaker 9:  opened these up, there's a fine mesh in there and that mesh did a really
Speaker 9:  good job of preventing anything from going into the
Speaker 9:  the speaker C itself. It's either like a really fine mesh, it felt like a
Speaker 9:  mesh when I was rubbing a a spider over it or tweezers but it could just
Speaker 9:  be textured plastic and it did an excellent job at keeping
Speaker 9:  liquid out. And that was for all of the phones,
Speaker 2:  Huh? 'cause you would think that would be the most natural place for it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, to be there. So I guess it makes sense that they would pay special
Speaker 2:  attention to it. Jayden did say he was a little surprised to
Speaker 2:  see the iPhone not keep everything out since the phone's a bit older. Maybe
Speaker 2:  the seal degraded or maybe it just wasn't a perfect seal in the first place.
Speaker 2:  But like we've been saying, the phone still worked, camera was fine, everything
Speaker 2:  was fine so maybe it's fine. Google's Pixel seven Pro was next
Speaker 2:  and kind of crushed it.
Speaker 9:  So this one was interesting because when I opened it up there was no liquid
Speaker 9:  inside it at all. It was dry like the, none of the water, like the
Speaker 9:  detection stickers were triggered.
Speaker 2:  The pixel three though not so good.
Speaker 9:  This is the front You can you obviously there's a big green mark here on
Speaker 9:  the, on the speed upper speaker and microphone and then You can see
Speaker 9:  the corners of the display too.
Speaker 2:  So that's like you're gonna see a drop of water underneath your screen basically.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I have the, the device here. It's not very visible
Speaker 9:  when I'm holding it now, but if I sort of tilted I can kind of see something
Speaker 9:  and when I turned it on it wasn't as, I mean you could, if you
Speaker 9:  really looked at you could detect it but it was sort of hard to see. But
Speaker 9:  regardless there's liquid in your display and that's not a good thing.
Speaker 2:  There was lots of residue all around the Pixel three actually in
Speaker 2:  the sim card slot and the USBC port and lots of other places you just don't
Speaker 2:  want liquid to be. It didn't seem like any of it had gotten so
Speaker 2:  deep as to totally destroy the phone except maybe that bit in the
Speaker 2:  display but it's not great either way. And the Nokia was even
Speaker 2:  worse. There was residue around the battery and the screen. There was actually
Speaker 2:  corrosion on the USB port and the liquid detection sticker inside
Speaker 2:  had triggered, which is usually bad news fair warranty. The other phones
Speaker 2:  though didn't trigger that sticker, even the ones that got a little liquid
Speaker 2:  inside. I thought that was really interesting. Again, there are plenty of
Speaker 2:  reasons for the differences here. Maybe the phone's just not that sealed
Speaker 2:  in the first place or maybe it degraded over time. Maybe it got banged up
Speaker 2:  in shipping. I don't know. Jayden and Sharam both kept saying that they wanted
Speaker 2:  to do more testing to test a phone the day it comes out and then test another
Speaker 2:  model of the same phone six months or a year or two years later to see
Speaker 2:  how things change over time. It's a really cool idea and I hope they do it,
Speaker 2:  but it requires a lot of phones and it gets really expensive really fast.
Speaker 2:  But for my purposes we're getting somewhere while he was testing the phones,
Speaker 2:  Chaan also took these super closeup slow motion videos of each
Speaker 2:  phone as he played the YouTube video and You can actually see them working
Speaker 2:  in almost every one of them. The sound starts, the phone starts buzzing and
Speaker 2:  immediately you get this burst of water coming out of the speaker grill.
Speaker 2:  It's like the tiniest little water fountain you've ever seen. The effect
Speaker 2:  slows down pretty fast, but that initial whoosh of air really
Speaker 2:  does fire some water out of the speakers.
Speaker 2:  The water comes out of both the top speaker and the bottom one, which in
Speaker 2:  Satan's tests were also the two places water was most likely to get in in
Speaker 2:  the first place. It's literally like spitting water out as it plays that
Speaker 2:  video, but as Chaan found, it doesn't get everything out.
Speaker 9:  I wonder if like once it got in there because that match does a really
Speaker 9:  good job of keeping stuff out if if a little bit did did get in it's,
Speaker 9:  you know, it's just gonna keep it in there as well too.
Speaker 2:  This is actually a pretty good summation of the situation here. So recent
Speaker 2:  phones, especially high end ones, have in fact gotten really good at keeping
Speaker 2:  liquid out. Your phone may not be completely waterproof forever in
Speaker 2:  all situations, but frankly there's a good chance You can drop it in the
Speaker 2:  river and it'll come out working okay, but if liquid does get in, it
Speaker 2:  can be tricky to get back out because it has to go back through that same
Speaker 2:  nearly impenetrable seal that it had to go through to get into your phone
Speaker 2:  in the first place. But can playing a video on YouTube help?
Speaker 2:  I think so at least a little You can shake or tap the phone to get some
Speaker 2:  liquid out and see that when it's wet and playing a video like these does
Speaker 2:  seem to generate some more powerful and forceful motion to get
Speaker 2:  the droplets moving. There's just no denying the evidence of those drops
Speaker 2:  flying out when you play the video and the phone starts vibrating. But it
Speaker 2:  seems like it's only gonna help in spots near the speaker. It's just not
Speaker 2:  moving enough air to like push everything around the phone and out
Speaker 2:  of the various holes. Those grills at the bottom and top are the easiest
Speaker 2:  place for liquid to get in and thus the easiest place to push them out. They
Speaker 2:  also happen to be right next to the speakers and what happens it seems is
Speaker 2:  that after that first bit of liquid is initially ejected out,
Speaker 2:  what's left ends up just kind of getting sloshed around as the speaker keeps
Speaker 2:  moving. So yes, a YouTube video might help a little, but
Speaker 2:  it won't solve all of your problems.
Speaker 9:  I say they kind of worry I can't hurt like, but I don't see it being an end
Speaker 9:  all be all fix or a way to pull all the liquid out.
Speaker 2:  There are lots of good tips out there for getting liquid out of your phone,
Speaker 2:  many of which boil down to the same thing. Try to get air moving with your
Speaker 2:  mouth or a fan or canned air but don't do it so aggressively that you might
Speaker 2:  break something inside of the device, put it in rice. Sure, use the silica
Speaker 2:  beads fine. There are a million strategies out there and many of them work
Speaker 2:  at least a little, but Chetan and Sharam both offered the same advice,
Speaker 2:  which is frankly pretty simple and pretty good advice. Don't take your phone
Speaker 2:  in the shower, it might survive. You might play the video after you get out
Speaker 2:  and it might be okay, but next time it might not. Every time your phone
Speaker 2:  gets wet in any way, you are tempting fate and eventually
Speaker 2:  one time you're gonna do this and the liquid damage Gods are not going to
Speaker 2:  care how quickly you manage to get the YouTube app open. But look, I'll just
Speaker 2:  level with you after going through this whole process and learning all of
Speaker 2:  this about how speakers work, I bookmarked one of these videos and just the
Speaker 2:  other day I spilled like two thirds of a can of seltzer right over top of
Speaker 2:  my phone, immediately shook it out, tapped it, played the video,
Speaker 2:  and my phone still works. I don't think my phone still works because I played
Speaker 2:  that video, but it certainly didn't hurt and it might have helped at least
Speaker 2:  a little bit. It's all about getting air moving, you know what I mean? I'm
Speaker 2:  sure I'll be back in those comments before too long. Next time I spill some
Speaker 2:  seltzer.
Speaker 2:  to be Labor Day and then it happens to be gadget season. That's how it usually
Speaker 2:  works. But right now we are in the middle of gadget season.
Speaker 2:  Samsung did its thing early, Google did its thing early, we're
Speaker 2:  barreling towards an Apple event. AI stuff is everywhere. It
Speaker 2:  is firmly gadget season and I think what we're actually
Speaker 2:  about to start is headset season. There's been some reporting that
Speaker 2:  Meta and Snap and others are about to launch
Speaker 2:  headsets and we're getting to a place where we've been doing this
Speaker 2:  VR and AR thing long enough that I think we can start
Speaker 2:  to ask questions about what we're doing here about how far off this tech
Speaker 2:  really is and about what these companies can do now that
Speaker 2:  works. The verges Alex Heath has been reporting on all of this
Speaker 2:  both on the site and in his excellent newsletter command line, which you
Speaker 2:  should absolutely subscribe to So I figured we'd bring him on and just try
Speaker 2:  to talk through all of it. Alex, hello. Hi So. I. Wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  Snap and I wanna talk about Meta and I think we should talk about Snap because
Speaker 2:  I think we're only gonna talk a little bit about Snap and then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk a lot about Meta. But basically you reported both of these companies
Speaker 2:  are going to launch big new headsets kind of within
Speaker 2:  what we think like a couple of weeks of each other in September a week. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Within a week of each other. So it's gonna be, it's gonna be a thing. I wanna
Speaker 2:  start with Snap because for years my like
Speaker 2:  Sneakiest hot take about the tech industry was that Snap was way further
Speaker 2:  ahead in all of this AR stuff than people realized and
Speaker 2:  that at some point it was, it was going to just release the thing and nobody
Speaker 2:  would've seen it coming. It sounds very much like all these years later we
Speaker 2:  are still not there. This might not be that thing. What are we doing
Speaker 2:  here? What is, what is Snap up to with spectacles? Like what is your sense
Speaker 2:  of what's going on inside of Snap as they think about this hardware thing
Speaker 2:  that they've been working on all this time?
Speaker 18:  Yeah, since I've been reporting on this since gosh many
Speaker 18:  years, I've felt the same way. Like when is this finally going to arrive?
Speaker 18:  and it keeps getting pushed out. Snap and Meta are
Speaker 18:  both showing these air glasses off that they've been working on, but they're
Speaker 18:  essentially glorified prototypes and Snap is
Speaker 18:  repeating its playbook from 2021 where it
Speaker 18:  released, I say released in quotes because it showed
Speaker 18:  AR spectacles and when we say that it's, you know, displays
Speaker 18:  inside the lenses where You can see virtual objects on the real world. It
Speaker 18:  showed those off and pitched it as kind of a dev kit for its lens creators.
Speaker 18:  And I got to try them. Journalists got to try them but Snap never sold them
Speaker 18:  and they're, they waffled a bit on whether they would sell the version they're
Speaker 18:  about to announce in September. The fifth generation, which I'm
Speaker 18:  told is, you know, it's, it's a meaningful upgrade but it's more of a like
Speaker 18:  an S type iPhone model. It's more of just a better faster
Speaker 18:  version of the design that they released in 2021,
Speaker 2:  Which would be something yeah, like the, the one, the one we saw a couple
Speaker 2:  of years ago was very cool. I got it in the most incredibly controlled
Speaker 2:  demo. Yeah. and it overheated like every 10 minutes. Same, but when it worked
Speaker 2:  it was, it was cool. Like the, the tech was fairly primitive but pretty good.
Speaker 2:  There's
Speaker 18:  A lot of good ideas in there. Yeah. Is what I remember and when, you know,
Speaker 18:  I kept thinking wow, like when they finally fix the bugs here and the
Speaker 18:  battery life and the display quality and the weight, like the
Speaker 18:  ideas in the interface and how you use this thing really
Speaker 18:  are compelling. It's just really hindered by the tech. And I would say that's
Speaker 18:  actually been the story of AR glasses since Snap and Meta
Speaker 18:  both started working are on them around, you know, in earnest around
Speaker 18:  2017. Yeah, 20 16, 20 18 is that the tech just
Speaker 18:  hasn't been ready for the vision of what these companies think these glasses
Speaker 18:  can do. And yes, in the same way that Snap invented a lot of social media
Speaker 18:  concepts like stories and ephemeral messaging that we use
Speaker 18:  today in META'S apps. They have been very early to eyewear with
Speaker 18:  spectacles and smart glasses and now Meta feels like it's
Speaker 18:  starting to take that narrative away from them. And I think they're hoping
Speaker 18:  that especially by going out, you know, a week before Zuckerberg is gonna
Speaker 18:  show off his glasses, their prototype will wow people and kind of
Speaker 18:  remind everyone that they were actually first and they're still moving ahead
Speaker 18:  here. But again, like they aren't selling these things so they're,
Speaker 18:  they're glorified prototypes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you think it even matters, even if Snap comes out and says, you
Speaker 2:  know, we've gone an order of magnitude ahead in technology, these things
Speaker 2:  are super cool, really exciting. What was it? You said they're, they're not
Speaker 2:  even planning to make 10,000 of them, right? It's like it's, it's a science
Speaker 2:  project like it, it is just a science project and I like, I wonder at some
Speaker 2:  point why SNAP is gonna continue to release these things.
Speaker 2:  Like what is, what is Spectacles doing for SNAP at this point in time?
Speaker 18:  That's a very good question and one that a lot of people inside Snap
Speaker 18:  aren't even sure about to be perfectly honest. I mean this is Evan Spiegel
Speaker 18:  and Bobby Murphy, the two co-founders baby this hardware
Speaker 18:  division, they're spending a lot of money still on it and Snap as a business,
Speaker 18:  it's just not been doing well. They've really struggled to scale their advertising
Speaker 18:  business and build a sustainable, profitable ads business on top of their,
Speaker 18:  you know, messaging app, which I should note is bigger than ever. They have,
Speaker 18:  I believe it's over 800 million users globally Snap as a,
Speaker 18:  as a social network is doing well. It's just that it's business is
Speaker 18:  not right. And so investors are looking at their investment in hardware
Speaker 18:  and going, do you really have the leash and the ability
Speaker 18:  to compete here in such a capital intensive space where
Speaker 18:  Meta is inve investing, you know, billions and billions of dollars
Speaker 18:  into AR and Snap is really the, the David
Speaker 18:  to the Goliath here and that's been their story in social media and I think
Speaker 18:  Evan Spiegel, the CEO thinks you know that they have a shot even in
Speaker 18:  hardware. But I have become very skeptical, especially in the last few years
Speaker 18:  that Snap can be a meaningful player here. I mean my read from just talking
Speaker 18:  to company insiders is that they want to have a seat at the table for
Speaker 18:  what Spiegel and Zuckerberg both agree could be the next major platform
Speaker 18:  shift, which is, you know, us using smart glasses and AR
Speaker 18:  glasses to augment, you know, how we use our phones and to eventually shift
Speaker 18:  usage away from phones to to wearables. That has been the narrative that
Speaker 18:  has been spun by both of them, like I said for eight
Speaker 18:  years now. It still feels far away. I think it's getting closer but
Speaker 18:  it's still not on the near horizon. And the question is whether Snap has
Speaker 18:  the, the leash to survive that long while Meta is investing so
Speaker 18:  much,
Speaker 2:  It does seem very clear that Snap thought
Speaker 2:  this would all be ready much sooner than it turns out it's actually going
Speaker 2:  to be ready. Everyone did. And that's not just Snap Snap, that's everybody,
Speaker 2:  right? Like that is the whole industry. It's like I think back to when all
Speaker 2:  the like Lyfts and Ubers and everybody were telling us that by 2020 everybody
Speaker 2:  would taking robot taxis, right? Like yeah it's, it's just the timeline
Speaker 2:  of all of this just everybody turned out to be wrong.
Speaker 18:  You know, it's, it's funny you said Robotaxis though because I was thinking
Speaker 18:  about that. I was in Phoenix last weekend and I was seeing all the Waymo's
Speaker 18:  on the street there and they're starting to pop up here where I live in
Speaker 18:  LA I see the SF every time I go up there and you know,
Speaker 18:  thinking about yeah how long we had to deal with companies
Speaker 18:  saying that self-driving was right around the corner and all of a sudden
Speaker 18:  it's kind of here, right? Waymo's doing hundreds of thousands of rides.
Speaker 18:  I think AR may be a similar story. I think it's interesting. Yes, they've
Speaker 18:  been saying it for a long time and it's easy to feel like, oh like you know,
Speaker 18:  it's just another year of prototypes and vaporware and it, it's
Speaker 18:  no closer. But I do feel like it's getting closer. I think it may be
Speaker 18:  a thing where we really don't see it at meaningful scale meeting millions
Speaker 18:  of units a year until towards the end of this decade. Like
Speaker 18:  20, 28 ish is I think when Meta especially expects it to hit.
Speaker 18:  But I'm expecting these to be good demos, spectacles and
Speaker 18:  META'S classes and it wasn't here for a really long time until
Speaker 18:  all of a sudden it was.
Speaker 2:  That's actually a good segue to meta because I think if there is going to
Speaker 2:  be a company in the immediate future that is able to just sort of
Speaker 2:  one day drop it on us, it seems like it's gonna be meta everything we're
Speaker 2:  hearing out of Apple is that Apple's ability to make something that is
Speaker 2:  very good and affordable is a long way out. Yeah. Snap. I
Speaker 2:  think we're both sort of slowly giving up on, it feels like if, if there
Speaker 2:  is a company that is going to figure this out in a like all of a sudden it's
Speaker 2:  mainstream kind of way, it's probably gonna be meta and my God would I not
Speaker 2:  have been on that five years ago? But it feels like, it feels like here we
Speaker 2:  are and especially the, the RayBan glasses have been so successful and it
Speaker 2:  feels like that has shifted Meta's thinking about how to
Speaker 2:  sequence some of this stuff in some ways. Like what's your sense of what
Speaker 2:  we're gonna see it connect in a couple of weeks.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, you're right that RayBan has shifted their view a little bit here
Speaker 18:  because these last RayBan Smart glasses, which I have, I don't know if you've
Speaker 18:  used them, the version two. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I have a pair. They're awesome. I use 'em all the time. They're
Speaker 18:  Quite good. Yeah. And it's the first meta hardware product I see normal
Speaker 18:  people using and talking about and they've been very pleasantly
Speaker 18:  surprised with how well it's done and what they're going to show at
Speaker 18:  Connect is separate from the RayBan line. I'm expecting updated
Speaker 18:  RayBan stuff but nothing meaningful. But really what the big AR
Speaker 18:  glasses thing is this project they've been working on since 2018
Speaker 18:  called Orion and they have put billions of dollars into this
Speaker 18:  product. I actually don't think it's a stretch to say they have maybe invested
Speaker 18:  snap's entire market cap as a public company into this one pair of
Speaker 18:  glasses. Yeah, yeah. Like trying to invent new metals, new battery technology
Speaker 18:  to try to make a pair of semi lightweight. They're not going to be
Speaker 18:  lightweight, they're about four x the weight of regular glasses, but still
Speaker 18:  that's a meaningful upgrade from like the early Magic Leap demos.
Speaker 2:  Well and like the Vision Pro or the Quest like it's, it's much closer to
Speaker 2:  glasses than those things.
Speaker 18:  Very chunky Clark Kent looking glasses that
Speaker 18:  do holograms lets you virtually, you know, conference with people
Speaker 18:  inter integrate with Meta's other apps. So having some 2D elements from
Speaker 18:  other apps brought into there and it's a prototype, it's not something they're
Speaker 18:  going to be selling, they're making even fewer of them than Snap spectacles.
Speaker 18:  They cost a lot of money. I mean both the new spectacles and or the Orion
Speaker 18:  glasses cost thousands of dollars to make per unit. So
Speaker 18:  this is very like out there tech that, you know, leaders at Meta
Speaker 18:  have told me it's prohibitively expensive to do this as a mainstream product.
Speaker 18:  Meta hoped, Zuckerberg hoped that Orion was going to be their first consumer
Speaker 18:  air glasses product. They made the call about two years ago to
Speaker 18:  make it a glorified prototype that they just show to the world. And I
Speaker 18:  think they're doing that because even though they don't have the same business
Speaker 18:  pressure as Snap, they need to justify what they're doing here
Speaker 18:  because this AR program has costs a lot of money and I think everyone looks
Speaker 18:  at Quest and goes, oh, like it's all vr. They have a lot of people
Speaker 18:  working on these classes and they're separate from
Speaker 18:  RayBan. But I think you'll see the RayBan stuff that they're doing
Speaker 18:  and Orion converge in the coming years
Speaker 18:  and they'll approach it from different angles, but they'll have the kinda
Speaker 18:  lower tech, cheaper smart glasses without high-end displays and then the
Speaker 18:  high-end display glasses and then those they hope will emerge towards
Speaker 18:  the end of this decade. But this is a big like moment in terms of just saying
Speaker 18:  like, we have something that works even though in a highly controlled
Speaker 18:  demo and we're not selling it, but here it is and here's like a
Speaker 18:  a a marker of where we are in the progression of this technology and
Speaker 18:  I'm expecting Orion to be the most advanced, you know, pair of air glasses
Speaker 18:  that that I will have tried. That doesn't mean it's a good product, right.
Speaker 18:  But it probably will mean it's a good demo and I think that's all meta hopes
Speaker 18:  for
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the context of this moment is really interesting to me because I feel
Speaker 2:  like if you rewind what a little over a year now
Speaker 2:  meta like front ran the Vision Pro trying to
Speaker 2:  basically get its thing out there before Apple did because there was this
Speaker 2:  perception that Apple was gonna come out and just instantly upend the market
Speaker 2:  and change everything and be the only name anybody cared about in this space.
Speaker 2:  That obviously did not happen. Like I think you and I were on the show about
Speaker 2:  a year ago talking about how that might happen and Meta was afraid and everybody
Speaker 2:  was nervous about what Apple would do when it entered this market. I, I think
Speaker 2:  if anything, apple has actually made it harder on everybody else because
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro has not, it hasn't done anything like, I, I dunno
Speaker 2:  that I'd call it a failure. It's just like a nothing, like no one thi no
Speaker 2:  one talks about the Vision Pro, it's just not there. It doesn't exist in
Speaker 2:  the world. So, and now Meta has this
Speaker 2:  hit in the RayBan glasses. Mark Zuckerberg has been on like
Speaker 2:  the, the PR 180 of a lifetime. So it
Speaker 2:  feels like the, the context for this company coming into this moment like
Speaker 2:  could not be more different than I think Meta would've expected
Speaker 2:  a year ago. And so to, to some extent, I wonder if this is gonna feel like
Speaker 2:  meta just sort of flexing on him much more so than being like, look, we're
Speaker 2:  still in the game. We're trying to be cool. It's just gonna be like Mark
Speaker 2:  with a bunch of gold chains on just being like this cool thing I build.
Speaker 18:  I guarantee you there will be some chains, but I, I don't know
Speaker 18:  man, I see that but I also just look at what they're announcing and it's
Speaker 18:  not a product. Right. Yeah. So we are still on the like demo phase
Speaker 18:  of AR glasses and I feel like we've been stuck in that since the
Speaker 18:  first magic leap and it doesn't feel like this year will move
Speaker 18:  us out of that phase. It feels like we're still stuck there. Yeah. And
Speaker 18:  it's hard to like, you know, I'm expecting to try Orion and the new spectacles
Speaker 18:  and it's hard to feel about how do I write about these because there,
Speaker 18:  it's kind of vaporware in a sense, right? It's not something that someone
Speaker 18:  can buy and take home with them. So what is the point? And
Speaker 18:  you know, I think each, you know, company Snap and Meta has slightly different
Speaker 18:  reasons for doing it, but I think they both just wanna say, look, we're
Speaker 18:  still in this fight, we're still in this race and we
Speaker 18:  think there is a, you know, pot at the end of the rainbow here. And the,
Speaker 18:  it keeps getting pushed further and further out. But here's what we've got.
Speaker 18:  And you know, I should note like Orion I think will be also
Speaker 18:  different because Meta has invested a lot in this
Speaker 18:  wristband. They're going to have that pairs with it that essentially allows
Speaker 18:  you to control it with your thoughts. It's EMG technology.
Speaker 18:  It's not mind reading, but they bought a startup called Control Labs that
Speaker 18:  we've covered a lot here on The Verge years ago to do this. And they,
Speaker 18:  they've been working on some really novel input technology for
Speaker 18:  wearables that I'm really interested in, even beyond the actual
Speaker 18:  displays. So that's something to watch as well. And then the AI piece, I
Speaker 18:  think Meta has meaningfully accelerated on in the
Speaker 18:  last year. I don't know, have you used the, the visual AI in the Ray
Speaker 18:  bands yet?
Speaker 2:  In bits and pieces? Yeah. Yeah. It's really cool. It's, it feels it's, it
Speaker 2:  feels kind of sticky most of the time when I use it, but it is, it is good.
Speaker 18:  It works like half the time for me, right? It still hallucinates, it still
Speaker 18:  makes things up, but it's fast and it's made me realize like, oh,
Speaker 18:  like a visual Chad, GPT, like AI
Speaker 18:  in my glasses that understands the world around me is just a killer
Speaker 18:  feature and when it works at scale will make me use my
Speaker 18:  phone less and I don't even need displays for that. And I think Meta's
Speaker 18:  seen that in the last six months even with how kind of rudimentary it is
Speaker 18:  now and said, wow, like we need to lean into this. And they have I think,
Speaker 18:  just better tech in this regard than Snap. And
Speaker 18:  I think for wearable glasses to take off, really we've, we've seen
Speaker 18:  now in the last year that you need that AI piece And I think that's something
Speaker 18:  meta will also keep leaning into very heavily at Connect. And
Speaker 18:  after that
Speaker 2:  It makes sense. So, I, I understand I think most of the motivation
Speaker 2:  for why Snap needs to talk about this stuff and kind of remind people that
Speaker 2:  it's in the game and still matters and get people to build for its
Speaker 2:  platform. And like I, like I, I get that from Snap Side for Meta.
Speaker 2:  I don't know that I get it quite as much because Meta is is doing very well
Speaker 2:  in ai, which are, if you're an investors, the only thing anybody cares about,
Speaker 2:  if anything, everybody views all this other stuff as a diversion. So to keep
Speaker 2:  doing this stuff basically out of the public view of Wall Street
Speaker 2:  seems like it sort of makes sense also. Like things are going well at
Speaker 2:  Meta, so coming out and being like, look, we have this cool thing that we
Speaker 2:  can't ship, but isn't it so cool? It just doesn't seem like it gains the
Speaker 2:  company all that much. But I guess to your point, if they've been doing this
Speaker 2:  now for six years, like literally maybe it's just for team morale, you
Speaker 2:  eventually have to show the people what you're working on. Like maybe it
Speaker 2:  really is just that simple.
Speaker 18:  I think that's a huge piece of it. And you know, people don't like working
Speaker 18:  on hardware that never ships and I think that was actually a big motivation
Speaker 18:  with the Vision Pro finally launching. I think just after so many
Speaker 18:  years you've got to have something to show and yeah, I think
Speaker 18:  meta being on its front foot versus its back foot this year means that,
Speaker 18:  you know, they feel better about doing this. But I think, you know, to
Speaker 18:  your earlier point about like what's the motivation Snap and Meta's,
Speaker 18:  you know, big picture motivation is actually very similar, which is that
Speaker 18:  they both grew their businesses under the thumb of Apple and Google
Speaker 18:  and mobile phone app store control. And
Speaker 18:  if there is going to be a coming hardware shift where people use
Speaker 18:  wearables at least as much as phones, if not more, they
Speaker 18:  want to have a seat at the table and they want to control their own destiny.
Speaker 18:  And Zuckerberg especially has been very clear about this in interviews with
Speaker 18:  me and others, that this is a huge motivating factor. I mean
Speaker 18:  he's been kind of Apple Public enemy number one for a while now
Speaker 18:  and you know, I don't think that if Apple, you know, finally
Speaker 18:  releases air glasses in the coming years, like I don't think it's a given
Speaker 18:  to assume that they would let Meta's apps on there. And I don't think meta
Speaker 18:  thinks it's given that they would do that. And so if you are
Speaker 18:  maybe gonna get boxed out in future hardware shifts, you know, you
Speaker 18:  better play to win and you better have your own hardware and that's the
Speaker 18:  motivation. But the question is, is that the right bet and is this
Speaker 18:  actually going to be hardware that normal people want to use
Speaker 18:  in the coming years? And I think the jury's definitely out on that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That tracks. But I, but I do think, I mean to your point, if this is
Speaker 2:  the sort of thing that is going to happen, you, what is, what's the phrase?
Speaker 2:  Slowly and then all at once. Yeah. Being early is much safer than being
Speaker 2:  late. Right? Unless you're snap and you literally can't afford to have spent
Speaker 2:  all this money. Like meta, meta can afford to be early, like literally with
Speaker 2:  dollars afford to be early in a way that I think it, it seems to be
Speaker 2:  willing to do that.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. I mean look at Waymo and, and Google and self-driving, right? You
Speaker 18:  know, they've, they've plowed billions of dollars into Waymo. There's been
Speaker 18:  many years in the last decade where investors and the public are like, what
Speaker 18:  are you doing? Just give up on this. It's never gonna work. All of a sudden
Speaker 18:  it's starting to work. People are getting picked up by Waymo's from the
Speaker 18:  airport, you know, they're out in the world working and now,
Speaker 18:  you know, if, if it hits, if it really hits and it hits scale and
Speaker 18:  is like the next Uber but cheaper to run and it is this huge
Speaker 18:  business benefit to Google, everyone will forgive the last 10 years
Speaker 18:  of, you know, sinking money into this for no result. And I think ar is
Speaker 18:  a similar story with perhaps an even greater return because you know, VR
Speaker 18:  is something that's isolating and you wear mostly inside and by yourself.
Speaker 18:  But the idea is that ar glasses are something you wear all day long
Speaker 18:  and take with you and the time spent in them is, is huge.
Speaker 18:  'cause you wear, like if you're me, you wear glasses almost all day. And
Speaker 18:  I think they see that as like a huge potential
Speaker 18:  way to create a new business. And yeah, I just think that I,
Speaker 18:  I like that you brought up self-driving because I think there's a lot of
Speaker 18:  analogies there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no it makes sense. And I do feel like the AR thing is so funny 'cause
Speaker 2:  it's like, it's like the AI story in that the biggest version of the story
Speaker 2:  You can tell is so damn big that you like seem ridiculous
Speaker 2:  if you don't try to chase it in some way, even though the odds of it getting
Speaker 2:  yeah, as big as you want. Like it seems to me to be just as likely that everybody
Speaker 2:  says No, I don't want a screen on my face. Thank you as they do to say
Speaker 2:  yes ar glasses forever. But the possibility if it hits, it's gonna
Speaker 2:  hit so big that there all of these companies are desperately afraid of not
Speaker 2:  chasing that thing, right?
Speaker 18:  And Meta has the money to be able to make this kind of bet and Snap increasingly
Speaker 18:  does not. And so the question is who is standing at the end of
Speaker 18:  the next few years here and who has the ability to, to keep
Speaker 18:  investing And I would put my money on Meta right now. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I I I tend to agree. Alright, one more question and then I will let you go.
Speaker 2:  You mentioned these things are super expensive to make and that's one of
Speaker 2:  the reasons these companies are not selling them. There was also a report
Speaker 2:  from the information a few days ago that meta scrapped what I think was supposed
Speaker 2:  to be its really high end project because they just never figured out a way
Speaker 2:  to do it at the price that they wanted to. And Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 2:  has been saying to you and others for forever that price is really important
Speaker 2:  in all of this stuff. And that one of the things Meta has been doing,
Speaker 2:  like he, he sort of intimated kind of in as many words we could have made
Speaker 2:  a thing as good as the Vision Pro, but we chose not to because it would've
Speaker 2:  been too expensive. And I'm curious now having seen what we saw from the
Speaker 2:  Vision Pro, both in terms of like how good the thing is, but also what it
Speaker 2:  has done in the world. What do you make of Meta's kind of
Speaker 2:  ongoing obsession with price? Like is this, is this the right move even in
Speaker 2:  the early days of these things to only wanna sell things cheap?
Speaker 18:  You know, I thought it was, but I don't know. I think these things need
Speaker 18:  to be better products before we start really caring about price.
Speaker 2:  Well that's the Apple be, right? Like who we're gonna make the best thing
Speaker 2:  possible, whatever it costs and then we'll figure out how to make it cheaper.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. And I think Meta has maybe focused and is continuing to focus a
Speaker 18:  little too much on price, but it's not to say that the Quest is not a good
Speaker 18:  product per se, but it's not something that I want to use,
Speaker 18:  let's put it that way. That's fair. And I think they have to figure
Speaker 18:  out why people want to strap these things onto their
Speaker 18:  face and that still has not really been figured out and
Speaker 18:  price feels kind of secondary because it's like, oh I have this
Speaker 18:  cheaper thing that you don't know how to use while you still don't know
Speaker 18:  how to use it. So why would you buy it?
Speaker 2:  It's an eighth, the price and still sort of pointless for you. Do you want
Speaker 2:  it now?
Speaker 18:  Right. But I think long term it is a iOS versus Android thing
Speaker 18:  all over again. Meta is going to be the cheaper, you know, your margin
Speaker 18:  is my opportunity player here. Whereas Apple will be Apple and
Speaker 18:  have Apple margins and charge a lot of money because they can
Speaker 18:  and they have a built-in, you know, loyalty base of people who will pay
Speaker 18:  anything for a new Apple product. And I don't see that changing.
Speaker 18:  I see meta canceling, you know, it's, it's high end kind of vision pro competitor
Speaker 18:  as more of a realization that this highend market for these
Speaker 18:  headsets, and I'm drawing a distinction between these headsets and air glasses,
Speaker 18:  but headsets at a high end, even with great displays,
Speaker 18:  the market's just not there yet and the software ecosystem's not there.
Speaker 18:  We've seen that with the Vision Pro in the last year and for Meta I think
Speaker 18:  it makes more sense for them to play at the lower end and let Apple have
Speaker 18:  the higher end.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean that to me is the lesson of the Ray bands, right? Yeah. That
Speaker 2:  it's like actually if you take something that does substantially
Speaker 2:  less but make it sort of socially workable
Speaker 2:  and make it good, you have something like that to me feels like a
Speaker 2:  much saner starting point for, what are they, they're they're like
Speaker 2:  350 bucks I think.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. And You can buy 'em with insurance
Speaker 2:  email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. You can hit me up on threads. I
Speaker 2:  don't know, we're
Speaker 22:  some people are ahead right now or will a company we've never heard of
Speaker 22:  probably be the winner in the long run? Thanks.
Speaker 2:  So this question comes at a really funny time because I just had a long conversation
Speaker 2:  with someone in the tech industry about more or less this
Speaker 2:  question, the question of whether or not the
Speaker 2:  AI industry is going to calcify, right? On the one hand
Speaker 2:  you have the fact that these things are vastly more expensive
Speaker 2:  all the time to train these models are super complicated, super humongous.
Speaker 2:  You need a lot of Nvidia chips that are hard to get like
Speaker 2:  it. It is very, very hard to go from nothing to competitive in
Speaker 2:  the AI world. On the other hand, it feels like it's
Speaker 2:  moving faster than ever. AI is going from meaning one thing to meaning
Speaker 2:  lots of things. There are lots of companies with lots of resources that have
Speaker 2:  not started playing this game in this kind of way. So it
Speaker 2:  both feels like there are big players and like nothing
Speaker 2:  has yet been decided. But to the question of first mover advantage, I have
Speaker 2:  two thoughts on this. One is that I think pretty clearly there
Speaker 2:  was some first mover advantage when Chat GPT came out at the end of
Speaker 2:  2022 that changed the industry, right? Like you, you
Speaker 2:  really cannot overstate the extent to which there is a tech industry before
Speaker 2:  the launch of chat GPT. And there is a tech industry after the launch of
Speaker 2:  chat GBT, right or wrong, correct or incorrect. The thing that
Speaker 2:  happened when chat GBT came out and a hundred million people used it
Speaker 2:  and went, oh my god, This is the future, changed
Speaker 2:  everything, right? And all of these companies had to scramble to keep
Speaker 2:  up. Google basically completely changed its company around
Speaker 2:  ai. Microsoft started spinning up lots of new things. It had some
Speaker 2:  advantage just by virtue of its existing relationship with open ai. All
Speaker 2:  these other companies that had been working on AI stuff kind of in the background
Speaker 2:  is a research project over the years. Like AI is not a new thing, but
Speaker 2:  AI as a consumer product is new. And chat
Speaker 2:  GPT, which I feel like I've said this a million times, but
Speaker 2:  OpenAI did not understand the extent to which this is going to be a hit consumer
Speaker 2:  product. So it was not ready for this either. But we've gotten
Speaker 2:  to the point now where OpenAI is the biggest name in AI and it's not close.
Speaker 2:  I think You can have interesting arguments about who's tech is the best and
Speaker 2:  who's best positioned and whatever. But OpenAI is a household name and that
Speaker 2:  is because of chat. GPT Chat. GPT is a household name. GPT as
Speaker 2:  a thing is a household name. People use that term
Speaker 2:  like they do ATM. It's nuts. I hate that we've allowed this to happen,
Speaker 2:  but here we are. We just use GPT in conversation. So,
Speaker 2:  I think to one extent, OpenAI bought itself a lot
Speaker 2:  of time and a lot of reputation and a lot of runway by being
Speaker 2:  first. It was also better than pretty much everything else that
Speaker 2:  came out right after both because it went first and because it was just better.
Speaker 2:  OpenAI had very good tech, they've been working on this for a long time.
Speaker 2:  Chat GPT was well ahead of everybody else. I don't think that's that
Speaker 2:  true anymore. It feels like for really the last, I don't
Speaker 2:  know year, but especially over the last six months, every couple of weeks
Speaker 2:  some company has released a new model that they claim is, you know, a a
Speaker 2:  step better than all of the other models, right? You have open AI doing it
Speaker 2:  with all the GPTs. Anthropic is doing it with the various versions of Claude.
Speaker 2:  Google is doing it with Gemini and Meta is doing it with Llama. There's this
Speaker 2:  incredible arms race. As these models get bigger,
Speaker 2:  they get faster, they get more efficient, they get cheaper for developers
Speaker 2:  to, they get cheaper for the companies to run. So you you, we have this
Speaker 2:  incredible sort of leapfrogging game happening between all of these companies.
Speaker 2:  On the one hand that kind of negates the first mover advantage, right? You
Speaker 2:  can argue Anthropic was late to this game, but I think it's caught up in
Speaker 2:  a really big way. I hear a lot of people talking about Claude,
Speaker 2:  which is Anthropics model kind of its version of chat GPT
Speaker 2:  being better and more fun to use and more useful than
Speaker 2:  chat GPT and Gemini. I think because of the way that
Speaker 2:  it's integrated with other Google services has some huge advantages.
Speaker 2:  What Microsoft is doing with copilot, which is kind of associated with but
Speaker 2:  not the same as open AI stuff, is also the same, right? So you have these
Speaker 2:  companies that have other huge advantages, which is basically they can attach
Speaker 2:  AI to their products that is going to make it easy for them to catch up.
Speaker 2:  The flip side is that as these models get bigger and as they get
Speaker 2:  more complicated and as they get more impressive,
Speaker 2:  the cost to build one just goes through the roof. Like the, these things
Speaker 2:  are so unbelievably expensive to train, forget about running them
Speaker 2:  and the cost every time somebody queries it. And you have to actually process
Speaker 2:  their information through this trend model. The cost of training
Speaker 2:  these models is so, so, so high and
Speaker 2:  not gonna go down, right? The only way these things get better is if they
Speaker 2:  get bigger and they do more. And for these kind of catchall models,
Speaker 2:  it's just gonna be a few companies that can do it. I don't think that's that
Speaker 2:  different from what we've seen before. I mean think about like cloud resources,
Speaker 2:  right? You have AWS, you have Microsoft Azure and you have Google Cloud.
Speaker 2:  Other companies can be in that game, but you have to have unbelievable
Speaker 2:  amounts of resources to have the amount of computing power, just the number
Speaker 2:  of data centers, the number of employees, what it takes to really operate
Speaker 2:  a global cloud network just isn't available to most
Speaker 2:  companies. And the same is gonna be true
Speaker 2:  Chad GPT is. But there's also tons of
Speaker 2:  smaller and different and more specific things. And, if you
Speaker 2:  think about AI in those terms, we're just at the very beginning of
Speaker 2:  a huge culture shift that doesn't actually depend all
Speaker 2:  that much on the models that companies like OpenAI are generating.
Speaker 2:  As this stuff gets more open source, there's gonna be more access for this
Speaker 2:  stuff. I think we're starting to see some of these models get commoditized
Speaker 2:  to the point where having the biggest, newest model is only going to be useful
Speaker 2:  for some things and that most people will be perfectly happy with the local
Speaker 2:  models that are able to run faster and locally on your computer or
Speaker 2:  the simple models that can run on lower end hardware, that run on TVs and
Speaker 2:  things like that. So what you're looking at instead of a race to the top
Speaker 2:  for these most impressive models, you're looking at just this kind of incredible
Speaker 2:  splintering around the whole industry. And if that's what's gonna happen,
Speaker 2:  there won't be a first mover advantage in the same way that there wasn't
Speaker 2:  a first mover advantage, like being the first website on the internet. It's
Speaker 2:  cool, it comes with some upsides, it might give you a lead, but the
Speaker 2:  thing that there is out there is way too big for any one company to win anyway.
Speaker 2:  I think it could go either way. And I think right now if you're OpenAI, you
Speaker 2:  have so much cache and so much
Speaker 2:  upside and the fact that Sam Altman is like the face of AI as a thing
Speaker 2:  is really useful to OpenAI and we will keep propelling
Speaker 2:  AI at the top of this industry and getting media coverage and getting developer
Speaker 2:  interests and all this stuff for a long time. But if AI is not
Speaker 2:  just for companies giving you models that You can do everything on,
Speaker 2:  but is actually as big as everybody says, it's too big for any one
Speaker 2:  company to be in charge of. I know that's not really an answer. It's a little
Speaker 2:  bit of both. There is a first mover advantage, but I think it's gonna get
Speaker 2:  away from everybody and I also think it's too complicated for that. I hope
Speaker 2:  that helps. Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you
Speaker 2:  to everybody who came on the show, and thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  Thank you to everybody, by the way, who has called and messaged and emailed
Speaker 2:  with your productivity systems after hearing the episode on Sunday. That
Speaker 2:  has been super fun to see. As always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or an AI model to sell me, You can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. we love hearing
Speaker 2:  from you and like I said, buying advice. If you have buying thoughts, hit
Speaker 2:  us up. We wanna hear it all. This show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam
Speaker 2:  James, and Wil Pour The. Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the
Speaker 2:  Vox Media podcast network.