# Transcript
ID: fd6984e5-e0c1-4748-852d-e36d66b98934
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5821366249742775117/6134522575627967655/s93290-US-5125s-1706263814.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Apple allowing alternative browser engines in the EU, Netflix getting WWE, Pixel 9 leaks, and more.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast, the European Union.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Look, I couldn't get what I wanted by talking about it on this show.
Speaker 1:  They
Speaker 3:  Earned it. So I called my friends in Europe and said Use the power of the
Speaker 3:  state. Yeah, boy did they ever,
Speaker 4:  They really did.
Speaker 3:  This is the wonkiest way to begin a show about cell phones has ever wonked.
Speaker 6:  We won in 1776 and we won again in 2024.
Speaker 6:  We're taking over.
Speaker 4:  Did we,
Speaker 3:  Do you think Okay, let's, let's begin. There's a lot of news this week. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Just an overwhelming amount of news. It starts,
Speaker 3:  I think we have to begin with the Digital Markets Act in Europe,
Speaker 3:  which is causing just an enormous amount of change to how
Speaker 3:  the iPhone and iOS are gonna work in Europe. David, walk us through it 'cause
Speaker 3:  it is bananas.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this is actually more bananas than I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of people expected and we were kind of expecting bananas. So basically
Speaker 6:  Apple today, Thursday announced iOS
Speaker 6:  17.4, which is coming out in March. Apple doesn't
Speaker 6:  normally like go way out of its way to make huge announcements about point
Speaker 6:  updates, but there are essentially three big pieces of
Speaker 6:  news in here which are kind of one piece of news in three different directions.
Speaker 6:  And the big thing here is that Apple is just opening up the app store
Speaker 6:  in a really big way. So Apple is going to now allow
Speaker 6:  alternate app stores, which it calls alternative app marketplaces.
Speaker 6:  And if you call them app stores, they will correct you and say app marketplaces
Speaker 6:  on the iPhone. Now I we, we can talk about how all of that works in
Speaker 6:  a minute, but that's the first thing. The second thing is they're now allowing
Speaker 6:  other browser engines to run on iOS. So
Speaker 6:  Chrome and Firefox and all these things can actually run their full tech
Speaker 6:  stack, which means they can run extensions, they can run all kinds of other
Speaker 6:  stuff. That is I think a big deal. And then the
Speaker 6:  third and more immediate things starting today is that the app store is now
Speaker 6:  open to game streaming services. Things like Game Pass and
Speaker 6:  Sony's PlayStation Plus and all that stuff that has not been allowed very
Speaker 6:  contentiously in the app store before. Epic wants to
Speaker 6:  be in the app store and can't be, can't get the Epic store on the iPhone
Speaker 6:  starting now. Those kinds of services are going to be available in the app
Speaker 6:  store. All of this, almost all of it is exclusive
Speaker 6:  to the EU. This is where the digital markets act is. This stuff is taking
Speaker 6:  place there and rather than do what we thought might happen, which is make
Speaker 6:  a big global change the way that it did with USBC, the
Speaker 6:  EU said it has to be USBC and Apple could have made two phones but elected
Speaker 6:  to just switch everything to USBC. Apple is very clearly cleaving
Speaker 6:  off this one part of the world and saying this is how things are going to
Speaker 6:  work in the EU and in the rest of the world. It is more or
Speaker 6:  less business as usual. The game streaming thing is the exception that is
Speaker 6:  global. Everything else extremely focused to the EU and
Speaker 6:  Apple has made very clear it is doing this against its will and
Speaker 6:  with great, great rage and disdain at the entirety of the
Speaker 6:  process.
Speaker 3:  Yes, they're very mad at Europe. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like a Paris baguette just like pointed at their head like
Speaker 3:  Do it Tim Cook is never eating cheese again. Yeah. Yeah. It's never happening.
Speaker 3:  But NELI,
Speaker 6:  What I really wanna know is like we, we've been talking about this for forever
Speaker 6:  and this just sort of like dropped. Yeah. Like is this
Speaker 6:  what you would've guessed this would be coming into this
Speaker 3:  To some extent, the thing that really got me these past few weeks
Speaker 3:  is Apple also had to do the alternative
Speaker 3:  payments thing and it has gone kicking and screaming
Speaker 3:  and basically made that a non-issue. They like weasel their way out
Speaker 3:  of, you have to provide outside links to payment services.
Speaker 3:  Right. Which they have to per court order in the United States and they made
Speaker 3:  that so expensive and so hard to do that. It's never gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  And one would assume then I really thought they would
Speaker 3:  find some way to do that in Europe too with these rules.
Speaker 3:  Then there was a picture of Tim Cook with Margaret Vest sticker who's the
Speaker 3:  competition head in Europe. And I pretty sure you know,
Speaker 3:  they were meeting about this and I feel more confident than ever
Speaker 3:  that Apple made a bit of a horse trade because the EU also wanted
Speaker 3:  them to open up iMessage. Right. And that's a weird one
Speaker 3:  in the EU. 'cause everyone EU uses like WhatsApp. They don't like, they don't
Speaker 3:  use iMessage. Right. So I'm pretty sure Apple got to keep iMessage closed.
Speaker 3:  They said we'll do RCS, which it's about time anyway. And the
Speaker 3:  EU said Okay, we're gonna leave iMessage alone, but you've gotta do the other
Speaker 3:  stuff. And that is the thing. Like I'm pretty sure that that is the,
Speaker 3:  the trade that was worked out. Yeah. And so Apple is like to some extent
Speaker 3:  going farther than we expected with the browser engines, with the app
Speaker 3:  stores, with game streaming. We should talk about game streaming being global.
Speaker 3:  I think that's really interesting. But to some extent they're just making
Speaker 3:  it, it's not quite as bad as the, you have to allow links to external
Speaker 3:  payment services in the us. Yeah. Like you can just put another app store
Speaker 3:  on there. Those app stores have to be approved by Apple. That apps
Speaker 3:  have to be notarized by and there's all this stuff, there's still hoops,
Speaker 3:  but it's not, it's not gonna not happen. Right. The way that external payment
Speaker 3:  services are gonna not happen. And then the browser engine thing,
Speaker 3:  I really think just the ability for Google to put the Chrome
Speaker 3:  browser engine on on the iPhone will make WebKit better.
Speaker 3:  Yes. 'cause Apple will finally have to compete and it can be shown that Apple
Speaker 3:  holds WebKit back in order to preference the app store.
Speaker 3:  And that alone, if all, if that just happens, if it happens in one country
Speaker 3:  in Europe, Luxembourg, Chrome can run on the iPhone and Luxembourg
Speaker 3:  that will make web kit better everywhere else, right? Yeah. Because the evidence
Speaker 3:  will be available. And I think that's amazing. But I, I
Speaker 3:  think there's a little bit of horse trading going on here where they protected
Speaker 3:  iMessage, which is the big lock-in, and they were a little more open to everything
Speaker 3:  else because they needed to protect
Speaker 6:  IMessage. To me, I actually think, and I'm, I'm gonna like try to think this
Speaker 6:  out here as I go because this has just occurred to me as you're talking.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So this might make no sense for a while, but go with me here. I think
Speaker 6:  the fact that they're treating game streaming as
Speaker 6:  different from the alternative app store thing is
Speaker 6:  really telling because in a certain way they're functionally the same thing.
Speaker 6:  Right? It's, it's an app full of other apps, right? Yeah. It's, it's, that's
Speaker 6:  what these game streaming things want and that's what the alternative app
Speaker 6:  stores want. And I think what Apple may have realized
Speaker 6:  is that the game streaming thing, people will
Speaker 6:  go to the ends of the earth to do. Right? Like the, if, if I am
Speaker 6:  a Game Pass subscriber, I will do whatever is required to get
Speaker 6:  game pass. And that stuff is big enough and powerful enough that people will
Speaker 6:  go through whatever hoops are required. So Apple is actually in a certain
Speaker 6:  way, smart to remove some of those hoops and just
Speaker 6:  open it up and, and to some extent admit defeat. Right? And it's like we,
Speaker 6:  this is, this is just Apple saying, you know what? You
Speaker 6:  wanted this, you can have it. And we don't know a ton about what the business
Speaker 6:  terms of all of that are gonna be. Apple has been weird about like, it has
Speaker 6:  to approve every individual game in the store before and that's been wonky.
Speaker 6:  So there, there's a lot left to play out there, but I think Apple for that
Speaker 6:  one is kind of just saying you, you want it, you got
Speaker 6:  it, you win on this one. I think it seems to me that that
Speaker 6:  there's a, there's a version of this that says Apple is just trying to
Speaker 6:  make it hard enough that not so that it won't happen
Speaker 6:  'cause it will happen. You're right. There will be alternate app marketplaces
Speaker 6:  on iOS very quickly, but I think they might be able to
Speaker 6:  make it hard enough that almost no one caress and, and the way
Speaker 6:  they've set it up, like Tim Sweeney, the CEO of Epic, which makes Fortnite
Speaker 6:  and all that stuff called it malicious compliance, right? Yeah. And we've
Speaker 6:  talked about that with a lot of what Apple has been doing. That's what the,
Speaker 6:  you can link out from your app, but you still have to pay us 27% even that
Speaker 6:  you're not doing any of this stuff through Apple anymore. That is pure malicious
Speaker 6:  compliance. And in this case too, I think you can accuse Apple of
Speaker 6:  trying to make it hard for developers to play this game. Like
Speaker 6:  if you want to do this, you have to make a different version of
Speaker 6:  your app essentially that works in the EU versus
Speaker 6:  the one that works in the rest of the world. But Apple will only accept one
Speaker 6:  version of your apps. So you have to make an app that is two apps, one of
Speaker 6:  which ones in one place, and one of which runs in the rest of the world.
Speaker 6:  You have to go through this process as an app marketplace to get
Speaker 6:  all of the apps in it notarized and your marketplace approved.
Speaker 6:  If you are a developer, you have to either set up a bunch of other payment
Speaker 6:  systems, work with all these different marketplaces, or you just say, you
Speaker 6:  know what, screw it. We're not actually saving that much money and just say
Speaker 6:  in the App store. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Except there are huge categories of apps that Apple won't allow.
Speaker 3:  Right. This is the thing that I think will be really interesting to you.
Speaker 3:  Yes. And I'm not even sure some of these apps should exist,
Speaker 3:  right? I
Speaker 6:  Mean, porn's the obvious one, right? Deep porn.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. Watch all the porn you want. It's, I'm just saying like,
Speaker 3:  I'm not sure deep fake porn generators should exist
Speaker 3:  on the iPhone. I think that that's a dangerous territory.
Speaker 3:  Apple would never allow that stuff in its store. You can see how an alternative
Speaker 3:  marketplace hoops aside, will certainly allow people to tap the
Speaker 3:  vast processing power of whatever a, a series chip
Speaker 3:  is in your phone to run some of these apps.
Speaker 6:  Even just like apps that show you objectionable content, right? The
Speaker 6:  kinds of things that Apple has not allowed before and is actually like a,
Speaker 6:  a weapon. Apple has wielded against platforms before that
Speaker 6:  is now going to be perfectly permissible to install on the iPhone through
Speaker 6:  one of these alternate stores. Like as long as it, as long as the app itself
Speaker 6:  is not like a security risk stealing your information,
Speaker 6:  it's Apple's content rules do not apply. And
Speaker 6:  that's gotta make Apple feel so gross and icky and
Speaker 3:  They don't like it. Yeah. So I, here's one. And don don't know if Reddit
Speaker 3:  still falls in this category. Tumblr certainly used to fall in this category.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Where Apple's content rules kept the app
Speaker 3:  from showing all the content on the service. Right? So the reason
Speaker 3:  Tumblr got rid of porn is because Verizon bought it and Apple said
Speaker 3:  to its partner, Verizon, it's big important partner
Speaker 3:  shut it down. Yeah. And Verizon said, we sell the iPhone No.
Speaker 3:  And Apple said shut it down and Verizon caved like end of story, right?
Speaker 3:  And then WordPress bought it and they tried to have a fight and they like
Speaker 3:  found the same little exception as Reddit, which is, eh, what
Speaker 3:  if you don't, you know, like that's basically how It works on Reddit. It's
Speaker 3:  basically how it was gonna work on Tumblr. But all these things, like all
Speaker 3:  these hoops we talk about all the time,
Speaker 3:  like Apple makes developers jump through hoops. There are some categories
Speaker 3:  of apps that just do not exist because of the hoops. And in
Speaker 3:  Europe
Speaker 3:  I, yeah, it's like not worth it for saving 3%. That's not
Speaker 3:  even 3%. But when it's existential,
Speaker 3:  I think a bunch of developers are gonna jump through the hoops and I think
Speaker 3:  the first category of apps that have existential
Speaker 3:  problems or the ones Apple forbids, which necessarily
Speaker 3:  means Apple's gonna win the first battle here by saying, look at all the
Speaker 3:  stuff you enabled. Like look at all the porn. Like that's what they're gonna
Speaker 3:  say, look, you made a porn marketplace. Are you, are you, are you happy Europe?
Speaker 3:  People say in Europe, being Europe is gonna be like, yeah we are historically
Speaker 3:  topless so that's fine. We don't believe in that. Like think
Speaker 3:  about what we invented. We're the French right and they're gonna be fine
Speaker 3:  with it. And I, but I, I think that there's
Speaker 3:  another turn here where there are categories of apps that
Speaker 3:  we can't even imagine that don't exist on the phone. There are
Speaker 3:  categories of business models that we cannot imagine that don't exist on
Speaker 3:  the phone. And we might see some of those develop in Europe because now they
Speaker 3:  have actual access to customers on their devices without having
Speaker 3:  to ask Apple for permission. And I think game streaming is that category.
Speaker 3:  It is the category of things where everybody can imagine it, everyone can
Speaker 3:  envision it and it does not exist. And
Speaker 7:  I do wanna say like David, you kind of said eh, it's not that big a deal.
Speaker 7:  I do think having to get App Store permission for every single game
Speaker 7:  that's gonna be on these streaming services is pretty onerous. Like that
Speaker 7:  was something that Nvidia and, and Microsoft and I
Speaker 7:  think even Google were pretty against a couple of years ago. And I'm curious
Speaker 7:  to see if there's, if their opinions have changed, we've reached out to them,
Speaker 7:  we haven't heard back yet, but really, really curious there because before
Speaker 7:  they were like, no, we don't wanna send every like cures of War five, we
Speaker 7:  don't want you approving that. We don't like why should we have to get your
Speaker 7:  approval for it?
Speaker 3:  Well then you take the console maker approvals for those games. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  That's true. But I think there, there's certain things, there's certain types
Speaker 7:  of games and stuff that might be more permissible in a console setting,
Speaker 7:  particularly like around gambling and that sort of thing that are less permissible
Speaker 7:  on the I store on, oh on the Apple store.
Speaker 3:  Oh, here's another whole category. Gambling, you mentioned gambling. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So gambling right now not allowed any NFT apps.
Speaker 3:  Any crypto apps do not exist on the iPhone. Totally. So if you're
Speaker 3:  in Europe, your ability to o open an app store that's like gambling,
Speaker 3:  pornography, cryptocurrency, mining. Yeah. the
Speaker 3:  time of your life. This is why Monaco exists from what I understand,
Speaker 6:  They're gonna get so rich, like the number of billionaires in
Speaker 6:  Europe is about to spike through the
Speaker 3:  Roof.
Speaker 3:  But all that stuff is like wild to think about. Right? That and it's gonna
Speaker 3:  play to Apple's favor because the stuff that most people can immediately
Speaker 3:  think of that is against Apple's rules is stuff that is morally questionable.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right, right. Or at least arguably morally questionable.
Speaker 6:  I think that there's a flip side to that. That is basically
Speaker 6:  businesses that couldn't afford to be on the iPhone, which
Speaker 6:  is like the, the, the rub has always been basically if you don't run a business
Speaker 6:  at a 30% margin, you can't exist in a useful
Speaker 6:  way on the iPhone because Apple's going to take 30%. So like audiobook is
Speaker 6:  one you hear a lot, right? Like it's very hard to make a thing that sells
Speaker 6:  audiobooks in a good useful way on the iPhone
Speaker 6:  because you have to give Apple 30% and that business does not afford you
Speaker 6:  30% margin to give to Apple. And now if you wanna be in
Speaker 6:  an alternate app store using non-Apple payments,
Speaker 6:  which in the EU you're gonna be allowed to do, you suddenly owe Apple nothing.
Speaker 6:  And that like your, your agreement with the marketplace Who knows what that'll
Speaker 6:  be, whatever. But that suddenly changes the kinds of business at
Speaker 6:  the low end of what you can do on the iPhone because you don't
Speaker 6:  have to give Apple 30% of everything that you do, which is pretty powerful.
Speaker 7:  I could see a company like Amazon who already has, knows how to make an app
Speaker 7:  store just being like, all right, we're gonna pull the Kindle app.
Speaker 3:  Do they?
Speaker 7:  Well technic they
Speaker 3:  Do in theory.
Speaker 7:  In theory they do. They've made something and it resembles an app store.
Speaker 7:  They could very easily be like, okay, we're gonna get rid of the Kindle app
Speaker 7:  on, on the Apple
Speaker 3:  Floor. And yeah. And I look forward to Amazon executing a
Speaker 3:  software platform at scale. It'll be great. Let's,
Speaker 6:  They're gonna put the silk browser in there. It's gonna be sick. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think, I think, you know, Andy will believe it when we see it.
Speaker 3:  But I look forward to your attempts. A large company runs a
Speaker 3:  Wix. No, you,
Speaker 6:  You know what I think is perfectly possible is that the Kindle app stays
Speaker 6:  in the app store but also goes into a separate
Speaker 6:  Amazon run marketplace. Like Alex you're talking about. And then Amazon can
Speaker 6:  say, you know what, if you want the easy way, here it is. This is the way
Speaker 6:  the Kindle has always been. But if you do this thing, just hook it up to
Speaker 6:  your Amazon account and you have one click purchasing for all of your Kindle
Speaker 6:  books and audiobooks forever. And I like, I hadn't really thought about that
Speaker 6:  until you mentioned Kindle, but like I would download a new
Speaker 6:  marketplace for that in order to be able to easily buy Kindle books on my
Speaker 6:  phone. I would go through whatever hoops I had to
Speaker 3:  Amazon and Spotify will start their marketplace tomorrow. Right. And
Speaker 3:  so Spotify can se sell you. Its, well I guess they're doing
Speaker 3:  audiobooks too. That's very competitive.
Speaker 7:  They're not gonna, yeah. Unless there's
Speaker 3:  Like, maybe they won't do that together. Maybe
Speaker 7:  Like Waterstones or somebody's like, we're gonna start the bookstore, the
Speaker 7:  book app bookstore or something free, free idea for you. Well,
Speaker 3:  At the very least I look forward to just a, an explosion of bad ideas. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And gambling and porn.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's gonna be great.
Speaker 6:  NELI is moving to Luxembourg is the other news on this
Speaker 3:  Podcast. Okay. So that's the app store side, which I think is like understandable,
Speaker 3:  right? You can see, okay, we're gonna open this up, we're gonna bypass the
Speaker 3:  app store rules, maybe lower some fees or maybe not, depending on how we'll,
Speaker 3:  you know, there, there's some complexity in there. But we'll let apps onto
Speaker 3:  the phone that don't have to meet apps, store rules. You can, you can
Speaker 3:  just imagine all kinds of apps that are gonna happen there. And some of them
Speaker 3:  will and some of they won't. And we will let that develop. The browser side
Speaker 3:  of it to me is actually the bigger deal. And I
Speaker 3:  mentioned Luxembourg, but I really mean this like
Speaker 3:  there is no pressure on WebKit on the iPhone Zero
Speaker 3:  Apple gets to do with that web browser exactly as it pleases and it gets
Speaker 3:  to impose whatever limitations on that browser it wants
Speaker 3:  and that is just very meaningful for a lot of things. Yep. It
Speaker 3:  means that the, the ability for apps to distribute on the web is
Speaker 3:  effectively capped on mobile by whatever Apple wants, whatever
Speaker 3:  boundary it wants for the app store. So I'll just give everybody this example.
Speaker 3:  I'm looking at my Mac, it is running zero native
Speaker 3:  apps right now. Well it's, it's running too. It's running Mime Stream and
Speaker 3:  Notion Calendar, which are both native. Nice. But that's only 'cause I'm
Speaker 3:  a snob and I read installer.
Speaker 3:  That's why it's so good. It's everything else is a web app. Yeah. Like, or
Speaker 3:  it best a, a wrapper around a web app, right? It's some
Speaker 3:  electron thing is happening to run Slack and almost everything else on my
Speaker 3:  Mac is a web app or running in Chrome. Almost every desktop application
Speaker 3:  that you can think of that isn't like a game or a, you know, a video editing
Speaker 3:  software, gene splicing whatever. You might need the actual power of this
Speaker 3:  Mac to do anything else that's like a reader or a information
Speaker 3:  management app or any of this stuff. Almost all of it on the cloud expressed
Speaker 3:  to you through a web browser. Every AI service you can think of is happening
Speaker 3:  on a data center expressed to you through a web browser. There's no chat
Speaker 3:  GBT app for the Mac. There's the web and that
Speaker 3:  is because the web is a great distribution platform on desktop computers
Speaker 3:  because there's actual competition between browser makers and then everyone
Speaker 3:  picks Chrome fine. Well
Speaker 6:  And because your browser gets to do stuff, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like your browser has access to system features and
Speaker 6:  it can store a lot of stuff on the desktop and it can run stuff
Speaker 6:  offline inside of a browser. Like your browser has so much
Speaker 6:  access to the rest of the machine on your desktop, which gives it all these
Speaker 6:  powers that phone browsers just do not have. And that is a
Speaker 6:  deliberate choice that Apple in particular has made for a very long time
Speaker 6:  and they are so mad. Oh they're so mad.
Speaker 3:  Well they're mad I, before I get to mad, I just want to stay on Apple making
Speaker 3:  that choice. Yes. It's a phone. Yes, it's battery constrained. Yes. The
Speaker 3:  screen is small. My old Mac are vastly less
Speaker 3:  powerful than my current iPhone. Right? Like when I do this show at home,
Speaker 3:  I do it on a 2015 iMac. I promise
Speaker 3:  you my iPhone is more powerful than that computer. Like vastly more powerful
Speaker 3:  than that computer. That computer is so much more capable. If I had to have
Speaker 3:  one computer forever, I would probably, between my current
Speaker 3:  iPhone and that Mac, I, yeah, I'd probably pick the iPhone just
Speaker 3:  for a number of reasons. but it would be hard, right? I'd be
Speaker 3:  like, well here's all the things I won't be able to do anymore. Right. And
Speaker 3:  that is weird. That's not related to the, the power of the chip.
Speaker 3:  No. It's related to the flexibility of the operating system and in particular
Speaker 3:  the ability of the browser to do almost anything. Right. It contains
Speaker 3:  a vastly more powerful, much less encumbered at platform in the
Speaker 3:  browser and WebKit stops. And so
Speaker 3:  just having another browser engine on the phone to show
Speaker 3:  everyone here's what you could do if you, you had great browsers on this
Speaker 3:  phone as the default I pr I Apple cannot make a version of
Speaker 3:  WebKit for Europe and a version of WebKit for everyone else. That sucks,
Speaker 3:  right? Like they just can't do that. And I think that pressure is gonna push
Speaker 3:  WebKit, which will then in turn push the app store, which will be good.
Speaker 3:  Will
Speaker 7:  That also mean in the EU the annoying like
Speaker 7:  download the app instead of using the website thing will go away?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Because you'll have all the people like using Chrome and it won't necessarily
Speaker 7:  flag as mobile.
Speaker 3:  No because there's a PM on some app growth team somewhere that's measured
Speaker 3:  in app installs and that she will bribe whoever
Speaker 3:  needs to put that cookie banner on.
Speaker 6:  But like that's actually, that's a perfect reason because like do you know
Speaker 6:  why people want app installs is because when they have an app install, they
Speaker 6:  get to put a thing on your home screen, they get to send you push notifications,
Speaker 6:  they get more power over what happens on your device. They get to
Speaker 6:  take things like your location and all this personal information about you.
Speaker 6:  Like that's stuff that Apple gave to app developers
Speaker 6:  that it could have given to web apps and just didn't
Speaker 6:  because Apple, it's all the same stuff, right? Like Apple wants
Speaker 6:  full control over every single thing that happens on its system and you cannot
Speaker 6:  do that to the web. And I think if you believe the web
Speaker 6:  is a good thing for that reason, this is a great thing. I think if you're
Speaker 6:  Apple, you do this kicking and screaming, which is very clearly what Apple
Speaker 6:  is trying to do. Like basically when you're Apple and you're writing in your
Speaker 6:  press releases that you're like big mad about this. Like
Speaker 6:  it's pretty, it's pretty brutal. It's
Speaker 7:  Very funny.
Speaker 6:  But no, I, I agree and I think the, the this improvement in the web,
Speaker 6:  which to Apple's credit Safari has gotten better
Speaker 6:  in the last couple of years, I would say almost certainly
Speaker 6:  because of regulatory pressure. But Safari has gotten better. You can now
Speaker 6:  install a progressive web app on your phone and it runs more or less
Speaker 6:  like an native app. You know what's crazy? The web has supported that
Speaker 6:  forever.
Speaker 3:  Like, do
Speaker 6:  You remember how many years you couldn't run background audio in Safari?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you left Safari, it would just stop playing whatever you're listening.
Speaker 6:  Like that's just a choice. And I think you're right that if this goes well,
Speaker 6:  that is one thing that will percolate back out is Apple is going to have
Speaker 6:  to win that stuff. And this is like, all of this is so tied
Speaker 6:  together in my brain now. 'cause like I spent all this time at the Google
Speaker 6:  antitrust trial where they talked a ton about this Apple deal and it's like,
Speaker 6:  oh, apple makes a lot of money because of this deal from Google. Google
Speaker 6:  is gonna be less inclined to give Apple all that money if Safari stops working.
Speaker 6:  So Apple has a real competitive reason to make Safari work
Speaker 6:  even in a world where it wants apps to work. So like this flywheel
Speaker 6:  of, can we make the web a little better? I think you're right, is going to
Speaker 6:  push Apple in good directions because it actually has found a way
Speaker 6:  to make a lot of money off of the open web. So like kudos to Apple. but it's,
Speaker 6:  it's a good thing for us. I I really think
Speaker 3:  It, it found, it pointed a gun at Google and said, do you want this
Speaker 3:  data? And Google said weed. Yes. Yeah, please.
Speaker 3:  The game stream one. I I, it's interesting it's Apple for the first time
Speaker 3:  admitting that the app store has segments and some are more lucrative than
Speaker 3:  the others. Right? And it, so it said, okay, games are,
Speaker 3:  we're fine, they're different. We're gonna treat them differently. We're
Speaker 3:  gonna go global because Microsoft will just like kick our butt all over the
Speaker 3:  globe if we only let this happen in Europe. 'cause then at every
Speaker 3:  Xbox developer event, Microsoft will be like, well you can do it in Europe.
Speaker 3:  Call your senator. Right? Like they'll just do it. And if
Speaker 3:  you'll remember during the Apple versus Epic trial, apple could
Speaker 3:  not figure out how to differentiate between Roblox and
Speaker 3:  the things you can build and develop and distribute in Roblox and everything
Speaker 3:  else. Like literally it could not distinguish between Roblox and Minecraft.
Speaker 3:  Like at at one point they were asked is, is Roblox a game? And they're like,
Speaker 3:  yes. And they're like, but it has purchases in it. And they're like, yes.
Speaker 3:  And they're like, okay what about in-app purchases in not Roblox. I'm like,
Speaker 3:  that's a game too. And they're just like, like
Speaker 3:  literally like I could not figure it out. And I think this is them for the
Speaker 3:  first time just being like, okay, there are things called games
Speaker 3:  and we're gonna put them over here and control them differently. And I,
Speaker 3:  that's a sign of maturity. But
Speaker 7:  Are they gonna do that with Roblox? Like is
Speaker 7:  somebody gonna go and approve the game where my, my godson is a prison warden.
Speaker 7:  He's very proud of his prison. Because you can do that in Roblox right
Speaker 6:  Now. Yeah. It's so hard to tell. So lemme lemme just read you the, the thing
Speaker 6:  that Apple says in its announcement, it says that each experience made available
Speaker 6:  in an app on the app store will be required to adhere to all app store review
Speaker 6:  guidelines and its host app will need to maintain an age rating of the highest
Speaker 6:  age rated content included in the app. So the first part or the second part
Speaker 6:  of that simple, straightforward, understood. If you have one, you know
Speaker 6:  NC 17 game NC 17 required to adhere to
Speaker 6:  is like a, an opening you could drive a truck through. Like does that mean
Speaker 6:  it's gonna get reviewed? Does that mean Apple can just kick you off if it's
Speaker 6:  bad? Does that mean just like handshake agreement? Don't do
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 6:  I have no idea. Yeah. Yeah. And it seems very important. 'cause to your point,
Speaker 6:  Alex, like the thing where everybody had to submit and
Speaker 6:  create and have reviewed every single game on their service was like a non-starter.
Speaker 6:  And the way that Apple phrases, it leaves open everything
Speaker 6:  from that to Apple doesn't care. Just be cool. Like
Speaker 3:  Yeah. one of the reasons it was a non-starter was the idea that you would
Speaker 3:  be distributing multiple game binaries. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 3:  dumb, right? For a streaming service. Whereas this is like, you'll have a,
Speaker 3:  a streaming service wrapper, you'll click on a game in it and it will stream
Speaker 3:  the game to you inside of that app. Which they were somewhat able
Speaker 3:  to do on the web. Like they were creaking their way towards being able to
Speaker 3:  do this on the web. Yeah. But if you basically have a cat like Netflix,
Speaker 3:  like Netflix has a catalog of titles in the thing and you push the button.
Speaker 3:  I think what Apple's saying is everything has to, I think this
Speaker 3:  is like a three
Speaker 3:  don't every song on Spotify. Right? But if
Speaker 3:  Spotify is found to break the app store rules, that's a problem.
Speaker 3:  Right? And like I don't, and Spotify is real testy about that, but they
Speaker 3:  don't review every movie on Netflix. But Netflix, I'm assuming if Netflix
Speaker 3:  added a hardcore pornography section like Apple would like get
Speaker 3:  in the game. You know what I mean? So I think there's a little bit of back
Speaker 3:  and forth there.
Speaker 6:  Can you imagine if Netflix opens an alternative app marketplace
Speaker 6:  in Europe that's just hardcore
Speaker 3:  Like with ads in four in four 20 p at four 8:00 PM
Speaker 3:  Unless you
Speaker 6:  They're listen, we gotta get that RP up somehow. Like let's go
Speaker 3:  Every day
Speaker 3:  for a while. The HPO Go app was the singular
Speaker 3:  exception to the app store rules. Oh. Because it just had the late night
Speaker 3:  category. Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So it did have
Speaker 3:  Porn, it did well. Very like VHS level
Speaker 3:  pornography porn of
Speaker 7:  Your 14. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well
Speaker 7:  Port of you're 12.
Speaker 3:  No, I was going the other direction out. You want that number to go
Speaker 3:  up?
Speaker 3:  That's we're looking for up 18 is like the real That's the line.
Speaker 3:  That's the actual spot. Yeah. but it was a, it was like a huge except and
Speaker 3:  everyone knew it. It was just like unspoken. Well Apple wants the HBO Go
Speaker 3:  app here and HBO's like our whole catalog's here. Including that part of
Speaker 3:  it, huh? Yeah. Everyone was like, why don't worry about it.
Speaker 3:  Why is this here?
Speaker 7:  Don't
Speaker 3:  Worry about it. And no one would ever talk about it. It's gone now the this,
Speaker 3:  the late night skin and max section of the
Speaker 3:  max app does not exist. But that would, that was the level of loophole
Speaker 3:  that existed. Yeah. Now that's a free for all. But I, I'm just gonna come
Speaker 3:  back to game streaming. I think that's gonna be the same deal, right?
Speaker 3:  You have a catalog, we're gonna spot check the catalog. Like once you
Speaker 3:  get to Microsoft and you the entire Xbox library, there's just
Speaker 3:  no way Apple's like, we're enabling this globally and we're
Speaker 3:  gonna, they're enabling 'cause they think there's gonna be a, a pot of gold
Speaker 3:  at the end of that rainbow. Right? They're gonna find some way to charge
Speaker 3:  money inside of that app. Well they, they want it to be successful in the
Speaker 3:  iPhone. They
Speaker 7:  Also rolled out that thing, one of the payment structures I think in the
Speaker 7:  EU now as if you have over a million downloads, you have to start paying
Speaker 7:  like a monthly like 50 cent fee or something per download.
Speaker 7:  Maybe. it was per annual.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's once a year. Once
Speaker 7:  A year. And so like game streaming really takes off in the EU that could,
Speaker 7:  that could get pricey. They claim that most people aren't gonna have to pay
Speaker 7:  that though.
Speaker 3:  I think what they're anticipating is there's Xbox
Speaker 3:  Cloud gaming and that's an app on your phone. And to get Xbox Cloud gaming,
Speaker 3:  you gotta pay 40 bucks a month. I don know some number. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  20 bucks a month and then it
Speaker 7:  Starts at like 20. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And the best way to get that customer to convert is for them to
Speaker 3:  sign up with an in-app purchase in a subscription. And so Apple's just
Speaker 3:  gonna take that money. It is like, great, here's a thing we want you to do.
Speaker 3:  Apple
Speaker 6:  Looked at this and said people are gonna get this subscription one way or
Speaker 6:  another. Why don't we make them do it on our phone?
Speaker 3:  Why don't we take our 30% there? Do you think there's just a
Speaker 3:  line of people outside of Tim Cook's office that was like, just like ideas
Speaker 3:  to collect 30%. A hundred percent. You know, there's like the VIP line
Speaker 3:  for the executives that he knows. Like there's like water, there's a guy,
Speaker 3:  there's like people I know problems. I have to solve ideas to take
Speaker 3:  30% and just like one after another. They just have three different tickets
Speaker 3:  and they're, you know, his receptionist is like now serving
Speaker 3:  56 and ideas for 30% and someone just like shuffles in
Speaker 3:  this is my time to shine 80 Q was just like tapping his foot, just like waiting.
Speaker 3:  'cause that they want Apple to and Google. Now as
Speaker 3:  we know from Google's own antitrust trial, every button
Speaker 3:  you push on your phone is an opportunity for them to make money. Yep. And
Speaker 3:  if they don't make them money, they're mad. And I think that should bring
Speaker 3:  us to how mad they are at the European Union. Yes. Because you mentioned
Speaker 3:  the press release and we haven't even read the, we're mad lines in the press
Speaker 3:  release.
Speaker 6:  Well, so Apple's big story has always been
Speaker 6:  that only Apple can provide a
Speaker 6:  protected, good, curated successful
Speaker 6:  experience for everybody that makes everyone happy and
Speaker 6:  doesn't steal all of your information and kill you and leave you in a ditch.
Speaker 6:  Like those are the two options. It's it's Apple or ditch, right? Like
Speaker 6:  that's in Apple's world that's what it's,
Speaker 6:  there's never been any real evidence that that is the case. But here
Speaker 6:  we are. So with the, with the browser one,
Speaker 6:  one of the things that happens with the browser now is the first time you
Speaker 6:  open Safari after updating to iOS 17.4,
Speaker 6:  you're gonna get a choice screen, which we know for sure Apple hates. Apple
Speaker 6:  has testified under Oath, vivid hates choice screens. And you're gonna boot
Speaker 6:  up Safari and it's gonna say, what do you want to be your default browser?
Speaker 6:  This is again only in the EU and you're gonna be able to pick Safari or
Speaker 6:  a list of other browsers I think to be named later.
Speaker 6:  And Apple says this changes the result of the DMAs requirements and means
Speaker 6:  that EU users will be confronted with a list of default browsers before they
Speaker 6:  have the opportunity to understand the options available to them. The screen
Speaker 6:  also in interrupts EU users' experience the first time they open Safari
Speaker 6:  intending to navigate to a webpage. Yeah. It's just this like passive
Speaker 6:  aggressive, like this is a bunch of bullshit. Look what you guys are making
Speaker 6:  us do. This is stupid. I hate it. That's the vibe.
Speaker 6:  I love it.
Speaker 3:  Here's here's what I will point out one that is true. Yeah. And it's great
Speaker 3:  to just to go like I'm not saying you should do this. Go
Speaker 3:  get an AI voice clone of your favorite Apple executive. I'm happy to read
Speaker 3:  that copy. It's great.
Speaker 3:  Don't do that. That's totally legal and morally questionable. But in the
Speaker 3:  new EU app stores totally available to you.
Speaker 3:  The thing that's funny about that is Apple is a hundred percent correct in
Speaker 3:  the context of choice screens as we've known them up until now. They've been
Speaker 3:  putting choice screens on Android and Windows in the EU for 1 billion
Speaker 3:  years. And you know what, people are still using
Speaker 3:  Chrome. Yep.
Speaker 7:  They use choice screens in app like Mac oss
Speaker 7:  right now if you go and you open a new browser and you're like I wanna use
Speaker 7:  this one, they're like, you sure? Like they still double check that stuff.
Speaker 7:  So, I don't. Well
Speaker 3:  Every browser wants you be a default.
Speaker 7:  They all, yeah, they all want that. And Apple's always like, Hmm. Really?
Speaker 7:  So it, it's one of those things where I was like this, okay, I get it. You
Speaker 7:  guys are mad. But also choice is good that
Speaker 3:  Well no, but this, this is the thing. So the argument is the EU has in MA
Speaker 3:  like trying to get people on Windows and Android. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  To not not use, use Chrome or Google search
Speaker 3:  for 1 billion years. Like Yep. You, you open
Speaker 3:  it, it's like what search engine would you like to use? Your choices are
Speaker 3:  Google and 500 Choices and everyone's like don don't know Google. Or you
Speaker 3:  open up a thing and it's like what browser do you wanna use? Your choices
Speaker 3:  are inner Explorer Chrome or 5 billion other options. Bing. And they're like
Speaker 3:  Chrome. And that's very interesting in this context
Speaker 3:  because people are gonna open up their iPhones and it's gonna say do you
Speaker 3:  want to use Safari or Chrome? The thing people in the EU
Speaker 3:  have been picking over and over and over again for 1 billion years.
Speaker 7:  See I don't think that's what's gonna happen. I don think it's gonna be Safari,
Speaker 7:  Firefox Opera Arc
Speaker 7:  Duck Duck Go probably has a browser. Yeah. And then like when you
Speaker 7:  scroll down past the top there will be go
Speaker 6:  Like spelled wrong and in a
Speaker 3:  Different font. Yes. But the cutting edge of European politics is that
Speaker 3:  these choice trains are legally required to be randomized. Oh.
Speaker 3:  And everyone still picks Chrome.
Speaker 3:  I just want to be clear. People they've tried, they're like, what if it was
Speaker 3:  a random choice screen? What if the choice screen paid you $5 to not pick
Speaker 3:  Chrome and they're like Chrome. And so this is the first time you're gonna
Speaker 3:  get the experiment where the, the goal is to get people
Speaker 3:  away from the default to the other default that the
Speaker 3:  European Union has been trying to get people away from forever. And it, I
Speaker 3:  am dying to know what happens. I
Speaker 7:  Re like I hope somebody chooses Internet Explorer. I hope somebody go make
Speaker 7:  that app right now. Just
Speaker 3:  An old school Internet Explorer. Yeah. Like but the old Mac version with
Speaker 3:  like the the Aqua blue bars and the tabs. That would
Speaker 6:  Be beautiful. Absolutely. Same.
Speaker 7:  Sold.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  An old ass browser should be one of the options.
Speaker 3:  IE three is gonna be rocking and rolling on this thing. Wait,
Speaker 6:  Can I just read you one more saucy line from the press release? So this is,
Speaker 6:  this is the big like omnibus
Speaker 6:  giant press release from Apple announcing all of the changes that begrudgingly
Speaker 6:  made at the beginning of, or sorry, at the end of the first paragraph it
Speaker 6:  says across every change Apple is introducing new safeguards that reduce
Speaker 6:  but don't eliminate new risks. The DMA poses to EU users.
Speaker 6:  It's like the ddu, the DMA is trying to ruin your life and Apple is
Speaker 6:  doing its best to stop it but we can't solve everything.
Speaker 6:  Thanks the EU.
Speaker 3:  There's a real, that's so good dichotomy here, right? Like Apple's pissed
Speaker 3:  that EU is me, those European regulators are telling us how to work our
Speaker 3:  phone and then inside of that is buried because you're too stupid to figure
Speaker 3:  it out yourself. Right? And it's like,
Speaker 3:  I don't know man,
Speaker 3:  I have a Mac, I can do whatever I want on this Mac going
Speaker 3:  pretty good. You know, like the mitigations you put on the Mac working pretty
Speaker 3:  well. Why can't my phone work this way? And I,
Speaker 3:  I think that moralizing, and we should talk about this in the context of
Speaker 3:  like Vision Pro apps or we have talked it in the context of Vision Pro like
Speaker 3:  Netflix and YouTube just like not being there. Yeah. All those developers
Speaker 3:  are pissed it at, they do not have the goodwill to make this argument. And
Speaker 3:  people have headphones for a very, very long time and they know
Speaker 3:  that Apple's like more like they understand how the phones work. Like
Speaker 3:  Apple's moralizing is kinda like falling on deaf ears
Speaker 3:  weird. It's just a weird moment for Apple, which historically has gotten
Speaker 3:  developers to do whatever it wants.
Speaker 6:  That was actually one thing about this announcement that surprised me was
Speaker 6:  how little of an olive branch to developers it actually
Speaker 6:  appeared to be, you would think at this moment with
Speaker 6:  The Vision Pro coming out. And I think there's real momentum
Speaker 6:  behind the idea of not playing Apple's developer games anymore. I mean
Speaker 6:  it Netflix has been kind of an edge case for a long time. Spotify and Epic
Speaker 6:  have been mad for a long time, but like YouTube
Speaker 6:  and others saying we're gonna wait and see and the the line they all
Speaker 6:  give is we don't know what this platform is gonna be. I think Netflix co
Speaker 6:  CEO Yeah Greg
Speaker 7:  Peters this week was like, we'll see if like, if it actually takes off
Speaker 7:  we might consider it but we're not gonna invest time and money into something
Speaker 7:  that's not like guaranteed to be good. Right.
Speaker 6:  Which is a perfectly valid excuse but it iss also not what people say about
Speaker 6:  Apple. Like do you remember when the iPad came out and everyone on earth
Speaker 6:  like fell over themselves trying to get on the iPad app store? It's like
Speaker 6:  that is the thing Apple is very good at. And this is the
Speaker 6:  opposite of that. And So I would've thought in this moment Apple would've
Speaker 6:  said, what's what can we do that will in reality
Speaker 6:  or in appearance feel like kind of a love letter to
Speaker 6:  developers in the same way that like every five years they release a new
Speaker 6:  Mac Pro to remind people that they love people who have macros
Speaker 6:  and there just didn't seem to be any of that. Well
Speaker 7:  When you're an effective monopoly, you don't have to do
Speaker 7:  that. You don't have to play nice because they're still one of the biggest
Speaker 7:  app stores. They're still one of the biggest platforms. They can just say,
Speaker 7:  yeah, do it. Netflix is still gonna have to be on the iPhone, it's still
Speaker 7:  gonna have to be on the iPad because those are huge. Right? So like this
Speaker 7:  is definitely one of those moments where I feel like 10, 15 years from now,
Speaker 7:  if there's some additional turns, we're gonna look back on this moment and
Speaker 7:  be like, oh this is where Apple really started to like it's hubris started
Speaker 7:  to show and it really started to have like kind of a decline. Yeah. But I
Speaker 7:  don't know if that's actually gonna happen, but I could certainly see talking
Speaker 7:  about it in a podcast 15 years from
Speaker 3:  Now. Well I think one that we should end it by figurine out.
Speaker 3:  Like how, how do we measure success here? Like here's the thing, I think
Speaker 3:  we have a big team in Europe and they are very quick to
Speaker 3:  remind me that one, they get more holidays, they get healthcare,
Speaker 3:  they're always on top of that. And then, you know, they pay nothing for internet
Speaker 3:  service. Like you wanna buy broadband in Europe, you're not paying as much
Speaker 3:  money as if you wanna buy broadband in the United States. And it's faster.
Speaker 3:  Like,
Speaker 7:  But no air conditioning. What's that about? Whatcha are you
Speaker 3:  Guys doing over there? Well, climate change has arrived for the Europeans.
Speaker 3:  We ran a great story several years ago about air conditioners in France.
Speaker 3:  We'll, we'll, we'll, we'll we'll dig it up and link it in the show notes.
Speaker 3:  But like there are ways to measure like how
Speaker 3:  European regulations raise or lower prices or lead to different outcomes.
Speaker 3:  Some of them are worse than here. Like there are some
Speaker 3:  aspects of like European regulation that have led to less
Speaker 3:  vibrant marketplaces for sure. Like we have big tech companies.
Speaker 3:  Europe does not, that's just a, that's just true.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You can read all kinds of academic literature on why that has happened,
Speaker 3:  but it mostly is because you can just go start a Google
Speaker 3:  in a garage here and then maybe take over a giant market,
Speaker 3:  right? You you can just monopoly your way up to that position if you want
Speaker 3:  here and we won't stop you. And in Europe they just like don't, it doesn't
Speaker 3:  happen that same way labor unions sit on the boards of big European companies.
Speaker 3:  That doesn't happen here. So you just end up, you can make lists of pros
Speaker 3:  and cons, but in this case I think we don't know what success looks like.
Speaker 3:  don don't know that the Europeans don't, they're just like, competition is
Speaker 3:  good, which is great. I love it. I'm all about competition.
Speaker 3:  But it's like at the end of this is it you need to
Speaker 3:  download a different app store to get Spotify and Netflix in the Kindle app
Speaker 3:  and then there's a bunch of weird stuff in the Apple App store. Like honestly
Speaker 3:  is that success?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think success is, oh I can just go buy a book or an
Speaker 7:  audio book or a movie or whatever and just do it and just be done
Speaker 7:  with it on the app. I choose like, I think that is, I think that is a, a
Speaker 7:  victory and oh I can just go have real chrome on my
Speaker 7:  iPhone
Speaker 3:  Agree there.
Speaker 7:  So So I think Yeah, I think, I think we're gonna pretty quickly see the victories.
Speaker 7:  I think what's gonna be interesting is, is all the economics afterwards and,
Speaker 7:  and, and then we'll we'll see the losses of like, oh we just have like a
Speaker 7:  whole really gross revenge porn app. Yeah. Just
Speaker 7:  hanging out on a store and, and now we're gonna be having to like
Speaker 7:  write a bunch of stories about this app store who refuses to take down the
Speaker 7:  revenge porn app. You know, that's gonna suck, that's gonna happen. don,
Speaker 7:  don't do that. Don't do it people. But when you do, I hate you
Speaker 7:  just know that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I I think figurine out like what does it look like if this worked?
Speaker 3:  Like what are the tangible improvements we want to have with our experiences
Speaker 3:  with our phones and yeah, I just wanna be able to buy stuff. I
Speaker 3:  want the user experience of buying content to be simpler and easier and not
Speaker 3:  feel like Apple's just taking a 30% cut from whatever creator.
Speaker 3:  That's pretty good. Yeah, I'll, I'll I'll take that. On the flip side, if
Speaker 3:  to do that you do need to go download a separate app store for every
Speaker 3:  kind of content app that's, that's like obviously worse. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  I, I think Apple is leaning towards it's gonna be chaos and you're gonna
Speaker 3:  want to be here anyway and I think we're all leaning towards the pressure
Speaker 3:  on Apple will be enough to change the actual app store and make it better
Speaker 3:  mean you. 'cause that's what competition does. I, I don't know where we're
Speaker 3:  gonna net out. I would just say like at this moment, regardless of how you
Speaker 3:  think, you should just think about like what does success for this thing
Speaker 3:  look like and how do you get there as opposed to it's definitely gonna win
Speaker 3:  or it's definitely gonna be a disaster. 'cause like I said, they've been
Speaker 3:  putting choice screens on Windows and Android for years. Like
Speaker 3:  one decade of antitrust regulation in Europe
Speaker 3:  around Google has resulted in no change.
Speaker 3:  None
Speaker 8:  Chrome's just
Speaker 3:  Great.
Speaker 3:  I think it is gonna be wild to put the Chrome icon on a choice screen and
Speaker 3:  an iPhone and see if people still pick
Speaker 6:  Safari. That's a really interesting test case here, right? Like the, the
Speaker 6:  thing that I think is interesting here is we've been talking sort of in
Speaker 6:  theory for a long time about whether people would just pick the
Speaker 6:  app store both developers and users because it's easier, right? Like
Speaker 6:  I, I think you can make a very compelling case that all of the stuff that
Speaker 6:  it's going to entail to go to the website of an app marketplace,
Speaker 6:  download it, go through the hoops to get it installed, say yes on that scary
Speaker 6:  screen that's like you're downloading another app store, you might die and
Speaker 6:  then download the other apps, do all the stuff there, maintain those things
Speaker 6:  like that might be arduous enough that most people will continue to choose
Speaker 6:  the app store, which is what Apple has said all along is the case. And now
Speaker 6:  we get to find out like that's the thing I'm excited about. And and the Chrome
Speaker 6:  example is a perfect one because Google's whole defense in
Speaker 6:  its antitrust case has been people use us because we're the best product
Speaker 6:  and we know because when people get to choose, even when they're bullied
Speaker 6:  into choosing, they choose us. And that's a pretty good
Speaker 6:  antitrust defense. Or at least it has seemed like one so far. And in
Speaker 6:  this case, apple is is gonna have to put up or shut up along the
Speaker 6:  same lines like we're about to find out how many people use Safari on purpose
Speaker 6:  and I think that's cool.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 3:  Me. All right. That's a great place to end it 'cause I am dying to the answer
Speaker 3:  and we just won't know until our European friends tell us
Speaker 3:  we we gotta take a break. We're this show is already way over. We'll be right
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 3:  We're back. We, we still have a lot talk. This show's gonna go it's five
Speaker 3:  hours. Yeah, but there's like a lot of streaming news this week. Cranz,
Speaker 3:  what's going on?
Speaker 7:  Okay, so Netflix had their earnings but before their earnings they had a
Speaker 7:  bunch of other stuff happen. So first up, Scott Staub, who was the
Speaker 7:  chairman for Netflix Films, announced he was leaving leaving, that was the
Speaker 7:  day before. And, and Scott is like not the only
Speaker 7:  reason that Netflix has a really successful film slate, but was
Speaker 7:  a big reason that they were like the most nominated film studio for three
Speaker 7:  years in a row. So, so him leaving Ooh surprising
Speaker 7:  then the morning before their earnings,
Speaker 7:  they announced that WWE Monday night Raw was gonna be coming
Speaker 7:  exclusively to Netflix and not only Netflix in the United States, but
Speaker 7:  world worldwide, which is apparently very huge according to
Speaker 7:  Chris Welch, our resident. Like WWE Superfan. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I had to, I had to go to him repeatedly this week being like, explain this
Speaker 7:  wrestling thing to me. But so, so those are both
Speaker 7:  like big things. And then they announced at their, after
Speaker 7:  during their earnings report, they announced that they were gonna be getting
Speaker 7:  rid of the 1199 basic plan, which they had already
Speaker 7:  been like phasing out I believe in the United States and a couple other places.
Speaker 7:  Now it's going away everywhere before, like you couldn't
Speaker 7:  even subscribe to it, but if you had already subscribed, you were fine. Now
Speaker 7:  you're gonna get bumped either to 6 99, which is the ad for, which is the
Speaker 7:  ad version or you're gonna get bumped to 1549, which is the
Speaker 7:  ad free version. Oh my gosh. So it just got a lot more expensive
Speaker 7:  basically to, to go without ads on Netflix. I
Speaker 6:  Just like to say
Speaker 7:  That's the real, just,
Speaker 6:  I just like to say I I theorized that that
Speaker 6:  was going to happen on this podcast. Yeah, you did. And oh my God, have I
Speaker 6:  been right? That they're just going to price you to pieces if you
Speaker 6:  want ad free and you want 4K and they're gonna keep the
Speaker 6:  ad, the, the ad based one cheap and eventually they're just going to
Speaker 6:  shove everybody down to that one.
Speaker 7:  And that's not entirely their plan, but that's a big part of the plan for
Speaker 7:  them. They've got about 23, it sounds like. They've got about 23 million
Speaker 7:  monthly active users who are currently on advertising. They really, really
Speaker 7:  like it. All those people love it 'cause they pay 6 99 and they get two screens
Speaker 7:  and they can watch it, but now they're gonna have to pay 1549 if they want
Speaker 7:  those two screens and no ads. And then if they want four screens
Speaker 7:  and 4K, they have to pay 2299. And then for each
Speaker 7:  additional user, so like if when Max goes
Speaker 7:  to college NELI next week,
Speaker 7:  7 99 per user, per month for tho those, those
Speaker 7:  higher ones, which
Speaker 3:  Is just, I can, I, I find it disgusting that they charge
Speaker 3:  per user and per screen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's, it's a lot. I'm, I'm really curious. Like
Speaker 3:  Even the cable companies weren't like per screen.
Speaker 6:  I I mean they kind of were, you had to get another box if you wanted another
Speaker 6:  screen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no, they were, yeah. You had to get the box and they'd be like, that
Speaker 7:  box is a hundred dollars.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well, basic cable was not per screen.
Speaker 7:  I never,
Speaker 3:  You could put, you could basic, you could splitter a basic cable subscription
Speaker 3:  to 5,000 screens.
Speaker 7:  I, I never lived in a region where I could do that. It was always I had to
Speaker 7:  have the little box.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  NELI, you're definitely the kind of person who would've like pirated TBS
Speaker 6:  for your whole neighborhood growing up like that. That feels right.
Speaker 3:  I am 100% the kind of person who figured out how to steal cable in the dorm
Speaker 3:  and met his wife that way. Aw, I'm just letting you know that I had a little
Speaker 3:  coax crimper. The, the whole thing. It's a, it was a drop. Gee,
Speaker 3:  I just looked in the ceiling, you know, I was, there it is. Let's see what
Speaker 3:  happens.
Speaker 7:  It was a real cable guy moment.
Speaker 3:  Sorry. I was a cool cable guy. All right.
Speaker 6:  But wait, Alex, you and I had basically the same exact reaction to this,
Speaker 6:  which is just that Netflix is just a whole ass cable company now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. So, so Netflix is effectively cable because Ted Sarandos, the
Speaker 7:  CEO, Greg Peters, the other CEO and the CFO, we're all like, well, yeah,
Speaker 7:  we have all this secondary programming, IE the suits, the young
Speaker 7:  Sheldon, the stuff they're not making and they just buy a license for, and
Speaker 7:  that makes them a lot of money. And with advertising that makes them more
Speaker 7:  money than, than original programming where they're having to spend billions
Speaker 7:  of their own dollars to make it. And even that original programming is the
Speaker 7:  most of their tops watch stuff. It's not all of their top watch
Speaker 7:  stuff. And your business, it's cheaper to buy young
Speaker 7:  Sheldon and and throw that up to your 200 something
Speaker 7:  million.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The 45th time CBS has sold young Sheldon, they're selling it for cheap.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And you could still watch Young Sheldon on Paramount Plus if you want. 'cause
Speaker 7:  I do. I don't, I watch lots of things there. Not young
Speaker 3:  Suits. Can I just say Suits is a, a scorge upon the Republic. It's a danger
Speaker 3:  to young people everywhere. It's
Speaker 6:  Terrible. I love suits. I'm so ashamed of how much I like that show.
Speaker 3:  Suits is the stupidest show in the entire world here. My,
Speaker 7:  Is this the lawyer you talking? Well,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's unwatchable if you are a lawyer, but my little
Speaker 3:  niece is her first semester of college, she was in her first finals in college
Speaker 3:  and she texted me and Becky and was like, should I be a lawyer?
Speaker 3:  'cause it's first finals and she's a STEM major. And I was like, are you
Speaker 3:  just studying for your chem final? And she's like, no. I was watching Suits
Speaker 3:  and I thought, if this doesn't go well. And we were both like, no,
Speaker 3:  do not be a lawyer because he wants suits.
Speaker 7:  It's gonna be like,
Speaker 3:  It's not like that. If you take one thing for
Speaker 3:  my entire career at The Verge, it's that being a lawyer is not
Speaker 3:  like being on suits
Speaker 6:  Unlike the West Wing, which is a perfect representation of what it's like
Speaker 6:  to be
Speaker 3:  In politics. No, it's closer. Like the people in
Speaker 3:  politics would like their lives to be. Like the West Wing lawyers
Speaker 3:  are not like, I wish it was more like suits
Speaker 6:  There. I will say I've, I've only watched like the first season of Suits
Speaker 6:  so far, and a I love it very much. And b no one ever does any
Speaker 6:  lawyering in that whole show. I don't think.
Speaker 7:  Well 'cause he, they
Speaker 6:  Gives cases. Is that what the lawyer, the
Speaker 3:  Entire, the entire plot is that he, Meghan Markle has to find cases for the
Speaker 3:  guy. Whatcha talking about?
Speaker 3:  This show's horrible. I watched five episodes. I was like, never again did
Speaker 3:  you?
Speaker 7:  But like Gina Torres,
Speaker 3:  I'm saying I'm gonna cancel Netflix. They keep making Americans watch suits.
Speaker 7:  But what's funny is that USA, which is part of Universal,
Speaker 7:  which is owns Peacock and I think was maybe an investor in, in
Speaker 7:  US at some point. I don't remember.
Speaker 3:  No, no, I will, I have a better disclosure about Suits.
Speaker 7:  Okay, go for it.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Right. Suits was on, I'm gonna drink while I want Suits was on USA,
Speaker 3:  right? Yeah. It's owned by NBCUniversal. NBCUniversal is an investor in Fox
Speaker 3:  Media, European Company, whatever. The real disclosure is that Suits was
Speaker 3:  the lead into Mr. Robot and I hosted the Mr. Robot after show
Speaker 3:  for many years and I had to watch the tail end of every episode of
Speaker 3:  Suits waiting for Mr. Robot to start so we could have the Mr. Robot Show.
Speaker 3:  And then, do you see what I'm saying? This is a real problem.
Speaker 3:  This is my antipathy towards suits.
Speaker 7:  That's fair. I I would have that too. I just, it was fine. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Mr. Robot's great though, and I don't know if you can still watch the after
Speaker 3:  show. We, we taped it in the studio right over there. Emily, Emily Oida was
Speaker 3:  my co-host one season. It was great. Oh, that's awesome. Megan Fe when actually
Speaker 3:  was my cohost the second season, Russell Brandon was there.
Speaker 7:  I would leave it on while I was writing my recaps of Mr. Robot.
Speaker 3:  Fun. But Netflix
Speaker 6:  Netflix, but
Speaker 7:  Netflix Netflix back to Netflix. Netflix back to Netflix, back to Netflix.
Speaker 7:  Netflix.
Speaker 6:  Like I I I went through and Alex you wrote a really good piece about this
Speaker 6:  basically Netflix cable turn. Yeah. And especially after the WWE
Speaker 6:  thing, but it's kind of amazing. You make the list of like, okay, what is
Speaker 6:  on cable? There's, you know, reality TV and all this sort of
Speaker 6:  like, nonsense background TV that people watch all day. Like Netflix
Speaker 6:  actually has a ton of that. It doesn't talk a lot about it, but it has a
Speaker 6:  ton of it. It's deep in the dating show game now. It is like, it's pretty
Speaker 6:  good at this game. You have the, the sort of endlessly re
Speaker 6:  watchable reruns of stuff. Netflix, that's the suits and kind of stuff you're
Speaker 6:  talking about. And actually Netflix is unusually good at making that stuff
Speaker 6:  popular again. You have the prestige stuff, Netflix has lots of that.
Speaker 6:  You have movie channels. Netflix has lots of that. And then what's the last
Speaker 6:  thing is sports. And sports is the one thing. Netflix. So for so long
Speaker 6:  was like, oh, we we're probably like live and sports don't really feel
Speaker 6:  like they're us. And now Netflix is just fully all in on both live
Speaker 6:  and sports.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And specifically wrestling, which is like extremely lucrative. I
Speaker 7:  don't think it's probably, I have no idea actually if it's as lucrative as
Speaker 7:  baseball or
Speaker 6:  Basketball. Oh, it's
Speaker 7:  Super lucrative. but it, it makes a ton of money and it does very, very well
Speaker 7:  in the United States. And one of the things that the, the people at WWE were
Speaker 7:  talking about was they were really excited because now they were gonna be
Speaker 7:  able to m like spread it internationally a lot easier instead of having to
Speaker 7:  make all these different deals and compete with local wrestling
Speaker 7:  leagues and all of that stuff. They can just be like, nah, anybody can just
Speaker 7:  turn on Netflix in any country and they can just watch Roman Reigns because
Speaker 7:  that's like the big wrestling guy.
Speaker 6:  Now. Did, did Chris Welch teach you about Roman reins this week? To be honest,
Speaker 6:  yes. Yes. Love
Speaker 7:  That. I
Speaker 6:  Was like, I love this for you.
Speaker 7:  I was like, who's, who's like the rock now of, of WWE E and he's like Roman
Speaker 7:  reigns. I was like, thank you. Wow. I actually feel
Speaker 6:  Like you would love wrestling.
Speaker 7:  I like, I like the, the idea of wrestling and I loved Glow,
Speaker 7:  but wrestling itself I haven't liked since I was a kid. And then once
Speaker 7:  I worked at a company that got bodied by a professional wrestler Oh yeah,
Speaker 7:  that's fair. That that reduced my life. That would do it my, or not my life
Speaker 7:  that reduced my like of, of wrestling. but it's cool. I like that they slap
Speaker 7:  each other. They like slide across their
Speaker 3:  Ring. I like that they slap each other.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And then they like have big dramatic moments. I'm like, yeah, this
Speaker 3:  Is great. Yeah, Z would like it. Like yeah, in theory, this is in
Speaker 7:  Theory, but like it's shot like garbage. It looks so ugly.
Speaker 3:  I don't know. I don't watch it. My freshman year roommate in college had
Speaker 3:  a both a Stacey Keebler poster and a rock poster. Oh yeah.
Speaker 7:  Wall that was like my wall. My brother had had lots of like the
Speaker 7:  rock and then Stone Cold Steve Austin in his room. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  what's up with all these posters of half naked men all over your
Speaker 3:  Walls? Yeah. It was a real distinction between the Stacey keyboard and the,
Speaker 3:  I was, that
Speaker 7:  Was when, that was when
Speaker 3:  Stacey I think was wearing more clothes in the poster.
Speaker 7:  The women started appear on my Brother's Wall shortly after.
Speaker 3:  Look, he was very happy with his fandom. Yeah. By the way, both
Speaker 3:  Chris Welch and Casey Newton, huge wrestling fans. Huge. And I have managed
Speaker 3:  none of it. It just doesn't look like anything to me. I love. but it is huge.
Speaker 3:  And I think from what I understand, wrestling fans have had a hard
Speaker 3:  time of it because there was a dedicated wrestling app that got merged in
Speaker 3:  some other streamer that has been a disaster. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  A lot of it's been like on Peacock. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  You know,
Speaker 7:  It's peacock
Speaker 3:  And I think they're very happy that Netflix might try that. That's the read
Speaker 3:  I get. What if Netflix does a good job is like people are excited about it
Speaker 3:  and
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it sounds like Netflix is very interested in like doing a lot of
Speaker 7:  the, the extra programming around it, the after shows and the, let's do a
Speaker 7:  whole, let's explain to Alex and NELI and everybody else who Roman Reigns
Speaker 7:  is kind of documentaries and maybe I'll watch one 'cause Who knows
Speaker 3:  Take suits off your service. I'll watch anything Netflix.
Speaker 3:  I'm just saying do it for America.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think Netflix
Speaker 6:  is going to end up looking really smart here. It's like
Speaker 6:  the, there's been rumors forever that every time TV rights come up, Netflix
Speaker 6:  is supposedly gonna bid this. There was a big story about it for Formula
Speaker 6:  One because Drive Is Survive is so successful. They're like, oh, maybe they'll
Speaker 6:  just buy the rights. But then they did the weird thing where it was just
Speaker 6:  like that golf tournament with a bunch of golfers and a bunch of F1 stars
Speaker 6:  and that was their big first foray into live sports.
Speaker 6:  It wasn't good, but I guess it did. Well I don know, but this is
Speaker 6:  like, what was it, a $5 billion, like 10 year long deal
Speaker 6:  or something like, this is serious.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's, it's $5 billion. It's 10 years. After five years they
Speaker 7:  have the right to be like, nevermind. Interesting. And they get everything
Speaker 7:  just fully packaged and sent to them. They're like, like W
Speaker 7:  WWE has done kind of everything. It's very turnkey for Netflix, similar to
Speaker 7:  a lot of their secondary licensing stuff. So it's like, on the one hand
Speaker 7:  I love original programming. I love thoughtful new
Speaker 7:  original programming. On the other hand, we've talked a lot about how that
Speaker 7:  was just gonna stop when advertising became more popular. So it makes
Speaker 7:  sense that Netflix kind of becomes USA network or
Speaker 7:  t and t Yeah. Whatever network you were really fond of. Spike TV was the
Speaker 7:  one I keep thinking about. Oh boy. And, and that's just
Speaker 7:  what it's gonna be now. And it, it's like a good value
Speaker 7:  proposition for most people. You spend 6 99 a month
Speaker 7:  and you get cable. Yeah. Effectively on demand. I see
Speaker 6:  It slightly differently. And to me it feels like the, the risk for Netflix
Speaker 6:  as far as I can tell, is just that it's gonna get out
Speaker 6:  over its skis trying to do everything all at once.
Speaker 6:  And like it's, it's deep into gaming now. It's doing live sports.
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 3:  Hate that
Speaker 6:  By the way. It's, it's doing all of these dating shows like
Speaker 6:  Netflix for a while felt
Speaker 6:  sort of understandable and focused in a way that I think worked for it. And
Speaker 6:  it was, it was doing a streaming service
Speaker 6:  and only a streaming service in a time when lots of other companies were
Speaker 6:  trying to do a streaming service and lots of other things. And it actually
Speaker 6:  helped Netflix and hurt those companies. And now Netflix is trying
Speaker 6:  to sort of do too many things. It feels like,
Speaker 7:  I think that's the strategy for Netflix though, because think about it. If
Speaker 7:  you are right now, I believe the second largest streaming service
Speaker 7:  after Amazon Prime, which kind of has big asterisk next to
Speaker 6:  It's Yeah, it's the largest streaming service. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So, so Netflix is effectively the largest and they're just under the
Speaker 7:  impression, they're like, yeah, you'll probably, you might go get Max, you
Speaker 7:  might go get Disney, you might go get Paramount, LOL, you might get Peacock,
Speaker 7:  whatever, but you're gonna get Netflix. And so we're going to like,
Speaker 7:  you're gonna spend at least $6 and 99 cents a month with us. So just
Speaker 7:  look, look at all the crap we can give you. Yeah, we can give you a bunch
Speaker 7:  of stuff.
Speaker 3:  They're the Microsoft word of streaming services.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And, and So I, that's why I said they're like the t and t, they're,
Speaker 7:  they're just the basic cable. It's just all of basic cable now in one place.
Speaker 7:  And the, the app is terrible. So you're constantly, anytime you open
Speaker 7:  it on your iPad, you just get a bunch of games and you don't wanna play those
Speaker 7:  on your iPad on a like fucking Netflix app. But you're gonna, because
Speaker 7:  they keep pushing that on you. And that's really annoying. But that, that
Speaker 7:  rant goes into, I think Netflix next turn is they need to figure out their
Speaker 7:  recommendation engine. It's really bad right now. They need to figure out
Speaker 7:  their, their user interface. It's not great right now. They've got a lot
Speaker 7:  of work to do to compete in that space because eventually if
Speaker 7:  all it does is repeatedly recommend Suits to NELI, he is
Speaker 7:  gonna unsubscribe and for good reason.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna do it right now. Yeah. You show me Suits one more time.
Speaker 3:  My Microsoft, this is Yeah. Your, this is why I mentioned Microsoft Word.
Speaker 3:  I know people at Microsoft would love to take stuff outta the toolbar.
Speaker 3:  They can't because Microsoft Word is not focused. It's not one thing.
Speaker 3:  It is, it's everything. A million things to a million different people. And
Speaker 3:  it now, it just has to be a million things. So if Netflix wants to be
Speaker 3:  suits and live TV and wrestling and
Speaker 3:  F1 docuseries and games, like that's a lot of things.
Speaker 3:  And like it just has to be all the things to all the people all the time.
Speaker 3:  Yep. I do think that like it's, I agree that
Speaker 3:  it, it's becoming, it's becoming more and more of what looks like a cable
Speaker 3:  bundle. The part where like they're doing the worst of cable
Speaker 3:  pricing per screen. That's why people started to hate the cable companies.
Speaker 3:  Yep. Fully why people started to hate the cable companies and like that's
Speaker 3:  the danger.
Speaker 7:  And, and they're just really hoping 'cause that, that per screen is only
Speaker 7:  for the ad free version. So, so under that it's, it's two,
Speaker 7:  that's it. And you, you get two screens and if somebody else in your family
Speaker 7:  is like, oh, I also wanna watch 'cause you have a big family, then you better
Speaker 7:  go get another subscription. And and that's the, the ad version,
Speaker 7:  the ad free version is the 7 99 a month. So, I can see them being like,
Speaker 7:  well You don't wanna deal with that. It's a dollar cheaper and you just have
Speaker 7:  to sit through some ads. And I personally will hate that because I cut
Speaker 7:  the cable in like 2007.
Speaker 3:  I can't get rid of one streaming service. I keep suggesting like, let's get
Speaker 3:  rid of this one. Then Becky's like, some comedy special I wanna watch is
Speaker 3:  on that one next month. And it's like, oh, that's
Speaker 7:  Criterion is so good. You can't get rid of Criterion.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Wait, that is actually a perfect segue into the other streaming news
Speaker 6:  this week that I thought was interesting, which is that Verizon made another
Speaker 6:  one of, its like we're bundling a bunch of streaming services together, announcements.
Speaker 6:  And then there was a story in the information where a bunch of Verizon people
Speaker 6:  were talking about like, we think that the value add here
Speaker 6:  is to be the management tool on top of all of your streaming services.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, well that's cable and that sucks. Like, you know, what I
Speaker 6:  want is like a harder company to get ahold of to deal with all of my stuff.
Speaker 6:  But I think the, the next turn for all of this with these companies
Speaker 6:  is like the rest of the ecosystem around this. Like,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna start to get more and more apps that are like, we're just gonna
Speaker 6:  make it easier for you to search stuff and we're gonna get all these companies,
Speaker 6:  Verizon's doing it, Amazon's doing it, Apple's doing it that are like, just
Speaker 6:  use us to subscribe to these streaming services. And I
Speaker 6:  actually think a, a real value to provide is
Speaker 6:  like we will just give you the button you can tap to turn
Speaker 6:  on your subscription or turn it off to a thing. And I think there's gonna
Speaker 6:  be real competition around that. Like, I just signed up for Paramount Plus
Speaker 6:  so that I can watch three weeks of football and God
Speaker 6:  help me if I get to that fourth week and accidentally pay for another month
Speaker 6:  of Paramount Plus. And there's gonna be a crazy competition to give me
Speaker 6:  a button that I can press to turn off Paramount. Plus
Speaker 7:  I could have just shared my login with you.
Speaker 6:  I don't want your login. Be careful. It's don don't. It's gonna be like,
Speaker 6:  oh, do you wanna watch
Speaker 3:  Star Rek? don Don, if you do that, don't. Then Kevin, Kevin Costner comes
Speaker 3:  to your house and shoots you,
Speaker 7:  Puts his hat back on, walks the
Speaker 3:  Door. That's why people have Paramount Plus. Yeah. S Watch Yellowstone. Oh
Speaker 3:  yeah. The show where there's dad
Speaker 7:  Who murders people of
Speaker 3:  Murder. Murdery dad. There's the good son who died.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Who murdered people.
Speaker 3:  He was also kind of murdery drunk daughter Murdery. Yeah. And then Call of
Speaker 3:  Duty son
Speaker 7:  And there's a, there's another son 'cause who's only like a half son.
Speaker 7:  All murdery though. Yes.
Speaker 3:  No, but the Call of Duty son is like the funniest part of that whole show.
Speaker 3:  They're like, what if one
Speaker 3:  guy's, I'm not saying I didn't like it, I'm just saying like every couple
Speaker 3:  episodes are like, do some Call of Duty shit. And he's like, all right dad.
Speaker 3:  And he like,
Speaker 7:  He like puts on, he puts on like all his old Army gear and is like, let's,
Speaker 7:  let's mess him up.
Speaker 3:  It's like, see you later. I guess that just, just Call of Duty stuff
Speaker 14:  Montana.
Speaker 3:  That's good. I look, I I wish you well.
Speaker 3:  Don't fuck with the Duttons. We gotta take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we're back five hour Vergecast. It's
Speaker 3:  happening. We're we're gonna do quick lightning round. Okay. I will say
Speaker 3:  we've had some listeners offer to personally sponsor the
Speaker 3:  lightning round, which is money that we will figure out how to accept
Speaker 3:  in the absence of these ignorant brands who won't pay us millions of dollars
Speaker 3:  to have the lightning round sponsored by the refrigerator companies. Individual
Speaker 3:  virtue listeners have offered us upwards of
Speaker 3:  $45 and we're gonna, we will find a way to take that money.
Speaker 3:  However, this week is the 40th anniversary of the
Speaker 3:  Macintosh and listener
Speaker 3:  Samar Sika. It is his 40th birthday. Aw. And so he offered to sponsor.
Speaker 3:  But because it's your birthday, we're we're giving you this one in the house,
Speaker 6:  But only this one Happy
Speaker 7:  Birthday. But
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The next time you, you march into your
Speaker 3:  CMOs office, you get us that check. You hear me? That's,
Speaker 3:  that's your goal for your 41st birthday.
Speaker 6:  Get
Speaker 3:  Us that check.
Speaker 3:  Happy birthday man. Thank you for listening. Thank you. It is very funny
Speaker 3:  that people have offered individually sponsored lightning round. I love it.
Speaker 3:  And we probably will find a way to take that money just because it is hilarious.
Speaker 7:  I love you
Speaker 3:  Guys and we'll do something good with it. All right. Lightning round. The
Speaker 3:  Mac, by the way, did turn 40 David, you had Walt on the, on the Wednesday
Speaker 3:  show.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Walt Mossberg, who has, I would say more stories about
Speaker 6:  the history of Apple and the Macintosh than any single
Speaker 6:  other person on planet Earth just came on and told us some stories about
Speaker 6:  the Mac. It was super fun. It was. He's a good hang. He has been on The Vergecast
Speaker 6:  in a long time. Yes. And he told me he's personally very upset with you about
Speaker 6:  it. We cut that out. But he said a lot of really mean things about you.
Speaker 6:  So we're gonna have to have him back soon.
Speaker 3:  I will. I listened to it. I was on a plane. I listened to it when I landed.
Speaker 3:  And David, I'm very disappointed in you that you did not know what the Apple
Speaker 3:  two Gs was. I owned an Apple two Gs. It was a very weird computer
Speaker 3:  and it was, Walt mentioned that he'd owned one and you're like, I've never
Speaker 3:  heard of it. And I was like screaming at my
Speaker 6:  Phone. I literally Googled it. 'cause I was like, is he saying the name wrong?
Speaker 6:  Like I thought I pretty much knew most and no, he was right. I was wrong.
Speaker 6:  I've
Speaker 3:  Never felt what it's like to be The Vergecast listener more than I was in
Speaker 3:  the waiting for an Uber just like screaming at my phone. You don't know what
Speaker 3:  that is. Yeah. And that I won't, I refuse to learn.
Speaker 3:  Sorry. That's right.
Speaker 6:  That's how I feel.
Speaker 3:  All right. That
Speaker 3:  Cranz, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 7:  I got two actually. So I. I'll, I'll go serious first. Okay.
Speaker 7:  There's a baby that's covered in technology.
Speaker 3:  This
Speaker 6:  Is the serious one
Speaker 3:  Is the baby. Okay.
Speaker 7:  It's not a real baby. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Good. Important note. There's,
Speaker 7:  There's a a, they're, they're doing fashion in, in France
Speaker 7:  and Scap, the fashion house was showing off their, all their new looks.
Speaker 7:  And a woman comes out and she's wearing this gorgeous gown covered in
Speaker 7:  like Intel fans from like
Speaker 3:  2000. Yes. Look at this dress. Is
Speaker 7:  It, it's sick. It looks so cool. And then someone else
Speaker 7:  came out in an outfit called The Mother, which
Speaker 7:  appeared to be primarily like a, a white top and like a white white
Speaker 7:  bottom. And then they were holding a baby made out of
Speaker 7:  old technology. Yeah. And it was just, it's a beautiful baby. You
Speaker 7:  gotta, when when you're not driving, take a moment. Go look at the baby.
Speaker 7:  I I love it.
Speaker 6:  This is a pull over your car and Google this thing like whatever you're thinking
Speaker 6:  in your mind right now. The reality is 50 times wilder
Speaker 6:  than that.
Speaker 3:  Both of these models are making catwalk face. Yeah. You know,
Speaker 7:  But holding the tech
Speaker 3:  Baby. But in the context of these outfits and that baby
Speaker 3:  totally recontextualize catwalk face, like Yeah. Just a what is going
Speaker 3:  on here? What
Speaker 7:  Sometimes you just got a baby made a tech.
Speaker 6:  If you were listening to this and you could acquire one of these outfits
Speaker 6:  and bring it to us, one of us will wear it on The Vergecast. I promise
Speaker 3:  Rosemary said the toddler was a reference to the alien movies.
Speaker 7:  Rosemary is the creative director for Capparelli. Yeah. So Daniel
Speaker 7:  Rosemary, he also said that now that the technology I grew up with is
Speaker 7:  antiquated, that so it's so antiquated that it's almost
Speaker 7:  difficult to source a certain vi as certain vintage fabrics and embellishment.
Speaker 7:  So that's why he did it. 'cause he was basically like, it's really hard to
Speaker 7:  find old fans for Intel processors and, and buddy
Speaker 7:  you just, you just get, get a new set of friends.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I got a closet full of laptops that would say otherwise.
Speaker 7:  Like we, we got you The Verge listeners. Got you. Like you need sourcing
Speaker 7:  for this stuff. You can pay us instead of whoever you paid for all of this
Speaker 6:  Technology. Have you seen our gadget closet come
Speaker 3:  20 years? Dress made entirely of USBA cables.
Speaker 3:  We got you. Calm. Now you want to talk about measuring success. All right,
Speaker 3:  David, I love that. What's yours?
Speaker 6:  Mine is that The Pixel nine leaks are already starting to come. So
Speaker 6:  presumably we're gonna get a glimpse of The Pixel nine in May or June
Speaker 6:  whenever Google io is, and then the real thing in the fall.
Speaker 6:  But the leaks are already starting to come out because Google is just
Speaker 6:  completely incapable of hiding a product. It appears
Speaker 6:  and it looks kind of nice, like it looks the, we will put the links in the
Speaker 6:  show notes, but they, they redid the camera bar on the back so that it's
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it does look nice being like a visor. It just looks like a camera bar
Speaker 6:  on the back.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 7:  Got, it's given some iPhone edges to it. Yeah. Or at least I thought like
Speaker 6:  It's, it's got the sort of rounded rectangle thing going on for it. It looks
Speaker 6:  nice. And mostly I just wanted to bring it up because I said I think it was
Speaker 6:  last week that after the Samsung announcement, I am, I'm bearish on
Speaker 6:  the future of The Pixel. And so a million people sent me this and we're like,
Speaker 6:  what about this new pixels coming? And to all of you, I wanna
Speaker 6:  say this looks great and I sincerely hope it's the greatest phone in the
Speaker 6:  history of the universe. I also think it's possible that no one at Google
Speaker 6:  knows it's being released.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which is why it's leaking out. Yeah. There's like one person on The
Speaker 3:  Pixel team who's like, let show it to people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's just like, do I, what is this phone on my desk? It seems neat.
Speaker 6:  Should I, should I show somebody?
Speaker 3:  Very good.
Speaker 7:  What's yours?
Speaker 3:  Well, I got two. Okay. But you had two.
Speaker 7:  I I do have two.
Speaker 3:  So I'll, I'll go then you and Sounds good. And then, right. That's how we're,
Speaker 3:  that's how we're gonna do it. And
Speaker 6:  I'll just be here. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You, well you started, we, you had Walt
Speaker 3:  your lightning round was I did another verb Chest that was better than this
Speaker 3:  one.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So Apple is all in on spatial audio
Speaker 3:  probably 'cause of The, Vision, Pro because it's all around you. Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  they're gonna start to pay artists
Speaker 3:  10% more for the spatial audio streams. Gimme page. So
Speaker 3:  pennies, pennies per stream. More if they people stream the spatial
Speaker 3:  one, which is designed to incentivize artists to both make the spatial mixes
Speaker 3:  and then promote them on Apples service as spatial mixes.
Speaker 3:  I hate this. I hate this so much.
Speaker 3:  One because I think, I think the math doesn't actually kind of work out.
Speaker 3:  So I was looking on on like random artists, sort of like job
Speaker 3:  boards, a spatial mix. People are buying 'em for 500
Speaker 3:  bucks. Like you're like, fire off your files to some poor engineer who's
Speaker 3:  like never heard your music before. They'll just generate a spatial mix.
Speaker 3:  Most of that sounds bad. Yeah. And I know that people are always arguing
Speaker 3:  with me. They think some of them sound good. I I know some of them sound
Speaker 3:  good. I'm a man who owned a super audio CD player. They could play the Beatles
Speaker 3:  and Quadraphonic sound. All right. I I understand.
Speaker 3:  Is that also how you met your wife? Is that No, that's what's,
Speaker 3:  that's what's driving us apart day by day.
Speaker 3:  I'm just telling you. I I believe you. I've been playing with surround audio
Speaker 3:  since the beginning. Yeah. If you do a good job
Speaker 3:  having more channels or more objects or however Atmos wants to work,
Speaker 3:  whatever, having more is better. Great.
Speaker 3:  If you do it like crap, it sounds worse. Which is why people are al like
Speaker 3:  always get reverted to stereo. Like it's the easiest thing.
Speaker 3:  It's the most addressable thing if there's more stereo
Speaker 3:  devices on the market than anything. And especially when you're like
Speaker 3:  farting out if 500 pop, like they're, it's not gonna sound
Speaker 3:  good. And most spatial mixes are that level. And
Speaker 3:  Apple incentivizing it because they want their headset to go off is just
Speaker 3:  the ugh, ugh. It's bad. I'm just telling
Speaker 3:  you it's bad. It's gonna make more things sound bad than sound good. Which
Speaker 7:  Is worse. That, or when DVDs were really into pan and scan,
Speaker 3:  That's kind of where we're at. Yeah. The that's a good, the good comparison,
Speaker 3:  right? That's like, what if we just shove this into that
Speaker 3:  box and you're like,
Speaker 7:  No, that's gross. Stop it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Look, there are some, I know there are some good ones, but even on Apple's
Speaker 3:  playlists there, there are really bad spatial mixes. And
Speaker 3:  it's because there just isn't the volume of people who care enough there.
Speaker 3:  It's not the volume of artists who are like, I'm going to sit down and
Speaker 3:  make a spatial audio record. They're more like, I'm on tour forever
Speaker 3:  because that's where the money is. I'm gonna buy some loops and do a rap
Speaker 3:  in my hotel room and hope that's a hit. Like, that's the reality of most
Speaker 3:  artists right now. And I'm not saying that's good or bad. Like that's just
Speaker 3:  where the music industry has forced most musicians
Speaker 3:  into money. Right? They make their money with sinks. They make their money
Speaker 3:  like ads and movie sync. They make their money
Speaker 3:  on selling their old catalogs to billionaires who then do more weird
Speaker 3:  stuff with them. They make their money on tour. They do not
Speaker 3:  make their money selling records. And so if you are like now to make
Speaker 3:  a, make your record more complicated, then we'll pay you more money.
Speaker 3:  Like that's ugh,
Speaker 7:  No one's gonna do that. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It doesn't seem like they're doing an app. Maybe I'm gonna be wrong. I just
Speaker 3:  like, look at this. I'm like, ah, we are, we are we gonna make music sound
Speaker 3:  shitty? So a headset sells more.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's MP three is all over again.
Speaker 3:  It's weird man. It's weird. Alright, I know someone's gonna send me some
Speaker 3:  facial mix. Like George Harrison's creeping up behind you. Yeah, I I've been
Speaker 3:  there. All right. What's your other one?
Speaker 7:  Have y'all heard of Powell World?
Speaker 3:  Just Pokemon with guns? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's Pokemon with guns. Yeah. That's, that's all it is. It's Pokemon with
Speaker 7:  guns.
Speaker 6:  I just love that. Those are exactly the words in exactly the order. I was
Speaker 6:  gonna say, this is just the unofficial tagline of Powell World now. I
Speaker 3:  Love it.
Speaker 7:  It is, it is so Pokemon with guns that there was a YouTube creator named
Speaker 7:  Toasted shoes who was like, look at this. IIII made it Pokemon with
Speaker 7:  guns. I I put in Pikachu and all and everybody, I, I moed all the
Speaker 7:  little creatures that you can capture and made them Pokemon and you can play
Speaker 7:  his ash. And guess what got shut down real
Speaker 7:  fast by Nintendo our, our boy toasted shoes.
Speaker 7:  It, it's unclear how he was modding it. 'cause it doesn't yet allow mods
Speaker 7:  'cause it's still in like alpha release. Yeah. It is blowing up the charts
Speaker 7:  on, on Steam and, and people are loving to try it out. There's a lot of
Speaker 7:  weirdness around it. but it is essentially what if you had Pokemon and what
Speaker 7:  if you had guns and also like had to do some survival stuff
Speaker 7:  and people are like just
Speaker 3:  A dash of survival stuff. Just
Speaker 7:  A little dash, just a little sprinkle. And apparently people are really,
Speaker 7:  really into that right now. Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  Do you think, is Nintendo gonna take down the main Palworld game that they're
Speaker 3:  not the not, I understand 'cause the mod was just like, what if I stole your
Speaker 3:  characters? They're
Speaker 7:  Like, no.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's like pretty cut and dry.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. He hadn't even released the mod. He'd just been like, I'm working on
Speaker 7:  it. And like showed some videos and Nintendo was in his inbox immediately.
Speaker 7:  Like, you're not, you are gonna stop that work right now.
Speaker 7:  The the Pokemon company says it is going to investigate Palworld because
Speaker 7:  it feels like, oh you do, you do cute creatures that you can capture.
Speaker 7:  We do cute creatures. You can capture, you use guns. We don't
Speaker 7:  and actually have a problem with you doing that. So it'll be a very
Speaker 7:  interesting
Speaker 3:  It's situation. But it's not actually the Pokemon, it's not, they just look
Speaker 3:  a lot like the Pokemon.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They just, yeah, they're very similar. Is it
Speaker 3:  Like they're
Speaker 7:  Very cute
Speaker 3:  Freak achu. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's not, they vibe like Pokemon in like a very real way. Like
Speaker 6:  if you didn't know the difference and you just shoved these
Speaker 6:  into a photo of a bunch of Pokemon, they would just fit.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. So, so it is, it's close enough that
Speaker 7:  we're gonna have a three hour special episode of The Vergecast with
Speaker 7:  NELI explaining
Speaker 3:  Everyone loves copyright the
Speaker 7:  Copyright of this situation. 'cause it's kind of weird, but Yeah, Nintendo
Speaker 7:  is, is not crazy about Pokemon with guns. So
Speaker 3:  It seems, it seems like they wouldn't be Yeah. It doesn't seem like they,
Speaker 7:  That's, that's not their thing.
Speaker 6:  But the whole rest of the world seems to be, didn't I read that? It's, it's
Speaker 6:  like on pace to be the most popular game on
Speaker 6:  Steam, like ever. Like
Speaker 7:  There's a bunch of different metrics Steam uses and one of them is most concurrent
Speaker 7:  players. And for years now, player Underground
Speaker 7:  Battlegrounds, was that the name? Its called PUG
Speaker 6:  Pg. Like only nerds use the whole name. I don't, I hate to
Speaker 7:  Be the word. You know. So PUG was, was, was is has
Speaker 7:  been the most played game concurrently and it seems like Pok,
Speaker 7:  excuse me, not Pokemon Palworld could, it's like the
Speaker 6:  In slit
Speaker 7:  Could, could take that, that, that title and, and pretty quickly too.
Speaker 7:  So we'll see. But also, how long will people play it?
Speaker 7:  Unclear. Everybody's really into it this week. They may not be into it next
Speaker 7:  week. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There may not be a game to play next week.
Speaker 7:  Nintendo may have just shut that down. Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 3:  Touch the nature of steam popularity it feels like, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. A lot of times
Speaker 3:  It goes. All right, I've got one last one. All right. Which is actually an
Speaker 3:  old story that David already mentioned, but he forgot to mention the, the
Speaker 3:  most important part.
Speaker 3:  So David did mention that Tim Sweeney had replied
Speaker 3:  to the app store changes and Apple's responses to them. And it's true, Tim
Speaker 3:  Sweeney did refer to them as malicious compliance. What David failed to
Speaker 3:  mention
Speaker 3:  was that he also called them hot Garbage. Yes. And
Speaker 3:  quote, it will take more time to parse both the
Speaker 3:  written and unwritten parts of this new horror show.
Speaker 6:  That's very good. But can I, can I drop some breaking
Speaker 6:  news on you? Fort tweet? There's Breaking News. Just tweeted that it's coming
Speaker 6:  back in the Epic game store
Speaker 6:  fort. It says later this year, Fortnite will return in Europe on iOS through
Speaker 6:  the Epic game store. Shout out
Speaker 3:  DMAI.
Speaker 6:  So it's like, yeah, Tim Sweeney hates it and is going to
Speaker 6:  take advantage of it at every available turn.
Speaker 7:  Bless Tim.
Speaker 3:  It's good. You need more idealistic. Yeah. Fortnite makers,
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 6:  Will say we've seen at least two just in the time we've been recording this
Speaker 6:  podcast, at least two alternate app stores
Speaker 6:  announcing that they're already beginning the process to becoming
Speaker 6:  an app marketplace on
Speaker 7:  IOS. How much porn?
Speaker 6:  Unclear. Okay. I can tell you one of them is, it's called the Alt Store
Speaker 6:  and it's started as this app Delta, which
Speaker 6:  originally was an app called GBA for iOS, which is a way to play
Speaker 6:  Game Boy ROMs. Yeah. On your iPhone, which is a thing Apple explicitly
Speaker 6:  does not allow. And now in theory, under this rule would
Speaker 6:  be perfectly allowable to do through an app marketplace.
Speaker 6:  Great. So like that's, that's coming, that's one of the ones that announced
Speaker 6:  they're, they're already working on this. Like it's gonna
Speaker 7:  Happen. I'll finally have a reason for that. That controller that I, you
Speaker 7:  can put on your iPhone. I never do it. 'cause I'm like, I only wanna play
Speaker 7:  ROMs and don don't wanna do that on, on the, that I legally own the games.
Speaker 7:  Of course, you should always legally own the games
Speaker 3:  I don not. I'm a hundred percent certain that, that it's still not legal
Speaker 3:  and that is just some folk wisdom. But the rom market is not big enough for
Speaker 3:  anyone to care.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So please don't sue me for that. I supported you in your PE worlds.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 6:  Okay. Yeah. Nintendo has bigger fish to fry at the moment, so you're you're
Speaker 6:  fine. Leave
Speaker 3:  Me alone. Oh my gosh. All right. Well, I'm gonna start a gambling store.
Speaker 3:  From what I understand, gambling is very lucrative,
Speaker 3:  so catch me in the gambling store, NELI
Speaker 6:  Porn, crypto and Gambling Depot coming to iOS in 2024.
Speaker 3:  I mean, just historically lucrative ideas.
Speaker 3:  Let's, let's, she wants to talk. Wouldn't I be
Speaker 3:  good at, I don't even gamble. First of all, this is true. Every
Speaker 3:  year at css I go to Vegas and whatever money other people are spending gambling,
Speaker 3:  I just use that money. I spend the same money, but I buy limousines. And
Speaker 3:  I promise you this is true. I've been doing it for years.
Speaker 6:  Douch for this. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We, we had a limo this year and everyone talks more about the limousine than
Speaker 3:  they talk about gambling at the end. It's,
Speaker 7:  It's true. I drank Bud Light out of a champagne crew. It's
Speaker 7:  beautiful. A
Speaker 3:  Wonderful moment. It was a good limo, except when Andrew took over the
Speaker 3:  ox and started playing some deeply weird shit in that car. That's it. That's
Speaker 3:  a Verge cast. We'll be back next week. There's it's
Speaker 3:  tech. New season is here. We have just started the year off to the races.
Speaker 3:  We'll be back next week. That's it.
Speaker 6:  That's Oh wait. Also, wait before we go,
Speaker 6:  we, next week is when The Vision Pro comes out.
Speaker 6:  And at some point when it makes sense, we're gonna do a whole
Speaker 6:  Vergecast about The Vision Pro. And if you have questions about The Vision
Speaker 6:  Pro, send them to us. Yeah. Call the hotline. Eight six six Verge one one.
Speaker 6:  Email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com. All of your vision Pro questions.
Speaker 6:  As soon as we can answer them, we will answer them. And we're gonna do a
Speaker 6:  whole Vergecast about, it's gonna be really fun
Speaker 3:  Looking at you with the eyes just staring at you
Speaker 3:  with our undead eyes. That's it. That's where Chest rock and roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 8:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is the production
Speaker 8:  of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced by
Speaker 8:  Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.