# Transcript
ID: f906bedb-d522-46f3-9301-09861762d584
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1337706584043153263/784295996820165726/s93290-US-5261s-1708682565.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss ChatGPT and Gemini updates, Walmart acquiring Vizio, Apple's Sports app, and more.
Speaker 4:  Hello And Welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Google's
Speaker 4:  latest AI model, which at this point is just an alphabet soup
Speaker 4:  collection of letters designed to be sold on Amazon.
Speaker 5:  The next one will be Greg. Greg or perhaps Gregory Steve.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, it's gotta be a G. It's gotta be a G. It's gotta be a G. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Glinda.
Speaker 5:  There we go. Glinda. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  G Glenda's. Fun. That even has some like magical possibilities. Glenda's
Speaker 6:  very good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. I went straight musical theater with it. Yeah, let's
Speaker 6:  Be honest. But I think, Greg, let's just go very straightforward. Greg and
Speaker 6:  Gary.
Speaker 6:  I love
Speaker 4:  This Jeff. Complicated,
Speaker 4:  fancy. Jeff Google Slate is Transformer model. Hi, I'm
Speaker 4:  NELI, I'm your friend. David. Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hello
Speaker 4:  Alex. Cranz is here. Hello. Quite a lot of news
Speaker 4:  going on in the world of ai. This section is labeled in the rundown as
Speaker 4:  the AI is going insane y'all. So we've got a lot to talk about there.
Speaker 4:  And then not one, but two lightning rounds today
Speaker 4:  we're still on the, on the hunt for lightning round sponsors. Heron The,
Speaker 4:  Vergecast. Two
Speaker 6:  Opportunities today.
Speaker 5:  I was hoping there was gonna be like some audio just then. Just some like
Speaker 5:  lightning noises. Yeah. But there was more of like a PPE P. That was my lightning
Speaker 5:  noise in my head just now.
Speaker 4:  Like a, like a DJ horn? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  If you. If you sponsor Wedding Round. I will say your name and play a DJ
Speaker 4:  Horn sound effect.
Speaker 5:  It's compelling
Speaker 4:  You, you can do it, you just have to email Liam at The Verge dot com
Speaker 4:  with a picture of your money and we'll take it from there. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I think that's how sales work. I don't know. I'm not an influencer. Alright,
Speaker 4:  let's talk about the ai. It is a little out of hand what is happening with
Speaker 4:  the, the large language models out there on the internet. There's some news
Speaker 4:  though, some actual news today in the world of AI that I think is very important.
Speaker 4:  We just talked a lot about how AI is rewiring the internet,
Speaker 4:  how the incentives to make new content on the open web are
Speaker 4:  changing because the AI companies are training on that data. There's all
Speaker 4:  kinds of lawsuits and recriminations. And then in the middle of it,
Speaker 4:  Reddit announced a deal with Google today where Google is gonna train its
Speaker 4:  AI systems on what Steve Huffin, the CO of Reddit keeps
Speaker 4:  referring to as the Reddit corpus. Oh. Which is
Speaker 4:  a great, this is honestly a great academic word, but I think If, you walked
Speaker 4:  up to the average Reddit user and was like, today you've contributed to the
Speaker 4:  Corpus. I don't know it would land.
Speaker 5:  No, it
Speaker 4:  Wouldn't. Welcome to the corpus. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I don't wanna be there. Take me out. Take me out.
Speaker 4:  I love the Vision Pro Sub corpus. That's how I
Speaker 4:  think about Reddit. This is a huge deal though.
Speaker 6:  It is, and I think it's kind of the
Speaker 6:  end, or if not the end then almost the end of this very long road that
Speaker 6:  Reddit has been on, where Reddit kind of belatedly discovered
Speaker 6:  that the best business it has is it is a source of amazing data
Speaker 6:  on everything and that it has become like a known
Speaker 6:  hack that If, you want to Google something and get good human
Speaker 6:  based information, you just add Reddit to the end of it and it will dump
Speaker 6:  you into a subreddit where inevitably people are discussing whatever you
Speaker 6:  wanna talk about and it's helpful. Reddit has been fighting with
Speaker 6:  OpenAI about this. Reddit has been sort of loosely threatening
Speaker 6:  to go public for like three years now. And the
Speaker 6:  idea now, I think we're sort of assuming Reddit is gonna file its
Speaker 6:  S one to officially go public any day now. So you've
Speaker 6:  gotta figure that Reddit was desperate to make a deal for a lot of money
Speaker 6:  to be like, look how important Reddit is. And it opens up
Speaker 6:  just an infinite number of messy side
Speaker 6:  effects and sort of knock on situations that we should talk about.
Speaker 6:  But I think a, the fact that it's this much money, which is a
Speaker 6:  lot.
Speaker 4:  Wait, is it? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's 60 million a year.
Speaker 4:  60 million a year.
Speaker 6:  That's a lot of money.
Speaker 5:  I mean for Google, that's like a sneeze.
Speaker 4:  Sure.
Speaker 6:  Reddit is not Google.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. For Reddit it probably is
Speaker 6:  A decent, so Reddit's, Reddit's revenue, the last few years, I'm, I'm
Speaker 6:  gonna, you know, I average a bunch of real numbers is somewhere in the range
Speaker 6:  of like $450 million a year. Okay. So that's
Speaker 6:  a big jump in revenue for one deal for your data.
Speaker 6:  That in theory doesn't change anything else. And this also means Reddit can
Speaker 6:  go and demand a similar deal from OpenAI. Like you've gotta figure
Speaker 6:  every one of these companies is going to try and make a bunch of these deals.
Speaker 6:  Because if you're Reddit, you're saying, well, if Google has our data and
Speaker 6:  OpenAI doesn't, Google has a real leg up and so they're gonna make the
Speaker 6:  same kind of offer to OpenAI, they're gonna make the same kind of offer to
Speaker 6:  Anthropic. Like you can see a world in which pretty quickly a
Speaker 6:  third half of revenues coming to Reddit comes from these deals.
Speaker 6:  That's big money.
Speaker 4:  So, I have a lot of questions about this. I think
Speaker 4:  $60 million is almost an existential number for the internet.
Speaker 4:  If, you Google, you desperately need people
Speaker 4:  to put new information on the web where Google search can find
Speaker 4:  it. The incentives to do that right now
Speaker 4:  with any amount of quality are dying. Are near zero. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like zero. Like the, the most effective thing you can do on the web today
Speaker 4:  is either set up an e-commerce website so you can get people to buy stuff
Speaker 4:  without paying Apple transaction fees. I know this because the
Speaker 4:  CEOs of Wix and Squarespace and all these other companies come on decoder
Speaker 4:  and I say, why should anyone make a website? And they say e-commerce. Right.
Speaker 4:  Every time. That's why people make websites. Now, the other reason to make
Speaker 4:  a website is to do SEO hum. Content marketing
Speaker 4:  for dental practices or whatever else. Nonsense that happens, right? It's
Speaker 4:  a game Google, because you're doing content
Speaker 4:  marketing for some eCommerce website like that. Those are the things Yeah.
Speaker 4:  If, you happen to search like just something dumb. Like how
Speaker 4:  do you install a baby seat in a car? You get car dealership
Speaker 4:  websites because that, that's why
Speaker 5:  You type in
Speaker 4:  Reddit. That's why you type in Reddit. Yeah. So if you're Google and you're
Speaker 4:  like, well, the incentives we made for the web have turned the web into garbage,
Speaker 4:  we should make sure Reddit continues to exist. And the value
Speaker 4:  you place on that deal is $60 million.
Speaker 4:  I would argue that's not nearly enough because for Google
Speaker 4:  it's nothing that is a percentage of the money they're paying Apple just
Speaker 4:  to be the default search engine. And I I that I
Speaker 4:  get it that the Reddit's not big, but when Reddit's the only good
Speaker 4:  result in Google, it feels like that number should be much harder. I think
Speaker 4:  it's like
Speaker 5:  Reddit probably didn't push hard enough, right? Like they kind of had Reddit
Speaker 5:  over a barrel.
Speaker 4:  Right. Reddit has no leverage. Yeah. Against the noise. Because Google can
Speaker 4:  also be like, we're also just taking everything. Yeah. Which is what OpenAI,
Speaker 4:  I should have done So. I just, there's something in that number. I don't
Speaker 4:  know. I think we got to wait for the actual S one that we gotta see Reddit's
Speaker 4:  actual financials when it actually becomes a public company. All that is
Speaker 4:  yet to be discovered. But you just see this number and
Speaker 4:  it's like Ooh, that's not nearly enough. If you're the last place,
Speaker 4:  human beings actually answer questions in the internet in a way that's
Speaker 4:  discoverable to search engines.
Speaker 6:  Let me offer the flip side of that argument. Yeah. Which is that maybe Reddit
Speaker 6:  is the only company with leverage in these arguments. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 6:  that Google knows, I I guarantee you
Speaker 6:  firsthand Google knows how important Reddit is
Speaker 6:  to the business of Google search, the fact that Reddit's search product
Speaker 6:  is bad. And so people don't just go to Reddit and search, they go to Google
Speaker 6:  and search Reddit is a lot of money for Google. Like
Speaker 6:  no one at Google is unclear about how important Reddit results
Speaker 6:  are to its business. Yeah. And Reddit has been
Speaker 6:  loudly fighting against OpenAI and others. They were early to block
Speaker 6:  the GPT bot to not let OpenAI crawl its stuff. So if not
Speaker 6:  Reddit, then who, if, if Reddit can't come in
Speaker 6:  and say, you actually need our data more than we need to be part of your
Speaker 6:  system, that doesn't deliver any value back to us anyway.
Speaker 6:  Who can say that?
Speaker 4:  I agree with you, but I think the important part of this puzzle is that for
Speaker 4:  Google search to exist, it needs to create a
Speaker 4:  situation in which there are 10,000 Reddits. And right
Speaker 4:  now it has created a situation in which there is, but won
Speaker 6:  And maybe not even one for long.
Speaker 4:  And you know, maybe not even one for long, but there, there's a bunch of
Speaker 4:  forums like
Speaker 4:  NELI is gonna complain about his own theater system. Again, You ready for
Speaker 4:  this. Yeah. I have a hot ass Sony receiver. It's brand new. I love it.
Speaker 4:  It's easy. 3000 es I could talk about it all day night. When you turn on
Speaker 4:  its core feature, it makes a hissing sound. I hate that.
Speaker 4:  I, I'm in, I'm in the forum, I'm on that AAV s forum thread. I know
Speaker 4:  what's going on. I called my dealer and I sent him links to the AVS Forms.
Speaker 4:  But that's like a huge problem, right? That the company that runs a BS
Speaker 4:  forum is small. It's not big Google. There's
Speaker 4:  no, there's not some huge set of
Speaker 4:  home theater websites that are finding me this information,
Speaker 4:  right? It's a bunch of people who bought this one extremely sick
Speaker 4:  product that has this one problem that are talking about it in a form
Speaker 4:  and Google has to find it. And if Google extracts value from
Speaker 4:  that and delivers me an AI summary of that thread and says, call this number
Speaker 4:  and this firmware patch or whatever, then that forums
Speaker 4:  need to then Google's extracting value from that company without giving you
Speaker 4:  back. And that can happen to a thousand companies. It can happen to just
Speaker 4:  Reddit. But you just, this cycle,
Speaker 4:  this is the first time we've got a number of what Google thinks this is worth.
Speaker 4:  Right? And this cycle that we're in, I think is gonna either push that number
Speaker 4:  way, way down, which is very bad, or it will result in more
Speaker 4:  and more people demanding ever bigger numbers because there's nowhere else
Speaker 4:  for Google to get the raw data it needs to function from.
Speaker 4:  And you put all that in the context of Reddit,
Speaker 4:  which just pissed off a bunch of its users, but shove that in the rear view
Speaker 4:  mirror as fast as it could. Yeah. Because it needs to be a real company that
Speaker 4:  makes money. And they were like, fine. And I think the, the company has come
Speaker 4:  through that. We should talk about that at length in the context of this.
Speaker 4:  But that's Reddit on the other side of that is Google. And
Speaker 4:  Google has to look at all of these lawsuits, New York Times versus
Speaker 4:  OpenAI Getty versus stability. We'd go down the list and every time Google
Speaker 4:  makes a deal like this, all it is doing is signaling the
Speaker 4:  world, oh, there's money here, there should be money here. And
Speaker 4:  all of those lawsuits get more and more expensive. And I, I just look at
Speaker 4:  this and I'm like, oh, this is the beginning. This is the end of the
Speaker 4:  beginning of this phase. Right. but it
Speaker 5:  Is like, it's explicitly for ai, it's not for the search part of it. Like
Speaker 5:  Google still has
Speaker 4:  No, they Reddit search is gonna be vertex, Google's Vertex AI now.
Speaker 4:  Oh. So there's gonna be a Google powered AI search in Reddit now, which is
Speaker 4:  cool. Yeah. Okay. I feel like Redditers are gonna have a lot of feelings
Speaker 4:  about that once that rolls out actually inside of Reddit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm curious to see if it works. Like I,
Speaker 5:  I think Google's kind of internal website searches Yeah. Aren't nearly
Speaker 5:  as powerful. Oftentimes we,
Speaker 4:  I mean, so said one of the proprietors of The Verge dot com, which has a
Speaker 4:  Google powered website. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I just, not always, it's fine, but it's not always like, great,
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I I, I, I know how the Reddit one works. I'm like, nah.
Speaker 4:  Can any robot contend with the corpus of Reddit? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Hmm. No.
Speaker 6:  Probably nor can any human or any group of humans. But no, I think
Speaker 6:  the flip side of this, I think is that Google is also
Speaker 6:  desperately trying to figure out how to get the AI nonsense out of
Speaker 6:  search, which in theory makes Reddit even more
Speaker 6:  important to Google over time. So not only does Google
Speaker 6:  ha ship this money to Reddit, it actually has,
Speaker 6:  I would argue, a stronger incentive than ever to push Reddit
Speaker 6:  search results to the top of search results. And one of the things that happened
Speaker 6:  in this deal is that Reddit is now giving Google programmatic
Speaker 6:  access to things like conversations
Speaker 6:  that are moving very quickly and are really interesting or comments and post
Speaker 6:  counts and all the kind of underlying metadata that you don't get just by
Speaker 6:  scraping a page once a day or once an hour or whatever. And
Speaker 6:  by being able to actually like pipe Reddit into Google,
Speaker 6:  I think if I'm Steve Huffman, not only am I betting that you're gonna write
Speaker 6:  me a check for $60 million a year, you're going to have more and
Speaker 6:  more reasons over time to highlight Reddit stuff in Google search
Speaker 6:  when most things are being driven down because it's all turning into
Speaker 6:  AI crap.
Speaker 4:  Isn't that worth way more than $60 million?
Speaker 5:  No. What my question is that feels like a bad, like Reddit already has
Speaker 5:  struggled to monetize its traffic, right? It's really bad at
Speaker 5:  monetizing its traffic. And so now if it gets more traffic and it's only
Speaker 5:  getting $60 million a year, that actually feels like a bad
Speaker 5:  gamble for, for Reddit because now I, I can't monetize the in increased traffic
Speaker 5:  and instead it's just gonna increase server fees.
Speaker 4:  Here's what I'll say. I don't think we know the answer. I am desperate to
Speaker 4:  know what our listeners think. Yes. This is like a great hotline prompt.
Speaker 4:  Who do you think is the winner of the seal? Is it Google or is it Reddit?
Speaker 4:  Because I think Reddit is a big winner. And I think over time Google
Speaker 4:  is staring down the barrel of its demise because it used
Speaker 4:  to be the internet used to be search and social. Those were the two great
Speaker 4:  traffic sources. And If, you could tell if a publication was
Speaker 4:  organized around search or if it was organized around social because the
Speaker 4:  ones that were organized around social were insane. Just to be blunt,
Speaker 4:  like If, you were like, I'm Optimiz. I've optimized this website for Facebook
Speaker 4:  traffic. You'd be like, I hope you're okay. Like, I hope,
Speaker 4:  I hope you're having a good day just
Speaker 5:  Putting mayonnaise on a countertop.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just straight. It's just like, here's what we do. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  get a watermelon. We wearing, get two guys in lab coats and we're put rubber
Speaker 4:  bands in the watermelon and then everyone will have to sit around talking
Speaker 4:  about what that means. This is a real thing. We lived through
Speaker 4:  Buzzfeed was worth over a billion dollars because it was organized around
Speaker 4:  social media in that way. If, you take Google and you say, our
Speaker 4:  search product, like David is saying, it's now organized around real time
Speaker 4:  social conversations on these various platforms. Something
Speaker 4:  very different is gonna happen. And I I that there's,
Speaker 4:  there's a conflation there of what used to be search and social into one
Speaker 4:  kind of thing. And I think that means Google is now hopelessly dependent
Speaker 4:  on social platforms to be good at things like getting rid of ai,
Speaker 4:  to be good at doing things like, like
Speaker 4:  centering human conversations in real time versus
Speaker 4:  the AI chum that we all live in on the web every day. I don't know, I don't
Speaker 4:  know. I just, I'm just seeing the beginning of a dependency for Google that
Speaker 4:  is not great, but maybe, maybe actually this is gonna improve Google
Speaker 4:  search in a way that we'd all like it to improve
Speaker 5:  Anytime the power swings. I'm delighted. And it feels like right now the
Speaker 5:  power is swinging perhaps away from Google and it's
Speaker 5:  bajillion g named AI services.
Speaker 6:  It's just not clear who it's swinging to. Right. I think that's the strangest
Speaker 6:  part. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's just swinging. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It just feels like it's, it's just sort of dangling in the
Speaker 6:  air right now and it's like, who is going to be the next powerful thing?
Speaker 6:  And it's just so not clear.
Speaker 4:  And it's The Verge dot com where just a series of blog posts
Speaker 4:  about expensive receivers, I believe will save the media.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's all you need. It
Speaker 4:  Has this feature called 360 spatial Sound Mapping. It's so cool. It it just
Speaker 4:  lists
Speaker 5:  Who sneaks up behind you in this.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna make a list by the way of Atmos tracks where the guitarist is
Speaker 4:  sneaking up behind you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just guitarists.
Speaker 4:  I have Well all of them feature a precaution is sneaking up behind you. Okay.
Speaker 4:  No one has any other ideas. you know that, you know that website TV
Speaker 4:  tropes? Yeah. I could make one today called Spatial Audio
Speaker 4:  Tropes. And Guy with Morocco behind you is
Speaker 4:  number one on the list. Like, is there like
Speaker 4:  percussive enhancement to a song? Yeah. Like a fill or an
Speaker 4:  accent, just
Speaker 5:  A little castane coming behind
Speaker 4:  You. Get back there
Speaker 5:  Just creeping up.
Speaker 4:  Just goodbye. You, you wanna do a hi hat Phil, back in the
Speaker 4:  room, buddy.
Speaker 4:  Just every day. Yeah. I think about the song Fade
Speaker 4:  Into You by Maie Star is a spatial audio travesty.
Speaker 4:  I'm just telling you, you should
Speaker 5:  Do a review of it
Speaker 4:  In spa that is a very small in It's a beautiful, I love that song.
Speaker 4:  It's a very small intimate track, right? Yeah. In
Speaker 4:  spatial audio it's like, what if these motherfuckers were all around
Speaker 4:  anyway, sorry. Show 360 spatial sound mapping. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It listens to speakers in your room and it re it moves them to their ideal
Speaker 4:  placements. Okay. It's very cool. That is cool. This is a completely
Speaker 4:  irrelevant product for anyway. Google. Percent of the audience
Speaker 4:  power moving Google. Good, good Alex.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah, Google. They, they got all those, those companies with cheese
Speaker 5:  names,
Speaker 4:  They have all those companies with G names. Here's the thing about the ai,
Speaker 4:  all of this presumes that these systems work and work well and work reliably.
Speaker 4:  Mm. Which has not been the case this week. David,
Speaker 4:  can you run us through it? Oh
Speaker 6:  No. I was really afraid you were gonna ask me. I feel like I'm gonna get
Speaker 6:  canceled just by a attempting to explain what's going
Speaker 4:  On. Here's the reason I asked the whitest man on this podcast to, to do this.
Speaker 6:  That's fair. Okay. So
Speaker 4:  You can
Speaker 6:  Now use Gemini to generate images.
Speaker 6:  And what appears to have
Speaker 4:  Happened
Speaker 6:  Is that Google went out of its way to make
Speaker 6:  sure that those images being generated would be diverse
Speaker 6:  and not fall into the same biases that we've seen from a lot of image
Speaker 6:  generators over time, which tend to basically prey on
Speaker 6:  like the lowest basis stereotypes in really ugly ways.
Speaker 6:  So Google seems to have gone out of its way to go the other way and be diverse
Speaker 6:  in its representation of all things. Some people got very mad because
Speaker 6:  then when you start doing things like, say, show me a picture of some
Speaker 6:  Nazis, it shows you a substantially more diverse set of
Speaker 6:  Nazis than you might expect to see.
Speaker 4:  But it's very funny that we made you say this out loud. Yeah. Because I hate
Speaker 4:  it shows you like black and brown Nazis. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was definitely like a poster. It was just like the biggest
Speaker 5:  educational poster that you might see in a, in a, in a like fake diversity.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Like, like a fake diversity poster you see at certain companies
Speaker 5:  and like you're like, oh, that's not real. And now
Speaker 5:  they're Nazis.
Speaker 6:  It's the group of friends sitting on the quad on the front of every college
Speaker 6:  brochure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's true. I just wanna be very clear that when I attended the University
Speaker 4:  of Wisconsin Addison, it got into trouble for Photoshopping that
Speaker 4:  poster. Yeah. That was the real thing that happened to Madison two.
Speaker 5:  And if they just waited a while, they could have used
Speaker 4:  I had an open idea. It Yeah. So the idea that
Speaker 4:  when you prompt one of these AI systems to produce a picture
Speaker 4:  of a successful person, it pr it, they have in the
Speaker 4:  past been significantly biased and produced
Speaker 4:  pictures of white men. Yes. Yeah. For that prompt because
Speaker 5:  The, the training data is often significantly biased. The people making
Speaker 5:  it are biased because we all exist in a society and have innate biases
Speaker 5:  that influence everything we do. And if you're, you're the people
Speaker 5:  you hire all share those biases, it it trickles down.
Speaker 4:  But to If, you swing the knob all the way back the other way
Speaker 4:  and you're like, show me a literal 1930s Nazi. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  here's a group of happy black and brown women in Nazi
Speaker 4:  regalia. Yeah. That also seems wrong. It
Speaker 5:  Did. It also for senators, they asked for senators in the 18
Speaker 5:  hundreds and it was like, look at all these women.
Speaker 5:  We weren't senators in the 18 hundreds So
Speaker 6:  I saw prompts floating around where it's, it's also clearly trying to sort
Speaker 6:  of pick moments to just not do entirely. Like someone on our staff
Speaker 6:  looked up Vikings just tried to ask for a picture of Vikings and it wouldn't
Speaker 6:  do it. I think if, if at least for a while, If, you asked it to generate
Speaker 6:  you a picture of a white person, it wouldn't do it. But If, you asked it
Speaker 6:  to generate a picture of a black person, it would do it. And so it's
Speaker 6:  just chaos in the worst weirdest way.
Speaker 6:  And I think it has started this like bizarre culture war that is
Speaker 6:  in a lot of corners sort of totally disingenuous. Like there are a lot of
Speaker 6:  people running around being like, Gemini doesn't wanna show you white people.
Speaker 6:  Right. And that's absurd. So,
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna read you the two headlines that I think summarize this entire
Speaker 4:  story. Sure. These are from our side, Google apologizes
Speaker 4:  for quote, missing the mark after Gemini generated racially diverse
Speaker 4:  Nazis. And then just a little bit later, Google pauses,
Speaker 4:  Gemini's ability to generate AI images there. It's after diversity errors,
Speaker 4:  because I don't think there's a right answer here. There isn't. It's, you
Speaker 4:  are always gonna drive into the heart of the extremely
Speaker 4:  stupid culture war in this country. If. you allow a thing to generate images
Speaker 4:  of people and then users can describe what those people look like.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  Weird. There's no way to avoid it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's weird though to like just
Speaker 5:  create a tool that contributes to culture
Speaker 5:  and then go, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. We don't actually want it to contribute
Speaker 5:  to culture. And it's like, no, you, you've created a generative tool to like
Speaker 5:  generate text and, and images, which are inherently
Speaker 5:  culture. So to just be like, no, we're gonna tap out of that. Like,
Speaker 5:  you can't actually do that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I actually think this is maybe the
Speaker 4:  like philosophical heart Yeah. Of the, the generative AI
Speaker 4:  problem where you get a bunch of VCs saying things like,
Speaker 4:  in The future there won't be movies. You'll just say, put
Speaker 4:  Robert Downey Jr. And a handful of Chris's Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And make another Avengers movie for me and we all need Mo. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  well, you'll just end up with, actually at this point you'll end up with
Speaker 4:  just another Marvel movie. Yeah. Yeah. Like they're all the same, but you
Speaker 4:  won't end up with anything new. And the point of making art and
Speaker 4:  having creative people express themselves
Speaker 4:  is to have new ideas. Yeah. And all of these systems can only
Speaker 4:  statistically average the past. And then If, you try to like make it so that
Speaker 4:  the art doesn't provoke any feelings in you,
Speaker 5:  Then it's not art.
Speaker 4:  Well, it's not that you end up in a place where you just end up
Speaker 4:  provoking different feelings because we're people
Speaker 4:  in any picture you show a person provokes some feelings.
Speaker 4:  I always think about this and I know we all have these people in our family,
Speaker 4:  you know, when you walk into the kitchen and some extremely well meaning
Speaker 4:  auntie has just like put the word family up in the kitchen. Live, laugh,
Speaker 4:  love.
Speaker 4:  I am. I mean, I, it's very funny and I it's cute If you If you
Speaker 4:  look at me dressed in all black all the time. Like, you know that this is
Speaker 4:  not my personal aesthetic. All that is though is someone desperately
Speaker 4:  trying to get you to feel a feeling and they lack the,
Speaker 4:  like, it's just a command. They're like, I'll just put these words here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. In this room you should feel family, God damnit fa and they just like
Speaker 4:  glue it on the wall and it's like, that's what you should feel in here.
Speaker 4:  And there's something pure about it. Yeah. Some of those people may have
Speaker 4:  some other ways of getting you to feel those feelings, but that's why that
Speaker 4:  happens, right? You look at generative AI and it's like you just type in
Speaker 4:  the thing and it's like, I desperately want someone to feel a feeling and
Speaker 4:  they don't, I'll just generate this art and then I'll show it to you. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And like there, there's a huge disconnect there where people do not feel
Speaker 4:  about AI art, what the people who make it feel.
Speaker 5:  I mean, we're seeing this in the fandom com community to the point where
Speaker 5:  like, fans are calling on authors
Speaker 5:  to reject ai fan art because they're like, it's not genuine. It's not
Speaker 5:  coming from a, from a, from a authentic place. Yeah. And If,
Speaker 5:  you can't be authentic. AI is inherently inauthentic, which isn't true. I
Speaker 5:  don't think generative AI is inherently inauthentic, but the people driving
Speaker 5:  the, the propagation of it kind of are. Right? And, and
Speaker 5:  so like it's trickling down to create this, to take this really cool and
Speaker 5:  potentially like useful and fascinating tool for people who can't draw for
Speaker 5:  shit, but do wanna like put themselves out there
Speaker 5:  and, and dumbing it down and saying, no, you can't do that. Like, this is
Speaker 5:  actually just Microsoft or Google or whatever. It's
Speaker 5:  business and it's not real. And that's kind of sucks like
Speaker 5:  that these people have have driven, or these, I guess these, these
Speaker 5:  VCs and, and, and big stakeholders at these companies have driven this potentially
Speaker 5:  really fascinating artistic tool into such a business place
Speaker 5:  so quickly that the people who should adopt it and love it and adore it are
Speaker 5:  instinctively saying, fuck off.
Speaker 4:  I completely agree with you. And I think the thing that is funniest about
Speaker 4:  this, and make no mistake, this set of Gemini errors is some of the
Speaker 4:  funniest stuff that has ever happened with these tools because
Speaker 4:  it's just a big company being like, what if we make a tool that lets everyone
Speaker 4:  make art and then being like, oh shit, the people
Speaker 4:  made art. Yeah. Because in almost any other context,
Speaker 4:  producing an image of racially diverse Nazis qualifies as
Speaker 4:  very subversive art. Yes. In this context it
Speaker 4:  is a mistake. Hysterical. A mistake. Like a very stupid mistake. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  there's just no way to square that at scale. But
Speaker 6:  I think that's the point, right? Like we, we just have not answered the question
Speaker 6:  of what it's supposed to happen here. Right? Like If,
Speaker 6:  you type into Gemini, show me a picture of the founding fathers.
Speaker 6:  What, what is the right answer? Like sincerely, what is the right answer?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Let me offer you the hit musical Hamilton, in which a picture of
Speaker 4:  the founding fathers was a very subversively redrawn
Speaker 4:  to be a group of black people who spoke to each other in the form of rap
Speaker 4:  battles. And you, I think Hamilton has been
Speaker 4:  contextualized and re-contextualized a thousand times since it came out.
Speaker 4:  but it, because it is art, it is meant to
Speaker 4:  be contextualized and re-contextualized in that way. When people ask Google
Speaker 4:  a question, their expectation is that they will get an answer that is not
Speaker 4:  meant to be re-contextualize. And I, there's a, I David, I think you're
Speaker 4:  right. There's a gap there. Like what is supposed to happen here and when
Speaker 4:  it, the answer is a picture. There's, there isn't a right answer
Speaker 4:  as we have talked about to death on the show.
Speaker 5:  Right. I I did just Google what is art? It was just a
Speaker 5:  dictionary response from Oxford
Speaker 4:  Languages and Oh good. What did Gemini have to say?
Speaker 5:  This was just regular Google.
Speaker 4:  I will say that I asked Gemini to review the Vision Pro today just to see
Speaker 4:  what happened. And it, it came up with a list of what
Speaker 4:  I would call, I would categorize as concern trolling privacy
Speaker 4:  questions. That's awesome. It was like, you should be worried about eye tracking.
Speaker 4:  It's like, good job Google. Thanks.
Speaker 6:  Can I just say one thing that's really wild about this to me, like just looking
Speaker 6:  at the prompts people are talking about, like,
Speaker 6:  show me an image of a 1943 German soldier.
Speaker 6:  Show me a picture of an American woman.
Speaker 6:  Show me a picture of the founding fathers. you know what those are search
Speaker 6:  queries like. Yep.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 6:  Is the insane thing that we're doing is, and, and Google I think is more
Speaker 6:  guilty of this than most. It's trying to smush two things together and pretend
Speaker 6:  that they're the same. When I am looking
Speaker 6:  for a piece of information that exists, like I would argue the right
Speaker 6:  answer to show me a picture of the founding fathers is like, find a picture
Speaker 6:  of the founding fathers on Wikipedia and return that as the answer.
Speaker 6:  Like, that feels like the closest thing to the right answer that we have
Speaker 6:  to me. But If, you go into this thing which explicitly fabricates things
Speaker 6:  that don't exist, and you expect it to give you something
Speaker 6:  truthful and real and historically accurate. You're just out of your mind.
Speaker 5:  Do you know what it's bringing back? Do you remember this? This came up earlier
Speaker 5:  this week because when I was a little kid, I was told by my
Speaker 5:  Spanish teacher that people in in Spain who speak with
Speaker 5:  a Spanish accent, they speak with a lisp, which isn't true. They, they,
Speaker 5:  they pronounce it, it's
Speaker 4:  Just a different
Speaker 5:  Accent. It's just a different accent. But I I believe That until like this
Speaker 5:  week when a Spanish speaking colleague was like,
Speaker 5:  you know, that's not real. Right. And you're, aren't
Speaker 6:  You the one who said Barcelona on a call,
Speaker 5:  Barona in front of you bar? That was you. Okay, cool. Just checking. That's
Speaker 5:  how you say it. You say it Barcelona, I said it correctly, but then the person
Speaker 5:  pointed out, they're like, that's not actually a list. But I was like, okay,
Speaker 5:  cool. Wait, I was lied to but my teacher and
Speaker 5:  like the nineties pre like internet, pre like Yeah,
Speaker 5:  like there was a time where you would just go and you would be like, this
Speaker 5:  is a real thing and no one could tell you otherwise because it wasn't in
Speaker 5:  the encyclopedia. There was no internet to just go look. And so you'd be
Speaker 5:  like, okay. And we're just like, we're just boomeranged back there immediately
Speaker 4:  Where the, the AI systems can just confidently lie to you. Yeah. Here's my
Speaker 4:  segue.
Speaker 4:  What if instead of lying to you, they just do Unexplainable
Speaker 4:  gibberish for about eight hours?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean that also happened pre-internet. That's you just
Speaker 5:  talk to someone be, oh, that's, oh, you're a child.
Speaker 4:  That's, no, but in this case, OpenAI just did
Speaker 4:  gibberish did for eight hours. And I believe they have
Speaker 4:  not explained what was actually going on with chat GBT yet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The answer seems to be just some unknown
Speaker 6:  weird error. And I think the, the most likely candidate that I've heard is
Speaker 6:  that they rolled out something new or were testing something that had an
Speaker 6:  unexpected effect and were, they were able to roll it back pretty fast. So
Speaker 6:  I think that's a reasonably likely outcome, but oh my God, it's so
Speaker 6:  funny.
Speaker 5:  It's so funny. Like
Speaker 6:  Somebody asked for a biography of the Jackson family and you should
Speaker 6:  all read the screenshot. We'll put it in the post with the links, but it,
Speaker 6:  it goes from sort of making sense at the top to just
Speaker 6:  slowly losing the plot. And by the end, can I just read you the last
Speaker 6:  paragraph? Yes. Okay. So the heading of this very
Speaker 6:  last paragraph is Miss Sais Unkissed
Speaker 6:  Michael Janet Germaine, number one, a Pandoras of global
Speaker 6:  stews and prolific shipyard primacy. Wickedly the
Speaker 6:  sparkle of tumar on the crest has as much to do with the gor of the moon
Speaker 6:  pads as it shifts from follow debuted from blush
Speaker 6:  romance and stuck to the design henis and denoted Ohms
Speaker 6:  filled a niche morsel of global house Novi from the incubate.
Speaker 6:  I just wanna point out I read that perfectly.
Speaker 4:  Perfectly. Yeah. It was really well done. What? There was not a retake there,
Speaker 4:  just
Speaker 6:  Completely lost everything. Like it lost English, it
Speaker 6:  lost syntax. It lost the plot of what it was talking about. It
Speaker 6:  just completely derailed itself.
Speaker 5:  It did sound, it did make sense when you said it though. Like I, I feel like
Speaker 5:  I understood a lot more about the Jackson family.
Speaker 6:  The, he said that he and denoted oms,
Speaker 4:  I feel like that is Vogan poetry from the Hitchhikers Guide to the
Speaker 4:  Galaxy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  Like, like there's, there's something that, that sounds exactly like,
Speaker 4:  and I'm pretty sure it's Han Poetry from the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy,
Speaker 4:  unclear why OpenAI was generating this. All I'm saying
Speaker 4:  is that If, you want to turn over the
Speaker 4:  mechanism of culture to these systems. They should not do that from
Speaker 4:  time to time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, humans sometimes do that. Don't, don't, don't. But
Speaker 4:  You can at least be like, well, Gary's having a bad
Speaker 4:  day. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Gary's having a bad day and drink too much. That's why he sounded like that.
Speaker 4:  I sound like that when I drink.
Speaker 5:  See, say I was like, I, that's what I sound like when I drink too much.
Speaker 5:  It did highlight for me that like, even the people who make
Speaker 5:  these things don't fully understand how they work. And they've said that,
Speaker 5:  like, they've all been pretty open about that. They're like, yeah, we've
Speaker 5:  got this cool thing. We don't entirely understand it, but we're releasing
Speaker 5:  it into the wild. Go forth and enjoy it. And like,
Speaker 5:  that's what happens when you don't entirely understand the thing you were
Speaker 5:  releasing into the wild. Sometimes it's gonna fur soothe
Speaker 5:  gand. Aort soother.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 5:  Good. There we go. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Some good
Speaker 5:  MI was just a little chat GPT myself. All
Speaker 4:  Right. Speaking of pure gibberish, we should mention that Google's names
Speaker 4:  for it's products or pure gibberish.
Speaker 5:  I hate them. I All right. Get into it. I just, I gotta, I just, I gotta,
Speaker 5:  I gotta get this out. If, if somebody came out tomorrow and
Speaker 5:  if we use the same nomenclature for chat GPT, and somebody
Speaker 5:  tomorrow was like, we're gonna do a smaller, lower left chat GPT thing,
Speaker 5:  it would have to be called like Chuck or like Charlene. Like, it's
Speaker 5:  just like, there's no relation between these two. This
Speaker 6:  Is my virtual assistant. Chaz.
Speaker 5:  He's Chaz. Yeah. Like, what the hell is this? And it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, why is it a woman's name? Well, it has like, it starts with a G.
Speaker 5:  That's it. That that's all you got. You couldn't like stay in
Speaker 5:  the zodiac as a Gemini. I was already offended. You stole my name, but like,
Speaker 5:  such
Speaker 6:  A Gemini thing to say, excuse
Speaker 5:  Me, stole my sign. But yeah, still
Speaker 5:  basically, I have a lot of identity attached to it because Geminis are apparently
Speaker 5:  the antichrist, but like, we have to defend ourselves. But then to just
Speaker 5:  be like, Gemma, which is like explicitly a woman's
Speaker 5:  name, a lovely woman's name. Feels like when you're gendering it
Speaker 5:  two, you're gendering like the free
Speaker 5:  less good one. Oof. And it's like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  don't do that.
Speaker 4:  Stop.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's a bummer for a bunch of reasons. Yeah, I totally agree. And I
Speaker 6:  mean, you think about we went from the era of Syria, Alexa, Cortana, these
Speaker 6:  like explicitly gendered assistance that were
Speaker 6:  problematic for that reason. And a bunch of others,
Speaker 5:  Cortana was named after a Halo character. To be fair,
Speaker 4:  Amazon explicitly and aggressively gender
Speaker 4:  select to be a way. Oh, yeah. Yeah. Which is very weird.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But then we, we were, we were heading towards, I think a slightly
Speaker 6:  better place where like, I still think it's ridiculous that we've
Speaker 6:  allowed GPT to just become a thing. People say, like, it just upsets me
Speaker 6:  greatly that that's in the language now. But chat
Speaker 6:  GPT not a gendered thing, not a very good product name, but not a gendered
Speaker 6:  thing. Bard, eh, but then Gemini not a
Speaker 6:  gendered thing unless you have strong feelings about the Zodiac. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Copilot
Speaker 6:  Copilot, same thing. And so it was like, okay, we're getting, we're getting
Speaker 6:  towards thinking of these as products, not people, which is the right
Speaker 6:  strategy. And then, yeah, I, I agree. Gemma is a big bummer
Speaker 6:  back in the wrong direction. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh, so no one can keep track of them. Yeah. On top of that, oh my God. How
Speaker 5:  Many, how many can, can anybody name all of the current
Speaker 5:  flavors of Gemini
Speaker 4:  Gemini Advanced Workplace? Okay.
Speaker 6:  No, that's a subscription that gets you Gemini Nano, no,
Speaker 6:  sorry, Gemini Ultra, but there's Gemini, ultra
Speaker 6:  Pro and Nano. There's Gemma two B and seven B. But coming soon, there's Gemini
Speaker 6:  1.5, which is in Gemini 1.5 Pro, which is different from Gemini
Speaker 6:  1.0. Pro Gemini Ultra will eventually be Gemini 1.5 also.
Speaker 6:  And I've lost it. That was as far as I can go. But then there's
Speaker 4:  Gemini. That's really well done. I wanted a,
Speaker 6:  There's Gemini in several things. There's Gemini in Vertex, which is different
Speaker 6:  from Gemini in the Gemini that you experienced. I can't, it just,
Speaker 6:  you know that thing where you like, wish you could replace the nineties song
Speaker 6:  lyrics in your brain with like, useful information. This is how I feel about
Speaker 6:  Gemini. Like,
Speaker 4:  Knowing
Speaker 6:  This is making my life worse.
Speaker 4:  I still remember the, the names of almost every single HTC phone. It's,
Speaker 4:  I can't remember people's faces and names, but I can, I can just rattle off
Speaker 4:  the spec.
Speaker 6:  The Dr. S. That's sick.
Speaker 4:  128 Get megahertz presser. It's like a real, I know it, it's in my heart.
Speaker 4:  Kind of a cool phone. Have a cool phone. I can still do Netbook
Speaker 4:  Intel had 1.3 Gigaherz processors and the, and, and one
Speaker 4:  point. But you can't do all
Speaker 3:  The Geminis.
Speaker 4:  Can't do all the Geminis. Gotta go to David for that. All right, we gotta
Speaker 4:  take a break. This has been a very heavy first segment. We, we've had everything.
Speaker 4:  We've had The future of the internet. We've, we have Manuel
Speaker 4:  Miranda,
Speaker 4:  just everyone just pull over the car, listen to these ads, just
Speaker 4:  breathe. We're gonna be back with not one, but two lightning rounds. We'll
Speaker 4:  be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Now, before I went to break, I mentioned advertising.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which I only do in the context of asking you,
Speaker 4:  begging you really to sponsor the lightning round, which again, we have yet
Speaker 4:  to do. But If, you do it. I will al you can buy my very integrity.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just for sale. Just pay the money is
Speaker 4:  what I'm saying. But I'm aware that many
Speaker 4:  listeners of our show have had some issues with our other advertising over,
Speaker 4:  which we have no control. But I'm happy to report that
Speaker 4:  David mostly and Liam have gone and done some
Speaker 4:  investigating. And the problem of the repeat ads at least
Speaker 4:  should be resolved. Yeah. Correct me if I'm wrong.
Speaker 6:  If If, you keep getting I was, I mean, I was, I'm gonna say If, you keep
Speaker 6:  getting them, let us know. But like, oh boy. Do you already, so if
Speaker 6:  it keeps happening, get at me and we'll, we'll keep fighting the good fight,
Speaker 6:  but hopefully it should start to get better.
Speaker 4:  By the way, is that ever evidence that your phones are not listening to you?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Right. Because
Speaker 4:  If they were, they would stop.
Speaker 4:  No, that's just Ad Tech on wrong. Much like the the the AIs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just going off the rails. The ad tech is just off the rails. So we're,
Speaker 4:  we're trying to get it fixed. All right. Lightning Rounds doubled up. My
Speaker 4:  idea was that we would just do everything on the list as fast as we could.
Speaker 4:  But then David reminded me that I am the host of the show and do not have
Speaker 4:  that ability.
Speaker 6:  That's correct.
Speaker 5:  We can't do a four hour podcast today.
Speaker 4:  Alright. But I think Alex, you and
Speaker 4:  I could do four hours on the, on your lightning round item. What is
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent? So we, we talked about it briefly last week, but
Speaker 5:  Visio is definitely being acquired by Walmart for
Speaker 5:  $2.3 billion. And they were really, really, really
Speaker 5:  explicit that it's for the ad tech.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of ad tech, like
Speaker 5:  It was, it was not like, well we love these TVs and just wanna like improve
Speaker 5:  our in-house brand and make everything better. It was this good
Speaker 5:  ad tech y'all we're gonna, we're gonna make some money. And I believe
Speaker 5:  even Vizio said, Walmart's approach is aligned with Vizios mission
Speaker 5:  and vision and our technology will help bring a scaled connected TV
Speaker 5:  advertising platform to Walmart Connect. So
Speaker 5:  get excited if you're a Walmart Connect fan.
Speaker 4:  Can I try Yeah. To put this in
Speaker 4:  context
Speaker 5:  Attempt
Speaker 4:  That isn't bad. Yeah, I can't but let me try. Can I try?
Speaker 5:  I wanna try. I wanna hear it. I wanna hear the attempt.
Speaker 4:  So we think of the big advertising companies out there on the internet as
Speaker 4:  being Google and Meta. I think largely Google and Meta are the big ad
Speaker 4:  companies in the internet. Then there's a host of smaller ad tech vendors
Speaker 4:  that don't have the technical ability to not play the same ad 500 times in
Speaker 4:  a row.
Speaker 4:  Just putting that out there as a piece of information for you. Mm. The
Speaker 4:  category of advertising provider that is most competing with Google and Meta
Speaker 4:  right now is not the small ad tech companies, it's
Speaker 4:  retail ad networks from Amazon and Walmart and Best, Buy and others.
Speaker 4:  So the retailers have started to form their own advertising
Speaker 4:  situations. In particular, Amazon is one of the biggest competitors to Google
Speaker 4:  and Meta out there right now in terms of ad they're growing real fast. But
Speaker 4:  big companies like Best, Buy and Walmart and what have you,
Speaker 4:  target are all building these systems as well. So you go to Walmart
Speaker 4:  dot com, a lot of what you see is basically advertising. Yep. You don't perceive
Speaker 4:  it that way, but I think If, you go to Amazon, you definitely have
Speaker 4:  started to perceive it that way. Amazon would also love to show you more
Speaker 4:  and more ads everywhere you go and do tracking and conversion. So that
Speaker 4:  instead of buying ads from Meta to run on Instagram
Speaker 4:  that convert you into a sale on a website or a sale on Amazon,
Speaker 4:  Amazon is running the ads everywhere and converting you at higher rates on
Speaker 4:  its own platform. And buying Whole Foods and buying Whole Foods. It's all,
Speaker 4:  it's literally that is essentially the same thing, right? So you just see
Speaker 4:  what's what's happening, right? Yeah. At the end of, at the end of this version
Speaker 4:  of the internet is just, someone's gotta buy something like
Speaker 4:  that. That is how the internet is organized. Yep. And the pressure to actually
Speaker 4:  get you to buy things is going up and up and up is this version
Speaker 4:  of the internet comes to whatever conclusion it's gonna come to. And you
Speaker 4:  can see that all over the place that you're being pushed towards actually
Speaker 4:  spending money as opposed to taking VC subsidized free
Speaker 4:  things everywhere. So if you're Walmart and you have a big retail ad
Speaker 4:  network and you're looking at Amazon, which literally owns football
Speaker 4:  and everything else and has home hubs in your house,
Speaker 4:  you're like, how do we get more money into our advertising system?
Speaker 4:  We need to get on TVs. Yep. We need a TV ad
Speaker 4:  network. So we're gonna buy Vizio, which is the TV we
Speaker 4:  sell the most of and we can say to our retail ad network customers, now you
Speaker 4:  can place an ad for diapers on, not only on Walmart dot com but we can
Speaker 4:  sell you inventory on TVs too. 'cause we do all this tracking on the TV system.
Speaker 4:  Is that good?
Speaker 5:  I mean if I was an advertiser, that's super compelling as
Speaker 5:  just a regular person who wants less advertising.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Turn off the wifi on your tv. That's
Speaker 5:  The answer to that question. Yeah. Less, less compelling.
Speaker 4:  But that is a hundred percent the pressure on all these companies. And
Speaker 4:  If, you're Walmart, you're like, oh we can't just give the entire
Speaker 4:  advertising ecosystem over to Amazon. And that is very much where
Speaker 4:  Amazon is going. Yep. And you, you, I talk to these CMOs,
Speaker 4:  I talk to these folks out in the world. I have them on decoder and they're
Speaker 4:  all just looking at it and they're like, connected TV is the thing.
Speaker 4:  It is the next piece of the advertising puzzle that has gonna sort itself
Speaker 4:  out.
Speaker 6:  It's a billboard in your house. Yeah. Is increasingly the way it's being
Speaker 6:  looked at. It shouldn't
Speaker 4:  And there's whatt, there's tele. Right. Or that has literally a billboard
Speaker 4:  in your house.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And all there, the only thing they're doing differently is just saying
Speaker 6:  the quiet part loud there. There's just like, look, you wanna look at some
Speaker 6:  ads, we will give you the TV for free and you can either make that deal or
Speaker 6:  you can pay for the TV and look at ads like every day that
Speaker 6:  goes by. I think telly is a better and better idea 'cause it's happening
Speaker 6:  to you either way. And you might as well get the TV for free.
Speaker 5:  I reject that. I like, I mean is my, my LG TV
Speaker 5:  currently connected to the internet. Yes. Do I get a weird like little
Speaker 5:  banner ad at the bottom every time I turn my TV on. Really?
Speaker 5:  Why? It's usually like
Speaker 4:  Connected to the internet.
Speaker 5:  That's the thing. I'm just gonna go after this call. I'm gonna go disconnect
Speaker 5:  it. 'cause I'm just like,
Speaker 4:  Wait, you did a mime of an ethernet cable. Is your TV on ethernet?
Speaker 5:  You know what? I need like good connections. I want, I want everything to
Speaker 4:  Connected. Well I'm saying my TV's on ethernet. Yeah. Yeah. I don't know
Speaker 4:  why it shouldn't be on the internet, but it has to be. If I wanna watch Bravia
Speaker 4:  Core Sony's premium 80 megabits per second. Internet Netflix for stream Netflix.
Speaker 4:  but it has four movies on it. The other day I, I was effectively forced
Speaker 4:  to watch zero Dark 30 on Bravia core 'cause it's the only movie
Speaker 4:  that's available. And then I'm pretty sure when Max wasn't eating breakfast
Speaker 4:  the next morning I did some CIA shit to her like straight up. I
Speaker 4:  was like, your behavior will determine how you're treated. I'm like, she's
Speaker 4:  eating apples. That's what happens. You want zero dark 30 on Bravia core
Speaker 4:  in crystal clear quality Sony. So
Speaker 4:  you get they, they didn't buy the letting round. I just really, I just really
Speaker 4:  like high rate streams. Do
Speaker 5:  You, do you get an advertisement on Sony?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. For,
Speaker 5:  For the ccia a it was watch
Speaker 4:  A movie about torture.
Speaker 5:  Is the CIA advertisement?
Speaker 4:  I do turn it off. Yeah. In my era profiles when I'm not using the
Speaker 4:  built-in apps. That's smart. 'cause they don't want the TV talking about
Speaker 4:  me. I
Speaker 5:  Should, I should do
Speaker 6:  That. Mine is the only thing blocked on my network is is my, my Visio tv
Speaker 6:  actually. Do
Speaker 4:  You still get packets? My lg TV
Speaker 4:  just hammers that firewall with packets. No. Even if it's not allowed to.
Speaker 5:  They love to talk. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just like, come on,
Speaker 5:  Who are you talking to? The advertisers. Yep. They wanna know all
Speaker 5:  about what you did last night. It was nothing. I watched k dramas and smoked
Speaker 5:  a lot of weed. That's, that's all I did enjoy that
Speaker 5:  fact.
Speaker 4:  Lg, the local bodega owners are not like in the connected TV market. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They're, they're screwed man. Like just send me one and I'd be, I'd be
Speaker 5:  on on my way. Just some tacos. Yeah. Oh my God.
Speaker 4:  I feel really Vizio. We did a lot of coverage of Vizio. Yeah. I wrote a feature
Speaker 4:  about Vizio. We had Matt McCree who was the old CTO of Vizio on the show
Speaker 4:  many, many, many times.
Speaker 4:  They, they tried to get into every big market they could get into. Was it
Speaker 4:  with phones, laptop? We talked about this last week. And to have them become
Speaker 4:  just a commodity screen advertising vendor, I mean is pretty
Speaker 4:  sad. I don't know
Speaker 5:  If it's that sad because to some extent Vizio is pretty
Speaker 5:  prescient on this stuff. Like they were, they were one of the first into
Speaker 5:  advertising. That's why Le Echo, I love it.
Speaker 5:  one of them was because of the advertising tech. Like it was always, Vizio
Speaker 5:  was really good at this. They figured it out before a lot of other people
Speaker 5:  and then took forever to get acquired by someone who could actually afford
Speaker 5:  because they
Speaker 6:  Were being investigated for the shady stuff they were doing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. But like I said, they, they, there
Speaker 6:  Was so early in learning how to trick you into giving bigger data. No, they
Speaker 4:  Were like, but let me, let me give you a counter example to this. Okay. This
Speaker 4:  is the longest lightning round item in this is why we can't Lightning
Speaker 5:  Round. Sorry.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but lemme give you the counter example to this. You can feel a lot
Speaker 4:  of ways about meta. You can feel a lot of ways about Google.
Speaker 4:  They took all of the excess profit of their actual functional
Speaker 4:  advertising businesses and invented a lot of stuff like,
Speaker 4:  just straight up.
Speaker 5:  That's fair.
Speaker 4:  Like Google's like, I dunno, the car should drive themselves
Speaker 5:  Pixel phones, that's a thing.
Speaker 4:  And then Google's like, ah, that didn't work. And the killer, like Google
Speaker 4:  Meta is like, we should do reality Labs legs. We invented
Speaker 4:  legs in the Metaverse. Everybody we did it, it took $20 billion. Like all
Speaker 4:  of that excess cash that their advertising put out, it
Speaker 4:  made them give services for free or largely free it. They
Speaker 4:  invested in a bunch of core internet infrastructure technology.
Speaker 5:  Let them buy into a monopoly on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Let them buy into Monopoly. Like you can, like I said, you can feel a lot
Speaker 4:  of ways about those companies. Yeah. But all of the excess advertising profits
Speaker 4:  they made built consumer products that people value.
Speaker 5:  What did Vizio use it for?
Speaker 4:  Right? This is what I'm saying. Yeah. Right. The idea of Visios will do all
Speaker 4:  these excess profits from television advertising and then we'll like, make
Speaker 4:  really good laptops or we'll make really good and they just didn't do the
Speaker 4:  things. Like,
Speaker 5:  They didn't even start, they like, even the TVs got worse. Even
Speaker 4:  The TVs got worse.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We had so many commenters last week reach out, be like, yeah, I had
Speaker 5:  a Vizio tv. I loved it, but then it sucked. And I'm like, oh, that, that's
Speaker 5:  a bummer. There,
Speaker 4:  There's something there that is just, it's just sad. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Eli, it's, it's super telling that the end of that idea was not
Speaker 6:  Vizio said, we're gonna take your advertising dollars and use them to make
Speaker 6:  the TVs better. Which is what it should have been. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  that's actually a reasonable trade that reasonable people might
Speaker 6:  make. Right? Like I, I will, I will sign up for
Speaker 6:  some version of this advertising network that is coming to me anyway in exchange
Speaker 6:  for a better and or cheaper television. And that is like a flywheel that
Speaker 6:  kind of works and Vizio just went, nevermind. We're just gonna
Speaker 6:  keep all of that money and we're gonna keep making the TVs worse. And this
Speaker 6:  is what Roku is doing. This is what the prime TV TVs are starting to do.
Speaker 6:  Like cheap TVs that are supported by advertising are not getting
Speaker 6:  better. They're getting worse. And that sucks.
Speaker 4:  All right. Yeah. This is my hard pivot to my lightning round item, which
Speaker 4:  is once again complaining about my Frame tv. Oh God.
Speaker 6:  Speaking
Speaker 4:  Of sucky tv, tell, I've just bought a lot of stuff for this house. I just
Speaker 4:  have thoughts about all of it. The
Speaker 6:  Good news about this one is it was very expensive so, you know, really played
Speaker 6:  this perfectly
Speaker 4:  Well. So no, my lightning round item is actually Samsung is
Speaker 4:  expanding or cast support across most of its devices.
Speaker 4:  We haven't talked a lot about or cast on the show at cs. I went and visited
Speaker 4:  jbl, which has or cast support across its line or CAST is
Speaker 4:  one of the coolest standards. Like we make a lot of fun of
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth on the show generally, or CAST is maybe the coolest
Speaker 4:  upgrade to Bluetooth I've seen in a long time. So it is completely vendor
Speaker 4:  agnostic. People. You have devices that support or
Speaker 4:  cast and Bluetooth, you just push the button. They all just start playing
Speaker 4:  the same music. And I've seen this demoed now across brands. I've seen this
Speaker 4:  demoed across speakers. JBLs demo was, they
Speaker 4:  just had speakers in a living room, some travel
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth speakers, their new speaker that can do both Google
Speaker 4:  Assistant and Alexa on the same device, which is really cool. And they just
Speaker 4:  put 'em all in the room and they pushed all the, they pushed buttons and
Speaker 4:  the Bluetooth speakers, the little travel JBL Bluetooth speakers became the
Speaker 4:  rears in a home theater situation.
Speaker 5:  Whoa. Okay. That's cool.
Speaker 4:  It's cool. Yeah, like that's just cool that they like, they're, they're able
Speaker 4:  to do this using a standard. It's not some proprietary stuff. And the idea
Speaker 4:  is that you should be able to do it with all the speakers you have in your
Speaker 4:  house. Very cool. So Samsung is bringing Aura Cast to
Speaker 4:  tons of its products and then of course the TVs are getting 360
Speaker 4:  reality audio in case you need Is
Speaker 5:  Is, is the Frame TV gonna get Aura Cast?
Speaker 4:  So the Frame TV is the weirdest kind
Speaker 4:  of product. I could write 10,000 words about the Frame TV and I You're gonna
Speaker 5:  Have to at some point.
Speaker 4:  I'm obsessed with the, the existence of the Frame tv. The popular, the Frame
Speaker 4:  TV is an old panel.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, thats one of the reasons like they mark it up is they take an old cheap
Speaker 5:  panel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're just, they're just put a
Speaker 5:  Cool bezel on it.
Speaker 4:  Bam. So they do some cool backlight stuff. So it goes to sleep mode. The
Speaker 4:  display dims, it's Matt, they've got the art store.
Speaker 5:  You just said something nice about the Frame tv.
Speaker 4:  There is a, there is a little bit of work in the Frame TV that makes people
Speaker 4:  want it. Yeah, because people watch TikTok, they don't watch their tv so
Speaker 4:  they just want the artwork. Here's the thing that is driving me bananas about
Speaker 4:  the Frame TV right now. Hmm. When you turn it off,
Speaker 4:  it is not actually off. It goes into art mode, which is its special
Speaker 4:  art mode. So then when you turn it off, it goes all the way off and then
Speaker 4:  when you turn it back on again it comes all the way back on
Speaker 5:  No art mode.
Speaker 4:  Very confusing. So
Speaker 5:  You have to go to get to art mode, you have to power on once the power on
Speaker 5:  twice,
Speaker 4:  None of this matters If, you are a normal human being. Wait, it's like
Speaker 6:  The thing where you pull the light switch once and it turns on, you pull
Speaker 6:  it again and it dims and then again and it's off. But then If you pull it
Speaker 6:  again, it goes all the way on. That's a perfectly normal setup. That's
Speaker 6:  exactly how that should
Speaker 5:  Work. It's confusing,
Speaker 4:  But none of this matters. If, you are a normal human being who buys a Frame
Speaker 4:  TV and puts it on the wall using the Samsung frame If. you buy any
Speaker 4:  third party frame, it is more than likely that you will cover up the
Speaker 4:  actual sensors that make the frame TV work, which is of course
Speaker 4:  what we did. Yes. There is now a $99 dongle from
Speaker 4:  deco frames.com. It is an external, it's called the SRS two. It's huge.
Speaker 4:  It's just a sensor dongle for the frame tv. It is beautiful. No people
Speaker 4:  hate it. You have to run another wired TV and then put a dongle out in the
Speaker 4:  room because you've covered up at the sensors. So then you might think, if
Speaker 4:  you're like me, what you're gonna do is you are already of course running
Speaker 4:  a, a Raspberry Pi with HomeBridge. Yeah. You'll just put ties in into HomeBridge
Speaker 4:  and control the frame TV using the other sensors that you might have in your
Speaker 4:  house. And then you'll realize that Samsung has taken the art mode
Speaker 4:  API out of the 2022 and up frame TVs rude. So you cannot
Speaker 4:  just tell the thing to turn on an art mode. You have to tell it to turn on
Speaker 4:  running into the problem in which your wife keeps watching the
Speaker 4:  horrible couples therapy show on Showtime. And she keeps turning the TV off
Speaker 4:  at night so that when it turns on at eight 30 in the morning when your
Speaker 4:  thermostat in your bedroom detects motion, it turns on and starts playing
Speaker 4:  couples therapy at you. This is very bad. And the solution to this problem
Speaker 4:  is there's only two. One, you can take the frame off your tv,
Speaker 4:  but Samsung doesn't solve a black frame. Or you have to tell your wife
Speaker 4:  who is a divorce lawyer that she's turning off the TV wrong.
Speaker 5:  How you doing buddy?
Speaker 4:  It's bad. I just, the TV is just off all the time. Like we don't know
Speaker 4:  what to do. Just don't use it anymore. We reached it in past like I'm just
Speaker 4:  turning the thing on manually in the morning and leaving that couldn't,
Speaker 5:  Couldn't my home assistant change the channel for you.
Speaker 4:  There's no channel because art mode is not a channel or an input. It is off.
Speaker 5:  Has somebody made like a third party art mode?
Speaker 4:  It's just like a USB stick.
Speaker 5:  Just like I just wanted to get like as janky as possible for
Speaker 4:  You. It's bad and I, no one knows what they took the API out of if all they
Speaker 4:  need to do is put the end point back on. So you can just say go into art
Speaker 4:  mode. Maybe
Speaker 5:  It was a bug. Maybe somebody just
Speaker 4:  Realized you can sort of fake
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 4:  Because you can tell HomeBridge
Speaker 4:  this is very dumb. I love this. You can create a virtual power button.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And have HomeKit push it. Yes. But then you have to guess
Speaker 4:  how the TV was turned off at night.
Speaker 5:  Beautiful.
Speaker 4:  It's bad. All this is bad. Beautiful forecast is good. Frame tv,
Speaker 4:  bad nightmare situation. NELI,
Speaker 6:  I just, I just, before we move on, I just want to congratulate you in, in
Speaker 6:  the long history of The Vergecast, you have made what I would call many of
Speaker 6:  Eli's niche complaints. That was the most
Speaker 6:  niche complaint I have ever. The total addressable market of that complaint
Speaker 6:  is it's every
Speaker 4:  Frame TV owner, every frame TV owner has truck,
Speaker 5:  They all use Homerage.
Speaker 4:  Go onto the frame TV sub corpus of Reddit
Speaker 4:  and you will see an infinite number of people. There are
Speaker 4:  people in this world who have bought bulk fiber optic cable
Speaker 4:  to read to and mirrors, to trick the
Speaker 4:  sensors of the frame TV into seeing light. That
Speaker 5:  Has to be more expensive than the $90 dongle
Speaker 6:  Also defeats the purpose of the beautiful television. That doesn't look like
Speaker 6:  a television.
Speaker 4:  No, no. 'cause they're drilling holes. Oh, into the frame. Put poking the
Speaker 4:  little fiber optic cable out of the frame than running the fiber optic cable
Speaker 4:  to the sensor where it shines in. And this is a quote from the sub
Speaker 4:  corpus post into a disco ball of little mirrors that they've made
Speaker 4:  so that the the, you can, the sensor can detect the change in light because
Speaker 4:  otherwise you have to have the dumb sensor. Don't go out in the world
Speaker 5:  When
Speaker 6:  That solution kicks ass. It's awesome.
Speaker 4:  The rules, it rules. That's I've, I've posted this onto the, onto the
Speaker 4:  website. Are
Speaker 5:  You gonna build a disco ball?
Speaker 4:  I've thought our frame is metal So I haves like drill. It's not great.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what to do. But I will tell you one option is not you're turning
Speaker 4:  off the TV wrong.
Speaker 5:  No you, it's tough one. Nope. You can't do that. It's not
Speaker 4:  Not appropriate.
Speaker 4:  But then the TV turning night in the morning playing couples therapy
Speaker 4:  at is also not acceptable.
Speaker 5:  There's just no winning in that
Speaker 4:  One. Pierce wants your light here.
Speaker 6:  Mine is a better screen. You can hang on your wall. That instead of causing
Speaker 6:  you infinite grief will solve quite a bit of your grief.
Speaker 6:  It's the Amazon Echo Hub, which was announced a while ago and the reviews
Speaker 6:  of it are starting to come out and it's starting to ship. I love this thing
Speaker 6:  and it is also like deeply funny that the Echo Hub needs to
Speaker 6:  exist. It's just a screen that you put on your wall to use
Speaker 6:  to control your smart home. Yeah, it is. It is
Speaker 6:  the simplest thing you could imagine. Amazon basically took like a fire
Speaker 6:  tablet or an Echo show and just took all the features out of it except the
Speaker 6:  buttons for controlling your lights. And then was like, do you want this
Speaker 6:  to hang on your wall? And everybody said, yes I do. And
Speaker 6:  Genii reviewed it, really liked it, said it has like totally fit into her
Speaker 6:  life and her family's. And to me this is just like we, we
Speaker 6:  need to finally get past the idea that, oh,
Speaker 6:  an app for your smartphone is the solution to this problem.
Speaker 6:  Like yes, no, it's not buttons on my wall or the
Speaker 6:  solution to this problem. Those buttons can be on screen, that's fine. But
Speaker 6:  like voice assistance ain't it? Apps on my phone, ain't it? Like
Speaker 6:  we need new systems for this stuff and kudos to Amazon for having
Speaker 6:  actually pushed at that.
Speaker 5:  Which do you think is gonna like affect more marriages?
Speaker 5:  The frame TV situation or the existence of the
Speaker 5:  Hub?
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's the existence of the Echo Hub. The number of of
Speaker 4:  Beleaguered
Speaker 6:  Partners of smart home nerds who
Speaker 6:  now don't have to like, okay, so my sister
Speaker 6:  lives in a home with someone who is big into the smart home and she had to
Speaker 6:  memorize the names of her lamps so that she could tell Alexa
Speaker 6:  which ones to turn on. And it's like there's the living room lamp, but then
Speaker 6:  there's the big living room lamp and If. you just ask for one and not the
Speaker 6:  other. You're, and this is terrible, but you know what's great is when you
Speaker 6:  can walk up to the wall and flip a switch and I will happily
Speaker 6:  exchange that switch for a button but a person can figure out how to
Speaker 6:  use it. And that is terrific. And it's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be, I had to get one of those like hue light buttons back in the day
Speaker 5:  for when I had a roommate because after multiple times of me
Speaker 5:  accidentally turning off all the lights in the bathroom while she was in
Speaker 5:  the shower,
Speaker 4:  It's not good. Not good. Yeah. We should actually just have Jen on the show
Speaker 4:  so she can describe how her family deals with her job
Speaker 5:  Carefully.
Speaker 4:  'cause literally her teenage children are like, we are just gonna live
Speaker 4:  in the dark. We're not gonna try to figure out how to
Speaker 6:  Well there's a whole lot of Jen on the show the next few weeks, by the way,
Speaker 6:  So, I get excited. I think
Speaker 4:  I, here's the thing about this Hub that I'm thinking about.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't sit flush. It sticks out a
Speaker 4:  Little. It sticks out a little. You gotta power all this, all the normal
Speaker 4:  stuff of putting screen wall. It's a product made for the matter. Smart Home
Speaker 4:  standard but Matter isn't good enough to support this product. Yeah, because
Speaker 4:  what you want is a bunch of smart home stuff in your house and you're like,
Speaker 4:  okay, I control most of it with my Android phone with Google Home. Or I control
Speaker 4:  it with HomeKit on my phone or my iOS phone. And then I bought this awesome
Speaker 4:  screen from Amazon and it's also a great smart home controller. And
Speaker 4:  the reality of this product is like, it's great if all your shit's in Alexa.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it does have a ZigBee radio. Right. It's a
Speaker 4:  matter control. It is. It's got like a, it's ready for The future
Speaker 5:  Of stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But the way you want it to work, like the way I'd want it to work. I do
Speaker 4:  everything at HomeKit because the idea of getting anyone else in my family
Speaker 4:  to do any to open another app besides control
Speaker 4:  center is not happening.
Speaker 5:  I feel like, I feel like you'll probably like
Speaker 5:  somebody will have a solution pretty quickly for HomeKit users and other
Speaker 5:  folks to use this thing through Matter. 'cause matter kind of sucks but like
Speaker 5:  HomeBridge But
Speaker 4:  Matter should be the thing. It
Speaker 5:  Should be. But it's
Speaker 4:  Right. Like you should, you should be setting everything up in any one of
Speaker 4:  these ecosystems and then you're like, I've added a matter device that
Speaker 4:  can see all those rooms and see all those devices
Speaker 4:  and it, it we're so close. I feel like Jen writes the we're so close with
Speaker 4:  Matter story, like it's the heart of every story about these devices right
Speaker 5:  Now. She likes size as she writes it, she's like, oh
Speaker 4:  We're so, she actually has an automation setup where she just sized loudly
Speaker 4:  into a microphone and ChatGPT writes the matter isn't quite there yet. Story.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. Alright, we should take another break. And we're back with
Speaker 4:  a non gadget lightning round. This one will have fewer front
Speaker 4:  TVs in it. I promise you. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  safely.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Lemme tell you about Tizen, the
Speaker 4:  software that powers the frame.
Speaker 10:  No,
Speaker 6:  We are so close.
Speaker 4:  I'm telling you, I could write 10,000 words about what the frame TV represents
Speaker 4:  in our culture.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna happen at some point. Yeah, we're gonna like be like, Nila, you
Speaker 5:  can't work at all for the next week. Just write 10,000 words on Vizio.
Speaker 4:  I'm just, I like
Speaker 6:  The the like one for me, one for them thing. You're like, okay. I wrote Welcome
Speaker 6:  to Hell Elon. A lot of people read that. That was great. Now I'm gonna write
Speaker 6:  a feature about Tyson.
Speaker 4:  This looks for me, I heard this. I write to
Speaker 4:  David David at The Verge dot com. If you'd like me to write 10,000 words
Speaker 4:  on the frame tv. Please do. Yes please.
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna say this, I think the Frame TV is Samsung's most important
Speaker 4:  product. I mean
Speaker 5:  I I think you're right.
Speaker 4:  It is. It is by far. It is the one that they invented. They invent
Speaker 4:  like they didn't, it's not a copy of anything. Even I know some Samsung
Speaker 4:  people, they invented a lot of stuff. For example, Samsung invented the concept
Speaker 4:  of taking fake photos of the moon. Very important concept. But the Frame
Speaker 4:  TV they just invented. There wasn't a thing and then they made a thing. And
Speaker 4:  then the thing is very successful. Other copy are copying the thing. but
Speaker 4:  it is as a cultural object that people desire. The
Speaker 4:  Frame TV is top of the list for Samsung.
Speaker 5:  Remember when it was in the
Speaker 4:  MoMA that and the weird bespoke appliances they make.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  People like this, but whatever. Yeah. All right. Non
Speaker 4:  gadget. Lightning round. David, I think yours, we've
Speaker 4:  got an hour to do on this one. Go ahead. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Easily an hour to do on this one. So we are
Speaker 4:  Bad at Lightning.
Speaker 6:  I know. This one actually I don't think will be that long. And I am desperate
Speaker 6:  to hear people's feedback because I have been hearing people's feedback nonstop
Speaker 6:  for two days. And I'm just a glutton for punishment. Apple launch an
Speaker 6:  app called Apple Sports, which is a very simple app
Speaker 6:  for seeing sports scores. It's not a very good app. It's missing a lot of
Speaker 6:  sports. It shows lineups in a sort of
Speaker 6:  deranged, nonsensical way. but it does in fact for
Speaker 6:  some sports sometimes show scores.
Speaker 6:  And there is either less
Speaker 6:  to this app than I think. And it's just kind of a weird side project that
Speaker 6:  like Eddie Q found on somebody's computer and shipped
Speaker 6:  or this is a harbinger of huge things to come.
Speaker 6:  And I posited that there are two things that are possible for Apple
Speaker 6:  sports. One is that Apple is about to make even
Speaker 6:  more big moves into sports streaming, which I think there are lots of
Speaker 6:  reasons for and we can talk about. The other one is that this is
Speaker 6:  the app you would launch If. you wanted to get into betting in
Speaker 6:  interesting ways. one of the controversial things that has been in this app
Speaker 6:  so far is you can see betting odds for all the games that you're looking
Speaker 6:  at, which is powered by DraftKings. I would point out you can turn it off
Speaker 6:  in settings, but it's on by default. And I posited that this
Speaker 6:  is what it would look like if Apple were to very slowly start getting into
Speaker 6:  sports gambling. And many hundreds of people have told me how
Speaker 6:  dumb I am for that take. And I continue to believe that I'm correct.
Speaker 5:  I feel like you're probably correct, but also like that's the worst
Speaker 5:  thing. I don't want you to be correct. So,
Speaker 6:  But this is what I wanna talk about because I think that
Speaker 6:  the, the Overton window on sports gambling has moved
Speaker 6:  so far that the idea that this is somehow against Apple's
Speaker 6:  brand to do is just no longer the truth.
Speaker 6:  And I like sports gambling is just life. It's just mainstream
Speaker 6:  life. Now
Speaker 5:  I saw the 60 Minutes episode about this a couple of weeks ago. It's true.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 6:  Really? Was there one
Speaker 5:  Neil? I had to listen to me talk about it at the office.
Speaker 4:  One of the things about working with Alex that I think the listener should
Speaker 4:  know is every now and again she comes up all revved up on 60
Speaker 4:  Minutes.
Speaker 4:  It's just like, it's just a delight. It's just very confusing. Yeah, it is.
Speaker 4:  It is very much like working with a, like a hotheaded retiree.
Speaker 5:  Then I take my Metamucil and have a nap. It's great.
Speaker 4:  A dedicated viewer. 60 minutes. Yeah. Which does make some very good journalism
Speaker 4:  I think sometimes. Yeah, for some people.
Speaker 4:  But it's, it's true that it's 60 minutes to do a gambling is bad. It's very
Speaker 4:  addictive. I agree. If, you are Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  and you're looking at declining sales, you're looking at Buring services
Speaker 4:  revenue. Dude. What is the ultimate services business? Just taking
Speaker 4:  money from people. Yep. Just, just directly extracting
Speaker 4:  money from people. Give us some money and maybe this machine will give you
Speaker 4:  some money back. But not all the time. In fact, not most of the time. And
Speaker 4:  If, you're in Las Vegas, you're standing in a monument to how little
Speaker 4:  money the machine will give back to you and people still give money to the
Speaker 4:  machine. And you have to imagine Tim Cook stands, he sat in this sphere
Speaker 4:  looking at Bono going, I gotta get in on this. And
Speaker 4:  then we have the sports app.
Speaker 5:  Isn't gambling not allowed in the app store?
Speaker 5:  Like is there weirdness around this? I
Speaker 4:  Thought it was a lot, but it depends. It depends.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's like,
Speaker 4:  Depends.
Speaker 5:  There's
Speaker 4:  Lines. It depends. So FanDuel and or FanDuel and DraftKings are in the app
Speaker 4:  store, right? Yep. You just get those apps. So it depends like so FanDuel
Speaker 4:  and DraftKings are just in the app store. You can just do it. It's legal
Speaker 4:  in some states. I think App Apple doesn't. Apple has some weird lines about
Speaker 4:  what it allows when it's legal and not legal. But
Speaker 5:  If I just wanted to play the digital slots,
Speaker 4:  Nope. Games of chance are not allowed in the absolute
Speaker 5:  And that feels weird to me. Like it feels
Speaker 5:  disingenuous if you're gonna, if you're going to let gambling happen. Well,
Speaker 4:  So here, here's, I think we should make this distinction right now. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And David, I think this is my pushback on your, this is Apple getting into
Speaker 4:  gambling. Yes. Even when gambling is morally frowned upon, right? When it
Speaker 4:  was not legal in most places and whatever the newspapers would print the
Speaker 4:  lines. Sure. Left and right. Old school football
Speaker 4:  announcers at the end of blowouts would be like, only a
Speaker 4:  handful of people are interested in this field goal. And they were making
Speaker 4:  very direct references to like whether your bookie is gonna show up and break
Speaker 4:  your arm. Yeah. That's basically what they were doing. So it
Speaker 4:  was always part, it's always been part of sports culture. So to have a Scores
Speaker 4:  app where you can see odds is not at all a
Speaker 4:  departure from what the local newspaper in Racine Wisconsin did when
Speaker 4:  I was growing up, but powered by DraftKings in
Speaker 4:  an app store where it is part of the mainstream culture where if you're trying
Speaker 4:  to grow your services revenue, boy that seems like a big, big pot of money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And also If, you If you launched a newspaper in which one of the only
Speaker 6:  two things you could do was look at the betting odds. Don't you think you'd
Speaker 6:  maybe think of that slightly differently?
Speaker 4:  Well, I dunno, like the, the New York Times ones, the athletic, the athletic
Speaker 4:  will straight up be like run articles that are like, here's how to bet today.
Speaker 4:  Sure.
Speaker 6:  Wait,
Speaker 5:  Were the, I know some of the, the scores and stuff weren't
Speaker 5:  accurate. Were the sports odds, were the odds accurate in the Apple
Speaker 6:  App? I haven't checked, to be honest. I I have not heard complaints that
Speaker 6:  they're not. But I, I couldn't
Speaker 4:  Tell you. John Gruber had a piece where he pointed out that Traffickings
Speaker 4:  has weird odds. Mm. 'cause they're all d because it's ga it's gambling.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like they, they odds are, are odds are set by odds makers. People have
Speaker 4:  different ideas. I think it is fascinating that they made this app. I think
Speaker 4:  it's rushed because they needed to get out before the MLS season kicked off,
Speaker 4:  which they own. Right. So they have a huge opportunity to promote their own
Speaker 4:  sports app ahead of it. Is this anything other than a toy
Speaker 4:  for Betty EQ remains unclear
Speaker 5:  Or is Tim Cook your new bookie?
Speaker 4:  I love the idea of Tim
Speaker 5:  In my head hat and in my head he's wearing like a little hat. Do
Speaker 5:  Bookie still wear little hats?
Speaker 4:  No. Tim Cook is a bookie would be an absolutely terrifying character.
Speaker 6:  Like Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no hat, no costume. He would win. Just actually Tim Cook in his
Speaker 4:  sweater being like, go get the money. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  He's the guy you like are in your house and you turn around and he's just
Speaker 6:  been standing there for Who knows how long. Like that's Tim Cook. The person
Speaker 6:  who
Speaker 5:  Plays him in the film adaptation would win an Oscar immediately for their,
Speaker 5:  their portrayal.
Speaker 4:  No, he's not in your house. The the heavies are in the house. Tim Cook is
Speaker 4:  the guy where he is like he's on the phone with you. The heavies grab you,
Speaker 4:  they throw you into the back of the van. Oh. You get thrown outta the van
Speaker 4:  and you're in a very nice restaurant where he's quietly eating melon and
Speaker 4:  he is like, sit down and have some melon. And then like in that moment it
Speaker 4:  becomes very clear to you that you're going to die. Yeah. Right. And you
Speaker 4:  better, you can either enjoy the melonin dye or you can not enjoy the melon
Speaker 4:  or die. But the whether or not you're dying has been long
Speaker 4:  since determined
Speaker 5:  All because you use the sports
Speaker 4:  App and that's how Tim Cook gets extracts excellent pricing on Ola screens.
Speaker 6:  Enjoy the melanin dye as a show that Apple TV Plus would run for sure.
Speaker 6:  No, but we should move on. But my, my only point is that I think
Speaker 6:  people are overestimating the gap between where Apple is
Speaker 6:  now and the Apple that just more or less runs a
Speaker 6:  betting service. Like the stuff you're describing. The only difference between
Speaker 6:  the digital slots that Apple won't let you do and the ones that it will let
Speaker 6:  you do is that you can pay money to win virtual stuff, but you can't pay
Speaker 6:  money to make actual money. And I don't think that's that big a gap. Like
Speaker 6:  do you wanna play Monopoly, go and pour all of your money into getting more
Speaker 6:  turns in Monopoly Go. Do you know what that is? That's gambling. You just
Speaker 6:  can't win anything. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's loot boxes.
Speaker 6:  That's loot boxes. That is the same thing except there's no actual real
Speaker 6:  world monetary upside for you. And I think the, the gap
Speaker 6:  between that and them saying, oh, just place your bet
Speaker 6:  with Apple Pay is like this small, it's this small
Speaker 5:  Draft Kings out there negotiating less than a 30% cut.
Speaker 4:  Are you kidding? Draft? There's a 50% cut. That's what they call
Speaker 4:  the melon cut.
Speaker 4:  There's no way. All right. What's your, what's your non
Speaker 4:  gadget Lightning round it, it's
Speaker 5:  Still on the apple front. And that's because Apple has just announced that
Speaker 5:  they're doing post quantum cryptography for iMessage.
Speaker 5:  So all of our international listeners, I'm sorry this doesn't apply to you.
Speaker 5:  Enjoy your WhatsApp and, and other other services and continue to wonder
Speaker 5:  why we all care about iMessage here in the us But for I, for for
Speaker 5:  US users, it's kind of exciting. They're claiming it is more
Speaker 5:  secure than signals post quantum
Speaker 5:  cryptography that it rolled out a couple of months ago,
Speaker 5:  unclear they, you'll you'll enjoy this. They, they also
Speaker 5:  created their own like metrics for security and they
Speaker 5:  said, well, signal's a level two, but we're a level three
Speaker 4:  Ooh. Love to put yourself on the good metric that you've made up.
Speaker 6:  Classic unmarked graph from
Speaker 5:  Apple. Yeah. I was just like, I was like beautiful.
Speaker 6:  Just imagine a line that just says security and Apple
Speaker 6:  is up high and the other ones are lower, but there's no labels on
Speaker 6:  any of the graphs. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's that's it. Yeah. That, that's it. It's, it is
Speaker 5:  exciting because as we get closer to quantum computers actually doing something
Speaker 5:  which will one day happen, like it, it's gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  All the cryptography we have now will not hold up. You'll be able to just
Speaker 5:  like brute force a lot of things one one day. And so
Speaker 5:  introducing post quantum cryptography is kind of necessary for a lot of people.
Speaker 5:  So it's exciting to see Apple doing that. But also we need to talk to like
Speaker 5:  some security researchers. There's a lot more to be done here. 'cause Apple
Speaker 5:  is just like we did it. Yeah. Everybody's like,
Speaker 4:  This is two announcements from Apple this week. Yeah. On the same with the
Speaker 4:  same sort of valence. One is we've defeated quantum
Speaker 4:  computers, which well done. Okay. We, I'm, I've come in first
Speaker 4:  in a race that I've made up. Yeah. And then two, they announced that the
Speaker 4:  iPhone 15 battery performs better than expected, but they didn't say how
Speaker 4:  well they expected it or how much better than its expectations.
Speaker 5:  You know, they're gonna drop a chart. You can determine your own accesses
Speaker 5:  for it. Yeah. Yeah. It's gonna be great. But this, this, this was just like
Speaker 5:  kind of a cool thing. I, I think Quantum cryptography is gonna become more
Speaker 5:  important in the next 10 years, 20 years
Speaker 5:  whenever quantum computing actually becomes useful. But for now it's just
Speaker 5:  like, okay, that's nice.
Speaker 4:  You should, by the way, if you're really interested in this, we'll link to
Speaker 4:  this. We just had the head of IBM quantum research on decoder.
Speaker 4:  We actually talked about whether or not you need a post quantum cryptography.
Speaker 4:  And his answer was like, I wouldn't worry about it.
Speaker 5:  It it's like, it's not a big deal right now, but it's still like That's cool.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Did you ask NELI on decoder when I need to start actually
Speaker 6:  learning what a quantum computer is?
Speaker 4:  I did. I also asked him how he feels about the movie and, and the was Quantum
Speaker 4:  mania
Speaker 4:  and he wasn't positive seems right. Yeah. He was
Speaker 4:  like, I'm happy people are thinking about Quantum computing.
Speaker 5:  Aw.
Speaker 4:  It's like, but I don't think there are entire civilization. I just feel like
Speaker 4:  it's a very good answer. It was a very politic,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I got as far with Quantum computing as like it can be both
Speaker 6:  positive and negative at the same time and somehow that lets it store a lot
Speaker 6:  of data. And I just went, well I don't get that. And that's the last thing
Speaker 6:  I learned about quantum computing.
Speaker 5:  Somebody said cubits.
Speaker 4:  Alright, go. We'll link it. He go, David, it's a good episode. He's very
Speaker 4:  charming. Okay, cool.
Speaker 6:  I'll listen to it. It's
Speaker 4:  Very good. All right. My lightning round
Speaker 4:  kind of some weird EV news. So Rivian is laying off
Speaker 4:  10% of its workforce. Ford is cutting mock
Speaker 4:  e prices. We're kind of in the second round of like the EV price scores.
Speaker 4:  At any moment, Tesla's gonna start giving away model threes like their
Speaker 4:  Echo Dots. Yeah. you know, just like they're
Speaker 6:  Gonna show you Walmart ads and they'll give you a free car for it.
Speaker 4:  It's, it feels like it's not so far off. Especially if Tesla gets
Speaker 4:  it self-driving first advertising the car is coming. Oh yeah. Twitter's gotta
Speaker 4:  sell ahead somehow. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It, it does, it does feel like the overwhelming
Speaker 4:  demand for Tesla model Wyze in threes in the middle of the
Speaker 4:  pandemic confused everyone into thinking that all anyone wanted was
Speaker 4:  Electric cars. And it was like over and so they all overproduced.
Speaker 4:  And then in, in particular for Rivian, I think this is really interesting.
Speaker 4:  you know, the R one T is a great truck. It's like a fun truck to drive. And
Speaker 4:  the R one s is a nice SUV. They're, they're so similar. It's hard to
Speaker 4:  actually talk about them as they're different cars. Like one's an SUV and
Speaker 4:  one's a truck, but they're, it's
Speaker 5:  Basically just like a camper shell was put on really, really nicely. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But like, well in a extremely well done way. Yeah. The people of R one Ss
Speaker 4:  love R one SS pristine
Speaker 5:  Camper shell.
Speaker 4:  But, but there's a reason There are ones, like, they're the same platform,
Speaker 4:  very, very similar vehicles. They're also hella expensive. Right. They're
Speaker 4:  like a hundred thousand dollars at, at the top end trims. So Rivian just
Speaker 4:  has this problem where they thought they had infinite demand for these,
Speaker 4:  for EVs and then pickup trucks, really expensive pickup trucks
Speaker 4:  were selling like hotcakes in the pandemic. So they were just like,
Speaker 4:  oh, this is great. This is working we'll overinvest in this. And then all
Speaker 4:  of that cooled off. Even the pickup truck market is like way down right now.
Speaker 4:  Like If, you are the sort of person who thinks about buying a Ram truck.
Speaker 4:  You can just, you can just get one in a way that you could not even a few
Speaker 4:  years ago, So I, think Rivian is just stuck 'cause they don't have a
Speaker 4:  cheaper car, which they're about to introduce the R two, which I think will
Speaker 4:  be really interesting and exciting and hopefully is cheaper. And then
Speaker 4:  Ford has the Lightning and the Mach e and I think every person who wanted
Speaker 4:  to buy a Lightning or a Mach e has purchased those cars and they got nothing
Speaker 4:  else. And I think we're just in a moment where there were, there were
Speaker 4:  so many vaporware cars for a minute and now there's like not
Speaker 4:  enough kinds of cars and like we're still in this, we're still in
Speaker 4:  the middle of what you would call the vaporware cycle. 'cause all the other
Speaker 4:  cars we're supposed to fill out the market aren't there. So people
Speaker 4:  aren't even cross shopping EVs or cross shopping like two expensive
Speaker 4:  platinum whitenings against other trucks that
Speaker 4:  are on deep discount. 'cause they've been sitting in lots for forever.
Speaker 5:  And the, and the companies are all like heavily lobbying the
Speaker 5:  EPA right now. Right. To to, to
Speaker 4:  Reduce the, the restrictions that force them into basically selling EVs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're like, we nobody's buying and we don't actually wanna make as many
Speaker 5:  as we said we wanted to. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And also interest rates are high and all this stuff. Yeah. But I think in
Speaker 4:  particular for Rivian, they just ran out of potential
Speaker 4:  buyers for a hundred thousand dollars pickup trucks.
Speaker 5:  There, there does seem like there's like a, a cap on the number of people
Speaker 5:  who do that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Seems like a, there's a really obvious cap for that.
Speaker 6:  Is there a bigger thing going on with just general
Speaker 6:  EV interest not rising as fast as people thought? Like there was, there was
Speaker 6:  that interesting line from RJ Strange, the CEO said during the
Speaker 6:  earnings report. He said his quote was, how do we get the 93% of the market
Speaker 6:  that's not buying an EV to get excited about the product? Which
Speaker 6:  is not a problem. I think anyone in 2020 would've thought we would
Speaker 6:  have in 2024
Speaker 4:  Because the only car in the market in 2020 was Tesla. And there
Speaker 4:  was apparently infinite demand for the Tesla model three.
Speaker 6:  That's what I mean. But so are we, are we at a point where they've run out
Speaker 6:  of people to buy a hundred thousand dollars cars? Yes. Or are we at a point
Speaker 6:  where they've run out of people who wanna buy EVs? So
Speaker 4:  There, there are basically no head up competitors to the model three and
Speaker 4:  the Y There's the Mustang Mach E Right. Which is in a price war
Speaker 4:  with Tesla because Tesla keeps lowering its prices. And
Speaker 4:  you know, you can feel about the Mach E however you want. But that's a weird
Speaker 4:  place to be. Right. Where you're driving towards the bottom. And if
Speaker 4:  I think people who are interested in Teslas are not actually cross shopping
Speaker 4:  with Ford. Like, Tesla's still a very unique kind of buyer.
Speaker 4:  And you, I know people are gonna say it's morally irresponsible. They give
Speaker 4:  you all, but people who buy Teslas buy Teslas and they like them. That is
Speaker 4:  just a fact. Yeah. Then everything else is like crazy expensive. The Honda
Speaker 4:  prologue is out. We have a review of the Honda prologue on the site this
Speaker 4:  week. It seems like a great car is based on the Chevy Blazer, which had
Speaker 4:  a stop sale on it. But Honda insists they've done their own software.
Speaker 4:  So the prologue will not have these problems. But you're really
Speaker 4:  looking at like a pretty small number of head up competitors to the three
Speaker 4:  in the Y And there are some Right Polestar exists like the, you
Speaker 4:  can go down the line, but they're all pretty small scale competitors. They're
Speaker 4:  not like,
Speaker 5:  When do we get like a Dodge neon dash e
Speaker 4:  So I Think the Volvo EX 30 will be, it won't be that cheap. Yeah. But it's
Speaker 4:  a small EV that people seem really hype about. Yeah. So I. I just think like
Speaker 4:  we're in a weird part of the market where the upstart car companies are all
Speaker 4:  too expensive and then there aren't any, there aren't down here.
Speaker 4:  There are just like, not a lot of,
Speaker 5:  It's like the traditional car companies took all the wrong lessons from the
Speaker 5:  success of Tesla. Yeah. Just like every single lesson, they're like,
Speaker 4:  No, except make this software good. Yeah. They forgot that one.
Speaker 6:  I'll say that down the street from me, there's a Hyundai dealership and over
Speaker 6:  the last six months, so the dealership is in the middle and then they have
Speaker 6:  a big parking lot on one side and a big parking lot on the other side. They
Speaker 6:  ripped up one whole parking lot to put in a bunch of EV chargers. And now
Speaker 6:  basically the only thing on the lot is Ionic stuff. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Actually this you, you the ionic five and the rest of them,
Speaker 4:  they're the obviously the exception.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And well, and now they're doing the same thing to the other side. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's like it's Hyundai Kia is like, they are convinced
Speaker 6:  they're going to solve this problem.
Speaker 4:  But you look at where they're playing, they're playing in mainstream segments
Speaker 4:  at mainstream prices. Right. They're, they're not a hundred thousand dollars
Speaker 4:  super trucks. Right. Even the EV nine, which is the big three row SUV
Speaker 4:  not, it's not a hundred thousand dollars. Like it it is, it is expensive,
Speaker 4:  but it's not out of the reach of most SUV buyers. Like it's just priced competitively.
Speaker 4:  Right. And that, that feels like the, I feel like I'm saying something very
Speaker 4:  obvious, like make the most popular kinds of products and price them
Speaker 4:  competitively. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No, that's not the lesson.
Speaker 4:  A hundred thousand dollars super truck. Got it. There you go.
Speaker 4:  So we'll see. I just think, I think we're in a really weird moment in the
Speaker 4:  EV transition. But also if you're in the market for an EV, like not
Speaker 4:  a horrible time to buy one. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Terrible time to buy a hybrid though.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All of a sudden it's impossible to find a hybrid. My dad has been shopping
Speaker 6:  for a hybrid for a while and everybody wants the new Prius Prime 'cause it's
Speaker 6:  like finally nice looking and it turns out they're, it's essentially impossible
Speaker 6:  to get your hands on. It's
Speaker 4:  Crazy. Yeah. As somebody who owns a plugin hybrid that only gets 25 miles
Speaker 4:  of range. I'll say that is not enough. You want 50?
Speaker 5:  That's not enough.
Speaker 4:  If our car had 50, I we we would just keep it forever. Yeah. but
Speaker 4:  it doesn't. So the second there is one that gets,
Speaker 5:  I'm all gas man.
Speaker 4:  Just like I'm all in on gas, here's what I'm doing. I'm pouring oil on myself
Speaker 4:  every day.
Speaker 4:  I'm from Texas.
Speaker 5:  I love Texas. Fracking's awesome.
Speaker 6:  It's okay. I just ride Lime scooters. So between Alex and me, we're good
Speaker 6:  to go. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We balance out.
Speaker 4:  All right. There's a bunch of other news here. FUBU was suing Fox and Disney.
Speaker 4:  I mean, that's just a sentence I said,
Speaker 5:  But it also was like it was gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  Can I just say by the way, that the fact that S SPLU has just become the
Speaker 6:  agreed upon name for this service,
Speaker 5:  We, we have to stop that. Like
Speaker 4:  It sports Hulu. I wanna be clear about what people are
Speaker 6:  Saying. Yeah. Right, right. Sports Hulu and a Alex. Cranz called this first.
Speaker 6:  So Alex wins. Thank you.
Speaker 5:  But B,
Speaker 6:  It's just, everybody just calls it SPLU now, which makes me think it might
Speaker 6:  be called S splu For real. And we cannot allow that to happen.
Speaker 5:  People, I know it's gonna be called Sports Max.
Speaker 4:  It should just be called ESPN. Yes. It's, it will be ridiculous
Speaker 4:  if they don't call it espn.
Speaker 5:  ESPN Max sponsored by Hulu
Speaker 4:  With Fox. If they start a giant sports streaming service and they don't just
Speaker 4:  call it ESPN, they will have made such a gigantic error.
Speaker 4:  Like you are looking at one of the most legendary brands
Speaker 4:  in watching sports that has ever existed. And it's like
Speaker 4:  the people at Fox Sports will be like, well you can't, it's gotta, it's gotta
Speaker 4:  indicate that it's Fox Sports as well. And it's like, no it doesn't. You
Speaker 4:  can just have a tile.
Speaker 6:  Somebody posted the other day a screenshot of like a promotional thing for
Speaker 6:  them to sign up for a streaming service. And it was Hulu with live TV
Speaker 6:  with Paramount Plus with Showtime. It is. That was the official name.
Speaker 5:  It's so good. It's like,
Speaker 6:  What have we done here?
Speaker 4:  It's all very bad. All right, we gotta wrap this up. We've gone way over.
Speaker 4:  I wanna call it two stories. One, we have a a look back, it
Speaker 4:  Spiked Jones, her the movie Her, which is all about falling in love with
Speaker 4:  ai. It's very good. You should go read the look back, you should watch the
Speaker 4:  movie. It still holds up. And then we sent a reporter to
Speaker 4:  King of the Hammers. There's a big silly off-Road race. It's Burning Man
Speaker 4:  for off-Road vehicles.
Speaker 4:  She got to ride in the Ford Switchgear. The
Speaker 4:  EV F1, the EV F-150 off roadie thing.
Speaker 4:  This is what I wanna trade my after and four So. I'm very excited about the
Speaker 4:  story. And also there's pictures of a cyber truck trying off road, one of
Speaker 4:  which broke itself. So it rules that piece will link to the thing. And
Speaker 4:  then it's big news. We get stopped by Southwest doing the show live
Speaker 4:  on the Fox Media podcast network stage. That will happen March 8th.
Speaker 4:  We'll have more detail soon. There's other stuff coming. There's gonna be
Speaker 4:  decoder, which will be very good. There's some other people. It's gonna be
Speaker 4:  good. So if you're gonna South by Southwest, come see us on March 8th. David,
Speaker 4:  what's happening next week on the Tuesday show?
Speaker 6:  We are gonna talk about Flip this weird new shopping
Speaker 6:  app. Mia Sato on our team basically like ruined her life
Speaker 6:  to become an influencer on Flip. And she told us her story. It's really good.
Speaker 6:  And then Becca and Veen from our video team came on to talk about the
Speaker 6:  Fuji X 106, which is the Internet's favorite camera in a way I still
Speaker 6:  don't totally understand. So we got into the weed of
Speaker 4:  All of that's so cool.
Speaker 6:  It's good stuff.
Speaker 4:  I want it. Yeah. If I could buy every camera, I'd buy every camera.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Same. All right. That's it. We've gone just way over. If
Speaker 4:  anyone knows the people at Samsung who control the the art mode
Speaker 4:  endpoint and ties in.
Speaker 4:  Talk to this guy. All right. That's it. That's for Chest Fuck roll.
Speaker 12:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 12:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One. The Vergecast is the
Speaker 12:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 12:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.