# Transcript
ID: af2f2431-4227-4421-80fc-963363cfeeda
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7183752148907953753/-4112892553261797519/s93290-US-6344s-1733495599.mp3
Description: Nilay and David talk a bit about this week’s launch of the Verge subscription, plus what’s coming next. (There’s still time to send questions for next week! 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com.) Then they talk about the streaming news of the week, and the ways streaming services are continuing to act like cable companies. Then Kylie Robison joins to talk about the lowering stakes for AGI, shipmas at OpenAI, and more. Finally, in the lighting round, it’s crypto and browsers and Intel. And more crypto.
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to broadcast the flagship podcast of paying us money
Speaker 2:  directly. Just show up in my house with a check. Give
Speaker 3:  It to me.
Speaker 2:  Hi, I'm Neli and I would like you to pay us money. I'm also your friend
Speaker 2:  David Pierce is here.
Speaker 3:  Hi. I want slightly less of your money than Neli does. I feel like
Speaker 3:  that's, that's my brand is like, like Neli only less.
Speaker 2:  That's what I'm here for TV but not very good.
Speaker 3:  Exactly. That's what I did here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, big Vir has today. Kylie Robinson's gonna join us to talk.
Speaker 2:  There's just a lot of AI stuff and all that boils down to what if
Speaker 2:  it's not as good as we said it was gonna be. And
Speaker 3:  They're all talking this week. Yeah. Is the real thing. I've noticed a lot
Speaker 3:  of people are talking and when they do that we have to
Speaker 3:  talk about it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So Kyle is gonna join us in a bit. David has put together a package
Speaker 2:  called Cable Is So Back, it's so bad, which is a threat
Speaker 2:  really. We have a lightning round with, I wanna
Speaker 2:  just say this as as directly as I can. A hilariously
Speaker 2:  amazing sponsor given the topics that we're gonna discuss today.
Speaker 2:  All kinds of stuff going on. But we should start with our own news because
Speaker 2:  what is the show about if not being totally self-indulgent about the making
Speaker 2:  of The Verge dot com? Right? That's what, that's what everybody tunes
Speaker 2:  in for, not tech News, just deep inside baseball
Speaker 2:  about our website. So the news this week, you probably
Speaker 2:  saw it if you're listening to Vergecast it, it's almost certain you saw our
Speaker 2:  news this week, we launched a subscription on our website.
Speaker 2:  It's $7 a month or it's $50 a year. If you're in the US and Canada and you
Speaker 2:  give us the 50 bucks a year, we're gonna mail you a print zine, which is
Speaker 2:  very fun called Content Goblins. It's very expensive to ship
Speaker 2:  and mail things overseas. So we're figuring out a way to
Speaker 2:  do something for our, our readers and our listeners overseas. I'm sorry that
Speaker 2:  we didn't figure it out right away. It's our first time, you know,
Speaker 2:  with a subscription product like this. So we're figuring it out. We, we have
Speaker 2:  some ideas we'll solve it, but that's the, the, the shape of it,
Speaker 2:  right? It's, yeah. If you've been listening to us, you've been reading the
Speaker 2:  site, you know that the internet and how we distribute media on the internet
Speaker 2:  is kind of broken. It's very hard to just make money giving
Speaker 2:  away things for free, which is this, this sort of economic reality that
Speaker 2:  makes sense and we all just pretended wasn't real for a long time.
Speaker 2:  What if I worked really hard and then gave you the, the effort for free
Speaker 2:  is that the internet is really founded on this idea and then it turns out
Speaker 2:  the platforms get to make the money and the people who work really hard and
Speaker 2:  give you the stuff for free mostly burn themselves out or go outta business.
Speaker 3:  Right. I think just to put a fine point on that, that is
Speaker 3:  a thing we've seen a lot of feedback to both with
Speaker 3:  our own subscription launch and also just kind of the subscription
Speaker 3:  ification of everything, right? Like the subscription fatigue is real. The
Speaker 3:  idea that anything you want, whether it's a website or a calendar
Speaker 3:  app or Netflix now costs some number of dollars a month instead of just
Speaker 3:  some number of dollars or nothing and ads and like, and
Speaker 3:  there's this idea that okay, why doesn't the ad
Speaker 3:  supported model work anymore? And and the reason is what you just
Speaker 3:  said, the reason is that it does, except it's been completely disintermediated
Speaker 3:  essentially by two companies who just took all of the money. Yeah. And so
Speaker 3:  what that thing where it was like, oh you put the ads in the newspaper and
Speaker 3:  I look at the ads and so the ads are how the things get that that is not
Speaker 3:  how it works anymore because of largely Google and Facebook who are not the
Speaker 3:  only companies that did this, but are mostly the companies that changed that
Speaker 3:  model for everybody.
Speaker 2:  And then you look at how people are making up the gap. And I spent a lot
Speaker 2:  of time thinking about our competitors in the creator economy on YouTube,
Speaker 2:  on TikTok what, whatever. And the platforms don't pay them enough
Speaker 2:  money directly. So they've all almost universally made the same
Speaker 2:  decision, which is to go take brand deals and we just won't. Like I am
Speaker 2:  allergic and like genetically incompatible
Speaker 2:  with a big company paying me money to tell me what to say. We're just not
Speaker 2:  gonna do it. So we, we just landed it. How do we solve
Speaker 2:  this problem? How do we make up the gap? And the answer is subscriptions.
Speaker 2:  I am blown away by how many people
Speaker 2:  immediately sign up for a subscription to our To The Verge. Yeah. Like
Speaker 2:  it blew our estimates and our goals outta the water. We ran outta print zines
Speaker 2:  and we were ordering a second round
Speaker 3:  Printing stuff is so expensive. Did you know this? I had no idea. Printing
Speaker 3:  stuff is so expensive
Speaker 2:  And we are totally used to internet economics, which is like just makes,
Speaker 2:  just make a million more page views. Website
Speaker 3:  More
Speaker 2:  Website. Yeah. And we can do it on demand, you know, like we'll just add
Speaker 2:  more servers to the AWS or whatever like it making digital
Speaker 2:  products is so easy and then print is like, we're gonna put
Speaker 2:  up a bunch of money and hopefully enough people sign up and then lots more
Speaker 2:  people did. So we have to sort out. So I'm just Thank you If you subscribed.
Speaker 2:  I really appreciate it. We really appreciate it. The number of people who
Speaker 2:  subscribed just to support our work, because you've been reading us for 13
Speaker 2:  years, is it's humbling. Like truly humbling. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We have staved off that we have to charge for our work for 13 years
Speaker 2:  and that is mostly because we do have a big audience, like a audience of
Speaker 2:  people who visits the site every day. Helen, our publisher, pulled the stat
Speaker 2:  55,000 people read The Verge every single day and have for the past year.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty wild. Like every single day for a year they have hit
Speaker 2:  the site, logged in and we can see them. That's not even counting the people
Speaker 2:  who hit us without being logged in. And we can't like see that. It's that
Speaker 2:  user account that is a crazy number. Like in the context of digital
Speaker 2:  media every single day. People who spend the average amount
Speaker 2:  of time on our homepage is six minutes. That is a crazy number. And that's
Speaker 2:  gone up since our redesign, which is a number that almost any other
Speaker 2:  publisher finds impossible to move. So we've made some bets about making
Speaker 2:  our own products really valuable and now we think it's valuable to pay for.
Speaker 2:  So hopefully more of you pay for us. A lot of you have asked us for an ad
Speaker 2:  free Vergecast. David, I don't know If you had the same disconnect in your
Speaker 2:  head here, that the ad experience on the website and the ad experience on
Speaker 2:  the podcast are the same ad experience for a lot of people.
Speaker 2:  It's all Yeah. And like that's not how, that's just not how my brain works.
Speaker 2:  'cause we are so divorced from advertise, like that's literally not the part
Speaker 2:  of the business that we are in. We, we just make this stuff and the ad show
Speaker 2:  up so it, it didn't even like really occur to me like
Speaker 2:  intellectually The Verge, like we should do an ad free VERGE cast. Sure.
Speaker 2:  Like it was on the list and then the immediate feedback is I'm paying you
Speaker 2:  make an ad free VERGE cast so we'll figure out something.
Speaker 3:  Well it is cool. I will say one of the things that I've taken away from it
Speaker 3:  is that like we spend all of our time inside of this thinking
Speaker 3:  about like individual things and individual products and individual
Speaker 3:  sort of pieces of the puzzle and the idea that
Speaker 3:  to most people it all feels like one thing is very cool, right? Like
Speaker 3:  I think to me the, the risk we run at The Verge sometimes is we just like
Speaker 3:  do a lot of things and it all becomes disconnected and weird and everybody's
Speaker 3:  like, why is this happening? And I think part of the thing we've gotten away
Speaker 3:  with for 13 years is we do a lot of that and we have this like big audience
Speaker 3:  of people who think it's fun. And so we get to like all do that together.
Speaker 3:  But it was very cool to have a bunch of people immediately understand like,
Speaker 3:  oh here are all the other things that I consume of yours. We got a ton of
Speaker 3:  people who were like, now that it's subscript a subscription, make everything
Speaker 3:  a social feed, do all of your quick posts on the activity pub. And I was
Speaker 3:  just like, yes, you get it. This is the thing. Yeah. Like we're gonna do
Speaker 3:  it now. This is, this is, this is all in service of that. And it was very
Speaker 3:  cool to see how many people just like instantly saw the whole size of
Speaker 3:  the whole thing. Ad free podcasts very complicated. Also
Speaker 3:  allow me to plug, we're gonna talk about a lot of this stuff in
Speaker 3:  more depth on Tuesday's show both with you and with Helen Havelock, our
Speaker 3:  publisher. We got a lot of questions. If you have questions,
Speaker 3:  email us vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the hotline eight six six version
Speaker 3:  one one. You have, I would say like a few hours from when you're hearing
Speaker 3:  this to get the questions in Pull over
Speaker 2:  In your car right
Speaker 3:  Now. Yeah, like do it right now because I have to record as neli in order
Speaker 3:  to get this all done. But we're gonna answer lots more questions in
Speaker 3:  lots more depth and we've gotten a a lot of really good interesting ones
Speaker 3:  that are like kind of about The Verge but are also just about like what does
Speaker 3:  it mean to be on the internet in 2024? Which is really interesting.
Speaker 2:  And I you're, if you're, and the one thing I'll point out is we're
Speaker 2:  always saying we have no idea how the business works. Helen is the business.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Helen super knows how the business works. She's,
Speaker 2:  She's the money. Yeah. And Helen's backstory is really great. She
Speaker 2:  came to us, she was on the Samsung account at Edelman and she joined
Speaker 2:  us as our engagement editor. And my pitch to her was, If you can,
Speaker 2:  If you can make people watch Samsung's branded content, you can definitely
Speaker 2:  make them watch VERGE stuff on these platforms. That was years ago. And then
Speaker 2:  she was so much better at running our company than me that I just made her
Speaker 2:  my boss because that was simpler than me asking her what to do and then
Speaker 2:  pretending that was my idea, which other
Speaker 2:  people find very easy and I find very challenging. So I was like, you're
Speaker 2:  the boss now go be the boss. So If you have questions about our business,
Speaker 2:  Helen is a person who will answer them. And I a lot of
Speaker 2:  the how do we charge, how much do we charge? What is the model
Speaker 2:  for this thing that is Helen and I going back and forth and like what does
Speaker 2:  it mean to run a website in 2024? The one thing I'll add before we stop talking
Speaker 2:  about ourselves is our approach to this subscription is different than a
Speaker 2:  lot of other publications. So I want our homepage to remain a
Speaker 2:  very useful free utility to a lot of people.
Speaker 2:  And if we have a lot of folks who listen to us who build things, where does
Speaker 2:  my customer come from is a very hard problem to solve on the internet. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And for most people the answer is like, I paid for Facebook ads or something.
Speaker 2:  I don't, we just don't wanna do that. And for publishers in particular, it's
Speaker 2:  like you are trying to get people to convert into subscribers on one story
Speaker 2:  at a time on social media that went viral and that I think the incentives
Speaker 2:  that are pretty broken, I want people to be our, become our subscribers
Speaker 2:  because we've just been really useful to them for a long time. So we are
Speaker 2:  very focused on The Verge dot com is a thing you can come to a bunch of times
Speaker 2:  a day with a lot of news on it, a lot of quick posts, a lot of free stuff.
Speaker 2:  And hopefully that's just useful and that's fine. And when we
Speaker 2:  are proven ourselves to be useful and good practitioners of
Speaker 2:  journalism and good stewards of our community, then you'll pay us money
Speaker 2:  already. Like some people are happy and they think we've done that, we have
Speaker 2:  to earn it. For the rest of you, I, we have some product stuff to do. I think
Speaker 2:  I agree with everybody. We should make it clear what stuff is freed, what
Speaker 2:  stuff is not. Yep. That's complicated. We can get into that with Helen. Like
Speaker 2:  there's reasons why that's complicated just on, based on how the paywall
Speaker 2:  works. It's not some conspiracy, it's just like literally
Speaker 2:  exposing that logic to people might be more confusing than not so we'll
Speaker 2:  we'll just like walk through it. But that's the goal that we have is to make
Speaker 2:  the heart of the thing a really useful free
Speaker 2:  service to people where you're like, I would like to go somewhere on the
Speaker 2:  internet where smart human beings are curating the
Speaker 2:  news and explaining how things work,
Speaker 2:  not AI slop. Right. And I, I feel like that we should just make that
Speaker 2:  a big useful free website and then our
Speaker 2:  reporting and analysis and reviews and all that other stuff, if that is useful
Speaker 2:  to you, if that is interesting to you, you can pay to support us. So that's
Speaker 2:  the plan. It has been two days, right. So
Speaker 2:  it's a little messy parts. Oh, and we cut down the ads by the way, when we,
Speaker 2:  we ask people what they wanna pay for we, when we've done surveys in the
Speaker 2:  past years, turn off the ads or gimme fewer ads.
Speaker 2:  It it's such, it's so by far the the first
Speaker 2:  answer. Yeah. That we take it off of the charts.
Speaker 2:  Like it's so overwhelmingly the thing that people wanted to pay for that
Speaker 2:  we had to remove it from the charts to see all the other stuff.
Speaker 2:  So we, we, I was, if I was a brat about anything, I was a huge brat about
Speaker 2:  that. And that is a new system. It's a new like ads
Speaker 2:  service that we had to build. It's a little buggy. It just give us a
Speaker 2:  little bit of grace. We're gonna figure it all out. But those are the things
Speaker 2:  that we really wanted to do and that's the model we really wanna have.
Speaker 2:  Give us your feedback.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. We talked a lot about not wanting to just like throw
Speaker 3:  a wall up in front of The Verge but build software. Yeah. And I feel like
Speaker 3:  we're, we're, we have a lot of work to do on that front, but that feels still
Speaker 3:  like the right goal as I think about all this stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And again, the thing that I'm just thinking about is like how do I,
Speaker 2:  how do we earn your money? Like I think we have to earn it and honestly we
Speaker 2:  have to earn it once a month or once a year. And I just wanna make sure that
Speaker 2:  the core service we provide continues to be useful and fun
Speaker 2:  and high quality and like people made it people with points of view and beliefs,
Speaker 2:  not just ai. That honestly as we will discover
Speaker 2:  later in the show, mostly it doesn't know what it's talking about
Speaker 3:  But it's doing stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So that's the plan. We'll see how it works. And the, by the way, the activity
Speaker 2:  bub stuff, the can we integrate with at Protocol in Blue Sky, it's
Speaker 2:  just so high on our list now. Now that I don't have to figure out how to
Speaker 2:  monetize that like inside of itself and I can just be like, this is for
Speaker 2:  subscribers. It's gonna get way easier to just be like, here, here's some
Speaker 2:  stuff to try out. Let us know how it works. Totally. So we're very excited
Speaker 2:  about that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's gonna be good. Now let's talk about cable because I
Speaker 3:  realized I just have subscriptions on the brand.
Speaker 2:  This is the next thing that we're doing. Yeah. We're Cable Network 24 7
Speaker 2:  cable news.
Speaker 3:  Listen, it, it could work. We're gonna buy Spinco from
Speaker 3:  show whatever company that is.
Speaker 2:  Comcast. Oh my God. Disclosure Disclosure.
Speaker 3:  NBC Universal is a minority investor in Vox Media. Hey, you did it. I have
Speaker 3:  Peacock. Yeah. The day of the Jackal is pretty good on
Speaker 3:  Peacock.
Speaker 2:  This has nothing to do with NBC Universal just TV shows. And I wrote one
Speaker 2:  up, I've been watching Landman on Paramount Plus. Okay. You, you're like
Speaker 2:  the
Speaker 3:  Eighth person who has told me the
Speaker 2:  Show's horrible now, now that I'm like in it, I'm like, they just, Taylor
Speaker 2:  Sheridan just wrote a show where he, he was like, here's all of my worst
Speaker 2:  instincts as a writer. But like they're pretty fun. Okay. You know what I
Speaker 2:  mean? Yeah. Like just do cowboy stuff. But what's it's like when
Speaker 3:  Let Aaron Sorkin direct a movie and you're like, this isn't a good movie
Speaker 3:  but it's it's you and I appreciate that. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's good. And it's like if more TV shows were
Speaker 2:  just that like compelling character actor just fast talking,
Speaker 2:  I'd be like, I should pay for cable again.
Speaker 2:  But most, most TV shows are like, this is fine if you're on your phone.
Speaker 2:  So I, that's a big setup for
Speaker 2:  the TV industry is desperately trying to reinvent the TV industry of
Speaker 2:  what, the late nineties, early two thousands
Speaker 3:  Thereabouts. Yeah. Like right before it became
Speaker 3:  easy to do things on the internet with is kind of what we're going back to
Speaker 3:  like in the, in those days where like many of our listeners will not
Speaker 3:  remember this, but like a webpage would literally load line by line as it
Speaker 3:  would go. Like that's what we're headed back to. That's what these companies
Speaker 3:  are trying to get. Again, the two big pieces of news this week
Speaker 3:  along those lines were that Disney announced its adding
Speaker 3:  ESPN into the Disney Plus app. They did this with Hulu earlier
Speaker 3:  this year and just basically like stuck Hulu as a tab and also
Speaker 3:  all of the Hulu content inside of Disney Plus. And then
Speaker 3:  at the same time Max is getting these like
Speaker 3:  always on HBO channels,
Speaker 3:  which I think are fascinating and it's doing them exactly wrong and we should
Speaker 3:  talk about that. But there is, there is this like incredible amount
Speaker 3:  of bundling A happening and
Speaker 3:  B, we're just going back to something should be
Speaker 3:  playing when you open the app again. Which is the thing I've been saying
Speaker 3:  about streaming for forever is like why, why do I turn
Speaker 3:  on my TV to a grid of icons and then click into one
Speaker 3:  of the icons and I'm presented with another grid of icons and then I click
Speaker 3:  into that and I'm presented with a big picture and then I press play and
Speaker 3:  I'm watching something like, just show me something. And it's like you, you
Speaker 3:  hear all the people who kept cable for forever. That
Speaker 3:  is the reason. It's because you turn the TV on and it shows you television.
Speaker 3:  Like there's, there are things happening when I turn my TV on is pretty compelling.
Speaker 3:  And like the, the fast channels, the, you know, two Bs and
Speaker 3:  Pluto's of the world have done a good job of replicating some of that where
Speaker 3:  you can just, you don't have to log in, you just flip it on and pick a thing
Speaker 3:  and it starts playing. And we're now starting to see that roll back into
Speaker 3:  these premium services in a really big way, which I find totally fascinating.
Speaker 3:  But between those two, it's like this is just cable that is, those are the
Speaker 3:  main two tenets of cable television.
Speaker 2:  So let's start with Disney Plus 'cause they added Hulu and now they're adding
Speaker 2:  ESP N and ESPN's their big bet. There's just a lot of weirdness there
Speaker 2:  because I, the ESPN app has a lot of live
Speaker 2:  sports in it. I watch NFL Prime to and on ESPN plus every
Speaker 2:  week. It's like the only reason to have ESPN plus my opinion. Sure. But it,
Speaker 2:  it's like hard to understand what is coming to Disney
Speaker 2:  Plus from SPN because it's like select live events
Speaker 2:  and that includes the Simpsons Fun Day football animated Monday night
Speaker 2:  football game. And it's like I don't, do I want that? Like
Speaker 2:  is that what I want? And then you look at what's on ESPN Plus and it's like
Speaker 2:  30,000 live events and it's like, okay, so in Disney plus
Speaker 2:  I get the cartoon NFL and on regular ES ESP NI get
Speaker 2:  every sport they have. It's weird, it's like a weird cutdown
Speaker 2:  version of ESPN lives inside of Disney Plus even their
Speaker 2:  studio shows, which presumably can do whatever they want. It's only select
Speaker 2:  studio shows. And I, by the way, I've never really looked at the full list
Speaker 2:  of ESPN studio shows. So the full list, you know, it's college
Speaker 2:  dame, it's college game day NFL matchup, the Pat
Speaker 2:  McAfee show. Everybody knows about pardon the Interruption, which
Speaker 2:  I think Vergecast listeners may not know what pardon the interruption is,
Speaker 2:  but every time David and I talk about what The Vergecast should be, we're
Speaker 2:  like what was just, pardon the interruption.
Speaker 3:  That's real.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then what I think is the ultimate distillation
Speaker 2:  of what every single ESPN studio show is. And I didn't realize they had a
Speaker 2:  show called this. It's just good guy, bad guy. I'm
Speaker 3:  So glad you noticed this too.
Speaker 2:  I've
Speaker 3:  Never heard of the show in my life.
Speaker 2:  And it's like, oh that's every s ESPN show.
Speaker 2:  It's just good guy, bad guy,
Speaker 2:  but good guy, bad guy is not on Disney Plus.
Speaker 3:  No good guy, bad guy
Speaker 2:  Anywhere. It might just be a fake one. They might have just thrown that in
Speaker 2:  the list like the, like the way that Van Halen used to do the Brown M and
Speaker 2:  MSM thing just to see If you were paying attention.
Speaker 3:  It's apparent it's an MMA show.
Speaker 2:  But so like this idea that you have the Disney plus app and we should talk
Speaker 2:  about the fact that it's Disney plus it's the app, right? Yeah. It's, and
Speaker 2:  now Disney plus that plus is almost more important than the
Speaker 2:  Disney part. Yeah because you're full of Hulu. You got all the
Speaker 2:  ESP n stuff except for the most important ESP n show of all Good guy, bad
Speaker 2:  guy.
Speaker 2:  I'm not even gonna look up. I don't even want to know it's better in my imagination.
Speaker 2:  It's weird, right, that you've got that is your new cable box.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like the idea is you opened Disney Plus and you are having like a cable-like
Speaker 2:  experience in there with content from all of these, these networks shoveled
Speaker 2:  through Hulu or shoveled through sports with ESPN or on the different Disney
Speaker 2:  tiles. Like they're very quickly getting back to this is just a cable box
Speaker 2:  that happens to run the Apple TV and then Max is coming at it from the other
Speaker 2:  direction, which is you open it up and there's some channels in here that
Speaker 2:  you can just start with. Peacock has a version of this going on inside the
Speaker 2:  app. Paramount Plus has CBS inside the app at some
Speaker 2:  point. Don't the Rokus and Apple TVs and the
Speaker 2:  Samsung ties in team have to just say stop it.
Speaker 2:  Like just give us the content directly. Not everybody wants 10 different
Speaker 2:  cable box apps on their cable box.
Speaker 3:  I think that's what all of those platforms would be thrilled to
Speaker 3:  do and are somewhat desperate to do. And I mean that's the animating principle
Speaker 3:  behind like Amazon channels and the thing that Apple
Speaker 3:  is trying to do where they're like, don't subscribe to Max,
Speaker 3:  just subscribe to Max through Apple TV and you'll get all the content just
Speaker 3:  natively built into the system that has like UI
Speaker 3:  upsides and it's easy to do in a way that sort of makes sense. But it's also
Speaker 3:  that gives this like precious user
Speaker 3:  data and branding stuff and content to those companies.
Speaker 3:  And so all of the streamers have absolutely no interest in doing it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Also, you often get a degradation in video quality when you play when you
Speaker 2:  do it that way.
Speaker 3:  That's true too. Which I notice on my television that I for sure
Speaker 3:  see the difference every single time that
Speaker 2:  Happens. I'm saying If you buy the, If you buy, If you stream on Max,
Speaker 2:  like you usually get the highest quality in the first party service. I
Speaker 2:  actually don't know this is true because Max has forgotten that I got
Speaker 2:  it for free from at and t during, during that Ill faded period.
Speaker 2:  And So I just haven't been paying for it. 'cause it's part of my at ts for
Speaker 2:  shit. And even in the fact that I'm saying it out loud, I don't think there's
Speaker 2:  anybody at at and t or Max who can identify my account and undo
Speaker 2:  this. Yeah. I challenge you right now to stop being
Speaker 3:  Free. The owner of that spreadsheet for sure does not work at any of those
Speaker 3:  companies. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They're gone. Nobody even knows where this data lives. Go
Speaker 2:  ahead. Turn off my free max subscription disclosure.
Speaker 2:  I haven't paid for that shit in years, but it's an only in 10 80 p
Speaker 2:  because I can't upgrade to 4K. Just just to torture
Speaker 3:  You specifically. I
Speaker 2:  Can't. Right. Anyway, I'm just saying like you notice that the, the first
Speaker 2:  party app often has the best quality. Yeah. Because
Speaker 2:  they're not giving the best quality to some partner. And so like it's like
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna do that 'cause I'm the one person in America who cares about
Speaker 2:  this. David is like, I buy everything through Amazon.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's fine. I probably,
Speaker 2:  But it does feel like
Speaker 3:  Passcode is very recognizable and easy to remember and it works out.
Speaker 2:  I'll just point it out. The, the cable era was not a great era for user choice
Speaker 2:  or sane pricing or user experience. Right.
Speaker 2:  You, you got a cable box, it had a bad grid guide.
Speaker 2:  You, you got a bunch of channels you didn't want. Right. Like none of that
Speaker 2:  was great. But one you turned on your tv, it just
Speaker 2:  worked and everything was there. Yep. And two, and I, this
Speaker 2:  to me is like the most important thing. The industry was making a lot of
Speaker 2:  money and a lot of people were employed and a lot of good TV was getting
Speaker 2:  made. And that is because they controlled their distribution.
Speaker 2:  Right. The the cable companies of the world, as evil as they were and The
Speaker 2:  Verge has published a story called Comcast, the
Speaker 2:  worst company in America that like, they didn't like, like Disclosure,
Speaker 2:  Comcast is an investor we have called out com. I personally have spent a
Speaker 2:  lot of my career calling out Comcast for not being a great company and
Speaker 2:  for having bad user experience and over billing people all the stuff cable
Speaker 2:  companies and is piece down the line. Right. But there was a thing that they
Speaker 2:  made where they owned their distribution and we sent video programming
Speaker 2:  over that distribution and everyone paid high rates and the prices were too
Speaker 2:  high. Yes. But you didn't know that you were paying a bunch of money for
Speaker 2:  ESPN, whether you wanted it or not. It just was like part of your cable bundle.
Speaker 2:  And everyone was like, fine, they've got cable, here's all this stuff I can
Speaker 2:  watch. And then we moved our distribution to the internet where everything
Speaker 2:  is free and no one's making money. The Hollywood's like eating itself alive.
Speaker 2:  And instead it's like a bunch of burned out 25-year-old influencers. And
Speaker 2:  it just feels like all of this stuff is an attempt to regain
Speaker 2:  the glory years of owning their distribution over here in some way.
Speaker 2:  I'm not sure any of it will work, but you can see exactly what these
Speaker 2:  companies are trying to do. They do not wanna put everything like
Speaker 2:  HBO does not wanna put its content on YouTube. Right. They want you
Speaker 2:  to go somewhere else and say it's worth more money 'cause it's over here.
Speaker 2:  And I, I don't know if that's like a winnable fight, but you can see what
Speaker 2:  they're trying to do.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think the, the thing that's gonna suck for users
Speaker 3:  in this world is you're gonna, you're gonna go
Speaker 3:  into Disney Plus as a Disney plus subscriber, right? And in in, in the world
Speaker 3:  we lived in before you're right. You were just paying for ESPN whether you
Speaker 3:  wanted to or not. You weren't paying what ESPN
Speaker 3:  is actually worth to people who want to watch it because that was being sort
Speaker 3:  of spread across everyone whether you wanted it or not. So the price was
Speaker 3:  relatively lower. Now what's gonna happen is you're gonna get
Speaker 3:  a teeny tiny sliver of ESPN content in your
Speaker 3:  Disney Plus, like the stuff you're talking about. You're not gonna get good
Speaker 3:  guy, bad guy, but you're gonna get, you're gonna get game day, you're gonna
Speaker 3:  get a, you're gonna get the Simpsons football and then you are going to be
Speaker 3:  relentlessly upsold on getting everything else in order to pull it all into
Speaker 3:  this app. And so what they're doing is they're saying not only,
Speaker 3:  like imagine If you had cable, but every single time you went to a channel,
Speaker 3:  the first thing it tried to get you to do was buy more of that channel. Like
Speaker 3:  that's, that's where we're headed. And that's the thing that feels bad. And
Speaker 3:  I, this is clearly the thing Disney is setting itself up to do is
Speaker 3:  just be able to do the upselling all in one place. And to a certain extent
Speaker 3:  that makes sense. And if you're somebody who wants the bundle, which is what
Speaker 3:  Disney is trying hard to sell you, that makes sense. But then we're
Speaker 3:  just back to you're paying for the bundle and you're subsidizing ESPN for
Speaker 3:  all the people who wanna watch it. So I, I'm kind of reaching a point where
Speaker 3:  it's like If you just add up the amount of content available to you for what
Speaker 3:  you used to pay for cable, it feels like the the deal we had for
Speaker 3:  cable is looking better and better over time.
Speaker 2:  And that's re remarkable to say. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It really is. Like I, it feels crazy, but I honestly am starting to feel
Speaker 3:  that way.
Speaker 2:  And it all of that is up against YouTube,
Speaker 2:  TikTok, whatever, whose economics are a bunch of kids show
Speaker 2:  up and make the work for free and then we pay them
Speaker 2:  not enough money to run sustainable businesses and then we collect the
Speaker 2:  ad dollars in the back of that. And that I, I
Speaker 2:  honestly dunno how much longer that has in it. Like a, I mean there's an
Speaker 2:  infinite supply of kids who wanna be famous who will work for you. YouTube.
Speaker 3:  That's the that's the thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But it feels like some bubble will pop there because the rates
Speaker 2:  aren't high enough. Like more and more people are watching YouTube and TikTok
Speaker 2:  and whatever and advertisers are putting more money into it, but then the
Speaker 2:  number of creators who want a piece of that pie is also going up.
Speaker 2:  And I don't think the amount of money going into the system is keeping up
Speaker 2:  with the amount of people who are taking money outta the system on the creator
Speaker 2:  rates. And so they're all getting paid less money and like some,
Speaker 2:  something will reconcile itself there. But none of that, like Mr.
Speaker 2:  Beast did not make his like labor law
Speaker 2:  violation, squid games. He made that for Netflix.
Speaker 2:  Right. Because Netflix can pay him the rates to do it. And
Speaker 2:  there's just something there that is like, If you wanna make that next turn,
Speaker 2:  you have to go to a place where the distribution is more valuable or like
Speaker 2:  people perceive it, it's worth real money. Not just free stuff on YouTube.
Speaker 2:  But that is still the thing they're all competing with.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no, IIII think that's right and it, the challenge is it feels like
Speaker 3:  it's not obvious where the people who turn out of that turn to
Speaker 3:  right. It's, it's back to the like where are you gonna go? Question. And
Speaker 3:  I think the Netflixes and Disneys of the world are
Speaker 3:  increasingly content to sort of skim off the top right. And give Mr. Beast
Speaker 3:  more money to go do the shiny things for Netflix. But for everybody else
Speaker 3:  who is just in the grind, there aren't that many
Speaker 3:  moves and the platforms know it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  By the way, this brings up the last thing on our list here of reasons Cable
Speaker 2:  is back, which is Vol. Walmart bought Vizio. Yes. Which is
Speaker 2:  weird. Vizio, we've covered Vizio a lot. If you're an old school
Speaker 2:  VERGE person, you know that Vizio like burst onto the scene. They're, I don't
Speaker 2:  think most people know this. They're, they're an American company. They're
Speaker 2:  in California. Like I've been to their offices. I met their old CEO
Speaker 2:  like ages ago. Met their old CTO, Matt McCrae, who's now I believe the CEO
Speaker 2:  of Arlo, the video camera company. Huh. But their business is, they make
Speaker 2:  really, really cheap TVs. They put a bunch of ad tracking
Speaker 2:  software on them and they subsidize the cheap TV with the
Speaker 2:  lifetime value of the advertising, which is not great. I I think most
Speaker 2:  people just don't like this. They've gotten in trouble for before. 'cause
Speaker 2:  it's intrusive. They don't surveillance stuff. The TVs are of
Speaker 2:  fine quality. Like Vizio is like, you know, their bread and butter now is,
Speaker 2:  it's the Super Bowl. We're gonna sell you a hundred inch TV for
Speaker 2:  $5. Right, right. And people just buy it 'cause they're all,
Speaker 3:  'cause you're then gonna hang it on your wall for a decade and we'll make
Speaker 3:  a lot of money off your ads.
Speaker 2:  Yep. And and they will just serve ads to you. Yeah. All of this really depends
Speaker 2:  on them owning the interface. Right. Or charging
Speaker 2:  money for you to run software and sell ads on that software. This
Speaker 2:  is Roku's model as well. Roku will give you a Roku box for $15 or no dollars
Speaker 2:  depending. And then If you wanna sell ads inside of Peacock on Roku,
Speaker 2:  Roku takes 30%. It's the app store model. Right. So they're all doing this
Speaker 2:  thing. I think Walmart realizes like connected TV is where a bunch of money
Speaker 2:  is going. That's what, that's what advertising people call running ads on
Speaker 2:  Smart TVs is connected tv. Yeah. And it's like, dude, it's the TVs. We're
Speaker 2:  always connected to
Speaker 3:  Something.
Speaker 2:  I dunno what you're talking about.
Speaker 3:  They're just connected to you now. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So CTV, which is what the industry calls it, is where a bunch of ad money
Speaker 2:  is going. They're excited about it. And Walmart, if
Speaker 2:  Walmart is where a bunch of transactions get processed at the end,
Speaker 2:  right? You're like, you see a bunch of ads for Procter and Gamble products,
Speaker 2:  where are you gonna buy 'em? Walmart is is almost always the answer
Speaker 2:  for like a bunch of categories. You just end up buying this stuff at Walmart.
Speaker 2:  So Walmart's like, great, now we own the ad network on the TVs and we can
Speaker 2:  do all the data tracking. And you're like, listen to how they talk about
Speaker 2:  it. You're like, guys, this is, this isn't as cool as you think It's,
Speaker 3:  But it is also in a certain way, like a perfectly efficient system. Like
Speaker 3:  the, the argument they're making works,
Speaker 3:  it's that plan is going to work. And they're talking about like they,
Speaker 3:  they're gonna run ads on the TVs in the stores
Speaker 3:  as a revenue stream now that they own visit. Like it's just
Speaker 3:  wild the set of things that suddenly become available when you Walmart and
Speaker 3:  you can just show people ads on their television. It's like
Speaker 3:  Amazon had to build a whole, you know, division of its company
Speaker 3:  out of fire TV to do this. Walmart just walked over and bought Vizio.
Speaker 2:  So Vizios platform Plus, which is its advertising business
Speaker 2:  now accounts for all of the company's gross profit. So that's
Speaker 2:  just one line from the press release. Yeah. How, how does Vizio make money?
Speaker 2:  All of its profit comes from this connected TV advertising business. The
Speaker 2:  quote from Walmart's chief growth officer, Seth Delaer, Vizio has
Speaker 2:  expertly changed their business over time, like building and quickly scaling
Speaker 2:  a profitable advertising business, pairing it with Walmart Connect, which
Speaker 2:  is their advertising business will be impactful and it allow us to invest
Speaker 2:  our business even further on behalf of our customers. And it's like, I don't
Speaker 2:  think your customers want you to invest in advertising on their behalf.
Speaker 3:  I don't think so either. But also it's gonna work.
Speaker 3:  I mean, this is the thing, right? And I think the, the reason
Speaker 3:  I I continue to find companies like Telly so fascinating is they're the ones
Speaker 3:  just saying the quiet part out loud, right? Like, we don't make money
Speaker 3:  on TVs because it's a big ass screen we can put
Speaker 3:  in your living room that you're gonna look at. And it turns out that's actually
Speaker 3:  pretty valuable. And e everybody now is
Speaker 3:  just making their TVs cheaper and cheaper. Telly was the one who's just like,
Speaker 3:  screw this, we're just gonna make it free. Telly also, I don't think has
Speaker 3:  shipped anything yet. So
Speaker 2:  No, people have tellies Do people have the TV under it? Yeah. Oh yeah. People
Speaker 2:  got those.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Where's mine? You
Speaker 2:  Should, I mean, you should get yours. Yeah, but I, I've seen like Reddit
Speaker 2:  Threads of like I have a TV with a TV under it. Okay. And then If you try
Speaker 2:  to like hack the TV under the TV tell like tell a CO will arrest you personally,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 3:  He comes to your house and just holds ads in front of you while you look
Speaker 3:  at the tv.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I'm just saying this is all the mix, right? Like the, the
Speaker 2:  distribution of all of this content is where the money is. Yeah. It is
Speaker 2:  not the content, like more
Speaker 2:  than anything, video on the internet is now defined by its distribution and
Speaker 2:  everyone is competing against the best business model of all time, which
Speaker 2:  is what if a bunch of 20 year olds make the content for free, right? And
Speaker 2:  then we distribute it with ads around it. It it, its like an unbeatable business
Speaker 2:  model. And so you have Walmart being like, well we
Speaker 2:  wanna sell ads for Walmart stuff. We're gonna buy Vizio and that will quote
Speaker 2:  allow us to serve our customers in new ways to enhance their shopping journeys.
Speaker 2:  And it's like, I dunno what that means, but, but it sounds like you're gonna
Speaker 2:  track the shit outta me.
Speaker 3:  Well, I just, I think a lot about the, the thing Netflix keeps saying where
Speaker 3:  it's, it's not trying to compete with YouTube,
Speaker 3:  it's basically pitting itself against YouTube as like a a higher end
Speaker 3:  thing. It's like, oh, do you want to be next to like, you know, crummy
Speaker 3:  cat videos on YouTube, knock yourself out, but come here and get the high
Speaker 3:  end stuff. And I, the the big
Speaker 3:  question for this entire industry is how compelling that case turns out to
Speaker 3:  be to advertisers. Because what is true is that there are billions
Speaker 3:  and billions and billions of dollars of cable and broadcast TV advertising
Speaker 3:  that are going to become available to somebody else very quickly, much faster
Speaker 3:  than anybody thought. And that money has to go somewhere. And
Speaker 3:  the question is going to be do they wanna plug it into YouTube because that's
Speaker 3:  where the audience is Or do they wanna plug it into the most sort of
Speaker 3:  similarly shiny thing to what this once was? And I don't think anybody
Speaker 3:  knows yet, at least at the like scale we're talking about.
Speaker 3:  But, but that is the, it's the same bet all of these folks are making. Like
Speaker 3:  they want you to subscribe, they want you to, but mostly they want you to
Speaker 3:  look at ads. And the thing they want you to do the most, especially in the
Speaker 3:  next couple of years when all of this money has to move somewhere, is look
Speaker 3:  at ads. And I think
Speaker 3:  you can feel about ads supported streaming however you want. I mostly think
Speaker 3:  it's fine to be totally honest. I I am, I am less annoyed by it
Speaker 3:  every day than I expect that I'm going to be. But that is
Speaker 3:  coming. It just is. That is the thing.
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna say this one time and then we can move on.
Speaker 2:  It is still way easier to watch an NFL game
Speaker 2:  and what you might call the stormy seas than it's to pay for.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And that is the real thing that they're all, they're all truly competing
Speaker 2:  against is the user experience of their business models are getting away
Speaker 2:  in the user experience to the point where it is deeply
Speaker 2:  confu. It's like confusing and bad and people are like, whatever, I'll just
Speaker 2:  take it.
Speaker 3:  Well If you remember the thing that happened right after the glory days of,
Speaker 3:  of the late nineties and the early internet was piracy and Hollywood
Speaker 3:  basically just fell all over itself because of it.
Speaker 3:  Who knows?
Speaker 2:  We'll see, it's same by the way, If you have a telly, the TV with the TV
Speaker 2:  under it, or you, you work at telly and you wanna arrest David Pierce, let
Speaker 2:  us know. I'm very, I
Speaker 3:  Look at the ads, NELI don't come from me.
Speaker 2:  I look my phone during the show. The greatest greatest episode of this podcast
Speaker 2:  would be David Pierce gets arrested by the CEO of Tel.
Speaker 2:  Like that we'll send a camera crew out for that. All right, we gotta take
Speaker 2:  break. We're gonna be back with Kylie to talk about what on earth is going
Speaker 2:  on with artificial intelligence. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  We are back. Kylie Robinson's here. Hey Kylie. Hello. There's a lot of stuff
Speaker 2:  on your beat. You're our senior AI reporter and that means every week
Speaker 2:  just a number of people say things about our robot overlords.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And this week they just all at the same time
Speaker 2:  decided that AGI was coming. That's what that feels like to me is like we're
Speaker 2:  just gonna, we're just gonna say this is happening and then people can interpret
Speaker 2:  that to mean whatever they want. Do
Speaker 3:  You think there's a group chat like, like I remember in like the early days
Speaker 3:  of the pandemic, there were a bunch of tech CEOs who were like in a WhatsApp
Speaker 3:  together trying to figure out what to do and how to manage things and all
Speaker 3:  that stuff. And I'm like, is there now just like a AGI when
Speaker 3:  WhatsApp chat where where it's just like Sundar and Sam being like, is
Speaker 3:  did we do it? Should we say it now? Is this the one? I
Speaker 2:  Hope So. I mean I kind of, there should be, by the way, the who's in, who's
Speaker 2:  outta that group chat is Oof. That's a, that's a good one. Spicy.
Speaker 3:  Maybe that's the problem. Just let Elon back in. All the
Speaker 2:  Lawsuits go away. You know how the New York Times is subscription product,
Speaker 2:  but mostly for video games. Like we should transition our subscription to
Speaker 2:  just being who's in or who's out of the AI group chat
Speaker 6:  Like a MySpace top 10 for
Speaker 2:  And it's, yeah, we just get to crowdsource that every day and then that happens
Speaker 2:  in real life. Perfect. You know, like today the
Speaker 2:  audience of the Virgin decided Sam's outta the group chat and he like wakes
Speaker 2:  up and he is like, I'm not in the group chat.
Speaker 6:  I feel like we need to ship this immediately. Actually
Speaker 2:  This is very good. That's worth $7 a month. Lemme tell you. Alright,
Speaker 2:  let's start with Sam Altman was on stage at the deal book conference.
Speaker 2:  He announced something that I, he I think we had as a scoop and then he announced
Speaker 2:  it and so we just like ran it. But let's start with this. Open Eyes is gonna
Speaker 2:  do the 12 days of what they're calling ship Miss. Yeah. Get it David.
Speaker 3:  I don't like it, so No, I don't get it. Explain it to me. You tell
Speaker 2:  No. All right. There's a, there's a man who comes into your house.
Speaker 2:  I ostensibly to give you gifts and I ship. Really eat all of your cookies.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And we celebrate him anyway. So Ship Miss, that's gonna
Speaker 2:  include soa, the video generator, a new reasoning model. And then Kylie
Speaker 2:  today they announced that the first thing that they're announcing as part
Speaker 2:  of SHIP Miss is a $200 a month
Speaker 2:  OpenAI plan. What is going on here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And you talked about us having the scoop. I made probably a dozen
Speaker 6:  calls the day before and people are like, shit Miss. And I'm like, no,
Speaker 6:  no, like shipping something. I'm sorry. Can we do this quickly? Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  they just released a $200 a month plan for like a new
Speaker 6:  special oh one model. And I got this
Speaker 6:  heads up like, you know, not a lot of time before. So I'm still
Speaker 6:  processing it and my first gut reaction is
Speaker 6:  that feels like such a joke. Like give us $200 and you get something so special,
Speaker 6:  just trust us. So yeah, it's like a special oh one
Speaker 6:  model. It's supposed to be better at coding, better at like, you know,
Speaker 6:  aggressive research if that's what you're into. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is that like the, you know, when did the Apple watch Shanny? I was like,
Speaker 2:  this one's made of diamonds $5,000 and it just kind of didn't matter
Speaker 2:  'cause some people just wanted to pay $5,000 for Apple Watch. Is that, is
Speaker 2:  that what's going on here or is it actually more capable or do we just not
Speaker 2:  know
Speaker 6:  They have internal testing that they released? I am always skeptical of
Speaker 6:  internal testing, whether that's fair or not. It's just like my natural response
Speaker 6:  is like, I would like a lot more testing and proof and of course I wanna
Speaker 6:  try it myself and see how I feel. And I wanna hear from engineers who use
Speaker 6:  it for coding. They're like, oh, I do actually feel a difference. So until
Speaker 6:  I see some of these markers, I'm not entirely sure myself, but they say that
Speaker 6:  yes it is better. But being an SF and being an AI
Speaker 6:  reporter, I'm imagining all the dudes in Hayes Valley who are like, oh my
Speaker 6:  God, I'm gonna pay $200 a month and would be so cool. Like yes, it is like
Speaker 6:  that Diamond Apple watch. It's just to have it, I would just recently
Speaker 6:  did an interview with the head of chat, GBT, Nick Hurley and he
Speaker 6:  was telling me that some people have multiple like paid accounts because
Speaker 6:  they like, they, it, it's, it's interesting. So some people, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  they're really into it, I guess paying more money.
Speaker 3:  There's such a like FOMO, fake arms race thing
Speaker 3:  to all of this that I think this is just part of, right? It's like everybody's
Speaker 3:  out here talking about the number of Nvidia chips that they're buying as
Speaker 3:  like a badge of honor for how cool your startup is. And like, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna get to the point now where come work at our startup and we'll give
Speaker 3:  you chat GPT Pro for $200 a month to do work instead
Speaker 3:  of going to that other startup that only gives you
Speaker 3:  plus, I guess what it's called, by the way, OpenAI, remember that moment
Speaker 3:  where you were like, we're gonna get better at branding and our names are
Speaker 3:  gonna make more sense. Whoops. Whoops, you lost that real
Speaker 3:  fast. But anyway, like I, it really does, again, I think it's,
Speaker 3:  it's possible that this will be like meaningfully better, but it really feels
Speaker 3:  to me like OpenAI is just like, we can,
Speaker 3:  we can do this thing where everybody is looking for any kind of tiny edge
Speaker 3:  and there are a lot of people with a lot of money who will pay for that edge.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Let's just see what happens. Like the the, the price,
Speaker 3:  what's the, what's the word for when you try to figure out how much
Speaker 3:  people are willing to pay for something
Speaker 2:  Elasticity?
Speaker 3:  The Yes, the price elasticity test is very much on in
Speaker 3:  the AI world right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think the New York Times had reported they wanted to, you know,
Speaker 6:  make tens of billions of dollars in revenue and like now we
Speaker 6:  kind of see what their plan was. They're like $200.
Speaker 2:  It's Apple Watch additions. Exactly. Carl Lagerfeld is gonna buy this
Speaker 2:  model and never set it up and he is just gonna wear around his unset up
Speaker 2:  Apple watch as a status symbol for a while and then move on.
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting. Like, I just wanna put that, I wanted to start
Speaker 2:  there, right? They're gonna ship a bunch of new products over the next 10
Speaker 2:  days, 12 days. The first one is this like outrageously expensive
Speaker 2:  model and we have to see how well it works. That is in the context of, hey,
Speaker 2:  a bunch of people are saying the models aren't scaling in capability the
Speaker 2:  way they were last year, right? Yeah. It's been two years since chat Vidi
Speaker 2:  came out. They did 3.5 and four Oh
Speaker 2:  and now oh one. Well these names are all horrible and like they're plateauing,
Speaker 2:  right? And there's a report that Gemini is sort of plateauing and actually
Speaker 2:  they need, Gemini is not as good as the old Gemini. Like there's a sense
Speaker 2:  that, okay, like a lot of hype happened because of the first big
Speaker 2:  step up in capability, but it's not just like a linear increase
Speaker 2:  in capability over time. And it feels like open eyes just kinda like running
Speaker 2:  at that and being like, no, this one's so good, it's worth 10 x more money.
Speaker 2:  And I, I can't quite square those things,
Speaker 6:  Right? I mean that's how I read the deal book story that
Speaker 6:  Heath did about, you know, AGI is actually not gonna be that big of a
Speaker 6:  deal. I just feel like they have drummed up so much hype, like
Speaker 6:  an unnecessary amount of hype and now they all have to reckon with that.
Speaker 6:  So like that's, that's the state is it plateauing a lot of
Speaker 6:  AI leaders right now. Like their common thing to say is like we've just gotten
Speaker 6:  used to it and now like companies can't keep up with like the hype and like
Speaker 6:  the progress they've had in the past, but scaling laws have brought us to
Speaker 6:  this point and they should take us more. You know, take us further.
Speaker 6:  But that remains to be seen I think. Yeah, they are experiencing some
Speaker 6:  plateauing. That's why we're seeing some incremental developments. And why
Speaker 6:  we're not getting like GPT five right now as much as they probably wanna
Speaker 6:  release it right now. It's clearly not ready.
Speaker 2:  I just wanna read you that quote that Heath wrote up. So Sam Altman is on
Speaker 2:  stage at the deal book conference this week with Andrew Erkin and he says,
Speaker 2:  my guess is that we will hit AGI sooner than most people in the world think,
Speaker 2:  and it will matter much less. Which is an incredible quote,
Speaker 2:  right? Because he, he has said on like, Reddit, we're gonna hit
Speaker 2:  AGI on current hardware. Yeah. Which is a remarkable claim
Speaker 2:  because if that's what you think we should just, again, I think we should
Speaker 2:  just stop all other work and get to that. But then he is like, and also it
Speaker 2:  will suck. Like, we're gonna make this, we're gonna, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  make AGI, artificial general intelligence can do any task as well as a person
Speaker 2:  and it will not be as good as you think it is. And it's like, so you're gonna
Speaker 2:  make a dumb person. Is that, what are you saying is
Speaker 2:  going to happen here? They
Speaker 6:  Said human intelligence, not, you know,
Speaker 2:  Super intelligence.
Speaker 6:  Sure, fair. But you know, they, they throw around human intelligence a lot.
Speaker 6:  You know, we're getting there. It's right now they're saying like a smart
Speaker 6:  college student, right? I don't know. I feel like they have just
Speaker 6:  like, they've screwed themselves on this hype and that's why, that's what
Speaker 6:  I read when I, when I saw that deal book line, I'm like, well, you know,
Speaker 6:  you've got a 10% expectations now before you say that, the next thing is
Speaker 6:  AGI. And everyone's like, this is AGI. You know, it feels like he's like,
Speaker 6:  well it's actually not gonna be that big.
Speaker 2:  And then some bigger context there is, there's reporting that
Speaker 2:  opening I can get out of its deal with Microsoft if it
Speaker 2:  decides all by itself that it's achieved AGI, which I think was related to
Speaker 2:  its like old structure. Yeah. Where it was like a nonprofit board and all
Speaker 2:  that board was there to do was D decide whether to achieve AGI
Speaker 2:  safely and or fire. So Sam Altman and they did one and not the other.
Speaker 2:  And Sam Altman got rid of them all and now they're gonna turn into a for-profit
Speaker 2:  company. So Microsoft is saddled with this weird clause in their deal.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Where if Sam Altman decides it's AGI, he gets to leave the
Speaker 2:  Microsoft deal, which is weird, right? That that's just a weird set of incentives.
Speaker 2:  I will, by the way, I'll preview that on Monday. Decoder
Speaker 2:  with Mustafa Soleman, who is the ex co-founder. Well he is,
Speaker 2:  he's not the ex co-founder who co-founded DeepMind, which is now Google DeepMind.
Speaker 2:  And he left and started inflection and then like weird reverse and we hired
Speaker 2:  his way and now is the CEO of Microsoft ai. And I asked him, the first
Speaker 2:  question I asked him was, are we gonna hit AGI in current hardware? And he
Speaker 2:  did not agree. Yeah. Hmm. I repeat the whole episode, but he was
Speaker 2:  kinda like, yeah, no, I mean maybe someday what he was like, what do you
Speaker 2:  think current hardware means? Which is an incredible response to that question.
Speaker 2:  And then he was like, what do you think AGI means? And I was like, I
Speaker 2:  I am the interviewer. You tell me good questions for you.
Speaker 2:  It was a good decoder. He's fun to talk to. We like each other. We like challenging
Speaker 2:  each other. That's all fine. But like, I don't think he agreed with Sam,
Speaker 2:  but I do think he was also moving the goalpost for
Speaker 2:  AGI. He very clearly, I was like, if we're gonna build this the
Speaker 2:  singularity, he was like, shouldn't we just stop and work on that? And he's
Speaker 2:  like, AGI is not the singularity. Yeah. Which is not the hype that we've
Speaker 2:  all been experiencing for a minute. Right. The hype was we have to stop this
Speaker 2:  because if we make it before we're ready, we'll destroy the world. That's,
Speaker 2:  remember that's Elon Musk. That is why all the people are leaving OpenAI
Speaker 2:  to start literally this company's called safer superD intelligence.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I, Ilya s giver, who was a big part of this
Speaker 3:  whole process in June of this year,
Speaker 3:  described AGI in the context of the OpenAI charter, which
Speaker 3:  presumably Sam Altman was part of and would agree with as a computer
Speaker 3:  system which can automate the great majority of intellectual labor. He called
Speaker 3:  that one useful definition. It is. So we cannot let
Speaker 3:  Sam Altman off the hook for doing this. We just can't. This is ridiculous.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like my man has spent a decade, he made AGI a thing
Speaker 3:  like Yep. The fact that we all use the term AGI is Sam Altman's fault.
Speaker 3:  And to now just come and, and try to just sort of offhandedly sit with
Speaker 3:  Andrew Russ, we're gonna be like, ah, it's not that big a deal Is is
Speaker 3:  bullshit. Yeah. And we, we should not let him do this. Totally. It
Speaker 3:  it is, it's a bunch of like political maneuvering because it's gonna make
Speaker 3:  his life easier to just declare it AGI and move on. You're right. That it'll
Speaker 3:  help with the hype because there, I think it's very clear that whatever this
Speaker 3:  moment where AI wins is not going to happen soon if it
Speaker 3:  happens ever. Yeah. It also lets them get outta the Microsoft deal. So like
Speaker 3:  I can see why you do this if you're Sam, we just all have to keep saying
Speaker 3:  out loud that this is what he's doing and it's bullshit. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Totally. I
Speaker 2:  Agree. He also, Andrew Erkin asked him about
Speaker 2:  OpenAI and Microsoft Disentangling. He actually quoted Alex Heath, which
Speaker 2:  yeah, Heath was very excited about this indeed. Immediate text from Alex
Speaker 2:  when this happened. Live in the room. And Sam said, I don't think we're
Speaker 2:  disentangling from Microsoft. Which again, I asked
Speaker 2:  SFA the same thing. And he is like, we'll see how it goes. And he said that
Speaker 2:  three times until I said, you said, we'll see how it goes three times now.
Speaker 2:  And he is like, oh, it's fine. So
Speaker 3:  His real, like Chris Martin and Gwyneth Paltrow being like, we didn't break
Speaker 3:  up, we consciously uncoupled. Like that's, that's how this will go. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  With Microsoft. And
Speaker 6:  Can I add my own tinfoil hat that today, because I've been so wrapped up
Speaker 6:  in OpenAI News, they obviously had this huge launch and a live stream and
Speaker 6:  I have all of these CEOs notifications turned on on Twitter of course.
Speaker 6:  And, and So I get like my own little feed of them and Satya like
Speaker 6:  reposted a bunch of Microsoft announcements that that came today
Speaker 6:  as well. That I think Tom Warren, he scooped some of those
Speaker 6:  but, and like no repost from Sam. No. Like this is my
Speaker 6:  favorite boy Yeah. Succession style. Like, it's like just, I was like, that's,
Speaker 6:  that's really weird timing that they're doing this in Satya's. Like it seems
Speaker 6:  like he's ignoring the whole AI
Speaker 2:  Lunch outta of a group chat. Man, $7 a month you can kick Sam Altman outta
Speaker 2:  the group chat.
Speaker 3:  These things are not accidents. Like that is definitely a tinfoil hat theory.
Speaker 3:  But like when you're Satya Nadella, you do not do that stuff Right. Without
Speaker 3:  thought behind it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There. Exactly.
Speaker 3:  The only person who tweets without thinking is Elon Musk. Most other
Speaker 3:  tech CEOs are doing stuff on purpose. Right.
Speaker 2:  That's actually a very good point. Okay. So this is like,
Speaker 2:  we're like laying up the context, right. OpenAI is gonna announce 12 days
Speaker 2:  worth of stuff, including a model that they think is so good that's worth
Speaker 2:  $200 a year. Sam Altman is moving the AGI
Speaker 2:  goalposts to like tomorrow. Right. He is like, I
Speaker 2:  can do this, I can do this on a Nvidia 40 60 for 20 bucks.
Speaker 2:  Like, doesn't matter. Like he's like, you give me an Xbox
Speaker 2:  enough gasoline, I'll give you AGI. Like that's where his head's at. And
Speaker 2:  then the reality of the products right now is that they're nowhere
Speaker 2:  near good enough. Yeah. So the Columbia Tao Center for
Speaker 2:  Digital Journalism released a report this week and
Speaker 2:  it basically asked Chacha Pi to identify the source of 200 quotes from 20
Speaker 2:  publications. And it just couldn't do it. Like it just
Speaker 2:  hallucinated its way through that it produced partially or entirely
Speaker 2:  incorrect responses on 153 occasions. And it only acknowledged
Speaker 2:  inability to accurately respond and inability to accurately respond
Speaker 2:  seven times
Speaker 3:  It it asked it just, just, just to say it again, it asked it
Speaker 3:  200 questions and it got 153 of them wrong. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it only admitted that it might be wrong seven times. Right.
Speaker 3:  Didn't admit that it was wrong. Admitted like the possibility that potentially
Speaker 3:  maybe it could be seven times.
Speaker 2:  And then in the culture people are using these tools without
Speaker 2:  a second thought. So Liz Lipato,
Speaker 2:  this is just a Liz banger, like I think she turned this around in five minutes.
Speaker 2:  I think there's all just poured out of her head in one stream of consciousness.
Speaker 2:  'cause I didn't know she was writing this story. It just went up today. But
Speaker 2:  it's very good because I get to say the following phrase on CNN
Speaker 2:  Anna Navarro Cardenas cited a list of
Speaker 2:  presidential family members who have been pardoned by presidents. And she
Speaker 2:  said, president Woodrow Wilson pardoned his brother-in-law Hunter
Speaker 2:  debuts. Which I
Speaker 2:  like. It's like, I know the internet made the robots say hundred deButts.
Speaker 2:  Like right, If you say there's a hundred deButts, I'm like, that's not real.
Speaker 2:  Like when the internet produces the words hundred deButts, I'm like, I know
Speaker 2:  what happened here a hundred of a hundred times. Right? Like there's a Reddit
Speaker 2:  Threads, it's like hundred debuts, there's full, there's like
Speaker 2:  lore, you know, it's like all that happened. Oh yeah. And the robots are
Speaker 2:  confused. So Liz went through this exhaustively to figure out where
Speaker 2:  this came from and she found out that like Chepe basically doesn't,
Speaker 2:  can't answer the question, which presidents have pardoned their family members.
Speaker 2:  Like you just read the piece and Never Cardena is
Speaker 2:  says take it up with chat GPTI said this thing wrong thing on cable
Speaker 2:  news about the words hunter debuts. Wow. And she's like,
Speaker 2:  take it up with chat GPT. And it's like, that's not correct first
Speaker 2:  of all. No. So she tweeted it and then she got it wrong and then she just
Speaker 2:  take up a chat. CBT. I'm just saying that is
Speaker 2:  crazy. Like we are racing towards
Speaker 2:  replacing all of our search engines with these tools, answer
Speaker 2:  engines, which is what Google has long wanted to think of it Google as
Speaker 2:  Google as a search engine. The 10 blue links was like, here are sources.
Speaker 2:  Go read these sources, you can trust them or not. And now they're, now it's,
Speaker 2:  here's an answer and their out is, here are some
Speaker 2:  links to footnotes. And it's like no one's ever gonna click the links. They're
Speaker 2:  just gonna, they're just gonna tweet the words hunter to butts. I I
Speaker 6:  Click the links. I have to defend myself because, but
Speaker 2:  You're a professional journalist.
Speaker 6:  I went on The Verge on our YouTube and I said, I really like
Speaker 6:  AI search because I think it helps me get my answers quickly, but I'm not,
Speaker 6:  I'm not paying, I don't think I'm even really paying close attention to what
Speaker 6:  it's saying. I'm clicking the relevant links because Google is so bad at
Speaker 6:  just telling me who said what, who reported what, and then I can just
Speaker 6:  go and look. I'm, I guess I'm never really paying attention to the answers.
Speaker 6:  And that's, and that's important with what we saw with that report
Speaker 6:  I had, again, I had just talked to the head of chat GBT and I am
Speaker 6:  writing about this, this story of how they started and how they started.
Speaker 6:  They were like, no one's gonna like this product because it is wrong and
Speaker 6:  so confidently wrong. They're like, we shouldn't release this. No one's gonna
Speaker 6:  like this. They're gonna hate it actually 'cause it hallucinates so often.
Speaker 6:  And they decided to go for it and re release it as a research preview
Speaker 6:  to see how people would use it. And people really loved it. And two years
Speaker 6:  later it is still confidently wrong and it is making
Speaker 6:  billions of dollars in revenue. Obviously it's not profitable, but still
Speaker 6:  like all of that besides the point, it still hallucinates like crazy and
Speaker 6:  people still love it. And I can't really figure out why that's the case.
Speaker 2:  If you'll recall a year ago everyone was like, we'll solve hallucinations,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. It was just waved away. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like we're we got this, we got this under control, we know what to do. And
Speaker 2:  it's like, no, you super don't have this under control. Yeah. Because the
Speaker 2:  words Hunter deButts have now appeared on the internet in its totally sincere
Speaker 2:  way, which is, you know, like if anybody had any
Speaker 2:  sense, they'd be like, okay, we should hit pause before we declare that this
Speaker 2:  thing is AGI. Right. And I think this to me is just a fundamental
Speaker 2:  question of all of these tools. Can this technology actually do the things
Speaker 2:  that the people say it can do? And right now it can't even
Speaker 2:  like deduce what is true and what is fake and what is just a
Speaker 2:  pure hallucination. Right.
Speaker 3:  Right. Well, and I think this is why the search piece of this is so interesting
Speaker 3:  to me because If you just take chat GBT as
Speaker 3:  a whole, right? And you say, okay, the idea that it gives you the incorrect
Speaker 3:  answer to this one specific question is a bummer. But
Speaker 3:  it is so sort of ancillary to what most people are using chat GBT
Speaker 3:  for fine. I don't necessarily buy that argument, but it is
Speaker 3:  an argument, right? That it's like, and this is what we hear with a lot of
Speaker 3:  AI stuff. You, you people do attest with it and they're like, well, real
Speaker 3:  users aren't doing that, so we're not actually that concerned with it. Feel
Speaker 3:  that about that however you want. But that is, that is a thing you can say
Speaker 3:  when it comes to search, the whole damn job is to find
Speaker 3:  relevant and true information right on the internet. And so, so the fact
Speaker 3:  that they've pivoted from like this is a good tool for writing code,
Speaker 3:  which is, which is a real thing that is true and it makes mistakes, but it
Speaker 3:  also writes good fast code. And that, that seems to be a
Speaker 3:  trade worth making for a lot of people who write code for a living when the
Speaker 3:  whole job is correct information retrieval, and you are presenting it
Speaker 3:  as I have answered your question about the web.
Speaker 3:  Then the, the stakes are different. And the idea that like this, this thing
Speaker 3:  sometimes makes mistakes, I think just no longer becomes
Speaker 3:  acceptable because you, you've now built a product on the idea
Speaker 3:  that it can do this thing that it just demonstrably can't do.
Speaker 6:  I don't think it's acceptable, but it's like also the people who are coding
Speaker 6:  and using it want it to produce correct code. And then like I've been told
Speaker 6:  junior engineers shouldn't be using it, but senior engineers can because
Speaker 6:  they know what's wrong and they can fix it and, and the output that it's
Speaker 6:  given. So I as like a senior reporter, I'm like, I, I know all of this, I
Speaker 6:  just need to find this information quickly and Google is just absolute
Speaker 6:  garbage at this. So I mean, I don't know, it just takes like
Speaker 6:  knowing that, and that's something I'm gonna keep referencing this one interview,
Speaker 6:  the head of chat BT said he was like, you know, the users at the beginning
Speaker 6:  knew that they were gonna have to check this information. They knew how to
Speaker 6:  prompt around things and they're fine with that. So like that's the people
Speaker 6:  using chat GBT to be clear. But I agree, I don't think it's
Speaker 6:  acceptable to be like we have the answers and we literally like 90%
Speaker 6:  of the time don't actually have an accurate answer. I think that's also unacceptable.
Speaker 3:  Like forget all the like bigger philosophical stakes. That's just a bad product.
Speaker 3:  Like what If you went to Google and it just gave you a bunch of links that
Speaker 3:  had nothing to do with your search, that would just be a bad product. Doesn't
Speaker 3:  it already kinda do that.
Speaker 2:  I fun links that make you feel good about yourself.
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 3:  It's, it's just like slightly nicer to you than it should be.
Speaker 2:  Lemme just give you an example of bad product. This also happened this week,
Speaker 2:  and I just wanna put this all in the context of we're we're defining
Speaker 2:  AGI down so we can say it happened, right? Yeah. And we're gonna charge $200
Speaker 2:  a month for some of our models the same week.
Speaker 2:  A misinformation researcher, the founder of the Stanford Social Media lab
Speaker 2:  got in trouble because he wrote an affidavit in support of an anti
Speaker 2:  deepfake law in Minnesota that is being challenged by court.
Speaker 2:  So like there's a law in Minnesota that says you can't deep fake politicians
Speaker 2:  during a political campaign. It seems reasonable. There's a lot of like First
Speaker 2:  Amendment stuff, whatever, it's being challenged in court by a bunch of conservatives.
Speaker 2:  And this guy, founder of the Stanford Social Media Lab wrote an affidavit
Speaker 2:  in support of this law to the court. And it turns out he used ChatGPT BT
Speaker 2:  to help him organize the citations and it hallucinated the citations.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 2:  Nice and it's like, what are you doing? You of all people know, right?
Speaker 2:  Right. You, you know that the duals hallucinate, but they're so confident
Speaker 2:  and you're like, screw it. Here it is. I here's the quote. I
Speaker 2:  wrote and reviewed the substance of the declaration and I stand firmly behind
Speaker 2:  each of the claims made at all, which are supported by the most recent scholarly
Speaker 2:  research in the field and reflect my opinion as an expert regarding the impact
Speaker 2:  of AI technology and misinformation and societal effects. Oh God. And then
Speaker 2:  he goes on to say that he used Google Scholar and ChatGPT four oh to quote,
Speaker 2:  identify articles that were likely to be relevant to declaration. So I could
Speaker 2:  merge that, which I already knew with new scholarship. And it's like the
Speaker 2:  new scholarship was made up. Right.
Speaker 3:  First of all, why
Speaker 2:  I asked a robot to hallucinate and then I added my ideas to it is like,
Speaker 2:  you know, that's not correct.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I also just, I'm convinced like somewhat
Speaker 3:  sincerely that this is just a bit like it's all, it's all
Speaker 3:  too perfect for this to have earnestly happened to this person. Like
Speaker 3:  not only it's, it's like he, it's like he hid it at the bottom just
Speaker 3:  to see if anybody would notice and somebody noticed
Speaker 2:  Brown m and ms. This is the real theme of The Verge House is when Halen shows
Speaker 2:  up and says, don't put brown m and ms in the dressing room. Right. To see
Speaker 2:  if you're paying attention so that you know the pyros right. And everything
Speaker 2:  in the world is explained by Brown m and ms. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Honestly, potentially. Did I
Speaker 2:  Hallucinate these citations? Were you reading that? Did you read my affidavit?
Speaker 2:  Judge,
Speaker 3:  But also I will say my, my wife is currently in grad school and is spending
Speaker 3:  an enormous amount of time doing things like putting together
Speaker 3:  perfectly formatted citations and actually got knocked off
Speaker 3:  points on a paper she turned in because everything was
Speaker 3:  right, but she like put the page number and the source in the wrong order.
Speaker 3:  Nice. And so loss points. And so she, I I've had like a year and a half now
Speaker 3:  of her just like raging against citation systems and so I'm like,
Speaker 3:  listen, if AI just wants to cite some stuff for me and I don't even have
Speaker 3:  to worry about it, great. Done. Perfect. Lock it in
Speaker 2:  The David Pea doesn't
Speaker 3:  Have to be real. Probably not. Nobody's gonna check anyway. No one's,
Speaker 6:  No one cares
Speaker 2:  Last. Well, last couple ones. I wanna put in the context of Sam Altman to
Speaker 2:  find AGI now, but the, the robots are just drunk, right?
Speaker 2:  That's right. Is that, that's basically the shape of this segment. That's
Speaker 2:  right. Google Sendar trial also on stage deal book
Speaker 2:  interview basically is Andrew Oar being like, are you doing a good job? And
Speaker 2:  he was like, I'm doing a great job. That's the whole interview. You can watch
Speaker 2:  it. I mean, they're both very chill people. So even that was like five
Speaker 2:  ticks more hostile than the actual interview was. But that's basically the
Speaker 2:  shape of it. Are you doing a good job? I'm doing a great job. Okay. And then
Speaker 2:  he says, Sundar says, I would love to do a side
Speaker 2:  by side comparison of Microsoft's own models and our
Speaker 2:  models any day, anytime they're using someone
Speaker 2:  else's models, which is very catty. And what he means is Microsoft's own
Speaker 2:  models suck and they have to use OpenAI models.
Speaker 6:  The girls are fighting.
Speaker 2:  It also means that if Sam Altman thinks OpenAI models
Speaker 2:  are about to be AGI sort of definitionally, so are
Speaker 2:  Google's,
Speaker 6:  I think they've all admitted that. Like they're going to, like Elon said,
Speaker 6:  like if, if we were to hit AGI, like we're all hitting AGI at the same time
Speaker 6:  someone asked like, are you gonna get it to it first? He's like, probably
Speaker 6:  not. We're probably like all in lockstep gonna get to it at the same time.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. If the last two years are in the indication they're all within like
Speaker 3:  four weeks of each other Right. On every development side. Truly. Like
Speaker 3:  it just keeps happening. Like yeah, OpenAI does something and then Anthropic
Speaker 3:  does something that's, you know, 10 know 10% better on benchmarks and then
Speaker 3:  meta is something that's 10% better on benchmarks. And then Google's like,
Speaker 3:  what's up Gemini? And then we just start the cycle over again. The
Speaker 2:  Apple is like, there's 10 people at your front door,
Speaker 3:  Front door, back door and outside. Yeah. And this is
Speaker 3:  just like, it, it, this stuff is both
Speaker 3:  the most competitive and the most rapidly commoditizing
Speaker 3:  thing I can remember. Yeah. It's very strange. And So I think this is where
Speaker 3:  you get to what all of these companies are desperately trying to convince
Speaker 3:  you that they either have some thing in the works
Speaker 3:  that is so much bigger and better that yeah, it's gonna change it or
Speaker 3:  that they're gonna productize it so much faster. And I think for Google totally,
Speaker 3:  their whole move here is we can build these products faster than everybody
Speaker 3:  else, right? Like if it's Sundar is out here just being like, our models
Speaker 3:  are great, we're they're gonna ship more stuff this year, we think, but
Speaker 3:  they're like, he's like, whatever we're Google, I built it into Gmail
Speaker 3:  and Google Drive. Like, what do you got, Sam?
Speaker 6:  Totally. I think it's, it's interesting these incumbents, like
Speaker 6:  Amazon has its own like new set of models and like
Speaker 6:  there is reports about OpenAI trying to, you know, bake
Speaker 6:  you make, make chat GBT you know, a customizable
Speaker 6:  enterprise product for people to use. So it's like they're, they're
Speaker 6:  competing in the, in this way and the incumbent and the incumbents
Speaker 6:  have a huge advantage obviously, but in terms of
Speaker 6:  like this, this hype cycle, this constant hype cycle that's like the only
Speaker 6:  thing I've learned as a AI journalist is like, just do not trust a single
Speaker 6:  thing. Just don't trust a single thing. They're gonna tell you, you know,
Speaker 6:  we're not gonna raise prices, we're close to AGI, we're like all of these
Speaker 6:  things and IJ just only trust what is released
Speaker 6:  and you can use in front of you at, at the very least, if
Speaker 3:  Sam Altman really wanted to be cool, the thing he should have said is like,
Speaker 3:  oh yeah, we hit AGI like two years ago. ChatGPT was AGI. Like, who's gonna,
Speaker 3:  who's gonna stop it?
Speaker 2:  And people, people believe that it is. I I honestly think they're very much
Speaker 2:  trading on a bunch of people who
Speaker 2:  just love smooth talkers, you know what I mean? Like If you, If you
Speaker 2:  can talk real fast and real confidently, you can get pretty far in America
Speaker 2:  and chat TV is like how fast and how smooth, you know,
Speaker 3:  You know,
Speaker 2:  Like it can just do it and then people just buy it. My niece
Speaker 2:  just by the way, refers to it just as chat, so it's home for Thanksgiving
Speaker 2:  and she just kept saying, let me ask chat. And I'm like, you know, it's just
Speaker 2:  lying to you. She's like, whatever, like close enough. Which is
Speaker 2:  terrifying. But it's also just like, that's the relationship people have
Speaker 2:  with this product and at some point they're trading on
Speaker 2:  it hasn't done enough damage yet. Right. But something will happen,
Speaker 2:  another researcher will get caught, another lawyer will, you know,
Speaker 2:  show up with a, a fake citation
Speaker 2:  enough people are getting in trouble that the markets they that have the
Speaker 2:  money to spend will know, will stop spending the money until they can guarantee
Speaker 2:  reliability or accuracy or even just efficacy.
Speaker 3:  foreseeable future and maybe forever is being the
Speaker 3:  cloud provider of AI tools. And, and it's the
Speaker 6:  who's first beat in journalism was on the cloud and enterprise team. I love
Speaker 6:  it. I love what it comes up, comes just
Speaker 3:  Back at
Speaker 6:  It now. I it's a all roads lead back to SaaS is
Speaker 6:  where where it is. Yeah. I mean like that's the fight. That's where all of
Speaker 6:  the money is and if they wanna make tens of billions of dollars and train
Speaker 6:  their a hundred billion dollar models, they're gonna need some big chumps
Speaker 6:  to pay up for these enterprise contracts. Seriously.
Speaker 2:  I guess so let me just end here. One, I feel like we should go back and find
Speaker 2:  all the quotes of CS saying that would solve hallucinations and we like,
Speaker 2:  did this happen? Right? And then two, when, whenever, however we define AGI,
Speaker 2:  we should be like, if, If you made a somewhat smart college
Speaker 2:  student that just made shit up
Speaker 2:  40% of the time, 153 times out of 200 just lied
Speaker 2:  to you, would you be like, you drive a submarine,
Speaker 2:  right? Like there's something there, there's a disconnect there. That
Speaker 2:  still feels like the most important thing. As much fun as these tools are,
Speaker 2:  there's just a meaningful disconnect where they don't actually know anything.
Speaker 2:  We'll see. Totally. Kylie, what's your sense on like
Speaker 2:  12 days of shipments are coming, what's your sense on the next turn
Speaker 2:  here? Is it just opening eye barrels towards being a for-profit next year?
Speaker 2:  Oh yes. That's it. Like that's the main thing. This
Speaker 6:  Whole time my mind has just been screaming about defense contracts and how
Speaker 6:  if these, if these ais are consistently wrong and now
Speaker 6:  they're like signing like deals with and Andrew, it's like, oh my god. Like
Speaker 6:  that's, that's coming, that's coming. And it's, it's, you know, like the
Speaker 6:  stakes are getting higher and I don't know if the models are ready for the
Speaker 6:  stakes that are coming and that's really stressful. I mean if they, they
Speaker 6:  wanna throw agents onto the payroll of major companies
Speaker 6:  and Yeah. Get even deeper into defense and then build all these
Speaker 6:  data centers. I mean 20, 25, yeah the stakes are just gonna keep getting
Speaker 6:  higher and these people are gonna keep making money and I think we are gonna
Speaker 6:  see, as you said, some of these serious consequences that I,
Speaker 6:  I don't think, I mean obviously we have seen a lot of serious consequences,
Speaker 6:  but I don't think it's really snapped anyone in the industry out of what
Speaker 6:  they're building, if that makes sense. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  By way. And Andrew's, this is nothing with, and Andrew, it's more Palmer
Speaker 2:  lucky. Palmer Lucky made a game Boy, do you know about this Game boy? And
Speaker 2:  Sean Holster has the game boy, he like put up a video of it on like our TikTok
Speaker 2:  or something and he was like writing a review of this game boy. And Jake
Speaker 2:  cast our executive editor are like, you realize that your story is Lockheed
Speaker 2:  Martin made a Game Boy. Right? That's a, it's a very VERGE story, but you
Speaker 2:  just take another run at it from that angle. So soon we'll
Speaker 2:  run like it's a real art versus artist story, you know, it's like,
Speaker 2:  can you listen to Ignition remix anymore? Oh my god, Lockheed Martin made
Speaker 2:  a Game Boy. Like they're the same, those are the same ideas. So we'll soon
Speaker 2:  publish it. I, I dunno If you call it a review, we'll publish what
Speaker 3:  Such a, what if it's like a really pretty game boy a moral, it's like, it's
Speaker 3:  a really pretty
Speaker 2:  Game boy of this game boy at some point. Good point. As as soon
Speaker 2:  as you wrestle with the essential nature of art versus the artist. Alright,
Speaker 2:  we gotta wrap it up here. The AI is telling me our time has come to a close.
Speaker 2:  Kylie, this was great. Thanks for joining us. Thanks for having me. All right,
Speaker 2:  we'll be right back with lighting around and wait till you hear who the sponsor
Speaker 2:  is.
Speaker 2:  We're back with the lightning round. Liam tell the people who
Speaker 2:  sponsored the lightning round this week.
Speaker 1:  This week's lightning round is presented by Amazon Q, the new generative
Speaker 1:  AI assistant from AWS
Speaker 3:  Feels just as good the second time. It does have
Speaker 2:  To say
Speaker 3:  It does, it has not lost its shine.
Speaker 2:  Say it again Liam.
Speaker 1:  This week's lightning round is presented by Amazon Q, the new generative
Speaker 1:  AI assistant from a
Speaker 3:  WSI don't even think we get more money for that. It just feels so good. It
Speaker 3:  just feels so good. I don't care.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna find ways as part of the subscription to let, to let you, the
Speaker 2:  people sponsor the lightning round. This is one of the, one of the ideas
Speaker 2:  we have,
Speaker 2:  but that's pretty good.
Speaker 3:  Do you think people would like our ads more if they were all read by
Speaker 3:  Vergecast listeners every time? It's like, you can come perform the ads
Speaker 3:  on our podcast,
Speaker 2:  Right? 'cause I, David and I won't do it. Right. You got that
Speaker 2:  pesky journalism, which is why we make li do it.
Speaker 3:  It's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  But readers can do whatever they want. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I guess I did just like steal an idea from every NPR show ever. So I probably
Speaker 3:  shouldn't be as proud of myself for that as I am. Wait,
Speaker 2:  NPR lets the listeners read the ads. Yeah, like
Speaker 3:  Radiolab like does the credits at the end and it's like the, it's it's
Speaker 3:  a thing. People do it like whatever they're brought to you by the
Speaker 3:  somebody Sloan Foundation that's like, and
Speaker 2:  They let people call
Speaker 3:  Its do it. Yeah. And people like it. We could do this. We
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying lighting around sponsored. Oh, we got a subscription going.
Speaker 2:  The lighting around, sponsored. We spend this money by the way, on making
Speaker 2:  journalism. It's, you know, this is who we are. But
Speaker 2:  one day I'm gonna skim a little off the top and we're gonna get a boat.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna turn this into a real basketball hoop one day. It's
Speaker 3:  gonna blow mines.
Speaker 2:  You're, you're gonna be the guy who buys Michael Jordan's house in Chicago.
Speaker 2:  It's just been on sale. That's the new VERGE cast studio in the suburbs of
Speaker 2:  Chicago for years. So you go to Highland Park, you just drive by the gates
Speaker 2:  and part of the problem is the gates say 23 on this. Nobody wants to buy
Speaker 2:  this house.
Speaker 2:  It's like too much house for for Highland Park, you know, because
Speaker 2:  no one else there is Michael Jordan. It's true. It's just been on sale for
Speaker 2:  years. You can look at the pictures. You also have to commit to living in
Speaker 2:  Michael Jordan's house, which has, which does, by the way, David have a basketball
Speaker 2:  court in it. And also a room where Michael Jordan definitely got drunk and
Speaker 2:  smoke cigars and play poker.
Speaker 3:  But then the price keeps going down. You just keep saying good things and
Speaker 3:  I don't understand the problem.
Speaker 2:  Look, when we were looking for, as when it was time to leave the woods, you
Speaker 2:  know, and like get max into school, I was like, what if we lose in Michael
Speaker 2:  Jordan's house? And that idea was quickly rejected.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's
Speaker 2:  What I have to say. It wasn't on the table for a variety of reasons. Alright,
Speaker 2:  it's the lightning round
Speaker 2:  again, sponsored by whoever Liam said it was sponsored by because I'm too
Speaker 2:  precious to say it, but think about it, rewind it and listen to it one more
Speaker 2:  time. Okay, so here's the thing. We got a lot of feedback that our other
Speaker 2:  segment, which who was name was show and Tell was too much like the lightning
Speaker 2:  round. So to separate these
Speaker 3:  Good solid feedback, by the way. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It was correct. It was fundamentally correct. So our idea here is lightning
Speaker 2:  round. We're just gonna run through headlines as fast as we can. Lightning
Speaker 2:  style and hopefully that is perceptually different than
Speaker 2:  everything else we do on the show. Yeah. Which is we talk about
Speaker 2:  headlines. Alright, so here's number one, Bitcoin just hit a hundred thousand
Speaker 2:  dollars.
Speaker 3:  I have nothing to say. I, I cannot describe to you how little I have to say
Speaker 3:  about this.
Speaker 2:  I will just, I will say the two things I've always said.
Speaker 2:  How about Bitcoin? I've said them on CNBC to an audience
Speaker 2:  of people who did not wanna hear them from me. One, the only reason people
Speaker 2:  care about Bitcoin is dollars, which is why this headline is Bitcoin is now
Speaker 2:  worth a hundred thousand dollars. Not it's useful, right? I like not
Speaker 2:  more transactions are taking place in Bitcoin, right? You only care about
Speaker 2:  this 'cause of dollars. So at some point you're, you're, you've just
Speaker 2:  given up the game that Bitcoin is worth any, like a Bitcoin
Speaker 2:  qua. Bitcoin means nothing, right? 'cause you only care about how many dollars
Speaker 2:  it's worth. Second, If you have a Bitcoin, your incentive to
Speaker 2:  spend it is effectively zero. Why would you ever spend a Bitcoin
Speaker 2:  if the numbers just gonna be go up? It's
Speaker 3:  A, it's an asset class and like that's fine, right? And I think the,
Speaker 3:  the, the thing that I have come to appreciate over the last couple of years
Speaker 3:  is that the number of people who want to talk to me about how
Speaker 3:  this is the future of the internet has gone way down. And the number of people
Speaker 3:  who just wanna talk about how much money they're making has gone way up.
Speaker 3:  And to me, like I'm fine with that, right? Like we should talk about the
Speaker 3:  price of Bitcoin, the way that we talk about the price of baseball cards.
Speaker 3:  Like it's, it's a, it's a thing that you have
Speaker 2:  A fake idea for children. It's a,
Speaker 3:  I wouldn't gonna say quite those words, but basically, yeah. And like congrats
Speaker 3:  to everybody who has made a lot of money on Bitcoin, sincerely. Like great
Speaker 3:  job. I'm happy for all of you. I am increasingly
Speaker 3:  unconvinced that there is any kind of text story in Bitcoin and I am
Speaker 3:  more suspicious every day of people who tell me that there is because
Speaker 2:  There's no reason to spend one, right? It is a fundamentally UNT transactable
Speaker 2:  thing because you are just wasting money because all you care about is dollars.
Speaker 3:  The only good stories about Bitcoin are the people who like spent a bunch
Speaker 3:  of stuff on one 12 years ago and now it's like we
Speaker 2:  Are those people. I want to also wanna be very clear, you can assign us a
Speaker 2:  disclosure. We might be bitter because one time Adrian Jeffries
Speaker 2:  bought pizza with Bitcoin. Oh
Speaker 3:  That's right. I forgot that.
Speaker 2:  You know, you know, look up that story. It was a great story.
Speaker 3:  It's tough.
Speaker 2:  Adrian was one of our best reporters. She was a great writer
Speaker 2:  and she went to a, went to a bar and bought pizza Bitcoin. And every day
Speaker 2:  I think, boy, we could have sponsored our own lightning round. We
Speaker 2:  could have afforded the lightning round if we just held onto those Bitcoins.
Speaker 2:  I would just say, and even like we, you know, I think then Trump too is gonna,
Speaker 2:  there's gonna be a lot of crypto talk and infinite, the crypto lobby is
Speaker 2:  all very excited. And fundamentally it's all because of dollars.
Speaker 2:  They're just excited about how many dollars they will be. They will, the
Speaker 2:  things will be worth. Let's see what that means. Okay, this one David, I
Speaker 2:  need you to explain to me, okay, DIA is the
Speaker 2:  browser company's AI powered follow up to Arc.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So the browser company made a browser called Arc.
Speaker 3:  It's very good and very cool and a lot of people liked it. So of course the
Speaker 3:  browser company decided to stop making it. That's, that's that
Speaker 3:  entire story. And now they're onto their second
Speaker 3:  product, which they are trying to make into something that is
Speaker 3:  like thoroughly everyday mainstream. And
Speaker 3:  they just put up a video this week that was like half recruiting video,
Speaker 3:  half kind of vision video released the
Speaker 3:  name of the thing showed off a little bit about what they're talking about,
Speaker 3:  but it is like, this thing is still in its very early days, but basically
Speaker 3:  they're making a browser that is like mostly
Speaker 3:  AI. And there's some neat stuff in here. Like you can, anywhere there's a
Speaker 3:  text box. And this is the thing you can do when you're building a browser,
Speaker 3:  right? Is you, you just have access to the whole web as long as somebody
Speaker 3:  has loaded it in a tab, which is a very powerful thing to be able to do.
Speaker 3:  And so they're, they're doing a thing where you can like click on the cursor
Speaker 3:  in any text box to bring up like a contextual AI menu
Speaker 3:  and it'll do stuff inside of that page on that
Speaker 3:  text box. Like whatever you want. And the, the big idea here
Speaker 3:  again is to like reimagine the way that you do all of
Speaker 3:  the things that you want to do online with ai. I will say the
Speaker 3:  reaction to this launch has not been super positive. Yeah. The two
Speaker 3:  Threads that I've seen most are why couldn't you build this into arc the
Speaker 3:  browser that lots of people already like and no thank you. I am
Speaker 3:  not interested in having more AI things pop up every time I go to a
Speaker 3:  webpage. I have to say I find both of those arguments very compelling.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean this is a hint at we're gonna do agents, right? You're gonna say
Speaker 2:  order me a sandwich and then something is gonna go browse the web and order
Speaker 2:  a sandwich on my behalf.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And you can make a pretty good argument that the best way to do
Speaker 3:  that is with a web browser, right? Because it's like, right,
Speaker 2:  'cause you have the web,
Speaker 3:  Right? But only like you, you have the web and also you have me to
Speaker 3:  work with you, right? Like you can, I can open up, you can open up a tab
Speaker 3:  and show it to me. That's like, is this the thing that you want? And I say,
Speaker 3:  yeah, and it orders the thing for me. So like there's a, there's a useful
Speaker 3:  feedback loop inside of the browser that can actually really work. It's also
Speaker 3:  just a way to get access to everything without having to build
Speaker 3:  APIs, right? Like we've talked about the things that the rabbits and
Speaker 3:  human of the world are having to jump through to get access to DoorDash.
Speaker 3:  My browser can just go to doordash.com. Like yeah, it just can do it.
Speaker 3:  And So I think I, I have always thought the browser company is
Speaker 3:  like directionally interested in the right things,
Speaker 3:  but I, I am, I'm, I don't know, somewhere between curious
Speaker 3:  and skeptical that branching off to build this whole other thing that
Speaker 3:  is just like an AI bot on top of your browser is actually the thing
Speaker 3:  that they think it's
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and it's funny, Josh Miller was just on decoder as the CEO o the browser
Speaker 2:  company. He is like, our goal is to make an operating system for the web
Speaker 2:  that runs your web apps in it, which is a big idea. Yeah. Right? Most of
Speaker 2:  our, my apps are web apps anyway. I'm gonna, the browser will be more operating
Speaker 2:  system me and connect all those apps. And this is like a totally different
Speaker 2:  idea,
Speaker 3:  Right? And this is what they've been saying. Like you, you could
Speaker 3:  sort of push this towards that thing you're describing and that vision you're
Speaker 3:  describing has been their vision all along. Right? And in a way ARC became
Speaker 3:  like a diversion on that. It's like a power user redesign of a browser,
Speaker 3:  which is not an operating system for the internet. Yeah. So it'll, we don't
Speaker 3:  know a ton about what this browser's actually gonna be. They didn't show
Speaker 3:  that much. It was just a lot of like high minded talk about the internet.
Speaker 3:  Oh boy. So we'll see. But I will say the, the large number
Speaker 3:  of people out there who are not psyched about what is happening to Arc did
Speaker 3:  not seem to be satisfied by what deal looks like so far.
Speaker 2:  All right, next one. Threads continues to respond to Blue Sky
Speaker 2:  in a variety of ways, but then also just on their own pace. Another big
Speaker 2:  step towards Fed Verse integration. Now you can follow people from MA on
Speaker 2:  servers
Speaker 3:  Kind of
Speaker 2:  Fed verse servers, which is 99% activity
Speaker 2:  hub servers or 99% ma on. Yeah. So they won't, the post won't show
Speaker 2:  in your feeds, but their profile and posts will do appear on Threads
Speaker 2:  and you can get notifications and they
Speaker 3:  Publish. This one is so funny to me 'cause it is genuine. I
Speaker 3:  think I've been hard on the Threads team for not doing this
Speaker 3:  better and faster, but like credit where credit's due, they continue to
Speaker 3:  do the work and, and I believe sincerely that this is a thing that they want
Speaker 3:  to do Right and well, but the middle
Speaker 3:  phases are so weird. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's so
Speaker 3:  Complicated. So this thing where it's like you can follow somebody on the
Speaker 3:  Fedi verse, but you'll never see it unless you go to their profile page.
Speaker 3:  Like it's like 2006 era. Facebook is just a very weird
Speaker 3:  solution to a problem. And you get the sense they only announced this publicly
Speaker 3:  because somebody would've noticed it and it would've been a confusing
Speaker 3:  thing otherwise, you know what I mean? But again, like this is
Speaker 3:  a signal that they've done the hardest part, right. Which is pull that stuff
Speaker 3:  into Threads, how to co-mingle it with everything else
Speaker 3:  that's being posted to Threads is a difficult problem. But
Speaker 3:  that's like a thread specific problem. It's a big sign that
Speaker 3:  they've done a lot of the like really important protocol work that it shows
Speaker 3:  up in Threads at all. So I think that's really exciting.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And so, you know, we want to federate quick posts and we are figuring
Speaker 2:  out how to do that. Actually don't wanna federate, I don't know how we're
Speaker 2:  doing any of that. And our people they call what you're describing the inbox.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So like outbox is easy, right? Like everyone has solved RSS
Speaker 2:  that's outbox. It's when somebody hits likes and it comes to you or you're
Speaker 2:  pulling in posts from other sites, right? So the inbox is really hard and
Speaker 2:  they've obviously gotten there and Meta has like big data
Speaker 2:  regulatory problems as well. Right? So I, I'm excited for 'em to do it. A
Speaker 2:  a big question I have is whether they will find a way to bridge
Speaker 2:  activity pub with app protocol such that Threads can interoperate with Blue
Speaker 2:  Sky. Because once you build that bridge it kind of doesn't matter. Like all
Speaker 2:  bets are off, you know, and,
Speaker 3:  And you gotta figure if Threads is truly threatened by the rise of
Speaker 3:  blue sky, that is one way to, if not kneecap
Speaker 3:  blue sky to at least like enrich yourself on its
Speaker 3:  gains.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And If you're meta, like why do you care about what protocol you've
Speaker 2:  chosen to support? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think that that work gets done either way, right? Like there are already
Speaker 3:  people bridging app protocol and activity pub in some
Speaker 3:  interesting ways, but it would be interesting to see meta just
Speaker 3:  try to try to eat the whole thing all at once. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They also, that's a search feature with filters, but like whatever they,
Speaker 2:  this is like baby steps.
Speaker 3:  We made search usable. It was literally that announcement like
Speaker 3:  great, I'm, I'm happy to be able to finally find a thing I was looking
Speaker 3:  for on Threads.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Also on Threads meta Nick Clegg came out and said they're
Speaker 2:  moderating too much. I don't, I don't want to say about that. He is like,
Speaker 2:  we mistakenly moderate too much, which is true Threads is like a notoriously
Speaker 2:  overmoderated place. He says too often harmless content gets taken
Speaker 2:  down or restricted and too many people get penalized unfairly. This is a
Speaker 2:  true, like many people have had this experience, particularly in Threads
Speaker 2:  at the same time. Donald Trump is President Marza is at Mar-a-Lago,
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk probably also just skulking around Mar-a-Lago as he has want to
Speaker 2:  do talking about free speech while suing his critics as
Speaker 2:  he has want to do. If you're Mark Zuckerberg, you're like, ah, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  moderate a little less Donald like free speech for everybody.
Speaker 3:  There's also a really interesting pandemic era apology
Speaker 3:  in this, in this stuff from Nick Clegg talking about,
Speaker 3:  I think Facebook in particular was really aggressive about
Speaker 3:  moderating what was perceived for one reason or another to bel
Speaker 3:  to be incorrect information about the pandemic in the early days of the pandemic.
Speaker 3:  And it was super controversial and it wasn't that long ago that
Speaker 3:  Zuckerberg basically said the Biden administration told him to do
Speaker 3:  that or pressured him. Yeah. I mean, again, right? I
Speaker 2:  Just give a thumbs up. You're in your car, just imagine you're giving a thumbs
Speaker 2:  down. Yeah. That is a pure SOP to this administration.
Speaker 3:  So that's what I mean. Right? But this is like, it, it's pretty clear
Speaker 3:  what this push is. It is, it is like we take no responsibility
Speaker 3:  for what happened during Covid and there there is like a, a giant strain
Speaker 3:  of the right wing that is like furious about how information was shared during
Speaker 3:  the early days of the pandemic and radicalized a lot of people in a lot of
Speaker 3:  directions. Hey,
Speaker 2:  Just a quick question, David. Remind me, who
Speaker 2:  was president in 2020?
Speaker 3:  Who's to say who can
Speaker 2:  Remember?
Speaker 3:  It was so long ago.
Speaker 3:  Biden Biden made him do it. Yeah. Is I think what what was hard, he showed
Speaker 3:  up,
Speaker 2:  He's like, come to Delaware.
Speaker 2:  It's just, there's a real flattening, I don't wanna, it's the lightning round,
Speaker 2:  you know, it's like a, this is a good time. We got a sponsor today.
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna get into it. I, it's painful to re-litigate, but there's, there's
Speaker 2:  some real smashing of ideas down into
Speaker 2:  stories that don't make sense. Correct. And all of these platforms in the
Speaker 2:  early part of the pandemic all took the same steps and you can
Speaker 2:  love them or hate them, but they, Biden was not the president at that time.
Speaker 2:  And that is a thing that they're apologizing for is their early missteps,
Speaker 2:  not the later ones.
Speaker 3:  Right. But it is also very clear that Facebook is not the only company that
Speaker 3:  is essentially just gonna walk away from caring about content moderation.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  No, that, that seems, that's just where we're headed. And it's, what's funny
Speaker 2:  about that is the blue sky, right? They, they moderate pretty aggressively.
Speaker 2:  I, I would say, but they're, they're out is that If you want just
Speaker 2:  the full fire hose, you can have it and you can experience an
Speaker 2:  unmoderated blue sky. Right. Or If you want an even more moderate blue sky,
Speaker 2:  you can have it. And that, that is a very powerful out that I think is ultimately
Speaker 2:  gonna be the future. And part of the reason I think they're doing activity
Speaker 2:  pop right to say you can leave, but you can, people here can still find you
Speaker 2:  over there. Right. Alright, we should talk about Intel for one second.
Speaker 2:  Sean has a big explainer. What happened to Gelsinger, the Intel CEO
Speaker 2:  out after three years?
Speaker 2:  David, do you buy this conspiracy theory that they were like, you have to
Speaker 2:  spin off the foundry. And he basically was like, no, I mean, I'm a
Speaker 2:  proud Intel man. And no,
Speaker 3:  It certainly makes sense. I I don't pretend to be like America's most source
Speaker 3:  chip reporter, but the, the thing that I I think
Speaker 3:  is most odd about the way this is going is that
Speaker 3:  If you want something that feels like a stable company and
Speaker 3:  stable transition, this is not how you get rid of your CEO. It's just
Speaker 3:  not like he, he re he quote unquote retired
Speaker 3:  effective immediately and then a source
Speaker 3:  who pretty clearly was like on or near the board of directors just ran
Speaker 3:  around telling reporters that they fired him. Like that's just what happened.
Speaker 2:  That's how I'm gonna go by the way, when it's my time, it's gonna be exactly
Speaker 3:  John Legend board member of Vox Media. Exactly. Is gonna go tell people how
Speaker 3:  he fired me. Like, but so and
Speaker 3:  so the, the, the conclusion that a lot of people including Sean have drawn
Speaker 3:  is that there must have been a fork in the road somewhere. Right? Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  if you're, If you Intel, that is the biggest fork sitting in front of you
Speaker 3:  is we've spent all of Pat Gelsinger 10 years so far
Speaker 3:  spending, I mean spending like money is going outta style on becoming
Speaker 3:  a foundry, reshaping the way that we make chips, reshaping the kinds of chips
Speaker 3:  that we make. Like they've bet on everything simultaneously all at once.
Speaker 3:  And there is a real case to be made that actually splitting it
Speaker 3:  into two so that you have a company that designs chips and a company that
Speaker 3:  makes them. And having those be separate things can be really useful.
Speaker 3:  And Pat Inger has pretty loudly said he thinks Intel needs to
Speaker 3:  be both of those things at the same time. So it, it, it, it
Speaker 3:  certainly holds up to like a logical reasoning that that
Speaker 3:  would be the thing where eventually they're like, well, Intel is
Speaker 3:  running into the ground faster than you can turn it around. We have to make
Speaker 3:  this change. And he was like, no, I have to finish the plan. Like, I don't
Speaker 3:  know the answer, but boy, does it make sense?
Speaker 2:  It does feel like he also got caught holding the bag for a bunch of bad decisions
Speaker 2:  that happened before he showed up.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, yes. He, I think the mistake he made was he gave
Speaker 3:  himself four years and he should have given himself 10 seriously. Like
Speaker 3:  he came in guns blazing and was like, we're gonna do, we're gonna do
Speaker 3:  five nodes in four years, which would've, which is like an unprecedented,
Speaker 3:  outrageous pace of chip development and did pretty well.
Speaker 3:  Well
Speaker 2:  Also a bunch of the chips had a bunch of bugs in them. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  right. We, we made some chips that self-destruct is a thing that
Speaker 2:  happened under Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Pretty well is pretty well was two kind. He did some things and
Speaker 2:  Right. Their best chips are, I believe made by tsmc.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Currently. Right. And and there's a bunch of really interesting history
Speaker 3:  in both Sean's piece, which links to an interview you did
Speaker 3:  on decoder a while ago with the author of a book called Chip War, which gets
Speaker 3:  into a all of this stuff. And there's like some Intel TSMC history.
Speaker 3:  That's really fascinating. We'll put all that stuff in the show notes. People
Speaker 3:  should go see it. But
Speaker 3:  it, it really, I just keep coming back to the idea that like
Speaker 3:  CEOs of companies where things are going well and they are stable, don't
Speaker 3:  resign effective immediately. Yeah. It just doesn't happen. And
Speaker 2:  Then, and then other ly they find
Speaker 3:  Right to everyone who will win.
Speaker 2:  All right, I'm gonna smash these two together. All right. Trump has picked
Speaker 2:  his SEC head and his antitrust enforcement head of
Speaker 2:  D-O-J-S-E-C head is Paul Atkins. He likes
Speaker 2:  crypto. Everyone's very excited. By the way, I love it when the crypto industry
Speaker 2:  says they oppose regulation by enforcement, which is a great phrase. If you
Speaker 2:  really unpack it, it means we're doing crimes and they're enforcing the laws
Speaker 2:  against the crimes. And they're like, what If you made real laws that said
Speaker 2:  these weren't crimes? It is very good. That is good. And I, there's more
Speaker 2:  nuance that it's just every time they say it, like I, every, like, the next
Speaker 2:  time I get caught speeding, I'm be like, officer, you're doing regulation
Speaker 2:  by enforcement. Like, I don't dunno what you're talking about
Speaker 2:  anyway. Gail Slater is the more important one. And I
Speaker 2:  trust person. You know, there's a big case against Google.
Speaker 2:  There's a big case against Apple. There's a lot of antitrust
Speaker 2:  in this world.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft lingering.
Speaker 2:  Yep. Gail Slater was on JD Vance's team is pretty well
Speaker 2:  respected. I have been told that a bunch of the antitrust folks in the world,
Speaker 2:  like the antitrust agitators are pretty happy about her. The
Speaker 2:  reason I'm bringing up JD Vance, he has given speeches where
Speaker 2:  he's like, Lena Kahn's doing a good job. Yeah. Google is a threat to the
Speaker 2:  kinds of companies that I'm aware of in my, his like, you know, two year
Speaker 2:  fake job as a vc. But you know,
Speaker 2:  when Trump appointed Gail Slater, long
Speaker 2:  rambly Trump Post on True social and he said, big tech is outta
Speaker 2:  control and it's hurting Americans and Little Tech And Little Tech
Speaker 2:  is words straight out of Mark Andreessen's mouth. Yeah. Andreesen
Speaker 2:  Horowitz. Right now it's, I think their whole thing is the little tech agenda.
Speaker 2:  Like that's what they branded it as. So you have, and they're
Speaker 2:  railing and Google and Apple as well. So you just have this person, we don't
Speaker 2:  know her, we're gonna try to talk to her, but she's inheriting a very aggressive
Speaker 2:  antitrust program. The people in and around that program, it seems
Speaker 2:  like are reasonably happy with this choice. We're doing some more reporting
Speaker 2:  that it's just a vibe. It's not, I am not gonna source that too much. Just
Speaker 2:  a, just a vibe I've caught. And then you have Donald Trump himself using
Speaker 2:  the words of his many, many wealthy benefactors
Speaker 2:  saying, who have like, long since been critical of the power of
Speaker 2:  the Apple and Google wield. It's gonna be weird in
Speaker 3:  Large part because it makes it harder for them to fund companies that are
Speaker 3:  hugely successful. Like, just, just to pull that thought all the way out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm not saying any of this is like some good faith dealing, I'm saying this
Speaker 2:  is about to be some of the most gangster tech regulation that any of us have
Speaker 2:  ever, ever experienced in the horse trading is outta control, right? Yes.
Speaker 2:  Like If you, one of the, though, If you are a crypto
Speaker 2:  salesman, like you, what you wanna do is sell NFTs on the iPhone.
Speaker 2:  That would be a huge market. If you could unlock buying and selling NFTs
Speaker 2:  on mobile, that'd be great. Right Now Apple's gonna take 30% of every digital
Speaker 2:  transaction. You want that to go away. You know how you can do that? A
Speaker 2:  big antitrust case against Apple. Apple does not want tariffs on every iPhone.
Speaker 2:  They, Tim Cook needs to go walk up down. Like that's just, we're all gonna
Speaker 2:  sit around the table at Mar-a-Lago and reshape the American economy.
Speaker 2:  Yep. Somehow like, I don't know. And that it's not gonna
Speaker 2:  be like a process based, evidence-based agency
Speaker 2:  rulemaking. It's, it's gonna be whoever talked to Trump last.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like truly sitting around a table making these decisions is,
Speaker 3:  is a not particularly like euphemistic way to describe
Speaker 3:  what's about to happen. Yeah. Like that, that is how it's going to happen
Speaker 3:  in so many ways.
Speaker 2:  But I think the, the, a lot of people assumed that Trump
Speaker 2:  would come into office and, you know, pro business, pro big business especially,
Speaker 2:  he would insult an antitrust person That what the, the, the took all
Speaker 2:  these cases away. And I think there's a greater than even odds that these
Speaker 2:  cases continue and remain as aggressive as there.
Speaker 3:  It, it, yeah. I would say the, the early signals on this do
Speaker 3:  push to more towards that than I would've expected. And
Speaker 2:  Let me just wrap all this together. Lemme just bring this together in Trump's
Speaker 2:  first term. Macan del Rahim was his antitrust enforcer. And you recall that
Speaker 2:  instead of preventing T-Mobile from buying Sprint, he brokered a deal in
Speaker 2:  which T-Mobile was allowed to buy Sprint, thus reducing the number of national
Speaker 2:  carriers from four to three in America. And he sold Sprint's assets to
Speaker 2:  Dish Network, America's vibrant fourth
Speaker 2:  carrier. And that has resulted in this week tr Verizon just raising
Speaker 2:  its prices because there's no competition. A a market turn,
Speaker 2:  I would say.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Alright, well we're dangerously close to a Snyder cut conversation
Speaker 3:  here. So last one.
Speaker 2:  Alright, Gail, what are you gonna let Zach Snyder do in your
Speaker 2:  antitrust regime?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's the, the big questions we ask here on the first cast. How was
Speaker 3:  your Spotify Wrapped this year?
Speaker 2:  It was mostly full of the Moana soundtrack, little Encanto
Speaker 2:  and more Frozen two than anyone has the the right
Speaker 2:  to, to really deal with Boy More Frozen Two. Mine is
Speaker 3:  Becoming a alarmingly
Speaker 2:  Similar to that straight Peter sat song on the Frozen two song. I, I don't
Speaker 2:  get into it, but I listen to it. I was like, that was just Peter Satra. And
Speaker 2:  then yeah, it turns out they were very inspired by the musical styles of
Speaker 2:  Chicago.
Speaker 3:  There you go. Mine, my number one artist was The Wiggles, which was pretty
Speaker 3:  exciting. So was my wife's. And between us, we were both top
Speaker 3:  3% Wiggles listeners. Very good. Yeah. Mine was
Speaker 3:  all kids music and then one unreleased Broadway
Speaker 3:  show song that I got really obsessed with because I found it on TikTok and
Speaker 3:  that's been my yearend music. But anyway, I bring this up to say two things.
Speaker 3:  One, sincere thank you to every single person who
Speaker 3:  sends us their Spotify Wrapped with us on it. Yeah. Makes sense. It is
Speaker 3:  the best. Every single one of them just rules. And like,
Speaker 3:  we've gotten people who are like, I spent five days listening to The Vergecast
Speaker 3:  last year and like, I cannot, it's, it's the best. That is like the best
Speaker 3:  feeling every year is when people are like, you're at the top. Unless we're
Speaker 3:  second to hard fork and then, ha, dare
Speaker 2:  You,
Speaker 3:  You're dead to me. But the second thing is,
Speaker 3:  everybody's doing rap now. Like Reddit has the thing,
Speaker 3:  the other music services have it. Podcast services have it. Like they're
Speaker 3:  all kind of doing their year interview thing. Spotify for its new innovation
Speaker 3:  this year, partnered with Notebook LM from Google
Speaker 3:  to do an AI podcast of your rap.
Speaker 3:  Have you listened to yours? No. They're very funny. Mine is like four and
Speaker 3:  a half minutes long and it's both awful and
Speaker 3:  delightful. It's just like, like imagine a sort of bouncy
Speaker 3:  stranger just reading your raps to you who
Speaker 3:  has never met you before. It's so fun and so funny. And you come out
Speaker 3:  of it being like, this is somehow the person that Spotify thinks I am. And
Speaker 3:  I don't know what to do about that. But like, we're, we're in a real like
Speaker 3:  wrapped arms race now and I'm extremely here for it.
Speaker 2:  It's like funny how like most of the time people are like, don't surveil
Speaker 2:  me. And at the end of the year they're like, tell me everything about myself.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Listen, if you're gonna collect all this data on me, at least, like
Speaker 3:  give it back to me once a year. In a funny way.
Speaker 2:  I'm very excited for the, the Vizio, Walmart wrapped
Speaker 3:  Here are all the ads you engaged
Speaker 2:  With this year.
Speaker 3:  That's actually a good idea. Here's,
Speaker 2:  Here's exactly how much laundry detergent we prodded you into buying.
Speaker 3:  Here's how much you overspent on Amazon this year. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Midyear you switched car insurance providers. That was us.
Speaker 2:  Same.
Speaker 3:  I mean, you know, they do that for their advertisers, right? All the clients
Speaker 3:  are getting wrapped right now.
Speaker 2:  All right. My, I just looked at my Apple Music wrapped and my number one
Speaker 2:  playlist was Taylor Swift Essentials. And my number two playlist was two
Speaker 2:  thousands indie rock. And you can really tell perfect that there's a battle
Speaker 2:  in our house over who gets to ask for music. It's very
Speaker 2:  good. Very good. All right. That's it. We're way over. We're like six hours
Speaker 2:  over. We've been podcasting for a full year now.
Speaker 3:  We're also both sick right now, So I just wanna say congratulations to both
Speaker 3:  of us. We
Speaker 2:  Did. If you, yeah. If you've heard it was about sniffling and coughing and
Speaker 2:  my and Max just like screaming in the hallway. Yeah. It's just one of those
Speaker 2:  s at the end of the year. It's a time. Once again, I wanna say thank you
Speaker 2:  to everybody who's subscribed, particularly Vergecast listeners who are telling
Speaker 2:  us or are subscribing just to support us. That means a lot. Like we've been
Speaker 2:  doing this for a long time. Yeah. 13 years is a long time to be doing a thing
Speaker 2:  and to have so many of you say, I can't believe I wasn't paying for this
Speaker 2:  already. Which is a real, real note. We have gotten mind blowing, so thank
Speaker 2:  you. We're gonna keep at it. We're very stubborn. No one ever, no one can
Speaker 2:  pay to tell us what to do except for you, apparently. So we're gonna figure
Speaker 2:  that out and also send us more questions. Call the hotline, send us, send
Speaker 2:  us questions. Yeah. Helen's on next week, so send us questions, we'll answer
Speaker 2:  them. We're gonna be as transparent with our business as we can be. We think
Speaker 2:  that's an important part of the whole puzzle here. And then we have a big
Speaker 2:  launch feature for the subscription Josh Jeza wrote about like
Speaker 2:  falling in love with AI and the companies that do it, and the people that
Speaker 2:  actually fall in love. Go read that. It is incredible. It is easily worth
Speaker 2:  your $7. Like, oh, unquestionably, straightforwardly read out stories worth
Speaker 2:  seven. Yeah. So go, go check that out. It's, it's good. And the art is amazing.
Speaker 2:  Oh, and you haven't read our magazine content goblins. Yeah, subscribe for
Speaker 2:  that. It's good. The photos are amazing. All right. That's it. That's for
Speaker 2:  Chest rock.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  is a production of The Verge and Vox Media podcast network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Liam James Will Pour and Eric Gomez. And that's it. We'll
Speaker 1:  see you next week.