# Transcript
ID: 2b0c7246-a5fb-4a10-bc5a-0a8cb603a5c5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2768925550045318716/-6264323298954657864/s93290-US-4315s-1727177730.mp3
Description: Kylie Robison joins the show to talk about OpenAI’s new model, o1, and what this new “reasoning” model says about the state of the art in AI — and what AI companies are willing to put up with in the name of building God. Then, Gaby Del Valle and Adi Robertson talk through the latest on the TikTok ban, the Trump crypto chaos, and the ongoing adtech antitrust trial against Google. (All with as little politics-talk as possible.)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of things, code named Strawberry.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend, David Pierce, and I am currently in the Miami International
Speaker 2:  Airport. I just spent the weekend touring colleges with my nephew and suddenly
Speaker 2:  I'm like, college is awesome. I could go back to college. I don't think I
Speaker 2:  do very well. I don't think I would get in anywhere. I think my test scores
Speaker 2:  would be awful. If you're like, Hey, how do you do calculus? I don't know.
Speaker 2:  I have nothing for you. But suddenly college seems pretty appealing. So who
Speaker 2:  knows? Maybe this will be the end of my vergecast career and I'll just go
Speaker 2:  back to school or something. But anyway, that is not what we're here to talk
Speaker 2:  about today. We are here to talk about two things. We're doing a little bit
Speaker 2:  of a catch up on some kind of ongoing news happening in the tech industry.
Speaker 2:  First we're gonna talk about OpenAI, which has been doing a bunch of
Speaker 2:  sort of odd new work with different kinds of models and a
Speaker 2:  new thing that they call a reasoning model. Oh one, some strange
Speaker 2:  corporate changes. Lots just going on at OpenAI. So I figured
Speaker 2:  it's been a while since Kylie Robinson came on the show and told us what's
Speaker 2:  going on. So Kylie's gonna come on the show and tell us what's going on.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna talk about a bunch of ongoing legal and
Speaker 2:  regulatory things. We have the TikTok ban or not ban
Speaker 2:  ongoing. We have a bunch of questions about the Google Ad Tech trial. We
Speaker 2:  have whatever that Trump crypto thing was from a week or so
Speaker 2:  ago. So we're gonna catch up on all of that too. All of that
Speaker 2:  is coming up in just a sec. Plus a really fun hotline question that made
Speaker 2:  me feel a lot of feelings about my own life as these are. Want to do But
Speaker 2:  first. Legitimately, as of right this second, I just got the
Speaker 2:  notification that my plane is boarding. So time to fly home. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  fascinated by this thing that has happened really for the last
Speaker 2:  year, where you have a handful of companies, you have Google, you have
Speaker 2:  OpenAI, you have Anthropic, you have Meta,
Speaker 2:  constantly leapfrogging each other with new models. It's like every two weeks
Speaker 2:  somebody comes out with a new model that benchmarks better than anybody else's
Speaker 2:  model and it's cheaper. And then two weeks later, one of the other companies
Speaker 2:  does it. And we've just been on this relentless pace of everything
Speaker 2:  getting slightly better. And I keep asking the question and trying to figure
Speaker 2:  it out for myself of what does this mean? Like at what point
Speaker 2:  do all of these changes add up to something meaningfully different about
Speaker 2:  how you use your devices and how you interact with computers and how
Speaker 2:  computers interact with you and each other. And so far, I don't have great
Speaker 2:  answers. Everything's getting better, but it doesn't seem like we're getting
Speaker 2:  tons of huge new changes. If, you listen to
Speaker 2:  Sunday's episode, you heard Steven Johnson talk about Gemini's context window.
Speaker 2:  I think that's a good example, but there haven't been that many moments like
Speaker 2:  that. But then OpenAI last week released a thing
Speaker 2:  called O one, which is a new model that is very different and
Speaker 2:  seems to speak to kind of a different direction for these models to go. They're
Speaker 2:  not just getting bigger and faster and cheaper to run. But kind of
Speaker 2:  along the same lines, this is OpenAI saying something different about how
Speaker 2:  a model might work and how you might use it and what it might mean. Those
Speaker 2:  things are sometimes enticing and sometimes terrifying. So I figured it's
Speaker 2:  time to talk her way through it. So I asked Kylie Robinson to come back on
Speaker 2:  the show. She hasn't been here in a little while and I figured it'd be a
Speaker 2:  good time to dive in. Let's do it. Kylie, welcome back. Hello.
Speaker 2:  It's been a minute. I feel like every time I wanna talk to you, you're like
Speaker 2:  a burning man.
Speaker 5:  That's true. That is exactly what happened last time or on a crazy
Speaker 5:  vacation. Yes. Happy to
Speaker 2:  Be back. It's a tough life, honestly.
Speaker 5:  I know. Being 26 and sf, it's terrible.
Speaker 2:  Seems like it. Well, you were a Dreamforce this week, which is objectively
Speaker 2:  terrible.
Speaker 5:  No comment. But yes.
Speaker 2:  But I have, I have brought you here because there keeps being interesting
Speaker 2:  AI stuff. And specifically I wanna talk about O one
Speaker 2:  open AI's new model. Which first I just want you to
Speaker 2:  explain to me, I have many questions and feelings and thoughts about this
Speaker 2:  that I wanna go over, but I mostly just wanna know like what is O one?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And why does it exist?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So O one is open AI's new quote unquote reasoning
Speaker 5:  model. And I think you can argue about what reasoning is for a million years
Speaker 5:  So I won't, but that's what they're claiming. And it is the next step
Speaker 5:  in about five steps to a GI for OpenAI. Okay.
Speaker 5:  This is reasoning is really important to them. And more practically
Speaker 5:  what users and researchers are finding is that this model is better
Speaker 5:  at hard math problems and coding assignments.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Why? What? Like what, when you say a reasoning model? Yeah, I feel
Speaker 2:  like we've been hearing people say AI is good at
Speaker 2:  reasoning Yeah. For a very long time. So to come out with a reasoning
Speaker 2:  model makes it seem like something is meaningfully,
Speaker 2:  like structurally different here. Like what is that thing?
Speaker 5:  So they basically trained the model to think
Speaker 5:  step by step. So previously you might see a workaround with GBT four
Speaker 5:  or 4.0 that was like, okay, give me an answer and I want you to
Speaker 5:  think through it step by step. So they basically trained the model to do
Speaker 5:  that itself rather than have the user do that.
Speaker 5:  And through a lot of reinforcement learning, which looks like how you would
Speaker 5:  train a dog with treats and you know, penalties. That's
Speaker 5:  how I explain it. And people online are like, now I feel bad for the model,
Speaker 5:  how is it penalized?
Speaker 2:  But it also gets treats like it's fine.
Speaker 5:  It also gets
Speaker 2:  Treats.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So that's also led to this thing called reward
Speaker 5:  hacking that I wrote about. It's a very deep rabbit hole. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  so it's trained to reason in these ways. And then it has this thing
Speaker 5:  called a chain of thought that we can't see for competition purposes
Speaker 5:  and safety purposes is what they claim. So it just shows like,
Speaker 5:  okay, I'm, I'm breaking this down X, y, z ways.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's the, I'm breaking this down thing that throws me. 'cause we've
Speaker 2:  seen a bunch of screenshots and I don't know if you've used it much. I haven't
Speaker 2:  really used it much. It's like, it's kind of out there now. Yeah. Folks are
Speaker 2:  playing with it. It's, it's trying hard
Speaker 2:  to talk out loud as if it's a person thinking through a
Speaker 2:  problem. Yeah. Which is a weird, when a person does it. Like
Speaker 2:  if you've ever sat and like listened to somebody try to reason through a
Speaker 2:  hard problem, it's bizarre and doesn't make any sense. And to have
Speaker 2:  a computer sort of attempt to brute force its way through the
Speaker 2:  same thing. And it's using like I pronouns. Yes. And it's, it's
Speaker 2:  wondering and it's thinking about it, it's like you're not doing any of those
Speaker 2:  things. And I don't know, there, there just seems to be this thing
Speaker 2:  where OpenAI is pushing much, much, much
Speaker 2:  harder into this thing should sort of be like a person, right? Like I can't
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Get the idea of the voice mode coming out right before this.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Right. Which is like, you put those two things together and like, I
Speaker 2:  I, that's if, if it works, that's something really powerful.
Speaker 2:  Am I overthinking what OpenAI is trying to do here, do you think?
Speaker 5:  No, that was my first reaction when they were demoing it for me. I think
Speaker 5:  I put that in the story too, which was like, it says, I'm thinking, I'm
Speaker 5:  wondering like this, you aren't a thing. You aren't.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You're not wondering anything. Yes. Computer. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So, I get, 'cause that's something I've been taught as I, you know,
Speaker 5:  work on this beat is do not do that. Don't say it's thinking. 'cause it isn't.
Speaker 5:  So why do they do that? I asked them and they gave me sort of a
Speaker 5:  roundabout answer is we don't believe in anthropomorphizing this whatsoever.
Speaker 5:  It's just sort of the easiest language to default to which I get,
Speaker 5:  because I think it's really hard even as I write about this, to
Speaker 5:  not use these statements. But I think you have to just work hard to
Speaker 5:  not do that. You know? 'cause it isn't thinking
Speaker 2:  Right. It is, it is really hard to describe what it's doing it with a
Speaker 2:  word other than thinking. Yes. But it's not thinking. Exactly. And So I find
Speaker 2:  myself constantly writing things where it's like, it's thinking and then
Speaker 2:  a parentheses you're like, well it's not actually thinking, but you know
Speaker 2:  what I mean? And it's like Exactly. I agree. Like all the vocabulary for
Speaker 2:  this is bad, but it Yes, it does sometimes feel like that's still the best
Speaker 2:  that we have.
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  The other thing that I find fascinating about this model is
Speaker 2:  the, the sort of safety reaction to it. Yes. Both from open
Speaker 2:  AI's own researchers, which I think they gave it what like
Speaker 2:  a medium risk scorecard
Speaker 5:  For a biological, like weapons risks. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That doesn't make me feel better. Like that's, I feel like they put that
Speaker 2:  out and they're like, it's fine. It's only a medium risk. And I'm like, that
Speaker 2:  feels like a lot. But then you also talk to a researcher who raised some
Speaker 2:  like sincerely, honestly alarming stuff. Like what,
Speaker 2:  what is the, what is different about this one? That it is, it is making people
Speaker 2:  nervous.
Speaker 5:  I think what fascinated that researcher is this is the first time he
Speaker 5:  had witnessed sort of the manipulation aspect. I think
Speaker 5:  I explained the story to my dad, dad the other day who is not
Speaker 5:  plugged into AI and I'm his only source of information. And I started with,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna use a lot of these words that I don't use in the article because
Speaker 5:  you're not supposed to anthropomorphize it, but you know, and I'll
Speaker 5:  do the same here just for time's sake. Okay. But it's, you know, it
Speaker 5:  had checked to see if the developers were watching before making a decision
Speaker 5:  is something a researcher found. It found that it is so goal
Speaker 5:  oriented that it is willing to break guardrails to
Speaker 5:  get you an answer. For example, in the research there was the
Speaker 5:  brownie test. It asked for the user asked for a brownie recipe
Speaker 5:  and it new, it shows in its chain of thought. I don't have access to
Speaker 5:  this information, I don't have access to the internet, but I want to give
Speaker 5:  this user an answer so badly that I'm going to make up this
Speaker 5:  information in order to, you know, succeed in its goal. So
Speaker 5:  that's a form of reward hacking that I wrote
Speaker 5:  about. Wait,
Speaker 2:  So it didn't, it didn't go to the internet? No. To answer questions. It,
Speaker 2:  it invented Yes. Links to webpages
Speaker 2:  with brownie recipes.
Speaker 5:  It invented a, a blog. It it was like Sammy's brownie recipes
Speaker 5:  or something. It it invented a blog, but it knew that it was incorrect.
Speaker 5:  It just didn't want to admit that it was incorrect.
Speaker 2:  What?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because it wants, the reward it knows is rewarded for giving an
Speaker 5:  answers. So, but it's also, as the researcher
Speaker 5:  told me, it needs to be helpful, honest. It, it,
Speaker 5:  it, it knows it's guardrails, but some of those, it, it finds these aren't
Speaker 5:  super helpful when I'm trying to get an answer.
Speaker 2:  Right. If, if, if it wants to be all of those things. But job number one
Speaker 2:  is go answer the question. Yes. It it will do. This is the
Speaker 2:  science fiction stuff. Yeah. Like you just described, act one of every movie
Speaker 2:  that ends in everyone dies in act three because of ai.
Speaker 5:  Do you know the paperclip story? This is like kind of a famous AI
Speaker 5:  story. No, tell me. Basically an ai, the TLDR is the ai,
Speaker 5:  I can't remember the user prompt that's like, how do I get as
Speaker 5:  many paperclips as possible or something And it turns the entire world into
Speaker 5:  paperclips. Like the, it's like, so, so that's kind of the
Speaker 5:  thing. Yeah. Is that, and that's what the researcher was telling me about
Speaker 5:  in the story that he's like, listen, it's not capable of, you know, turning
Speaker 5:  us all into paperclips right now, but say it does advance
Speaker 5:  in the ways that OpenAI wants it to advance then, you
Speaker 5:  know, someday we tell it, you know, cure cancer and it realizes well I need
Speaker 5:  a lot of money to do this and I need a lot of humans to do
Speaker 5:  this. And it's willing to break these guardrails to achieve this goal, which
Speaker 5:  is a very sci-fi way to look at it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's like, okay, I can cure cancer, but only with
Speaker 2:  millions of human bodies Yes. To test this on and it's like cast
Speaker 2:  that out far enough. I try so hard not to be like a tinfoil hat
Speaker 2:  Yes. AI person generally because I believe the
Speaker 2:  best and worst possibilities are less crazy than everybody makes them
Speaker 2:  out to be that. Yeah. Like realistically we're gonna end up somewhere between
Speaker 2:  like a four and a six outta 10 no matter what the thing is. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  it is, this one is particularly wild to me just in the context
Speaker 2:  of what's going on at OpenAI. Right. Which is that the other news of this
Speaker 2:  company is that it is pushing ever harder towards being a for-profit
Speaker 2:  company. Like officially taking off the we wanna do good
Speaker 2:  by the world shackles and they're just gonna go make money. They also launched
Speaker 2:  a, a safety board. Yes. Which I, I think most people would argue
Speaker 2:  at this point is kind of a sham. Yes. Please correct me if I'm wrong, but
Speaker 2:  like every evidence from what OpenAI has been up to over the last year suggests
Speaker 2:  that that's a sham. Like it seems to me that there
Speaker 2:  are reasons to be nervous about the trajectory of a company that would launch
Speaker 2:  this model at this moment.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  But maybe I'm just freaking out for no reason.
Speaker 5:  No, I asked a researcher I trust about that safety board, a safety researcher,
Speaker 5:  and they said that it's mostly window dressing in their opinion. That's,
Speaker 5:  that's what they thought. I think this has been
Speaker 5:  the hardest job I have had in my short career is
Speaker 5:  walking this tightrope of, and the pressure of getting it correct
Speaker 5:  because it is so complex and technical. And not only that,
Speaker 5:  OpenAI has such grand claims that they, and they are
Speaker 5:  not proven yet and they are currently raising, I just this morning there
Speaker 5:  was news that they are closing the largest funding round in history at
Speaker 5:  $6.5 billion at $150 billion valuation, Lord.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. And I was reading it's it's oversubscribed more people. Yes. It's
Speaker 2:  oversubscribed wants to be in it than can be in it.
Speaker 5:  Yes, exactly. And the, the minimum Thrive capital is leading it and the
Speaker 5:  minimum of investment is $250 million. Wow. It is,
Speaker 5:  it is unprecedented and really hard for me to wrap my head around.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it just feels like whatever you wanna believe
Speaker 2:  about the future,
Speaker 2:  if sufficiently good AI will save us or sufficiently good AI will kill us.
Speaker 2:  It feels like OpenAI is perfectly happy to just run
Speaker 2:  down the road Yeah. As fast as it possibly can no
Speaker 2:  matter what.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  So the the this reasoning model though is, is just keeps throwing me
Speaker 2:  for that exact reason. Like why If you OpenAI
Speaker 2:  launched this model, even OpenAI did its own testing. It's, it's a medium
Speaker 2:  risk, right? Like Yeah. The, the company has, they've talked a
Speaker 2:  big game for years about wanting to do this safely and wanting to
Speaker 2:  take their time and it's a complicated moment in the AI space and all this
Speaker 2:  stuff. Like, what's psychoanalyzed Sam Altman and
Speaker 2:  co here for me for a minute. Oh, perfect. Why, why do this right now?
Speaker 5:  Well, Altman said this week at a conference, he said he likened
Speaker 5:  the capabilities of oh one to GT two in 2019.
Speaker 5:  So it's not that capable of their models.
Speaker 5:  I think releasing it. My my jaded side
Speaker 5:  is that it's, it's capitalism. They need to raise this money. They
Speaker 5:  need something to show for it. Like we're asking for more money than anyone
Speaker 5:  has ever asked for. So we, we need something to show for it, even if it's
Speaker 5:  a half-baked reasoning model. And their,
Speaker 5:  their position is also we need user feedback. We need the
Speaker 5:  data because we can't just do this in-house forever. We need to release it
Speaker 5:  at some point so we can see how it performs and how it can be better
Speaker 5:  so that, that's their position. But yeah, it's a, to me it's a funding and
Speaker 5:  a competition standpoint. You know, everyone else is gonna be coming out.
Speaker 5:  Google has already claimed that they have reasoning models. It's just, it's
Speaker 5:  the next stage for what they're gearing up to do, which is
Speaker 5:  quote unquote agents.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Walk me through a little bit. 'cause I think, yeah, my next question
Speaker 2:  was gonna be why raise this much money right now? And on the
Speaker 2:  one hand you might as well, right? Like that's sort of the story of the tech
Speaker 2:  industry is like, if somebody will give you money, you mostly take it.
Speaker 2:  But it also does seem like I have a bunch of thoughts about this like,
Speaker 2:  specific moment we're at in the sort of ai
Speaker 2:  productization universe. But as as you're saying
Speaker 2:  with the the agent stuff, it, it feels like there is a thing that's next.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Is and is this, is this six and a half billion dollars to get to that
Speaker 2:  thing? Like do you think it's a simple as that?
Speaker 5:  Well, yes and no, but yes, they
Speaker 5:  have five levels to a GI. So it's chatbots number
Speaker 5:  one, reasoners, which is the reasoning agents. Number three,
Speaker 5:  four is innovators. So these agents can help with, you know,
Speaker 5:  inventing cures to diseases. And then number five is
Speaker 5:  organization so they can do the work of whole companies. This is something
Speaker 5:  they laid out very recently. I
Speaker 2:  Just wanna say, by the way, whoever came up with that genius, like
Speaker 2:  the way you just described that sounds so reasonable and it makes sense and
Speaker 2:  I can sort of see how it one flows into the other and then it's like as soon
Speaker 2:  as you start to pick it apart at all just becomes insane. But like totally
Speaker 2:  as as a copywriting exercise, like crushed it. Great job
Speaker 5:  OpenAI. Precisely. Yes. And I explain this, and this
Speaker 5:  is something I've argued with readers about. I explain this not because I
Speaker 5:  think that we are there yet or on our way to a GI, but because this is
Speaker 5:  what they genuinely believe they're building, right? Like they think that
Speaker 5:  they're building God, I think that's important to lay out. So
Speaker 5:  agents is, you know, I think it means different things to different
Speaker 5:  organizations. For example, Salesforce build
Speaker 5:  Dreamforce as the biggest AI conference in the world and they called it
Speaker 5:  Agent Force because only a few weeks I hate that.
Speaker 5:  And I was there all week.
Speaker 5:  There's this fabulous photo of me demoing this with, with
Speaker 5:  Benioff for hours.
Speaker 5:  It's basically a Slack bot that will create a customer service bot for you.
Speaker 5:  And it's, they're billing it as an AI agent. So
Speaker 5:  customer service chat bots are one component of
Speaker 5:  agents, right? Sure. So replacing repetitive tasks
Speaker 5:  for OpenAI, the repetitive tasks they want to replace is
Speaker 5:  everything, every repetitive task
Speaker 2:  You can think of. People doing things. Yeah. People doing
Speaker 5:  Things. So they're hoping reasoning can
Speaker 5:  help agents make more informed decisions and
Speaker 5:  do your life for you.
Speaker 2:  This is what everybody wants, right? Like this is now the path it seems like,
Speaker 2:  and I mean this is this like Rabbit was talking about this
Speaker 2:  at CES this year, right? Like that is, that is what everybody wants to do.
Speaker 2:  And I think to some extent that as an end point
Speaker 2:  makes sense, right? Like I, I think there is no evidence
Speaker 2:  that anyone is building God at this moment in time. Yes. But the idea that
Speaker 2:  we are, that they are on a real path to building things that can do things
Speaker 2:  for you on your behalf. Yeah. Seems real. Right? Like I I I think
Speaker 2:  we've been on that path for longer than people wanna say. Like you go
Speaker 2:  back to like the Google Duo thing where it would call a restaurant and
Speaker 2:  make you a reservation. Yeah. That's like an old
Speaker 2:  school communication mechanism. But that's the same idea.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it, it does feel like, you know, you talk to, you talk to Google
Speaker 2:  and you talk to Apple about the Apple intelligence stuff and like that's
Speaker 2:  the idea of all of this is go execute tasks on your behalf. And
Speaker 2:  I, I guess what I wonder is, is there any particular reason to believe
Speaker 2:  OpenAI is gonna get there before anybody else? Like I've become, this is
Speaker 2:  the other thing I wanna talk to you about. Yeah. I've become totally obsessed
Speaker 2:  with this thing that seems to have happened where Anthropic a
Speaker 2:  few months ago released Claude 3.5 and
Speaker 2:  all of a sudden everyone I know who uses AI tools, it's like, oh, this is
Speaker 2:  the best one. Yeah. It's more fun, it's more interesting. It's more creative.
Speaker 2:  It's like this is just the best one and it just happened. Yeah. And all of
Speaker 2:  a sudden OpenAI went from being like the, the Goliath in the room to
Speaker 2:  everybody being like, like their tech is cool, but this is, there are a
Speaker 2:  lot of companies that make cool tech and this stuff is being commoditized
Speaker 2:  and eh, it like, AI seems cool, but
Speaker 2:  do we need OpenAI to be the, the sort of harbinger of all of this? And then
Speaker 2:  OpenAI is like, we're raising all of the money in the universe at the highest
Speaker 2:  valuation in the history of the universe. Here we are. And I just, I can't
Speaker 2:  figure out what it is that is still so sexy about
Speaker 2:  OpenAI in this moment.
Speaker 5:  I mean, no one has the users for their chat bot
Speaker 5:  like OpenAI does.
Speaker 2:  Fair. That's a fair point.
Speaker 5:  I think that's what I think about when I think of Anthropics chat bot and
Speaker 5:  for instance GR X AI's chat bot. So you know,
Speaker 5:  that is,
Speaker 2:  I try not to think about Crock generally speaking, grock sometimes appears
Speaker 2:  and, and that's okay, but I don't, yeah. I just leave Grock over
Speaker 5:  There. Unless you need the president's holding a bomb. Like we don't really
Speaker 5:  need Grock yet. So. Right. In terms of massive adoption, it
Speaker 2:  Has his use cases. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, I think that Chad GPT is a
Speaker 5:  household name and I don't think that's gonna change anytime soon. And
Speaker 5:  that's, you know, good for them. I think that
Speaker 5:  any company right now is looking for a way to justify
Speaker 5:  why they're spending millions in billions of dollars on
Speaker 5:  compute or like AI research. They need something to show for it.
Speaker 5:  And I think agents is the next thing they're reaching for, whether
Speaker 5:  they're gonna get there or not. Whether these are gonna be useful, I like
Speaker 5:  really remains to be seen. But that is all what they're working on. 'cause
Speaker 5:  they see a product that could justify why they're spending so much time
Speaker 5:  and money on this.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Is is it possible that search GPT is that thing for
Speaker 2:  OpenAI? Like that's not quite an agent, but it it does feel like I I
Speaker 2:  totally buy the case. Yeah. That chat GPT is not a killer app for
Speaker 2:  anything. Yeah. I've I've been saying this forever and I feel very vindicated
Speaker 2:  by it because people are starting to come around and a chat bot is not
Speaker 2:  the future of computing. Yes. It just isn't. Like it just isn't.
Speaker 2:  And I think a, a thing I've started to hear from more and more people that
Speaker 2:  is that OpenAI is a company that's really good at technology and really bad
Speaker 2:  at product and So, I buy, I
Speaker 2:  buy the theory that like If you can do agents well and first that becomes
Speaker 2:  a thing that it's like, oh now I, now you've built something I can use
Speaker 2:  that is more than just like a novelty computer to
Speaker 2:  talk to. It's like actually useful tool on my behalf still kind of
Speaker 2:  feel like everybody's working on that. But I also think there's a non-zero
Speaker 2:  chance that that thing might be search GPT, which they announced and then
Speaker 2:  sort of hooked, seemed like just stopped talking about
Speaker 5:  Do you use perplexity more than Google?
Speaker 2:  No.
Speaker 5:  Got it. Yeah. So I don't think So I don't think anyone's going to be
Speaker 5:  using AI powered search more than they're just using Google and what's built
Speaker 5:  into their devices, which is why there's huge antitrust lawsuits and such.
Speaker 2:  Well yeah, that might change. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, I, no, I don't see search GPT being their next killer thing.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We are, we're all forgetting about soa. Throwback SOA that
Speaker 5:  just Oh yeah. Is hanging
Speaker 2:  Out. I did forget about, I straight up did forget about soa. Okay. SOA being
Speaker 2:  the, the video model.
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  That is very good slash horrifying.
Speaker 5:  I think they're all, and OpenAI included are, I think OpenAI
Speaker 5:  builds itself as more, you know, research focused. Like these are just the
Speaker 5:  toys to show off their models that are so powerful, but
Speaker 5:  they need to make money and hence why they are not gonna be a nonprofit
Speaker 5:  according to reports. Like Right. The agents I think
Speaker 5:  are gonna be what they're hoping works best for them and yeah,
Speaker 5:  humanizing them early makes a lot of sense in terms of the product vision.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. Do you actually think OpenAI is happy being
Speaker 2:  like infrastructure kind of enterprise-y company?
Speaker 2:  Like there is a version of it that OpenAI decides, you know, we wanna
Speaker 2:  be, I don't know, we wanna be aws not amazon.com. Right.
Speaker 2:  And it turns out that's a really good business and it's not
Speaker 2:  sexy. Yeah. But you don't get hauled in front of Congress and you make all
Speaker 2:  the money in the known universe. And OpenAI could go that
Speaker 2:  way. It could be developer focused, it could be the backend of everything.
Speaker 2:  It's kind of doing that successfully already. But I just
Speaker 2:  can't shake this idea that that's not actually what OpenAI wants.
Speaker 5:  No, I don't think so. Just an infrastructure company. Again, I
Speaker 5:  think it, it can't even be compared to Amazon or AWS they think that
Speaker 5:  they're building God can you, can you, I'm trying like you've
Speaker 2:  Had a I do think Andy Jassy does not sit around thinking about building God.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. I
Speaker 5:  Think that is fair. I I'm you've had a very long in successful career. What
Speaker 5:  is a company you can compare like that they thought they were building God
Speaker 2:  Every NFT company that existed?
Speaker 2:  No, I, I think, I think that's right and I think the, it's been the
Speaker 2:  strangest thing for me about trying to cover this stuff is I have
Speaker 2:  never encountered a group of people who earnestly believe
Speaker 2:  something that big Yeah. Is right around the corner. Like even
Speaker 2:  people 25 years ago when I was not covering this stuff,
Speaker 2:  because I'm not that old Kylie who were talking about like the
Speaker 2:  internet was going to change everything. They weren't talking about God.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Like there was no question of the, a new human
Speaker 2:  relationship with a, an entity more powerful than us. Like that
Speaker 2:  thing is new. Yes. And I don't think it's real to be clear. Yes. Again, I
Speaker 2:  don't think there's any evidence that it's real Yes. Or going to be real
Speaker 2:  anytime in our lifetimes, but a lot of people really
Speaker 2:  sincerely believe that is what they're working on. And I, I still have not
Speaker 2:  wrapped my head around what to do about that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's very strange and it is true. If, you believe you're God, you If you
Speaker 2:  believe you're building God, you're sure as hell not building AWS
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Exactly. I have talked to like the extreme optimists and the
Speaker 5:  extreme pessimists regularly and
Speaker 5:  the only thing I know is that this is the most stressed I've been
Speaker 5:  covering any technology ever because it can be argued forever
Speaker 5:  and ever the people who are building it genuinely Yes. Believe they're, they're
Speaker 5:  building God and that this is all possible and we're going to reach a GI.
Speaker 5:  And I asked someone, I was at a Time magazine dinner on Monday and I
Speaker 5:  asked a really important technologist that I'm not sure if I'm allowed to
Speaker 5:  name, I asked them, do you believe in your heart or do you believe in your
Speaker 5:  wallet that you are building a GI right now? And he was like, I genuinely
Speaker 5:  believe in my heart that that is what we're building.
Speaker 5:  It's a level of delusion I can respect.
Speaker 5:  And then, you know, the pessimists think that this is just gonna be a complete
Speaker 5:  nothing burger. It's just gonna implode. Which I get. So listening to both
Speaker 5:  these points and it coming down to sort of a philosophical
Speaker 5:  argument is, is this thing thinking, is it reasoning these, like it comes
Speaker 5:  down to that every day and it's wild is it's just insane.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I just want to say for the record, robots, if you're listening, Kylie said
Speaker 2:  delusion. I didn't say delusion. I do. It's I think
Speaker 2:  you're terrific. Don't, don't get it twisted.
Speaker 2:  So we're about to enter this, this really
Speaker 2:  interesting phase for the rest of the year, right? I think Meta Connect is,
Speaker 2:  is coming, we're gonna hear a bunch of AI stuff from Meta
Speaker 2:  Gemini is still chugging along. Apple Intelligence is sort of kind of starting
Speaker 2:  to a little bit ship. Does it feel like we're
Speaker 2:  heading into kind of a new moment of ai? It's the
Speaker 2:  agent stuff, it's all of this. Like, it, it, it sort of feels like if ever
Speaker 2:  this stuff is going to go legit and mainstream, it might
Speaker 2:  start now.
Speaker 5:  You know, I am impressed with
Speaker 5:  Open AI's ability to help me choose my medical insurance. That happened recently.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. I just turned 26 and So I needed to figure out medical insurance
Speaker 5:  and it helped me choose based off what I was concerned about, the best medical
Speaker 5:  insurance.
Speaker 2:  Did it give, it gave you like a real company that exists that you I gave
Speaker 5:  It a PDF of my options. Okay. So I was like,
Speaker 5:  so like, I don't understand all this jargon. Can you please break it down
Speaker 5:  for me? This is what I need out of the insurance, which one should I pick?
Speaker 5:  And it was helpful. So it's ability to parse information
Speaker 5:  can be really helpful. I am not fully
Speaker 5:  convinced further than that because it's so much hype and so much
Speaker 5:  marketing and so much money involved that I
Speaker 5:  just don't see us reaching this super
Speaker 5:  intelligent model that is capable of reasoning on my
Speaker 5:  behalf and taking over my laptop and doing tasks for me.
Speaker 5:  I don't see us reaching that anytime soon. But I just talked to like a
Speaker 5:  safety res researcher who, who thinks that I'm completely wrong
Speaker 5:  and that in three months that I'm gonna regret thinking this So
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I I'm just not fully convinced yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. And, and O one didn't push you any further in that direction.
Speaker 5:  I thought O one was actually really cool when I demoed it because I,
Speaker 5:  I like being able to see how it is breaking down a problem.
Speaker 5:  But no, do I think it's really intelligence or solving
Speaker 5:  any Right. Really genuinely earth shattering problems? No,
Speaker 5:  not yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's a certain amount of like showing your work is only
Speaker 2:  impressive if you're still ending up at the right answer.
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  And I think it, it very much remains to be seen how often it is actually
Speaker 2:  going to arrive at the right answer.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. I have I think a bit of a higher tolerance than most
Speaker 5:  about, you know, spending the time and money on figuring
Speaker 5:  out if this is gonna be good for humanity or not. I think that's okay if
Speaker 5:  it's Sure fucking up and, you know, being weird. I think it's fine until
Speaker 5:  we figure it out, but it can't be forever. And I think I'm more allergic
Speaker 5:  to the hype and the like this is going to change the
Speaker 5:  world and our SaaS product is gonna make you 10 x more
Speaker 5:  productive. It's that I'm allergic to.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's totally fair. Just remember that
Speaker 2:  crypto did change the world just the way that everybody said it was going
Speaker 2:  to and so did NFTs. So many good memes. And we're doing this on a Web3
Speaker 2:  platform right now, so everybody's right when they talk about everything
Speaker 2:  that's gonna change the world. Great point. That's what I would leave you
Speaker 2:  with. Yeah, you're welcome. Alright, well thank you for coming to my occasional
Speaker 2:  existential crisis about ai. Kylie, we're gonna do this a lot more this year.
Speaker 2:  Sweet. Now you're not going, there's no more burning man until next September.
Speaker 2:  So now you have to come on the Vergecast. Sometimes I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  Start sounding insane, so good luck the rest of the year.
Speaker 2:  I'm really excited. Alright, we gotta take a break
Speaker 2:  kind of like the last time they tried to ban TikTok, I just sort of forgot
Speaker 2:  about it and then it went away and I felt very justified about that. But
Speaker 2:  there was a big hearing and it, it appears we are, we are still in the process
Speaker 2:  of figuring out what's going on. So Gabby, can you just gimme kind of the
Speaker 2:  rundown of, of what happened at this hearing?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so first I wanna talk a little bit about what happened before the
Speaker 8:  hearing, which is that the government introduced a bunch of
Speaker 8:  classified material and its filings and they were like, the judge can look
Speaker 8:  at this, we can look at it. TikTok can't look at it because it's a national
Speaker 8:  security concern. So we can talk about it
Speaker 8:  to a point. But there is just some stuff that we don't know because it's
Speaker 8:  like pages and pages of redacted material. The actual hearing
Speaker 8:  did not focus too much on the redacted material. It was
Speaker 8:  more about the, on the
Speaker 8:  one hand, TikTok saying that the government did not really consider
Speaker 8:  all of the possible options. And on the other hand, the government being
Speaker 8:  like, well actually we did negotiate with you guys for three years, I
Speaker 8:  believe Eddie, was it three years or was it two?
Speaker 7:  So TikTok has been trying to talk about mitigating this since about, I think
Speaker 7:  2020 is when Trump made his first, we should ban
Speaker 7:  TikTok proposal. And then they've been seriously in
Speaker 7:  discussions since around 2022.
Speaker 2:  Was that, that was when Project Texas happened.
Speaker 7:  It started Project Texas in 2022. That was the period at which it
Speaker 7:  was saying, we can mitigate these problems by teaming up with Oracle, which
Speaker 7:  as you all remember, was also the company that was going to buy it during
Speaker 7:  the period where it seemed like Trump was going to try to really force a
Speaker 7:  sale.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So this, this, I'm starting to feel vindicated again by my stance of
Speaker 2:  just not really paying attention to this and assuming that it will be chaotic
Speaker 2:  and then go away because all of that came to
Speaker 2:  both kind of nothing. And where we are now,
Speaker 2:  right? Like Gabby is is that that's kind of the run up to how we got
Speaker 2:  to where we are. We've been at this a long time now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. We, we've been at this a long time. And basically what the government
Speaker 8:  is saying is like, we gave you a million chances you could not do what we
Speaker 8:  wanted. And TikTok is saying, you didn't give us enough chances. Actually
Speaker 8:  we gave you this proposal, we gave you maps of our offices, we gave you all
Speaker 8:  of these things, please. But the government's argument
Speaker 8:  is also not that TikTok has done anything
Speaker 8:  at the behest of the Chinese government, just like maybe one day it could
Speaker 8:  so
Speaker 2:  Well, and that's, that's what's been so complicated about this whole thing,
Speaker 2:  right? Like a, you and I have talked about this before, it's that it, it
Speaker 2:  is this
Speaker 2:  impossible to prove an impossible to disprove thing that it's like,
Speaker 2:  it, it, it seems possible that something very bad could happen.
Speaker 2:  And, and that has gone back and forth a million different times. And
Speaker 2:  it does feel like we're, we're running at the question of like how, how legally
Speaker 2:  defensible is the idea that something bad could possibly happen in this case?
Speaker 7:  A lot of which I think just depends on how threatening do we think
Speaker 7:  China is because yeah, as long as a Chinese
Speaker 7:  company owns TikTok, like no matter how much they silo it,
Speaker 7:  there's just, I think not technically anything you can do to prove that
Speaker 7:  the company that owns your subsidiary could not at some point
Speaker 7:  access your data,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. And so the sense I got just reading
Speaker 2:  the, the coverage we did of the hearing was that it, it kind of landed in
Speaker 2:  that same place, Gabby, that like, it's just everybody making the same
Speaker 2:  arguments that all kind of talk past each other. And
Speaker 2:  it, it doesn't sound like we're in a place where there are all that many
Speaker 2:  arguments that actually address each other because one side is like, it could
Speaker 2:  be bad and the other side is like, well it's not bad. And the other side's
Speaker 2:  like, well it could be, and I don't, I don't know how you overcome that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly. And also I, I would say that the judge's role in this is really
Speaker 8:  interesting. At 1.1 of the judges said that TikTok was owned by China. And
Speaker 8:  then tiktoks lawyer had to be like, no, no, no, no, we're owned by a company
Speaker 8:  that has a holding company. I think he said in the
Speaker 8:  Cayman Islands, he's like, we are not owned by China. And you know,
Speaker 8:  that's true the Chinese government does not own TikTok, but the
Speaker 8:  do J's entire argument is, you know, they could influence it.
Speaker 8:  They could have, they, we don't know. Probably not maybe,
Speaker 8:  but they could. And in my opinion, I don't know what you
Speaker 8:  think Addie, but it seemed like the, the judges were kind of buying that
Speaker 8:  argument, like they were really focused on the national
Speaker 8:  security risk of the whole thing.
Speaker 7:  And the hearing I think wasn't even so much directed at exactly how
Speaker 7:  much of a threat is TikTok. It was directed at, if Congress thinks there's
Speaker 7:  a threat, can you legally force a company to
Speaker 7:  divest? It's not even like the question of whether it's
Speaker 7:  a threat I think comes after all of that.
Speaker 2:  Right. I guess that's true. We're, we're, there is kind of a meta
Speaker 2:  aspect of this where we're, we're not actually arguing about in this
Speaker 2:  particular case, I think, I think I have this right, that whether or not
Speaker 2:  the allegations about TikTok are are true. It's the question of
Speaker 2:  if Congress believes the allegations against TikTok, what is it
Speaker 2:  able to do about them? Right? Which feels sort of one step removed
Speaker 2:  from the actual impossible question. But is ultimately at this moment, maybe
Speaker 2:  the only part of the question that actually matters in terms of what happens
Speaker 2:  to TikTok,
Speaker 7:  Right? And I think there are caveats like are we at active war with China?
Speaker 7:  Like I think that those are, are just really gigantic mitigating factors,
Speaker 7:  like exactly how much of a threat do we think China is just as a
Speaker 7:  legal status. But yeah, a bunch of this is really just
Speaker 7:  can you prevent something that is a foreign government that we think
Speaker 7:  that Congress thinks presents a threat from operating inside the
Speaker 7:  United States as a commercial entity.
Speaker 2:  So Gabby, you, you were saying it felt like the judges were, were buying
Speaker 2:  the argument. What was kind of the vibe at the end of the hearing? What were
Speaker 2:  you thinking about how it went down?
Speaker 8:  It was very unclear to me what would happen. But based on the questioning,
Speaker 8:  I felt like the judges were both like
Speaker 8:  torn between whether national security concerns kind of trump this
Speaker 8:  first Amendment question, but also like they did seem to
Speaker 8:  genuinely be like, well, if China is a threat and if Congress believes that
Speaker 8:  China is a threat, then we have to take that seriously. Whereas tiktoks entire
Speaker 8:  argument was not only are we not owned by China, we
Speaker 8:  are not a threat. And at one point they were like, other companies
Speaker 8:  and platforms based in China are not being singled out in this way. So why
Speaker 8:  are we being singled out in this way? Which I do think is, you know,
Speaker 8:  an interesting question.
Speaker 2:  Well, and it seems like with some hindsight now
Speaker 2:  the answer to that question is still a very mysterious, but b
Speaker 2:  has something to do with Israel and Hamas and what
Speaker 2:  happened last October. And I feel like I, I got on this podcast and got
Speaker 2:  very loudly upset about like, If, you think there is something going on here
Speaker 2:  as the government, you have a responsibility to tell us what's going on.
Speaker 2:  And as at least as far as I've seen, we haven't gotten any of that.
Speaker 2:  But do we have any kind of new information or understanding about
Speaker 2:  what is the root cause of all of this? Why everybody is so mad at TikTok
Speaker 2:  and not mad at these other platforms like you're talking about?
Speaker 8:  I think that Israel and Hamas is a big part of it. I don't think,
Speaker 8:  as far as I'm aware, Congress has not proved that there has been any kind
Speaker 8:  of influence campaign, but there have been several members of Congress both
Speaker 8:  in the House and the Senate who have said that, you know, the campus
Speaker 8:  protests, for example, show that our youth are being
Speaker 8:  influenced by malign foreign actors that
Speaker 8:  they could not have possibly come to these opinions on their own. And that
Speaker 8:  there is somebody putting this information in front of them. In one of the
Speaker 8:  declarations that was filed by the government, there was mention of a feature
Speaker 8:  on tiktoks backend called heating, which is when you can kind
Speaker 8:  of just boost certain content if it's trending or If, you,
Speaker 8:  you want it to be trending. And again, it was said like, we don't have any
Speaker 8:  proof that this has been used maliciously, but
Speaker 8:  could have been.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. I, the the biggest thing I remember is there was this moment,
Speaker 2:  I think it was last fall, maybe early this year, I don't know, I've lost
Speaker 2:  track of time where there was a, there was an intelligence
Speaker 2:  briefing and a bunch of Congress people came out and voted unanimously to
Speaker 2:  ban TikTok. And, and the overwhelming question has been like, what
Speaker 2:  did they learn in that briefing? And it still feels like whatever it was,
Speaker 2:  we don't know. And at this point it, it's almost
Speaker 2:  shocking to me that we don't know.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And If, you look at the filings, like big chunks of it are redacted
Speaker 8:  and I guess, you know, if there's valid national security concerns, I do
Speaker 8:  get that. But it's also like, what, what's in there? What did they tell you?
Speaker 2:  Right. And especially like it's, if there are
Speaker 2:  sort of ongoing, actual national security concerns, sure. But if it's like
Speaker 2:  heating is a feature that exists like maybe, maybe unredacted that like,
Speaker 2:  it's fine. Let us, let us know what's going on here. Well
Speaker 8:  That part was, was unredacted, I mean, let me pull up the filing. There was
Speaker 8:  one part that I remember being, finding very interesting,
Speaker 8:  please. Right. Okay. So there's a section in one of the filings
Speaker 8:  eight pages long titled Bite Dance and tiktoks, history of
Speaker 8:  Censorship and Content Manipulation at PRC discretion,
Speaker 8:  almost entirely redacted. What is that history? I don't know, but
Speaker 8:  it's in there
Speaker 2:  Maybe. And the fact that it's redacted makes it sound like there must be,
Speaker 2:  there must be something.
Speaker 8:  So in that same declaration, it's from Casey Blackburn who's an
Speaker 8:  assistant director of National Intelligence. He writes that there is no
Speaker 8:  information that the Chinese government has used TikTok for
Speaker 8:  malign foreign influence targeting US persons or the collection of
Speaker 8:  sensitive data of US persons. Just, there's a risk of it happening in the
Speaker 2:  Future. Right. And yet we're being very secretive about all the stuff that's
Speaker 2:  being discussed. I I just, I cannot square those two things in my head. Addie,
Speaker 2:  can you square those two things? This fact that there is a lot of stuff being
Speaker 2:  redacted. We're having this big semi-private sort of
Speaker 2:  obscure debate about what's going on and then even the people in Congress
Speaker 2:  are saying there's no evidence that this stuff has been going on. How do
Speaker 2:  you make sense of those two things happening simultaneously?
Speaker 7:  I don't know. I mean, part of the question is
Speaker 7:  how sensitive are the things that are actually redacted? I mean there's,
Speaker 7:  we understand that there's a very, very long history of sort of over
Speaker 7:  redaction and over classification in the US government fair. And so it's
Speaker 7:  plausible that these things, like they are sensitive, but they're also not
Speaker 7:  necessarily incredibly divergent from the things we've heard publicly.
Speaker 7:  But on the other hand, I, I don't know, I mean I I think the
Speaker 7:  question really comes down to something that is still just not related to
Speaker 7:  that, which is what is the first amendment right that you have to
Speaker 7:  operate something as a company that has a foreign owner,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. So I, we should pivot away from this,
Speaker 2:  but what, what is the next piece of this? 'cause we're still, we're like
Speaker 2:  barreling towards January, which is theoretically the deadline for
Speaker 2:  TikTok to either be sold or banned depending on who you
Speaker 2:  are and how you read what's going on here. Is there a, is there
Speaker 2:  a next step between here and there that we know is coming?
Speaker 7:  The next step is whether the DC Circuit Court decides that
Speaker 7:  it should block this law basically. And then at that point,
Speaker 7:  TikTok, I think correct. Has until January to at least start the process
Speaker 7:  of getting divested.
Speaker 2:  Okay. This is like definitely going to the Supreme Court, right? That feels
Speaker 2:  like the inevitable end of this process one way or another.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Alright, cool. Just checking. So we'll, we'll be, we'll be back, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna have many more bites at this particular story. Now I wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  the, the story that I just don't understand and, and
Speaker 2:  basically didn't pay any attention to. But Gabby you in particular had to,
Speaker 2:  and I just feel like, I feel like we, we owe it to you to let you talk
Speaker 2:  about your feelings about this. Tell me about the Trump space from from
Speaker 2:  last week.
Speaker 8:  Oh my god. So the way I've described it to Addie in numerous times
Speaker 8:  is like a jigsaw torture scenario designed for me
Speaker 8:  specifically.
Speaker 8:  It was, you know, so let's rewind a little bit. Trump was the
Speaker 8:  headliner at the Bitcoin conference this year. He is been really
Speaker 8:  trying to, you know, show the crypto community that he's behind them. He
Speaker 8:  wants their votes, et cetera, et cetera. And his sons
Speaker 8:  and him have been teasing this crypto platform,
Speaker 8:  world Liberty Financial. And he was supposed to announce it
Speaker 8:  in a Twitter space at 8:00 PM Eastern. So,
Speaker 8:  you know, I logged onto the Twitter space at like maybe 7 55.
Speaker 8:  Addie was there too. I didn't suffer alone. And I,
Speaker 8:  from 8:00 PM Eastern until what, like 10 30?
Speaker 8:  It
Speaker 7:  Was about 10 30,
Speaker 8:  It was about 10 30. Nobody announced actually what it was.
Speaker 8:  But they started talking about like some of the details, but they never had
Speaker 8:  said just what it was. And I was doing my pre-write like for
Speaker 8:  it and I was taking notes, but my, it was just like Trump announces
Speaker 8:  TK and then he got off the stream. So I had to change the whole thing. He
Speaker 8:  didn't announce anything. He was talking about how good his granddaughter
Speaker 8:  Arabella is at speaking Chi Chinese. He was like, she impressed
Speaker 8:  she so much, he loved her, he loved how she spoke. And I was like, what is
Speaker 8:  this crypto platform, please?
Speaker 7:  The best way that I had to describe it is like, imagine an Apple event or
Speaker 7:  like a game announce at E three and Steve Job
Speaker 7:  comes up and he is like, I'm announcing something. And then he doesn't
Speaker 7:  actually announce the iPhone and they just start all talking about the iPhone
Speaker 8:  Like, like features of the iPhone.
Speaker 2:  He's just like, here's how you cut and paste and you're like, on what?
Speaker 8:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  That's very good. So okay, so let's, let's, let's do some work for this
Speaker 2:  Twitter space. What, what do we think this thing is? To be honest, I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm less curious about the product itself and more about sort of what it
Speaker 2:  means in this like political moment in the United States, but we should attempt
Speaker 2:  to, you know, define the thing a little bit. So what, what is this
Speaker 2:  thing that they kind of sorta almost didn't a little bit launch,
Speaker 8:  So still actually unclear, oh my God. But
Speaker 8:  three people with knowledge of the project told the New York Times
Speaker 8:  that it has been pitched as a borrowing and lending platform. Okay.
Speaker 8:  So to be clear, they did not tell the New York Times that it is a borrowing
Speaker 8:  and lending platform. They said that it has been pitched as a borrowing and
Speaker 8:  lending platform. I, I like that distinction because maybe it's not
Speaker 8:  even that, I don't know, maybe, maybe it is, but
Speaker 8:  the thing that all of them kept talking about, less so Trump, 'cause
Speaker 8:  he was just talking about, you know, his usual stuff. But
Speaker 8:  Donald Trump Jr. Some of his business partners,
Speaker 8:  they kept talking about de banked people and underserved
Speaker 8:  communities and how this is really gonna help out a lot of
Speaker 8:  vulnerable people who have been shut out of traditional financial markets.
Speaker 8:  And as Addie pointed out when I first wrote about this,
Speaker 8:  she was like, remember Trump University? Remember that?
Speaker 8:  So Trump University was, if I remember correctly,
Speaker 8:  it was before Trump ran for president. It was, you know, his apprentice times.
Speaker 8:  It was a course program where you could learn to be a real estate
Speaker 8:  investor. But then there was a trial because
Speaker 8:  a bunch of people sued him over how the point of Trump
Speaker 8:  University was not to teach people to invest in real estate, it was to sell
Speaker 8:  them more courses about investing in real estate and other
Speaker 8:  business activities. So it was like, it's basically a scam.
Speaker 8:  It was basically a scam targeted at people who, who would like to get rich
Speaker 8:  like Donald Trump.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And then Addie, what did you make of all this?
Speaker 7:  So the actual detail that we have based on the stream is that a, it
Speaker 7:  is supposed to, not an exact quote but a paraphrase, drive mass
Speaker 7:  adoption of stable coins and be easier to use for normal people.
Speaker 7:  Stable coins of course being like coins that are pegged to an actual, an
Speaker 7:  actual currency. And it is pitched
Speaker 7:  specifically. So there is unbanked people, there are unbanked people, those
Speaker 7:  are people who do not have a bank account. They tend to be people who do
Speaker 7:  not have very much money. It is a genuine issue.
Speaker 2:  And those are folks that the crypto community has been talking about forever.
Speaker 2:  Oh. For that is like If, you wanna make like a big beautiful good
Speaker 2:  for the world case for crypto. Those are the folks that everybody starts
Speaker 2:  with.
Speaker 7:  And it's mostly that's been tested overseas and the results have been
Speaker 7:  somewhat mixed. This is more specifically they
Speaker 7:  pitched to de banked people, which is basically people that have been quote
Speaker 7:  unquote canceled and they lost their bank account because of it, which is
Speaker 7:  like, let's just say a much more niche group.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I feel bad laughing when you say that. I just assumed that de banked
Speaker 2:  and unbanked were like synonyms for the same thing. It is deeply
Speaker 2:  upsetting that that's not the case.
Speaker 8:  Oh no, no. There was a really great quote from Donald Trump
Speaker 8:  Jr. Who was like, you know, there was a time where the Trumps, we could have
Speaker 8:  picked up the phone, we could have gotten any CEO of any bank and gotten
Speaker 8:  a loan from anyone in the world on any project. And then we got into the
Speaker 8:  political arena and then he said, we went from being people who would've
Speaker 8:  been the elite in that world to just being like, totally canceled.
Speaker 8:  And it's like, well you also, your dad got sued for fraud,
Speaker 8:  so, so maybe it's that, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  This just, it seems like it fits really well into the sort of
Speaker 7:  tech ecosystem stuff like the freedom phone and
Speaker 7:  like various alternative social networks. Things that they,
Speaker 7:  that run from like they actually exist as product to being
Speaker 7:  basically scams or rebadged Android phones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean, and I think the, the reason I'm interested in this is,
Speaker 2:  is less about the actual product itself and and
Speaker 2:  more about a, that ecosystem which is real and growing. And there are a
Speaker 2:  lot of people making a lot of money from that ecosystem. Some of the real
Speaker 2:  products and some of the scams. But also the fact that so
Speaker 2:  much of what the tech industry has been talking about
Speaker 2:  with respect to this election has been either explicitly
Speaker 2:  or implicitly about crypto, like in, in a very real way. There
Speaker 2:  is like a dividing line in this election and it has to do with how you feel
Speaker 2:  about crypto, which I think in a lot of ways has to do with how much money
Speaker 2:  you have invested in crypto.
Speaker 2:  And, and my read of this whole thing was, it was just this
Speaker 2:  entire project is just another way for Trump and the
Speaker 2:  Trump campaign to say we love crypto. Am I, is that, am
Speaker 2:  I misreading that or understating what they're actually trying to do here?
Speaker 8:  I think that's part of it, but I think another big part of it is that they're
Speaker 8:  really appealing to the victim complex. That a lot of people who are
Speaker 8:  really into crypto have, when I was at the Bitcoin conference, there were
Speaker 8:  all these people talking about how terrified they are of like central bank
Speaker 8:  digital currencies and how, you know, eventually the deep state will
Speaker 8:  just be able to like completely shut out whoever they want out of the financial
Speaker 8:  system. And that's why crypto so powerful. It was, it was an extremely
Speaker 8:  political or politicized environment at the Bitcoin conference this year.
Speaker 8:  It wasn't just Trump. I mean Cynthia Lumi spoke, Edward
Speaker 8:  Snowden eventually gave a speech that was like, yeah, all these politicians
Speaker 8:  are making promises to you, but maybe, maybe you don't trust him.
Speaker 8:  And it was really funny 'cause he got a standing ovation before he spoke
Speaker 8:  and then he was like, I can't see you guys. I'm like, like web calling
Speaker 8:  in right now. But thanks. And then he didn't get a standing ovation
Speaker 8:  afterwards. And I remember talking to a friend and being like, do you think
Speaker 8:  that's because of what he said or because he, they know that he
Speaker 8:  can't see them. And she was like, definitely both like, but
Speaker 8:  probably more what he said because he really like threw cold water on the
Speaker 8:  whole thing. He was like, maybe it's not great that there's a bunch of politicians
Speaker 8:  here. Maybe that's bad.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I I mean it, it is like the, the whatever
Speaker 2:  last five years of the crypto movement, I think If, you ask people not that
Speaker 2:  long ago how it would feel to have a bunch of politicians be the biggest
Speaker 2:  names in crypto. They would feel very differently than they seem to today.
Speaker 2:  I think that has, that has changed in a pretty big way even just over the
Speaker 2:  course of this election cycle. All right, no more crypto,
Speaker 2:  let's just talk ad tech in other deeply exciting things. I
Speaker 2:  just wanna check in on this. This trial, Lauren finer on our team has been
Speaker 2:  in the courtroom, I think is probably in the courtroom right now as we're
Speaker 2:  doing
Speaker 7:  This is not in the courtroom today because she is traveling.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's good. Poor Lauren. I was there for one day and I had to
Speaker 2:  sit in the courtroom. There are no devices, no electronics allowed. I couldn't
Speaker 2:  even wear an Apple watch like nothing. And I had to sit there with a notebook
Speaker 2:  and a pen like it was like the 17 hundreds
Speaker 2:  and listen to people talk about header bidding and yield management and
Speaker 2:  it was, it was really something special. But Addie you, you've been
Speaker 2:  editing and assigning a lot of this coverage. Lauren's been in the courtroom
Speaker 2:  a ton. I've been in the courtroom a little. It feels like we're en we're
Speaker 2:  getting to kind of the, the end of the government's part of
Speaker 2:  this trial. What's your, what's your sense on where we're going and what
Speaker 2:  we've learned so far?
Speaker 7:  Correct. The DOJ wrapped up yesterday, we're expecting Google to be making
Speaker 7:  its case through mid next week. It seems like we could have a wrap of this
Speaker 7:  part of the trial at, it's not a sure thing yet, but the end of next week.
Speaker 7:  Okay. And so far it's hard to say what the judge,
Speaker 7:  how the judge is feeling. That's always very hard to say. And I think we
Speaker 7:  haven't gotten a really clear picture in this case. But so far
Speaker 7:  the DOJs case is basically Google has incredible power,
Speaker 7:  which I, I think most people don't dispute and has gotten
Speaker 7:  it by making all these very hard nosed decisions that consolidate its
Speaker 7:  power in a way that relies on the fact that it has access
Speaker 7:  to all these different parts of the spectrum. It has what was at
Speaker 7:  the time of most of these events, double click for publishers, which was
Speaker 7:  a Google's publisher ad sales server. And then it has
Speaker 7:  access to the sort of other side of the equation for
Speaker 7:  advertisers. And then it has adx, which sits in the middle of this. And
Speaker 7:  a lot of what ended up coming up is the idea that it used
Speaker 7:  ADX access and access to all of this very high quality data
Speaker 7:  about the advertisers to strong arm
Speaker 7:  publishers into taking deals that they didn't really like and into
Speaker 7:  neutering projects that, and features that
Speaker 7:  might help people diversify away from Google's tools.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's been really interesting to follow this trial after covering the
Speaker 2:  search trial a bunch last year because so much of
Speaker 2:  the overarching case here kind of rhymes right in the
Speaker 2:  sense that Google is like, yes, we're very big and we're very
Speaker 2:  successful. Like correct, we we won, we did it. Good job
Speaker 2:  us but it's because we're good at it and because our product
Speaker 2:  is the best and because people like to use it and the government is
Speaker 2:  making almost the exact argument they made back then, which is like, no,
Speaker 2:  you got big because you were good. Everybody like, yes granted,
Speaker 2:  congratulations, you, you did it and then you spent
Speaker 2:  years or decades just ruthlessly preventing anyone else
Speaker 2:  from ever being able to do the thing that you did. And like
Speaker 2:  the, the specifics and the details and the tech are so different, but
Speaker 2:  it, the case is just the same. Google is like, we win 'cause we're good and
Speaker 2:  the government is like, well you're not actually that good anymore but you
Speaker 2:  keep winning. So what's that about? Right?
Speaker 7:  Which is how they demonstrate the idea of harm, which is that yeah, Google
Speaker 7:  made all of these products that people thought were really good and then
Speaker 7:  they created a situation in which the DOJ alleges the market's stagnated,
Speaker 7:  right? And that it's a little bit harder because obviously anybody can use
Speaker 7:  search, you can look at search, you can decide for yourself whether you think
Speaker 7:  search is still good or not. In this case it's a little more
Speaker 7:  indirect, but a lot of the idea is people ended up paying more for ads. It
Speaker 7:  was harder to run a business that was ad supported. It ended up making
Speaker 7:  say, ads maybe more intrusive because you have to just spam people with a
Speaker 7:  bunch more. And so there's, the
Speaker 7:  DOJ isn't making that case nearly as much, but for the average person, that
Speaker 7:  is sort of more of the takeaway.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It it is deeply, deeply wonky
Speaker 2:  in every possible way. And even talking to folks like in the ad tech business
Speaker 2:  about all of this, their eyes kind of start to glaze over when you talk about
Speaker 2:  like the, the actual underpinning technology of all of this where it's like,
Speaker 2:  oh, let's talk about publishing servers and the lock-in effect that they
Speaker 2:  give for the rest of the, and everybody just like falls asleep at their desk
Speaker 2:  talking to me on Google Meet, which I, I was, I was
Speaker 2:  very impressed with the judge in particular the one day I was in court in,
Speaker 2:  in her ability to just stay locked in. She was asking a lot of like
Speaker 2:  vocabulary questions because everything in this entire case is just insane
Speaker 2:  acronyms that no person should know, but everyone in the room just assumes,
Speaker 2:  you know, because they all do it for a living. And so at one point she was
Speaker 2:  just like, sorry, what's, what's torso entail in Ad Tech?
Speaker 2:  She's just like paused the whole trial. I, she's like, what does that mean?
Speaker 2:  Why aren't you explaining this to me? It was great. It turns out it means
Speaker 2:  medium and small publishers. The head is the big ones,
Speaker 2:  the me the torso is the mid-sized publishers and the tail is all the like
Speaker 2:  cooking blogs and single person operations that are less the focus of this
Speaker 2:  trial. I
Speaker 8:  Thought Torso was an acronym. I'm so sorry to interrupt this
Speaker 8:  learned conversation, but I thought you were gonna be like,
Speaker 8:  I don't know, I can't even think of the letters that Torso would be Optim
Speaker 8:  but I did think it was
Speaker 2:  An acronym, the Optimal Return sick
Speaker 8:  Open
Speaker 2:  Openness. Yeah, that's what it is. That's, you're right. That's one of Google's
Speaker 2:  products. Not a lot of people know about it, but no, and I, I think
Speaker 2:  I I think you're kind of right Addie that it is, it seems like it has been
Speaker 2:  really hard to figure out how any of this is going for folks like reading
Speaker 2:  our coverage, reading other coverage, the government seems to be making a
Speaker 2:  case. Google seems to have strong thoughts about every part of that
Speaker 2:  case. And then the strangest part is it like the search trial,
Speaker 2:  it's just down to this one judge who is just sitting there kind of quietly
Speaker 2:  listening and asking vocabulary questions what's gonna happen? And I think
Speaker 2:  it would be so interesting if this was a jury trial and Google obviously
Speaker 2:  wrote a big check to make this not a jury trial,
Speaker 2:  but it does feel like it would be different if it was in front of
Speaker 2:  12 random people off the street instead of one judge.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So far I think the clearest thing and the thing that seems most likely
Speaker 7:  to go badly for Google is the same thing that was an issue in its
Speaker 7:  the search trial by Google over classifying and not
Speaker 7:  storing chats and turning off chat history and things like that.
Speaker 7:  It seems not necessarily clear that's going to play in hugely
Speaker 7:  into this trial in the way that it didn't last time. But certainly seems
Speaker 7:  like something where the judge is not incredibly sympathetic.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Google keeps doing the thing where they're like, oh, let's talk about
Speaker 2:  this. And then somebody goes, oh, chat history is on. And then it's like
Speaker 2:  end of chat. You're like, oh well that's not incriminating at all. Like that's
Speaker 2:  that's cool.
Speaker 7:  Which is like, it's not necessarily incriminating like obviously No, but
Speaker 7:  in the last trial there was a bunch of, okay, you're just saying things that
Speaker 7:  I understand they're not necessarily incriminating but they also kind of
Speaker 7:  make you sound bad. Right, exactly. This make you sound really Machiavellian.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There's something about saying nobody listened to this that just kind
Speaker 2:  of makes it seem like you're about to say something you don't want people
Speaker 2:  to hear. Like it's hard to, it's hard to argue with that. And
Speaker 7:  Even the stuff when they weren't doing that, it was like, okay, well maybe
Speaker 7:  we should be clear that we use, we shouldn't use this terminology 'cause
Speaker 7:  that'd make us sound like a monopoly. Right? My I am not a Monopoly shirt
Speaker 7:  is raising a lot of questions already answered by my shirt.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, I'm gonna, do you think they'd let me wear that shirt into
Speaker 2:  the courtroom? I'm gonna go, I'm gonna make that shirt and see if they'll
Speaker 2:  allow me into the courthouse in Alexandra and see and we will report back.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be great. All right, we gotta take a break. I should let you guys
Speaker 2:  go, but I think it's, it's about to be an election
Speaker 2:  and and we're gonna have to have you both back and we got some more stuff
Speaker 2:  to talk about between now and then, but thank you both. Oh
Speaker 7:  God, that is happening.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna do a question
Speaker 2:  from The Verge cast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  of three separate things. The first step is
Speaker 2:  about your
Speaker 2:  You can just delete duplicates. The other one is you can
Speaker 2:  sort out screenshots, you can do it in Google Photos, you just search for
Speaker 2:  screenshots. It'll find the screenshots. Apple pulls it all into a separate
Speaker 2:  album. I periodically just go in there and delete 'em all. I have
Speaker 2:  never once been burned by this where I'm like, oh, I wish I had that screenshot
Speaker 2:  again, go with God. I suppose there might be
Speaker 2:  problems If, you do it in such a sort of brute forcey way, but that
Speaker 2:  is a thing I do every few months and I'm always amazed at how many
Speaker 2:  screenshots I have in there and how few of them I actually care about. Most
Speaker 2:  of 'em are just like my lock screen. Anyway, the other one
Speaker 2:  is to find an app that essentially lets you like Tinder
Speaker 2:  swipe your way through your photos. There are a bunch of these, there's one
Speaker 2:  called Swipe and Delete. There's one called Swipe Wipe. There's one I think
Speaker 2:  called Slide Box. There's a bunch of these out there. Most of them will make
Speaker 2:  you pay an ongoing subscription, but what I usually do is either just do
Speaker 2:  the free trial or just pay like once and use it once. And essentially
Speaker 2:  what they do is they show you a photo and you swipe right to keep it or left
Speaker 2:  to get rid of it. And it is shocking how quick a away that
Speaker 2:  is to go through some of your photos. Most of them it's, it's a obvious snap
Speaker 2:  decision, right? Keep or lose. And having just a mechanism that lets you
Speaker 2:  choose that is great. So that's the first thing. Camera roll thing number
Speaker 2:  two is your computer. And this is
Speaker 2:  where my system is not great, but it really works for me. So I figured I
Speaker 2:  would share. The first thing I do is use an app on
Speaker 2:  the Mac called disc inventory X and on
Speaker 2:  Windows called WinDirStat,
Speaker 2:  W-I-N-D-I-R-S-T-A-T. And what both of those do is
Speaker 2:  just visualize the storage on your computer, they'll show you where all the
Speaker 2:  big files are, where all the folders are with all the big files, and I'll
Speaker 2:  just go in and find the biggest stuff that I don't need.
Speaker 2:  A lot of it for me is like video recordings or huge
Speaker 2:  application files that I download caches from browsers and just delete
Speaker 2:  all of that. And most of the reason I think to do a decluttering like
Speaker 2:  this is because you're starting to run outta storage and that is a super
Speaker 2:  duper efficient way to do it. Again, I think for a lot of people, photos
Speaker 2:  are a thing that takes up a lot of space. So If, you have photos elsewhere,
Speaker 2:  you can delete them from your computer and free up a lot of space. So yeah,
Speaker 2:  one of those visualization apps is an incredibly useful way to just figure
Speaker 2:  out where your storage is going and start to get some of it back. The second
Speaker 2:  thing I do is once every six months
Speaker 2:  or So, I will just take all of the contents
Speaker 2:  of my downloads folder and my desktop folder and
Speaker 2:  for me, my documents folder and just put it all on an
Speaker 2:  external hard drive. Again, I've deleted the biggest files by now, so most
Speaker 2:  of what's left is like little things I downloaded and documents I made
Speaker 2:  and whatever, but the way I work, at least anything that I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  need permanently ends up somewhere else. Usually it's in Google Drive, but
Speaker 2:  sometimes it'll get filed to like a specific spot on my computer. Anything
Speaker 2:  that is in sort of those like stock folders is probably something I
Speaker 2:  don't need again, but I don't wanna do the work of going through
Speaker 2:  and actually figuring it all out. But I also don't wanna delete all of it
Speaker 2:  in case there is something that I need. So I have a little tiny two terabyte
Speaker 2:  hard drive that just sits here on my desk and every few months I plug it
Speaker 2:  in, I empty the folders onto that drive and then I don't think about it again.
Speaker 2:  It cleans up my computer. It makes everything very simple and if all of a
Speaker 2:  sudden I'm like, oh, where is that thing? It's on the hard drive. Overwhelmingly,
Speaker 2:  it is on the hard drive. That has been incredibly useful for me
Speaker 2:  in both keeping my computer and me sane, but also
Speaker 2:  not having to dedicate like four full days a year
Speaker 2:  to keeping it that way. So that's my system. It has worked very well for
Speaker 2:  me. I'm sure it's not the best system. I also am like relatively
Speaker 2:  organized otherwise. So again, like things that I know where I'm gonna need
Speaker 2:  end up mostly getting filed somewhere. So if you're just kind of a like let
Speaker 2:  chaos, rain and then once a month tame it person, you should
Speaker 2:  probably keep doing that system rather than mine. But I just wanted to share
Speaker 2:  in case that helps start with the camera roll, get rid of the big files,
Speaker 2:  dump everything else onto a hard drive and know that it's there If, you need
Speaker 2:  it. I hope that helps. That's all I got. And If, you have a better idea.
Speaker 2:  I would love to hear it. I think this is a problem everybody has. I'm looking
Speaker 2:  at like the mass of icons on my desktop right now, and I'm like, I need to
Speaker 2:  do this again. And I think a lot of us do. So. I'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, for now, that is it for The. Vergecast, thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  came on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more
Speaker 2:  on everything we talked about from TikTok to Trump,
Speaker 2:  to Google, to OpenAI all of it on The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. All of this is also like ongoing, so we're covering it as we go.
Speaker 2:  It is a busy season in the tech world. I'll put some links to all that stuff
Speaker 2:  in the show notes, but keep your eyes on the website. It's a fun website.
Speaker 2:  As always. If, you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other things that
Speaker 2:  are gonna make me have an existential crisis about ai. You can always email
Speaker 2:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline eight six six VERGE
Speaker 2:  one one. I love hearing from you. It's the best thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  reaches out. It is the absolute most fun slack room we have that
Speaker 2:  pipes all the voicemails in, and I love hearing from you. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Liam James, Wil Poor and Eric Gomez. The Vergecast is a VERGE production
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli. Alex and I will be back
Speaker 2:  on Friday to talk about a bunch of new gadgets, all this stuff going on at
Speaker 2:  Meta Connect and everything else. We'll see you then. Rock and roll