# Transcript
ID: 98a55f5e-7844-4369-bdb9-810ff78f4cc0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2651276610520942922/-6567404957991219309/s93290-US-4359s-1708422299.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of sneaky gaming strategies:
03:45 - Verge producer Will Poor reports on a right-to-repair bill in Oregon and what's next in the right-to-repair movement.
The right-to-repair movement is just getting started
Status of Right to Repair legislation state by state, via repair.org
iFixit explains parts pairing
Jessa Jones’ iPad Rehab
Apple Is Lobbying Against Right to Repair Six Months After Supporting Right to Repair
The current draft of Oregon’s Right to Repair bill
33:13 - Tom Warren breaks down the news from Microsoft’s gaming chief about Xbox games coming to PS5 and next-gen hardware.
Microsoft’s gaming chief on Xbox games coming to PS5, next-gen hardware, and more
1:00:49 - David Pierce and Alex Cranz answer a question from The Vergecast Hotline about the crackdown on password sharing for streaming services.
Netflix might ruin password sharing for everyone
Disney Plus is finally cracking down on password sharing in the US
Hulu is cracking down on password sharing, just like Disney Plus and Netflix
The Vergecast and Decoder are live at SXSW this weekend, March 8th and 9th. SXSW attendees can see both shows live on the official Vox Media Podcast Stage at the JW Marriott, presented by Atlassian. Learn more at voxmedia.com/live.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (8 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Sneaky Gaming Strategies.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting in my basement doing Legos,
Speaker 2:  which is a sentence I have not been able to say for a long time and I'm very
Speaker 2:  excited to say so. Liam James, our producer got me this Polaroid
Speaker 2:  one step Lego thing for Christmas this past year, which is
Speaker 2:  part of, I'm sure you've seen this, but Lego doing all the stuff with old
Speaker 2:  technology and everything from the set of the office to
Speaker 2:  the McLaren Formula one car, taking all of that stuff, putting it into Lego
Speaker 2:  form and making it available for adults. It's all, I think like
Speaker 2:  ridiculously expensive to the point where I have not been able to talk myself
Speaker 2:  into actually buying one of these things for myself. But I've realized it
Speaker 2:  makes an awesome gift and I hope more people give me these cool Lego sets
Speaker 2:  as a gift. So I'm gonna spend some time putting this thing together. I realized
Speaker 2:  today I've been kind of intimidated by it. It's, let's see, it's
Speaker 2:  516 pieces and it is 18 and up
Speaker 2:  and you would think I would be able to handle that, but I feel like I'm rusty
Speaker 2:  with Legos. It's been a while and the idea of actually sitting here and putting
Speaker 2:  this thing together is both very fun and kind of intimidating. But I have
Speaker 2:  an afternoon. I have shows to catch up on. It's gonna be awesome. I'm very
Speaker 2:  excited and pretty soon you are going to see this thing in a background when
Speaker 2:  we record The Verge cast, I promise. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming
Speaker 2:  up for you today. We're gonna do two things. First, we're gonna talk to Will
Speaker 2:  Poor, who has been kind of immersing himself in the world of Right
Speaker 2:  to Repair. It's a really interesting time in the world of Right to Repair.
Speaker 2:  There have been big bills that have gone through. There's some real momentum
Speaker 2:  for the idea that you should be able to Repair your own gadgets, but there's
Speaker 2:  still a lot of work to do and it's not clear that all of the
Speaker 2:  pieces are actually gonna start to come together quickly in a way that makes
Speaker 2:  this stuff really work the way that it seems like it ought to. So Will has
Speaker 2:  been talking to tons of people. He's gonna come and give us kind of his first
Speaker 2:  report on what he's learned so far. Then we're gonna talk to Tom Warren about
Speaker 2:  Microsoft's news from last week. So we talked about this a little on Friday's
Speaker 2:  show, but Microsoft made what seems like a relatively small set
Speaker 2:  of gaming announcements last week that kind of hide this huge
Speaker 2:  vision for The future of gaming and the way that things are going to change
Speaker 2:  in the gaming industry in a really big way over the next two years. Microsoft
Speaker 2:  might be wrong, it might be early, it might be late, but it is not
Speaker 2:  betting as small as it would have. You think Tom knows everything about what's
Speaker 2:  going on here and he's gonna help us figure out what the real story
Speaker 2:  of Microsoft and Xbox and gaming really is. All that is coming up in just
Speaker 2:  a sec, but now I get to go do the thing that is my favorite with Allego Set
Speaker 2:  where you open it up and just dump it on the ground and kind of see what
Speaker 2:  happens. This is where I inevitably like lose six pieces that turn out to
Speaker 2:  be very frustrating for hours, but it's like the beginning of a puzzle, right?
Speaker 2:  You pour it out, you kind of take stock and you see what you have. This is
Speaker 2:  either gonna take me an hour or six months and you'll never hear me
Speaker 2:  again. So wish me luck. This is The Vergecast. Let's go
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So last year was a big year for The right to
Speaker 2:  repair movement. There were three major laws. We had one in New York, Minnesota,
Speaker 2:  and California, all of which passed, and all of which said a very basic
Speaker 2:  thing to electronics makers that you have to let other people repair
Speaker 2:  the products you make. That means giving independent repair shops or even
Speaker 2:  individual people access to the same parts and tools and
Speaker 2:  information that you, the manufacturer give your own Repair shops
Speaker 2:  or to use just one example that I'm confident we're going to refer to
Speaker 2:  1 million times throughout this story. If your iPhone breaks the Apple store
Speaker 2:  shouldn't be the only place equipped and allowed to iFixit. Last
Speaker 2:  year, in the midst of all this, we had Kyle, Wes, the CEO of iFixit on the
Speaker 2:  show to talk about just how big a deal the California law
Speaker 2:  was in particular
Speaker 5:  With the California law we're up to 20% of the US population
Speaker 5:  has passed The right to Repair lot
Speaker 2:  At the time Apple had just signed on to support that law and soon after
Speaker 2:  pledged to abide by it nationally. So on paper this was a big
Speaker 2:  victory lap moment for all of The, right, to Repair people. But now it's
Speaker 2:  2024, which is the year that these laws are actually supposed to go into
Speaker 2:  effect. And we wanted to know what that means. What's actually changing out
Speaker 2:  there in the world of electronics repairs. Like if your iPhone breaks this
Speaker 2:  year, are you better off than if your iPhone broke last year?
Speaker 2:  Our producer Will Poor has been looking into that question for a while and
Speaker 2:  he claims he has answers of which I'm always suspicious Will poor Welcome,
Speaker 2:  To, The Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Hello. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Do you have answers?
Speaker 6:  I do. I have a lot of answers. I talk to a lot of people to try to understand
Speaker 6:  what's going on here. I talk to Repair shop owners, activists, lawmakers,
Speaker 6:  and big companies like Apple and Google and you know, shocker,
Speaker 6:  the answer really depends on who you talk to. The advocates for these
Speaker 6:  laws, the folks who have spent years trying to establish the idea of
Speaker 6:  repair as a right, they're pretty jazzed.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it was an absolutely monster year for Right to Repair.
Speaker 6:  That's Nathan Proctor. He runs The right to Repair campaign for the Public
Speaker 6:  Interest Research Group. He said last year started with a disappointment
Speaker 6:  that big New York bill got watered down by the governor at the 11th hour.
Speaker 7:  I think we just went all out last year. We really put everything we had into
Speaker 7:  it and then Minnesota passed the broadest right to
Speaker 7:  Repair Bill. We've seen yet even broader than when New York did with fewer
Speaker 7:  loopholes. Then Colorado passed an excellent farmer
Speaker 7:  right to Repair Bill, which was the first of the nation on that. That was
Speaker 7:  an extremely difficult fight. Hang
Speaker 2:  On. Did, did he just say farmers? Are we talking about farmers?
Speaker 6:  We are. We absolutely are. Right to Repair is this huge deal in
Speaker 6:  agriculture also. It's not just consumer electronics, huh? That's because
Speaker 6:  John Deere and a whole bunch of other companies have gotten super,
Speaker 6:  super controlling about who can repair their tractors.
Speaker 2:  John Deere is like the apple of the tractors, right? I'm remembering this
Speaker 2:  now that they're like super mad about anybody who wants to Repair their tractor.
Speaker 6:  They're the leader in this space. They're a huge problem for farmers and
Speaker 6:  it's a huge deal for agriculture because farmers'
Speaker 6:  livelihoods depend on the stuff. you know, it's not like, like most of our
Speaker 6:  phones where it's, this is an annoyance but it's not make or break. So this
Speaker 6:  kind of thing comes up in sort of higher stake situations like
Speaker 6:  agriculture. Wheelchairs is another place where this debate
Speaker 6:  is happening. Other kinds of medical equipment. So it's a lot broader than
Speaker 6:  just consumer electronics. Anyway, here's the rest of the Nathan quote.
Speaker 7:  And then California just absolutely overwhelmingly passed
Speaker 7:  and you know, and people know or might know that Apple
Speaker 7:  endorsed that bill, which I think is just a sign of is how much momentum
Speaker 7:  we had
Speaker 6:  That Apple endorsement was notable because for years it was
Speaker 6:  the go-to example of a big powerful company Lobbying
Speaker 6:  super hard against repair laws. So the endorsement was
Speaker 6:  evidence of industry warming up to independent Repair, which is just
Speaker 6:  not how things felt for a long time
Speaker 7:  In all the years that we've been on Right? to Repair, you know, we've heard
Speaker 7:  just absolute throw spaghetti at the wall kind of
Speaker 7:  arguments against it. The big categories are safety,
Speaker 7:  security, privacy liability, intellectual property.
Speaker 7:  I remember vividly when ah, Abraham's lobbyist,
Speaker 6:  That's the Association of Home Appliance manufacturers,
Speaker 7:  Claimed that if people were able to fix their own
Speaker 7:  dryers, like you know, closed dryers that you know, they have a latch and
Speaker 7:  the door and what if the door latch came undone because you didn't do the
Speaker 7:  repair right? And then your child put their arm in there and got it ripped
Speaker 7:  off by your dryer. So right to Repair means
Speaker 7:  dismembering children.
Speaker 2:  So this is wild. This went a whole way. I did not expect, but this
Speaker 2:  makes me think of the thing you always heard from Apple and others about
Speaker 2:  like If, you try to take your phone apart, you're gonna blow up the battery
Speaker 2:  and burn your house down. Right? That's kind of the consumer electronics
Speaker 2:  version of this and I think maybe equally realistic as someone who has
Speaker 2:  blown up a battery trying to take my phone apart in the past
Speaker 6:  It happens. But yeah, I mean this is how far back this, the safety
Speaker 6:  argument against right to Repair goes and this is a drum that, that all
Speaker 6:  kinds of manufacturers have been beating for a really long time,
Speaker 2:  But they're starting to, if not give up on the safety argument,
Speaker 2:  at least roll it back a little. It sounds like
Speaker 6:  Yes, manufacturers are giving up on some arguments
Speaker 6:  that just have not panned out for them in the past. you know, the times
Speaker 6:  are changing. Apple in particular has started to publish repair
Speaker 6:  manuals on its website. It has this self-service Repair program,
Speaker 6:  which The Verge and lots of other people have pointed out feels a lot like
Speaker 6:  malicious compliance because it's super expensive and complicated. But in
Speaker 6:  general, apple is playing ball with these new laws.
Speaker 7:  Apple announced more DIY options in December. you know, these
Speaker 7:  companies are getting ready for it. you know, So, I think that like it's
Speaker 7:  clear that to some degree that there will be compliance. Like they, they're
Speaker 7:  planning for it. They think that's great. I'm glad that they're not all gonna
Speaker 7:  fight. Okay,
Speaker 2:  So this all lines up with roughly where we were
Speaker 2:  with Kyle a few months ago. We have some laws, not everything
Speaker 2:  is perfect, but the people who have been fighting this for a long time and
Speaker 2:  like you said, they've been fighting for this for a long time, are pretty
Speaker 2:  happy. But I don't know, you're setting this all up in such a way that it
Speaker 2:  makes me think there there are those who should be psyched, who are not psyched.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. So here's the other shoe dropping. I really wanted to talk
Speaker 6:  to Repair shop owners about this 'cause they're the people
Speaker 6:  that the advocates for these laws say that they're written for and I did.
Speaker 6:  And truthfully, they're not expecting a lot of material improvement
Speaker 6:  here. Hmm. One owner I talked with was Jessa Jones who runs a
Speaker 6:  repair and data recovery shop in Western New York and she
Speaker 6:  echoed pretty much every other shop owner I talked to. Basically
Speaker 6:  she thinks the laws are well intentioned but they don't address some really
Speaker 6:  critical things. For example, there is this very basic practice that
Speaker 6:  any repair shop should have at their disposal.
Speaker 8:  I would like to be able to have a filing cabinet where I put
Speaker 8:  any phone that is here for parts or pieces or donated or
Speaker 8:  old or something I buy. I wanna be able to put it in a file cabinet where
Speaker 8:  at any point in time here comes a matching phone model that I can
Speaker 8:  go to my file cabinet junkyard of parts and I can
Speaker 8:  take out a perfectly fine working, let's say
Speaker 8:  true depth camera out of this phone and install it in that phone.
Speaker 8:  And I can take two bad and make one good,
Speaker 6:  But she can't do that with iPhones. Take the true depth camera,
Speaker 6:  that's the iPhone's front facing camera system. She can order a new one
Speaker 6:  direct from Apple. It's about 185 bucks for an iPhone 15.
Speaker 6:  Making that part available technically puts Apple in compliance with
Speaker 6:  the current repair laws. But if she opened up her file cabinet
Speaker 6:  junkyard and swapped in a working camera from a dead iPhone
Speaker 6:  face, ID might just stop working. That's because the motherboards of
Speaker 6:  modern iPhones keep track of some other parts within the phone
Speaker 6:  and If you swap in an aftermarket part or even a genuine
Speaker 6:  apple part that apple didn't sell you, your phone might start acting
Speaker 6:  up.
Speaker 8:  If I replace your battery with a quality aftermarket battery,
Speaker 8:  you can no longer go into your settings and see your battery
Speaker 8:  health. You lost a function. That's terrible. That's wrong.
Speaker 8:  And that's what's happening now.
Speaker 2:  So let me just real quick make sure I understand what's going on here. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  it seems like what you're saying is if I have a
Speaker 2:  perfectly good iPhone where most of the parts are still working and then
Speaker 2:  I have another perfectly good iPhone where most of the parts are still working
Speaker 2:  and I take one perfectly good part out of one iPhone and put it in the other,
Speaker 2:  there's a pretty good chance it just won't work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, and this is what's so like mysterious and galling about Apple products,
Speaker 6:  specifically Apple products full of genuine apple components do
Speaker 6:  not play nicely with one another. People have done this famous screen swap
Speaker 6:  test where they'll take two modern iPhones, swap the screens, so
Speaker 6:  two working phones, two working screens, and all of a sudden those screens
Speaker 6:  won't work properly anymore. Weird. It's super weird and it's because
Speaker 6:  of this process of software locking components to the motherboard.
Speaker 6:  It's called parts pairing and it makes repairing iPhones a minefield.
Speaker 6:  I Fixit has been keeping really careful track of which parts cause
Speaker 6:  which problems when replaced. Some parts lose functionality,
Speaker 6:  others trigger these warning messages that you can't dismiss and there's
Speaker 6:  no telling how the next iPhone is gonna behave or even which parts
Speaker 6:  could break retroactively down the road.
Speaker 8:  You get into this really difficult and seemingly
Speaker 8:  pointless sea of problems where you don't know
Speaker 8:  what is just serialized serial numbers paired to your
Speaker 8:  logic board and you have to harvest it from your device versus
Speaker 8:  which ones of the guts can you use that came in the phone you bought on eBay.
Speaker 8:  So it's very challenging.
Speaker 2:  The skeptical part of my brain here says that this is purely
Speaker 2:  malicious on Apple's part, that Apple has a big repair business, that it
Speaker 2:  has lots of reasons to uphold and this is one basically
Speaker 2:  impenetrable way to win that fight. But just
Speaker 2:  for the sake of satiating, the other part of my brain that doesn't believe
Speaker 2:  everything is a conspiracy theory designed to ruin customers. What is
Speaker 2:  the good reason for parts pairing? Is there a theoretically good reason for
Speaker 2:  parts pairing?
Speaker 6:  Sure. I mean, apple and other manufacturers will tell you that there are
Speaker 6:  lots of reasons why at minimum it's helpful to assign like a digital
Speaker 6:  serial number to each specific part. That's a super basic thing that
Speaker 6:  helps them keep track of inventory and all kinds of stuff. Okay. And even
Speaker 6:  more than that, there are these kind of wonky calibration related reasons
Speaker 6:  that make it helpful for your phone to know which specific
Speaker 6:  part it's talking to. Like which one came off the manufacturing line.
Speaker 6:  So there's a lot of sort of nitty gritty stuff that is completely invisible
Speaker 6:  to the end user and completely benign. But it's also just way too easy for
Speaker 6:  a manufacturer to do really frustrating, really visible things with this
Speaker 6:  technology too. And in the case of iPhones, it really does seem
Speaker 6:  designed to kind of nudge you towards apple's parts, towards
Speaker 6:  apple's repair shops towards that very polished Apple experience.
Speaker 8:  I think that Apple is best thought of as the kind of mom that
Speaker 8:  cuts your stake when you're 30. you know, it's just like, let me, let me
Speaker 8:  help you with that. Let me help you with that. In their heart of hearts,
Speaker 8:  they truly just don't want for you to have
Speaker 8:  to live the sad life of someone who has an iPhone with a cracked
Speaker 8:  screen or a cracked rear camera glass. Or
Speaker 8:  maybe the, the waterproofing isn't as tight as it used to be because
Speaker 8:  you replaced the battery with some shop. you know, they don't want for
Speaker 8:  you to have the hint of any kind of negative
Speaker 8:  experience. They wanna cut that stake for you.
Speaker 2:  It's an amazing analogy because A, I kind of do want that
Speaker 2:  in my life, right? It's, and you, it's see how's right there are, there
Speaker 2:  are upsides to having someone cut my steak. For me it does make me feel
Speaker 2:  better, but also it can be both well intentioned and
Speaker 2:  problematic all at the same time, right? Like I think there's a cognitive
Speaker 2:  dissonance of all of this that is, has always been hard for me to wrap my
Speaker 2:  head around, but that's a pretty good analogy for it. Totally.
Speaker 6:  And even If, you remove apple's like secret
Speaker 6:  private heart intention out of it. It is just a practice
Speaker 6:  that ensures a really clean experience and then occasionally
Speaker 6:  is super, super frustrating.
Speaker 2:  And this is increasingly common. We've talked a bunch about Apple at this
Speaker 2:  point. I think Apple is the most obvious just because it's sort of clear
Speaker 2:  how it works. Apple has Apple stores and the genius bar and the whole repair
Speaker 2:  process is visible to people in the way that it's not for most other companies
Speaker 2:  and products. But if I'm not mistaken, parts pairing is kind of
Speaker 2:  everywhere, right? Like I have this vague memory of people being mad
Speaker 2:  about the Xbox disc drive being a separate thing, but
Speaker 2:  paired to the Xbox somehow in some similar way.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And PlayStations do it too. TVs very commonly have certain
Speaker 6:  paired parts. We talked about John Deere tractors earlier. It is
Speaker 6:  a tough thing to keep track of because it's not something that manufacturers
Speaker 6:  advertise. It's sort of down to the repair community and
Speaker 6:  advocates to kind of ferret this stuff out generation by generation
Speaker 6:  of these products. So it's a tricky thing to track but it, it is
Speaker 6:  out there. But also everyone I talk to reiterated
Speaker 6:  over and over again that Apple is far and away the leader in this space.
Speaker 6:  They are just, everyone is looking to them for innovation in how
Speaker 6:  to do frustrating parts, pairing type things. And you know,
Speaker 6:  the other thing is that Apple sold 230 million iPhones last year.
Speaker 6:  So it's, you know, fair. This is is super ubiquitous practice for that reason
Speaker 6:  alone,
Speaker 2:  Especially in the US Like it's, it's easy to forget this around the world
Speaker 2:  because the iPhone is not so dominant elsewhere. But in the US there is a
Speaker 2:  one in two chance that If you own a phone, it's an iPhone. Totally. And I
Speaker 2:  guess that is true like as Apple goes so goes so many industries at
Speaker 2:  this point I guess including the Repair industry.
Speaker 6:  Totally. And, and so If, you talk to any repair shop in the
Speaker 6:  US that's like that iPhone dominance is, is the thing that keeps
Speaker 6:  them up at night for them. The right to Repair story
Speaker 6:  often just feels like the apple parts pairing story.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's a long history of Apple policies dictating everybody
Speaker 2:  else's, especially in the US on this. Did you talk to Apple about any of
Speaker 2:  this by the way Apple is like theoretically in support of all this. Did they
Speaker 2:  talk to you?
Speaker 6:  Not really. I, I did reach someone from their comms team but they didn't
Speaker 6:  wanna talk to me on the record about any of it.
Speaker 2:  I think anyone listening to The Vergecast knows how we all feel about that
Speaker 2:  over time. So let's go back to Jessa for a minute. Our, our repair
Speaker 2:  shop owner. What does she want, what do people who own
Speaker 2:  these shops want to see happen? Like what does a victory for them
Speaker 2:  look like in this space right now?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well I asked Jessa that exact question.
Speaker 8:  I would like to see the resumption
Speaker 8:  of aftermarket technology being
Speaker 8:  accepted by the phone. you know, a lot of times like the batteries, they
Speaker 8:  are better than the ones that you would get in the phone. They have a little
Speaker 8:  bit of a better capacity. They last longer. They're really robust by now.
Speaker 8:  These have been out for a long time and I don't think that it's
Speaker 8:  The right message to send that it's inherently
Speaker 8:  untrustworthy, untoward or shameful to put an
Speaker 8:  aftermarket part in instead of a branded part.
Speaker 6:  And as frustrating as these legal battles have been as she's watched them,
Speaker 6:  she still sees promise in that route.
Speaker 8:  I do like seeing these bills that have been passed and I do think that
Speaker 8:  parts pairing is a really probably the most important part of
Speaker 8:  the story.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so we have all these new rights repair laws, but it seems
Speaker 2:  like most of them don't address parts pairing at all and it increasingly
Speaker 2:  sounds like parts pairing is the most important part of this story.
Speaker 2:  So where are we actually at here?
Speaker 6:  Well, we're at pass more laws basically. Let's
Speaker 2:  Get some more
Speaker 6:  Laws. Yeah, always more laws and that might happen this year.
Speaker 9:  Good afternoon. And Welcome to the Senate Energy and Environment Committee.
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna open up public hearing public on Senate
Speaker 9:  bill 1596. And while you read that
Speaker 9:  I'm
Speaker 6:  Gonna go. So right now Oregon is considering a repair bill that
Speaker 6:  targets parts pairing way more directly than any of those existing
Speaker 6:  laws. I've been following the public hearings in Oregon and I talked to one
Speaker 6:  of the bill's chief sponsors, Senator Janine Salman. I asked
Speaker 6:  her, you know what it's like to get a bill like this one over the finish
Speaker 6:  line And the first thing she pointed out is that this is the fourth attempt
Speaker 6:  for a repair law in her state.
Speaker 9:  The first time it was a very broad net, it encompassed a lot
Speaker 9:  of product. And then when I got involved, the scope was narrowed and it became
Speaker 9:  the consumer items, the cell phones, the laptops and such. And
Speaker 9:  it did not even move out of the house. The third time
Speaker 9:  was last year. It did move out of Senate energy and Environment.
Speaker 9:  There was a delay in our floor session because there was
Speaker 9:  six weeks where there was a pause due to a senate walkout. So
Speaker 9:  it died and then California then passed their bill and then we started
Speaker 9:  working right after the session to really fine tune and look at
Speaker 9:  Oregon's policy, what we would be bringing forward
Speaker 6:  Forward. So it's a grind, but the fourth law has been
Speaker 6:  introduced with parts pairing language intact.
Speaker 9:  I know that the advocates feel very strongly about that. That was something
Speaker 9:  that was either never introduced in other bills or was
Speaker 9:  amended out or compromised out.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But it's in there this time. Right? What does it say exactly?
Speaker 6:  It says that manufacturers like Apple can't use parts
Speaker 6:  pairing to interfere in a repair. They can't reduce the functionality
Speaker 6:  or performance of a product and they can't display misleading
Speaker 6:  alerts or warnings about replacement parts.
Speaker 2:  I'm guessing Apple is not psyched about that specific language.
Speaker 9:  Apple has asked us to remove it, but I strongly believe that
Speaker 9:  it's a consumer loss to do so.
Speaker 6:  Can you, I would love to hear anything you can tell me about your conversation
Speaker 6:  with Apple directly or indirectly.
Speaker 9:  You know, I've engaged with, with Apple many times. I met with the Apple
Speaker 9:  lobbyist and we kind of went over like hey these are the issues that we see
Speaker 9:  could potentially be changed. They were introduced in California,
Speaker 9:  So I took all of that in the second meeting I was told to come alone.
Speaker 6:  What that, that paints a picture in of itself. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's amazing. Some truly cloak and dagger
Speaker 2:  politicking.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's ridiculous. So to their credit,
Speaker 6:  apple has gotten a little less cloak and dagger about all of it. A
Speaker 6:  spokesman did finally testify publicly at a hearing a couple
Speaker 6:  weeks ago though. He was basically just there to say, please leave parts
Speaker 6:  pairing out of this.
Speaker 10:  I'd like to begin by saying that Apple agrees with the vast majority of
Speaker 10:  Senate Bill 1596. However, it is our belief that the
Speaker 10:  bill's current language around parts pairing will undermine the security,
Speaker 10:  safety and privacy of Oregonians by forcing device manufacturers to allow
Speaker 10:  the use of parts of unknown origin and consumer devices.
Speaker 6:  So the line here is basically just that aftermarket parts are a crap shoot.
Speaker 6:  They could be good, they could be shoddy, they could be dangerous. Parts
Speaker 6:  pairing is Apple's way of steering customers away from questionable
Speaker 6:  components like Explodey batteries. They're super worried about security
Speaker 6:  features like touch ID components.
Speaker 10:  Apple could be required to allow third party biometric sensors to work in
Speaker 10:  our devices without any form of authentication, which could lead to unauthorized
Speaker 10:  access to an individual's personal data.
Speaker 2:  So this is a slightly different take than, than we've been talking about
Speaker 2:  with some of the parts pairing stuff, which is I think the, I have a
Speaker 2:  working Apple thing and I wanna put it in another working Apple thing
Speaker 2:  is one version of parts pairing. But I have to say I find this slightly
Speaker 2:  more credible. The idea that you shouldn't just buy
Speaker 2:  any battery you find on Amazon. And I mean you and I have both bought
Speaker 2:  crappy things on Amazon. Remember all those hoverboards that exploded? Like
Speaker 2:  maybe protecting people from themselves is not a crazy idea. What do,
Speaker 2:  do you buy that argument?
Speaker 6:  It's funny, we're coming back around to the safety argument. Yeah, you're
Speaker 2:  Right. Kids in dryers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we're back to dismembering children. But it's, you're right
Speaker 6:  that batteries are an easy punching bag because they fail and sometimes they
Speaker 6:  fail catastrophically. So as a DIY repair
Speaker 6:  person, you absolutely should do your homework and find a trusted
Speaker 6:  supplier of an aftermarket battery or you should go to a trusted
Speaker 6:  repair shop. As for the kind of rogue fingerprint sensor
Speaker 6:  that can hack your phone. Hmm. I talked to a security expert and they
Speaker 6:  said it was possible but really farfetched.
Speaker 2:  It sounds scary. It's a good like visceral example.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean it falls really neatly into the category of what
Speaker 6:  advocates refer to derisively as Fudd or fear
Speaker 6:  uncertainty and doubt. Which is just a very diffuse
Speaker 6:  tactic for people who want to scare you away from a thing. It kind of
Speaker 6:  does go back to the issue though of just finding a good repair shop and a
Speaker 6:  good aftermarket supplier. Yeah. That's that not gonna sell you a super sketchy
Speaker 6:  part and that is just a leap that Apple doesn't want customers
Speaker 6:  to have to make basically. So that's Apple's take on
Speaker 6:  the Oregon bill. But the other notable thing about this bill in particular
Speaker 6:  is Google used it as an opportunity to come out fully in support of Right
Speaker 6:  to Repair, including all of the parts pairing stuff in this Oregon bill.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. And they're basically using this bill to loudly say,
Speaker 6:  yes you can have a hardware business without controlling what goes
Speaker 6:  into that hardware after the fact.
Speaker 11:  I can't speak as well to that 'cause that's simply something that we do
Speaker 11:  not do
Speaker 6:  That is Google's head of consumer hardware, Steven Nickel on a call with
Speaker 6:  me last week.
Speaker 11:  You can have that quality, you can have that safety with your
Speaker 11:  repairs processes that we implement and not be concerned about it. Right?
Speaker 11:  We work with really good repair providers. We also make the process as
Speaker 11:  simple as possible so we're not as concerned.
Speaker 6:  So obviously Steven knows that taking this more relaxed approach means
Speaker 6:  that more aftermarket parts are gonna find their way into Google products.
Speaker 6:  But here again, he just didn't project any worry about it.
Speaker 11:  We want you to have that best experience. And so, you know, we believe
Speaker 11:  that best experience means authorized parts. We know that other parts
Speaker 11:  are out there, third party parts for various aspects, right? But continually,
Speaker 11:  we believe if we put out this experience and we make authorized parts available,
Speaker 11:  accessible and affordable, you're gonna select those, right?
Speaker 6:  So that is basically where things stand at the moment.
Speaker 6:  Google and Apple both support the basic concepts
Speaker 6:  in these repair bills and now they are duking it out with lawmakers over
Speaker 6:  specifics like parts pairing, which is not super satisfying for
Speaker 6:  shop owners like Jessa. It's slow moving, it's precarious,
Speaker 6:  but everyone involved is starting to reach the marrow
Speaker 6:  of this debate. And along the way Senator Solomon is noticing that same
Speaker 6:  shift that Nathan Proctor and other advocates are seeing in the industry.
Speaker 6:  This really slow but steady realization that
Speaker 6:  opposing repair laws just isn't a good look.
Speaker 9:  You know, having folks that have been at the table but are now neutral,
Speaker 9:  having Amazon Neutral, having Intel neutral,
Speaker 9:  Microsoft, OBI, which is the Oregon business and industry which has been
Speaker 9:  in opposition is now neutral. So this policy is coming and
Speaker 9:  I'm really excited to to be one of the ones to bring that forward.
Speaker 6:  Gotcha. So to be clear, getting to neutral is the win because all of those
Speaker 6:  groups were in opposition. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  It's an absolute win.
Speaker 2:  This goes back to something Kyle said to us last year, which is basically
Speaker 2:  that the big shift was making it very hard
Speaker 2:  for someone to credibly loudly be against right? to Repair.
Speaker 2:  And it does feel like that has shifted that we've gone from sort of a
Speaker 2:  reasonable people can disagree way of thinking about this stuff to right
Speaker 2:  to Repair is, is The right idea? And we can argue about the details of it,
Speaker 2:  but this is clearly how it should work. And I think at this point that
Speaker 2:  particular battle does seem like it has been won.
Speaker 6:  It absolutely has. And everyone I talked to said the same thing
Speaker 6:  that 10 years ago it was perfectly acceptable for a manufacturer
Speaker 6:  to say, no, we know best. We own this entire
Speaker 6:  process, this is how we operate. There was no
Speaker 6:  pressure to even give lip service to this idea.
Speaker 6:  And if nothing else, there is now a lot of pressure to give lip service to
Speaker 6:  this idea. Right?
Speaker 2:  You have to at least pretend to care now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then And now it's the whole battle is going from
Speaker 6:  pretending to care to if not actually caring, being
Speaker 6:  forced to participate in ways that are really meaningful. Right? And
Speaker 2:  Figurine out how all of this is actually supposed to play out in the
Speaker 2:  real world. We're still at the phase of if my phone breaks, where am I
Speaker 2:  supposed to go and what am I supposed to do? But that's a much more interesting
Speaker 2:  next phase I think than am I allowed to fix my own phone? Yes.
Speaker 2:  It also seems like that is leading us to the next question, which is basically
Speaker 2:  like how is all of this supposed to work in the real world? Because I'm also
Speaker 2:  increasingly aware of the fact that everything we own is technology and everything
Speaker 2:  we own breaks in new spectacular ways. And so we're gonna need
Speaker 2:  this big vibrant repair ecosystem and we figured out
Speaker 2:  like very little of it yet, but at least we can get to the work of figurine
Speaker 2:  out how it's all supposed to work as opposed to figurine out whether we're
Speaker 2:  allowed to do it right.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. And it's a very good point that like as smartphones go
Speaker 6:  today, so could go a lot of different things in The future. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So I wanted one last perspective on this, which is the Zoom all
Speaker 6:  the way out. Why is this gonna matter to everyone in The future perspective?
Speaker 6:  So I called up someone who thinks a lot about how to keep all of this
Speaker 6:  technology working for us.
Speaker 12:  My name is Stacey Higginbotham, I am a policy fellow at Consumer Reports.
Speaker 6:  Stacey spent years reporting on the internet of things. So when
Speaker 6:  she looks at a technology like parts pairing, she sees trouble ahead for
Speaker 6:  a lot more than cell phones.
Speaker 12:  We're adding software to a lot more products that historically
Speaker 12:  haven't had software in them. A good example would be your home
Speaker 12:  appliances. Your current home appliances may not have like a wifi
Speaker 12:  chip in them and they may not have a lot of software that allows them to
Speaker 12:  do cool features, but your next one probably will. Those companies are
Speaker 12:  learning from what Apple's doing and they're going to be implementing similar
Speaker 12:  sorts of software pairing techniques to make these devices
Speaker 12:  less repairable by third parties, but also just less
Speaker 12:  something that the consumer themselves has ownership of. If that
Speaker 12:  makes sense. And that's the big risk here I think with software pairing
Speaker 12:  is that it's not gonna stop with your phones, it's gonna go to everything
Speaker 12:  because as we connect our devices to the internet, they get not just
Speaker 12:  radios, they get software and cool features and you're
Speaker 12:  gonna lose control over a lot of that going forward.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you've just brought up the like big huge galaxy
Speaker 2:  brain sized question behind all of this, which is do we actually
Speaker 2:  own the stuff that we buy? And like we cannot get into
Speaker 2:  that now because dear God, the things that we'll do to me in
Speaker 2:  this episode. But that does feel like this question, right? All of this
Speaker 2:  boils down to like, is my iPhone, my car, my
Speaker 2:  dishwasher? Like is that mine to do with as I please? Or am I
Speaker 2:  essentially operating something under someone else's purview?
Speaker 6:  Exactly. And iPhones are just far enough out ahead of all
Speaker 6:  of this that it is easy to look at them and start to go like, oh,
Speaker 6:  what if the whole world worked like that? And so that's what we're doing
Speaker 6:  right now with consumer electronics like iPhones and it's
Speaker 6:  what a lot of this right to repair movement really boils down to
Speaker 6:  in the end. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So someday, very soon you're gonna come back here and we're just gonna get
Speaker 2:  deep in our feelings about ownership and I'm gonna yell about Kindle books
Speaker 2:  getting removed from Kindles and it's gonna be a whole thing. Yep. But for
Speaker 2:  now, you mentioned more laws we're gonna cover right to Repair a lot this
Speaker 2:  year. I actually think this is like one of the big sort of trundling along
Speaker 2:  in the background stories in this industry and you're deep in it now. You're
Speaker 2:  gonna keep covering it for us, but set the stage for the rest of the year
Speaker 2:  for us a little bit. What is 2024 gonna look like in this space?
Speaker 6:  Well, we're gonna have to see, it's really hard to predict what
Speaker 6:  happens with all of these different bills. So I'm gonna be following what's
Speaker 6:  going on in Oregon. That bill that we talked about just passed out of committee.
Speaker 6:  It's headed for the full Senate in Oregon right now. So we'll see
Speaker 6:  what kinda legs, lucky number four in Oregon looks like I'll
Speaker 6:  keep track of other state bills and I wanna just keep talking to Repair shop
Speaker 6:  owners and DIY folks because parts pairing is really important
Speaker 6:  for them. But there's a ton of other stuff that they're grappling with every
Speaker 6:  day that is very closely connected to The, right to Repair that has
Speaker 6:  nothing to do with anything that regulators are trying to tackle right now.
Speaker 6:  So there's just a lot more going on here. And as you say, I think
Speaker 6:  this year is gonna be a big year both for the
Speaker 6:  laws and for people asking those, those even larger questions.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. How should the people get in touch with you? Like we said, you're
Speaker 2:  gonna be covering this all year, If, you are run a shop and want to talk
Speaker 2:  about it or just have feelings about your iPhone screens. How should, how
Speaker 2:  should people find you?
Speaker 6:  Oh, email me, William dot poor@voxmedia.com and
Speaker 6:  I will check back here when I learn more about all those things.
Speaker 2:  Awesome, thanks. Will appreciate it as always. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Absolutely.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about some big and slightly confusing news from
Speaker 2:  Microsoft. We'll be
Speaker 4:  Right back.
Speaker 13:  safely.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So we talked a little bit about this on Friday's show, but
Speaker 2:  Microsoft made some big gaming news last week that was also kind of
Speaker 2:  small news. The company announced a couple of new bits of information
Speaker 2:  about how game streaming and Game Pass are doing, but also said that it's
Speaker 2:  gonna take four games which have previously been Xbox exclusives and make
Speaker 2:  them available on the PlayStation and the switch in and of itself. This is
Speaker 2:  not like earth shattering News, it's a couple of games in a couple
Speaker 2:  of new places, but there's something bigger going on underneath
Speaker 2:  all of this. And The Verge is Tom Warren, I guarantee you knows
Speaker 2:  what, it's Tom Warren Welcome back to The Vergecast. Hello. You have had
Speaker 2:  a week my friend.
Speaker 14:  I have. It's been an Xbox week.
Speaker 2:  I feel like Microsoft likes to do this to you every once in a while where
Speaker 2:  they're just like, for five straight days we're gonna ruin Tom's life.
Speaker 14:  They're like, Tom is, it's his birthday so we're just gonna mess up his
Speaker 14:  week. But all the times that he's messed up our weeks let's
Speaker 14:  back. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's kind of him. Yeah. So okay, so let's talk about the news, which will
Speaker 2:  take us not very long. And then I wanna talk about all the stuff
Speaker 2:  underneath the news because this is very much sort of the, the tip of the
Speaker 2:  iceberg above the water kind of moment for, for Microsoft and Xbox So, I
Speaker 2:  wanna talk about all of that. But the news of this podcast,
Speaker 2:  which is just the funniest way ever for Microsoft to release this news. What
Speaker 2:  new stuff did we get from this Microsoft announcement on Thursday?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, I mean the, the big news is obviously the stuff that's been rumored
Speaker 14:  for weeks or months now and that is the Microsoft bringing four
Speaker 14:  games, which they're not actually naming, we'll get into that,
Speaker 14:  but four games to PlayStation and Nintendo Switch or
Speaker 14:  Nintendo Switch. I don't think every single of those games will come to
Speaker 14:  both as far as I'm aware. But yeah, four games on multiple
Speaker 14:  platforms essentially. Now obviously Microsoft does publish, you know, Minecraft
Speaker 14:  and games like that and they're gonna be publishing Call of Duty now 'cause
Speaker 14:  of Activision Blizzard on multiple platforms. But I still think this is
Speaker 14:  still, although they downplayed it, I still think it's pretty seismic. Like
Speaker 14:  it's, you know, putting your Xbox exclusive games that
Speaker 14:  people have purchased on Xbox onto rival platforms is
Speaker 14:  definitely a strategy shift. Even if they framed it as just four
Speaker 14:  for now we're just gonna, you know, take some learnings out of it and stuff.
Speaker 14:  But that, that was the big news and then they kind of softened
Speaker 14:  the blow of that because obviously they knew it was gonna be pretty controversial
Speaker 14:  amongst exports fans and like doom and gloom with the fact that
Speaker 14:  they're working on a next generation console, which you know, you'd expect
Speaker 14:  them to be right. But they, they're saying it's gonna be, you know, some
Speaker 14:  giant technical leap. So it's, we'll see what happens there. Other than
Speaker 14:  that there was the first Activision Blizzard game, Diablo four coming to
Speaker 14:  Game Pass, a sort of reaffirmation of Game Pass being, you know,
Speaker 14:  games being day one on Game Pass and then just this kind of light
Speaker 14:  sort of theme throughout it of bringing the games to players where they're
Speaker 14:  at. you know that that that very much that multi-platform thing. So
Speaker 2:  Right. So, and that seems to me like the big picture underneath
Speaker 2:  all of this and and my sense is Microsoft would very much like you
Speaker 2:  to think that it's just sort of running an experiment, just trying
Speaker 2:  some things, seeing what happens. Let's just put some games out. Who
Speaker 2:  knows what'll happen but underneath you get the sense that this is like,
Speaker 2:  this is a moment for Microsoft that is much bigger than
Speaker 2:  it would have you believe. So like dig all the way down to the bottom of
Speaker 2:  the iceberg here. Like what is this sort of big picture thing that Xbox
Speaker 2:  is trying to do? You get this leaked memo from Phil Spencer that I think
Speaker 2:  kind of seems to lay it out in bigger picture terms but even that might
Speaker 2:  be downplaying it slightly. Like paint me the biggest version of this picture
Speaker 2:  here.
Speaker 14:  So I. Think we have to, to paint the picture, we have to understand why
Speaker 14:  they would even do this in the first place, right? 'cause it sounds If you
Speaker 14:  said it's a year ago, people would be like, no way, they're not gonna bring
Speaker 14:  exports games to Station that's just like, you know, conspiracy theory or
Speaker 14:  whatever. But If you look like, so two, two years ago they obviously announced
Speaker 14:  the acquisition Activision Blizzard at the time they had 25 million Game
Speaker 14:  Pass subscribers and they announced that since then we've never heard anything
Speaker 14:  more about how many Game Pass subscribers they've had at the time. They
Speaker 14:  were kind of pushing Game Pass as the reason to buy an export series s and
Speaker 14:  x. They launched the series s as a $300 console. That was kind of
Speaker 14:  the game pass console, right? That you buy that to to get the Game Pass
Speaker 14:  subscription. That was the way in right. Sales of those consoles haven't
Speaker 14:  gone as well as Microsoft hoped. We've seen that, that they're still lagging
Speaker 14:  far behind the PS five and Game Pass has stalled. So Phil
Speaker 14:  Spencer admitted that in like late 2022, so probably
Speaker 14:  about about 10 months or so after they, they announced that 25 million
Speaker 2:  And I think you can fairly safely assume that the fact that we have not heard
Speaker 2:  much since then is not a sign that it has massively turned around
Speaker 14:  Not good news. Yeah. But the one thing we didn't mention with the, the news
Speaker 14:  is that they actually said 34 million now.
Speaker 2:  Oh interesting. Okay.
Speaker 14:  Which was pretty much spot on what analysts said. They said
Speaker 14:  33.3 million. So it's like very close. That
Speaker 14:  includes Game Pass Core, which used to be exports Live Gold.
Speaker 14:  So that is an interesting part as well. But when you take that
Speaker 14:  example of Game Pass stalling, Microsoft needs to find revenue growth
Speaker 14:  elsewhere if they're not selling the consoles and, and getting that user
Speaker 14:  base up so they can sell, you know, the, the micro
Speaker 14:  transactions, the gains, all the in-game content, everything else you need
Speaker 14:  to find revenue from elsewhere, right? You still need to grow and Microsoft
Speaker 14:  needs to grow, especially when they're, they're putting so much money on
Speaker 14:  the line for these studios. So I think that's the main driver behind
Speaker 14:  this. And you are right, like they're, they're framing it like it's a test,
Speaker 14:  right? They're gonna learn and I'm, I'm sure yeah, they'll, they'll learn
Speaker 14:  a bunch of stuff but they've already been publishing on PlayStation and
Speaker 14:  Nintendo for, for years now. So there's not a lot of learnings that they,
Speaker 14:  they're gonna pick up there that they don't already know. So
Speaker 2:  If I'm Microsoft, it feels like you, you take kind of the last couple of
Speaker 2:  years and you can, you can do one of two things. You can either say we believe
Speaker 2:  that streaming and cloud and Game Pass is The
Speaker 2:  future. We, we think we're early. Microsoft has a really long history of
Speaker 2:  being slightly too early to really good ideas. Yes. But we are gonna keep
Speaker 2:  pushing on this and they've talked a lot about how they're in third place
Speaker 2:  and this is the way to win the next generation. And so if you're Phil Spencer,
Speaker 2:  there's a version of this story where you say the only way out is through,
Speaker 2:  right? Yes. The other side is to say maybe this isn't
Speaker 2:  working and then to say, okay, let's go back to something that feels
Speaker 2:  more like a way that you can actually make money in the gaming industry.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And the two ways to do that are either make games that people buy on
Speaker 2:  lots of platforms or make a gaming platform on which people
Speaker 2:  buy your hardware and play your games. And it feels like Microsoft is
Speaker 2:  wanting to say that it's still on the streaming is The future
Speaker 2:  side of things, but it's kind of like trenching back towards this like very
Speaker 2:  normal way of running a gaming business.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And that's, that's a good point. Like the, the cloud stuff is also
Speaker 14:  a big part of this as well because they, they kind of bet on cloud being
Speaker 14:  bigger than it perhaps has been or, or will be potentially in
Speaker 14:  the next sort of five years. Essentially. They've had, they've also had
Speaker 14:  this vision of exports everywhere, right? Like on on every screen or whatever,
Speaker 14:  which we've heard them saying is leak memo, it's always been that vision
Speaker 14:  like on PCs, on consoles, on cloud, you know,
Speaker 14:  getting it to mobile devices through streaming. That's always been that
Speaker 14:  vision. They've just kind of tweaked it to now include PlayStation and
Speaker 14:  Nintendo Switch as targets for that, for that vision. Something that I haven't
Speaker 14:  seen anyone's kind of picked up on or I haven't written about it, I probably
Speaker 14:  should. But If you think about this when you, when you publish a game on,
Speaker 14:  on a, on a rival platform, say like Blizzard, they publish like
Speaker 14:  Overwatch on multiple platforms. You sign in with your blizzard ID
Speaker 14:  to to get into that game. That gives you cross progression and, and all
Speaker 14:  sorts of account link and stuff. Once, if Microsoft does that with its games
Speaker 14:  that it brings to PlayStation switch, like it requires an account where
Speaker 14:  you get some of that e exports ecosystem, the cross saves and If,
Speaker 14:  you do wanna buy an exports, then all your saves are there. All that sort
Speaker 14:  of stuff that they, they constantly talk about. And once if they do
Speaker 14:  eventually then start selling subscriptions to give you in-game stuff
Speaker 14:  or like perks and and stuff for those games. I don't know exactly
Speaker 14:  how that'll work in terms of the platform holders allowing that, but it's
Speaker 14:  a possibility that these could even be like tro horse games for for, for
Speaker 14:  something like that down the line. 'cause they know they can't get Game
Speaker 14:  Pass natively on those con on those consoles 'cause they, Sony's gonna want
Speaker 14:  their folks in cart. Nintendo is and just like Microsoft would if, if
Speaker 14:  it was the other way around. So I do feel like there, there's a possibility
Speaker 14:  that they might be able to work around some stuff with the account stuff.
Speaker 14:  We'll see
Speaker 2:  That's interesting and, and so maybe I'm not giving Microsoft enough sort
Speaker 2:  of vision credit there that maybe they're not just pulling back to,
Speaker 2:  we have to sell people video games because that's how you make money in the
Speaker 2:  gaming business is by selling people video games. Right. And we have to do
Speaker 2:  it any way possible that they can do a little bit of that while also still
Speaker 2:  pushing on this Xbox everywhere, every
Speaker 2:  screen should be an Xbox kind of strategy. Which like it'll actually I think
Speaker 2:  is The right strategy. I think it's again, it, it seems like Microsoft is
Speaker 2:  early here and whether it can survive how early it is remains
Speaker 2:  to be seen. but it does feel like that ought to be where all of this
Speaker 2:  goes. And maybe Microsoft isn't giving up on that entirely by doing this.
Speaker 14:  No and I think a part of it is also they, they obviously Game Pass was pretty
Speaker 14:  disruptive. It was de definitely something that kind of shook up the, the
Speaker 14:  industry a little bit. It definitely made Sony respond, right? They they,
Speaker 14:  they responded with with subscriptions beyond what they were offering.
Speaker 14:  And I do wonder if that's kind of Microsoft's plan here as well is like
Speaker 14:  to try and shake up this idea exclusivity. 'cause obviously we saw the
Speaker 14:  Sony president announce just hours funny enough before
Speaker 14:  Microsoft's event that they wanted to aggressively pursue multi-platform
Speaker 14:  or that that's the way they say it. But I think the way that you can really
Speaker 14:  understand that is is pc, 'cause he did mention computers in particular
Speaker 14:  So I think that's more them saying they want to be day and date on
Speaker 14:  PC more often 'cause there's money to be had there, right? Like hell
Speaker 14:  two came out recently and it's, it's doing massive amounts and I think
Speaker 14:  this is Microsoft kind of saying Sony you should probably do this as well,
Speaker 14:  you know, like do it on PC and I don't know whether we'll see Sony do
Speaker 14:  PlayStation games on exports anytime soon. But the other part of
Speaker 14:  all of this with, if people are all publishing on different rival
Speaker 14:  platforms and stuff, it's just vows just sitting there sort of laughing,
Speaker 14:  right? Yeah, true. They've got all the exclusives they want, right? They
Speaker 14:  they're getting the PlayStation ones, they're getting the, the Microsoft
Speaker 14:  ones, they're not getting the Nintendo ones unless Nintendo does PC games,
Speaker 14:  which I do think they should. But they are building quietly building
Speaker 14:  the steam deck and Linux platform to rival Windows and that's one of
Speaker 14:  the, the last touch points of Windows for consumers is gaming, right? Like
Speaker 14:  if Microsoft loses that they lose a lot of consumer in really
Speaker 14:  if that goes away, So I think there's, there's definitely a part of that
Speaker 14:  as well that Microsoft's looking towards. They're seeing what
Speaker 14:  Vows doing in that strategy there. There's a possibility that we could have
Speaker 14:  gaming consoles that are steam decks, right? They are basically
Speaker 14:  a game console now so you can plug it into your tv.
Speaker 2:  Well and speaking of that, we were sort of anticipating potentially getting
Speaker 2:  some big hardware announcement. We've been waiting for the Xbox handheld
Speaker 2:  for what feels like years now and we didn't get one
Speaker 2:  but you asked Phil Spencer about it and I would describe the answer he gave
Speaker 2:  you as the closest thing to saying yes we're building a
Speaker 2:  handheld that he could possibly say without saying the words Yes we're building
Speaker 2:  a handheld. Was that your read of of what's going on?
Speaker 14:  Yeah and that was my, because he said like unique hardware, right? Like
Speaker 14:  and positioning the hardware teams to sort of design in a way that they
Speaker 14:  haven't before And obviously they're gonna have to create unique hardware
Speaker 14:  if, if they are putting more of these games across platform. You need, you
Speaker 14:  need to have the hardware be some some sort of unique thing. So that
Speaker 14:  doesn't seem too surprising. But yeah I did ask him 'cause he always likes
Speaker 14:  a bunch of people's tweets about handhelds so I'm like, it's
Speaker 2:  Such a funny strategy. I love
Speaker 14:  It. It's so obvious, right? Like he's obviously trying to say something
Speaker 14:  but, and I think part of it is they obviously have to improve the Windows
Speaker 14:  situation on handhelds so there's competitors to Steam Deck. But yeah, like
Speaker 14:  the exports handheld itself, I'm very curious if they, if they do that
Speaker 14:  and when and on what sort of platform that runs. 'cause I,
Speaker 14:  I think the, the most ideal thing that they could do, which they could
Speaker 14:  technically do is just whether they could put all these things together
Speaker 14:  is have it run Windows but never expose Windows. Like Steam Deck
Speaker 14:  has Linux and doesn't really expose it unless you want to go into the desktop
Speaker 14:  but then have it run the virtual machine of exports os on top so you can
Speaker 14:  get exports games on it. 'cause then you don't have to worry about the PC
Speaker 14:  game pass store and the Microsoft store and which isn't very good on
Speaker 14:  pc and then you get the best, best of both worlds, right? You can still
Speaker 14:  play steam games on it as well. Like that would be If you wanted to sell
Speaker 14:  me a steam deck that was running. That would be, I think a lot of people
Speaker 14:  would buy that.
Speaker 2:  I think so too. Well, and this goes back to one of the strangest
Speaker 2:  Microsoft strategies to me and I I, you and I have talked about this before,
Speaker 2:  but I'm curious how you're thinking about it now, which is Microsoft never
Speaker 2:  seems to be able to decide whether it wants to make its own hardware and
Speaker 2:  it, it kind of vacillates in and out between betting really big on surface
Speaker 2:  and doing some really interesting work and really changing the PC industry
Speaker 2:  and then this sort of pull back from the innovation there, which,
Speaker 2:  you know, caused Panos pane to leave and some other machinations going on
Speaker 2:  there. but it seems like if I'm Microsoft and I am all in on the hardware
Speaker 2:  business, they should have built more Xbox stuff by now. So
Speaker 2:  it seems like there's, there's one way to read that that's like, well these
Speaker 2:  two things are too obvious to have not been together by now. Right. If
Speaker 2:  Microsoft actually cared about doing this and if you're taking the Windows
Speaker 2:  strategy, you just kind of are happy running on partner devices rather than
Speaker 2:  trying to build your own. Yeah. But then it is pretty obvious that they're
Speaker 2:  building a handheld. So like what do you make of this? Like, does Phil Spencer
Speaker 2:  wanna build this hardware or is he trying to like start an ecosystem of hardware
Speaker 2:  that he can just put his games on.
Speaker 14:  I think ultimately they probably do wanna build the hardware. Okay. There'll
Speaker 14:  probably be some sort of combination of the Surface team doing that or helping
Speaker 14:  out with it. 'cause they, they kind of help out with some of the export
Speaker 14:  stuff anyway. And a lot of the lab testing is kinda shared. But yeah, like
Speaker 14:  I, I do think they'll build it. It's just, it comes back to the question
Speaker 14:  of what platform would it run on? And I think that speaks to probably why
Speaker 14:  they haven't done it before. There's been that weird, like there always
Speaker 14:  this weird split between exports and, and PC stuff and Microsoft's always
Speaker 14:  tried to kind of force the console stuff onto pc, but PC games don't really
Speaker 14:  want that. They use Discord and Steam and they don't really care about
Speaker 14:  an exports party chat or whatever. Like that's not a thing. Right. And it's
Speaker 14:  just, I think that is reflected internally. Like there's like
Speaker 14:  the old days, what was that org chart where like Microsoft's business units
Speaker 14:  were pointing guns at each other. Like I think that's still, that's right.
Speaker 14:  That still kind of exists a little bit and there's still fiefdoms and stuff.
Speaker 14:  you know, like I do think that exports hasn't been able to do exactly what
Speaker 14:  it wants on Windows because the Microsoft stores there,
Speaker 14:  you know, there's a control of Windows. That's a way from exports. So if
Speaker 14:  they can break down those barriers somehow, like they're gonna have to,
Speaker 14:  if they want their gaming business to, to, to survive on Windows at least
Speaker 14:  anyway. 'cause Valve is doing some impressive stuff. And
Speaker 14:  I don't know, that's the, that's the biggest f threat I think to, to Microsoft's
Speaker 14:  gaming stuff rather than Sony
Speaker 2:  When Microsoft talks about its competitors, Phil Spencer and others, they
Speaker 2:  talk a lot about PlayStation and Nintendo. Yeah. But they don't talk a lot
Speaker 2:  about Valve. Like how much do you think Valve weighs on
Speaker 2:  Phil Spencer's mind as he considers The future of Xbox?
Speaker 14:  I think more so these days, although he probably wouldn't admit it, but
Speaker 14:  I, I I think you can just see like, obviously Steam Beck isn't doing huge
Speaker 14:  numbers right now, but it's starting that category of devices, but
Speaker 2:  It's like Beloved.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And it's beloved
Speaker 2:  Gamer like Capital G gamers, like love that thing. And I think, I feel like
Speaker 2:  if I'm Phil Spencer, the thing I've learned over the last decade is I have
Speaker 2:  to keep the capital G gamers happy.
Speaker 14:  Yes, exactly. Yeah. Like it is becoming, it's something that's had
Speaker 14:  promise for like 10 years and now it's like an actual reality. Like people
Speaker 14:  are actually playing these things. They're not just some random OEM
Speaker 14:  from somewhere. Like that's creating them. This has got the full backing
Speaker 14:  and, and Proton on Linux. That's the main, that's the key, right? It's getting
Speaker 14:  those games, like not emulated, but you know, like translated
Speaker 14:  onto Linux. So yeah, I I feel like if they can tie it all over
Speaker 14:  together internally at Microsoft, then they could pull something off like
Speaker 14:  the windows underneath and the exports on top. But there's licensing stuff.
Speaker 14:  Like they publish a say when they bring their game to exports. It's on a
Speaker 14:  console Right. Not on a pc.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  So there's a lot of stuff to like work through if they're ever gonna do
Speaker 14:  that. I dunno whether it ever realistically happen, but that would, I, I
Speaker 14:  still maintain that if they did pull it off somehow it would be
Speaker 14:  a killer device.
Speaker 2:  It does feel like this is a year where if everything goes
Speaker 2:  right, Microsoft's vision for this could come sort of to
Speaker 2:  fruition in really interesting new powerful ways. Right? Yeah. It has
Speaker 2:  Activision Blizzards, so it has this big new, I mean title in Call
Speaker 2:  of Duty, but also this big new pipe into mobile in a way that Phil Spencer
Speaker 2:  has been telling you for years is really important. With all the changes
Speaker 2:  coming to the app stores, Microsoft might have an in to be able to
Speaker 2:  do more stuff. The handheld thing could start to happen. Like it just feels
Speaker 2:  like if, if Microsoft's vision of kind of Xbox everywhere and being
Speaker 2:  this platform across all different screens
Speaker 2:  like it, it does seem like a lot of things would have to go right. But you
Speaker 2:  can sort of see how the pieces would start to fit together. Right.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, no you can And and, and you mentioned mobile and I think that's like,
Speaker 14:  that is a key one for them 'cause they're obviously gonna be publishing
Speaker 14:  a bunch of like Call of Duty mobiles. It's, it's huge. So we've tion B of
Speaker 14:  activation is a king Candy Crush. The all the rest, they get really big
Speaker 14:  entry point into mobile and they've obviously were trying to leverage that
Speaker 14:  to build a store on iOS and Android. But then obviously the Apple changes
Speaker 14:  and, and, and Phil mentioned, I I specifically pushed him on the, the Apple
Speaker 14:  changes for exports cloud gaming. 'cause I think that's, that's kind of
Speaker 14:  a precursor I I'd say to the, the mobile store because they've been trying
Speaker 14:  to get that app on there for, for years now and they've had to do a progressive
Speaker 14:  web app instead. And it's interesting that he said we can't
Speaker 14:  monetize exports cloud gaming even if they were to do an app.
Speaker 14:  So obviously whatever Apple's changes are under the hood, they're not good
Speaker 14:  enough for Microsoft. And it's also interesting that those changes and what
Speaker 14:  Apple's doing in iOS 17.4 by removing the PW
Speaker 14:  apps means that exports cloud gaming is basically just gonna, it's gonna
Speaker 14:  be a link now. It's not even gonna feel like a slightly native app. So
Speaker 14:  that puts him back a, a step back as well in the EU markets at least
Speaker 14:  anyway.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Apple's ability to claim it has opened up the app store
Speaker 2:  while seeming to not satisfy anyone who wants a more
Speaker 2:  open app store has been very impressive. Is he still
Speaker 2:  thinking about mobile as kind of the center of what's next
Speaker 2:  in the gaming ecosystem in the same way?
Speaker 14:  I feel like a few things have shifted, right? Because for mobile for Microsoft
Speaker 14:  that when they were thinking about it, it was more cloud right before a
Speaker 14:  BK ably King. But now the
Speaker 14:  cloud has slowed down and people aren't really as interested in it and
Speaker 14:  handhelds are emerging, right. As, as the kind of mobile now almost.
Speaker 14:  I feel like that's, that's shifted things a little bit. It's definitely
Speaker 14:  shifted our thinking. Like we thought that cloud would, you know, grow like
Speaker 14:  Microsoft did. And I think targeting mobile native games in iOS and Android
Speaker 14:  is, is still a ways off. Like they have, they have these big ones but they
Speaker 14:  still need to build a, a bunch of different games there. So I
Speaker 14:  don't know that it's necessarily changed. I think it's just definitely pushing
Speaker 14:  more towards the handhelds than, than Cloud to get to, to that sort of mobile
Speaker 14:  state or this idea of exports everywhere, you know.
Speaker 2:  Well and to that point, actually, one of the things you asked Phil that I
Speaker 2:  thought was a very funny way of asking the question was basically would you
Speaker 2:  rather continue to pursue the next Minecraft or the next PAL world or
Speaker 2:  the next version of these individual games? Not
Speaker 2:  gaming platforms but games that are sort of universes and platforms unto
Speaker 2:  themselves rather than trying to get more game past subscribers. And he said
Speaker 2:  he, he gave you a really wishy-washy answer, which is basically like, we'd
Speaker 2:  like both, which like of course, but it does seem like we
Speaker 2:  might be entering a phase where rather than I have access to,
Speaker 2:  you know, these 10 AAA games all in one place, we're kind of entering a place
Speaker 2:  where the AA game is the platform. Like that's
Speaker 2:  what Fortnite is becoming. That's Minecraft. Is that Roblox is that
Speaker 2:  maybe that's the next turn rather than I have a bunch of sort
Speaker 2:  of disparate games all available in the same app and Microsoft is gonna like,
Speaker 2:  all you have to do is look at the money and that's what it would tell you
Speaker 2:  to chase right now. Right.
Speaker 14:  I no, I agree. And I, I kind of posed a question to him is like, that's
Speaker 14:  my thinking that they'd rather have a, another Minecraft light or a Fortnight,
Speaker 14:  you know, like these are essentially social platforms that,
Speaker 14:  that teenagers hang out in. Right. Just to, to to chill with their friends.
Speaker 14:  So who wouldn't want that? And the, the amount of in-game revenue like that,
Speaker 14:  that's like a big chunk of the exports content and
Speaker 14:  services revenue, right, is for from, from all these in-game purchases.
Speaker 14:  So, so I'm sure they would love a massive hit like that and Powell World
Speaker 14:  was obviously a big one for them, having that just not
Speaker 14:  exclusive to exports, it's just the fact that Sony doesn't allow those early
Speaker 14:  access games on their platform. But having that available in exports is,
Speaker 14:  I feel like that's probably been pretty enlightening as well. So yeah, like
Speaker 14:  I feel like they, they would still prefer to have one of those big games
Speaker 14:  than, you know, another million game pass subscribers
Speaker 14:  or whatever. 'cause they, they'll probably get the games of pass subscribers
Speaker 14:  on the back of that anyway.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah, I mean, and I think what does seem to be true is that making
Speaker 2:  one of those that is a big hit is a lot harder and a lot more finicky than
Speaker 2:  it gets credit for. So he's probably right to kind of hedge his bets a little
Speaker 2:  bit there. but it certainly seems to be true that If, you can get
Speaker 2:  one of those handful of spaces online where people actually wanna be and
Speaker 2:  hang out and spend time. I mean you've, you've caught lightning in a bottle
Speaker 2:  and you should chase that kind of to the ends of the earth.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, it's, I think it's the thing that they're tracking internally as well.
Speaker 14:  It's like, it's the engagement right there that everyone tracks these days
Speaker 14:  as well. The time spent in a game, the time spent on the console rather
Speaker 14:  than we've sold X amount of consoles, which is,
Speaker 14:  is great, but it, that's a funnel win to your software and If, you don't
Speaker 14:  have the games to keep people sticky in, in there and they're going elsewhere
Speaker 14:  for, you know, whether it be Netflix or whatever for their entertainment
Speaker 14:  needs. It's keeping that sticky experience to, to keep people spending
Speaker 14:  and keep people playing and all that sort of stuff. So that's definitely
Speaker 14:  the, the way that they're looking at internally
Speaker 2:  Makes sense. So, okay, last thing and then I'm gonna let you go. The four
Speaker 2:  games that are coming from Xbox to other platforms, Microsoft has not announced,
Speaker 2:  but you know, because you're, you're, you're better at this than everybody
Speaker 2:  at Microsoft, sorry, everybody at Microsoft. What do you make of the
Speaker 2:  four games that Microsoft picked to do this with and then also
Speaker 2:  you asked Phil about Starfield and Indiana Jones kind of these bigger name
Speaker 2:  games, the sort of central franchises. Do you think we're gonna see those
Speaker 2:  at some point here in The future go down the same road? Yeah,
Speaker 14:  So like the, the four games are kind of interesting 'cause CF P's obviously
Speaker 14:  like it's a pirate game, which would be kind of funny to watch Exports
Speaker 14:  fanboy and PlayStation fanboy battling out in the sea, right.
Speaker 14:  Thinking each other and it's actually kind of perfect, virtually murdering
Speaker 14:  each other. So that, that's gonna be quite funny to witness. And I
Speaker 14:  think that one makes sense, right? It's a multiplayer game, live service
Speaker 14:  game. You do want those games across as many platforms as possible because
Speaker 14:  when, when the numbers dwindle then it doesn't make for such a
Speaker 14:  good game less people playing it. So that one makes sense. Similar sort
Speaker 14:  of thing for grounded as well, similar sort of multiplayer sort of experience
Speaker 14:  there and stuff. And then you've got like HiFi Rush, which I think is
Speaker 14:  probably one of the ones where it's like less obvious why it should go on
Speaker 14:  other platforms. But I think the way they kind of launched it, it was like
Speaker 14:  a shadow drop after an exports I think like developer direct that they had
Speaker 14:  and it didn't really have much fanfare, but it's like a great game. So like
Speaker 14:  one of the, I think Phil described it as like a hidden gem, which is true.
Speaker 14:  And then they want more people to experience that and it could, I guess
Speaker 14:  get people to think differently about exports games or exports as the platform,
Speaker 14:  like that sort of thing. Same, same kind of same thing with Penman as well.
Speaker 14:  They need to do one about app is that we should have known, knew it was
Speaker 14:  gonna go on Switch or PlayStation all the time because in Mike's
Speaker 14:  blog posts, when they first announced it, at the bottom of it they said
Speaker 14:  exports console launch exclusive. So AKA
Speaker 14:  is gonna go elsewhere. Like they, they had it there plain as day all along.
Speaker 14:  But yeah, like beyond that, these are the four that they're talking about
Speaker 14:  initially. But beyond that there are bigger questions around
Speaker 14:  Starfield. Obviously Indiana, Jones, other games, there's a
Speaker 14:  bit of a backlash as well with the exports fans at the moment about Starfield
Speaker 14:  and some of the reporting around it and Indiana, Jones, So, I just wanna
Speaker 14:  be super clear that Microsoft is considering both of those. It was
Speaker 14:  considering, it still is, considering it's not off the menu, it's not on
Speaker 14:  the menu, it's not been finally decided or anything like that. So those
Speaker 14:  still could come, but they might not, we don't know yet. It's not a finalized
Speaker 14:  decision like these four tiles are, but I think the, the important thing
Speaker 14:  is the fact that they were even considering it shows you what
Speaker 14:  their ambition is here, right? The talk of exports, every
Speaker 14:  screen's an exports, exports everywhere, all that sort of stuff. If, you
Speaker 14:  if If you add it all together, you can, you know, and you look at their
Speaker 14:  finely crafted messaging during that podcast, If, you read between the lines
Speaker 14:  and you look at very no bias or anything like that, you could pretty much
Speaker 14:  see what their strategy is, right? They, let's go slowly, surely
Speaker 14:  maybe some learnings, maybe we'll launch day and date, certain game
Speaker 14:  in The, future unannounced games, all that sort of stuff. Like they, they,
Speaker 14:  they're toying with all these sort of ideas. Nothing is final, but I think
Speaker 14:  it's, it does come down to the fact that they're, they're even thinking
Speaker 14:  about that stuff. That's the interesting part for me. I think that was the
Speaker 14:  bit when I heard that they were like thinking about some of these things
Speaker 14:  then, you know, it's a bigger strategy shift than the way they kind of
Speaker 14:  teased it out on Thursday.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And you get the sense that Microsoft is trying to do a huge
Speaker 2:  thing without anyone realizing how huge a thing it is, which
Speaker 2:  Microsoft has learned the hard way. When it makes giant noises about how
Speaker 2:  it's gonna change every industry forever, it goes badly. So this time they're,
Speaker 2:  it seems like they're trying to make just as big a change, but like
Speaker 2:  so quietly that nobody notices.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And then it gives them the the room to adjust as they go, right? Like
Speaker 14:  they, they, they could have some plans for certain games to come in
Speaker 14:  like the next six months. And the problem everyone also has to think about
Speaker 14:  is that this is gonna cost them money to port this, to, to do the work and,
Speaker 14:  and it's not something they just go, okay, we're gonna, we're gonna put
Speaker 14:  this game in here and then, you know, Monday they publish it. This, this
Speaker 14:  is planned months in advance. This is like a, a big project internally.
Speaker 14:  So it's not, it's not something they've just thought, oh we're gonna do
Speaker 14:  these four games. But yeah, it does, it does give them that freedom to sort
Speaker 14:  of tweak things as they go. Look at what the fans reception, look at the
Speaker 14:  sales numbers, all this sort of stuff. They'll have people pouring over
Speaker 14:  all this data with MATLAB for hours and hours I'm sure. But yeah,
Speaker 14:  like I think it still speaks to that there's something bigger going on
Speaker 14:  for sure.
Speaker 2:  All right, well I suspect it's gonna be a big year so we're gonna have to
Speaker 2:  check in a few times, but Tom, thank you as always. Appreciate it. Thanks
Speaker 14:  Simon.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to the Birch
Speaker 2:  Cast Hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always, the number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one. The email is Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We love all of your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show
Speaker 2:  every single week. We've been getting a lot about the Vision Pro and if I'm
Speaker 2:  being honest, I'm excited about the idea of talking about something other
Speaker 2:  than the Vision Pro. So If, you have questions about anything on Earth other
Speaker 2:  than the Vision Pro, please send them in 8 6 6 Verge one one
Speaker 2:  Vergecast to The Verge dot com. This week we have a question about passwords.
Speaker 17:  Hey Vergecast, my question is kind of simple. Do you think the recent slate
Speaker 17:  of crackdowns on Netflix, Hulu, et cetera, on
Speaker 17:  password sharing will achieve their goal of getting more paid
Speaker 17:  subscribers? Will people just throw their hands up and say it was fun while
Speaker 17:  it lasted? you know, like many families, friend groups and the like,
Speaker 17:  you know, mom and dad pay for Netflix and Max, I pay for
Speaker 17:  Hulu, Disney Plus and Amazon and we've had our little happy
Speaker 17:  Netflix Amazon sharing ecosystem. Now
Speaker 17:  that I can't access the Netflix account, I kind of refuse to get my own
Speaker 17:  partially out of spite and partially out of my budget,
Speaker 17:  genuinely not allowed for it. So I'm wondering, do you
Speaker 17:  think there'll be more people like me who say you know it and just
Speaker 17:  do without, or more people who will suck it up and you know, get their own
Speaker 17:  subscription. Who do you think is gonna blink first us as the services?
Speaker 17:  Thanks, hope to hear you guys answer this question on the show. Appreciate
Speaker 17:  what you do.
Speaker 2:  Of course we have a question about passwords and we have a question about
Speaker 2:  streaming. Who else? But Alex. Cranz. Alex. Welcome.
Speaker 18:  Hey.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so first of all, I wanna know, does your family have a, who pays for
Speaker 2:  what streaming arrangement? Because my family a hundred percent does and
Speaker 2:  I'm glad to know that others do too.
Speaker 18:  Yes. But it's really just, I pay for everything and then my mom, when she
Speaker 18:  wants to watch things or my sister, they like text me and they're like,
Speaker 18:  can I have your password?
Speaker 2:  So it's just everyone mooches off of you.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, they're just all mooches. But I guess it's like reciprocal. I mooched
Speaker 18:  off my mom for, you know, 18 years. So
Speaker 2:  That's fair. This is your way of paying them back. That's beautiful. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So what do you think, I realize I have a pretty strong opinion here that
Speaker 2:  I can't base on anything, but I'm curious what you think. Well,
Speaker 18:  The data suggests that consumers blink
Speaker 18:  first. That we blink before the companies do, right? Like Netflix has
Speaker 18:  been successful with their password sharing crackdown so far, which is like
Speaker 18:  a major bummer because I really want them to blink first. But now
Speaker 18:  that Hulu's doing it, now that Disney Plus is doing it, we're we're getting
Speaker 18:  more more people in on it. At some point that's gonna stop, right?
Speaker 18:  At some point people really are gonna stop saying, no, I just don't need
Speaker 18:  this product. And Netflix has been like really successful because it's
Speaker 18:  Netflix, right? Hulu might not be as successful. even that
Speaker 18:  everyone should go watch Fargo. It's great. you know, a lot of people will
Speaker 18:  be like, I don't need to watch Fargo or whatever new FX show is
Speaker 18:  on, I'll need to watch Bluey. That's that's the Disney plus
Speaker 18:  one, right? Yeah. Like that may happen, in which case, yeah,
Speaker 18:  suck it streamers stop trying to like crack down on all of us. Just
Speaker 18:  let us do what we want. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's basically where I land too. I think. It seems to me that it's clearly
Speaker 2:  going to work from a technological perspective. Like I, I think when the,
Speaker 2:  when Netflix started doing this, everybody's like, oh this will be easy to
Speaker 2:  get around. Like spoiler alert, super not easy to get around. They have more
Speaker 2:  or less done the thing they set out to do. And from that
Speaker 2:  perspective, it's clearly gonna work and anyone who wants to
Speaker 2:  lock people out is going to lock people out. They're getting very good at
Speaker 2:  this, it's very sophisticated, it's just gonna work. I do think that if you're
Speaker 2:  a streaming service, the very last thing you want to do is give people
Speaker 2:  a reason to say, do I actually watch anything on here? Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  like to your point, right, there are streaming services that I pay for. Like
Speaker 2:  for me, weirdly enough, it's actually Disney Plus I don't use Disney plus
Speaker 2:  that often. I don't really know why. Like I like all the stuff that's on
Speaker 2:  there. It's just not, when I sit down to watch something, it's probably the
Speaker 2:  fourth app I open. And so for me, the minute
Speaker 2:  it becomes sort of in my face whether I want to keep paying for Disney
Speaker 2:  plus, I'm probably gonna say no. And I think what's about to happen to a
Speaker 2:  lot of people is it is going to be put in their face. Do you still want to
Speaker 2:  pay for this? And I think you're right that the answer for most people for
Speaker 2:  Netflix is yes, right? Like I, I watch an alarming amount of Netflix.
Speaker 2:  Most of it is not stuff I couldn't live without. There are very few things
Speaker 2:  on Netflix that feel like core to my personality and life,
Speaker 2:  but it's just where I go to watch stuff. And that's pretty powerful. And
Speaker 2:  also only Netflix gets to be that thing. And so for me, I feel like
Speaker 2:  Disney Plus can probably get away with it just because it has some of that
Speaker 2:  same like core content to some people. But like Hulu is
Speaker 2:  actually probably a good example. Like how much stuff is there on Hulu that
Speaker 2:  if Hulu suddenly went away from your life, you would be like devastated without,
Speaker 18:  I really liked Fargo
Speaker 2:  Fargo is really good. I'll give you that
Speaker 18:  Look, the new season was excellent, but it it, I I agree. Yeah. Like
Speaker 18:  Hulu is is one I probably I i I might churn on, right? I might, I
Speaker 18:  might subscribe when I need it and, and unsubscribe when I don't.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. My, my big Galaxy brain take is that it is both
Speaker 2:  going to work and it is also going to like speed
Speaker 2:  up this crazy consolidation that is happening in this industry right
Speaker 2:  now where having the account is going to be the way that you
Speaker 2:  win, right? Like having a login that I have, which for lots of people,
Speaker 2:  they're not going to have a login anymore and they're gonna have to make
Speaker 2:  a new one. And making people make a new login is hard and you lose a lot
Speaker 2:  of people when you make people do it. And So I think it's gonna take all
Speaker 2:  of these like not quite Netflix streaming services and it's gonna
Speaker 2:  make their lives much harder in service of
Speaker 2:  trying to get more people. So I think it's, it's gonna consolidate.
Speaker 18:  That's why they're doing that thing where they're, where they're bundling,
Speaker 18:  right? Like true. That's why Paramount Plus you can get that now through
Speaker 18:  Amazon. 'cause they acknowledge that most people only want that for either
Speaker 18:  their Taylor Sheridan or their Star Trek fix or to watch the Super Bowl
Speaker 18:  poorly. Like so So I think they, they, they kind
Speaker 18:  of recognize what's gonna happen and a lot of them have made peace with
Speaker 18:  it and, and Netflix can get away with it. Netflix has shown it works for
Speaker 18:  Netflix, so Netflix is gonna keep doing it and it'll be fine
Speaker 18:  until one day you say, ah, do I need to watch that many K dramas? Maybe
Speaker 18:  I can watch something else on another channel and be done.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. We're definitely in a phase where Netflix kind of continues
Speaker 2:  to flex on everybody and everybody is trying to do a Netflix impression and
Speaker 2:  it seems less and less likely that it's gonna work for a lot of these companies.
Speaker 18:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right, well we'll see. In the meantime, we still should have been angrier
Speaker 2:  about this the whole time and I am angry about it now and we will continue
Speaker 2:  to be angry about it.
Speaker 18:  Just find a great website where you can download a file and
Speaker 18:  then you put that on a software program and it, it, it stuff
Speaker 18:  happens. I don't wanna get too into it, but you, you can work around it
Speaker 2:  At the end of this Alex's Plex server will be the only streaming service
Speaker 2:  left and it will be great. Just
Speaker 18:  Pay me money. Don't actually pay me money. I nobody, please don't come and
Speaker 18:  shut me down. I do not share it with people for money that's wrong and
Speaker 18:  immoral.
Speaker 2:  Well, we're all going to jail, but thank you Alex, appreciate it. You're
Speaker 18:  Welcome.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who was on
Speaker 2:  the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about at The Verge dot com, lots of right to Repair coverage, lots
Speaker 2:  of Tom's stuff, especially his interview with Phil Spencer, which you should
Speaker 2:  read. All of it's really interesting. We'll put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 2:  but you know, The Verge dot com, it's a website be like it. As always, If
Speaker 2:  you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other games you'd like to see
Speaker 2:  ported to new platforms. You can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8 6 6 Verge one, one. Hearing from
Speaker 2:  you is my absolute favorite thing about doing this show, so keep 'em coming.
Speaker 2:  This show's produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and Will pour The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network, NELI Alex
Speaker 2:  and I'll be back on Friday to talk about more AI news, mobile World Congress
Speaker 2:  and a whole bunch of other stuff. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.