# Transcript
ID: 68947a2f-8145-45df-b01d-67a2a338e470
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3393552290628264372/7456654366887083626/s93290-US-4467s-1722936131.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of what the future of Kindle turns out to be:
We’re once again trying out a couple of our favorite new show formats.
In Version History, we talk through the whole story of Quibi, from its early days as NewTV to its extremely ill-timed launch to its ultimate demise.
From Variety: Quibi Has Raised $1.75B After Closing $750M Round to Fund Launch
From Variety: Jeffrey Katzenberg’s NewTV Closes $1B, Major Studios Among Investors
Quibi’s CES 2020 launch
Quibi app review: short-form streaming in a shifting landscape
Steven Spielberg is writing a horror series you’ll only be able to at night
Quibi’s Super Bowl 2020 commercial
From The Wall Street Journal: Jeffrey Katzenberg and Meg Whitman Struggle With Their Startup—and Each Other
How Quibi imploded less than six months after launch
11 reasons why Quibi crashed and burned in less than a year
Next, we try out our as-yet-untitled debate show. The Verge’s Kevin Nguyen and Alex Cranz take on a surprisingly contentious topic: is the future of books print or digital?
The Boox Palma is an amazing gadget I didn’t even know I wanted
Kobo’s great color e-readers are held back by lock-in
From The Wall Street Journal: How the Kindle Became a Must-Have Accessory (Again)
The Playdate makes a surprisingly good e-reader
Later, producer Andru Marino answers a question from The Vergecast Hotline about a very unusual shopping situation for MP3 players.
NW-E394 Walkman Digital Music Player
Mighty’s ‘iPod shuffle for Spotify’ gets upgraded battery and Bluetooth
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (21 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of whatever the future of
Speaker 2:  the Kindle turns out to be. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am still
Speaker 2:  on vacation. This is the second week that I am out right now. If
Speaker 2:  you're hearing this on Tuesday, I am probably at,
Speaker 2:  with my parents in upstate Connecticut, just hanging out.
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm probably on an inner tube in a lake as everyone should be at some
Speaker 2:  point this summer. Anyway, while I'm gone, we've been doing this
Speaker 2:  little mini pilot season. I hope you enjoyed. Last week we talked about Roku
Speaker 2:  and we talked about car play, trying out some new formats and structures
Speaker 2:  for the show, and we're gonna do something similar today. We have two more
Speaker 2:  versions of those same shows. We figured instead of just doing one pilot,
Speaker 2:  we'd try it twice. We'd get to learn a lot about how it went. Maybe we'd
Speaker 2:  be better at it the second time. Maybe you'd be more familiar. We'd love
Speaker 2:  to hear your thoughts. We're gonna try it again. This time we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about Roku and we're gonna talk about eBooks, both super fun, very
Speaker 2:  excited for you to hear them both. And as I mentioned before, we really,
Speaker 2:  really want to hear your feedback. I wanna know everything you think about
Speaker 2:  these formats, about these shows, about whether you'd like to hear more of
Speaker 2:  them, about whether you hope we never, ever do them again. All of it. We've
Speaker 2:  been experimenting with this stuff. We always like trying new formats and
Speaker 2:  new ideas, but we also love what this show is, and we don't want to
Speaker 2:  change it just for the sake of changing it. So tell us everything you think
Speaker 2:  about the show, about the formats, about the stuff that we're covering in
Speaker 2:  particular, if you have ideas for what you wanna see us do on either of those
Speaker 2:  shows and segments, please let us know. Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call
Speaker 2:  the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one, one. We wanna hear everything. Alright,
Speaker 2:  two more pilots. Let's go. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  to do that with tech. There's so many old gadgets and so many old apps and
Speaker 2:  so many interesting stories baked into these sort of moments in
Speaker 2:  tech history. And we've been trying to figure out what is a fun way to go
Speaker 2:  back through a lot of that stuff. Talk about where we were, how we got to
Speaker 2:  where we are now, what still matters, the legacy of all these things and
Speaker 2:  all of that. So we kind of cobbled together a show based
Speaker 2:  on all of the different stuff that we liked from all the other rewatch podcasts.
Speaker 2:  And like I said, we've been calling it version history. Last week we talked
Speaker 2:  about the Roku Netflix player, which was very fun. And this week we are talking
Speaker 2:  about, I would say, a Wilder story
Speaker 2:  that either is more important or less important to the world, depending on
Speaker 2:  how you look at it. That's right. It's time to talk about Quibi
Speaker 6:  Big stories told in six to 10 minute episodes, or
Speaker 6:  Quibi
Speaker 2:  Neela Patel. Hello. Hello. Alex Krantz. Hello.
Speaker 5:  How do y'all coming
Speaker 2:  Off the smashing success of our first version
Speaker 2:  history pilot last week? I don't know, people might have hated it. I'm on
Speaker 2:  vacation. We'll figure it out when I get back. We're, we're gonna do this
Speaker 2:  again this time with what I would say is everyone's favorite streaming service
Speaker 2:  of all time. It's called Quibi. And again, just quick reminder, the, the
Speaker 2:  way that we're structuring this, we're gonna do kind of a brief history lesson.
Speaker 2:  This one's gonna be fun because it's very recent and we all were journalists
Speaker 2:  through the whole run of this. So I think we, we all covered this in different
Speaker 2:  ways. Then we're gonna talk about reviews and how it was perceived in both
Speaker 2:  as a, as a product and a cultural thing. And then we have some questions
Speaker 2:  we're gonna answer about like, what it was and its legacy in the future.
Speaker 2:  And then at the end, we're gonna decide if it belongs in the version History
Speaker 2:  Hall of Fame, all of the prerequisites for which we have not yet
Speaker 2:  decided. It's gonna be great. Alex, I feel like you should
Speaker 2:  do the Quibi history. This is near and dear to your heart in a way that I
Speaker 2:  find very mysterious and strange. It's true. So can you tell us the story
Speaker 2:  of Quibi as we go here? I
Speaker 5:  Can. I can. Because once upon a time, there was a man named Jeffrey Katzenberg,
Speaker 5:  and, and he was one of the most powerful men in Hollywood. He, he still
Speaker 5:  is in 20 24, 1 of the most powerful men in Hollywood,
Speaker 5:  creator of Dreamworks, which was major studio. And, and he
Speaker 5:  wanted to get in on streaming because at this point, this is
Speaker 5:  2018, we know that NBC's got something in the works. We know
Speaker 5:  Disney's got something in the works. We know HBO Warner Brothers at
Speaker 5:  t whatever that mess is, is planning something,
Speaker 5:  Apple's planning something, everybody is planning a streaming service. And,
Speaker 5:  and, and Jeff is like, yeah, I wanna do that too. But he, he knows
Speaker 5:  that it can't just be any streaming service. He knows that he, he needs to
Speaker 5:  do something different to complete with Netflix, and it's not just make good
Speaker 5:  content. So he, he, he thinks of something, he calls it new
Speaker 5:  tv originally back in 2018, probably a significantly
Speaker 5:  better name than Quibi. He goes, he gets a lot of funding. He
Speaker 5:  raises over a billion dollars, $1.75 billion
Speaker 5:  just pulling in the money. He starts picking a bad inventory. I mean, he's
Speaker 5:  really, he's doing good things, but he still has to make a product and
Speaker 5:  release a product.
Speaker 7:  Can I, can I tell a story about this time? Yes, please. So I went to
Speaker 7:  a fancy, like dinner at a code conference
Speaker 7:  around this time, and I was sitting in just the most unusual group of people.
Speaker 7:  It was like the founder of Soylent, another guy, me
Speaker 7:  and Katz. And Katz was like, I'm thinking about this thing. And
Speaker 7:  he explained what would be become, and I will tell you my reaction was like,
Speaker 7:  oh no.
Speaker 7:  And I think I might've said, you know, YouTube exists, continue on.
Speaker 5:  It's true.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. YouTube exists is a useful frame for all of what's about to come.
Speaker 5:  But, but you know, YouTube was made by the tech people and, and what what
Speaker 5:  Jeff wanted to do was make something for the rest of, for like Hollywood,
Speaker 5:  right? Like that was his big deal was he knew Hollywood in a way that Netflix
Speaker 5:  and YouTube and everybody else didn't. And so he goes and he gets someone
Speaker 5:  who also knows Hollywood, famous Hollywood
Speaker 5:  exec. Sure. Right? Meg Whitman. Everybody knows her as a Hollywood
Speaker 5:  exec, right?
Speaker 7:  That's HP and eBay. Really two hollywoody companies.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  If I had to name too,
Speaker 5:  He goes and gets Meg largely because he does need someone in tech. He needs
Speaker 5:  somebody who understands tech. So he goes and he gets Meg and he is like,
Speaker 5:  do you wanna be my my CEO with me? We'll do it together. And she's
Speaker 5:  like, hell yes. And I wanna be a fly on the wall in that particular coffee
Speaker 5:  meeting. Right? Like that, that, that's a dream of mine. Jeff Meg called
Speaker 5:  me with the recordings. I I wanna listen to 'em. Anyway, so they come
Speaker 5:  together and they, they decide to release this product. And then we all,
Speaker 5:  we're all at CES in 2020 and we know this is coming. We know it's
Speaker 5:  called Quibi. We know they are spending a ton, like a billion
Speaker 5:  dollars on content. And they've got, they've got what
Speaker 5:  Steven Spielberg, they've got Catherine
Speaker 5:  Hardwick, they've got all these big actors and actresses. Everybody's
Speaker 5:  working on Quibi stuff. And there's, there's some, there's some energy around
Speaker 5:  it. I'm just gonna use the word energy because I don't think any adjective
Speaker 5:  can describe it.
Speaker 7:  Wait, can I also color in the energy for you? Yes. So
Speaker 7:  before the CS unveil, which I know Alex will talk about, they had
Speaker 7:  briefings. Hollywood, like a normal company comes to version, like, we'd
Speaker 7:  like to tell you about our product on our embargo. So You can write about
Speaker 7:  it. And we're like, great, here's one reporter. They demanded everyone.
Speaker 7:  They're like, all of you come Seriously, like Casey Newton, who was
Speaker 7:  writing the interface about platform democracy, democracy
Speaker 7:  was like, I'm going to the Quibi briefing. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  why? And he was like, I'm just excited to see someone
Speaker 7:  talk about building a platform with this much ambition and this much money.
Speaker 7:  And I, he, I will never forget, he came out of the briefing and he was like,
Speaker 7:  the only thing I got was that they are spending more per minute of video
Speaker 7:  by like a thousand than any other platform it's ever thought of.
Speaker 7:  They're like, here's what you do. You open this app and you watch video on
Speaker 7:  YouTube. They get the videos for free from other people. No, no, no. That's
Speaker 7:  not what we're doing. We've taken the fanciest directors from Hollywood and
Speaker 7:  paid the millions of dollars per minute of video. And I was like, that and
Speaker 7:  how are you gonna on it? And they're like, ads. And they're like the same
Speaker 7:  ads and they're like, yes.
Speaker 5:  It was a beautiful moment. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They very proudly talked about how they were spending Game of Thrones level
Speaker 2:  money on like, everything that they were doing. And it's like, well, no,
Speaker 2:  you, there's a reason. It's Game of Thrones.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And
Speaker 2:  You're making one about like haunted house flippers at Game of Throne Throne's
Speaker 7:  Budgets. Oh my God. It was very good. It, the whole thing was incredible.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But that was before cs, like before C they were getting the feedback
Speaker 7:  before CS we're like, so the dollars in are big and then the
Speaker 7:  dollars out are small. What's your plan? And they'd be like, quality.
Speaker 5:  And, and I kind of, it makes sense. We'll get into it, but it makes sense.
Speaker 5:  Right? YouTube is, is basically cable access tv and
Speaker 5:  they're like, what if we put actual, not like actual
Speaker 5:  producers and people who know how to make entertainment on this instead of
Speaker 5:  everybody just experimenting. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Certainly a thing. Maybe 10 years too late. Anyway, so,
Speaker 5:  so they decided to announce Quibi. They, they have this big event at
Speaker 5:  CESI know. We, we all got invited. We all went and did the briefings. I sat
Speaker 5:  there with Meg Whitman, had a a, a document in front of her with my name
Speaker 5:  on it, my photo, and a whole bunch of information about me.
Speaker 5:  And she just, because I guess they get that right, like their CEO, it's a
Speaker 5:  normal way. They get prepped and she just power move, just left it sitting
Speaker 5:  right between us. So I could see it. Oh my God, that's
Speaker 7:  So good. Good. Jeffrey
Speaker 5:  Katzenberg, just pacing in the room.
Speaker 7:  You were at GIZ then?
Speaker 5:  I was at GIZ and, and came out and, and we had the one
Speaker 5:  briefing with, with Jeff and, and Meg. And then we had another briefing with
Speaker 5:  the CTO and the CPO, the chief product Officer and the Chief Technology
Speaker 5:  officer. And one meeting with like a bunch of the actors and
Speaker 5:  filmmakers. Yeah. And Catherine Hardrick was like, I just wanna like, take
Speaker 5:  control of people's phones so they can see everything I make. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, yeah, me too. I didn't say that, but I thought it real hard.
Speaker 7:  We also did this gauntlet. I did it with Ashley Carmen and
Speaker 7:  we rewrote our entire, like we had, we thought there was a story
Speaker 7:  and we had been like working on it. 'cause we'd already had these briefings
Speaker 7:  and we threw the whole thing out after we met with Katzenberg, we were like,
Speaker 7:  we gotta start over. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You just know at that moment it was gonna be a bomb.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I, I don't You can read that story. Yeah. Yes. That the
Speaker 7:  answer is yes, we, but like, it was also just the man
Speaker 7:  is very charming. Yes.
Speaker 5:  He was terrifying and, and quiet in my interview with him.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. With, with us. It was a full, I've, I've
Speaker 7:  encountered Katzenberg several times. I actually just did an event
Speaker 7:  about digital, like digital parenting at one of the companies he's invested
Speaker 7:  in and he was there. Yeah. And you know, he's, he's very charming,
Speaker 7:  but this was like full sales pitch katzenberg and you
Speaker 7:  were like, this man thinks his energy can
Speaker 7:  overcome reality. It was just like one of the most that we, we just started
Speaker 7:  our whole story over we're like this whole, that actual technology
Speaker 7:  has nothing to do with this product. He,
Speaker 5:  He, he, he definitely approached it differently with the Gizmoto crew.
Speaker 2:  I mean, and You can argue that the thesis of his energy can overcome reality
Speaker 2:  is the whole thesis of Quibi. Yeah. Basically. Like, this
Speaker 2:  thing is probably too late. It's very
Speaker 2:  specific. It's doing kind of a weird thing that seems to be running against
Speaker 2:  everything the culture is doing, but Jeffrey Katzenberg. Yeah. Like that
Speaker 2:  was how this thing was covered at the beginning. Right. It was like Jeffrey
Speaker 2:  Katzenberg doesn't screw up. He will, he will do it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Don't bet. Against Jeffrey. Yeah. Was the Yeah. Over and over and over.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Everybody assumed he was gonna do it and, and they bring it
Speaker 5:  out and they knew they, it was clear that they knew content alone
Speaker 5:  wasn't gonna win this. Right. They knew we're late to this. We have a lot
Speaker 5:  of content, but that alone isn't gonna win it because eventually there'd
Speaker 5:  be the show about the lady with a golden arm. And that was a terrible show
Speaker 5:  anyway, by the
Speaker 7:  Way. Our headline was Quibi versus the World. That's where we, we came out,
Speaker 7:  we were like, okay, this is actually what we're hearing.
Speaker 5:  They did one thing, their, their big thing, the big technological innovation
Speaker 5:  here was that it would basically deliver two streams at the same time
Speaker 5:  and you'd see, and you'd see a stream depending on how you turned your phone.
Speaker 5:  So you'd either see it in, in profile or you'd see it in landscape. Those
Speaker 5:  are the only two ways to watch it. and it would change depending on it. And
Speaker 5:  some of the filmmakers were really, really excited about this. Other filmmakers
Speaker 5:  gave two shits and didn't do anything with the format, but most of
Speaker 5:  them did do it. And, and it was like, I wanna say kind of impressive
Speaker 5:  technology. The technology itself was impressive. Then they
Speaker 5:  finally launched it during COV when everyone was at their
Speaker 5:  home.
Speaker 7:  Can I just remind everyone that the, the, the rotate your phone technology
Speaker 5:  Turntable or what, what was
Speaker 2:  It called? Turnstile.
Speaker 7:  It was called Turnstile with a y. Yep. Like wild style
Speaker 7:  from the Lego.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But wait, but Butrans, you just glossed over a thing that's
Speaker 2:  very important. So CES 2020 happens.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Quibi launches April 6th, 2020. Between those two things,
Speaker 2:  what relatively important world event would you say happened?
Speaker 2:  Somewhere right in the middle? TikTok
Speaker 7:  Launch. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Birds of Prey. The movie came out and it was really,
Speaker 5:  really good. But also, yeah, COVID, which
Speaker 5:  probably a lot of us interacted with at that CES then
Speaker 5:  started interacting with a whole lot of other people. And, and we had a worldwide
Speaker 5:  pandemic. And this device, you know, Quibi was made to be
Speaker 5:  for you on the go. It was the whole pitch was, yeah, you watch a little bit
Speaker 5:  on your way to work, you watch a little bit on your lunch break while you're
Speaker 5:  at work. You watch a little bit on the train, on the way home from work.
Speaker 5:  The assumption is that you would be doing a lot of traveling in that time
Speaker 5:  to and from places that didn't happen because we were
Speaker 5:  all at home because of lockdown, because of Covid. And this
Speaker 5:  product, which was already late, was charging 4 99 with ads
Speaker 5:  7 99 without, unless you were a T-Mobile customer, in which
Speaker 5:  case you got it for free for a brief period
Speaker 5:  of time, but you had to be a T-Mobile customer. That's a choice
Speaker 5:  You can make.
Speaker 7:  It is.
Speaker 5:  And it was just like the minute it launched, he was like, well no, this isn't
Speaker 5:  gonna succeed. The whole reason this exists
Speaker 7:  Katz's argument was that everyone was at home and he'd made a product for
Speaker 7:  watching on the train.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so then he scrambled, he panicked and was like, well, we need to
Speaker 5:  now release some sort of like, for the TV version
Speaker 5:  of this app that is very dependent on your phone and how you
Speaker 5:  rotate your phone to get the scenes. And that was a real challenge. And
Speaker 5:  then he was doing some really wild stuff to get people in
Speaker 5:  the office and get people working on it and thinking about it at Quibi itself.
Speaker 5:  Do y'all remember that?
Speaker 7:  No. What was going on? They
Speaker 5:  Were just really trying to entice people into work. And, and, and he was
Speaker 5:  as, as, as Neli said, like he was really just using the force of being Jeffrey
Speaker 5:  Katzenberg to get people to try to make this succeed. He was like, no,
Speaker 5:  everything is totally fine. Yeah. We're just going through a little blip.
Speaker 5:  It'll be okay. We just need to keep going. We've got all this content. We're
Speaker 5:  working on an app that we're gonna release so that people can watch it in
Speaker 5:  their homes. It's gonna be fine. It's gonna be fine. It
Speaker 5:  wasn't fine. Spoiler
Speaker 7:  Alert. Not fine. Wait, real quick. The, the one I think
Speaker 7:  important piece of Quibi history that you missed so far, Kran? Yes. Is the
Speaker 7:  Super Bowl commercial. This is just like, not even in my brain. Can I play
Speaker 7:  you the entirety of the Super Bowl commercial right now? Yes. I would like
Speaker 7:  to play it for you.
Speaker 9:  Where's the car? Like where are you? I'll be there in a Quibi.
Speaker 9:  Good. A Quibi less than 10 minutes.
Speaker 9:  Next. Daddy got pun. Thanks Daddy. Got pun.
Speaker 9:  Quick bites, big stories. Quibi.
Speaker 7:  That's it. That's the whole Super Bowl commercial. Nowhere in there does
Speaker 7:  it say we made a streaming surface. Nowhere in it does it say, here is what
Speaker 7:  we're doing. But you do learn that a Quibi is a quick bite and a quick
Speaker 7:  bite is less than 10 minutes. And that is apparently very important.
Speaker 7:  That was a Super Bowl commercial. What a time. I
Speaker 7:  made the joke about TikTok earlier. But it is also true
Speaker 7:  that the thing that happened in the pandemic was people just started opening
Speaker 7:  TikTok all day. Yes. All night. Because it was free. You
Speaker 7:  got quick bursts of content. You could just scroll right on by
Speaker 7:  A lot of the ideas that were in Quibi that like led to Quibi were
Speaker 7:  right there in TikTok. They're the same ideas. People are gonna watch video
Speaker 7:  on their phone. We should make it super easy. The videos should ideally be
Speaker 7:  as short as possible.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The difference is Quibi was paying the people,
Speaker 7:  I dug up the quote, I have it from just Jeffrey. Katzenberg. Yeah. They're
Speaker 7:  making content at a hundred dollars a minute. We are making content at a
Speaker 7:  hundred thousand dollars a minute. And he says that like
Speaker 2:  It's a, it's a,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This was his winning argument in our briefing.
Speaker 5:  The reaction in Hollywood to this was really, really weird at that time because
Speaker 5:  a lot of the filmmakers and stuff felt that this was him trying to get around
Speaker 5:  by breaking up the films and all the footage into these short bites. Get
Speaker 5:  around paying the actual rates.
Speaker 7:  Right. Get around the union fees. Oh, and then, and then he's like, I'm spending
Speaker 7:  literally $10,000 more than, or like a hundred thousand dollars more
Speaker 7:  than everybody else. Weird. Just weird, weird time. So the, I'm just saying
Speaker 7:  the money in money Out was like a real,
Speaker 5:  The the, the way that Quibi ended is still like the part that really gets
Speaker 5:  me because he announces that like Yeah, they're about to be layoffs.
Speaker 5:  Tells the employees, did they play a song from the movie
Speaker 5:  Trolls? Yes. Called Get Back Up Again. And he's like,
Speaker 5:  this will make you all feel better.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God. and it and it did.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And now Quibi is the largest streaming service in America.
Speaker 7:  Thank you. Trolls.
Speaker 7:  No, I just wanna, I, before we get to the actual end, the part where
Speaker 7:  their technical ideas and their user interface and
Speaker 7:  user behavior ideas were correct is actually stunning. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They were right about, people are gonna watch a lot of video on their phones
Speaker 7:  and we should make it shorter and more vertical. And
Speaker 7:  maybe they needed to trick Hollywood into making vertical video by doing
Speaker 7:  turnstile. But like, they were correct about what was about to happen to
Speaker 7:  video on phones. Yes. They were absolutely wrong about the
Speaker 7:  mathematics of those videos. Yes. And who should make them and why people
Speaker 7:  would watch them and all of that stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Wait, can I just quickly read you a line from, so Chris Welch reviewed
Speaker 2:  the app for us when it first came out and here's just a, a line from it that
Speaker 2:  really jumped out to me. He says, opening Quibi starts you off in the for
Speaker 2:  You tab, which uses a vertical card interface. It feels more Instagram and
Speaker 2:  less Netflix carousel. You'll see a show's title metadata And. if you stay
Speaker 2:  on one card for a few seconds, video begins Autoplaying. Yeah. That's just,
Speaker 2:  it's just TikTok. Yeah. Like it's, it's, it really is kind of amazing
Speaker 2:  how
Speaker 7:  To be clear. TikTok was out and you know, and it's Tom Conrad
Speaker 7:  was our CTO, he's a smart dude.
Speaker 2:  And also like Snap had done a lot of this stuff. So like the idea that vertical
Speaker 2:  video that auto played was gonna be a thing was like, not surprising, but
Speaker 2:  to its credit. Quibi was like, yeah, this is, this is
Speaker 2:  the thing. We're not gonna like go 90 it and tell everybody that the solution
Speaker 2:  is to flip your phone over. Like,
Speaker 7:  Except they did like they did it. They they did it. They did a
Speaker 2:  Little bit. They did
Speaker 7:  Do that. They
Speaker 2:  Did say that. They did do that a little.
Speaker 7:  They have a patent Unturn style, which is just the funniest, but like,
Speaker 7:  I just want to it, I mean I've dunked on Quibi more than anybody has ever
Speaker 7:  dunked on Quibi. But the thing for a bunch of Hollywood
Speaker 7:  executives and Meg Whitman to like correctly identify
Speaker 7:  how entertainment would change because of like product
Speaker 7:  changes was what? Like they nailed it and then they
Speaker 7:  got completely blown up by not only pandemic, but their own sense
Speaker 7:  that they could literally increase cost by a thousand
Speaker 7:  and then somehow make it up on the backend, which no one can do.
Speaker 5:  To be fair, that's what all of the streaming services were doing at that
Speaker 5:  time, right? Like everybody was investing a ton
Speaker 5:  of money into, to making their own services. So Quibi was doing the exact
Speaker 5:  same thing as everybody else. How
Speaker 7:  Did it work out for all?
Speaker 5:  It worked out terribly.
Speaker 5:  The, the only difference is they were part of biggest, like everybody else
Speaker 5:  was es established studio. This wasn't like Dreamworks thing, this was
Speaker 5:  Katzenberg was like, I'm gonna go make my own new company to be at the start
Speaker 5:  of something new and I'll get everybody else involved. And then the pandemic
Speaker 5:  just cut 'em off at the knees. Like, I genuinely think
Speaker 5:  if it had come out in a different time, it would've lasted at least
Speaker 5:  six months longer.
Speaker 7:  Well, okay, so big bet from
Speaker 5:  Crz. There we go. Six
Speaker 7:  Extra months.
Speaker 2:  This is one of the, the big questions I want to, I was gonna get to, but
Speaker 2:  let's just do this now. Yeah. The, is there an alternate timeline in which
Speaker 2:  this thing was more successful? Feels like the question
Speaker 2:  of Quibi, right? Because when Quibi died, Katzenberg just a hundred percent
Speaker 2:  blamed the pandemic. Yes. Right. He's like, this would've worked except for
Speaker 2:  the pandemic.
Speaker 7:  Just, and I just wanna call out. He ended it in maybe the most noble
Speaker 7:  way of ending a thing. Oh, totally. That has raised us. He just gave the
Speaker 7:  money back to shareholders. Yeah. She was like, I'm not burning the rest
Speaker 7:  of your money. This isn't gonna happen. Here's your money back. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  there's that. But he did fully blame the pandemic. I do feel like opening
Speaker 7:  the multiverse door around Covid is,
Speaker 7:  is just a rough, a rough game to play.
Speaker 2:  Fair.
Speaker 7:  Many different decisions could have been made during that time.
Speaker 2:  Yes. But this is the unusual thing that literally lived and died entirely
Speaker 2:  inside of the pandemic, right? Like, it's not just that it's fortune changed,
Speaker 2:  it's that it's, its entire story is actually a pandemic story. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So I, I'll just go back to what leaving the door closed.
Speaker 7:  YouTube existed, TikTok existed. The game that they were
Speaker 7:  trying to play had already been won by services
Speaker 7:  that, you know, You can have a lot. I have a lot of feelings about the fact
Speaker 7:  that these services do not pay very high rates. I think a lot of people in
Speaker 7:  Hollywood have a lot of feelings about the fact that these services do not
Speaker 7:  pay very high rates to their creators. Ka are trying to being like, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna pay much higher rates and then figure out how to get people to pay
Speaker 7:  for quality. Very noble. I think no matter what,
Speaker 7:  maybe you get six more months. Like Kranz is saying, they would've run up
Speaker 7:  against the fact that YouTube exists. And YouTube is fundamentally what all
Speaker 7:  these these companies are competing with. And to some extent TikTok is,
Speaker 7:  would TikTok have, has grown as quickly minus the pandemic
Speaker 7:  is the multiverse door that is just like hard to figure out,
Speaker 7:  but hey, there's an app on your phone that's free full of infinite content
Speaker 7:  versus, Hey, there's an app on your phone you have to pay for that's full
Speaker 7:  of some content is at the end of the day, it's just like really hard to win
Speaker 7:  that game.
Speaker 2:  Right? And I think even, even then there was an understanding that they were
Speaker 2:  competing against infinite content, but the belief was that like we, we can
Speaker 2:  do it better and better will win. And crans, I feel like the thing that we've
Speaker 2:  learned a million times over now is that better doesn't actually always win.
Speaker 2:  Well also, I don't even know if better usually wins.
Speaker 5:  Quibb wasn't better. Like, like most of, most of the shows that were on
Speaker 5:  Quibi, not all a bunch of 'em were killed. I know Gizmoto had like a documentary.
Speaker 5:  I think VERGE had one, a bunch of us had it. We
Speaker 7:  We, no, it
Speaker 5:  Didn't happen.
Speaker 2:  Can we, can we pause on that really fast? I went back and was reading a bunch
Speaker 2:  of stuff and there were like three disclosures and stories that are like,
Speaker 2:  there have been conversations about a VERGE show on Quibi Eli, I need to
Speaker 2:  know the story.
Speaker 7:  So there was a polygon show on Quibi? Yes. A da you know, Quibi broke
Speaker 7:  its content up into three categories. There was the spotlights,
Speaker 7:  there were Quibi and then there was something called Daily
Speaker 7:  Essentials. And they thought Daily Essentials would be sticky and this all
Speaker 7:  made sense. Again, none of this was incorrect. You got your Halo things,
Speaker 7:  you got the stuff everybody watches every day that makes your product sticky.
Speaker 7:  And then you got whatever weird garbage in the middle to find. That's how
Speaker 7:  you program anything. So Polygon had a new show about games and then they
Speaker 7:  wanted to do a tech show obviously. And so we were like in the mix and like
Speaker 7:  I had to disclose it constantly that like someone else is having a conversation
Speaker 7:  and that thing I keep talking about where I don't live on the business side
Speaker 7:  of our company and I don't tell them what to do and they can't tell me what
Speaker 7:  to do. Boy were we just like staring at each other through Bulletproof
Speaker 7:  Glass. Like, I was like, like I
Speaker 7:  don't wanna waste time on this. And that was where that ended basically.
Speaker 2:  Did you ever sit in a meeting about what The Verge Quibi show was
Speaker 2:  gonna be
Speaker 7:  Only on the Vox Media side? Never with Quibi. Okay. Where they were like,
Speaker 7:  here's our thought. And I was like, weird. You know, like,
Speaker 7:  you, like you are gonna, like, we
Speaker 7:  give this away for free on our website. Why would anybody watch
Speaker 7:  this on Quibi? Who, that was basically where it ended for me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Can I read you a just the names of a few shows that did exist?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And these, I actually am lifting directly from the CES presentation.
Speaker 2:  So this is not just shows that exist, this is shows that like Quibi was very
Speaker 2:  excited about. There was the, now there was
Speaker 2:  architecture, nightgowns was just a show, one
Speaker 2:  was called Beauty. Sure. There was one called 50 States of Fright
Speaker 2:  that was gonna be a whole anthology series that was a horror thing set in
Speaker 2:  a different state for each one for reasons. One was called Don't Look Deeper,
Speaker 2:  which I always liked. And then there was one just called Action scene.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Just, it's just called Action Scene. The only one I remember watching
Speaker 2:  was the one with one of the Hemsworth's where he was being hunted by Christophe
Speaker 2:  Waltz. That's the only one I remember. I liked that one. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There was, there was a lot of garbage I think is the, is the best way to
Speaker 5:  say it. Most of none of it was very good. And, and after Quippy
Speaker 5:  kind of started to die, they started selling off a lot of it. Trying to like
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Like Roku bought a bunch of it, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Roku bought a bunch of it. And I think it is telling that none of
Speaker 5:  those shows survived. I think, I think that is telling. And I, and part of
Speaker 5:  that is probably, certainly Quibi a big part of that was the shows just weren't
Speaker 5:  very good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which by the way, we, we've talked about this a a bunch, so I'll just
Speaker 2:  blow through the review stuff. That thing is, is I would say the main criticism
Speaker 2:  is basically there are a lot of people who are like, there's some really
Speaker 2:  cool technology here for a 1.0 app. It's actually pretty good. A lot of people
Speaker 2:  agreed with what Chris said about the, the tab people liked turnstile. Fun
Speaker 2:  fact. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 2:  Neat. But overwhelmingly it's like, there's nothing here that is like particularly
Speaker 2:  compelling. It just Quibi didn't have like its thing, it didn't
Speaker 2:  have the House of Cards, it didn't have, its like HBO equivalent.
Speaker 2:  It just, it needed one winner and it just didn't have it.
Speaker 5:  No Mandalorian. Right.
Speaker 7:  And the interesting thing about that, going back to what Kranz was saying
Speaker 7:  about Hollywood is everyone wanted Katz's money.
Speaker 7:  No one wanted to bet against Kaz, but then there were all these like
Speaker 7:  contracts and labor questions about like, how do you cut a show up like this?
Speaker 7:  And so he absolutely bought everyone's like sea list work.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Yeah. Like, here what's the, what's the least risky thing that we can
Speaker 7:  sell to this thing that might blow up, but we don't want to bet against
Speaker 7:  it. Right. So everyone, everyone made a deal and took the money, but just
Speaker 7:  like very obviously they were putting up their like
Speaker 7:  c content
Speaker 5:  Again, the golden arm. Just go Google Quibi Golden
Speaker 5:  Arms, take a minute, Google it and you'll be like, oh, I get it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Were there any like, underrated winners? Kranz? Like do you have
Speaker 2:  any Quibi shows that you hold onto and you're like, actually that was a banger
Speaker 2:  and nobody knows.
Speaker 5:  I vaguely remember there was Reno 9 1 1, like sequel. Oh
Speaker 5:  yeah. That was like, it was a nice little diversion and, and the, the House
Speaker 5:  Flipper show and I don't think the Steven Spielberg one ever came out. That
Speaker 5:  was the one that was like, we heard so much about before Quibi was, that
Speaker 5:  was
Speaker 2:  The one you could only watch at night. Yeah. Right. Wasn't that the thing?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it was
Speaker 5:  Steven Spielberg's idea. He like came to them, was like, I hear you're doing
Speaker 5:  this stuff. Here's what I want to do. And that was like, I think the most
Speaker 5:  interesting part of this was listening to all these different filmmakers
Speaker 5:  actually really engage with tech tech the technology in a way they haven't
Speaker 5:  with other streaming platforms. Like even TikTok, they just haven't touched
Speaker 5:  like, oh there's an actual product here. I can fuck with the way they did
Speaker 5:  with Quibi. But then none of it was successful and they never tried it again.
Speaker 5:  That
Speaker 2:  Sounds about right. Alright, before we get outta here, let's, let's roll
Speaker 2:  through the, the, the big questions that we do here on version history. What
Speaker 2:  was the best thing about this thing?
Speaker 5:  Turnstile. Legit. It was, it was, I think it's a fascinating
Speaker 5:  technology. I
Speaker 2:  Kind of agree. Like I don't, I don't know that it was a good idea, but it
Speaker 2:  was, it was awesome. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was just cool. You just look at it and you're like, this rips, I don't
Speaker 5:  know if it's gonna work. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like did it accomplish anything? I don't know.
Speaker 7:  What are you two talking about?
Speaker 5:  David and I are just having the best time over here. What are you talking
Speaker 5:  about? Turnstile was awesome. That was the only part of it.
Speaker 7:  You should You can go read the turnstile patent. They had very complicated
Speaker 7:  ideas about Yeah. How you should frame a video so you could turn it
Speaker 7:  inside the viewport. That's cool. In the sense that like, you know, you like,
Speaker 7:  you look at a Rube Goldberg machine, you're like, that's a very impressive
Speaker 7:  or like a giant, you know those like videos where people have set up a huge
Speaker 7:  amount of dominoes? Yeah. And you're like, I just wanna see 'em fall down.
Speaker 7:  Like I don't care about the the millions of hours you spent setting it up.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Turnstile is brain A SMR. It's just like, yeah, I just wanna
Speaker 5:  like soothingly think about this.
Speaker 2:  Nila what do you think was the best thing about Quibi?
Speaker 7:  Going back to what I said Casey's reaction was if you just remember that
Speaker 7:  period that was like, it was a dark
Speaker 7:  and boring time in tech in, in like a particular way. and it
Speaker 7:  like, here's this explosive amount of money and new ideas
Speaker 7:  and like we're gonna blow it up in the, we can do it with
Speaker 7:  just like confidence and bluster and a, an enormous amount of cash
Speaker 7:  was actually great. Like it was a good reminder
Speaker 7:  that You can have a new idea. And what contextually,
Speaker 7:  especially through the pandemic was like not a choice. And
Speaker 7:  so like there's that of it, but at the same time, like, do you,
Speaker 7:  I don't even remember this, at that same CES, Samsung
Speaker 7:  introduced a TV that rotated and like Katz was like furious
Speaker 7:  at it because he was like, they stole my idea and I was like, no dude. Like
Speaker 7:  all the videos are vertical. Yeah. Like they are reacting to
Speaker 7:  Instagram and TikTok. Like they didn't steal Quis
Speaker 7:  idea.
Speaker 5:  Can you imagine people just getting up and flipping their tv like, oh I wonder
Speaker 5:  what this scene will look like this
Speaker 7:  Way, way. I mean they still have it. The the Frame TV You can buy a mount
Speaker 7:  for a Frame TV that auto rotates it when you play vertical video on it. I
Speaker 7:  have not bought such a mount, I've stared at it many, many times
Speaker 7:  and then tried to bring myself to a place where I think the right thing to
Speaker 7:  do is cast a vertical video to a TV that's motoring around
Speaker 7:  my,
Speaker 5:  We're we're staging an intervention. If you ever reached that place, like
Speaker 5:  emotionally
Speaker 7:  This, let's do it. But like, we're many generations deep into those products
Speaker 7:  now because the companies understand that people are watching vertical video.
Speaker 7:  So I, I think the, the thing about it was the, the idea that Hollywood
Speaker 7:  would have some bluster here and that would be a counterbalance and it all
Speaker 7:  got blown up for all the reasons it got blown up and you just haven't seen
Speaker 7:  that. You've just sort of seen Hollywood like, like fall over
Speaker 7:  instead. And I, I would like to see some, some energy come
Speaker 7:  back. Fair enough. Alright. What was the worst thing about Quibi? I have
Speaker 7:  a very strong opinion about this, but I wanna know what you guys think. It's
Speaker 7:  the name. Yes. It's gotta be the name. There we go. Yeah. It's the name.
Speaker 7:  As I've said many times on this show, one of my strongest held beliefs is
Speaker 7:  that you cannot overcome a terrible name. Like I, I honestly it sounds like
Speaker 7:  a bit, I believe it's so sincerely. I don't know man. iPad,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's fine. You can turn like a name into a good name.
Speaker 7:  You cannot turn a terrible name. I see what you mean. You can, can't survive
Speaker 7:  like a CAC or higher is fine. I got you. And but if you,
Speaker 7:  if you have an F name, you're it's never coming back. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. I,
Speaker 7:  I agree with you. Quibi is an f name.
Speaker 5:  Quibi is one of the worst. I had so much fun
Speaker 5:  ripping on that name and everything I wrote about that site, like, like
Speaker 5:  just looking for puns, looking for, it's just a horrible, horrible name.
Speaker 7:  And the fact that they tried to make it that unit of time in the qui like
Speaker 7:  awful.
Speaker 5:  Like it was just, you were trying to, they were trying way too hard to make
Speaker 5:  Quibi happen.
Speaker 7:  Do you think that, do you think that they're like forever pissed that TikTok
Speaker 7:  won? Like the Kesha spelling of TikTok?
Speaker 5:  Yes. I think that, I, like Keisha gets it, they should have gone
Speaker 5:  to her and been like, Hey, help us fix this name. But
Speaker 2:  I think if, if TikTok had come out being like, you know, it's like the clock
Speaker 2:  does right guys, it would've been worse. You know what
Speaker 5:  I mean? Yeah. If they'd done a Super Bowl ad where they're like, I'll be
Speaker 5:  there in a TikTok, like Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Yeah. Maybe the Super Bowl ad was the worst thing. But yeah.
Speaker 5:  Actually could take it back. Super Bowl ad was the worst thing. It, it really
Speaker 5:  just put it all together.
Speaker 2:  If you could go back in time and make Quibi before somebody else made
Speaker 2:  Quibi, what would you do differently?
Speaker 5:  Make it before 2020.
Speaker 7:  Fair. You know that golden Arm thing is really interesting 'cause it went
Speaker 7:  viral. Just not on Quibi if you remember this. They they, they, it was
Speaker 7:  a Hollywood app. It was like heavily D DMed. You couldn't even screenshot
Speaker 7:  it. Yeah. And at one point they were like, oh we know people wanna screenshot
Speaker 7:  Quibi. We're gonna build this like convoluted system where
Speaker 7:  we pre-select screens and clips for you to share in
Speaker 7:  the, and it's like no, to just let people do like, let people make memes.
Speaker 7:  That's the one thing I would've changed is like, make this thing more social.
Speaker 7:  'cause that was the thing they missed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I agree. I think that was gonna be my answer too, is like embrace
Speaker 2:  the other parts of TikTok. Right. Which are like, let people, I think
Speaker 2:  you, you probably can't like let people stitch and duet stuff like that
Speaker 2:  doesn't feel right. But like let people clip stuff and share clips. Let people
Speaker 2:  make memes out of it. Like you're talking about let people share screenshots
Speaker 2:  like they had done so many different things. Even just with like the way
Speaker 2:  they've licensed content that it's like just blow up the idea of what it
Speaker 2:  means to like be a show even further. And I actually think there's like some
Speaker 2:  really interesting stuff you could do there. Also, I would name it not Quibi,
Speaker 7:  That's
Speaker 5:  Important. I realize Sam Raey directed that The
Speaker 2:  Golden arm speaking of C material. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Who he
Speaker 7:  Just, I feel that the Golden Arm gets a bad rap. There's some, it's in my
Speaker 7:  brain and you know, I don't, I'm not gonna burn the calories to get it out,
Speaker 7:  but it's like it was a joke in some way and it got decontextualized
Speaker 7:  as a joke into people believing Quibi thought it was serious and then it
Speaker 7:  became a different kind of joke. The
Speaker 5:  Actress was like, this was a joke. We were like making fun of people obsessed
Speaker 5:  with like tech and stuff. And instead everybody was like, Nope, you got a
Speaker 5:  dumb golden arm. I'm gonna laugh at the golden arm. Dumb. It's dumb.
Speaker 7:  I don't, again, it's in there somewhere. Yeah. And I, you know, someone else
Speaker 7:  can Google it and send it to us.
Speaker 2:  All right. We have two more Quibi questions. Question number one is could
Speaker 2:  you reboot it in 2024? Could Quibi post
Speaker 2:  Pandemic post TikTok? Could we do Quibi now?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but it would just be friends episodes cut up and put on there but
Speaker 5:  like paid for instead of Shadow put up on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  So it's just TikTok minus the impending copyright lawsuits basically.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2:  Nila, you're very pensive.
Speaker 7:  I want to say Yes. Really? Yeah. I'm, I'm trying to make
Speaker 7:  the case and it's much harder than I thought it would be. You
Speaker 7:  know, you don't wanna be a reflexive No, it would be really hard to raise
Speaker 7:  the money now. Quibi was a true Zer zero
Speaker 7:  and straight phenomenon. The content would be easier to get 'cause all the
Speaker 7:  other streamers are kind of falling apart and they want to sell things. But
Speaker 7:  getting people to download an app that isn't TikTok in 2024
Speaker 7:  and pay money for it seems hard.
Speaker 2:  Do you think the thesis that somebody at some point
Speaker 2:  will do a really good high-end mostly vertical
Speaker 2:  streaming service is real? Like can Holly, will somebody
Speaker 2:  eventually make a vertical feature film starring Chris
Speaker 2:  Pratt that is like good and successful
Speaker 5:  Not as long as YouTube and, and TikTok and totally free content
Speaker 5:  exists, right? Like if there's no real clear path to making money
Speaker 5:  back on that, who is gonna invest the money in that?
Speaker 7:  You know what I think vertical video, I was reading a, a
Speaker 7:  story about fashion brands wanting things
Speaker 7:  shot on iPhones for their ad campaigns now 'cause it's more authentic, which
Speaker 7:  is fascinating for a million reasons. I think vertical video is
Speaker 7:  personal and horizontal is Hollywood. And I don't think You can cross
Speaker 7:  that gap. That's that's just my, that's my guess. I I I, I'm switching my
Speaker 7:  answer to no You can't do it. I try, I tried, let it be
Speaker 7:  said that I really tried and it you did try and it it's still not
Speaker 7:  good a good idea. YouTube still exists.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I don't know. Part of me wonders, I mean like YouTube and TikTok
Speaker 2:  are forever trying to find ways to get fancy content
Speaker 2:  and fancy content is forever trying to find ways to get the engagement
Speaker 2:  and excitement and user generated content of those other platforms. and it
Speaker 2:  does feel like at some point there might be a middle ground that makes sense
Speaker 2:  but maybe it's just the two ends of the spectrum and actually every time
Speaker 2:  you try to cross the two it doesn't work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The economics are just super weird. 'cause you, okay, you start making
Speaker 5:  movies for YouTube then you need contracts with the unions, which means
Speaker 5:  why aren't all the people making stuff already for YouTube not getting
Speaker 5:  contracts and then it's like, oh boy, nobody wants to touch that.
Speaker 5:  Okay,
Speaker 2:  Well then let me ask the question slightly differently. Will Netflix ever
Speaker 2:  make a vertical movie that is just
Speaker 2:  vertical?
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 2:  No. No way. Why
Speaker 7:  Not? Because where are you gonna distribute it? You're gonna distribute it
Speaker 7:  on phones only on Netflix, not TVs people. There's no way
Speaker 7:  anyone's gonna watch a vertical video on their tv. But what
Speaker 2:  If you have a TV that that turns
Speaker 7:  This is it. Samsung's gonna buy the first vertical Netflix show.
Speaker 5:  Wait, what's Samsung's streaming service called that? That's where it's gonna
Speaker 5:  appear. It's gonna,
Speaker 7:  It was called Milk Video.
Speaker 5:  Alright.
Speaker 2:  Okay, last question. Does Quibi belong in the version history Hall of fame?
Speaker 7:  No. No, no, no, no.
Speaker 5:  No
Speaker 7:  Real strong reaction from you? Absolutely not.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 7:  Sorry. So in my, like my personal hall of fame, just 'cause
Speaker 7:  it was so nuts. Like it was all of tech and media were conspiring
Speaker 7:  to gaslight the American public.
Speaker 2:  It definitely goes in the good content Hall of fame. Not itself,
Speaker 2:  but the content about it was, it was, it was a terrific year.
Speaker 5:  When we say Hall of Fame, what do we mean? Because like in a lot of
Speaker 5:  respects this is a Hall of Famer, just not like a good product.
Speaker 7:  What in which respects would you say this is Hall of Famer
Speaker 5:  Again, from what you said, like the drama The drama was
Speaker 7:  Was beautiful. Like the Clown Hall of Fame. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  The Trolls Hall of Fame.
Speaker 7:  No, there's no no, no. We got a high bar. The Hall of Fame is like an industry
Speaker 7:  shaking there. You can that you remember what life was like before
Speaker 7:  and what life was like after.
Speaker 5:  So the Juicer Row goes in the Hall of Fame.
Speaker 7:  No, your idea of what a Hall of Fame is is very confusing
Speaker 2:  Here. Here's my, here's my early idea for the Hall of Fame. I think it has
Speaker 2:  to have either been very good, very important
Speaker 2:  or very interesting and you kind of need at least
Speaker 2:  two of those three things to be in the Hall of Fame. And I think Quibi was
Speaker 2:  just interesting. That's fair. Like it wasn't important and it wasn't good.
Speaker 2:  It was very interesting. But I feel like it doesn't quite like
Speaker 2:  move over. Like I, I've just, I don't know. The other failure that comes
Speaker 2:  to mind was like Theranos Theranos I think was very interesting and very
Speaker 2:  important in that like what it meant in the bigger world
Speaker 2:  was a lot more than
Speaker 7:  This Hall of things sucks.
Speaker 2:  Theranos will probably never be on this show. Let's be clear.
Speaker 5:  We'll put the Game Boy or something in there. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  There will be good things someday we'll get to those.
Speaker 5:  The iPhone five is gonna go in there.
Speaker 7:  She's a deeply confusing hall of fame.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be great. I'm excited about it. Listen, these are just pilots.
Speaker 2:  We're just figuring stuff out here. That's all. It's alright. Thank you
Speaker 2:  both for doing this with me. This was delightful. If you have an idea for
Speaker 2:  a better name than Quibi tell us and we'll bring it back and it'll be amazing.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break then we're gonna go back. We have more pilots,
Speaker 2:  we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  these things we've had teeny, tiny, inconsequential debates about which music
Speaker 2:  app you should listen to. All of this stuff is very fun. And Liam James,
Speaker 2:  our producer, has been wanting to find a way to structure this for a while
Speaker 2:  and kind of put us in a room, pit us against each other and have us like
Speaker 2:  fight for real about which thing is better. So
Speaker 2:  that's essentially what this show is. Last week we talked about CarPlay versus
Speaker 2:  the automakers Neli and I got, I would say, more heated than either of us
Speaker 2:  expected. I definitely won, but you know, that's neither here nor there.
Speaker 2:  This week the debate is about books, print books, digital books.
Speaker 2:  Who reads in the future and what do they do it with? Let's do it.
Speaker 10:  Good day. I am Liam James, the moderator for today's debate. And my job
Speaker 10:  is to facilitate a debate between today's VERGE cast hosts on the
Speaker 10:  topic of books versus e-readers. First up, we have Alex
Speaker 10:  Kranz, deputy editor. Welcome to the debate, Alex.
Speaker 5:  Hi. I am so happy to be here and destroy my competition
Speaker 10:  Versus Kranz. We have Kevin Nen, our features editor at The Verge. Welcome
Speaker 10:  Kevin. Thanks
Speaker 2:  For having me.
Speaker 10:  Before we get started, I'd like to share the rules for our audience. Each
Speaker 10:  person will make their case directly to The Vergecast audience. A virtual
Speaker 10:  coin toss will determine who gets to go first following open statements.
Speaker 10:  Each host will be given two minutes to answer my questions with an option
Speaker 10:  of up to a minute in rebuttal from the opposing host. The questions were
Speaker 10:  not shared in advance and our hosts may use the internet to confirm factual
Speaker 10:  details, but they use their limited time while doing so. Okay,
Speaker 10:  so with the rules outta the way, let's move on to the topic for today. We're
Speaker 10:  gonna talk about eBooks versus printed books. Now,
Speaker 10:  eBooks, as we know them today, have been around for decades,
Speaker 10:  believe it or not. In fact, You can go all the way back to the 1970s
Speaker 10:  to get early examples and prototypes of what we now consider to be
Speaker 10:  an ebook. But it was in 2007 that Amazon released the first
Speaker 10:  Kindle and it kind of revolutionized the whole ebook market.
Speaker 10:  Kindle had wireless connectivity that allowed people to download books
Speaker 10:  directly to the device, simplifying the whole process and making
Speaker 10:  it something that regular consumers could buy and use and enjoy.
Speaker 10:  Now since then, tons of other companies have come out with similar devices
Speaker 10:  to the Kindle, but it's still a relatively small market
Speaker 10:  compared to actual printed books. So we ask the question,
Speaker 10:  which is better, an ebook or a printed book. Now we move on
Speaker 10:  to our opening statements at virtual coin toss.
Speaker 10:  Let's see, Kevin is the visiting person, so he gets to pick
Speaker 10:  heads or tails. Kevin, heads
Speaker 5:  Or tails. I see how it is.
Speaker 11:  Let's do tails.
Speaker 10:  Tails. Rigged tails. Okay.
Speaker 10:  Okay. It is tails. Kevin, would you like to go first or second?
Speaker 11:  You know, I'm a gentleman. Alex, why don't you go first?
Speaker 5:  I see how it is. I see how it's,
Speaker 10:  Kevin wants that, that final word at the in the closing arguments. Okay.
Speaker 10:  And with that, we'll go to our opening statements. Alex, you have two minutes.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Hey, gentle readers at The Verge. Listeners,
Speaker 5:  wonderful human beings. I'm here to talk to you about eBooks and why they
Speaker 5:  rule number one, You can put 'em on anything.
Speaker 5:  Can't do that with a book. Books you have to like take with you.
Speaker 5:  You can only have one, two at a time, unless you're really strong. eBooks,
Speaker 5:  You can have like dozens depending on the storage of your e-reader or
Speaker 5:  phone. Also great about eBooks, they can be changed
Speaker 5:  at any time. So you know, if, if a company says, Hey, we need to
Speaker 5:  release an edit for this book because we, we messed something up,
Speaker 5:  they can just push that edit out and then you'll get the the fixed version
Speaker 5:  of that book. And I think that's really great and can never go wrong for
Speaker 5:  anyone. Also, eBooks are really, really nice because
Speaker 5:  of accessibility. They are very, very easy to read.
Speaker 5:  They are wonderful fonts out there that allow people with dyslexia to
Speaker 5:  read a little easier. There are ways to make the fonts bigger so people
Speaker 5:  with really bad eyesight can can see the text easier. And you
Speaker 5:  just don't have that kind of flexibility from a traditional book where you
Speaker 5:  usually have to have some sort of magnifying glass and then you have to walk
Speaker 5:  around carrying a magnifying glass and then everyone judges you because you
Speaker 5:  have a magnifying glass. And I think you'd wanna avoid that most of the time.
Speaker 5:  And You can with something like the books Palmer or the
Speaker 5:  Kindle, you know, any of 'em. Or the Libra from Kobo. A
Speaker 5:  lot of different companies make really, really nice e-readers that have really,
Speaker 5:  really nice displays. They have really, really
Speaker 5:  good features in them. And again, they give you that flexibility
Speaker 5:  and I think that's what's most important about eBooks, is the
Speaker 5:  flexibility they provide to you. How much longer do
Speaker 5:  I go? I didn't look when I started.
Speaker 10:  You had 11 seconds left, but now it's over. Oh, perfect.
Speaker 5:  Oh, and in conclusion,
Speaker 5:  eBooks rule, regular books are fine. Thank you for your time.
Speaker 10:  Okay, Kevin, what say you? Well,
Speaker 11:  I just wanna start, you know, I feel like I'm being cast as a
Speaker 11:  Luddite by my opponent. And I have to say, I do think eBooks
Speaker 11:  are an interesting technology. You know, I own a book's Palmer, like half
Speaker 11:  of The Verge staff now, and so I'll start with some concessions. eBooks
Speaker 11:  are faster, sometimes they are cheaper. We'll talk about that later.
Speaker 11:  And they are great for accessibility, especially for the visually impaired.
Speaker 11:  That said, the book, the print book is an old and
Speaker 11:  near perfect technology. It's inexpensive, it's durable, it's
Speaker 11:  shareable, it's also accessible in a very different way. No
Speaker 11:  technology, no modern technology needed, no software
Speaker 11:  necessary, no updates. And also in a time when we're being not
Speaker 11:  just in books, but across all of the media, we consume video games, tv,
Speaker 11:  film, music, a little more skeptical of our platforms and
Speaker 11:  what kind of access we'll have to our media in the future.
Speaker 11:  Print books give you that access forever. Owning a library of your own
Speaker 11:  physical books means you'll be able to read them in perpetuity to sell them,
Speaker 11:  to share them with friends, to get rid of them if you want. That's a kind
Speaker 11:  of freedom that is not offered by most of the ways we read digitally.
Speaker 11:  But I think most importantly, I think reading is about being deliberate.
Speaker 11:  Reading is not about reading as much or consuming as much as You
Speaker 11:  can as quickly as possible. I think reading, good reading is about
Speaker 11:  good habits and discipline. A print book is isolated from the rest of the
Speaker 11:  things on your phone, and that's what makes the reading experience so powerful.
Speaker 11:  Meaning that when you read, you'll be more focused and hopefully more patient
Speaker 11:  and you'll just take in more ideas. You'll have more enjoyment
Speaker 11:  out of what you're consuming. Maybe you'll even think about it outside of
Speaker 11:  consumption itself. You know, art is meant to be experienced. I also
Speaker 11:  think books allow you to be very deliberate with your time. The
Speaker 11:  physical presence of a book on your nightstand is a reminder of what you're
Speaker 11:  reading and what you've decided to spend your time with. I also think being
Speaker 11:  deliberate about what we choose to spend our time with is important too.
Speaker 11:  We all know that Amazon's monopoly is in eBooks, and
Speaker 11:  I think every publisher and author in bookstore would probably say that
Speaker 11:  it's not great for the ecosystem. You know, if you listener don't believe
Speaker 11:  in monopolies, I think you have some skepticism about how much you buy
Speaker 11:  from Amazon. There's also a whole ecosystem of independent bookstores that
Speaker 11:  sell print books that support authors as well.
Speaker 10:  And that is your time.
Speaker 11:  Alright.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'm ready.
Speaker 10:  Kevin, you'll have an opportunity to finish that thought with your first
Speaker 10:  question. However, our first question goes to Alex Krantz. Alex,
Speaker 10:  in your opening statement you mentioned the ability to carry more books
Speaker 10:  with you than is possible with printed books. This reminds me of the
Speaker 10:  iPod, but in that category, music has very much moved
Speaker 10:  into the digital realm. Why haven't books been able to do the same?
Speaker 5:  You know, that monopoly Kevin mentioned, I, I think that
Speaker 5:  does actually have a lot to do with it. I think eBooks are not consumed at
Speaker 5:  the same way that music is consumed. And so people are much more, as Kevin
Speaker 5:  said, deliberate with their choices. And there have been very, very few
Speaker 5:  options for them historically, right? Historically it was Barnes
Speaker 5:  and Noble and Amazon and they both kept very, very tight control over their
Speaker 5:  ebook marketplaces. That has become to change in the last few years.
Speaker 5:  Also coinciding with a rise in reading of eBooks and a
Speaker 5:  rise in the sales of e reading devices. So I think things
Speaker 5:  are changing due to companies like Kobo due to choices like
Speaker 5:  Libby, which allow you to check out eBooks from your library.
Speaker 10:  Kevin, you mentioned in your opening statement that books are a near
Speaker 10:  perfect technology, but as we look towards younger generations,
Speaker 10:  it seems like books have fallen off as a form of media
Speaker 10:  and entertainment and pleasure. What does the publishing industry need to
Speaker 10:  do to solve that problem?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I actually don't think there's a lot of evidence to say that, you
Speaker 11:  know, gen Z is AC actually reading less. It's just the
Speaker 11:  format that they're reading in. And honestly, you know, with Zoomers, however
Speaker 11:  they wanna read, that's great With me, I still think reading's just a greater
Speaker 11:  way to access a, a deeper level of idea and thought than, you know, maybe
Speaker 11:  consuming a lot of YouTube content. But I think it's, publishers
Speaker 11:  just need to think about what like younger readers actually are interested
Speaker 11:  in. I think the industry itself is run by a lot of like much older
Speaker 11:  people that don't understand the youth. So I think just understanding the
Speaker 11:  trends and what young people are actually interested in publishing
Speaker 11:  books around those topic areas is probably the waste place to start. Because
Speaker 11:  I actually don't think the resistance to reading has anything to do
Speaker 11:  with books themselves, but what publishers are choosing to put out in the
Speaker 11:  landscape
Speaker 10:  Krantz opportunity to respond.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think Kevin's wrong and that the youth
Speaker 5:  aren't reading as much because they wanna read on their phones.
Speaker 5:  No, that's not true. We're like, you look at TikTok, you look at book talk
Speaker 5:  and there is a lot of reading of actual physical books there, but they're
Speaker 5:  also really, really pretty. And they'll show you just the paper side. They'll
Speaker 5:  never show you the spine, but, but they, they wanna show those books
Speaker 5:  off. However, the majority of people are not TikTok creators, they're
Speaker 5:  just people living in their home, particularly Gen Z and
Speaker 5:  they enjoy reading other ways, right? The phone is the center
Speaker 5:  point of their technological universe and having those opportunities
Speaker 5:  there are really, really important. But I do agree that there has been a
Speaker 5:  struggle due
Speaker 10:  Time
Speaker 5:  To the fact that Amazon, that time, that's, it's all Amazon's fault.
Speaker 11:  We're actually gonna end up in agreement here. Yeah, we're
Speaker 5:  Gonna be like, actually both are great. Amazon's the real villain.
Speaker 10:  Okay. Kranz, the next question is for you. I wanna stick on
Speaker 10:  book sales for a moment here. One of the more harsh
Speaker 10:  criticisms that is perennial to eBooks is
Speaker 10:  the cost of them that they are oftentimes, if not
Speaker 10:  usually cheaper than their printed counterparts. Apple
Speaker 10:  notoriously colluded with other book publishers to try
Speaker 10:  to raise the cost of eBooks when they introduced their own
Speaker 10:  digital book platform. Do you think authors are
Speaker 10:  getting the short end of the stick when
Speaker 10:  consumers buy eBooks?
Speaker 5:  Depends on their publisher. Honestly, I think authors are, are
Speaker 5:  highly dependent on their publishers and the deals they make with their publishers.
Speaker 5:  Both Kevin and I are published authors, Kevin with his name Meander a
Speaker 5:  pseudonym because it was a romance novel. And what you find
Speaker 5:  out is that it that You can make a lot of money through digital
Speaker 5:  sales and we've seen really good examples of that usually involving a person
Speaker 5:  boning some sort of sentient dinosaur or sign.
Speaker 5:  But you know, it happens, it's out there. And the
Speaker 5:  worst part of this is that I think the publishers are still getting in the
Speaker 5:  way and taking a significant cut and trying to make sure that the cut that
Speaker 5:  the authors receive via eBooks is the same as via
Speaker 5:  traditional print, despite the fact that traditional print has a much higher
Speaker 5:  cost.
Speaker 10:  Kevin, a chance to respond.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I'd like to respond. This is strange because I actually, in some ways
Speaker 11:  I think I'll be siding with crayons on this, but ebook
Speaker 11:  royalties are actually by percentage higher for
Speaker 11:  authors than they are in the print book space for hardcover an
Speaker 11:  ebook, it usually mets out to about the same, but once he gets a paperback,
Speaker 11:  you know, selling an ebook versus a paperback actually nets a lot more for
Speaker 11:  the author on a per unit level. But I actually don't think
Speaker 11:  publishers are the villain here. They do a lot to protect, I think you
Speaker 11:  know, apple and you know, PRH did collude to raise
Speaker 11:  the cost of books, but it was like to protect, you know,
Speaker 11:  an existing infrastructure of cost that was being driven down by the digital
Speaker 11:  marketplace by Amazon. So publishers do
Speaker 11:  understand that like when they're healthy, authors are healthy too and they
Speaker 11:  do a lot more to protect the interest of authors than Amazon does.
Speaker 5:  So it's Amazon's fault.
Speaker 11:  It's Amazon's fault.
Speaker 10:  Okay. Moving on to the more the technology
Speaker 10:  side of these, of these two technologies, the next question is for you Kevin.
Speaker 10:  What do books provide to the reader that eBooks
Speaker 10:  cannot?
Speaker 11:  I'm not sure if they provide something that the ebook doesn't, but I do
Speaker 11:  think the experience of reading a print book is much richer. I actually
Speaker 11:  think, you know, we talked earlier about how young people, but I actually
Speaker 11:  think everyone has struggles with this. Like I think we all wish we read
Speaker 11:  more. I think we all wish we had time to read more. I think we all wish
Speaker 11:  we had the patience and space to read more and I think the print book
Speaker 11:  gives you that space more so than reading off your phone or
Speaker 11:  a device or something that can do many things. I know we've talked
Speaker 11:  a little bit about E ink devices or dedicated digital reading
Speaker 11:  devices. Some of them are very good, but I just think the focus,
Speaker 11:  even to just choose one book and stick with it is a very
Speaker 11:  powerful thing. A print device or a print book does that, a device doesn't
Speaker 11:  give you the device just gives you too much choice and
Speaker 11:  it's just kind of, you don't want the same feeling of scrolling Netflix
Speaker 11:  endlessly when you're trying to read a book
Speaker 10:  Kranz instead of giving you a chance to respond. I'm gonna ask you a similar
Speaker 10:  question. eBooks provide many features on top of the reading
Speaker 10:  experience. Some of these could be criticized as
Speaker 10:  distractions, some of them could be described as
Speaker 10:  providing new ways to help readers understand
Speaker 10:  or gain knowledge about what writers are talking about.
Speaker 10:  What is essential to you as an ebook reader
Speaker 10:  in terms of these features? What is the the minimum required?
Speaker 5:  All right, first I'm happy to answer that question, but I'm gonna take five
Speaker 5:  seconds to respond to Kevin. And one thing's books provide that eBooks don't
Speaker 5:  is paper cuts. So take that Kevin. I've never gotten a,
Speaker 5:  is that
Speaker 11:  To you often?
Speaker 5:  Never gotten a paper cut from my books Palmer that I've had for two days,
Speaker 5:  but I have gotten a paper cut from, is a yearbook in my childhood
Speaker 5:  bedroom? It sucks. Anyway, that was more than five seconds. But what really
Speaker 5:  matters about eBooks is, is the flexibility. I think that flexibility is
Speaker 5:  so, so, so, so crucial to e-readers and, and that ability to be able to switch.
Speaker 5:  For me it's also, I read really, really quickly and
Speaker 5:  I tend to read one book at a time. Like the the focus problem that Kevin
Speaker 5:  has discussed. I don't have myself and so I like to read a book and then
Speaker 5:  just move on to the next one. And I hate having to wait
Speaker 5:  because I want everything now and the fact that I get instant access
Speaker 5:  with an e-reader and I don't have to worry about is somebody gonna deliver
Speaker 5:  it to my doorstep? Do I need to go down to the bookstore to buy it? I can
Speaker 5:  just have it. And oftentimes while still paying an independent bookstore
Speaker 5:  and making sure they get a cut of the profit is just something really rewarding
Speaker 5:  about the ebook and digital books in general. Great. and it doesn't give
Speaker 5:  you paper cuts,
Speaker 10:  Kevin, a chance to respond. I just
Speaker 11:  Wanna say I don't think I've ever gotten a paper cut from reading a book.
Speaker 5:  You're going to now
Speaker 11:  I think you
Speaker 5:  Need to be reading more of those like really big like tabletop books.
Speaker 5:  You know, with the super thick pages you'll be getting a ton of paper cuts
Speaker 5:  that TaeKwonDo one I had when fifth grade. Oh my god.
Speaker 5:  All over my fingers.
Speaker 11:  But yeah, no, no response from me there.
Speaker 10:  And our final question for you, Kevin, while
Speaker 10:  doing the research for this episode, one of the things I saw that came up
Speaker 10:  more often than not for the side for
Speaker 10:  printed books is the experience of marginalia.
Speaker 10:  I know that eBooks have this ability now, but many people
Speaker 10:  that I read opinions of fought that it's
Speaker 10:  just nothing in the, just not even close.
Speaker 10:  It's an order of magnitude different to them. Do
Speaker 10:  you think marginality is important? Is that something as a
Speaker 10:  reader you participate in? And do you think that
Speaker 10:  is part of what makes the book on your perfect technology?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I mean the marginalia in an ebook reading experience
Speaker 11:  is one that's just imitated from the print book, right? So I don't
Speaker 11:  think it surpasses it unless you feel very strongly about your highlights
Speaker 11:  sinking to the cloud, in which case I would urge you to read digitally
Speaker 11:  then. But no, I think writing in the margins highlighting, I think
Speaker 11:  those physical acts actually help in terms of helping you
Speaker 11:  synthesize and remember things that you're experiencing. My issue with
Speaker 11:  reading on electronic devices is that the advantage of them
Speaker 11:  is that they are frictionless, but I actually think friction is a good thing
Speaker 11:  When you're taking in art, when you're taking in information, when you're
Speaker 11:  trying to learn, when you're trying to remember things, writing in the margins
Speaker 11:  is just a great way actually to remember things. It's why you take notes
Speaker 11:  in school. It's not just so You can refer to them later. It's 'cause it
Speaker 11:  does something to your brain that helps you process it. And I think that
Speaker 11:  experience isn't quite as replicated in e reading as it is
Speaker 11:  in a print book. That said, I'm someone that writes really stupid things
Speaker 11:  in the margin. So I'll revisit some of my books and I've just written LOL.
Speaker 5:  Can I respond? Yes. Okay, my response. Why are
Speaker 5:  you all writing in your books? Get a notebook.
Speaker 5:  Everybody just, just go get a notebook, put the little page number down.
Speaker 5:  Do the librarians and booksellers in your lives a favor. Don't go writing
Speaker 5:  in your books. That's just that that's I'm, that's not even an argument.
Speaker 5:  I'm not, I'm just upset everyone's writing in their books to the point that
Speaker 5:  we have a whole word described for it. It's now a feature on a kindle.
Speaker 10:  Okay, fascinating. POV from you both. It's time now to move on to
Speaker 10:  closing statements and at first we have Alex Kranz.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I could just say eBooks rule and regular books
Speaker 5:  drool. I think that would be like a really evocative statement here because
Speaker 5:  eBooks do rule and like if a ebook gets read,
Speaker 5:  it's fine, you just dry it off. Or you buy a new e-reader and you still have
Speaker 5:  all your books. You leave your copy of King Arthur and the Round Knights
Speaker 5:  of the round table out on the the porch and it gets totally
Speaker 5:  soaked. And then 20 years later you're like, why are my pages all weird?
Speaker 5:  That sucks. That's why books suck compared to eBooks. But really
Speaker 5:  the truth of it is, is that even though eBooks are, I think substantially
Speaker 5:  better in a market improvement over the reg, the traditional book, what's
Speaker 5:  really, really nice about them is that they provide for a lot of people,
Speaker 5:  everyone who says that they make you ill or sick or something like that is
Speaker 5:  generally proven to just be like a normal book nerd.
Speaker 5:  And You can technically write in the marginalia, is that what it's
Speaker 5:  called? You can write in your books on an ebook, but you shouldn't.
Speaker 5:  And You can just go get a notebook and You can just write in it like a five
Speaker 5:  star binder. You get yourself a trapper keeper, you write all your notes
Speaker 5:  in there, You can organize them, it'll look beautiful. You put little stickers
Speaker 5:  on it. I think that is really, really and crucial. And You can do that with
Speaker 5:  both books and eBooks. But ultimately I just
Speaker 5:  think that eBooks are a really, really powerful new medium that
Speaker 5:  provides opportunities for a lot of people that might not other have otherwise
Speaker 5:  have the opportunities or access to libraries which are an endangered species
Speaker 5:  in the United States. So support your Republic library. Go check
Speaker 5:  out some books, eBooks specifically, and that's why eBooks are the
Speaker 5:  best.
Speaker 10:  And a note for our listeners that were born in the 21st century, A
Speaker 10:  trapper keeper is a fancy binder from
Speaker 10:  the nine or I believe the early nineties that had a fabric
Speaker 10:  covering and a zipper and there
Speaker 5:  Was unicorns,
Speaker 10:  Unicorns, pockets, all kinds of things. Alright Kevin,
Speaker 11:  I don't think I'm gonna reach the kind of person who thinks only about efficiency.
Speaker 11:  It's true. The ebook is a more efficient form of a book, whatever that means.
Speaker 11:  I'm here appeal to the reader who doesn't think of books as merely content.
Speaker 11:  I wanna speak to the person that sees not just the value of books as a medium,
Speaker 11:  but also wants to see a future where making books as healthy and sustainable
Speaker 11:  because those are the conditions I think we should hope for, for all artists,
Speaker 11:  writers, and creative people to say otherwise is to wish for future where
Speaker 11:  a large hydraulic press smushes everything violently into an iPad.
Speaker 11:  I'm an author, Kranz is an author. Many of our friends are authors of
Speaker 11:  fiction, of non-fiction. And for the friends that are a little crazier of
Speaker 11:  poetry, not one of them would prefer you read their work as an ebook
Speaker 11:  instead of print. No editor, no publisher would prefer you read the digital
Speaker 11:  version. Every independent bookstore could use your business and you should
Speaker 11:  shop there unless you want a future that's just Amazon. And for the folks
Speaker 11:  out there who wanna save a few bucks because their imagination is that the
Speaker 11:  ebook is less expensive, I think that's the logic of a cheap person. It's
Speaker 11:  the same kind of argument that leads people to leave bad tips at restaurants
Speaker 11:  because the core of that argument is entitlement and a lack of
Speaker 11:  appreciation of understanding of what goes into making the things you enjoy.
Speaker 11:  In this moment where AI threatens creative industries, I would challenge
Speaker 11:  us to think about the people who make the art we enjoy to challenge us and
Speaker 11:  make us think differently. Thank you.
Speaker 5:  You waited until the end to call me out like that.
Speaker 10:  Wow.
Speaker 5:  I can't, and I don't even have a rebuttal time.
Speaker 11:  I
Speaker 5:  Just think this is outrageous.
Speaker 10:  Only a minute and 26 seconds too. That was, that was impressive. Oh yeah.
Speaker 11:  It's like I don't care about winning this debate. I just want people to
Speaker 11:  think Alex Kranz is a bad tipper,
Speaker 5:  Which
Speaker 11:  Isn't even true,
Speaker 5:  Man. I'm gonna get so much hate now for tipping 5%. It was one time guys,
Speaker 5:  Alex, it was one time all restaurant. It's an accident.
Speaker 10:  Okay, Vergecast listeners, what do you think? Did Kranz make
Speaker 10:  the case for eBooks or was Kevin Wright about the perfect
Speaker 10:  technology that is printed books? Let us know what you think by calling
Speaker 10:  8 6 6 VERGE one one
Speaker 12:  there was no camera on it so I could use it where I was working. But the
Speaker 12:  thing that gets me is having music that I can carry around
Speaker 12:  with me and not have some sort of external
Speaker 12:  attachment, whether that be Bluetooth or wifi. And I'm
Speaker 12:  just wondering, is there any other solution other than buying
Speaker 12:  an old old iPod off of eBay and using
Speaker 12:  that? Is there no modern solution? Because it seems to be that everything
Speaker 12:  has Bluetooth or wifi and what I'm looking for is
Speaker 12:  just a strict MP three player that has headphones
Speaker 12:  out like a three and a half millimeter headphones out, like no Bluetooth,
Speaker 12:  no wifi, something I have to either load on a SD card
Speaker 12:  or maybe plug it into my computer to add the music. But I was just
Speaker 12:  wondering, maybe somebody somewhere inside your place of business
Speaker 12:  has an answer or a fix. If I ever hear from back, hear back from you, I
Speaker 12:  would be super ecstatic to see what you guys come up with. Thanks, I love
Speaker 12:  you guys.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so every once in a while we get a question on The Vergecast hotline
Speaker 2:  that sends somewhere between one and all of us, just
Speaker 2:  deep down a rabbit hole. This time that happens to our
Speaker 2:  producer Andrew Marino. Hi Andrew.
Speaker 13:  Hi David.
Speaker 2:  So what'd you find this time?
Speaker 13:  Okay, so yeah, this was actually kind of hard. Like a lot of this stuff
Speaker 13:  is connected to the internet. You have to use Bluetooth to connect
Speaker 13:  to it.
Speaker 13:  Sony still makes Walkman's and a lot of them
Speaker 13:  are very high end. They're basically an Android phone.
Speaker 13:  It's like has Android on it, touchscreen, that's all connected to the internet.
Speaker 13:  But they do make one Walkman for $80.
Speaker 13:  It looks like an iPod Nano. Yes. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Wait, can I just quibble with that for just a quick second? So you, you just
Speaker 2:  held it up to the camera as we're recording and what I would say is like
Speaker 2:  if you imagine an iPod nano, but like the iPod nano you would
Speaker 2:  find like on Temu or like if you searched on on Alibaba
Speaker 2:  Express, like you, it's, it's a real, like we have iPod nano at home
Speaker 2:  kind of situation, at least from what I can tell. Yes,
Speaker 13:  It's an iPod nano without a scroll wheel. It's,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, okay. Yeah, that's, that's right.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Sony still makes it like a Walkman MP three player.
Speaker 13:  What is great about it, it is not connected to the internet. It does not
Speaker 13:  have Bluetooth. It is exactly what this person wants. It has
Speaker 13:  only eight gigabytes of memory on it. It's not
Speaker 13:  a lot, but you know, that's enough to swap a bunch of stuff
Speaker 13:  out. I was easily able to just plug this right into my Mac
Speaker 13:  drop songs into it, like a flash drive and it showed up immediately
Speaker 13:  on the MP three player. I brought it over to a pc,
Speaker 13:  plugged it into a pc, same thing. Showed up, showed up, dropped a
Speaker 13:  song into it, like a thumb drive and it showed up on the player.
Speaker 13:  It works just, it works great.
Speaker 2:  I feel like there's a catch coming here. What is, what is the catch?
Speaker 13:  There's, there's actually not a, not a huge catch. It doesn't sound
Speaker 13:  amazing. Okay. I'm actually like surprised how
Speaker 13:  easy it is to get one now it's $80. You can get one on Amazon,
Speaker 13:  You can get one on Sony's website. It has micro USB, which is
Speaker 2:  Great. That's a catch. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  I would also like to note that it has an FM radio in it.
Speaker 13:  So when you plug in your headphones, your headphones act as a little antenna.
Speaker 13:  You can listen to the radio and I think that's just a beautiful thing.
Speaker 2:  That's cool. and it has a headphone jack, which seems very important.
Speaker 13:  It has a headphone jack.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. Wait, so what, what is the full name of this thing? Okay, I'm
Speaker 2:  assuming it's some insane hexa decimal nonsense like Sony likes to do.
Speaker 2:  It is
Speaker 13:  The NW E 3 9 4 Walkman, Digital
Speaker 13:  Music Player.
Speaker 2:  That is the fakest sounding that I've ever heard in my life. Okay, so this
Speaker 2:  is, this is good news. This thing exists. I was thinking we were
Speaker 2:  gonna end up down the road of like modding an iPod Classic,
Speaker 2:  which is a thing I've seen a bunch of people doing recently. You can actually
Speaker 2:  get it to run sort of one specific app or just get
Speaker 2:  it to connect better to modern computers. I thought that might be the answer,
Speaker 2:  but this is like you're, you're telling me there is at least one half decent
Speaker 2:  dedicated offline music device that exists in the world still?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, totally. This will, this will do it if other people are looking for
Speaker 13:  something like this but can use Bluetooth. The
Speaker 13:  Mighty player is another good option. Do you remember that one?
Speaker 2:  That was the one that was meant for Spotify specifically, right? Yeah.
Speaker 13:  It syncs with your Spotify, like
Speaker 2:  An iPod shuffle looking thing.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Okay. It uses the internet to sync
Speaker 13:  in Bluetooth to sync, but it doesn't use the internet while you're actually
Speaker 13:  using it. Disconnect it from your
Speaker 2:  Phone. I see.
Speaker 13:  Okay. So that is a fun option if You can do Bluetooth. But yeah,
Speaker 13:  the Sony one, no Bluetooth, no wifi, you're
Speaker 13:  all set to go. It's like a thumb drive with a screen on it
Speaker 2:  Isn't know while that, that feels like sort of magical now that You can just
Speaker 2:  plug a thing in, drag some MP three files and it just like works. What a
Speaker 2:  concept it is.
Speaker 13:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I will say it is kind of odd that Sony is making this thing as a low
Speaker 2:  end device. 'cause you would think that people who might want something,
Speaker 2:  I guess are also the people who want the kind of high res,
Speaker 2:  super high fidelity audio that you're talking about. To make it as kind of
Speaker 2:  an entry level device is a little surprising. I wonder if Sony imagines this
Speaker 2:  as like mostly a thing for kids. Yeah. Instead of, you know, super
Speaker 2:  duper music fans.
Speaker 13:  That's probably right. Maybe for people who work on military bases,
Speaker 13:  we don't know.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. I mean listen, there's a lot of 'em out there. Yeah. Alright,
Speaker 2:  well no reasonable person should be required to remember that bottle name.
Speaker 2:  So we'll put the, we'll put the link in the show notes, but Andrew, you,
Speaker 2:  you did, this is like the most successfully we've ever answered a hotline
Speaker 2:  question. This is great. We just found the thing
Speaker 13:  Happy to help
Speaker 2:  Anonymous. I hope that helps. Let us know how you feel about the your your
Speaker 2:  cool new Sony Walkman. Andrew, thank you as always.
Speaker 13:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 2:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything.
Speaker 2:  We talked about tons of Quibi coverage. The Virg was alive during
Speaker 2:  Quibi, unlike the Roku Netflix player a million years ago. So we have coverage
Speaker 2:  of the whole life of that company and it is wild to read in retrospect. Plus
Speaker 2:  lots of stuff
Speaker 3:  I.