# Transcript
ID: cce8cc60-d747-4906-80aa-bccd1a847bb3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5163312489323103879/2416802536545814872/s93290-US-5832s-1712921796.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Piece, and Alex Cranz discuss David's review of the Humane AI Pin, Taylor Swift's music back on TikTok, a new party speaker, and much more.
Speaker 2:  Hello. And Welcome To our Chest, the flagship podcast of appreciating The
Speaker 2:  good vibes on the hardware
Speaker 5:  That that might be the truest one we've ever done. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's, that's what we do. But we totally get it. There's room to make
Speaker 2:  things even better. By which I mean functional. Hi, I'm your friend. NELI
Speaker 2:  David. Pierce is here. Hi Alex Cranz is here. Hi.
Speaker 2:  It's a big week on The Vergecast. All right. It's like maybe the biggest
Speaker 2:  week we've ever had because David has reviewed the Humane ai pin. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It it it has come full circle. This really does feel like it's been a very
Speaker 5:  funny experience in that like almost exactly a year ago
Speaker 5:  was that first Ted Talk that Imran Chowdry, the CEO and
Speaker 5:  Co-founder of Humane gave that We were just like, this is nothing.
Speaker 5:  I don't believe it. We basically sat here and we're like, I don't believe
Speaker 5:  any of the things that happened in this demo. And
Speaker 5:  it turned out that's sort of true.
Speaker 2:  We'll get, we'll get to it. We'll get to it. And If you were a fan of arguing
Speaker 2:  about the Vision Pro Score. Boy, get ready for us to Oh hell yeah. Tell
Speaker 2:  you about the Humane score from totally opposite perspectives. I'm ready.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. That happened. Taylor Swift is back on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God. I have some completely irresponsible gossip to share about the
Speaker 2:  status of TikTok in Universal Music Group. I love this. And so, If, you're
Speaker 2:  listening and you feel like you've always wanted to substantiate some gossip.
Speaker 2:  Get ready. 'cause I'm looking for you.
Speaker 2:  There's other news OpenAI and copyright trouble as always. So is Google.
Speaker 6:  I mean, there's really important news, which is that Kobo announced
Speaker 6:  color E-readers. Yes. All three of us are just
Speaker 6:  stoked. The three of us that care.
Speaker 5:  It's just Alex, Alex and
Speaker 2:  Alex again, the flagship podcast of appreciating The good vibes on the hardware.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, exactly. That's, that's a hundred percent that story. That's who you're,
Speaker 2:  yeah. And then the most important news of all, which is that Sony has a new
Speaker 2:  party speaker. Exactly. We're appreciating
Speaker 5:  Lies. This really is a big Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If. you like The Vergecast. You're gonna love this Vergecast
Speaker 2:  that I can promise you. Let's start, let's get right into it. David,
Speaker 2:  you magnetically clipped a robot to your body
Speaker 2:  for several weeks. It was
Speaker 5:  Warm as I want to do.
Speaker 2:  It got warm. It only ever spoke to me and I believe Korean or Arabic.
Speaker 2:  Oh. Because every time I tried to use it, it was locked in a translation
Speaker 2:  loop. So I I have no experience with it. What, you gave it a four,
Speaker 2:  you said it didn't work. Tell us about it. Sure.
Speaker 5:  So the whole idea of the pin and this like new
Speaker 5:  generation of AI gadgets is that your smartphone is actually
Speaker 5:  slower and worse than you think. Basically the
Speaker 5:  idea is like instead of taking out my phone and unlocking it and doing
Speaker 5:  stuff and tapping on screens and typing things, I should just be able to
Speaker 5:  like touch the thing on my chest and
Speaker 5:  it should do things on my behalf. And I think that is like a super
Speaker 5:  interesting idea. Anyone who has ever watched a sci-fi movie ever
Speaker 5:  sort of knows what that looks like.
Speaker 5:  And so I spent a couple of weeks like running around
Speaker 5:  asking it questions about where I was and asking it questions about the
Speaker 5:  world and using it to try to play music and try to, you know, make
Speaker 5:  phone calls, which you can do on the AI pin and you can send text messages
Speaker 5:  and it takes notes for you and all this different stuff. And
Speaker 5:  I am simultaneously more bullish on AI gadgets than
Speaker 5:  ever and so deeply done with
Speaker 5:  the Humane AI pin.
Speaker 2:  All right. I wanna unpack that and I will say
Speaker 2:  bizarrely a huge split in the comment base on this review. Yeah. The
Speaker 2:  commenters on YouTube love the review as far as I can tell. I think you did
Speaker 2:  a great job. Your buddy Ben Strass, we gotta talk to him. He's calling, he's
Speaker 2:  calling in the show later, later today. They're like, this is great. We love
Speaker 2:  this review. All the things we, and then our commenters picked up on the
Speaker 2:  inherent tension of what David just said, which is, this product is horrible,
Speaker 2:  but I'm excited about this category. And said, why nothing about this product
Speaker 2:  has proven that this category is viable. Which I would say is a fair
Speaker 2:  criticism. Why do you think this thing which does not work,
Speaker 2:  I believe is a sentence that is in your review, made you excited about this
Speaker 2:  category?
Speaker 5:  It so this, I mean, this is where we're gonna get into arguing about the
Speaker 5:  score, right? Because it, it, it's not that it doesn't work ever,
Speaker 5:  it works seriously. No, this is like, there were, there were a handful
Speaker 5:  of moments in two weeks of testing this thing that were like
Speaker 5:  legitimately eye-opening, right? Like standing in Penn Station,
Speaker 5:  tap the thing. I'm like, tell me what restaurant this is and if, if it has
Speaker 5:  good reviews and somewhere between one and a thousand
Speaker 5:  seconds later it comes back and, and gives me like real
Speaker 5:  information. Like people like this on the menu. It has 4.3 stars
Speaker 5:  on Google. People say it's a little expensive, but the servers are
Speaker 5:  friendly like that. That is like a astonishingly useful thing
Speaker 5:  to have done for me. Just truthfully. So like one of the things I've
Speaker 5:  discovered is like I have a dog, so I'm forever walking the dog and I
Speaker 5:  have a kid who is often only happy in a stroller. So I'm just forever out
Speaker 5:  walking in my neighborhood. And one thing that
Speaker 5:  I do when I am forever out walking in my neighborhood is I end up like
Speaker 5:  remembering things I need to do. So I'm, I'm constantly like pulling out
Speaker 5:  my phone and using Siri to set reminders or add something to my calendar
Speaker 5:  or just write a note down in my notes app.
Speaker 5:  Every single one of those things better to do on a
Speaker 5:  device that is touching my body, right? Like it was better on my
Speaker 5:  chest than it was in my pocket.
Speaker 5:  All true. Right? So there were like a handful of these moments where I was
Speaker 5:  like, oh, having this thing that actually does abstract away all of the
Speaker 5:  things I have to do to get into my phone and just lets me say the
Speaker 5:  thing that's in my brain and it's then out of my brain. Awesome.
Speaker 5:  Loved it. Great. The problem with the pin
Speaker 5:  is that it doesn't do it enough. And the problem with this whole category
Speaker 5:  is that like I know how to write down a note in my phone and I know when
Speaker 5:  it has worked it, it's annoying, but it works
Speaker 5:  and I can do it reliably every time. The
Speaker 5:  pin I just stopped trusting was the problem, right? So it's like when it
Speaker 5:  works, it's cool. And it worked just enough that I was like,
Speaker 5:  there is, there is something here. This, it's just
Speaker 5:  so far away from that something at this moment that it's like I can't in
Speaker 5:  good conscience tell you to even try it, but like, you should want The good
Speaker 5:  version of this to exist.
Speaker 2:  So I know you talked to Humane through the course of this review. They can't
Speaker 2:  have been surprised by their own pro One assumes they're not hopelessly surprised
Speaker 2:  by their own product. Why did they ship this now? Did you get a
Speaker 2:  sense?
Speaker 5:  I I don't know the answer to that question and I have asked that question
Speaker 5:  to myself and to them many times. I think the, the honest truth is like
Speaker 5:  there comes a time in the process of making hardware where you just have
Speaker 5:  to ship the damn thing. Like it's just really expensive to not
Speaker 5:  ship a product. Especially a product that a lot of people have given you
Speaker 5:  money for. And you have made many of, I
Speaker 5:  think If you were to rewind a year and tell
Speaker 5:  Humane this is the point where they would be Now I would bet they would not
Speaker 5:  be shipping this product right now because they also have, they claim this
Speaker 5:  gigantic software update coming this summer that adds really basic stuff
Speaker 5:  like setting timers. You can't set a timer that's
Speaker 5:  like the joke about assistance is that the only thing they can do is set
Speaker 5:  timers. The joke about Sir is they can only set one Humane can't set any,
Speaker 5:  it can't set any. And
Speaker 2:  So like, look, AI systems are bad at math, I think historically is a thing.
Speaker 2:  And so just counting must be very challenging for you. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's totally down
Speaker 2:  Even harder.
Speaker 5:  But, but yeah. So there's this big software update supposedly coming this
Speaker 5:  summer that's gonna add some of that functionality and, and fix some of the
Speaker 5:  things that don't work now. So my guess would be they
Speaker 5:  want to ship the like August version of this thing today.
Speaker 5:  And that is just not where they are. But like there comes a time
Speaker 5:  when, for a variety of reasons you're just locked in to when something ships
Speaker 5:  and it's really expensive and really hard, especially for a first generation
Speaker 5:  hardware company to delay by months and months. Yeah. It's just
Speaker 2:  Hard. Alright, let's take it in pieces. 'cause there's a line in your review
Speaker 2:  where you say, none of this is ready. Not the hardware, not the software,
Speaker 2:  not the ai. That's a, that's all of it.
Speaker 5:  That's all the things that's
Speaker 2:  That's all of it.
Speaker 5:  I'm ready. That's one thing
Speaker 2:  You very clearly are ready for this thing.
Speaker 6:  David's a 10 out of 10. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  He's he's ready. He's ready to go. Yeah, of course. There's a picture in
Speaker 2:  the review of David using the thing where he just looks like the world's
Speaker 2:  happiest secret service agent. you know, he's just like, he's just beyond
Speaker 2:  thrilled to be like tapping on his chest and whispering a secret, you know?
Speaker 2:  So you're obviously ready, but the thing isn't ready. Let's start with the
Speaker 2:  hardware. Three pieces, right? Hardware, software, ai. Yeah. What about
Speaker 2:  the hardware isn't ready?
Speaker 5:  The hardware is kind of in the thing
Speaker 5:  we see a lot with first generation hardware, which is just, it's full of
Speaker 5:  little wonky bugs. The biggest one
Speaker 5:  by a mile is thermals. Like this thing is small. I have it sitting
Speaker 5:  right here. Like it's, it's, it's,
Speaker 2:  It is shockingly small. I saw it big in the office and I was amazed at how
Speaker 2:  small
Speaker 5:  It's, yeah, it is like not a large thing and it's, it's a nicely made thing.
Speaker 5:  It's made of aluminum. It's pretty durable. I've dropped it, I threw it in
Speaker 5:  the wash the other day just to see it's,
Speaker 6:  It's pretty big to put on your chest. Like,
Speaker 5:  I mean yes, it, that's compared to all of the other chest wearables
Speaker 5:  that I've had in my life.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it, it's like, it's like broach size and how many people do you know
Speaker 6:  that wear broaches that aren't 80 and at church?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But they kill it. Those
Speaker 2:  Bro. Huge market though. Those people are sitting on an enormous amount of
Speaker 2:  wealth that they have to transfer to their children. Some, I mean,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, and they can just transfer it into Humane
Speaker 5:  Kids.
Speaker 2:  It's directly to Humane,
Speaker 2:  but it's, it's smaller than you think, but bigger than it should be I think
Speaker 2:  is a fair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I think that's exactly right. It is, it is both too big and impressively
Speaker 5:  small for sure. But the biggest pro, I mean I'm holding it now. I've been
Speaker 5:  holding it in my hand for 15 seconds and it's warm. Like
Speaker 5:  I'm not kidding. That's like a real thing that's happening right now. And
Speaker 5:  that is the overwhelming issue, right? It gets warm when you use it.
Speaker 5:  It gets warm so quickly when you use it that it pretty frequently
Speaker 5:  overheats and shuts down. It gets warm when
Speaker 5:  service is bad. Which service is often bad because you're using like, they're
Speaker 5:  using some weird MVNO of T-Mobile that doesn't God really work.
Speaker 5:  So it's just like, again, all these are things that like most of the time
Speaker 5:  when we review a first gadget from a company, it's like this, like
Speaker 5:  the first pixel watch had a lot of little tiny hardware bugs.
Speaker 5:  And that's the kind of stuff where you're like, okay, this is the sort of
Speaker 5:  stuff that with an extra couple of revs of the tooling
Speaker 5:  and the engineering and working on this, you actually start to solve these.
Speaker 5:  So there's like, in the hardware, there's not a lot that I would call like
Speaker 5:  show stopping bad. It's just that
Speaker 5:  none of it is quite ready. But the main thing that really like
Speaker 5:  causes problems is like it, it'd be nice to be able to use this thing and
Speaker 5:  you use it and it's like you can't anymore because it's too hot and it
Speaker 5:  also, right, let's send the video sits on your skin,
Speaker 2:  Right? So it gets hot and shuts itself down. Which If you
Speaker 2:  will recall was happening a lot in the demos at efa.
Speaker 2:  The trade show there. I think we were, everyone rightfully was like, well
Speaker 2:  it's a trade show, bad wifi, bad cell signal using generous a trade show.
Speaker 2:  Generous. Generous we given of doubt. That's exactly right. It
Speaker 2:  feels like you were probably not using it on the floor of a
Speaker 2:  trade show in Berlin.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I do love a trade show. Yeah, but no, I was using it, I was
Speaker 5:  using it at my house, I was using it in our office. I was using it on the
Speaker 5:  streets of New York and Washington DC Like I I, one of the weird things
Speaker 5:  about reviewing this is that it's not
Speaker 5:  a gadget you're supposed to use very much. Like the whole point of it is
Speaker 5:  that you don't use it all the time. You can just like quickly accomplish
Speaker 5:  the thing you need to accomplish and then put it away. And to that I would
Speaker 5:  say it's $700. That's insane. But,
Speaker 5:  so it's like, it was a weird thing to test in that sense because it's like,
Speaker 5:  yes, if I use this thing constantly for several hours,
Speaker 5:  it's gonna, it it's gonna die. Like the battery life in that sense
Speaker 5:  is bad. But you're only supposed to use it for
Speaker 5:  like a few seconds at a time, a dozen times a day. And
Speaker 5:  that is very different from what it takes to actually like test the edges
Speaker 5:  of a product like this. So I, I struggled with that a lot in the course of
Speaker 5:  this. It's like it has this little green laser projector that it's like if
Speaker 5:  I use that for a three minutes at a go, it overheats and the
Speaker 5:  battery dies.
Speaker 2:  That's, so I, that's the one that's just a flaw in
Speaker 2:  the product. Yes. Straightforwardly, If you use its display
Speaker 2:  for more than a few minutes. It shuts down.
Speaker 2:  You there's being generous, there's the benefit, the
Speaker 6:  Doubt. Yeah. No, that's just bad. How are you supposed to watch Dune too?
Speaker 2:  Like come on as, as villain view as he is the author
Speaker 2:  intended. Yeah. Great. So there's that,
Speaker 2:  right? Like some parts of it don't work and it just overheats. Then there's
Speaker 2:  the battery life, which I think in all product reviewing is
Speaker 2:  challenging 'cause we overuse this stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's like our job.
Speaker 5:  I tried to like alternate days between like use the hell out of
Speaker 5:  this and use it like a regular person and on the, on the use
Speaker 5:  the hell out of it days. I mean I killed it comes with the, the thing itself,
Speaker 5:  two extra batteries and a charging case and I would kill
Speaker 5:  all of those in a, in a day of like heavily testing the thing.
Speaker 5:  On a normal day I would kill the two battery boosters and
Speaker 5:  the thing, but like I would get through the day, I would charge everything
Speaker 5:  overnight and it would be fine. So it's like, it was kind of like being a
Speaker 5:  power user of a phone on a normal day. So like that I track is like not great,
Speaker 5:  but not showstopping. But it's like, again, if I look at the
Speaker 5:  screen, it dies. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So that's the, just like the thermals and the battery, right? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  yeah. Like the seam inherently flawed. If the thing is overheating and the
Speaker 2:  batteries are dying too fast, then there's this screen, right? Just keeping
Speaker 2:  on with the hardware or the projector, which there's
Speaker 2:  again, the line in your review is like they try to do everything possible
Speaker 2:  to not have a screen and then they have this,
Speaker 5:  This thing should just have a tiny touch screen. Like I'm, I, I am so a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent convinced that for the stuff they want to do with the screen, which
Speaker 5:  is basically like simple music playback settings,
Speaker 5:  menus, and to be able to look at a text instead of
Speaker 5:  having it spoken aloud to you tiny touchscreen, the end.
Speaker 2:  But then you'd have to take it off and like look at the screen. This I I
Speaker 2:  I was reading that and I'd like, but then you would have to manipulate it
Speaker 2:  instead of having it clipped to your chest. No, you do this, you go, you
Speaker 2:  one of these
Speaker 5:  Look upside down. Yeah. Yeah. I would remind you that either way I'm, I'm
Speaker 5:  putting my hand right here. Like my hand is out. I have
Speaker 5:  to use my
Speaker 2:  Hand. But this is seamless and has lasers.
Speaker 5:  It does have lasers. You cannot take away the lasers.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying, do you want a laser projector? Do you want to fiddle with
Speaker 2:  not a smartphone touchscreen look, A laser projector, let's go for it.
Speaker 2:  Sure. I know how that decision was made. Yes, but it doesn't work is
Speaker 2:  the issue. Correct? Like I, I watched the video of you trying to use the
Speaker 2:  menu If, you haven't seen this video, pull over in your car, it's so good.
Speaker 2:  And just watch David like rotate his hand in frustration
Speaker 2:  and then imagine that like you're any person encountering
Speaker 2:  David on the street, but you don't know, like it's just him rotating
Speaker 2:  his hand and getting increasingly frustrated.
Speaker 5:  I I really like, I I have been accused by a couple of people of like
Speaker 5:  acting out that part and I I cannot
Speaker 5:  explain to you the extent to which that is not an exaggeration
Speaker 5:  of the current situation. Like
Speaker 5:  they just tried so many things. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  it's, they tried too many things and not enough of them work.
Speaker 5:  And so it's like, there there are just so many little pieces of it where
Speaker 5:  it's like you, you, you hold your hand out and if it was just
Speaker 5:  a thing for like look at this text instead of having it read to you out loud,
Speaker 5:  great. Makes total sense. And actually does that job fairly well unless
Speaker 5:  you're in bright light, in which case it doesn't work at all. Yeah. And you
Speaker 5:  can't see anything projecting like, I don't know how you've put me in the
Speaker 5:  position of having to defend this device that I hate.
Speaker 2:  No, this is the heart of your review. You're, you, the
Speaker 2:  heart of your review is you saying that it doesn't work and then
Speaker 2:  it's broken and that no one should buy it. And then being like, but I love
Speaker 2:  it. Yeah. It was so good. It's in there. There's like a real tension in there.
Speaker 2:  I don't love it. I feel, I feel like it's because you have a toddler and
Speaker 2:  you know, I toddlers are notoriously bad at things
Speaker 2:  and you like love 'em. You're like, oh man, you don't know what you're doing.
Speaker 2:  Like I could see people dad just like coming through. That might be
Speaker 5:  True.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like you, you were just like really happy about the
Speaker 6:  idea. Like they were trying something and it seemed like David was like,
Speaker 6:  you know what? I respect you for trying,
Speaker 5:  I just, do you remember, do you remember the early thing that they said about
Speaker 5:  the Apple watch? Which is like, this is, this is a closer to you
Speaker 5:  and more aware of you computer.
Speaker 5:  I still want that. Like yeah, that, I think that was a good idea
Speaker 5:  in 2015. And I think it's a good idea now and it
Speaker 5:  is just alarming how not close we are to that technology,
Speaker 5:  but like I I just, an Apple watch plus
Speaker 5:  good Siri is still a thing that I want and would use all the time and
Speaker 5:  I actually think has like a real place in our lives and but, and
Speaker 5:  now everybody's like, okay, well we're gonna do that but we're gonna bake
Speaker 5:  in these better language models and generative AI and we're gonna be able
Speaker 5:  to actually put all the pieces together. And the answer is like, nope, we,
Speaker 5:  we didn't do it yet. It's not even close. But like again, I I'm a decade
Speaker 5:  deep into being like, yeah I do want a computer that is closer
Speaker 5:  to me than my smartphone and we
Speaker 5:  just don't have it yet.
Speaker 2:  At the end of this we're gonna rank our children on a one to 10 scale. Let's
Speaker 2:  see if they're worth the ongoing subscription fees that we are clearly paying.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be great. So that's the hardware, right? It's buggy that the projector
Speaker 2:  doesn't work very well. Overheats problem one
Speaker 2:  then you're like, the software which I did not know was called Cosmos.
Speaker 2:  Mm Yeah. C-O-S-M-O-S Kobo very good.
Speaker 2:  They
Speaker 5:  Just call it Cosmos, but it is definitely
Speaker 2:  Cos
Speaker 5:  It's an os. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They very good
Speaker 6:  Cosmo
Speaker 2:  Unrelated to anything Cosmos just like you both outta nowhere. It's called
Speaker 2:  Cosmos. Why the hell not? Yeah. I have still have the same set
Speaker 2:  of questions actually that I did a year ago. You want this thing to make
Speaker 2:  a phone call, you have to sit around configuring a computer somewhere, right?
Speaker 2:  And that is, that happens on Cosmos, that happens on their website. Like
Speaker 2:  what does Cosmos do? Does it run applications?
Speaker 5:  So what
Speaker 6:  Does it do?
Speaker 2:  Like what is the point of an OS and a thing that is just a voice activated
Speaker 2:  chat GPT? I don't know. So because
Speaker 5:  It's not just a voice activated chat GPT, right? Right. Like that's the,
Speaker 5:  the, the thing that Cosmos is basically is like an overlapping
Speaker 5:  Venn diagram of AI systems. So like when it wants to
Speaker 5:  do something very basic on the device, that's one system when it wants
Speaker 5:  to go to basic internet real time questions, that's another
Speaker 5:  system. I think it's perplexity, but I can't vouch for that
Speaker 5:  for sure. Perplexity is on every other device that's doing this. So
Speaker 5:  it seems like a natural assumption. But basically Cosmos is like the routing
Speaker 5:  system for you wanna do a thing, where does it go?
Speaker 5:  And just the fact that that exists is part of the problem because
Speaker 5:  what it means is every time you want to do anything, you
Speaker 5:  have to ask Cosmos to do it for you. And then it goes and figures out
Speaker 5:  what it needs to do. It assembles all those tools, pings those tools to do
Speaker 5:  the thing, comes back, translates all that into an answer and give it to
Speaker 5:  you. And you know what that does is it takes so
Speaker 2:  Long,
Speaker 5:  It takes so long and the the biggest
Speaker 5:  overwhelming problem with the pin as a user experience
Speaker 5:  is even when it works, it's slow to the point of being
Speaker 5:  borderline unusable in, in most situations. Like
Speaker 5:  the, the thing where you ask at the time and it tells you the time so fast,
Speaker 5:  just beautiful. It tells me the time so fast for almost
Speaker 5:  everything else. It is somewhere between five and 30 seconds
Speaker 5:  of dead silence while it tries to do something for you. And the silence,
Speaker 5:  I got to the point where literally I'm like, I wish this thing had hold music.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So at least I could know it was doing something like
Speaker 2:  The or computer sounds like do, do, do do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right, right. The the like old dial up sound when it boots
Speaker 5:  up to go do something for you. Like give me that
Speaker 2:  Actually this thing would be incredible if it made like 56 K modem sounds.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that'd be good. Every the time I went out to the internet, everyone
Speaker 2:  around, you'd be like, what is happening bong like all over the place. It
Speaker 2:  would be fair. We're just, we gonna make modem sounds for the rest of the
Speaker 2:  show.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's the rest of the show. It's a good show guys. Don't
Speaker 5:  Worry about it.
Speaker 2:  It's, we're, we're nominated for a webby. If you'd like to vote for the rich
Speaker 5:  Cast, this one for a modem sounds,
Speaker 5:  this will not be the episode that we send it to the weddings.
Speaker 2:  So it's slow. I mean this is the thing that I, I've been thinking about a
Speaker 2:  lot, right? So you ask Cosmos, you ask the AI pin to do
Speaker 2:  something, the operating system cosmos what assembles a prompt or like
Speaker 2:  first it figures out if it knows what request you're asking,
Speaker 2:  what system on the backend should do the request and then it
Speaker 2:  it assembles a prompt for you and goes and asks that system.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's that's about right. I think there are, there are versions
Speaker 5:  of it that are less kind of generative ai prompt based. Like if
Speaker 5:  it's just connecting to title, it doesn't have to do quite as many complicated
Speaker 5:  things.
Speaker 2:  No, this is the reason I asked this question in that way. 'cause when you
Speaker 2:  asked it to play Texas Holden by Beyonce Yeah
Speaker 2:  I think the Unicode character in Beyonce's name, she has an accent over the
Speaker 2:  e in her name. It like broke it. It did. So it spat out the
Speaker 2:  Unicode number or like the hex code and then
Speaker 2:  it, you know, when like they broke Bing and turned it into Sydney.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. In whatever prompt exploit showed you like the
Speaker 2:  instructions to make Sydney not be horny and d bing like it
Speaker 2:  did that. Right. It was like ask for a prompt in this way, don't tell the
Speaker 2:  user or the other thing, blah blah blah. And I was like this,
Speaker 5:  Don't ask for clarification. I enjoyed
Speaker 2:  That part. Don't ask for clarification is incredible. Yeah. It's beautiful.
Speaker 2:  So it was, it was that, right? It was like those pre rule that the instruction
Speaker 2:  set right. For the ai but you were just asking to play music which should
Speaker 2:  not require an ai.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Agreed. Right. And so that's that what you're seeing there is I believe
Speaker 5:  the work of Cosmos, right? Which is like, it takes me saying play music,
Speaker 5:  it says,
Speaker 2:  Oh I believe this is the work of the cosmos, this is the
Speaker 5:  Work of the cosmos somewhere Neil deGrasse Tyson is screaming
Speaker 2:  Actually.
Speaker 5:  And it, it then figures out what I'm asking and to what
Speaker 5:  it should go ask. But I don't, I it's, I could be
Speaker 5:  completely wrong, but I don't think title is running like an
Speaker 5:  LLM against its own music. I think it just has an API that cosmos is plugging
Speaker 5:  into to find that song. So that's what I mean like the end points don't all
Speaker 5:  have to be ai right. But in the middle there is this mysterious
Speaker 5:  AI translator that just isn't very good. And even when it is good, it's really
Speaker 5:  slow.
Speaker 2:  Did you ask Humane if they, anyone had ever tried to listen to Beyonce on
Speaker 2:  their product? So
Speaker 5:  They, they did say that particular thing was a bug and they fixed it. And
Speaker 5:  it is true that since then I have not gotten Unicode spat back at me.
Speaker 5:  But it still will not consistently play Beyonce when I
Speaker 5:  ask it to play Beyonce. So like it's, it's broken in a sort of less
Speaker 5:  spectacular way now, but it is still very much broken.
Speaker 2:  But this is the part where I'm just still stuck on. Okay, so Cosmos,
Speaker 2:  it's doing prompts right? Like that revealed that there is
Speaker 2:  some LLM style prompting system happening in
Speaker 2:  there and you are interacting with your voice with
Speaker 2:  an LLM that then might go do stuff like play a title song through the
Speaker 2:  API. Yeah. So is it running that model locally or is that
Speaker 2:  happening in the cloud?
Speaker 5:  No, all of that is happening in the cloud as far as I can tell. It
Speaker 5:  does essentially nothing locally.
Speaker 6:  So it's heat is coming from the fact that it is constantly trying to
Speaker 6:  use its garbage antennas to connect to garbage. T-Mobile internet.
Speaker 2:  Wow, that's a lot of garbage out. There's
Speaker 6:  A lot of garbage. I mean I assume they're garbage antennas. They may be lovely,
Speaker 6:  but in practice they seem not great.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's, it's very small. The whole device is very small and is doing
Speaker 5:  a lot of really aggressive thermal throttling, which is not great when
Speaker 5:  what you need is reliable fast connectivity. Yeah. So yeah, I know, I I think
Speaker 5:  you're exactly right And the first answer that Humane gave
Speaker 5:  me as to why this thing is warm is connectivity. But again, it
Speaker 5:  didn't seem to matter if it was good or bad, it's just when it is connected
Speaker 5:  it is warm and it is connected all the time.
Speaker 6:  Well be the nice in the winter time.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Like a hand warmer. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I've been telling people that the, the comparison for me is like, you know
Speaker 5:  that thing where you, you you like crack the hand warmer and put it somewhere
Speaker 5:  and it kind of is there for too long and it's not like burning,
Speaker 5:  but it's like a little, you, you've sort of overheated one small part of
Speaker 5:  your body. That's what it feels like to wear the pin all the time.
Speaker 2:  Do you ever get what I have imagined it is you ever get thermal runaway
Speaker 2:  in your phone, like your phone just like over tries to connect and gets hot
Speaker 2:  in your pocket for like one second. Yeah. And you're like, why?
Speaker 6:  And you're oh my butt's on fire,
Speaker 2:  What is going on? Yeah. And then sometimes I'm not saying my brain is
Speaker 2:  broken this way, it just feels like that's happening anyway even though it's
Speaker 2:  not because you have too many phones in your life. Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's basically right. That
Speaker 6:  May just be a Vergecast
Speaker 2:  Situation. It's a very, but for this audience, yeah, we're gonna make modem
Speaker 2:  sound for the next 30 minutes. So so
Speaker 2:  that's the software, right? It's running this os in the cloud
Speaker 2:  that appears to be LLM style that can go take actions with other LLMs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's
Speaker 2:  What about the, just the, the nuts and bolts of it? Like how do you put contacts
Speaker 2:  into it?
Speaker 5:  So that part, they, they have a web app called Humane Center. They all call
Speaker 5:  it.center 'cause the website is Humane dot center. That is
Speaker 5:  basically a pretty simple just way to
Speaker 5:  manage your thing. Like it's, it's the equivalent of like when you buy a
Speaker 5:  device that connects to your phone and you download the companion app to
Speaker 5:  like get everything connected. It's just that in the web. But it's,
Speaker 5:  when you take photos, that's where the photos upload. When you
Speaker 5:  do notes, that's where your notes go. It keeps track of all of the things
Speaker 5:  you've asked and all of the responses. So this is like, when I say I'm transcribing
Speaker 5:  the thing, I'm literally copying and pasting from its record of
Speaker 5:  our interaction anyway. And the way you connect it is right now
Speaker 5:  you just go in and you log in with your Google account or your Microsoft
Speaker 5:  account and that downloads your contacts. And again, this
Speaker 5:  is why it's so inexcusable that this stuff doesn't work. Like, you know what
Speaker 5:  else is in my Google account is my email and my calendar and so many other
Speaker 5:  pieces of information that would be useful for my pin to know. But it just,
Speaker 5:  it just doesn't have those things despite the fact that it has access to
Speaker 5:  my Google account. But I actually like it. This
Speaker 5:  was a little bit hard to test because as part of the review process, Humane
Speaker 5:  did some of that setup for me ahead of time,
Speaker 5:  which I ca I don't totally know why, but that is just how it worked.
Speaker 5:  And so I don't have perfect out of the box setup up
Speaker 5:  information on exactly how that works. But I do know that it, I spent five
Speaker 5:  minutes in the center like getting accounts connected and then never really
Speaker 5:  thought about it again.
Speaker 2:  So it it it can sync your contacts.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean that's, that's all, that's all it's doing. So like when I say,
Speaker 5:  you know, call NELI, it looks in my
Speaker 5:  contacts and finds NELI and then people I know named
Speaker 5:  Eli and then my friend Marin for some reason. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Good stuff. But, but, but your contacts, there's just like basic stuff. Ask
Speaker 2:  it to make a phone call to someone. It needs my name and my phone number
Speaker 2:  in a database. Did you put that in the database or did it syn it from
Speaker 2:  Google?
Speaker 5:  It pulled that from Google.
Speaker 2:  So it it did do that. Yeah. And then when you, I guess you asked it to send
Speaker 2:  an email, but it can't send an email yet.
Speaker 5:  That's right. It just doesn't have an email feature. No, you can do things
Speaker 5:  like, you can give it memory in the way that like chat
Speaker 5:  GPT has memory now where you can say like, remember that Anna is my wife.
Speaker 5:  Remember that this is the number I call NELI on.
Speaker 5:  And like that kind of stuff you can do sort of piece by piece
Speaker 5:  manually. But like in general, I have probably multiple numbers for both
Speaker 5:  of you. If I went to call it would be like, it does this thing Siri does,
Speaker 5:  right? Where it's like, which number do you wanna call? I hate that. I'm
Speaker 5:  like, it's the one I always use. Like what are we talking about here? But
Speaker 5:  anyway, but yeah, it is, it's pulling that directly from Google.
Speaker 6:  I really love that it's an AI that doesn't remember like
Speaker 6:  the favorite number for you automatically.
Speaker 5:  So much of this stuff is, yeah, that
Speaker 6:  Feels like just a core thing AI should solve and be good
Speaker 2:  At the I dial this number all the time. Yeah, yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  I hate
Speaker 2:  That one. Yeah. Call, call Becky iPhone. It's like there's no other phone,
Speaker 2:  there's just all these old numbers I haven't cleared out. Yeah, right. That's
Speaker 2:  the software. Is there anything else to say about the software? does.center
Speaker 2:  work on a phone? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's fine. It's a web app. Like again, it is, it's, I I didn't
Speaker 5:  dwell on it much in the review because it's kind of the least interesting
Speaker 5:  part of it is like, it's just a very simple device management
Speaker 5:  app. Like if you've ever been in the settings for your Google account to
Speaker 5:  like see what apps it's connected to. It's just that it's,
Speaker 2:  The reason I'm asking is 'cause all the stuff it wants to do, like photos
Speaker 2:  syncing, does it send the photos to Google Photos by itself? Or do you have
Speaker 2:  to download them and upload them?
Speaker 5:  You have to download them and upload them. Which is, I would argue maybe
Speaker 5:  the single biggest gap in this because you, if you're
Speaker 5:  Humane you can solve a lot of your feature problems just by connecting to
Speaker 5:  other services, right? Like it can't do reminders like fine just pipe
Speaker 5:  two reminders on my phone. Yeah, it doesn't do calendar.
Speaker 5:  That's fine. I've already logged you into my calendar. Like
Speaker 5:  there's so many of these things that it's Right,
Speaker 2:  But then they, they can't, right? Like ideologically they're like, that stuff
Speaker 2:  is bad. We're doing it the new way with prompt engineering. That's
Speaker 5:  Right. And yeah, I think what you'll see over time I would bet
Speaker 5:  is Humane Humane has big ideas about people
Speaker 5:  building stuff for Cosmos and like it being sort of its own app
Speaker 5:  universe. But I think pretty quickly you're gonna start to see it go the
Speaker 5:  other way too and just plug into a lot more services. And then the
Speaker 5:  pin becomes like a universal input system for all of your other
Speaker 5:  systems, which I think is a way more compelling idea than having it be its
Speaker 5:  own like self-contained universe.
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  Right. Right Now it shuts down If, you use it for more than a couple minutes.
Speaker 2:  That's, I just wanna come back to the, there's that, okay, so that's hardware,
Speaker 2:  that's Cosmos software. And then the last thing you said, which I think is
Speaker 2:  the most, the biggest one to unpack, which is the AI stuff isn't ready.
Speaker 2:  What do you mean by that?
Speaker 5:  I don't know If, you guys know this, but AI is a liar sometimes.
Speaker 5:  And so the, I would put it into like three buckets, right? There's like the
Speaker 5:  stuff that just straight up doesn't work where you're like,
Speaker 5:  I need to set a timer or like there's a piece of information that I need
Speaker 5:  that this tool does not have access to right now. One of the things that
Speaker 5:  they showed at the very beginning in those early demos was nutrition stuff
Speaker 5:  where you like point it at, I think it was a handful of almonds in that first
Speaker 5:  demo. Is that right? Or like a chocolate bar bar. It was nuts. It was nuts.
Speaker 5:  And you ask like, is this good for me? And
Speaker 5:  that those features just don't work yet. It, what it can do I discovered
Speaker 5:  is read a label sometimes again, sometimes,
Speaker 5:  sometimes it couldn't read a label on a bag of Chex Mix and tell me if it
Speaker 5:  was healthy, but it could read a label on a box of Cheerios and tell me it
Speaker 5:  was healthy. So that doesn't make any sense. But anyway, so there's a set
Speaker 5:  of things that can't do and like the nutrition stuff j just doesn't exist
Speaker 5:  yet. That's like a feature they invented for that demo that is not yet on
Speaker 5:  the pin. Then there's stuff that sort of
Speaker 5:  occasionally works because AI is a liar sometimes. And I feel like my favorite
Speaker 5:  example of that was like running around asking it to sort of tell me
Speaker 5:  about the world, right? And it's like it has this feature called vision that
Speaker 5:  it could you say like, look at this building and tell me when it's open
Speaker 5:  or look at this restaurant and tell me if it has good reviews.
Speaker 5:  Sometimes it gets that right. And again, it's very cool when it does and
Speaker 5:  other times it's just full lies. It told me
Speaker 5:  there are a bunch of great moments like this in the video where we were down
Speaker 5:  at the New York Stock Exchange and there was this company called Ride
Speaker 5:  RYDE that I, I assume had just iPod that day. So they had the big banner
Speaker 5:  outside and I pointed it at it and I said, look at this and tell me what
Speaker 5:  company it is. And it thinks and thinks and thinks and thinks and thinks.
Speaker 5:  And then eventually goes, this company is called Lyft Very
Speaker 5:  confidently
Speaker 7:  So confident.
Speaker 5:  And sometimes it would, it would misidentify buildings, it would tell me
Speaker 5:  I was in completely the wrong place in New York City. It told me the Brooklyn
Speaker 5:  Bridge was the tribal bridge with absolute a hundred percent confidence.
Speaker 5:  Sometimes it would break and just describe the scene around me. I'd be
Speaker 5:  like, what bridge is that? And it would be like, in, in the scene there are
Speaker 5:  two poles in the water and buildings across the way. And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  what are those buildings? And it would be like, they're buildings.
Speaker 7:  Okay. It's
Speaker 5:  Close. Yeah, it's great. And then the third thing is just stuff that
Speaker 5:  it just constantly fails at all the time,
Speaker 5:  which is like things that it should be able to do and just can't, like
Speaker 5:  make a phone call where it was like half the time, truly half I would say
Speaker 5:  like, call NELI or call Anna, text somebody
Speaker 5:  and it just wouldn't do it. And I think like, there are a bunch of
Speaker 5:  problems with this. I also wrote about this company this week called
Speaker 5:  Aboard, which is doing some really interesting like visual AI
Speaker 5:  information organization stuff. And they were doing a demo for me and
Speaker 5:  he at one point like types in the prompt and just nothing happens. And his
Speaker 5:  co-founder is like, oh no, what, what do you think went wrong? And he just
Speaker 5:  goes, ah, that's, that's just the ai. And it's just like, it's, it's like
Speaker 5:  a little like fear animal that you like can't quite
Speaker 5:  trust, but it's like sometimes around being cute and you're like, oh, what
Speaker 5:  am I? And so like that's just true. And so you're trying to interact with
Speaker 5:  this thing that sometimes just decides it doesn't like you and doesn't wanna
Speaker 5:  work. Other times it's just a moron and just can't
Speaker 5:  do lots of stuff. I,
Speaker 2:  I point out, once again, you're describing a toddler I
Speaker 7:  Was about to say like, that's a child. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Sometimes you just, why are you, why are you trying to kill yourself kid?
Speaker 2:  Right. Just stop it.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 7:  For right in the, the socket
Speaker 2:  Just directly.
Speaker 7:  Great.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Arthur's new thing is he likes to pick up the dog's water bowl and
Speaker 5:  just pour it all over himself and then get upset about how wet he is.
Speaker 7:  Well,
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 2:  Humane Pin everyone. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  But so that's the thing. And it's really, it's the like stuff it can't do
Speaker 5:  you solve over time, right? Like there are, there are features you can build
Speaker 5:  that's that I understand how we get out of the, it
Speaker 5:  lies unpredictably and at random and about everything.
Speaker 5:  This is like the fundamental problem of AI to me right now. Right? It is
Speaker 5:  like I spent so much time asking a question, even a basic
Speaker 5:  question. Like I, it turns out like half my search history is just asking
Speaker 5:  questions about things my dog ate. Like is is he going to, or is she going
Speaker 5:  to die because she ate this? And the answer's usually
Speaker 5:  no. So that's good. But I found myself, I would ask the pin that question,
Speaker 5:  it would give me an answer and then I would have to get out my phone and
Speaker 5:  check Yeah. Just to make sure, because I don't trust the ai because you shouldn't
Speaker 5:  trust the ai and it just completely
Speaker 5:  defeats the purpose. And like we're so far away from these things being
Speaker 5:  reliably honest and reliably fast and reliably
Speaker 5:  useful that it's like what's the, what's the point?
Speaker 2:  So the the thing that I'm stuck on is you stack the unreliability in this
Speaker 2:  product, right? Yes. You have Cosmos, which appears to
Speaker 2:  be some sort of AI system that's like parsing a request and then figurine
Speaker 2:  out what to do. And then often it's going to another AI system, which is
Speaker 2:  chat GPT in a lot of cases it feels like, which is unreliable in its specific
Speaker 2:  ways or perplexity, which is in unreliable. It's specific ways.
Speaker 2:  I asked per perplexity to compare how long
Speaker 2:  a car I'm thinking about buying is with my current car. And it just couldn't
Speaker 2:  figure it out. It was just like the, the length of a Jeep Grand Cherokee
Speaker 2:  is not available. And I was like, that's, I'm pretty sure it's available.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's a lot. And I asked it again and said, please provide me the
Speaker 2:  length of the Jeep Grand Cherokee.
Speaker 5:  Like, no, that's literally your job.
Speaker 2:  It's like, just go get, you're a search engine, just do it. Just
Speaker 2:  figure it out. But that's like you're stacking it up, right? You're
Speaker 2:  stacking up one unreliable LLM with another one with potentially another
Speaker 2:  one. And you, it just feels like you get to a place where it's,
Speaker 2:  it's fun. But all of that is almost guaranteed to have a mistake
Speaker 2:  embedded in somewhere.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Or so
Speaker 2:  A hallucination embedded in somewhere.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I, I had a call with Bethany Bonno, the co-founder of
Speaker 5:  Humane the day before the review went live, just to basically be like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  this thing is not kind. Just like no surprises, wanna let you know what's
Speaker 5:  coming. This is the thing we do with a lot of stories. Just like you, you
Speaker 5:  should not be surprised by what's coming. Yeah. This is,
Speaker 2:  This is like, we had questions core journalism
Speaker 5:  Too. Yeah, yeah. And I, I, I had questions and I was like, If, you wanna
Speaker 5:  respond to some of these things, let me know. And that was when, you know,
Speaker 5:  she started talking about software updates. But I started by saying, here's
Speaker 5:  what I wanna understand is like a lot of these things just straight up
Speaker 5:  don't work and I can't figure out whose fault it is.
Speaker 5:  Like is it yours as, as hardware builders? Is it yours
Speaker 5:  as software builders? Is it the AI models
Speaker 5:  underlying a lot of this? Is it the end points that don't know how to interact
Speaker 5:  with those LLMs? Like who is it? And she literally just laughed and, and
Speaker 5:  the answer is kind of everybody. But the problem is, you're exactly right.
Speaker 5:  Until all of that stuff is good, not just one part of it, but
Speaker 5:  until all of it is extremely reliable and fast and
Speaker 5:  good, none of it works.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So now we come to the heart of the matter here on The Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  which is, I read the review in drafts. I did not
Speaker 2:  receive a no surprises phone call. I just read the review in Google
Speaker 2:  Docs. And at the bottom, David gave it a four out of 10. And then he
Speaker 2:  left himself a note that said maybe this should be a three. I was told fine
Speaker 2:  with a four. And I add the comment and I said it should be a three. And you
Speaker 2:  did, you
Speaker 5:  Said you should give it a three LOL. Yeah. Was the entirety of your comment?
Speaker 2:  I think I made myself clear.
Speaker 2:  We've just described a thing that overheats that does not work for more than
Speaker 2:  minutes at a time. Who software is often confused by the existence of
Speaker 2:  Beyonce unforgivable sin and it shows reliant on a number
Speaker 2:  of systems that lie to you consistently and may murder your
Speaker 2:  dog. That $700, I think is what I would say with a
Speaker 2:  $24 month.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. I was gonna say, you have to yell the price at me several times.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna be, it's coming so many times is, is that not a three? What,
Speaker 2:  where'd the extra point come from Pierce
Speaker 5:  It honestly, there there's a decent chance it should have been a three. I
Speaker 5:  I was, I it's like, I'll just, I'll just be honest about
Speaker 2:  That. Every review podcast is just us being like, I should have taken one.
Speaker 5:  No, it's
Speaker 2:  Like,
Speaker 5:  I'll I'll tell you off my logic and you can tell me whether it's fair or
Speaker 5:  not. A three in our score, I believe the exact
Speaker 5:  phrase is bad. That is, that is the first word next to
Speaker 5:  three in our review rubric. Yeah. And I think four
Speaker 5:  is like multiple outstanding issues, I think is what it said. And so
Speaker 5:  it's, it's somewhere between those two things. Right? And for me,
Speaker 5:  I, I tilted the scale based on there were enough
Speaker 5:  things that it did that were cool and valuable
Speaker 5:  and eye-opening that I wouldn't just call it bad, like I, I call
Speaker 5:  it broken on purpose, right? Because it's like, it is not,
Speaker 5:  this is not a stupid product, it's just not a
Speaker 5:  good product. And I think
Speaker 5:  again, it's very possible it's a three. Like I would not tell anyone to buy
Speaker 5:  this product
Speaker 2:  $700 20 10 24
Speaker 2:  a month. It's just funny coming for the guy. Seven. It's very good. What's
Speaker 2:  very good. Would If you give a Vision Pro estimate? No, I, I, I saw the,
Speaker 2:  the score published this morning and I thought to myself, I know exactly
Speaker 2:  how the bridge has goes. Would you
Speaker 5:  Rather have eight eight Humane AI pins
Speaker 5:  or one Vision Pro?
Speaker 2:  I'm taking the cash man, just gimme the cache neither.
Speaker 5:  To be fair, it's also only five Humane pins. But anyway,
Speaker 5:  I, yeah, I I'm, I'm still torn between those two things. And the, the
Speaker 5:  tiebreaker for me was like, was honestly, I think the same as the tiebreaker
Speaker 5:  for you was like, this occasionally does things that are awesome and I
Speaker 5:  don't know how to, I don't know how to factor that in. It doesn't do it often
Speaker 5:  enough. It doesn't do enough of them, but it occasionally does things
Speaker 5:  that you're like, oh, I see it now. And I had, I had just enough of
Speaker 5:  those moments that I was like, okay, this thing is not
Speaker 2:  Reviewer. Like you've spent a long time with a thing. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  then you write about what it's like and then someone else reads it and they're
Speaker 2:  like, Nope. And, but I look bit weird. See, I, I, I
Speaker 2:  read this
Speaker 6:  Review and I was like, you know, the four makes sense because I could see
Speaker 6:  his affection for like what they tried, what they attempted.
Speaker 6:  I could see like, he was like, you know what, there's some cool shit happening
Speaker 6:  here.
Speaker 2:  $700
Speaker 6:  Once
Speaker 2:  Dollars a month, 20
Speaker 6:  Times. You try it. I
Speaker 5:  Think the fairest criticism you can give me of this score is I think if a
Speaker 5:  bigger company had made it, I probably would've given it a three.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But it's a small company.
Speaker 5:  I think I, I think I might have given them one point just for a startup
Speaker 5:  tried to do a hard thing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I, I buy that
Speaker 5:  Ultimately, which I don't think I realized until it had published, but I
Speaker 5:  think that might be what I did.
Speaker 6:  But I think that's okay. Right? I mean
Speaker 5:  It is and it isn't, right? Like it doesn't make the product any better, but
Speaker 5:  it at least, like,
Speaker 5:  I think I, I think I might have given it, like I think if Google had
Speaker 5:  made this thing and it was this exact thing, I think I probably would've
Speaker 5:  been slightly harder on it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Because Google also wouldn't have the same excuses.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like, like I think Humane has some real fundamental
Speaker 6:  acceptable excuses. I mean, not when it comes to money, it has a ton of
Speaker 6:  money.
Speaker 5:  It does.
Speaker 6:  It's, it is not lacking for money, but it is lacking for
Speaker 6:  that experience putting this kind of product out into the world on a
Speaker 6:  consistent basis and taking a big swing. And like Google
Speaker 6:  doesn't do that. Well,
Speaker 2:  If Google had put this out one, they would've leaked it in full like a long
Speaker 2:  time ago. Right.
Speaker 6:  It would've been plastic.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It still wouldn't have properly worked with Genome. Correct.
Speaker 2:  That's a classic. And then we would've taken a point off,
Speaker 2:  like a pre point deduction because they're, they would've killed it in a
Speaker 2:  year.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. We would've known
Speaker 2:  It's gonna, no further updates would be available for this product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. In fact, that's what happened with their last attempt at like a wearable
Speaker 6:  came off, right?
Speaker 2:  It's like we're deducting a point. The Google pre-death point,
Speaker 2:  it's just coming off. I look, I buy the, you know, it's a startup. They did
Speaker 2:  a hard thing, but the way they talk about it actually, I'll, I'll,
Speaker 2:  I will connect it to the Vision Pro. The way Apple talked about the Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro definitely affected how I reviewed the product in the end. Is that
Speaker 2:  fair? Is, it's as fair as
Speaker 2:  Humane being a startup, right? It it affects your perception of the product.
Speaker 2:  And it's like they can't, it couldn't do it couldn't, it couldn't withstand
Speaker 2:  the weight that was being placed on the marketing, which is also
Speaker 2:  1000% true of Humane. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. Humane thing,
Speaker 2:  Right? And like today, you know, the, the joke at the top of the show,
Speaker 2:  Humane put out their statement in response to all the reviews. I don't think
Speaker 2:  they were surprised by these reviews. No. And they said big thanks for all
Speaker 2:  the reviewer feedback on the AI pin. It's been a wild ride from launch till
Speaker 2:  now. Hearing from all of you is super valuable. The team appreciates The
Speaker 2:  good vibes and the hardware and the potential it's unlocking, but we totally
Speaker 2:  get it. There's rooms makes things even better. We'll, all we we're all ears
Speaker 2:  and how we can up our game, especially with Cosmos os your insights are gold
Speaker 2:  guidance. We can improve making AI Pin better for daily use. That is
Speaker 2:  180 degrees different from how they talked about this thing
Speaker 2:  until yesterday. Yeah. Right. And I, there's something
Speaker 2:  there that I think is just really interesting.
Speaker 5:  I would give them 8% more credit than that. I think If, you look at
Speaker 5:  Humane in the last several weeks, they've been putting out this stream of
Speaker 5:  like videos and stuff showing people how to use it and they've been making
Speaker 5:  more jokes at their own expense. I mean, If, you go back to that original
Speaker 5:  launch video, it is the most ludicrously selfer.
Speaker 5:  Like, it's the video where Imran and Bethany are standing there like looking
Speaker 5:  sad as they use their pin. Do you know what I'm talking about? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's beautiful. The video is absurd and it's, it's extra absurd now having
Speaker 5:  used this thing because they, they treat it as if they had invented fire
Speaker 5:  and like it's, it's preposterous. But I think recently
Speaker 5:  for whatever reason they have, they have pulled back a bit and been
Speaker 5:  a little more honest and open about what this thing is and how it works in
Speaker 5:  some of the limitations and all that stuff. And I think that's good. And
Speaker 5:  I, I do, I do wonder, and I have wondered many times if they had
Speaker 5:  launched this thing more the way Rabbit has, which is like, oh, look at this
Speaker 5:  fun silly little toy we made. Isn't it cool looking if I would feel differently?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I'm getting a rabbit in two weeks and I'm very curious to see,
Speaker 6:  I'm so excited how it
Speaker 5:  Feels as a cheaper, much less
Speaker 5:  ambitious in a lot of ways. Gadget.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think, I think the, the score for the Humane pin is
Speaker 6:  reflecting that ambition in kind of a positive way. And we're reflecting,
Speaker 6:  we're saying, you know what, it's okay to be ambitious. That's why the vision,
Speaker 6:  like part of the Vision Pro having a seven is it's ambitious. It, it, it
Speaker 6:  swung for the fences. It missed
Speaker 6:  real bad.
Speaker 2:  Can I just say one thing about Vision Pro? And then we, we,
Speaker 6:  I just like to, I like to poke this at the seven. I can't wait till I read
Speaker 2:  Something. I'm aware that everyone thinks the seven is pure cowardice. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I would just, I would just tell you
Speaker 6:  My Kobo review, we're gonna have like a two hour VERGE cast on the
Speaker 6:  score for, I thought about
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be thought about filing a draft of this review with a seven out
Speaker 5:  of 10 as the score just to see what would've
Speaker 6:  Happened.
Speaker 2:  By the way, one thing about the Vision Pro then we, we then we gotta move
Speaker 2:  on.
Speaker 2:  Hot new app for the Vision Pros and Netflix and Amazon Prime app. It's
Speaker 2:  a browser. It's just a browser with, with the skin on it. Web apps are saving
Speaker 2:  the Vision Pro. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Saving
Speaker 6:  Is generous.
Speaker 2:  I'm saying your YouTube app, your Netflix app, the one that actually supports
Speaker 2:  facial audio.
Speaker 2:  I'm just saying Turnabout's fair play. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Apple apple's like Official accounts. We're recommending that app. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 5:  It's it's gonna be web apps, it's gonna be anything. It's gonna be web apps.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. It's so funny. It's very good. All right, David, I know that
Speaker 2:  you're excited about the prospect of AI gadgets, but I'm sorry man. Maybe
Speaker 2:  the rabbit's gonna do it for you.
Speaker 5:  Probably not.
Speaker 2:  We have to take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  dog.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. There's quite a lot in this section. We thought
Speaker 2:  it was gonna be a, like a lightning round, but we should just start with
Speaker 2:  Taylor Swift, I think. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well that's how we start Every VERGE cast now it feels like.
Speaker 6:  I love Taylor.
Speaker 2:  Who doesn't? I was on the Ezra Klein show and I mentioned Taylor Swift, and
Speaker 2:  he goes, well, she's singular. She can't, you can't win the argument with
Speaker 2:  that. He's very good. He was, he was not wrong. No, but I, I
Speaker 2:  thought I'd like play the Ace card, you know? Yeah. And he was like, Nope.
Speaker 2:  Nope. That's, that's not everyone can be Taylor Swift Hearts broke
Speaker 2:  across America that day. Alright. Taylor Swift famously
Speaker 2:  owns her own masters, but has distribution through Universal Music Group.
Speaker 2:  Also her publishing the songwriting money flows through Universal, universal,
Speaker 2:  you may know. So a bit of a spat with the tiktoks.
Speaker 6:  They, they're not happy with each other. They
Speaker 2:  Don't like each other. Universal is pulled all of its music off TikTok leading
Speaker 2:  to oceans of TikTok grids that are just silent.
Speaker 2:  Very sad people. It's been a long time. Right. This happened
Speaker 2:  and I, I think on this show we talked about it and the, the sort of consensus
Speaker 2:  prediction was either to get fixed right away or never get fixed. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Unfortunately, Taylor has a new album coming out.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna get fixed.
Speaker 2:  Well, I don't know if it's fixed, but Taylor's music is back on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Mm. And the prevailing theory is because she owns her own masters,
Speaker 2:  she can just cut her own deal
Speaker 6:  That that tracks, that tracks
Speaker 2:  It tracks. But she's got the album command.
Speaker 6:  She's gotta promote it.
Speaker 2:  She's gotta promote it. Lots of artists have been like kind of doing this
Speaker 2:  on the side. Like Olivia Rodrigo also universal artist. Her music isn't there,
Speaker 2:  but she made a TikTok promoting her shows using a fan edit of her songs.
Speaker 5:  It's been so fun, by the way, to watch artists try to figure this out. Like
Speaker 5:  I think the situation is terrible for artists generally speaking, but seeing
Speaker 5:  a bunch of, like, there, I saw a bunch of singer songwriters after this was
Speaker 5:  happening, like start to play live versions of
Speaker 5:  their songs on TikTok so that other people could use it as sounds
Speaker 5:  and everybody's playing like sped up versions of their songs and like the,
Speaker 5:  the remixes are blowing up everywhere. It's the, all the ways people are
Speaker 5:  finding around this band is just totally fascinating.
Speaker 6:  I just love that you guys have much nicer tiktoks than mine. I was like,
Speaker 6:  I wish I saw all of that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's just like deep fried memes. It's
Speaker 6:  Just Jojo siwa climbing out of the sea over and over again.
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 2:  Don't refuse to know who this is.
Speaker 6:  I won't keep it that way.
Speaker 2:  I will not know.
Speaker 6:  Watch it. Oh my God. It's upset.
Speaker 2:  And the internet knows that. I don't wanna know. Even I'm a person saying
Speaker 2:  out loud like, yeah, I won't say it. you know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Tiktoks like pass and
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's just like, don't show it to 'em. Like the tar, the ad targeting
Speaker 2:  is like, this ain't gonna work. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Not the right audience. Keep going for
Speaker 2:  You. Keep going. If you, I will not know. No,
Speaker 6:  I'm happy for you. I like, I wanna be over there. How do I get, how do I
Speaker 6:  get to that TikTok? I wanna watch people like do cool covers of their songs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's truck jumps and, and acoustic covers. Yeah. Okay. So I'm very
Speaker 2:  curious about the status of universal and TikTok. Yeah. Every social
Speaker 2:  platform has an existential dependency on the music industry.
Speaker 2:  If, you lose those rights. All kinds of bad things stop happening to you.
Speaker 2:  So Universal is the biggest label around it has CEO,
Speaker 2:  sir Lucian Grange is sir very powerful,
Speaker 2:  not shy kind of bra. I have a little mustache. I don't know if he has a little
Speaker 2:  mustache.
Speaker 6:  I just, I think that when I hear Sir,
Speaker 2:  He's like a guy behind the guy type. Okay. But also very famous and very
Speaker 2:  powerful. He basically told YouTube to cut it out with fake Drake.
Speaker 2:  Like that stuff went up on YouTube and he was like, cut it out. And, and
Speaker 2:  YouTube caved. Right. They put out If, you recall they put out their like
Speaker 2:  AI principles. They have this like new licensing system that they're going
Speaker 2:  to deploy that is like outside of regular copyright law. It's like special
Speaker 2:  YouTube, ai, copyright law, all this stuff they're gonna do, they're doing
Speaker 2:  it at the besst of Universal music. 'cause YouTube isn't done. And Neil
Speaker 2:  Mohan who runs YouTube is like, this is a licensing business. And like our
Speaker 2:  partners need to be happy and great TikTok just done.
Speaker 2:  Like, they just, whatever the other labels are actually kinda happy about
Speaker 2:  this. Yeah. If, you look at the charts right now, top two artists on the
Speaker 2:  charts are Warner Music artists. Mm. This is like a real thing that
Speaker 2:  is going on.
Speaker 6:  It's one of them. Beyonce.
Speaker 5:  Well, and there's a sense among some people fighting this
Speaker 5:  fight that universal overplayed its hand in that sense, right? That like
Speaker 5:  Right. TikTok was the only company with enough clout of its own
Speaker 5:  to fight back against Lucid Grange and all of these sort of
Speaker 5:  big swinging music labels. Because TikTok
Speaker 5:  needed UMG less than UMG needed TikTok. And that seems to be this
Speaker 5:  battle that we are still very much in the middle of that. Again, Taylor,
Speaker 5:  Swift being singular is able to just cleave her way out of,
Speaker 2:  Well, so TikTok thinks it has this power to break artists and create
Speaker 2:  Cher. And really it's just kind of kinda like moving money around because
Speaker 2:  the labels make no money from TikTok plays as it is. They make very
Speaker 2:  little money from those streams. All their money is on Spotify, apple music
Speaker 2:  or whatever. But they create share, like people listen
Speaker 2:  to the songs in TikTok, then they go to their streaming services. So it can
Speaker 2:  shift the money and especially can break new artists. It
Speaker 6:  Can break new artists and like, isn't still the primary way that these artists
Speaker 6:  make money is performing. It's not, it's not anything digital. It's
Speaker 6:  all going and doing a concert and taking a
Speaker 2:  Lot of money. Yeah. It's like 70% of artist revenue is that side.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And, and this is really good. Great for that. Right? Like a
Speaker 6:  perfect way to promote yourself.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You're on tour, you're doing a thing. I would argue
Speaker 6:  Part of Taylor's recent success is because Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Of this. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean, Taylor's singular as we, she is Singular as we, as I have been told
Speaker 2:  anyway, so I've just been poking at this and poking this and trying to figure
Speaker 2:  out what's going on. So the other labels are happy. And what you would expect
Speaker 2:  is Universal walks. The other labels are like, we also want a better deal.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna walk and then all the labels together collectively pressure TikTok
Speaker 2:  and cutting them better rates. But because of this dynamic, which is where
Speaker 2:  the big bad label Universal with all of the artists
Speaker 2:  walked, including Taylor, the other labels got a benefit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So you see this dynamic like playing out in the industry now Taylor's
Speaker 2:  back. We'll see how that goes. But here's what I've heard, and it's sketchy
Speaker 2:  and un If, you can confirm this, let me know. Calling
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 2:  Hotline was basically Universal. Wanted a bunch of, well, wanted a bunch
Speaker 2:  of provisions that looked like they're YouTube provisions,
Speaker 2:  like don't do bad AI stuff with their content. And they wanted an increase
Speaker 2:  in royalties, obviously in TikTok said no.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's what I got for you.
Speaker 6:  That that sounds, that sounds like why, why this would break down.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So like if you know, you know, lemme know. Yeah. Just what
Speaker 2:  I, I would love the actual deal terms, but the, the sense I get is that
Speaker 2:  there's money, which should be solvable,
Speaker 2:  but money is usually solvable. But next to it is a bunch
Speaker 2:  of stuff that looks like what Universal wanted out of YouTube,
Speaker 2:  which is we want some special AI stuff, AI terms,
Speaker 2:  and like, it's just not happening.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And TikTok is just very different company
Speaker 6:  than YouTube and Google. Right. Like, like their motivations for all of
Speaker 6:  this is very different. I was seeing today, there was a story in I think
Speaker 6:  the information about how TikTok was looking into working with
Speaker 6:  companies to develop like AI avatars to better sell. Yeah. Like they
Speaker 6:  don't care who's on the platform, they can monetize it. So I think they're
Speaker 6:  much less incentivized to make these deals than, than
Speaker 6:  YouTube was.
Speaker 2:  I think you, I think TikTok is a danger to itself. Mm.
Speaker 2:  I agree with that. I I think they are so rapidly turning that thing into
Speaker 2:  the home shopping network and just making it so commercialized.
Speaker 6:  I, and I think in a, in a way that's really putting people off. We had a,
Speaker 6:  a story on the site this week about from, from V 'cause she called, she's
Speaker 6:  gonna be calling in a lot of these kind of gadgets we see on TikTok. And,
Speaker 6:  and the first one she did, she spent her own money like $350
Speaker 6:  because there was a, a wand that would make the skin beautiful. And like
Speaker 6:  some of us, just like our skin to be dewy and and glowing. And
Speaker 2:  I'm one of those people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wait, let me guess. Can I guess, I bet it didn't work.
Speaker 6:  Unclear
Speaker 6:  what did work was the fomo, the, like, the, the massive, massive
Speaker 6:  regret she had. And, and, and that's like that we're seeing that
Speaker 6:  constantly with TikTok. They just constantly selling crap. There's the not
Speaker 6:  crap. Some of it seems to be workable. They, they love
Speaker 5:  To sell. No, the crap is fine. Yeah. You're good with crap. Okay. I think
Speaker 5:  you can, you can, you can stage a convincing legal defense on crap there.
Speaker 5:  I forget about
Speaker 2:  That.
Speaker 5:  But No, I, I, I totally agree. And I think in general, TikTok is
Speaker 5:  this platform that is not interested in being tied
Speaker 5:  down to anything. Like, it moves so fast culturally, it moves
Speaker 5:  so fast technologically that you don't get the sense that
Speaker 5:  it's interested in having any rules for anything for any reason.
Speaker 5:  And YouTube is just so much more
Speaker 5:  sort of lowercase and uppercase mature than that. Right. That it is like
Speaker 5:  learning how to play by these rules in order to be around for a long time.
Speaker 5:  And TikTok just wants to move a million miles an hour in every direction
Speaker 5:  all the time. Yeah. And I certainly enjoy TikTok less than I
Speaker 5:  used to because of that. Like the, the platform is sort of
Speaker 5:  unrecognizable from what it was even 12 months ago
Speaker 5:  now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The the sort of like 20 20 21 TikTok
Speaker 2:  heyday is, is gone. Yeah. you know, I, I maintain a list of
Speaker 2:  tiktoks that should be PhD thesis and media studies, and
Speaker 2:  many of them are deleted now. They're just gone. Like, the creators have
Speaker 2:  quit. They've pulled 'em down. Like they just don't wanna be a part of it
Speaker 2:  anymore. And I, there's something about that where it's like, this thing
Speaker 2:  is getting so commercial so fast,
Speaker 6:  It's so like, I can't tell you how many ads I see now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it's just got, it's, it's mainly those Lenovo headphones and the guy
Speaker 6:  being like, man, I found you. I love these Lenovo headphones. Apple
Speaker 6:  doesn't want you to know how good they are. And I'm like, sir, I think that's
Speaker 6:  just, you're lying to me. I I don't think you have that insight
Speaker 6:  into Apple or Lenovo's business. Why are, why
Speaker 6:  is this on my feed? Why does it have thousands of likes and views? Is
Speaker 2:  That the ones with the screen on the case?
Speaker 6:  No, it's like they go in your ear. Oh, weird. Like twisty way those.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Don't worry. We'll, we'll be checking 'em out. We wanna see if they
Speaker 6:  really are as good is Apple.
Speaker 2:  I love that you're just like V
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Buy crap that
Speaker 6:  View. Like, do I have to? And I'm like, enjoy.
Speaker 2:  I'm excited for this. Yeah. It's gonna be fun. This is gonna be the greatest
Speaker 2:  series of TikTok videos we ever make because all the, everyone else on TikTok
Speaker 2:  is getting paid.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Everybody else is getting paid. We're just like, what does it actually
Speaker 6:  work? Let's find out. Let's, and it doesn't, let's stop, stop buying it.
Speaker 2:  I look, I think between the Universal stuff, not having that catalog and
Speaker 2:  not from what I can tell, making any steps towards a resolution.
Speaker 2:  Eventually all the other label deals are going to come up.
Speaker 2:  And la the the labels might be short term thinking and like
Speaker 2:  they're getting benefit now all of them are actively
Speaker 2:  talking to all of the platforms about AI stuff. Yep. All of them
Speaker 2:  did. They do not want their stuff trained upon. They do not want the videos
Speaker 2:  that their stuff gets used in trained upon. They want AI
Speaker 2:  controls. And like, some of the platforms have like weird,
Speaker 2:  like you have to make a distinction between the kinds of AI you use. So If
Speaker 2:  you roll up to, I don't know, Spotify and you're like, don't use ai. Spotify
Speaker 2:  is like, dude, we've been using ML to do our playlist for like a
Speaker 2:  hundred years. Yeah. Like, we're gonna keep use. Like, and so
Speaker 2:  there's this whole education process happening in the industry, which is
Speaker 2:  fascinating. Other interesting companies or like tools that
Speaker 2:  use AI to like, help you filter sounds or like pull out stem. It's like
Speaker 2:  they're in the same conversation where like, this isn't that this isn't the
Speaker 2:  bad thing. Yeah. But it's all got, everyone thinks AI is generative ai.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I noticed that. It's, it's really consistent and
Speaker 6:  really annoying. Yeah. I'm like, somewhere James is just screaming.
Speaker 2:  But it's, I I just think like the next term for TikTok is like this rapid,
Speaker 2:  I mean the, the term is Kobo Al's term, it's ification.
Speaker 2:  Right. Where it gave a lot of value to users. It built up a huge user
Speaker 2:  base. In and Out is like aggressively trying to re extract that value
Speaker 2:  from its user base. I feel like people are being like, you know what, Instagram
Speaker 2:  reels exist, YouTube Shorts exists. Like I don't, I don't have to do
Speaker 6:  This here. Or like
Speaker 2:  Other ways also might get banned.
Speaker 6:  Y Yeah. Other, there's just other ways to spend
Speaker 6:  your time. And I, I, I don't know, I think we're, we're about to hear
Speaker 6:  have a, a turn from this real love of these short
Speaker 6:  super ephemeral videos to something more
Speaker 6:  stable
Speaker 2:  Novels.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Scrolls. Yeah. We're we're everybody's gonna be doing only scrolls.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's The future
Speaker 2:  Only Scrolls is a hell of a name for a property. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It just, it it just like Shakespeare nudes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The famous, famous writer of scrolls. William Shakespeare.
Speaker 2:  Sorry.
Speaker 6:  But I do think we're gonna see like a change in how, how people are
Speaker 6:  consuming. Like, I, I think there's, there's a rapid moment of change Yeah.
Speaker 6:  In how we consume media and, and, and what we're consuming and what we prioritize.
Speaker 6:  And I'm, and there's so much happening in the space. We're gonna talk about
Speaker 6:  it in a little bit, but like, what's happening with movies and, and streaming
Speaker 6:  a ton is happening there and it's happening really quickly. And now we're
Speaker 6:  having the same thing with social media. And these are all ways we consume
Speaker 6:  our media and they're all in this moment of enormous transition. And
Speaker 6:  what does that look like on the other side?
Speaker 5:  Alex, you are so close to pitching Quibi that I just,
Speaker 5:  I just want it You're, you're so
Speaker 6:  What what you want is, I think what The future is is actually like an app
Speaker 6:  where the vi whole video will change format If. you turn it when you
Speaker 6:  flip, when you turn the phone.
Speaker 2:  Have you thought about Below
Speaker 5:  Your Mind has a show that's only at night. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It'll only launch with
Speaker 2:  Pandemics thought about what if shows came out at night
Speaker 5:  That,
Speaker 2:  David, have you ever asked the AI pin to generate you a nude William Shakespeare?
Speaker 5:  No. I I could, but we'd get the explicit tag on, on the podcast. We can't
Speaker 5:  have that.
Speaker 2:  Actually, this brings us to the other big story of the week. I think a big
Speaker 2:  New York Times piece on OpenAI and Google and all the rest finding
Speaker 2:  ways to generate more training data. I think OpenAI is getting
Speaker 2:  itself into a lot of trouble here. Like they're a startup. They played really
Speaker 2:  fast and loose. Right. Ask for forgiveness, not permission. Oops.
Speaker 2:  We're now the hottest company in the world. We have billions of dollars in
Speaker 2:  Microsoft Partnership and we're getting sued by the Times. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like the, the the ask forgiveness not permission works when you're not
Speaker 6:  a super powerful company and you, you don't have a ton of money behind
Speaker 6:  you. Works a lot less when you've got Microsoft Money Bags,
Speaker 6:  Microsoft behind you. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So OpenAI needed more training data to train GPT four. It
Speaker 2:  developed a system called a Whisper, which transcribed YouTube videos and
Speaker 2:  then trained on over a million hours of YouTube videos. That's not great.
Speaker 2:  There's a little back and forth in the media going on about this. So Joanna
Speaker 2:  Stern at the Wall Street Journal, we may have mentioned this particular thing
Speaker 2:  before, but Joanna was talking to Mira Mirati, the CTO of OpenAI. She
Speaker 2:  said, did you train on YouTube videos and Mira in every way
Speaker 2:  possible said, I don't know, which is insane.
Speaker 5:  While also making a face that said Yes
Speaker 2:  Not great. And then Neil Mon was on, I believe Bloomberg.
Speaker 2:  And they asked the same question and he was like, well, if they
Speaker 2:  did, that would violate our terms of service.
Speaker 6:  But it also, and that same New York Times story, wasn't there bits about
Speaker 6:  how you Google had done, had also trained on some YouTube
Speaker 6:  videos.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So Google owns YouTube. Yeah. So this is very challenging for Google.
Speaker 2:  So Google is built, and IIII say this just as a factual
Speaker 2:  matter, Google is built on a very expansive view
Speaker 2:  of copyright law, and it has aggressively expanded the boundaries of
Speaker 2:  copyright law throughout its existence. So the, the very idea of a Google
Speaker 2:  index like requires you to go read a bunch of data.
Speaker 2:  Google image search requires them to host copies of lots of images. That
Speaker 2:  was a lawsuit. YouTube Viacom famously sued Google for a bunch of
Speaker 2:  stuff on YouTube. It was found out later Viacom employees uploading videos
Speaker 2:  to YouTube to promote them in the echoes of the TikTok situation. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But they, they beat Viacom like YouTube YouTube exists. So Google
Speaker 2:  just like constantly expands the boundary of copy law, like
Speaker 2:  as a function of its existence. That's a thing that Google Books we're gonna
Speaker 2:  scan all the books in the world without permission to make an index of them
Speaker 2:  and then convince a judge that this will sell more books. Sure. It worked.
Speaker 2:  That, that worked. Google won those cases when it was like a, a cuddle
Speaker 2:  bug, you know, just a bunch of goofballs. We got slides in the office.
Speaker 2:  Have you ever, you know, like the judge had like a Dell pc Yeah. And they're
Speaker 2:  like, this internet's amazing. Right. Those days are over. It's a gateway.
Speaker 5:  Well, and again, when the theory behind all of those products was to help
Speaker 5:  people find them. Yeah, yeah. Right. Like it wasn't always true, but that
Speaker 5:  was, at least the story was that Google is saying, we are going to, we are
Speaker 5:  going to ingest this stuff in service of helping people find them and
Speaker 5:  go back to you the creator of them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We are gonna, we're gonna index all these links and then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  send you to the webpages that Right. We're, we're linking to, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  ingest all these images and then you can go look at the images for real fine.
Speaker 2:  But it is also true that the judges were evaluating a service that
Speaker 2:  existed on like a CRT monitor in the den in the computer room.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And Google was a bunch of like 20-year-old kids, and they were just
Speaker 2:  a, just like a different company, a different time, a different company,
Speaker 2:  different cast of characters, different relationships to power, blah, blah,
Speaker 2:  blah, blah, blah. You come to now, and you have
Speaker 2:  OpenAI headlong into a dispute with Google
Speaker 2:  about training on YouTube. You have Google in a headlong dispute with its
Speaker 2:  own creators about whatever the YouTube terms of service, say Google expanded
Speaker 2:  its terms of service recently. All these are gonna be, you have the
Speaker 2:  New York Times suing OpenAI, you have all these lawsuits happening simultaneously,
Speaker 2:  or all these conflicts happening simultaneously. And none of these, I just,
Speaker 2:  none of these companies are as sympathetic as Google was.
Speaker 6:  I think it's because it's, they're so nakedly doing it for money in
Speaker 6:  a way they weren't before. Right. Like, like the the the cost for
Speaker 6:  or the benefit for, for regular people is, is much lower
Speaker 6:  now than it was before. And, and I think that's what we're seeing with a
Speaker 6:  lot of the, just the general tension around generative ai is it feels like,
Speaker 6:  okay, we are, we are devaluing things that we
Speaker 6:  tend to feel very value, like very strongly about all in the effort
Speaker 6:  to make Eric Schmidt richer. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  shockingly people don't wanna do that. I'm surprised.
Speaker 2:  So a very funny part of the story is Meta
Speaker 2:  a less sympathetic company on the scale of things. Although Zuck, now that
Speaker 2:  he's ripped with the shaggy hair and The good jackets. Oh my God.
Speaker 6:  He's got
Speaker 2:  The v he's come back around.
Speaker 2:  They want to train today so bad that they considered buying Simon and Schuster.
Speaker 2:  It's just a straight up book publisher. So they could just ingest all the
Speaker 2:  books without copyright Wars. That's crazy. That's just a crazy place for
Speaker 2:  us all to be,
Speaker 6:  I i i this New York Times story, and I really encourage our audience to,
Speaker 6:  to go read it. It's called How Tech Giants Cut Corners to Harvest
Speaker 6:  Data for ai. It came out on Sunday, this Sunday, if you're listening to
Speaker 6:  this on Friday. Yeah. It came out this last Sunday is it's really, really
Speaker 6:  good. And I think what really struck me, the big takeaway I came outta this
Speaker 6:  story with was that these companies have all
Speaker 6:  recognized there is an intrinsic value in creating cool stuff,
Speaker 6:  in putting it out into the world. They recognize that and they're now saying,
Speaker 6:  how do we make machines copy all of that and
Speaker 6:  so we can do it poor, like we can make, we can do it worse
Speaker 6:  for more money. And I think like that was just a really
Speaker 6:  like demoralizing thing I think to read as a cr as somebody who does create
Speaker 6:  things. And that's like my job. It was like, oh, that,
Speaker 6:  that sucks. But the story was just fascinating 'cause it was just like they
Speaker 6:  are in such a race to get data to buy Simon and Schuster to,
Speaker 6:  to potentially steal their own products from Google or
Speaker 6:  from YouTube and, and from, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. So a clear problem here, and this is sort of always a problem when
Speaker 2:  it comes to regulating companies this rich, is that all of this might just
Speaker 2:  seem like an acceptable tax to them. Yeah. So yep.
Speaker 2:  We ripped off a bunch of book publishers, Sarah Silverman's mad, we're just
Speaker 2:  gonna pay her the money.
Speaker 2:  But some of these, some of them are not going to settle. Like I don't think
Speaker 2:  Sarah Silverman's gonna settle. I don't think the Times is gonna settle that
Speaker 2:  case for money. And so if they, they lose those cases, the precedent
Speaker 2:  is really bad. And the case that I'm just thinking about a lot
Speaker 2:  is what if YouTube creators pressure Google
Speaker 2:  into suing OpenAI or being in some open financial conflict with,
Speaker 2:  with OpenAI? What if YouTube creators sue OpenAI directly and say you
Speaker 2:  scraped YouTube and implicate Google along the way
Speaker 2:  because neither one of those companies wants to set the precedent
Speaker 2:  that training an AI model is copyright infringement.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They both want it to not be. And and that was one of the things in
Speaker 6:  the story was like Google is even like, are we suppo, are we allowed to,
Speaker 6:  to scrape our own stuff from YouTube? And everybody's like, don't worry about
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 2:  Right. And then they expanded their terms of service keeps. Yeah. OpenAI
Speaker 2:  told us when we were writing about the story that OpenAI uses numerous sources
Speaker 2:  including publicly available data, big circle around what that
Speaker 2:  means and partnerships for non-public data and that it
Speaker 2:  is looking into generating its own synthetic data,
Speaker 6:  Which is insane.
Speaker 2:  So multiple terms, I would just remind everyone
Speaker 2:  listening to this, having something on the internet does not mean it is free
Speaker 2:  to use. People get very confused about this concept. Like you can
Speaker 2:  put something on the internet that does not mean it is publicly available.
Speaker 2:  Like it me it means that it's there. Like
Speaker 2:  technically
Speaker 6:  It technically means that it look at it publicly available and that people
Speaker 6:  can access it. Access it. Yeah. But it doesn't mean that it's actually
Speaker 6:  legally publicly available. Can't just take it. Yeah. Because because there's
Speaker 6:  incidents of people being like getting sued for for accessing publicly
Speaker 6:  available publicly. Yeah. I'm using scare quotes here, publicly available
Speaker 6:  data. And then it was like, no, you weren't actually supposed to go in there
Speaker 6:  and you knew you weren't supposed to
Speaker 2:  Bad. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  Bad. I would say two things to that though. One is that the
Speaker 5:  precedent we have on a lot of that stuff leans toward
Speaker 5:  it is okay to scrape websites and
Speaker 2:  Eh eh,
Speaker 5:  And you are also the one who comes on this show every time we talk about
Speaker 5:  copyright law and reminds us all that copyright fights are a coin
Speaker 5:  toss.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And like I'm just saying, like If you, if open AI's position is we
Speaker 2:  use publicly available information, the def what OpenAI believes publicly
Speaker 2:  available means actually turns out to be massively important, right? Yes.
Speaker 2:  And it, I think what they mean is we clicked on it on a website
Speaker 2:  and so it's ours now. That
Speaker 5:  Does seem to be the case. Yeah. Yes.
Speaker 2:  And and I'm just saying like, there's not an interpretation anywhere where
Speaker 2:  that is the thing. Right. And so you just get to a point where like any YouTube
Speaker 2:  creator, Mr. Beast, do it for the views. you know what I'm
Speaker 2:  saying? Just tell OpenAI you're gonna sue them because they copied your YouTube
Speaker 2:  videos.
Speaker 5:  I sued Google for a hundred million dollars. Right.
Speaker 6:  He'd give it
Speaker 2:  Away. No OpenAI, I'm a YouTube creator and I sued OpenAI. And OpenAI is
Speaker 2:  gonna say, your video is publicly available. We believe that this is
Speaker 2:  not copyright infringement. And Google is gonna sit in the middle of that
Speaker 2:  being like, we need to protect our YouTube creators. This
Speaker 2:  is not in our terms of service. That's what Google said to us. Google takes
Speaker 2:  technical and legal measures to prevent unauthorized use when we have a clear
Speaker 2:  legal or technical basis to do so that's, that's Google's approach,
Speaker 2:  right? This is ours. We have contracts with creators. You can't just take
Speaker 2:  it there. There's just a war here coming. Yeah. 'cause all these
Speaker 2:  companies are like, we're gonna go read the entire web. And Google's like,
Speaker 2:  but that's what we do. Like what? Like something bad. And
Speaker 2:  they run one closed platform in YouTube. And I I just could
Speaker 2:  not tell you what happens next. So that's one that's just publicly available.
Speaker 2:  Then there's synthetic data. Oh my God. Which is bananas. So all these
Speaker 2:  companies now are like, we're running outta training data. The humans are
Speaker 2:  not making art fast enough for us to steal. What if we train
Speaker 2:  on AI generated data? And I just, I'm like, you guys are gonna
Speaker 2:  kill yourselves.
Speaker 6:  Well that that was the, the consensus in the story too. They spoke to like
Speaker 6:  actual experts who were like, no, that's bad. That that just
Speaker 6:  makes all the problems worse. All the hallucinations just
Speaker 6:  get worse. You just start going down these weird rabbit holes. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  then you have Kevin Rus like, am I in love with my ai? But that's what
Speaker 6:  happens.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Sydnee is like, I love myself, but also I hate myself
Speaker 2:  becoming finally the full goth sydnee that we've been looking for.
Speaker 5:  I think the thing that really jumps out to me about this story just from
Speaker 5:  like a purely unrelated but insane thing is that Whisper
Speaker 5:  was created at OpenAI explicitly to do this.
Speaker 5:  Like Whisper is amazing technology and, and
Speaker 5:  the like speech to text stuff that is happening again. Like
Speaker 5:  we're all journalists, we like transcribe things all the time. More and more
Speaker 5:  of that is being powered by Whisper. Whisper is now like a publicly available
Speaker 5:  technology that OpenAI just put out there and open source than anybody can
Speaker 5:  have it. It is remarkable tech. And the idea that it was built
Speaker 5:  just to steal a bunch of YouTube videos is
Speaker 5:  wild. And like it's hysterical. What a deeply bizarre like,
Speaker 5:  secondary effect of all of this. Yeah. But it also, I think
Speaker 5:  the, this story of training data becoming
Speaker 5:  really valuable and really expensive is starting to be
Speaker 5:  everywhere. Like there, there's stories about all these companies, whether
Speaker 5:  you want to train a large language model or you're like a creative
Speaker 5:  tools company looking for images to train your healing brush
Speaker 5:  on this stuff is getting expensive. And I think like one thing we
Speaker 5:  hear a lot as journalists is that The future of the media is making
Speaker 5:  stories that are training data for these models that like our job is
Speaker 5:  gonna be to report real time information to a large language model. And that's
Speaker 5:  our business. And I find that like bleak is all hell. But there is that,
Speaker 5:  that that future is coming where like there are
Speaker 5:  going to be businesses that are made that make a lot of money
Speaker 5:  just being training data. And that is nuts. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There are gonna be people who are like, don't worry, our artificial writing
Speaker 6:  is way better than anybody else. Oh,
Speaker 2:  That's already true. It's already true. I
Speaker 6:  Know. But it's like, it's gonna be like more common.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Like the next phase of ClickFORMs.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. Alex, you came to us from Geo Media. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wow. It wasn't always a click. It started
Speaker 6:  as one, then it
Speaker 2:  Stopped. I'm sorry. I'm, I then it went, I came up with Eng Gadget. I always
Speaker 2:  had Eye on Gizmoto and I
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Now I'm just talking
Speaker 2:  To No,
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. I like, like I, I think about that a lot and you, you hear people
Speaker 6:  talk about how upset I, I talk to a lot of writers and stuff who are like,
Speaker 6:  oh no, our jobs are gonna be taken away. And it's like, well, the click farm
Speaker 6:  jobs are gonna be taken away. Yeah. That, that, that first. But those are
Speaker 6:  also the first jobs You get media a lot of times now. Especially nowadays.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, okay. So that, that on Ramp is
Speaker 6:  gone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I look, I think the idea that they're gonna train these systems on
Speaker 2:  synthetic data, 'cause they've run out of real data. It's hysteric and they
Speaker 2:  copyright Wars are in full effect. I just keep saying, I know what we are
Speaker 2:  gonna write about for the next 10 years. Yeah. Yeah. Like, no AI can figure
Speaker 2:  that out. I
Speaker 12:  Just always thought it
Speaker 2:  Was gonna be, you can barely tell David the time.
Speaker 5:  That's also like that, that cycle you just described is the end of the internet.
Speaker 5:  Seriously.
Speaker 5:  Like Google training on Google
Speaker 5:  created data from Google training is the end of
Speaker 5:  the internet. Yep. Like that, that becomes an unusable disaster in
Speaker 5:  record time.
Speaker 2:  I keep, like Alex just said, she accidentally invented Quibi. Once you
Speaker 2:  get enough people talking about that, everyone accidentally invents Yahoo.
Speaker 2:  Like, what if we made a list of good websites? It's like, yeah, that's
Speaker 2:  Yahoo. That's, that's what that was.
Speaker 12:  It was unsustainable.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna make a list of good websites here at The Verge dot com, which
Speaker 2:  you can visit to which, which you can visit directly in your web browser
Speaker 2:  and which is written by people. And it'll be sustainable for now.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back with lightning round.
Speaker 2:  I'm very excited about my lightning round item. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. I'm gonna go last.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you're, there's big caps next to yours. Like it's in all
Speaker 2:  Caps. It's in all caps. It's beautiful. You wanna go first? I'll
Speaker 6:  Go first. I'll go first. I'm gonna do two actually you do two. I love it.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna do two. Yeah. The first one is gonna be, because I just have to
Speaker 6:  talk about it. Kobo has new color e-readers.
Speaker 6:  They're both sitting in my house right now. They're using Kaleido three.
Speaker 6:  It's exact same stuff that Onyx Books has been using since last year.
Speaker 5:  Oh. you know, Kaleido three, that technology that everyone knows and is familiar
Speaker 5:  with and has definitely heard us. The
Speaker 6:  Three people listening to this podcast right now are like, yes. She gets
Speaker 6:  sick. Classic
Speaker 5:  Kaleido three talk. Am I right Eli?
Speaker 6:  I got you.
Speaker 2:  I got you. I'm like, Alex is talking Kaleido three again.
Speaker 6:  Don't worry, but it, it, it, they look really cool. I only got
Speaker 6:  'em yesterday. I haven't gotten to play with 'em yet. But I think what's
Speaker 6:  really exciting about it is Kobo is probably one of the largest e-reader
Speaker 6:  manufacturers for buying stuff in the United States. Yeah. They're, they're
Speaker 6:  Amazon's primary competitor. So that was what was exciting to me. It was
Speaker 6:  like, oh wow. Someone who actually competes with Amazon is doing this and
Speaker 6:  Amazon has a new guy in charge of devices. Ooh. Just saying
Speaker 6:  that color e-reader from Amazon, that color Kindle. It's coming.
Speaker 2:  Hey, pano is shaking things up over there from, from
Speaker 6:  What I'm told. I'm feeling it. I'm feeling
Speaker 2:  It. I mean, how could he not?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do you think he walked in there and was like, I'm pumped. He was like, I'm
Speaker 2:  not pumped. Let's work on it. Pumped. This is not
Speaker 2:  36 hours to pump me up. Get
Speaker 5:  My pump honey.
Speaker 6:  And they were like, Kaleido three. And he's like, I don't know what that
Speaker 6:  means. I, I, now I'm pumped.
Speaker 2:  So you getting one? You gonna review this thing? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I've got 'em. They're You've got 'em. They're sitting in my house. I've only
Speaker 6:  turned on one so far. Oh my God. 'cause they got here last night and I was
Speaker 6:  like, woo. Very excited. Like in Slack at 6:00 PM
Speaker 6:  being like, guys, guys, guys, I got packages. People are like, it's 6:00 PM
Speaker 6:  and I'm leaving. I'm going home to sleep.
Speaker 2:  Very good. I'm excited for these reviews. Full one hour Vergecast,
Speaker 2:  whether or not we distribute that one. Yeah. We'll decide at a later time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it'll just be for the three of us. And Liam, I'm sorry, Liam.
Speaker 2:  Hey If. you wanna hear more about the Kaleido three Write Alex a note. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Alex dorans The Verge dot com. She'll read 'em. I will
Speaker 6:  Read it. Ondo three. Yeah. On That's, that's the technology. Please.
Speaker 6:  This is the Kobo Libra color.
Speaker 6:  Don't
Speaker 2:  Quote me on that. I I love that. you know the display tech but not the name
Speaker 2:  of the product. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm just very
Speaker 5:  Excited. This is and it's color with a u It's very important 'cause it's
Speaker 5:  Canadian. All right.
Speaker 2:  So that's one. That's
Speaker 6:  One. The other one is the MPA. Do you remember they used to be called
Speaker 6:  the MPA. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They got rid of America. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They got rid of America because they did.
Speaker 2:  So what happens?
Speaker 6:  They did. They they were
Speaker 2:  Like, they're like the Chinese work. It's huge.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We need to be more universe. We need to be more global. So we get rid
Speaker 6:  of the America.
Speaker 5:  They should have gone the other way. Just be the motion picture Americans
Speaker 2:  Or the w just add the world.
Speaker 6:  No, that and Paul.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Au
Speaker 6:  Al that's what they call Jack Palitz.
Speaker 6:  But they, they are back and they, there's big
Speaker 6:  distributor conference happening right now in Vegas where they see a lot
Speaker 6:  of trailers and a lot of stuff. And the, the head of the MPA, the MPA
Speaker 6:  said We want to work with Congress and we are working with Congress
Speaker 6:  to bring back site blocking, which is Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's just annoying. Yeah. Really. Like you hear from their side
Speaker 6:  where they say there's a lot of piracy going on. We're losing a billion
Speaker 6:  dollars a year to piracy. We wanna stop that. So we want to
Speaker 6:  block sites that Americans use to pirate stuff. And that's true.
Speaker 6:  And you know how they, they, they got piracy to not be a big deal the last
Speaker 6:  time they introduced easy to use accessible streaming
Speaker 6:  platforms. And that worked really, really well until they decided to make
Speaker 6:  them really expensive. Yeah. And it's like, there's a direct
Speaker 6:  correlation there, guys. You're not serving your audience. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And, and so the MPA is back. It's like 2007 all over
Speaker 6:  again. I'm just,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna have to write a sopa Pippa explainer one more time. Where's Alexis
Speaker 2:  Hanian when you need him.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Get ready. Get ready.
Speaker 2:  Probably half of our audience doesn't remember this. There was an anti-piracy
Speaker 2:  bill called sopa that would basically have forced various
Speaker 2:  ISPs to take websites off the internet if they did piracy stuff. And Alexis
Speaker 2:  Hanian, founder of Reddit will and on the war path to stop this, we
Speaker 2:  wrote about it. I was all angry about it. The whole thing. Sopa and Pippa,
Speaker 2:  you can go look it up. It was a real thing that happened. It, it didn't happen.
Speaker 2:  The internet waged war on Congress and they didn't do it. And I don't think
Speaker 2:  they've ever forgiven us. Nope.
Speaker 6:  And they're back. They're back. They're
Speaker 2:  Ready. Some ideas never die. It
Speaker 5:  Is such funny deja vu that like Alex, you're exactly right that it's like,
Speaker 5:  how is no one at this meeting being like, what if we just didn't
Speaker 5:  make everything so horrible for everyone
Speaker 2:  All the time?
Speaker 5:  Like, isn't it weird that all these people are desperate to give us their
Speaker 5:  money to watch shows and we won't let them so they have to do it illegally.
Speaker 5:  Like strange wonder how we could fix that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They just need to figure out a digital distribution model where they
Speaker 6:  make enough money to be happy in all of their very expensive cars while also
Speaker 6:  not forcing apparently a billion dollars worth of money to go into piracy.
Speaker 6:  Instead. There might be something there.
Speaker 2:  If you got idea again? Alex Do Cranz The Verge dot com. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Hit
Speaker 2:  Me up. She's open to ideas. All right. David, what's yours?
Speaker 5:  Mine is just a thing that I find very funny. So I think it was last week
Speaker 5:  that Marissa Mayer's company came out with this new app called Shine,
Speaker 5:  which was a way to basically share photo albums with friends.
Speaker 5:  And it was the ugliest app that anyone had ever created in the history. It's
Speaker 5:  very bad of the universe. It's like, imagine you
Speaker 5:  had never seen an app and you said, I'm going to design an
Speaker 5:  app in three minutes. That's what this app looked like. And there was some
Speaker 5:  great stories, including from our friends at Platformer about like the weird
Speaker 5:  chaos that it seems to be to work for Marissa Meyer and all this stuff that
Speaker 5:  went wrong. But it has brought up this very funny thing that I have come
Speaker 5:  to very much enjoy, which is that it turns out sharing photos with your friends
Speaker 5:  remains like a disastrous technical problem. It's part
Speaker 5:  of the whole like blue bubble, green bubble apple antitrust stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's a really hard thing to do across platforms. It's one of the things that
Speaker 5:  has made like Google Photos very successful, is it's a thing you can use
Speaker 5:  to share photos. And so Meta rolled
Speaker 5:  out an update to the Messenger app, which I still
Speaker 5:  want to call Facebook Messenger every time. Yeah. Even though it's just called
Speaker 5:  Messenger, that the whole update is that now you
Speaker 5:  can send better photos in Messenger and people are like amped
Speaker 5:  about it, where you can send like original resolution photos
Speaker 5:  in Messenger and they will get to their recipient.
Speaker 5:  Good. And I think that's great.
Speaker 2:  Well done.
Speaker 5:  You know what, what a cool world we live in that this is like an
Speaker 2:  Unbelievable
Speaker 5:  Feature upgrade.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All that 5G. And we're just now getting to full res photo sharing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's just so funny to me. Like we, we've hit this point where phones are
Speaker 5:  just cameras for all intents and purposes. Like that is the most important
Speaker 5:  thing your phone does at this moment is take pictures and video. And we have
Speaker 5:  not yet solved how to send those to your friends.
Speaker 5:  Isn't that weird? It's very weird to me.
Speaker 2:  We, I we've solved it in a number of billion dollar company ways
Speaker 5:  Have we?
Speaker 6:  The US government's trained to solve it.
Speaker 2:  That's what you
Speaker 5:  Are. Eli If, you took a photo and you wanted to send an an
Speaker 5:  original resolution version of that photo to
Speaker 5:  my Android phone and Alex's computer right now. How would you do it?
Speaker 2:  Dropbox?
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 2:  Sorry. We just had the Kobo Dropbox on decoder, so that's what I came up
Speaker 2:  with. It's most upsetting possible answer,
Speaker 6:  But Yeah. But it's
Speaker 2:  True. Like he was great. I enjoyed
Speaker 6:  The interview. Maybe not Dropbox, but it would be cloud, right? Yeah. You
Speaker 6:  just, you'd upload it. That's what I
Speaker 2:  Told. Yeah. I'd walk over to you and I would plug one USBC cable into my
Speaker 2:  phone and one us BC cable into your phone and we would just see what end.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That works, right? Isn't that a thing? That totally works with no confusion
Speaker 2:  all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So what could possibly go wrong? But anyway, yeah. Kudos to Messenger
Speaker 5:  for
Speaker 2:  Boosting Marissa Myers idea
Speaker 5:  For, for making Good Shine, as I
Speaker 2:  Call it. Yeah. By the way, everyone should go read. We'll link to the, the
Speaker 2:  platform or story about the internal, that company is like 30 people and
Speaker 2:  that story is shockingly well sourced.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's like, wow. It's good. No one likes working.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I'm shocked.
Speaker 2:  It's very good. Where's the pick
Speaker 6:  Of her on the Zamboni?
Speaker 2:  Anyhow, it's beautiful by the way, here. Here's some like Verge lore.
Speaker 2:  A long time ago in our first office on fifth Avenue,
Speaker 2:  there was a company next to us and it was like a horrible office. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  there's a company next to us called Stamped David. You remember Stamped?
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. And this is when
Speaker 5:  With no E right? It was just
Speaker 2:  Stamped with no e Yeah. And I don't even, I don't even know what Stamped
Speaker 2:  did or does, but this was when Marissa Meyer was, she was
Speaker 2:  at Yahoo and she was buying every company to try to make Yahoo relevant again.
Speaker 2:  And one day she snuck into our offices and bought, stamped,
Speaker 2:  ran away again. And we were like, why didn't you tell us? We're right here.
Speaker 6:  Just we wouldn't wanted to say hi. Yeah. Very funny. It looks like some sort
Speaker 6:  of clothing company now.
Speaker 2:  Oh sure. Yeah. We like woke up to like a headline on TechCrunch that was
Speaker 2:  like Yahoo. Buy stamped. And we're like that right there. Like those guys
Speaker 2:  next to
Speaker 6:  Us. Oh no,
Speaker 2:  It was very good. All right. Here's mine. The most important story of the
Speaker 2:  week. As you may know, the
Speaker 2:  Sony Corporation in the late 1980s invented the concept of
Speaker 2:  Megabase.
Speaker 6:  I love where this is going also because I know, 'cause I have the rundown
Speaker 6:  in
Speaker 2:  Front of me. Megabase, I would say altered the fabric of our
Speaker 2:  reality
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent
Speaker 2:  Across America. And really the world naww
Speaker 2:  people would push the mega base button and things would change. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Just you know, gravitational waves, the whole thing
Speaker 6:  Just bumping
Speaker 2:  Parties started happening. Yeah. The Butterfly
Speaker 5:  Effect is actually about mega bass
Speaker 2:  If. you add a yellow sports Walkman with a mega base button.
Speaker 6:  Whoa.
Speaker 2:  Right. World was your oyster Sony moved away from the
Speaker 2:  Megabase branding in the late 2010s, I would
Speaker 2:  say.
Speaker 6:  Was it because of Meghan Trainor?
Speaker 2:  They moved to something called Extra Base. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Ooh. I had a pair of those headphones. They're good. Which
Speaker 2:  Was deeply confusing and upsetting to, I think everyone is
Speaker 5:  Extra base, more or less than Megabase.
Speaker 2:  They never answered my questions. Okay. I've demanded the various CEOs
Speaker 2:  of Sony come on our shows and explain what happened. And they have all
Speaker 2:  uniformly refused. They,
Speaker 6:  They just suddenly emails. I don't even
Speaker 2:  Think deleted. Don't even, yeah. I don't think they got the, I think the
Speaker 2:  message were sent away. They were put on a memory stick and then
Speaker 2:  no one could read the memory stick. And that was the end of that extra bass
Speaker 2:  has been with us until recently.
Speaker 2:  Did it? Sony is replacing extra bass,
Speaker 6:  Double extra bass
Speaker 2:  With a ULT power sound.
Speaker 6:  No, no. Sony, who does the naming
Speaker 6:  at
Speaker 2:  Sony? ULT Power Sound is a new brand for Sony's new
Speaker 2:  like party speaker products. They have a new, they have
Speaker 2:  a new, they have a new party speaker which will come to, okay.
Speaker 2:  All of the new products have a ULT button on them. This
Speaker 2:  replaces the megabase or extra base buttons. The ULT,
Speaker 2:  the ULT buttons offers several modes. ULT one gets
Speaker 2:  you deeper lower frequency base while ULT two delivers.
Speaker 2:  Powerful punchy base. Mm.
Speaker 6:  What does that mean,
Speaker 2:  Mega An extra. Oh, they should have just labeled the mega. I don't understand.
Speaker 6:  Well that's too many X's. On on on the, the,
Speaker 2:  The flagship case of the ULT Power Sound Line is
Speaker 2:  a 64 pound party speaker. Yeah. Called the ULT Tower 10,
Speaker 2:  which costs $1,200. Does
Speaker 6:  It have a screen on it?
Speaker 2:  It has 34 LED light zones but no screen. It has like a
Speaker 2:  touch screen at the top. Oh. It just looks, it looks bananas. It really
Speaker 2:  does have 34 LE lights ends and I'm gonna have one
Speaker 2:  and there's not like another, I don't know what you, what you thought was
Speaker 2:  gonna happen. Does your
Speaker 6:  Wife story know you're gonna have
Speaker 2:  One? It has an ex balance speaker unit. I dunno what that means, but
Speaker 2:  Sounds sick.
Speaker 6:  He did just open up
Speaker 2:  Amazon and it comes, it comes with the wireless microphone.
Speaker 6:  Oh, for karaoke.
Speaker 5:  While you were saying all of those words. Oh my god. This thing's enormous.
Speaker 2:  It's so, so big.
Speaker 5:  It's literally, there is a picture of a man rolling it and it's, it's
Speaker 5:  like, like imagine do you, you know, do you ever see the thing where people
Speaker 5:  like check a bag with golf clubs in it? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's a si. It's the size of a golf
Speaker 5:  Bag. It's that size. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Every single photo that they made for this product is bananas.
Speaker 2:  Just like every single photo is, it's in the center of dance
Speaker 2:  floors just fully lit being
Speaker 5:  Four feet tall
Speaker 2:  And then everyone's standing in a circle around it.
Speaker 6:  That's how people party.
Speaker 2:  I love it so much. I can't, I can't get enough of it
Speaker 2:  and I all, I wish Is that a, anyone would
Speaker 2:  tell us what ULT stands for? I think it is
Speaker 2:  short for Ultimate.
Speaker 5:  So, okay. I'm so glad you brought this up because while you were saying
Speaker 5:  whatever those nonsensical words you were saying to explain this thing, I
Speaker 5:  was trying to figure out the answer to this by scrolling up and down Sony's
Speaker 5:  website. There are only two things that could be right.
Speaker 5:  It's either ultra or ultimate. Are there other possibilities?
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 6:  Ulterior
Speaker 2:  It has like a ulterior, ulterior mode. Ulterior. I'm trying to think of like,
Speaker 2:  is it a acronym? Like it stands for Ultimate Live
Speaker 5:  Upsettingly Loud Tower?
Speaker 6:  Probably,
Speaker 5:  But I think based on again the, the deep journalism I've been doing scrolling
Speaker 5:  up and down this website, I believe it is ultimate because the word ultimate
Speaker 5:  appears, I would say a, a surprising number of times on this website.
Speaker 6:  It weighs more than a child.
Speaker 2:  I mean some children. Some children, yeah. Children comes in a variety of
Speaker 2:  sizes.
Speaker 6:  63 pounds. More than a toddler probably, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's more than my, well she's not
Speaker 6:  Toddler. I was like, I don't know what toddler weights are.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, definitely. It's like two Arthurs. It's like a max and a half.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, that's about right.
Speaker 2:  Right. I just got Arthur's a little younger than Max. I'm just like doing
Speaker 2:  some rough perfect
Speaker 6:  Units, Verge units of measurement.
Speaker 2:  That's good. I can't wait to get one of these. Also
Speaker 2:  the marketing material says massive base ultimate vibe. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 2:  just what I say now.
Speaker 6:  They're having so much fun in these, these picture
Speaker 2:  Massive base ultimate vibe. So
Speaker 5:  From now on If, you wanna sponsor the lightning round. You are officially
Speaker 5:  contributing to the NELI Patel party speaker fund.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we're trying to get $1,200. We're gonna put one in the back here. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  we've had other Sony speakers, like other giant Sony speakers in our office
Speaker 2:  and we can't get rid of them. Like Sony will send them to us. They don't
Speaker 2:  want those because they know that we care and then we're like, do you want
Speaker 2:  this back? And they're like, no, it would cost much to mu many dollars to
Speaker 2:  send us back because
Speaker 6:  It's four feet
Speaker 2:  Tall. When we did the Mr. Robot be so tall when we did the Mr. Robot After
Speaker 2:  show, we would like wheel it into the after show, like the writer of Mr.
Speaker 2:  Robot Cord. I was like, what the fuck is that?
Speaker 2:  It's very good. Anyway, I just want to mark If, you are a certain
Speaker 2:  kind of technology fan. It is important to know that we've gone from
Speaker 2:  Megabase to extra base to ULT Power Sound.
Speaker 2:  And I, I think it's important to just take a moment and say, look, a new
Speaker 2:  generation is here. I don't know if that generation will be defined by ai.
Speaker 2:  I don't know if it'll be defined by face computers, I
Speaker 2:  dunno. But I know that this is the generation that is defined by ULT Power
Speaker 2:  Sound,
Speaker 5:  Massive base, ultimate vibe.
Speaker 2:  Oh, David, I forgot to ask you where the AI Pin fits on the, the scale of
Speaker 2:  wearable bullshit. Oh, I mean it's, it's,
Speaker 2:  it's nowhere. I think I know the answer. So it's, it's kind of, but it's
Speaker 2:  value over fids and I think I know the answer, which is zero value. So maximum
Speaker 2:  fids,
Speaker 5:  What's interesting of that's true, but what's interesting about it is I would
Speaker 5:  say it gets like a 0.75 of the face
Speaker 5:  multiplier
Speaker 2:  Because it's not your face. I
Speaker 5:  Was surprised at the extent to which people noticed it, like
Speaker 5:  out in public. There was, there was a very funny moment where we were
Speaker 5:  running around shooting the video and it's like a, a weird thing in general
Speaker 5:  because there's three people pointing cameras at me as I'm doing this. But
Speaker 5:  I stood in front of the, the Fearless Girl on Wall Street, that little statue
Speaker 5:  and people were taking pictures of me as I took pictures of the Fearless
Speaker 5:  Girl statue. It was fantastic. But like, it's
Speaker 5:  very noticeable, especially when you're standing there sort of talking down
Speaker 5:  at your chest.
Speaker 5:  You like, I get more looks wearing the pin than I do wearing like the Ray
Speaker 5:  Band Smart glasses.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. you know, you know what gets a lot of looks, the ult talent
Speaker 2:  to which weighs 64 pounds and it's 34 L units
Speaker 5:  As you carry it above your head, say anything style,
Speaker 2:  Here's what you wanted to do. You want down shift from Ult one to Ult two.
Speaker 2:  They'll feel it every time. That's it. That's the Red Chest. Everybody
Speaker 2:  rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 3:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One. The Vergecast is the
Speaker 3:  production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 3:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.