# Transcript
ID: 63c9e95f-6583-4d6d-aff5-5d8161994014
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1245504073312368668/9118866104502155597/s93290-US-6498s-1746180838.mp3
Description: Everywhere you look, antitrust fights have the potential to reshape the tech industry. Nilay, David, and The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes start by digging into the latest ruling in the Apple / Epic trial, in which a furious judge rips open the App Store in a way Apple likely never saw coming. The way we pay for apps is about to change, and fast. After that, it's time for an update on the Google and Meta trials, as Google tries to preserve its search empire and Meta tries to make the case that basically every company on the web is its vicious competitor. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for another installment of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, plus some notes on this week's Worldcoin launch and the strange new Meta AI app. Also: party speakers. Always party speakers.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast about being right
Speaker 5:  about esoteric legal opinions four and a half years later
Speaker 5:  after you wrote that blog post. So it's a niche, but it's ours. I mean, honestly,
Speaker 5:  like what else is it?
Speaker 6:  You? You bid your time. And finally, finally,
Speaker 5:  It took a long time, but I can say,
Speaker 5:  we can all say it's a flagship podcast of people who can say, I wrote this
Speaker 5:  blog post four years ago and I was right. That's true. That's where you
Speaker 5:  wanna be in life. And I welcome our tiny but dedicated community, our
Speaker 5:  competitor podcast in this field as you know, our our week. And yeah, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna win this Webby next year for sure. I'm your friend Neil. That's David Pierce.
Speaker 5:  Hello, Jake Cast is here. Hey,
Speaker 6:  Good to be here.
Speaker 5:  Obviously what we're talking about is the big Apple ruling that came down
Speaker 5:  this week. Apple was found in contempt of court, referred for
Speaker 5:  criminal proceedings because an Apple executive lied in court
Speaker 5:  under oath. I was joking with a big tech executive today
Speaker 5:  that sometimes I think we founded The Verge 13 and a half years ago to
Speaker 5:  cover this story. Like we just needed to be here
Speaker 5:  because Apple got in trouble for lying about the difference between a button
Speaker 5:  and a link and how much those should cost. And The
Speaker 5:  Verge, The Verge was just lying in wait to be like, yep, buttons
Speaker 5:  and links. That's what we do here.
Speaker 7:  I had the exact same experience reading the ruling. We're gonna talk a lot
Speaker 7:  about this, but I had this distinct moment of being like, oh,
Speaker 7:  where do the buttons go? Is The Verge. That's the
Speaker 7:  whole, the whole question we are here to answer Yep. Is where do the buttons
Speaker 7:  go?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's a line in there that says A better design button would make
Speaker 5:  the market more competitive. And I was like, well, we did it. That's The
Speaker 5:  Verge cast. Like, I dunno what to tell you. That's our whole show.
Speaker 5:  That's all we ever talk about. So we, we gotta talk about that at length.
Speaker 5:  All of us have been covering that story every inch of that story for a long
Speaker 5:  time. So we gotta talk about that. Meta is still in trial.
Speaker 5:  It's antitrust trials ongoing. David was at the Google trial where Sundar
Speaker 5:  Hai was on the stand this week. We, we will talk about
Speaker 5:  Brendan, we always talk about Brendan. He, he lurks, he looms
Speaker 5:  over the ecosystem. But first I, I wanna start with a party
Speaker 5:  speaker. Update
Speaker 7:  Party speaker update.
Speaker 5:  Very important party speaker, update
Speaker 7:  Party speaker Capitalism is in the running to become the newest
Speaker 7:  podcaster than a podcast at the Bcast.
Speaker 5:  So as you all know, It is our belief that the market for gigantic
Speaker 5:  Bluetooth party speakers with LED lights in the drivers is
Speaker 5:  bigger than anyone can comprehend. It is right in front of you, but it's
Speaker 5:  so big you can't see it
Speaker 7:  Just like the party speaker.
Speaker 5:  It's a worldwide phenomenon. It is driving the whole tech industry
Speaker 5:  and no one wants to talk about it. It's shrugged under the rug. And we talk
Speaker 5:  about it here on the Birch Cast. We're five generations into
Speaker 5:  these things. The market is demanding them. People are providing them over
Speaker 5:  and over again. They're getting bigger, they're getting bolder. So we've
Speaker 5:  asked people to send us these party speakers in the wild. It's like crypts.
Speaker 5:  Have you seen Bigfoot? I will say a lot of people send
Speaker 5:  us photos of the speakers in the box in the store. I
Speaker 5:  appreciate you. I love that you see a speaker and you think of us.
Speaker 5:  It makes me happy. That's not what we want. That's not in the wild,
Speaker 5:  you know what I mean? It's, that's in captivity. It's
Speaker 5:  constrained.
Speaker 7:  The Speaker zoo, as we call Best Buy. I
Speaker 5:  Wanna see what's really happening. I wanna see what this market really looks
Speaker 5:  like. So we've gotten a million pictures of
Speaker 5:  speakers in stores, but that's not quite it. I appreciate you, but that's
Speaker 5:  not it. We've gotten a, a second million set
Speaker 5:  of photos of speakers at kids baseball and softball games.
Speaker 7:  Yes, those are, those are very good. Those qualify. These
Speaker 5:  Are the primary market from what I can tell. Walk-on music for 12 year
Speaker 5:  olds who are about to just hit a dinger. That's what party speakers are for.
Speaker 5:  Everyone's very happy about this.
Speaker 5:  Great.
Speaker 5:  I would like to understand what is going on in Europe based
Speaker 5:  on the imagery we have received from our listeners in Europe. So
Speaker 5:  Daniel sending a picture of two people
Speaker 5:  riding a scooter, like one of those bird scooters. The person
Speaker 5:  in front is sitting on what appears to be a three foot party speaker
Speaker 5:  with his hands on the handlebars, and then there's a person standing
Speaker 5:  on the back on the break and they're just cruising.
Speaker 7:  This might be the coolest picture I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 5:  It is one of the most European pictures I've ever seen in my entire life.
Speaker 5:  We'll run it. We'll put smiley faces over the faces, the whole thing. If
Speaker 5:  you watch it on YouTube, you can see the photo.
Speaker 5:  We'll, we'll put it in the container post on the website as itself. Everybody
Speaker 7:  Looks really
Speaker 5:  Cool. Daniel says he thinks that the speaker's on the lights are on.
Speaker 5:  He took the photo from his car. I appreciate you having the wherewithal to
Speaker 5:  be in your car. See this, pull out your phone, snap a photo, think of us
Speaker 5:  and send us the photo. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  There's a little motion blur in here. Like something's happening.
Speaker 5:  That's what you want. Like if you run a tech podcast, you want
Speaker 5:  people to see this and be like, I need, i I need to send this in.
Speaker 5:  That's the kind of citizen journalism we're looking for. Daniel says he thinks
Speaker 5:  it was on because the lights were on, but he was in a car so he can hear
Speaker 5:  it. And then he said, and then he says, somehow it's
Speaker 5:  not the first speaker on scooter I've seen in Oslo either.
Speaker 5:  So there's a hot new trend in Norway where people are putting
Speaker 5:  speakers on the scooters and cruising around with the
Speaker 5:  speaker as a chair. I love it. I love it. Just send us more
Speaker 5:  photos of that. Is it
Speaker 7:  Possible that portable stool that plays music is,
Speaker 7:  is an underrated feature of the party speaker?
Speaker 5:  I dunno,
Speaker 5:  I'll just say this. Smart. It's a, it's crypted, right? It's it's everywhere.
Speaker 5:  It's nowhere. No one can see it. There's no research. The great analysts
Speaker 5:  of our time are not writing party speaker notes to CNBC. You know, like
Speaker 5:  we have to do this together ourselves, otherwise no one will
Speaker 5:  understand it. Okay. So that's one I, again, I dunno what's going
Speaker 5:  on in Europe. And then there's even more European speaker activity.
Speaker 5:  Fabio writes us, Fabio sent us a video. He says, I'm writing you from the
Speaker 5:  law Italy, where I realized I have witnessed the largest
Speaker 5:  concentration of party speakers outside of US Navy ship for weeks without
Speaker 5:  realizing it. Yesterday as I was walking through the Porto Vincia subway
Speaker 5:  station, I think that's how I pronounce it, I saw LEDs lighting up a, a
Speaker 5:  kid-sized party speaker and realized I was the right person in the right
Speaker 5:  situation to send you an email that would fill your heart with joy. I love
Speaker 5:  you Fabio.
Speaker 7:  You were right Fabio. It did
Speaker 5:  The subway station there in Port Venga has, is the ideal place for people
Speaker 5:  of all ages, genders, nationalities, and passive lives to gather and train
Speaker 5:  their dance moves. What each of these groups had in common was party
Speaker 5:  speakers blasting music in the echoing hall. All different songs of different
Speaker 5:  genres of music. I'm saying there were four plus speakers,
Speaker 5:  but only because I managed to film four speakers. But believe me, there were
Speaker 5:  more. And then he sent us a video of competing
Speaker 5:  groups of European teenagers, like practicing
Speaker 5:  dances in the subway station with different speakers and they're all like
Speaker 5:  kind of next to each other.
Speaker 7:  This suggests a possibility that I had not even considered until
Speaker 7:  just now, which is a party speaker arms race. Oh yeah. That is
Speaker 7:  the party speakers. The only way to outdo someone else's
Speaker 7:  extremely portable party speaker is with a larger, extremely
Speaker 7:  portable power speaker with more base and more
Speaker 7:  lights. More lights. And this is, this is, this is how like the
Speaker 7:  way Apple gets you from a MacBook Air to a fully kitted out MacBook Pro.
Speaker 7:  You just, you gotta go up the line or you're gonna get bested on a party
Speaker 7:  speaker.
Speaker 5:  So wait until you're the next one. Come
Speaker 7:  On.
Speaker 5:  So I said last week, my dream, because we had heard that
Speaker 5:  the US military has a lot of party speakers in it. And I said, can someone
Speaker 5:  please send me a picture of a party speaker next to a fighter jet preferably
Speaker 5:  taking off. I will say I, I requested taking off at dusk,
Speaker 5:  but we got the next best thing. Jason, who is a literal fighter pilot who
Speaker 5:  listens to the show. Thank you very much. Jason says, I can confirm that
Speaker 5:  the US Navy is a target population for the party speaker market.
Speaker 5:  I'm a pilot in a US Navy FA 18 squadron, and our sailors
Speaker 5:  love the big party speakers for providing something to listen to while working
Speaker 5:  in the hangar while shore side or in the hangar bay of an aircraft carrier
Speaker 5:  when deployed. They can't wear AirPods while working. They need to maintain
Speaker 5:  clear ears and the work environment can be loud. So you need speakers to
Speaker 5:  pump out a good amount of volume. Anything that has lights added, cool factor.
Speaker 5:  The Navy units don't own purchase them or sailors do it on their own dime
Speaker 5:  to make work a bit more pleasant. It is not uncommon to have
Speaker 5:  dueling party speakers playing very different music separated by a hundred
Speaker 5:  feet. It is chaos for the ears, but it helps with morale. And he sent
Speaker 5:  us a photo of a party speaker next to an F 18, which
Speaker 5:  rules, and he actually gave us the model number of the speaker. It is
Speaker 5:  an Edison PSL 800. I love it.
Speaker 5:  This is like what maybe the best photo we we've ever gotten at the perch.
Speaker 7:  It really is. It's very good. And I also, I like this because
Speaker 7:  you can sort of imagine the meeting at Sony and all these other companies
Speaker 7:  where they were like, should we, should we make it so that you can like,
Speaker 7:  use a bunch of them sort of together? Like you can, you can chain them together
Speaker 7:  via Bluetooth or whatever. And somebody's like, who in the hell is gonna
Speaker 7:  put more than one of these in a room? They look at the size of this thing,
Speaker 7:  why would you need more than one? And the Navy's like, listen guys, I need
Speaker 7:  six of these all at once
Speaker 5:  Together. No, they, so a lot of them can do like Aura cast and actually be
Speaker 5:  chained together. Like this is a, a part of like a
Speaker 5:  mesh audio standard that exists. Everyone's very, they've all done the, the
Speaker 5:  bad thing, which is they took the standard and they named it their own thing.
Speaker 5:  So you don't know, but it's actually this thing called the Wirecast. And
Speaker 5:  so you can chain like a hundred speakers together with just a standard that
Speaker 5:  exists that all the companies support. But
Speaker 7:  That's good.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But that's not what we're seeing. We're seeing groups of
Speaker 5:  competing teens playing different music on different speakers
Speaker 5:  right next to each other. Groups of sailors doing fighter
Speaker 5:  jet maintenance, playing different songs and different speakers right next
Speaker 5:  to each other. This is like the, the end result of, I'm listening to my own
Speaker 5:  TikTok on the subway, but now with like, this is your arms race.
Speaker 7:  We are all listening to everyone's TikTok on the subway.
Speaker 5:  I love it. I love it. All of you. Thank you for emailing us. Even
Speaker 5:  the people who send us pictures of the speakers in Walmart, this is an
Speaker 5:  escalation. You gotta send us even better pictures and videos of party speakers
Speaker 5:  in the wild where I I can, we, we have to figure
Speaker 5:  this out as a community. There's, there's no market
Speaker 5:  intelligence on party speakers. If there is, it's like locked away
Speaker 5:  in the Sony vaults.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna bring it out. We're gonna bring this to light. The media's not
Speaker 5:  talking about this.
Speaker 7:  The mainstream media could never,
Speaker 5:  That's what say, do you see this in the New York Times? Right? You turn
Speaker 5:  on CNN Night. Are they showing you pictures of fighter jets with party speakers?
Speaker 5:  Edison, PSL eighties, eight hundreds. That's what,
Speaker 5:  not even whatever. They're not talking about this.
Speaker 5:  I love it. Thank you all so much for sending this stuff. We, we wanna see
Speaker 5:  more of it. It is, It is very funny to me and I
Speaker 5:  love that we're doing this little project together. Alright, we should talk
Speaker 5:  about Apple. It's a big one. Middle of the night
Speaker 5:  filing from Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers, the judge in the case
Speaker 5:  Epic versus Apple. That case filed in 2020
Speaker 5:  big trial, right? Epic said Apple had a monopoly over its own devices,
Speaker 5:  which is a very, you know, it's a very big argument to make
Speaker 5:  in 2020 that like, you have to rewind your brain. This is the beginning of
Speaker 5:  the modern tech antitrust era, right? All this stuff hadn't
Speaker 5:  happened. The idea that Meta and Google and Apple would all be facing federal
Speaker 5:  lawsuits about having monopolies was not on the table in 2020
Speaker 5:  when Epic filed this case,
Speaker 7:  Epic also picked this fight very specifically and very
Speaker 7:  aggressively. Like, it, it, it dropped the 1984
Speaker 7:  commercial. It dropped it, it did a thing with
Speaker 7:  payments inside of Fortnite designed to get kicked out of this. Like
Speaker 7:  antitrust moves slowly. And this case has taken five years,
Speaker 7:  but Epic has pushed harder and more aggressively
Speaker 7:  and more like with more spectacle than anybody else
Speaker 7:  in this entire whole realm of antitrust fights.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it, it, it against Google it It is won in like
Speaker 5:  substantial ways against Apple. You know, it's really interesting is again,
Speaker 5:  it was, it was so early that I think the judge in that case
Speaker 5:  looked at Epic's arguments. It looked at the
Speaker 5:  standards of sort of like 1980s antitrust standards that we had,
Speaker 5:  again, 2020 pre lien Khan at the ftc, right? This is the Trump administration.
Speaker 5:  This case was filed under. So we hadn't had this big conversation
Speaker 5:  about changing antitrust standards and whether Ronald Reagan was bad. All
Speaker 5:  this stuff that created the conditions that we're now this is before all
Speaker 5:  that. So I think the judge looked at all of that and said, well, I'm not
Speaker 5:  gonna be the first judge in this case to accept
Speaker 5:  this like, pretty big idea that Apple has a monopoly over
Speaker 5:  its own devices in this specific way. Like, no, I'm not, she's like, not
Speaker 5:  gonna happen. But I have all this evidence that the app
Speaker 5:  store's bad and that Apple restricts competition on the app store. And I'm
Speaker 5:  sitting in California and there's a California unfair competition law,
Speaker 5:  and I'm gonna say under this California com unfair competition law, which
Speaker 5:  is very broadly construed. Apple has to stop
Speaker 5:  prohibiting developers from even saying
Speaker 5:  you can buy digital services and digital products elsewhere for
Speaker 5:  a cheaper price. Because at the time Apple prohibited Netflix
Speaker 5:  and Spotify and Epic and anyone else from even saying
Speaker 5:  this subscription is $3 cheaper if you do it on our website. You
Speaker 7:  Couldn't even say, you can also subscribe on our website. You couldn't even
Speaker 7:  have a link to your website. Yeah. It's like in in the Apple ecosystem,
Speaker 7:  the broader internet did not exist and was not allowed to exist.
Speaker 7:  And that was, that was the, that was the thing Epic won on, right? Like it,
Speaker 7:  it lost on some of its bigger swings, but like we all spent a lot of time
Speaker 7:  though in those years talking about the phrase anti steering provisions and
Speaker 7:  like, and that that became the thing here. Well
Speaker 5:  So you know, there's this narrative, I could argue this either way, but there's
Speaker 5:  this narrative that Apple won most of the case in Epic only won this small
Speaker 5:  thing and anti steering was the whole thing.
Speaker 5:  It was the whole thing. What Epic really wanted was to put the
Speaker 5:  Epic game store on iOS and control its own store. But you
Speaker 5:  only wanna do that if what you're mad about are Apple's rules for
Speaker 5:  its store. Sure. And what is the biggest rule? The biggest rule
Speaker 5:  is the Apple tax. Like far and away, the biggest rule is that to put a button
Speaker 5:  to buy anything in your app, you have to pay Apple 30 or 15 or whatever
Speaker 5:  percentage structure it worked out to by now.
Speaker 5:  And if you get rid of that rule, the incentives for wanting your own
Speaker 5:  store kind of fall. Right? You, you, you've solved the problem.
Speaker 5:  The only reason you want other store is to have lower rates or in, in the
Speaker 5:  case of the alternative stores we're seeing in Europe to do apps
Speaker 5:  that Apple otherwise wouldn't let you do. Right? Emulators and porn apps
Speaker 5:  and stuff like that. But for the vast majority of developers, all they really
Speaker 5:  cared about was, I can't do purchases in this app without paying Apple a
Speaker 5:  fee. Like Netflix doesn't care. You
Speaker 6:  Can look to Europe like we haven't seen that much change. We have,
Speaker 6:  which may might be because Apple's rules are so strict over there still,
Speaker 6:  but how many, you know, brand new ideas for apps
Speaker 6:  or models for apps are we seeing over there that couldn't exist in the
Speaker 6:  app store, right? Apple was just like, here's emulators.
Speaker 5:  Well, so the number one model was emulators. Yep. And the instant that
Speaker 5:  happened, apple changed its rules to put emulators in the store. And so you
Speaker 5:  see like competition leads to results. But my point is,
Speaker 5:  the whole game here was always anti sti. It was
Speaker 5:  always letting developers say, you can transact for cheaper somewhere
Speaker 5:  else. And Apple lost. It just lost. And so in, in the
Speaker 5:  realest way, the biggest part of the problem was being dealt with by the
Speaker 5:  court. And I think this judge again remind your brain to that period in time
Speaker 5:  was looking at the landscape of antitrust policy and antitrust law and saying,
Speaker 5:  yeah, I can't just like change the law
Speaker 5:  before it's re before it's time. Like she
Speaker 5:  just wasn't gonna do it. That's not, it's not how district courts work. Maybe
Speaker 5:  courts of appeals do that. Maybe Supreme Court does that. They love doing
Speaker 5:  that. But the sort of district court judge in Apple versus Epic wasn't gonna
Speaker 5:  say, you know what, this lien at con's, a real firecracker,
Speaker 5:  like, it's just like wasn't gonna happen. So the Apple lost in this state
Speaker 5:  court claim, they litigated ninth Circuit. They lost, they asked this
Speaker 5:  Supreme Court. Supreme Court said, no dice, you're this is done. And then
Speaker 5:  I think Apple didn't take it seriously and they,
Speaker 5:  Jake wrote the entire narrative, which we should talk about. They did played
Speaker 5:  all these games to fake compliance with this ruling
Speaker 5:  'cause they weren't taking it seriously. And I got caught, like
Speaker 5:  caught in the worst way. And now the judge is like, actually
Speaker 5:  we're not just doing my small anti steering rule, we're doing the big one.
Speaker 5:  Like, you're not allowed to do anything because you've delayed for so long,
Speaker 5:  you've made the harm worse. So now it's a free for all
Speaker 5:  app developers can do anything they want effective immediately to do transactions
Speaker 5:  in their apps. No more fees and you have no choice. And she says
Speaker 5:  it's worth reading this entire opinion in full 'cause It is full of bombs.
Speaker 5:  She, at the end she says, this is an injunction, not a negotiation.
Speaker 5:  So it's like this is over.
Speaker 7:  I do think, I think the the narrative here is important. And Jake, I know
Speaker 7:  you wrote this through and you should kind of give us the timeline because
Speaker 7:  I think, I think saying Apple didn't take it seriously, actually,
Speaker 7:  lets Apple off the hook a little bit. I think Apple
Speaker 7:  basically got this ruling and had two years worth of meetings about how
Speaker 7:  to give two middle fingers to this ruling and to continue to get what it
Speaker 7:  wants and to essentially, like we, we talked about it on the show as malicious
Speaker 7:  compliance. Like this was the most malicious possible version
Speaker 7:  of compliance to the point where Judge Gonzalez Rogers decided
Speaker 7:  actually this isn't compliance at all. You, you have gone out of your way
Speaker 7:  to not comply with this order while looking like you're complying with this
Speaker 7:  order. And in fact lying to the court about how you're not complying with
Speaker 7:  this order. But Jake, you, you ran down the timeline here. Can you just give
Speaker 7:  us like the short version of it? Yeah. And,
Speaker 6:  And the judge is, is pissed. Like she, she sees through all of it and is
Speaker 6:  is furious about how it went down. Yeah, I think Apple has for a really long
Speaker 6:  time operated in this environment where it can kind of just, you know,
Speaker 6:  control whatever it wants and do things how it wants to, nobody's really
Speaker 6:  on them.
Speaker 6:  They, they make some tweaks around the edges and say, sorry, see you later.
Speaker 6:  And they got this ruling and you know, back in, in
Speaker 6:  2021
Speaker 6:  and it was, it was, it, it felt pretty narrow and it, and it was kind of
Speaker 6:  open-ended. It was just right. You have to allow links and buttons. You have
Speaker 6:  to allow them to go to the web. You can still charge if you want to. You
Speaker 6:  just have to, to do it in a, in a reasonable way.
Speaker 6:  And so Apple sat down and they went, okay, how are we gonna comply with this?
Speaker 6:  And they kept looking at options and basically each time they would look
Speaker 6:  at something as the judge kind of paints the picture,
Speaker 6:  they, they often had this sort of like Goldilocks array, right? There was
Speaker 6:  the, Hey, let's do the great version of this where developers love it and
Speaker 6:  you know, it really hurts us. Let's do the middle option where we do a
Speaker 6:  little bit of, of restriction or let's just go all out and, and make sure
Speaker 6:  that devs don't get too much here and we protect our, our profit.
Speaker 6:  And so, you know, first they, they go, okay, what,
Speaker 6:  what percentage cut do we wanna take on the web? Should we do no cut? Should
Speaker 6:  we do a little sum? Should we do something else? And they're like, no, no,
Speaker 6:  no, we should do, we should do it. We should take a cut. What cut Should
Speaker 6:  it be some, you know, Phil Schiller's, like, I don't think we should do a
Speaker 6:  cut at all.
Speaker 6:  Tim, Tim Cook goes, eh, 20%, 27%, let's do 27%.
Speaker 6:  How do they get to 27%? Eh, they just invented,
Speaker 6:  you know, how, how should these links and buttons look? Should they be rich
Speaker 6:  buttons that, that are clearly buttons? No, they should be text links
Speaker 6:  because we don't, we don't look ugly. Should there be a a, a screen
Speaker 6:  to notify you that you're going out to the web, oh, we should make sure it's
Speaker 6:  a big giant popup that takes over the whole screen. And so every single time
Speaker 6:  the judge looks at and goes, they ha they internally
Speaker 6:  discussed options that were not so bad and
Speaker 6:  then they chose the worst option. And I think there's this thing that happened
Speaker 6:  where they had some leeway, they could have put some
Speaker 6:  restrictions in place, they could have done a fee, they could have done a
Speaker 6:  big pop-up. But I think when they chose the worst option
Speaker 6:  every time the judge just goes, sorry, all all
Speaker 6:  you've done is maintain the status quo. I said that this
Speaker 6:  is anti-competitive. You can't just
Speaker 6:  continue to be anti-competitive. That's exactly what the injunction says
Speaker 6:  to do. And when she gets to the end of this, she, she's just like
Speaker 6:  utterly put out and just saying, I don't think there's any
Speaker 6:  reasonable world in which Apple believed it was actually
Speaker 6:  complying with the injunction I put down.
Speaker 5:  So there's another term to this. The the anger is
Speaker 5:  doubled, tripled, quadrupled because there was
Speaker 5:  a first hearing about compliance and Apple showed up
Speaker 5:  and lied to the judge and said, we commissioned this report that says
Speaker 5:  here's how much value we provide and this is why it's these rates.
Speaker 5:  And they add an executive, a VP of finance come on in it and say all these
Speaker 5:  words about when the decisions were made. And the judge didn't buy it in
Speaker 5:  the room at that time. And she sent them away and she ordered document
Speaker 5:  production. She got all their emails and all their slacks, all their meeting
Speaker 5:  notes and said, we're gonna have another hearing to find out what you are
Speaker 5:  doing in real time to see if what you are saying to me is true.
Speaker 5:  And so all of this stuff that we have, Jake wrote it through,
Speaker 5:  It is just a story. The judge wrote a story in her opinion and we just,
Speaker 5:  Jake just translated it from legalese to like human,
Speaker 5:  it's just a story about Apple having these meetings backed up by notes.
Speaker 5:  It it, at moments Apple engineers and PMs and designers are
Speaker 5:  literally discussing how to make the language scarier because the
Speaker 5:  execs will like it better. Like that is a literal phrase that we have from
Speaker 5:  their slacks. And
Speaker 7:  Then an Apple executive showed up in court and tried to argue that Yeah,
Speaker 7:  in design terms, scary doesn't mean what you think it does. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's a term of art.
Speaker 7:  Judge Roger's just like, no, it's
Speaker 5:  Not, this is all designers are like, scary it up a little bit. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  People say that all the time.
Speaker 5:  Jake, what did the judge say? It strains in credulity or something. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Oh. She, she, she said it, it strains common sense.
Speaker 6:  She's like, like absolutely. Like come on, I cannot believe you
Speaker 6:  are lying about scary having a specialized meaning.
Speaker 6:  Like you want, you want it to be a scary message. They kept adding scarier
Speaker 6:  language. So at the end of it, Tim Cook looked at it and was like, we need
Speaker 6:  to add some more. Like they all just wanted the, this is,
Speaker 6:  we're talking about the full screen popup that appears when you click a web
Speaker 6:  link that that is this big warning that you're leaving, that leaving the
Speaker 6:  app. It's like they, they had an option that was just a little popup that
Speaker 6:  said, Hey, you're opening Safari. And they're like, no, like giant
Speaker 6:  paragraph of text. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And, and just neli to finish what you, you were just saying the, the thing
Speaker 7:  that they discovered after getting all of this documentation was that this
Speaker 7:  study that Apple had commissioned basically saying here's why we're worth
Speaker 7:  30% that they said they then made all of their decisions about actually came
Speaker 7:  at the end of all of this process. Yeah. Where Apple had spent months and
Speaker 7:  years debating what to do here and then gave
Speaker 7:  themselves data at the end to justify all the decisions they had already
Speaker 7:  made
Speaker 5:  And then showed up in court and lied about it.
Speaker 6:  Right? Well, and this was a particularly big deal because the last time around
Speaker 6:  the judge had said, Hey, okay, you can charge a commission
Speaker 6:  for stuff outside the app store. It just has to be based on something.
Speaker 6:  And so in this ruling, she's going,
Speaker 6:  what is this based on? You had the opportunity to value your technology
Speaker 6:  to figure out what it was worth and you just didn't do any of that. You
Speaker 6:  decided on a number and then worked back to, to get up to that number.
Speaker 5:  And that was a big out, I think she even calls it an out in the ruling. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is a big out for Apple, right? It's not everyone gets to put their
Speaker 5:  buttons in and not pay you any money. It's, we understand the court
Speaker 5:  understands that you spend a lot of money developing iOS in the iPhone app
Speaker 5:  developers, you, it's fair to expect them to pay you for that work in some
Speaker 5:  way. Figure it out, figure out the formula that's fair.
Speaker 5:  So that developers can make good decisions and they're, it feels
Speaker 5:  like they participate in a market and Apple picked a bunch of numbers that
Speaker 5:  basically made it impossible for developers to leave an app purchasing, right?
Speaker 5:  Instead of 30, they picked 27%. And every developer, it's in this record
Speaker 5:  as well, says, well, Stripe is gonna cost us more than 3%. Yep.
Speaker 5:  So this is just not worth it to us. And Josh says, well, that's just not
Speaker 5:  right. Like you just picked a number because it sounded good
Speaker 5:  and you know that developers aren't gonna leave. Like here's all this evidence
Speaker 5:  of these executives talking about how developers won't leave. The only person,
Speaker 5:  by the way, who comes off looking good in this entire sequence of events.
Speaker 5:  Phil Schiller.
Speaker 7:  Phil Schiller. Yeah. Kudos to Phil who was, who was the one saying we
Speaker 7:  should not take commissions and fees.
Speaker 5:  You know, Phil ran the app store for years. I think he's still, he, you know,
Speaker 5:  he has like some emeritus role at Apple now. I think he still plays a, a
Speaker 5:  very active role in the app store. Oh yeah. He's the one who talks to developers
Speaker 5:  like he is the face of that organization to
Speaker 5:  developers. He, I, you know, he used to work with Steve Jobs
Speaker 5:  very closely. I think he was there in like the power book years when Apple
Speaker 5:  was not a behemoth. I think he knows what it's like to be the underdog and
Speaker 5:  need those developers to do what you want them to do instead of
Speaker 5:  punishing them to do what you want them to do, which is what you can do when
Speaker 5:  you're very powerful. And at every turn he is like, well, what if we do the
Speaker 5:  right thing? And Luca matri apple's, CFO is like,
Speaker 5:  what if we just charge them all the money we can And Tim Cook is picking
Speaker 5:  the finance team. Yep. Literally the words Cook chose poorly
Speaker 5:  are in this decision. And I, I, look, we have a lot of people
Speaker 5:  listening to us. We're, this isn't, we're not interpreting the decision.
Speaker 5:  This is the judge saying it as clearly as she can. This
Speaker 5:  is over. I have made these findings a fact. This is what
Speaker 5:  happened and this is what Apple has to do Now, no more excuses
Speaker 5:  actually at the very end, I think the last line of the ruling is there will
Speaker 5:  not be another bite at the apple, which you can just see her just hit and
Speaker 5:  return at the end of that one and be like, bang,
Speaker 7:  Take it outta the typewriter, duck and tongue.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, there's something there where, look, I mean these are big
Speaker 5:  businesses. They have to print a bunch of money. Apple stock price affects
Speaker 5:  things like firefighter pensions in this country. Like these are massive
Speaker 5:  load bearing pillars of the American economy. They have a lot of people that
Speaker 5:  they're beholden to, but you can just see
Speaker 5:  that they picked the, the finances over the
Speaker 5:  product over and over again. And if they had just figured out a way
Speaker 5:  to make in-app purchases worth more to developers than
Speaker 5:  leaving the ecosystem, they pro developers, I think would've picked
Speaker 5:  in-app purchases every single time. It's just easier.
Speaker 5:  And they didn't, they instead they, they punished the the ability to compete,
Speaker 7:  Right? I mean that, that's what we've been hearing from developers for years,
Speaker 7:  right? And that's, that's what Apple knew when it went from 30 to 27%, right?
Speaker 7:  Is even if, even if it was a reasonable
Speaker 7:  financial gain for those developers, which it wasn't because of like payment
Speaker 7:  processing fees, the convenience kills it, right? Like
Speaker 7:  the most people I have talked to over the years have always said,
Speaker 7:  I'm happy to play by the platform rules as a tiebreaker just because it's
Speaker 7:  simpler. It makes building my app simpler. It's easier for users who have
Speaker 7:  to click fewer buttons to subscribe like it when it works financially,
Speaker 7:  It is the better option. And so if Apple had just found a way to make itself
Speaker 7:  a tiebreaker, it would've won and instead it way overshot.
Speaker 7:  And so Judge Gonzalez Rogers just basically blew the whole thing up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So just to sum up her ruling, and it's just literally she says to
Speaker 5:  summarize, the court found that Apple's 30% commission allowed it to reap
Speaker 5:  super competitive operating margins was not tied to the value of its intellectual
Speaker 5:  property and was less anti-competitive. Apple's response was to charge a
Speaker 5:  27% commission, again, tied to nothing on off app
Speaker 5:  purchases where it had previously charged nothing and extend the commission
Speaker 5:  for a period of seven days after the consumer had left the app. So if you
Speaker 5:  left the app in a link and then bought something on that website, seven days
Speaker 5:  later you still owed Apple money, which is nuts. Apple's goal
Speaker 5:  was to maintain its anti-competitive revenue stream. The
Speaker 5:  court prohibited Apple from denying developers the ability to communicate
Speaker 5:  with and direct consumers to other purchasing mechanisms. Apple's response
Speaker 5:  was to impose new barriers and new requirements to increase friction and
Speaker 5:  increase breakage rates with full page scare screens, static URLs and
Speaker 5:  generic statements. The goal was to dissuade customer usage of alternative
Speaker 5:  purchasing opportunities and maintain its anti-competitive revenue stream.
Speaker 5:  In the end, apple sought to maintain a revenue stream worth billions in direct
Speaker 5:  defiance of the court's injunction. This is bad. That's just bad. Brutal.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And again, this is not, apple says it will appeal, but
Speaker 5:  this is not gonna be the same kind of appeal. Like, but in the
Speaker 7:  Meantime also the, the other thing is, and, and this is the flip side of
Speaker 7:  what happened before is Apple did nothing for a long time because they didn't
Speaker 7:  have to. Now it has to do something like, the thing that is going to
Speaker 7:  change quickly is that developers are going to start
Speaker 7:  updating their apps with loud aggressive ways for you to pay for the
Speaker 7:  app outside of the app store because they can now, like even, even
Speaker 7:  under the provisions before there were all kinds of wacky things, right?
Speaker 7:  You could, you could have one link. It wasn't allowed to be in the normal
Speaker 7:  in-app purchase flow, it had to be somewhere else in the app, which was in
Speaker 7:  like, it was all designed, it was just, just shenanigans all the way down.
Speaker 7:  And now
Speaker 7:  by the rules of this ruling, I can open up my app and the very first thing
Speaker 7:  it shows me is a link to go subscribe somewhere on the web. Yeah. It can't,
Speaker 7:  I can't pay in a button in the app is
Speaker 7:  the one difference, right? Like it's still, it can send me to i a
Speaker 7:  website that takes Apple Pay, but it can't take Apple Pay right there.
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 5:  We're gonna find out because we're gonna find out, this is what I was saying
Speaker 5:  about being right four years ago. Four years ago, the injunction was Apple
Speaker 5:  can't prohibit developers from using buttons and external links.
Speaker 5:  The difference between a button and an external link exists only in
Speaker 5:  our shared metaphysical reality. Sure. Like Right.
Speaker 5:  We all just decide that as a, as a family, what the, the difference between
Speaker 5:  those two things are. And like in this ruling there
Speaker 5:  are literal pictures of buttons and links that the court thinks
Speaker 5:  are competitive and aren't competitive. And Apple every time
Speaker 5:  chooses the least competitive one. Yeah. It defines button
Speaker 5:  all the way down to a piece of plain text with
Speaker 5:  a little, you know, that little box with the arrow
Speaker 7:  That's a button
Speaker 5:  Indicates you're, you're about to go. They're like, that's the, that's a
Speaker 5:  button. You can have that button and the court's like that's not a button.
Speaker 5:  And apple's like, isn't it though? And that's where we're at, right? And
Speaker 5:  so what my headline four years ago is The future of the App Store depends
Speaker 5:  on the difference between a button and a link. Like Apple pushed back on
Speaker 5:  that hark, they're like, we everyone knows. And then for four years
Speaker 5:  it spent time trying to convince the court that these shitty button, these
Speaker 5:  shitty links were actually buttons. This is a real thing that happened in
Speaker 5:  our nation's court system. And the judge eventually got tired of this and
Speaker 5:  said not. And now she said, look, we're, we're not arguing buttons
Speaker 5:  and links anymore here. Here's what I'm saying. To make up for all of your
Speaker 5:  bad behavior. You are no longer allowed to impose any commission or any
Speaker 5:  fee on purchases that consumers make outside an app. And
Speaker 5:  that means you have no reason to audit, monitor, track, or require developers
Speaker 5:  to report any purchases or any activities that consumers make outside the
Speaker 5:  app. So Apple had this ability before, but they acted badly. So the course
Speaker 5:  says, Nope, that's gone. I'm just taking it off the table. They're no longer,
Speaker 5:  Apple's no longer allowed to restrict or condition developer style language
Speaker 5:  formatting, quantity flow or placement of links for purchases outside an
Speaker 5:  app. So anything, any quality of a link is now off the table.
Speaker 7:  Those two things right there are the whole ball game.
Speaker 5:  It's the game that's the app store that
Speaker 7:  Is Apple going from what it wanted to the
Speaker 7:  180 degree, not what it wanted. Like this is the worst
Speaker 7:  case Apple scenario.
Speaker 5:  Apple also prohibited from prohibiting or limiting the use of buttons or
Speaker 5:  other calls to action or otherwise conditioning the content style, language
Speaker 5:  formatting, float or placement of these devices for purchases outside an
Speaker 5:  app so that you can style the buttons any way you want now. So now the difference
Speaker 5:  between a button and link does, it doesn't matter. You can style 'em both
Speaker 5:  any way you want. She
Speaker 7:  Had a different bullet for links and buttons. She knows what she's doing.
Speaker 7:  Josh has figured this out
Speaker 5:  When I say this as a VERGE story,
Speaker 5:  They're not allowed to exclude categories and developers and apps
Speaker 5:  from obtaining the link provisions, which they were going to do, right?
Speaker 5:  They were going to say games in particular had to keep paying the money.
Speaker 5:  All those Candy Crush whales are about to get a, you know, 30% discount.
Speaker 5:  They're not allowed to interfere with the consumer's choice to proceed in
Speaker 5:  or out of an app by anything other than a neutral message arising users.
Speaker 5:  They're going to a third party site. So no more scary language and they're
Speaker 5:  not allowed to restrict the developer's use of dynamic links that bring customers
Speaker 5:  to a specific product page in a logged in state rather than just
Speaker 5:  requiring static links that make customers have to log in again.
Speaker 5:  Again, this is very virgie, right? Apple was saying you can only have
Speaker 5:  static links, so you couldn't carry login tokens through the links.
Speaker 5:  So you would land on, you know, netflix.com, but it wouldn't know that you
Speaker 5:  were logged into the Netflix app. You'd have to log in again to get your
Speaker 5:  discount. Apple knows this is friction. So the judge says, no, I'm all the
Speaker 5:  way to mandating the use of
Speaker 5:  dynamically generated links in apps so developers can pass
Speaker 5:  login states. That's, this is the ballgame. To your point, David, this is
Speaker 5:  the whole game. It's the whole game. They got Apple lost its revenue stream
Speaker 5:  in the app store in-app purchase revenue is gone, is
Speaker 5:  going to go down. If they'd played ball, they could have
Speaker 5:  maintained a healthy chunk of it.
Speaker 6:  One thing that I don't know if anybody has looked at in like 15 years or
Speaker 6:  however long the app store has existed, what does it actually look like for
Speaker 6:  Apple to compete with web
Speaker 7:  Purchases?
Speaker 6:  What does it do? What changes now if they, if they have to contend with
Speaker 6:  this?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I can think of a million things off off just off the top of my head
Speaker 5:  app. If you buy everything in the app store or the Apple system,
Speaker 5:  you have a catalog in one place of everything that you bought. You have a
Speaker 5:  catalog of every subscription that you have. You can cancel those subscriptions.
Speaker 5:  You can manage your purchases. Maybe you can transfer purchases to someone
Speaker 5:  else because there's a shared centrally maintained database of who owns what.
Speaker 5:  You don't need a blockchain for that if you just trust Tim Cook to run that
Speaker 5:  database. Like there's a million things you can do if you
Speaker 5:  are the central transaction provider that Apple has not had to do or not
Speaker 5:  even been pushed to do because you can't buy anything anywhere else.
Speaker 5:  And so the only thing you can offer outside is it's a little
Speaker 5:  bit cheaper than you're terrified of that. But if you say to customers,
Speaker 5:  protect your purchase with by buying it with Apple, it will cost a dollar
Speaker 5:  more. But here's all these services you get for that dollar. Like maybe that'll
Speaker 5:  work. It's also easier. You don't have to, you don't have to do anything
Speaker 5:  else. You're just like, push this button. But I I don't, they haven't had
Speaker 5:  to have these ideas.
Speaker 7:  Right? I mean, I, the other thing I think is gonna be interesting here is
Speaker 7:  we're gonna see a lot of different ideas about how to
Speaker 7:  solve some of this friction. I mean, it's not, it's not not
Speaker 7:  ironic that the simplest way to pay for things on the web is Apple Pay.
Speaker 7:  And, and in many ways what is going to happen here is people are going to
Speaker 7:  punt from a thing that gives Apple a huge commission to a thing that gives
Speaker 7:  Apple a small commission. And that's fine. But we're also seeing
Speaker 7:  pretty quickly any company that collects payments is going to
Speaker 7:  try to find a very quick way to collect payments on the
Speaker 7:  web for your app subscription like this. This is going to become a really
Speaker 7:  interesting competitive business. Like Stripe is out here already
Speaker 7:  promoting stuff that it's doing. Patreon has big ideas about what it's gonna
Speaker 7:  do. Like the, the quick internet
Speaker 7:  transaction market has never had to be interesting in this space because
Speaker 7:  there hasn't been a reason to do it. And so not only is Apple gonna have
Speaker 7:  to figure out how to compete, all these other companies are gonna have a
Speaker 7:  chance to figure out how to compete. And I think that to me is where a lot
Speaker 7:  of this stuff gets super interesting. It is like Netflix is just
Speaker 7:  gonna want me to input my credit card number, right? But in a, in a fair
Speaker 7:  fight against in-app purchases where they are now at
Speaker 7:  the same price because they can be, because Netflix doesn't have to pay 30%.
Speaker 7:  There's actually fascinating competition to see who can give me the most,
Speaker 7:  to be the one where I put in my credit card details,
Speaker 5:  The thing that gets me at that, which I, I was not expecting this
Speaker 5:  outcome. I knew there would be a fight about buttons and links. I just
Speaker 5:  wanna call, I wanna point this out. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  We're all very proud of you.
Speaker 5:  I'm very proud. If you're not proud of yourself, yourself, if you don't love
Speaker 5:  yourself, you know no one else can, can love you back. Is that true?
Speaker 7:  Let's go down that rabbit hole for a while. Should we talk about this for
Speaker 7:  a
Speaker 5:  Minute? Is that just a Coldplay lyric? I'm not a hundred percent sure. All
Speaker 5:  right. It's a weird time in America. I'm coursing with emotions.
Speaker 5:  This outcome from, you know, our standpoint
Speaker 5:  is consumers is the best outcome because instead of
Speaker 5:  we will force the app store to compete head up against an entire
Speaker 5:  other app store that's different rules and weirdo experiences
Speaker 5:  and you know, all this other stuff you're worried about. It's actually just
Speaker 5:  everything's gonna get cheaper in the same app store that you loved today.
Speaker 5:  That Apple could have solved this so long ago.
Speaker 5:  Like that. It's nuts that we're talking about like alt store in Europe
Speaker 5:  and how Epic might do Epic game store and we are having these pitched antitrust
Speaker 5:  battles and you gotta get all the way to like, can you construct
Speaker 5:  a legal argument using the existing consumer welfare standard to prove that
Speaker 5:  Apple has a monopoly on its own platform. And at the end of the day, they
Speaker 5:  just screwed it up and they got to the result that I think most developers
Speaker 5:  wanted, which is we're still gonna rely on the app store for discovery for
Speaker 5:  distribution, and now we can just collect more
Speaker 5:  margin from the things people buy in our apps with alternative payments.
Speaker 5:  Or
Speaker 7:  There's another version of the upside here, which is now all of a sudden
Speaker 7:  there's a stuff that if you're a developer, you can put into
Speaker 7:  the app store as in app purchases, if this forces Apple to
Speaker 7:  be more competitive on that front too, right? Like step one is everybody
Speaker 7:  just goes and buys stuff elsewhere. But like the best case scenario is there
Speaker 7:  is a step two where Apple is forced by that to be more competitive and play
Speaker 7:  ball within app purchases so that you can start to do things like buy Kindle
Speaker 7:  books in the app store again. And there, like we, we've talked a lot
Speaker 7:  over the years on the show about all the kinds of things that you can't do
Speaker 7:  in the app store because it's not a 30% margin business. And
Speaker 7:  things like, things like books and audiobook are like right there on that.
Speaker 7:  And so we've made the experience awful. And so if this works and becomes
Speaker 7:  actually competitive, it, it actually turns back towards making the app
Speaker 7:  store version of everything better. I'm not counting on
Speaker 7:  that because Apple will appeal to death before it allows that to happen.
Speaker 7:  But like the, the tie here should be good for
Speaker 7:  both sides and ultimately for however you want to use the app, it should
Speaker 7:  be better when these fees start to fall apart.
Speaker 5:  I'm glad that you have a, a good and kind heart because you went to,
Speaker 5:  people will buy art and culture more easily and I went to, oh fuck,
Speaker 5:  the NFTs are coming.
Speaker 5:  What can't you buy in the, what can't you buy in an app right now? Well,
Speaker 5:  you know what definitely isn't a 30% business NFT,
Speaker 5:  there's 30% of nothing is what? So
Speaker 5:  we'll see what happens. There's that. But I, we I I do think we're gonna
Speaker 5:  see a new kind of competition here.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's and the, the joy in the developer community.
Speaker 7:  Yes, It is unreal. I mean it, it truly is. Like we've just gotten
Speaker 7:  an outpouring and Jake, I think you've seen more of these than I have even
Speaker 7:  over the last several hours as this has been happening of just the grand
Speaker 7:  enthusiasm from people who are like, oh my God, finally the day has come,
Speaker 7:  we can play in the app store again.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Developers are usually pretty wary about criticizing Apple.
Speaker 6:  And here everybody's just like, got it, let's go. We're ready. We've been
Speaker 6:  waiting for this. Like we, we have the product ready, we're submitting it,
Speaker 6:  like it, people are ready to go.
Speaker 7:  There was one Ryan Jones who's the developer of an app called Flay that are
Speaker 7:  really like, it's, I always follow flighty because they're always
Speaker 7:  at the forefront of like interesting Apple features. Like whenever Apple
Speaker 7:  releases anything flighty is there. I'm like, cool, great job. Flighty
Speaker 7:  and Ryan Jones, who, who runs the app tweeted. So what's gonna happen starting
Speaker 7:  tomorrow? Apps in the US will have save 20% with Apple Pay type buttons right
Speaker 7:  next to normal buttons, or better yet only have the link out button on the
Speaker 7:  paywall. Apple specifically cannot limit anything about the buttons. That's
Speaker 7:  something I had not even thought of that ev people might just bypass the
Speaker 7:  idea of in-app purchases entirely. And when you hit the subscribe button,
Speaker 7:  it might just take you to the web, which is a thing
Speaker 7:  everyone is familiar with. And suddenly, so like not only do I have to compete
Speaker 7:  within app purchases, I might be able to do away with them entirely.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then, and then you're still completing it in the Apple ecosystem
Speaker 5:  with Apple Pay for a much lower fee.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 5:  The thing that I think is gonna be really fascinating is it's developers
Speaker 5:  do this quickly enough and everything gets cheaper and more
Speaker 5:  competitive or more vibrant and there's all this excitement in developer
Speaker 5:  community and then Apple Appeals and starts fighting to
Speaker 5:  put the genie back in the bottle. It still might not matter if they win.
Speaker 5:  'cause you can't, you can't be like, well we won this court case
Speaker 5:  so everybody stop it. Go
Speaker 7:  Make your app worse. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like we will have run the AB test. They
Speaker 6:  Like that 30%.
Speaker 5:  Look, Todd Hazelton this morning woke up and was
Speaker 5:  like, oh, I gotta write this down. Like the amount of pressure on Apple is
Speaker 5:  out of control right now. So he we'll link that piece too. It's, It is really
Speaker 5:  good. But he just listed them. He's like, okay, tariffs, tariffs are gonna
Speaker 5:  increase the costs of every product and Apple has to figure out how to work
Speaker 5:  that into its margin. The Google search remedies case, which we'll talk about
Speaker 5:  in a second here, might just take $20 billion off of Apple's bottom
Speaker 5:  line. And that's pure margin. Google just pays Apple $20 billion to be
Speaker 5:  the default.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It might just go away. That's the, that's one of the very real results of
Speaker 5:  the case that is ongoing. And then the entire part of the
Speaker 5:  business that's growing is services every quarter. Now it's services,
Speaker 5:  it's growing. It's not Apple TVs and, and MacBooks. It's not the
Speaker 5:  iPhone, it's not the iPad. It's services.
Speaker 5:  What services? They don't wanna say it. They want you to think a severance.
Speaker 5:  It's not severance,
Speaker 5:  it's Candy Crush Whales. Yep. Apple's entire business has been
Speaker 5:  taking 30% of Candy Crush whales and that's been growing for years.
Speaker 5:  And so you, you're gonna take that too now. So you're gonna lose the 20 billion
Speaker 5:  from Google, you're gonna lose the Candy Crush whale money. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  increase the margin pressure because of tariffs. Wow.
Speaker 5:  That whole business has changed. By the end of this year, the entire, all
Speaker 5:  of the fundamentals of Apple's business will be like flipped. And
Speaker 5:  then what's the next turn that everyone's talking about? Whether you believe
Speaker 5:  in it or not, it's like ai, ai, ai, well they had to delay their AI
Speaker 5:  project. Like this company is suddenly like real shaky.
Speaker 5:  And that's not to say the iPhone's bad, the thing that they do
Speaker 5:  is really good. It is still like the centerpiece of the modern tech economy,
Speaker 5:  but you're just like, wow. All of the pieces of this puzzle just got real
Speaker 5:  frayed around the edges. Like what's gonna happen? How
Speaker 5:  do they recover from this? And I'm, I'm hopeful that there's
Speaker 5:  smart, creative, really interesting people who work at Apple that
Speaker 5:  they are finally forced to be creative and invent the next
Speaker 5:  turn as opposed to figuring out more and more, more ways to
Speaker 5:  extract dollars from the iPhone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean, it, It is funny to watch this sort of rhyme with the Google
Speaker 7:  trial in that I, if you sort of boil it all the way
Speaker 7:  down like Apple found its version of Google
Speaker 7:  search in the 30% commission, which is just essentially a
Speaker 7:  perpetual money machine, right? It is. If if you want to exist in
Speaker 7:  the world, you have to give us money. That's, that's what Google did with
Speaker 7:  the internet and that's what Apple did with mobile, right? And it, it, boy
Speaker 7:  did it work gangbusters, but is eventually, if, if you get someone who is
Speaker 7:  willing to peel that apart, it becomes really
Speaker 7:  hard to put back together. And like Google is, is furiously fighting to
Speaker 7:  not have happened to it. Essentially what just happened to Apple, which is
Speaker 7:  a judge says absolutely not. Like you just can't do this thing anymore.
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 6:  Am curious if Apple, you know, still tries to, to pull
Speaker 6:  something here. You know, the, the judge puts some pretty strict limits on
Speaker 6:  things, but Apple explored some other options, right? They were like, hey,
Speaker 6:  we could, we could charge people based on how many downloads their apps get.
Speaker 6:  That's one of the things that they pulled in Europe,
Speaker 5:  But they're not allowed to do it anymore.
Speaker 6:  They can't, they can't condition links on that. They could just charge people
Speaker 6:  that would totally upend the app store model.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think if you're Apple,
Speaker 7:  that's pretty dangerous.
Speaker 6:  You're probably fearing this ruling,
Speaker 7:  Which is the goal, right? Like Judge, judge Gonzalez Rogers here is, is very
Speaker 7:  much attempting to strike the fear of God into this company. Like, if you
Speaker 7:  cross me again, I will ruin you is pretty much the message
Speaker 7:  of this thing. It
Speaker 6:  It, it reads a little like that. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean, it It is going, It is gonna be really interesting to see because
Speaker 7:  I'm, I'm confident there have been meetings all day in Cupertino about
Speaker 7:  not, maybe not how to ignore this, but how to get around it. Like how do
Speaker 7:  we keep getting our services revenue without this?
Speaker 7:  And some of those meetings are about products and some of those will not
Speaker 7:  be about products, but, but like the, the, this ruling
Speaker 7:  intentionally and in as many words opened the
Speaker 7:  floodgates for developers and It is basically like they, they get to do this
Speaker 7:  now and you can't stop them or it's illegal. Like
Speaker 5:  It also opened the floodgates for regulators. So
Speaker 5:  I was talking to some antitrust people yesterday after the ruling hit and
Speaker 5:  a little bit of insight, maybe I can share that. But the overwhelming
Speaker 5:  feeling was like finally someone has called Apple out on their
Speaker 5:  hubris. Mm. Apple, their rep around the world
Speaker 5:  when it comes to this stuff is how dare you
Speaker 5:  no Will will fight you till you die.
Speaker 5:  Arrogance and hubris just absolutely like the comparison was made
Speaker 5:  specifically to Google and they're like, Google's pretty arrogant and noncompliant
Speaker 5:  as well, but at least they pretend that they're nice. Which tracks like totally
Speaker 5:  tracks. Yeah. Like Google's, like we make YouTube music
Speaker 5:  just a bunch of goofballs over here. Yeah. Apple's like, we make the iPhone
Speaker 5:  and none of you will ever have taste like we have taste, so
Speaker 5:  please shut up. And like it just bit them in the ass here. Like they
Speaker 5:  didn't have to get to this position and now they're totally
Speaker 5:  constrained.
Speaker 7:  Well, and to that point, one of the things Apple has said over and over throughout
Speaker 7:  this whole process is, and every big tech company does this, is they, they
Speaker 7:  yell and scream about security and privacy, right? That if you do this,
Speaker 7:  if you allow developers to put links in their apps,
Speaker 7:  it it will devastate privacy on the internet. People will be opened up to
Speaker 7:  fraud, everything will be horrible. And it all over
Speaker 7:  this ruling from Judge Al Rogers, it just says that is
Speaker 7:  a lie and that's not what you think. That is not how you feel. And I can
Speaker 7:  prove it. Right. And that is like the, the stuff in this documents was you
Speaker 7:  had a meeting about money and then you told a story about privacy and those
Speaker 7:  two things have nothing to do with each other. And I'm tired of hearing the
Speaker 7:  privacy story because it's about money. And that is like,
Speaker 7:  we've all kind of known that, but it's, it, it's different to
Speaker 7:  say it when you have the meeting minutes in front of you and it's like, oh,
Speaker 7:  you know what never came up in this meeting about whether it should be 27%
Speaker 7:  or 30% user privacy. Turns out you don't actually care
Speaker 7:  except as a justification to the public who you hope don't really
Speaker 7:  understand what's going on.
Speaker 5:  The thing that I heard specifically yesterday when I was talking to some
Speaker 5:  folks was if the DOJ is smart, they will take this
Speaker 5:  ruling and amend the complaint against Apple for
Speaker 5:  antitrust to include a bunch of what you're saying, right. That you can take
Speaker 5:  your complaint and amend it. The complaint is basically the offense monopoly
Speaker 5:  and it Apple uses it to legally command all kinds of other
Speaker 5:  industries. And there's a laundry list of ways to do that.
Speaker 5:  Well, if you're smart, now you have a bunch of evidence that says, oh, they
Speaker 5:  super do that, and you're gonna, you're gonna amend your complaint to
Speaker 7:  Put it and all of their defense again, which is about privacy and security
Speaker 7:  and taking the best care of users
Speaker 7:  may not actually be what you're worried about.
Speaker 5:  Yep. So these things begin to stack up, like the regulators around the world
Speaker 5:  are looking at this decision and they're looking at this judge saying, you
Speaker 5:  know, actually I can just body up and punch Tim Hook in the nose. And they're,
Speaker 5:  they're emboldened. Like the joke I keep I was making last night was like,
Speaker 5:  there are bells ringing in Paris. Like there's a bunch of happy gray suited
Speaker 5:  European lawyers being like, finally
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Like it's happened. Like someone has finally like punched, like landed a
Speaker 5:  punch and it's because of Apple's attitude. And that is such an own goal.
Speaker 5:  Like they did not have to get here.
Speaker 5:  That's a, we have a statement from Apple that says they disagree with the
Speaker 5:  judges' ruling. They're, they're going to appeal it. There's,
Speaker 5:  there's an amount of, even all the statements we're getting, the indie app
Speaker 5:  developers I think are very excited. The big companies like
Speaker 5:  Spotify and match groups that have been fighting this the loudest. A little
Speaker 5:  more measured, right? Like they're all
Speaker 7:  The, the proof is gonna be in the pudding, right? Like it's, it's, it's going
Speaker 7:  to be the app updates. Like I, I sincerely believe the next
Speaker 7:  14 days of app updates from all of these companies is gonna be fascinating
Speaker 7:  because you, so here's
Speaker 5:  The one that's gonna be the most fascinating. Tim Sweeney says Epic will
Speaker 5:  put Fortnite back in iOS. Yep. How
Speaker 7:  I was talking to j Peters about this earlier, like this, this suggests that
Speaker 7:  Epic has been updating the Fortnite iOS app for years,
Speaker 7:  waiting for this day. I'm serious. Like that is what has been going on is
Speaker 7:  Epic has been waiting to win so that it can, it can victoriously
Speaker 7:  and ceremoniously reappear in the app store triumphant over
Speaker 7:  Apple's monopoly and it's gonna work. And I
Speaker 7:  like, I guarantee you every big app developer, wait,
Speaker 5:  No, how will it work? So the, the mechanics of this case, epic
Speaker 5:  broke apple's rules by shipping a secret update to
Speaker 5:  iOS Fortnite that allowed people to purchase stuff in Fortnite without an
Speaker 5:  app purchases. Apple kicked him outta the store, said, you broke our
Speaker 5:  rules. Epic said, aha, it was a troll. And they filed a lawsuit
Speaker 5:  they've gotten here where Apple's non-compliance with the injunction
Speaker 5:  has gotten Apple in a bunch of trouble. But Epic lost
Speaker 5:  on, did you willfully break the iOS developer agreement?
Speaker 5:  There's nothing in this ruling says Apple has to give Epic its
Speaker 5:  developer account back. Like how are they gonna put it back in the
Speaker 7:  Stock? That's a good point.
Speaker 6:  So I think
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Unclear. Do you have Fortnite ready? Because they, they brought it to the
Speaker 6:  EU a couple months back. Oh yeah, that's right. Yeah. Yeah. 'cause they,
Speaker 6:  they launched that big game tour. They had another battle with Apple over
Speaker 6:  a developer account in the European Union, which Apple
Speaker 6:  briefly banned. So It is, it remains unclear to me
Speaker 6:  it they have a developer account in the US
Speaker 6:  or if Apple is required to, to by any means, let
Speaker 6:  them have Fortnite on the store. I feel like Apple's allowed to just be like,
Speaker 6:  eh, sorry guys. Like we're pretty pissed about this.
Speaker 5:  I will say Tim Sweeney put out what he calls a peace proposal, which
Speaker 5:  is super not a peace proposal.
Speaker 7:  No, it's just a nice, he says
Speaker 5:  Epic puts forth a peace proposal. If Apple extends the court's friction
Speaker 5:  free Apple tax free framework
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back now onto active litigation
Speaker 5:  here, here on the America's favorite tech litigation podcast.
Speaker 5:  Look, we open with party speakers to draw you in.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, if people would launch more gadgets, we would talk
Speaker 7:  like could. It's, it's about to be developer conference and gadget season
Speaker 7:  again, and I'm very much looking forward to that. Wait, can I sidetrack you
Speaker 7:  because David, there was something you you wanted to talk about up front
Speaker 7:  that we skipped over. Oh, you're right. So we, we could do a little
Speaker 7:  intermission here. Let's, let's do a brief gadget like a cleanser. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Because I, I need to know Nila you in particular, but both of you.
Speaker 7:  We gotta talk about the Slate truck for like five minutes because we talked
Speaker 7:  about the Slate Truck with Tim Stevens on Tuesday show. He wrote a great
Speaker 7:  story for us. He's written a couple of great stories for us about the Slate
Speaker 7:  truck. I, I would say, without giving too much away traffic to our website
Speaker 7:  suggests that this is the most interesting thing that anyone has done in
Speaker 7:  a very long time.
Speaker 5:  It's neck and neck between Slate Truck and calling Jeff Bezos a coward.
Speaker 5:  That's our audience.
Speaker 7:  That's about right. Yeah. So let's let, what do you think
Speaker 7:  you, you weren't here for our talk with Tim on, on Tuesday. What do you make
Speaker 7:  of the sidetrack?
Speaker 5:  I listened to it actually the other day. I love Tim. Tim and I used to work
Speaker 5:  together in Gadget. He, it's so much fun when he writes for us and
Speaker 5:  does stuff for us.
Speaker 5:  I, I'm like, take my money. It's,
Speaker 5:  I don't need a pickup truck anymore. I used to need a pickup truck
Speaker 5:  when I lived in the woods on an unpaved road and had to take my own trash
Speaker 5:  to the dump once a week with a baby in the house, which meant the trash could
Speaker 5:  not stay in the house for more than two days. Do you understand what I'm,
Speaker 5:  do you understand what the baby was doing?
Speaker 7:  Babies like trash
Speaker 5:  Babies make the worst trash in human history.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's real. It's not great. So yeah, we, you know,
Speaker 5:  there was a time when I like loaded the bed of a pickup truck like several
Speaker 5:  times a week in a pandemic and drove away and that was great. And then I
Speaker 5:  moved to Westchester, pickup truck was incompatible with this area,
Speaker 5:  sold the pickup truck. And then I saw the slate truck and I was like, what
Speaker 5:  if,
Speaker 5:  what if I found a reason to take my own trash to the top?
Speaker 7:  But it's not a very picky pickup truck. Like I, no, it's very small. Never
Speaker 7:  once in my life been like, you know, what I need is a pickup truck. And I
Speaker 7:  have still been on the Slate Auto website a half dozen times this week being
Speaker 7:  like, I could buy this car. They
Speaker 5:  Did the one extremely smart thing about this late auto website. Even if you're
Speaker 5:  not a pickup truck person or a car person, they, the configurator is so much
Speaker 5:  fun. It's because the thing is so modular by design. They're
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know today I want a yellow SUV tomorrow a a red pickup
Speaker 5:  truck with a Bluetooth speaker. And they, you're like, screw with it. I think
Speaker 5:  they're, they're their ability to
Speaker 5:  capture the trends in cars right now with what people
Speaker 5:  are doing with cars and not what like Ford thinks people are doing
Speaker 5:  with cars is super interesting. So
Speaker 5:  every, you know, car culture is dominated by people wrapping their cars
Speaker 5:  like all over the place. People buy like car, people buy what, you know,
Speaker 5:  you, when you're like trying to buy a car, like a used car, if you're a car
Speaker 5:  person, there's a party that's like, I wanna make sure I get the color I
Speaker 5:  want. But there's another part that is like, I know exactly what set of
Speaker 5:  specs and option packages I was looking for and the color is almost immaterial
Speaker 5:  because I'm absolutely gonna wrap this car when I get it. Like that's just
Speaker 5:  a thing that happens in this world. Lots of people wrap new cars. So
Speaker 5:  for slate to say, you know what, like we can just do away
Speaker 5:  with a paint shop or metal body panels and
Speaker 5:  assume that our customers are gonna wrap the car to their specifications.
Speaker 5:  There's something about that that I think is incredibly smart,
Speaker 5:  right? They're, they're not at the, what does the big company think
Speaker 5:  the market wants? They're at the, what is the community doing
Speaker 5:  and how do we deliver to the community, the product that might work?
Speaker 5:  And I don't have any of that's gonna work, right? Like it's new. I don't
Speaker 5:  know if the car's any good. Like we haven't, no one's ever driven in one.
Speaker 5:  I think listening to 10, it sounds like Slate hasn't spent a lot of time
Speaker 5:  driving. It does.
Speaker 7:  They've sat in it a lot. Yeah. That we know for sure. But has it gone
Speaker 5:  Anywhere? There's something about that which I love, which is like, they're
Speaker 5:  at the fringe of car culture in a very specific way that I think is super
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  That's fair. Jake, you're, you're famously a truck guy. Everyone who knows
Speaker 7:  you, knows you love a cable knit sweater and a pickup truck.
Speaker 7:  What do you think of this thing?
Speaker 6:  I, I'm neither a car guy nor a truck guy, but this is the coolest truck I've
Speaker 6:  ever seen. That's how I feel. This is the thing. It's like every single time
Speaker 6:  I I I am in a car, I have a problem with something. The speaker system is
Speaker 6:  terrible. The infotainment system is terrible. The I I love that.
Speaker 6:  They're just like, listen, you are gonna be mad about it anyway,
Speaker 6:  whatever. Get a, bring your own speaker. I don't care. You're gonna put your
Speaker 6:  phone up anyway. Like, just do it. I, it's, it's like such a delightful
Speaker 6:  approach. It feels very friendly and, and welcoming and like, I,
Speaker 6:  I kind of love that even though it's actually like deeply for tinkerers.
Speaker 6:  The big question to me, and again, not a car guy.
Speaker 6:  People love really large vehicles and they started with
Speaker 6:  a truck and a small truck. Like when I see old
Speaker 6:  trucks in the wild, the wild being the streets, I,
Speaker 6:  I like, I'm like, oh my God, they're so cute. Like, there's adorable little
Speaker 6:  truck that, that was actually just a full size truck from 10 years
Speaker 6:  ago. So I I I'm really curious
Speaker 6:  how that taps into the market they're going for, but it's a really cool
Speaker 6:  idea.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Neli, is there a, is there a turn towards, obviously like
Speaker 7:  everywhere else it's, you know, the nineties and early two thousands again,
Speaker 7:  are we gonna do that with cars? Are we gonna go back to like, you know, the,
Speaker 7:  the cars our parents had back in the day? Is that, is that coming? Because
Speaker 7:  that's kinda what the site truck is aesthetically.
Speaker 5:  So one, I want people to go on TikTok
Speaker 6:  And technologically
Speaker 5:  And technologically and technologically, they're all gonna have cigarette
Speaker 5:  lighter in the beginning. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 7:  I run with a boombox on my passenger seat for a long time like that. That's
Speaker 7:  a real thing.
Speaker 5:  Go on TikTok and just search for the Ford Ranger song. No further commentary.
Speaker 5:  It's just an ecosystem of content that you can be a part of. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  When I say my TikTok feed is trucks jumping over stuff, I'm offering you
Speaker 5:  a door that's very good. You know, the, the market's
Speaker 5:  distorted it, the, the trucks are big and they cost a hundred
Speaker 5:  thousand dollars because trucks are excluded
Speaker 5:  from some fuel economy standards and people buy them and then
Speaker 5:  you make them bigger and then dentists can write them off on their taxes
Speaker 5:  in specific ways. And then you make 'em cost so much money. 'cause that's
Speaker 5:  just pure margin for the automaker. Like it's just, there's just like
Speaker 5:  a nonsensically to that part of the market. Because when you show people
Speaker 5:  a picture of like the Rivian R three X, everyone's like, that's what I want.
Speaker 5:  I want, I want a weird little eighties hatchback that goes 300 miles
Speaker 5:  on a charge. Like gimme that. You show people a Ford Maverick, which is still
Speaker 5:  huge compared to, to the slate truck. And they're like, that's, I want that,
Speaker 5:  gimme that. So there's a distortion in the market that I think everyone thinks
Speaker 5:  is real, but it's like, it really is like a, the attack part tax is
Speaker 5:  like section 1 7 9. It's like you can write off the full value of a giant
Speaker 5:  vehicle all at once if you run a small business and you claim that
Speaker 5:  yes, you know, your dry cleaners needs a truck of this size and so people
Speaker 5:  do it and like the, there's just a distortion in the market.
Speaker 5:  And I, I think this is the anti tote to that in a real way. But I know why
Speaker 5:  car makers have been making their cars bigger. I will. The other thing I
Speaker 5:  will, I'm curious if the audience feels this way. I think all cars
Speaker 5:  are ugly right now. Like they are so ugly.
Speaker 7:  I agree with that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Very, very few cars are just straightforwardly beautiful. And
Speaker 5:  this trend back to sort of classic designs, like very handsome
Speaker 5:  profiles, it just can't come fast enough.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I totally agree. We, we've been lost in this like, cars
Speaker 7:  should look like the future thing for a while now. And like
Speaker 7:  there's a, there's a Hyundai and Genesis dealership just down the street
Speaker 7:  from me. And so like every day some new
Speaker 7:  stupid spaceship looking thing comes driving by my front door and
Speaker 7:  I'm like, what, what have we done here? Like, people love the iion,
Speaker 7:  it's all fine and every single one has like more weird angles
Speaker 7:  and it's like, why these aren't cars anymore? What are we doing here? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  My favorite weirdness in the current car design market is
Speaker 5:  everyone has decided the headlights should be vertical, but we should still
Speaker 5:  pretend to have very tiny, small horizontal headlights like eyebrows.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, this looks horrible. Like if any of you looked at the cars,
Speaker 5:  I, I just dunno what's going on. So it's nice to see
Speaker 5:  some classic profiles come back. I think
Speaker 5:  the, the car's not gonna ship for it another year, two years. It's vapor
Speaker 5:  tilt ships man. Like Yep. But you know, who doesn't love dreaming out a vaporware
Speaker 5:  car? It's like America's favorite pastime.
Speaker 7:  That's what we do here. It's, and it's past, it's a render.
Speaker 7:  So at least, at least we're past that point. It's not just a drawing of a
Speaker 7:  car. It is a car. And that's, that's something. Yeah. Jake, thank you
Speaker 7:  for that. I feel much better. Let's go back to the courthouse because there's
Speaker 7:  so, there's so, so much.
Speaker 5:  Alright. Alright. David, you, let's start with Google 'cause it, it's simpler.
Speaker 5:  The meta case is so complicated, it's gonna take us minute. David, you were
Speaker 5:  at the Google trial in the courthouse this week with Sundar try in the stand
Speaker 5:  for what I gather it. He was just there to say, please, please don't make
Speaker 5:  me scrum. Kind
Speaker 7:  Of. I I actually expected him to be a tiny bit more that than he
Speaker 7:  was. And so I've been in the courthouse three out
Speaker 7:  of the eight days now and I think we, I've missed a couple of interesting
Speaker 7:  people, but I've seen a bunch of the most interesting moments of the, the
Speaker 7:  remedies trial so far. And the, the thing that he's become abundantly
Speaker 7:  clear is that Google is petrified of the
Speaker 7:  part of the DOJs remedies that suggests that what Google actually needs
Speaker 7:  to do is take its search index, its ranking
Speaker 7:  information, which is just like how it ranks all the stuff, when it puts
Speaker 7:  it on the page and the query streams that it gets, which is all the stuff
Speaker 7:  that people are actually searching for and essentially give that to anyone
Speaker 7:  who wants it at, at what the DOJ calls a marginal cost. Nobody knows
Speaker 7:  what a marginal cost is or who's gonna decide. That is one of the things
Speaker 7:  Google's concerned about. But of all the things the DOJ wants,
Speaker 7:  that is the one that Google is terrified of. And
Speaker 7:  so Sundar, when he was on the stand, spent a long time
Speaker 7:  talking about how scary that is. And you could tell
Speaker 7:  the line he had rehearsed either in his head or with a bunch of people who
Speaker 7:  worked for him at Google. I suspect both. Yeah. You know, he you think he
Speaker 7:  just workshopped in the mirror that morning at the hotel? Yeah, he's just,
Speaker 7:  he's just in the car on this way going reverse engineer. Reverse engineer.
Speaker 7:  Was he? He But his whole thing was essentially that if
Speaker 7:  Google has made itself into what It is because it has
Speaker 7:  essentially out invested and outspent all of its rivals for 25 years.
Speaker 7:  And it's true, right? Like no, nobody has tried harder at search for
Speaker 7:  longer than Google. Certainly true.
Speaker 7:  And the thing he kept saying is, if you do this, if you take away
Speaker 7:  all of the stuff that we have done and you give it to everybody else who
Speaker 7:  asks for it, I don't know how as Google we can
Speaker 7:  continue to justify investing in search the way that we have. And
Speaker 7:  what he said is, if if you give people all this data, they can reverse engineer
Speaker 7:  Google. If you have all the information, you have the order in which we rank
Speaker 7:  that information and you have all the stuff that people are searching for,
Speaker 7:  that's the whole thing. That's it. You, you can, you can get from there to
Speaker 7:  every single thing about how Google works is Google's argument. They don't
Speaker 7:  have to give you the algorithm, but if you have the inputs and the outputs,
Speaker 7:  you can figure out the algorithm. And he, he over and over was
Speaker 7:  like, if you let people reverse engineer Google, why would I
Speaker 7:  keep building Google? And It is like, it, it just forcefully
Speaker 7:  saying that over and over. And he has really interesting thoughts about Chrome
Speaker 7:  because he, he started Chrome, like Chrome was how
Speaker 7:  Sundar sort of made his rise inside of Google in the first place.
Speaker 7:  But the thing for him is he's like, you cannot make us give this away because
Speaker 7:  it will crush Google search. And then the, the DOJ is sitting there
Speaker 7:  being like, yeah, that's, that's the goal. That's what we're here for. And
Speaker 7:  so it's, it's fascinating like for so much of this trial in the, in the liabilities
Speaker 7:  phase and in the remedies phase, these two sides have been talking completely
Speaker 7:  past each other. Google is like, we're very good and the
Speaker 7:  DOJ is like, everything you've done is illegal and they're, they, they just
Speaker 7:  have not been speaking to each other. And, and it was Sundar was the first
Speaker 7:  time that it was like, oh, we're actually all talking about the same thing
Speaker 7:  now. And, and what Google is saying is you
Speaker 7:  think that what you have to do is solve some of the problems that
Speaker 7:  you've created. And what I'm saying it will happen is it
Speaker 7:  will kill Google.
Speaker 7:  And it was just, it was just fascinating. And like Judge Meta who is
Speaker 7:  overseeing all of this, has asked a lot of questions about how big a deal
Speaker 7:  this kind of thing would be in the opening arguments. He asked a lot of questions
Speaker 7:  about what's a behavioral remedy and what's a structural remedy and does
Speaker 7:  this change within Google search constitute a behavioral
Speaker 7:  remedy which is easier to ask for and get or a structural remedy,
Speaker 7:  which is essentially breaking up Google and s Bahai's argument is, this is
Speaker 7:  breaking up Google. Like, it, it, he could not have been more apocalyptic
Speaker 7:  about what happens if this happens. And it was fascinating.
Speaker 5:  You know, it's interesting there's some wonkiness about behavioral remedies
Speaker 5:  and structural remedies.
Speaker 5:  The behavioral remedy is you're gonna change the way you act
Speaker 5:  and the government will watch out. Right?
Speaker 7:  Be cool,
Speaker 5:  Be cool, or we we're show up, right? We're watching you. And
Speaker 5:  there's a big argument you can actually listen to Rebecca Slaughter
Speaker 5:  FCC commissioner on decoder earlier this week. Her argument is,
Speaker 5:  behavioral remedies are more intrusive, right? It's the
Speaker 5:  government over your shoulder saying what you can and can't do. Right? And
Speaker 5:  the structural remedy where you break it up is actually the more democratic
Speaker 5:  small deed democratic
Speaker 5:  solution. 'cause you're just like, well you're broken up now, everyone try
Speaker 5:  your best with government out. And there's there's some real back and forth
Speaker 5:  there, right? Like do you want a Google that has
Speaker 5:  this administration sitting over its shoulder being like, are you behaving
Speaker 5:  yourself if you don't, if you love this administration, do you want to
Speaker 5:  Google that? I don't know has president a OC sitting over their
Speaker 5:  shoulder saying, are you doing what I want? Like there's a lot to contend
Speaker 5:  with there in the behavioral remedy. Whereas the structure remedy might be
Speaker 5:  the end of Google. If you listen to sunder Shy, like I, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's hard to evaluate which one's like a better idea,
Speaker 7:  Right? I mean It is sort of funny. I I went into this thinking and I have
Speaker 7:  talked to a bunch of people who confirmed that they were also thinking this
Speaker 7:  people sort of in and around the trial that the, the
Speaker 7:  idea that Google should have to divest Chrome was the
Speaker 7:  big swing nobody thought they would get right? That this was, this was the
Speaker 7:  thing you performatively give up in order to get the other stuff and that
Speaker 7:  it would wind down to just, just don't you,
Speaker 7:  you can't pay Apple $20 billion a year that that was gonna be where this
Speaker 7:  landed. The DOJ has argued far
Speaker 7:  more forcefully for the idea that
Speaker 7:  solving search in this way is what has to happen. And Google has come to
Speaker 7:  believe pretty clearly that it's a real threat and that it would be much
Speaker 7:  scarier. Like you get the distinct sense that Google would much rather sell
Speaker 7:  Chrome than give up this search data.
Speaker 5:  Well, you know, it's, there's like a natural experiment for Google 'cause
Speaker 5:  they're just the default on iPhone. That's like, it's not iOS Chrome that's
Speaker 5:  making them the money right now. Right? It's Chrome
Speaker 5:  search or it's, it's Google searches and Safari,
Speaker 6:  Right? What they would lose if they lost Chrome, right? If somebody else
Speaker 6:  is operating Chrome, I guess the threat is that they have their own search
Speaker 6:  engine or AI service to replace it. But if app, if they can still
Speaker 6:  offer a cut of search traffic and just say like, Hey, if you want to,
Speaker 6:  it's still just gonna be more Google search.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna be paying a lot.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. To be clear, Google would very much like to hold onto Chrome and Sundar
Speaker 7:  talked to a lot about that and mean
Speaker 5:  It's his baby. It
Speaker 7:  Is his baby. But also he talks a lot about the Chromium project, which is,
Speaker 7:  he is correct in saying Chromium is the most important
Speaker 7:  thing in web browsing right now. And It is, it's a technically open
Speaker 7:  source thing that Google fundamentally controls and runs and operates. He
Speaker 7:  said 94% of the code commits to chromium over the last year have been
Speaker 7:  from Google employees. It spends huge amounts of money on chromium.
Speaker 7:  Microsoft's browser is based on chromium, like brave is chromium. Almost
Speaker 7:  all of the browsers people use are chromium or Chrome.
Speaker 7:  And that, that matters, right? Like that's a huge deal. And the idea
Speaker 7:  of some other company, like I asked, I asked
Speaker 7:  a a a person around this trial, like, is the idea of
Speaker 7:  open AI administering chromium terrifying to you? And
Speaker 7:  they just laughed at me
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 7:  And, and Chromebooks change, ChromeOS changes. Like It
Speaker 7:  is a huge change for Google in a really meaningful way and all of a sudden
Speaker 7:  the the default Android browser becomes not yours, which is meaningful too.
Speaker 7:  But, but again, like
Speaker 7:  that is all immaterial to Google if it can't win
Speaker 7:  at search anymore. Like Chrome only matters because search matters. And
Speaker 7:  if you kill search, who cares?
Speaker 5:  I find this Chrome argument so disingenuous. Can I just say that
Speaker 5:  like I agree. Everything is Electron is Chrome. Half of the desktop apps
Speaker 5:  I'm running right now are chromium. That's true. Like
Speaker 5:  right Notion calendar is a chromium app. Like it's running, it's just an
Speaker 5:  electron thing, right? Like whatever,
Speaker 5:  all of those companies have an enormous incentive to make sure their apps
Speaker 5:  still work and that chromium is good. Google has an
Speaker 5:  enormous incentive to make sure the Android browser is good, which means
Speaker 5:  it will continue developing chromium upon which It is based.
Speaker 5:  So this idea that if they don't have chrome, just like Chrome on Windows
Speaker 5:  anymore, that they won't just immediately
Speaker 5:  fork chromium. They can't, they, that's not allowed. They're not one to
Speaker 7:  Their browser at all. They be allowed by, by the rules of the, the remedies
Speaker 7:  that the d OJ has proposed. Google would not be allowed to do that.
Speaker 7:  I mean, it, it could land elsewhere, but the idea of like,
Speaker 5:  It could, right? They can negotiate their way outta that to say we need to
Speaker 5:  make our first party browser on Android. Right?
Speaker 7:  A question we've gotten a bunch from folks actually is like, couldn't Google
Speaker 7:  just make another browser and there's a ton of wiggle room in it, but like
Speaker 7:  letter of the law? No, it couldn't, it would not be allowed to.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean it just feels like that's, that's the give and take here, right?
Speaker 5:  Like a bunch of people are still very motivated to keep chromium going.
Speaker 5:  A lot of people don't spend the money 'cause Google will, right?
Speaker 7:  That's the interesting counterfactual,
Speaker 5:  Right? But if that development moves elsewhere, it's not like all those people
Speaker 5:  have suddenly lost from incentive like Electron as an open
Speaker 5:  source platform unto itself relies on a chromium. You can just see how
Speaker 5:  that development ecosystem will like help. It won't be as big, it won't be
Speaker 5:  as rich, right? You won't get as many like, you know, old time classic
Speaker 5:  Google neck beards like doing chromium under the good of their heart that
Speaker 5:  like against no revenue, which is a thing that a company at Google
Speaker 5:  Scale can do and a company with Google's culture can do. Like,
Speaker 5:  you know, I've interviewed Sundar before, I'm like, is AI killing the web
Speaker 5:  for like an hour? And he's like, I love the web. And that's like, you believe
Speaker 5:  him because he made Chrome. He he cares whether or not he's actually killing
Speaker 5:  the web. I mean that was the harder that conversation last year. I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't know what's gonna happen here. It just feels very much like
Speaker 5:  Google making a search a little bit more interoperable
Speaker 5:  against the worry that someone will reverse engineer all of search
Speaker 5:  and then make it so that Google is worth nothing to consumers
Speaker 5:  is is just like fake worry. There's still
Speaker 5:  Google. The ver people still say they're gonna Google it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like you could make Bing an exact copy of Google
Speaker 5:  today and people wouldn't use bing. Bing has
Speaker 5:  made Bing an exact copy of Google today and people won't use Bing.
Speaker 5:  There's something about this that just seems, I dunno, we'll see
Speaker 5:  what happens. But it feels like they're making all of
Speaker 5:  this, you know, it's like the smartest people in the world are saying we
Speaker 5:  can't solve this problem. It just never rings sincere to me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no, I I think that's fair. And, and I, the other thing I should say
Speaker 7:  about chromium is I've talked to a lot of people who make browsers
Speaker 7:  who would love for Google to be less intense about
Speaker 7:  running chromium. Like everybody I talk to who doesn't work at Google
Speaker 7:  and works with chromium is like, God, it's so annoying that Google runs chromium
Speaker 7:  because what they want goes and everything they do is to benefit Google in
Speaker 7:  some way. And wouldn't it be great if we had a neutral thing that
Speaker 7:  just wanted browsers to be great? The problem is that's very expensive and
Speaker 7:  no one has ever done it before. But to your point, no one has ever done that
Speaker 7:  before because Google always has. Yeah. So like I, is there a a
Speaker 7:  way in the wings for this to work? It's certainly possible. The DOJ certainly
Speaker 7:  believes there is are are
Speaker 5:  There scaled open source projects that run the entire world that don't have
Speaker 5:  a Google involved? Yes, Linux exists.
Speaker 5:  Now, does Linux have its own deeply fucked
Speaker 5:  governance problems? It absolutely does, but like
Speaker 5:  it exists
Speaker 7:  Somewhere. Sundar PCI just heard you comparing Google to the Linux Foundation
Speaker 7:  and started sobbing uncontrollably.
Speaker 5:  I'm, the whole world is like, man, I hope the one guy shows up to commit
Speaker 5:  code to Linux for free. And like it works. Like thus far
Speaker 5:  it has worked. That's true. All right. That's a Google case where David,
Speaker 5:  I think you're gonna be in that courtroom a bunch just down the hall.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, upstairs around
Speaker 7:  The court, down the hall. It's, it's all, it's all pure chaos.
Speaker 7:  My favorite thing is this is a little inside baseball for everybody. So the
Speaker 7:  way this works is these, these courtrooms,
Speaker 5:  We should say it's the meta case that's just down the
Speaker 7:  Hall. Oh yeah. The meta case is just down the hall. And what I should say
Speaker 7:  is the courtrooms typically don't allow any electronics at all. Right? Like,
Speaker 7:  you can't, you can't even type on your laptop while you're in there. You
Speaker 7:  can't have phones, no, nothing. So what a lot of media members do who wanna
Speaker 7:  like take notes and write stories, there are media rooms for
Speaker 7:  each one of them, and sometimes it's another courtroom and they just get
Speaker 7:  like a video feed of the trial and they watch it there. They move the media
Speaker 7:  rooms around every day. So every morning you show up at the courthouse and
Speaker 7:  it's just pure chaos of a bunch of reporters trying to figure out which room
Speaker 7:  to go to. And every morning there's somebody who thinks they're in the Google
Speaker 7:  trial, but it's actually in the meta trial and vice versa. And the
Speaker 7:  other day when I was there for Sundar, they started the morning
Speaker 7:  with a completely unrelated criminal trial, just like it was just another
Speaker 7:  trial that that Judge Meta is overseeing. And so for five minutes, he just
Speaker 7:  had like a procedural conversation with a lawyer about when they were gonna
Speaker 7:  talk to this guy about his crime. And people are like pouring
Speaker 7:  into the media room as this is on the screens being like, who's in the jumpsuit?
Speaker 5:  There's this guy in like
Speaker 7:  An orange prison jumpsuit and everybody's trying to figure out which Google
Speaker 7:  executive this is. Yes, it's fantastic. I enjoyed every,
Speaker 5:  It wasn't Andy Rubin, it
Speaker 7:  Was not in fact. But so the, the meta trial, there are like
Speaker 7:  three, there are a lot of things going on in this meta trial and,
Speaker 5:  But we should note Lauren Finer is in that. Do you, do you and Lauren see
Speaker 5:  each other in the courthouse?
Speaker 7:  We do. We pass each other in the hallways a couple times a day. That's hilarious.
Speaker 7:  And Lauren, Lauren has become like sort of the, the house mom of the courtroom.
Speaker 7:  Every time, every time I look around she's like directing somebody where
Speaker 7:  to go and telling 'em where the cafeteria is and she's like, no, the mediums
Speaker 7:  are like, Lauren lives in the, the district court of DC That's right.
Speaker 7:  And someday she will leave and she'll be on The Vergecast and it'll be very
Speaker 7:  exciting. But there are, there are kind of three threads that I wanna talk
Speaker 7:  about from the, the meta trial this week. And the first is TikTok, which
Speaker 7:  has come up an awful lot in the course of the meta trial
Speaker 7:  because the like, big open question
Speaker 7:  for all of this, and we've talked about this is like, what is a social network,
Speaker 7:  right? And that, what was it, what was it
Speaker 7:  one day where TikTok was gone has turned into
Speaker 7:  this incredibly interesting data point of who competes with who based on
Speaker 7:  what happened when TikTok was gone. And tiktoks head of
Speaker 7:  operations was on the stand this week talking about what reels is
Speaker 7:  versus what TikTok is and how people use Reels isn, how people use TikTok
Speaker 7:  and how Instagram has adapted Reels,
Speaker 7:  isn its own app to match TikTok. But this question of
Speaker 7:  like, what is TikTok and
Speaker 7:  how have all the other apps, particularly within Meta responded to it, has
Speaker 7:  become like one of the most important parts of this whole trial. And
Speaker 7:  it's deeply bizarre because TikTok is supposed to be gone. So,
Speaker 6:  So is it good for meta or bad for meta when people flock
Speaker 6:  to its apps in, in place of TikTok, right? That shows that
Speaker 6:  they're, the, the, the sun around which everything else orbits.
Speaker 6:  On the other hand, it shows that people are other places.
Speaker 7:  It's really true. And also a lot of different,
Speaker 7:  a lot of different witnesses on the sand this week have been forced to acknowledge
Speaker 7:  that there is nothing remotely unique about Instagram at all.
Speaker 6:  I mean, over and over, over
Speaker 7:  Like, oh yeah, Instagram's just a copy of
Speaker 6:  Other apps. Apps smashed together.
Speaker 7:  Exactly. Which I've enjoyed very much. Like there was a, there was a line
Speaker 7:  from, I believe his name was Aaron Pressman at, or Aaron Presser, excuse
Speaker 7:  me, at TikTok who called TikTok Reels
Speaker 7:  ISN shorts, virtually and deliberately indistinguishable and function
Speaker 7:  and user experience quoting something that the company had written
Speaker 7:  in March. It's fabulous. I just love it. It's very good.
Speaker 7:  But th this, this TikTok thing, I I think to your point, Jake
Speaker 7:  is like Meta is trying to prove that it has millions of competitors, right?
Speaker 7:  And that that TikTok competes with Instagram, and Instagram
Speaker 7:  competes with Facebook and actually this is like a huge teaming ecosystem
Speaker 7:  of places people hang out and spend their time.
Speaker 7:  The the case against It is that
Speaker 7:  Facebook is a, is a personal social network and that that's, that's
Speaker 7:  what it does. And that that's where it has a monopoly and thus all
Speaker 7:  the stuff that it has done is monopolistic. And the
Speaker 7:  the TikTok thing, I think on balance probably helps
Speaker 7:  meta because what they're saying is they, they've had
Speaker 7:  executives from Tumblr and Pinterest and Strava
Speaker 7:  come up on the stand and say, we're not a social network.
Speaker 7:  We are, we are about interests, right? Like even, even Twitter folks said
Speaker 7:  this, like, we're, we're a place to go for things that you're interested
Speaker 7:  in, which is not the same as a place to go to find people that you're friends
Speaker 7:  with. But Meta gets up and is like, well, when TikTok dies, everybody comes
Speaker 7:  to our app and then when TikTok comes back, everybody leaves and goes back
Speaker 7:  to TikTok. So what are we gonna, what do we do?
Speaker 6:  I, I do think it's really interesting, like it feels to me, and, and tell
Speaker 6:  me if I'm wrong, but it feels to me like a lot of this case
Speaker 6:  is premised around this I idea of the personal social network
Speaker 6:  you connecting with your friends and your family, which is this very old
Speaker 6:  school, old school, you know, 10, 15 years ago, I guess
Speaker 6:  vision of social media. And I feel like if Facebook vanished
Speaker 6:  today, I don't know that there would be a one-to-one replacement,
Speaker 6:  right? That is just not how people are thinking about social media anymore.
Speaker 6:  As I think, which may maybe
Speaker 7:  Where all my angriest neighbors to try to send their friends to jail,
Speaker 6:  There is another app for that that is next for That's true. Yeah. But like,
Speaker 6:  maybe that hasn't popped up because Facebook has this monopoly and they're
Speaker 6:  being anti-competitive, but maybe it has hasn't popped up because people
Speaker 6:  just want different types, types of experiences on social media. And I feel
Speaker 6:  like that's what we're seeing with all these other companies that they're
Speaker 6:  calling up.
Speaker 5:  But this was Mark's insight. I mean, this is the heart of the case
Speaker 5:  is Mark Zuckerberg woke up and said, every so often
Speaker 5:  there's a new thing that people want to do on their phones that
Speaker 5:  gives rise to another social network. There's another kind of sharing dynamic.
Speaker 5:  And so Facebook was whatever it was not, or not for
Speaker 5:  colleges. And then he identified photo sharing on Instagram and
Speaker 5:  said, I gotta buy that one. And then he identified, and there's all these
Speaker 5:  emails where he lays out his thinking and then he identified group
Speaker 5:  messaging and messaging and said, I gotta buy WhatsApp. And so the, the
Speaker 5:  point here is the anti-competitive move
Speaker 5:  was to stifle the thing that could have taken Facebook's market share
Speaker 5:  and whether or not they could have bought a TikTok.
Speaker 5:  It's like we, you're just getting into this place where they became so big
Speaker 5:  that TikTok was too big to buy and also owned by the Chinese government or
Speaker 5:  controlled by the Chinese government somewhere. Like, it's like, it's the
Speaker 5:  weirdest one because they, they did try to buy Snap,
Speaker 5:  right? And they, Evan said, no,
Speaker 5:  I have this quote here from Rebecca Slaughter is a commissioner of the FCC.
Speaker 5:  She was a democratic commissioner of the FTC. She's appointed by Trump in
Speaker 5:  the first term, legally fired by Trump in this term. But she is
Speaker 5:  one of the commissioners at the FT C who voted this case out of the commission
Speaker 5:  and said we should go to trial on it. And so I asked her about this market
Speaker 5:  definition thing. I was like, this is dumb, right? Like
Speaker 5:  Met is a narrative about this is like putting us in personal social
Speaker 5:  networking is whatever. And she said, look, all antitrust cases are what
Speaker 5:  market definition to a degree, it's very tortured things that makes people
Speaker 5:  hate lawyers. The concept of antitrust law is very simple. The administration
Speaker 5:  of it gets very complicated. Market definition is always hard. Everyone has
Speaker 5:  a different view about the right way to define a market. It all gets litigated.
Speaker 5:  And then she went on to tell me what this case is really about is
Speaker 5:  whether meta bought competitors to eliminate the risk of competition. That
Speaker 5:  is the argument at the end of the day. Did it not wanna compete on the merits,
Speaker 5:  but instead take out potential competition through acquisition in order to
Speaker 5:  build and maintain a monopoly in a way that's illegal. It's not more
Speaker 5:  complicated than that. So I think Meta is putting a lot of stock into the
Speaker 5:  existence of Mei. It's like, here's this dumb thing we can say to make everyone
Speaker 5:  think everything else is dumb. And then you have the actual Federal Trade
Speaker 5:  Commission saying no, this case is, you saw Instagram as a rising
Speaker 5:  threat and you bought it to kill it. And they've shown that now I
Speaker 5:  think pretty conclusively. And here are all of these other threats.
Speaker 5:  If you could have bought TikTok when TikTok went down, people came to your
Speaker 5:  apps, they're obviously competitors. If you could've, you would've, I don't
Speaker 5:  know how that's gonna go. I I really don't. This is, this case is real weird.
Speaker 5:  It's like this old lawyer cliche. I keep saying like, if you don't have the
Speaker 5:  law, you argue the facts. If you don't have the facts, you argue the law.
Speaker 5:  And if you don't have either, you pound the table. This is like old law professors
Speaker 5:  say this, they think they're very clever,
Speaker 5:  but that's what, what the, that's what's happening here. Like Meta is trying
Speaker 5:  to argue the Esoterical law of market definition and the government is like,
Speaker 5:  but you bought Instagram,
Speaker 7:  Right? And that, I mean we talked about this last week, but that was the
Speaker 7:  thing that was so damaging about the, the Kevin system. Bit of it. And to
Speaker 7:  that point actually, I think the, the most interesting piece of all that
Speaker 7:  this week has been about WhatsApp, which has come up
Speaker 7:  more this week than in sort of previous parts of the testimony. And
Speaker 7:  it has become very clear that Facebook was petrified about what
Speaker 7:  messaging apps might do to Facebook in particular. And
Speaker 7:  there the, it was really worried that Google was gonna buy WhatsApp and turn
Speaker 7:  it into a, a cross platform social network. Which is very funny
Speaker 7:  because at the same time Lauren is hearing this, I was sitting in the
Speaker 7:  courtroom listening to Sundar talk about how bad Google Plus was
Speaker 7:  and get burned by the plaintiffs for how bad Google Buzz was
Speaker 7:  and use, they, they literally use that as an example of how Google is not
Speaker 7:  able to take care of its user's privacy. That's how bad Google Bus was. And
Speaker 7:  so Google this company that can't make a social network to save its life,
Speaker 7:  Facebook is terrified, is gonna spend a bunch of money on WhatsApp, make
Speaker 7:  it cross-platform and take over the world with it. Because to your point,
Speaker 7:  they perceived messaging apps as the
Speaker 7:  future of how people interact with their friends and family. Which check,
Speaker 7:  correct. They won That was it, that was, that was exactly correct. The,
Speaker 7:  the group chat has taken over the Facebook feed in a real way
Speaker 7:  and they were worried about iMessage and the all of this stuff, right? They,
Speaker 7:  they looked at all the messaging apps out there and said, okay, we are the
Speaker 7:  place people hang out with their friends right now that is going to move
Speaker 7:  to messaging apps. It's more private, it's, it's easier to administer. Like
Speaker 7:  there's just a lot of reasons for it. And they went and got
Speaker 7:  WhatsApp A because they understood that that was gonna work. B, because they
Speaker 7:  understood that Facebook's own stuff, including Messenger was not gonna be
Speaker 7:  that. There's been some really interesting testimony from folks at Facebook
Speaker 7:  who were just like, messenger just wasn't that thing. It was popular, but
Speaker 7:  it just, it wasn't, it it wasn't gonna win. And then they
Speaker 7:  were, they were worried about what iMessage might be like. There were questions
Speaker 7:  inside of Facebook about whether Apple was going to turn on ads
Speaker 7:  and more social features inside of iMessage and
Speaker 7:  Apple's just like, we're not gonna do that. That's a stupid idea. We would
Speaker 7:  never do that.
Speaker 7:  But that, that's been the other thread of this is is the same thing
Speaker 7:  Mark Zuckerberg on Instagram, which is photo sharing is is
Speaker 7:  the way people are going to share going forward. And he was right about that.
Speaker 7:  He was also right about messaging apps. And so now the question is, did
Speaker 7:  did Facebook sort of neuter WhatsApp by buying it or
Speaker 7:  did it help it ascend to new heights? Which is the exact same question about
Speaker 7:  Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't know man, it my, did you look at all these cases,
Speaker 5:  the end like apple's just first quarter of the year is like,
Speaker 5:  well, Apple's gonna be a whole different company. Google's gonna come out
Speaker 5:  of these cases. By the way, we haven't even talked about ad tech remedies
Speaker 5:  like that hasn't even started, right? You, you, you think Google will be
Speaker 5:  a different company if you pull apart search, wait until you gut the money.
Speaker 5:  Google's gonna end the year in a totally different place. Yeah. Meta might
Speaker 5:  end the year in a totally different place. Like we're in for a restructuring
Speaker 5:  of the internet. It's coming
Speaker 7:  Good.
Speaker 5:  Something's gonna happen. If you know what It is by, by all means tell me.
Speaker 5:  I I think it's party speakers. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's something. Something's something's up. You can feel it in the air. It
Speaker 5:  should be exciting. It's weird. Like so much other stuff is so foreboding
Speaker 5:  that I think this feels foreboding, but it's, I think it's actually exciting.
Speaker 5:  Like there's space, these companies
Speaker 5:  under all this pressure is going to create space. Yeah. Other people are
Speaker 5:  gonna build stuff.
Speaker 7:  You look at what happened at the Microsoft case and it's like a, because
Speaker 7:  of the Microsoft case, we got Google. Like that's, that's just a thing that
Speaker 7:  happened, right? And we're, we're now doing that at greater scale
Speaker 7:  with a bunch of different companies all at once. And it's, it,
Speaker 7:  we're doing it at a very weird economic moment. So I think like
Speaker 7:  this is ordinarily a time that you would see venture capitalists just like
Speaker 7:  falling all over themselves to invest in everything everywhere. Because suddenly
Speaker 7:  there's, it feels like there might be space in tons of these markets for
Speaker 7:  the first time. That's not happening because they're all in group chats being
Speaker 7:  weirdos with each other. They've
Speaker 5:  Got dumber ideas. One of the, one of the answers regulators
Speaker 5:  I talked to yesterday said, VCs have hated Apple for so long.
Speaker 5:  It is only a matter of time before the money starts falling.
Speaker 7:  I, I believe it. I mean there's so much there.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. We'll see. I'm just saying it's all this stuff is happening
Speaker 5:  and you can argue about the, the individual twists and turns,
Speaker 5:  but this is the stuff that creates space for new companies and honestly It
Speaker 5:  is a little exciting. Yeah. Alright, we gotta take a break. We're gonna run
Speaker 5:  through this sliding round. It's gonna happen. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  can't just podcast with you. Clowns forever.
Speaker 5:  We got party speakers to find exactly. Can someone invent a metal
Speaker 5:  detector for party speakers? Think about my Navy ship is leaving soon, so
Speaker 5:  I have to finish this podcast. Please, please. More enlisted service members
Speaker 5:  send us photos. Neli, is It, is it time? It's the lightning round. But is
Speaker 5:  It, is it once again that time for America's? It's time. It's time. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It is time for America's favorite non-food podcast
Speaker 5:  within a podcast that I feel I can say comfortably. Award-winning,
Speaker 5:  future award. A word for composed award-winning
Speaker 5:  podcast in a podcast. Brendan right is dummy. Alright,
Speaker 5:  so a a quiet, another quiet week for Brendan. He did
Speaker 5:  congratulate himself a lot. So you, we, we just hit a hundred days of the
Speaker 5:  Trump administration.
Speaker 5:  Brenda put out a tweet with just a list of things that he says he's
Speaker 5:  accomplished. He, Brendan believes that he strengthened national security
Speaker 5:  in advanced public safety. He believes he is protected consumers and
Speaker 5:  expanded America's space economy. Brendan all by himself is that Brendan's
Speaker 5:  job. He's unleashed high speed infrastructure. He's restored our leadership
Speaker 5:  in wireless, which as you know, is under constant
Speaker 5:  existential threat if you don't
Speaker 5:  upgrade the 5G network. Something China.
Speaker 5:  Yep. It's just there, it's just in the background all the time. And you know,
Speaker 5:  he says he is restored free speech. So it's a long list. You can, we will
Speaker 5:  link it. It's a tweet,
Speaker 5:  you know, under restoring free speech, he claims that he has joined DOJ Assistant
Speaker 5:  Attorney General Slater and FCC Chairman Ferguson to launch a campaign
Speaker 5:  to smash the censorship cartel and restore free speech rights, which
Speaker 5:  means sending threatening letters from the government about other people's
Speaker 5:  speech and just upside down world all over the place with Brendan.
Speaker 5:  So Brendan's very proud of, it's a very Trumpian, everything he says
Speaker 5:  is a thing that he didn't do. Yeah. And a lot of it's just stuff the Ft C
Speaker 5:  does. Like, he's like, we did a spectrum option. It's like, yeah, it was
Speaker 5:  Tuesday at the FEC. Great. What I wanna call it this week is we,
Speaker 5:  there's a bunch of other hundred days coverage of Brendan that we should
Speaker 5:  call out. We did big piece Carl Bode, who we love working with,
Speaker 5:  just ran down all the stuff Brandon has done. It's basically familiar, I
Speaker 5:  think to Vergecast listeners, particularly listeners of America's favorite
Speaker 5:  podcast on the podcast. Brandon Carl dummy. That piece is great. Carl is
Speaker 5:  a ferocious writer. He has been the model for how I
Speaker 5:  think about writing for consumer advocacy and consumer rights for a long
Speaker 5:  time. He just did a great job. So go read that piece. I also wanna call out
Speaker 5:  other people have started taking note of Ren in real meaningful ways.
Speaker 5:  So Fire, which is a free speech advocacy organization, not
Speaker 5:  without its own controversies that has a strong point of view in what cases
Speaker 5:  it takes and doesn't take people a lot of feelings about it. You might almost
Speaker 5:  call it the more conservative, free speech advocacy organization. I wouldn't
Speaker 5:  go that far, but some people do. They have a long piece about how
Speaker 5:  Brendan sucks.
Speaker 5:  Like just Straightforwardly Fire published a piece called Brendan
Speaker 5:  Carr's bizaro world FCC. They have a cartoon of him
Speaker 5:  with a backwards FCC logo dressed up like, like Bizaro superman.
Speaker 5:  And the caption of the cartoon, Brendan is saying the FCC should operate
Speaker 5:  as the nation's speech police that we're just gonna link it
Speaker 7:  Full on the nose. But you know, it's
Speaker 5:  A little on the nose. Yeah, but it's not just us screaming it. Right? It
Speaker 5:  It is some of our nation's preeminent free speech
Speaker 5:  organizations, some of which, like, I'm, I'm pointing this out just to
Speaker 5:  point it out, are not always aligned with what people think my politics are.
Speaker 5:  Although I think my politics are basically like, free markets are good and
Speaker 5:  don't be racist, which aren't exactly communists, but whatever, whatever
Speaker 5:  you think my politics are,
Speaker 5:  they don't always align with some of these groups. So racism is bad. They
Speaker 5:  call me Uncle Woke.
Speaker 7:  You just said like eight things that people are gonna make us put on T-shirts.
Speaker 7:  Now I just want you to know that including they call me Uncle Woke. That's,
Speaker 7:  that's a, that's just everyone who's listening. Please know. I will make
Speaker 7:  that t-shirt.
Speaker 5:  Like what, what It's, so I get these notes, like I did the piece
Speaker 5:  about calling Jeff Bezos a coward. I got to the most bananas emails of all
Speaker 5:  time just like calling me like literally like,
Speaker 5:  you are a communist. And I was like, the only political opinions I've really
Speaker 5:  expressed consistently are like, free markets are good
Speaker 5:  competition makes better products. Like what do you want from me? Exactly.
Speaker 5:  And the answer is state regulated speech.
Speaker 5:  Clearly the LA Times is a good piece about Brendan running down all the things
Speaker 5:  he's done. So the coverage is out there. It's not just us. It's not just
Speaker 5:  me Uncle woke. But as always, I wanna end Brendan Carr as a
Speaker 5:  dummy by saying, Brendan, I know you listen, I know you love
Speaker 5:  attention. You do. You, you, you live for it. Come
Speaker 5:  on the show, man.
Speaker 5:  If you can defend any of this crap, you should do it. You should make the
Speaker 5:  argument, you should say the words out loud to me and then win. Don't you
Speaker 5:  wanna win? Brandon? Don't you wanna collect this trophy from me? I'll,
Speaker 5:  I'll make you a trophy if you win that debate and you can have it, you could
Speaker 5:  tweet about it, you could show it to your buddy Elon, the offers in
Speaker 5:  front of you. I just, I don't think you can do it. So
Speaker 5:  as always, Brendan, I think you're a dummy, but you are welcome on decoder.
Speaker 5:  You're welcome on The Vergecast. You're welcome to one of those, you know
Speaker 5:  those things I do on YouTube now where like 20 kids wave flags of people
Speaker 5:  sitting in the center. We'll do that. Let's go. I don't think
Speaker 5:  you will. 'cause I think you're a dummy and I think you know that you can't
Speaker 5:  win. As always, this has been, Brendan Carr is a dummy America's favorite
Speaker 5:  podcast. Within the podcast,
Speaker 7:  TikTok Trends with Brendan Carr is very clearly a podcast
Speaker 7:  we need to launch. So Brendan, Brendan, get at us.
Speaker 5:  What's that? It's, what's it called? P Polonium. But
Speaker 5:  you know what I'm
Speaker 6:  Talking about. It's like Jubilee. Jubilee. Is that it?
Speaker 5:  Oh, by the way, if any, if there's any like young reporters out there who
Speaker 5:  wanna to profile Jubilee email us. I'm fascinated by this
Speaker 5:  entire situation. Whatever is going on, there is some of the
Speaker 5:  weirdest new media that has ever existed. And I, I
Speaker 5:  don't understand how any of it works. I would like to know more. Do you want
Speaker 5:  to write a feature? Send us pitch.
Speaker 7:  Love this. Jake, I, I need, I have a favorite to ask.
Speaker 7:  I put a story that Alex Heath wrote about world coin in our
Speaker 7:  rundown, and I didn't read it because I refuse to learn anything about world
Speaker 7:  coin. So can you explain it, David, while I don't pay
Speaker 6:  Attention, David, I was worried for, for folks who, who are
Speaker 6:  watching at home, we, David just drops a gigantic document with a bunch
Speaker 6:  of stories that we may or may not discuss. I try my best
Speaker 6:  to prep for all of them. World coin is so
Speaker 6:  inexplicable. I I spoke
Speaker 6:  repeatedly with Alex Heath about this story. I've read this story,
Speaker 6:  I edited this story. I still cannot truly explain
Speaker 6:  what world Coin is, why it exists or what it's doing. It re
Speaker 6:  the, the, the main news, the, this is the, the, the
Speaker 6:  eyeball scanning startup, Sam
Speaker 5:  Altman from Samal, from eyeball scanning startup. It
Speaker 7:  Has an, it's
Speaker 6:  An orb. They have an orb. Yeah. Scans your eyes, puts you on the blockchain
Speaker 6:  and that validates your id. Here's the most important thing.
Speaker 6:  You can now verify yourself on Tinder by getting your
Speaker 6:  eyeballs scanned by Sam Altman. Yep. And
Speaker 6:  when you're swiping through Tinder, that's either gonna be a clear
Speaker 6:  way to know that somebody is or is not a match for you. So I think that's
Speaker 6:  a big upgrade. The main, the the actual news is they're bringing it to the
Speaker 6:  US for the first time. It's, it's legal in most states.
Speaker 6:  Not all of them, but they're bringing it to the us. You can now get your
Speaker 6:  eyeballs scanned, you can now get on the blockchain. You can now get some
Speaker 6:  of the world coin.
Speaker 6:  I think the idea is that this is somehow going to
Speaker 6:  help authenticate humans. Yeah. As being humans
Speaker 6:  in a world of AI nonsense happening on the internet. I'm not
Speaker 6:  quite sure where the crypto coin comes in. That
Speaker 6:  still feels a little like fuzzy magic. It'll be worth value
Speaker 6:  somehow. But yeah, the main, the main thing is they have brought it to the
Speaker 6:  us now they're opening some stores. You'll be able to go to razor stores
Speaker 6:  and while you're shopping for gaming accessories, you can get your eyeballs
Speaker 6:  scanned and get on the blockchain. I would say everything about this
Speaker 6:  feels like Mad Libs. I, I, I still
Speaker 6:  like, I'm not sure how this all came together. I'm not sure how
Speaker 6:  they decided to partner with Tinder. Well,
Speaker 5:  'cause they, they need off providers or they need to prove that being
Speaker 5:  an off provider is useful to someone. So you're, you go, you're, you
Speaker 5:  know, like you're worried about getting catfished on Tinder and you're like,
Speaker 5:  you know what? That's an eyeball skin. That's a real person. Mm.
Speaker 6:  These eyeballs match. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's like a, it's like they, they look, they did this announcement
Speaker 5:  in San Francisco, Alex Heath went, lots of people went. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Sam Hunt was there. People wanna be there. The real quotes about all of this
Speaker 5:  came at a previous event that they had last October
Speaker 5:  because
Speaker 5:  like any startup, they need scale. Like they need people to scan their
Speaker 5:  eyeballs to make everything work. And so they're announcing in the us which
Speaker 5:  will get them scale. But I just wanna read this quote from last year
Speaker 5:  to provide access to every human. We need more orbs, lots more
Speaker 5:  orbs, probably on the order of a thousand times more orbs than
Speaker 5:  we have today. Not more orbs, but more orbs in
Speaker 5:  more places.
Speaker 5:  Then they're launching a service called Orb on
Speaker 5:  Demand that will let people order orbs. Much like a pizza
Speaker 5:  you would have delivered to your apartment. So you can push a button
Speaker 5:  and someone with an orb will come to your apartment, scan your
Speaker 5:  eyes.
Speaker 5:  I can't, it's, it's so silly. I love it. I
Speaker 7:  Love it. This is all completely vindicated, my total uninterest in knowing
Speaker 7:  anything about this story.
Speaker 5:  I love it. Look the world soon our social networks will be full of weird
Speaker 5:  AI avatars all trying to bone you and marry Kevin Rus.
Speaker 5:  And I will prove I knew. And you're gonna have to push the orb button and
Speaker 5:  have an orb show up at your house and verify that
Speaker 5:  it's actually you who is deeply in love with Kevin and not some rogue
Speaker 5:  ai.
Speaker 7:  And It is me, Kevin, you're listening. Get at me. I'm right
Speaker 7:  here. I've been right here
Speaker 5:  All along. It's very good. It's very good. All right. Should we do like one
Speaker 5:  or two more?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, let's do
Speaker 5:  One or two more. We need like a pallet cleanser. I would say We need more
Speaker 5:  orbs. A thousand times more orbs is a good palate cleanser.
Speaker 7:  Let's, let's do, let's do the Trump thing really fast just so you can take
Speaker 7:  another cover.
Speaker 5:  I said pallet cleanser, man. Wait,
Speaker 6:  Wait. Can I talk about some more AI nonsense? Yes. There's this, so meta
Speaker 6:  launched a meta AI app, and it, it has a social
Speaker 6:  feed of things. People are just sharing their AI prompts.
Speaker 6:  So you can have a conversation with Meta's ai and it'll just post the transcript.
Speaker 6:  You'll be talking to it. You can hear somebody say like, Hey, what kind of
Speaker 6:  crackers should I eat today? And then the AI just is like, oh, maybe you
Speaker 6:  could try a whole grain. And they're like, I don't think so. It is,
Speaker 6:  I I, I think the idea is to give people an idea of what they're supposed
Speaker 6:  to do with ai. I have to tell you, this is the single strongest
Speaker 6:  argument against AI that I have seen yet. If you scroll through this feed,
Speaker 6:  It is just like total nonsense, nonstop. It is incredible.
Speaker 6:  I can't look away.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 5:  Awful. I mean, that's what they want, right? Is I wanna see
Speaker 5:  what, how somebody has Joe Broken meta ai. You know, mark Ser gave an
Speaker 5:  interview that Ben Thompson, I think he came out today as we were recording,
Speaker 5:  and he says explicitly the thing we were talking about a couple
Speaker 5:  weeks ago. He says, the future of Met
Speaker 5:  Ben asked Mark, like, what do you wanna do with ai? And Mark is like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  I wanna do better ad targeting, obviously, you know, we wanna help people
Speaker 5:  make more content, you know, feeds full of AI content, all this stuff. And
Speaker 5:  he says this thing in the middle where he's like, eventually we're gonna
Speaker 5:  make the ads for advertisers and you're just gonna connect to your bank account
Speaker 5:  and tell us what business outcomes you want. And then we'll, we'll just like,
Speaker 5:  deliver you results. Like we'll just have sold your products for you, which
Speaker 5:  means they're gonna like, make videos of your products with ai, write the
Speaker 5:  copy with ai,
Speaker 5:  generate infinite amounts of creative with ai. Like
Speaker 5:  you're just gonna, it's like literally a black box. Like you give them some
Speaker 5:  money, they make an advertising campaign, and then some of your products
Speaker 5:  get sold. And that's his literally his vision for the future of ai.
Speaker 7:  It's so funny to put that next to the thing that meta
Speaker 7:  executives have been saying for a while, which is that like a lot of people
Speaker 7:  go to these services and appreciate the ads as content.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, there, there just is this belief that actually what people
Speaker 7:  really want is AI made stuff like that, that is like a cultural
Speaker 7:  value at meta. That AI stuff is good and people will like
Speaker 7:  it. And I see no evidence of that fact in the
Speaker 7:  actual real world.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Are you tell us what your objective is. You connect to your bank account.
Speaker 5:  You don't need any creative, you don't need any targeting demographics, you
Speaker 5:  don't need any measurement except you're able to read the results that we
Speaker 5:  spit out. And it's like, you know, you guys have a, have a lot of
Speaker 5:  like ad fraud scandals. Like you're, you kind of famous for inflating the
Speaker 5:  metrics like that. Give
Speaker 7:  Us a lot of money and trust us, we're Facebook what could possibly go wrong.
Speaker 5:  I wrote a story about this. I emailed some media people, some ad agency people.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna read this quote. This is a re return. I said, can you respond
Speaker 5:  to this? One person said, I've reacted pretty viscerally to this.
Speaker 5:  I need a moment to say something smart, which is incredible. And
Speaker 5:  another person did not take the time and they just said,
Speaker 5:  quote, read the results that we spit out is gold the full cycle towards their
Speaker 5:  customers from moderate condescension to active antagonism to we'll
Speaker 5:  fucking kill you.
Speaker 7:  Perfect.
Speaker 5:  Perfect. So I, I suspect there's a, a war coming between meta
Speaker 5:  and the a industry. They're not happy with it. All right. A pallet
Speaker 5:  cleanser. Just to end it on like the nerdiest note. I can end it on. In a
Speaker 5:  happy note. LG has spent 20 years
Speaker 5:  trying to make ole panels with blue phosphorescent backlights.
Speaker 5:  It says it's ready to manufacture tandem panels that use both fluorescence
Speaker 5:  and phosphorescence. This will bring power conduct down by 15%.
Speaker 5:  There's nothing that makes me happier.
Speaker 7:  None of what you just said sounds like words to me. We're happy about this.
Speaker 7:  This is good.
Speaker 5:  Everything about the future is, is predicted first by
Speaker 5:  what happens in display technology. It's absolutely true,
Speaker 5:  right? You can't get curved phones or folding phones without curved or
Speaker 5:  bendy OLED panels. You couldn't make smartphones without thin LCDs with low
Speaker 5:  power draw. You, you couldn't make laptops with CRTs,
Speaker 5:  although some people did try. You. You see what
Speaker 5:  I'm saying? You, you can look ahead to what the display industry is doing.
Speaker 5:  You can predict the future. And I'm just saying
Speaker 5:  20 years in the making, slightly thinner, brighter, better.
Speaker 5:  Oh, adss are coming and something will happen.
Speaker 7:  That is exciting. I'm into that. See, I've been doing a lot of research on
Speaker 7:  the Sony Watchman from the eighties recently for a project that will become
Speaker 7:  very clear to everyone later this year.
Speaker 7:  And the, the like enthusiasm for a slightly different
Speaker 7:  take on A CRT. Unbelievable. Yeah. People were freaking out. They were like,
Speaker 7:  they made the CRT this big instead of this big. It's gonna change everything.
Speaker 5:  It didn't, I'm just saying people react mostly to what things look like and
Speaker 5:  the, the way you change things, how things look like, you change the display
Speaker 5:  technology. So if you pay attention to that, you will know what things are
Speaker 5:  gonna look like then. Then you know the future. And you don't need an orb
Speaker 5:  to do it.
Speaker 5:  We need more orbs, a thousand times more orbs. That's it. That's
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 15:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 15:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 15:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 15:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 15:  that's it. We'll see you next week.