# Transcript
ID: 4f233f48-9bf3-4ee5-a78f-8d5c60969e1d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6490319938406389617/1966135754580332553/s93290-US-6492s-1754992231.mp3
Description: This week on The Vergecast, we enter the Jen-era of Hot Girl Vergecast Summer, with a deep dive into the business of the smart home. The Verge’s smart home reviewer, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy (aka Jen), chats with Ken Fairbanks, a longtime customer of Insteon who ended up buying the smart lighting company when it went into bankruptcy.
Ken shares the story of how one of the original smart lighting protocols, founded in the post-X10 era when home automation moved from wired to wireless, floundered, and how he and a band of users brought it back from the dead. He dishes what he’s learned about how to keep the lights on — from customer loyalty and the value of subscriptions, to what tariffs are doing to the industry and how some hardware companies are just pyramid schemes.
Then, in a special supersized (and we mean SUPER) Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com), Jen is joined by smart home expert Richard Gunther, co-host of The Smart Home Show, to tackle a bunch of your burning smart lighting questions. They answer everything from how to move your smart home to which Thread border router you should buy for your Matter setup. Plus, they run down their own smart lighting set-ups.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of finally
Speaker 2:  figuring out how to get all of my smart lights working in one single
Speaker 2:  app. I'm your friend Jen Tuy and welcome to the
Speaker 2:  Jen era of The Vergecast. I will be here for the next two weeks
Speaker 2:  while David gets to play with his gorgeous baby. Today on the show
Speaker 2:  we are going to find out how you go about saving a smart home
Speaker 2:  company. I'm chatting with Ken Fairbanks, CEO of
Speaker 2:  Insteon Technologies about the unlikely comeback of one of the
Speaker 2:  original smart lighting companies. Then the guy I
Speaker 2:  go to when I have questions about smart lighting, Richard Gunther
Speaker 2:  is going to join me for a super sized Vergecast Hotline,
Speaker 2:  all about smart lighting, where we tackle your burning and frankly,
Speaker 2:  super complicated questions about how to make smart lighting work for you.
Speaker 2:  And all that is coming up right after the break. This is The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. One of the biggest fears for every smart home user
Speaker 2:  is that the products that they rely on to make their homes work well One
Speaker 2:  day stop working In 2022, I covered this exact
Speaker 2:  story. How Smart Lighting Company Insteon went dark
Speaker 2:  overnight. Someone flipped the switch and hundreds of thousands of customers
Speaker 2:  were figuratively at least left in the dark.
Speaker 2:  Insteon was not a fly-by-night startup either. It was floundered in
Speaker 2:  2005 as one of the first smart lighting companies in the post
Speaker 2:  X 10 era when Smart Home went from wires to wireless.
Speaker 2:  So what do you do when the product your home relies on
Speaker 2:  stops working the way it's supposed to? My guest today, Ken
Speaker 2:  Fairbanks, is an early Insteon user and he had a really
Speaker 2:  unusual solution to that problem. He bought the company.
Speaker 2:  Now three years later, Insteon is back with a new website,
Speaker 2:  new products, and Ken installed as CEO.
Speaker 2:  Welcome Ken. Thank you so much for being here with us on The Vergecast today.
Speaker 6:  I'm looking forward to it. Thank you for the opportunity.
Speaker 2:  So as I was just mentioning, you are one of the
Speaker 2:  smart home users that actually decided to buy the Smart Home
Speaker 2:  Company, but you weren't exactly a
Speaker 2:  typical Insteon customer where you actually helped start
Speaker 2:  this company early on and have a lot of experience in the smart home.
Speaker 2:  So can you tell us a little bit about your background with Insteon?
Speaker 6:  Sure. So I was with Hewlett Packard for 20 some years. I left
Speaker 6:  Hewlett Packard in early two thousands and started doing some business
Speaker 6:  consulting here in Southern California. And one of the companies
Speaker 6:  I got introduced to was Smart Home.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And Smart Home is the company that owned
Speaker 2:  Insteon, is that right? Yes,
Speaker 6:  Yes, absolutely. Right.
Speaker 2:  That's a great name. Yes it was. How did they get Smart Home as their
Speaker 2:  name?
Speaker 6:  Well, they were one of the early internet retailers and so URLs
Speaker 6:  and names, you know, weren't as popular as they are now. So
Speaker 6:  they got Smart home before anybody else did actually. So it was
Speaker 6:  by luck and being early to the marketing place I guess is the, the answer
Speaker 6:  to that.
Speaker 2:  Wow, great. Okay, so you were working for, you got to know Smart Home?
Speaker 6:  Yes, I was consulting with them, helping them start to look at how
Speaker 6:  they would roll out the Insteon technology and also the line of
Speaker 6:  products that the lighting control products that they were gonna make. And
Speaker 6:  then after six months they asked me to join the company And I did as the
Speaker 6:  general manager of the technologies and products part of the company.
Speaker 6:  So that's how I got involved with them.
Speaker 2:  So before we go into all of the, the trials and tribulations and how
Speaker 2:  Insteon is hopefully on The Verge of a new dawn, tell me
Speaker 2:  just a little bit about Insteon for people who are listening who have
Speaker 2:  never heard of this smart home lighting system
Speaker 2:  and what Insteon does.
Speaker 6:  So when Smart Home was starting out, they were selling a product
Speaker 6:  from a company called X 10.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so that's the original smart home protocol, right? Yes. And that was
Speaker 2:  like over the wires?
Speaker 6:  Right. Okay. And that was the technology owned by somebody else. Okay. And
Speaker 6:  they were just selling the products. 'cause at that point they were just
Speaker 6:  an internet retailer,
Speaker 2:  One of the first ever internet retailers, is that right? Like one of the
Speaker 2:  first dotcoms?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they were hard coding the website. There was no Shopify or any of
Speaker 6:  those things.
Speaker 2:  So
Speaker 6:  They're actually hard coding, you know, the website to get it up and running.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, very, very early on, I think it was one of the first ones that
Speaker 6:  that got involved in taking advantage of the internet and the business was
Speaker 6:  perfect for that because they were selling home automation and lots of little
Speaker 6:  pieces and so really hard in a brick and mortar kind of thing
Speaker 6:  to be able to put enough product out and all the different brick and mortars
Speaker 6:  to be able to satisfy. So this internet really fit this business
Speaker 6:  segment extremely well and like that's why they succeeded and did so
Speaker 6:  well as well.
Speaker 2:  But then from this internet company, they
Speaker 2:  form a smart home protocol and a smart home line.
Speaker 2:  How did that jump happen? Some,
Speaker 6:  Some of it was just to be lucky. So they became the largest reseller of this
Speaker 6:  X 10 technology and the founder was lucky to find
Speaker 6:  a very bright engineer named of Dan Craig. We call him the father of
Speaker 6:  Insteon and he still works with me. Oh as well. So he's the one that
Speaker 6:  developed the protocol. So he understood how the X 10 technology
Speaker 6:  worked and understood the issues with the X 10. There were a number of issues
Speaker 6:  with the technology itself and he then really developed the Insteon
Speaker 6:  protocol. And that's, and And I kind of related to it, you can k
Speaker 6:  Insteon does at its heart run on the power line just like
Speaker 6:  X 10 did
Speaker 2:  The power line of your home. So like all the wiring in your home. Okay. Right.
Speaker 6:  In essence, how that works, it's, it was kind of curious to me, but it, you
Speaker 6:  have the power in your house is 110 volts and it goes from
Speaker 6:  positive to negative and it does that 120 times a second. So at
Speaker 6:  those split seconds there's no electricity in your house. It just bare copper
Speaker 6:  wire. So you at that precise second use that to transmit and that's
Speaker 6:  why you get the, the most reliable signal. 'cause it's hardwired, all the
Speaker 6:  devices are hardwired
Speaker 2:  And this was X 10, that's how X 10 worked.
Speaker 6:  That's XX 10 worked as well.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And then Insteon uses the same technology,
Speaker 6:  Well the same concept but different technology and how the signal
Speaker 6:  is propagated and put on the line. I kind of related to, in the old days
Speaker 6:  you had those dial up modems, right. You know
Speaker 6:  that Right. And very slow. And then DSL came along, it
Speaker 6:  uses the same copper wires but DSL and its speed and its
Speaker 6:  reliability had nothing to do compared to the old motives. And
Speaker 6:  that's kinda the same thing here. The Insteon technology took the reliability
Speaker 6:  of this up to professional class from where it was with X 10, which is really
Speaker 6:  a hobbyist kind of technology. Right. And so that's how they
Speaker 6:  developed that. And then that's about when I joined is we're just
Speaker 6:  getting ready to start close to launching that technology and the products.
Speaker 2:  And so the technology is this hardwired
Speaker 2:  system with a radio, radio, wireless, radio
Speaker 2:  frequency. So this was like one of the first sort of wireless smart lighting
Speaker 2:  radio frequencies developed around the same time as like
Speaker 2:  Z-Wave and ZigBee. Is that right?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely correct.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And how does it differ from those types of technologies
Speaker 2:  though?
Speaker 6:  Well, it's lots of different ways. So first of all, it's a mesh network.
Speaker 6:  So we're not a routed network. So those networks are dependent upon
Speaker 6:  you send a signal out or command out the next device and it's trying to get
Speaker 6:  to a device. Next device has to repeat that. And so you actually, if you
Speaker 6:  try and turn all the lights on in a house at once, you're gonna get what
Speaker 6:  we call popcorning because the message is routed, it has to go through. And
Speaker 6:  if one of those switches gets broken, then you're gonna
Speaker 6:  have a networking problem. So with the mesh network, every
Speaker 6:  device, when you broadcast, every device hears that the signal at the
Speaker 6:  same time and then we'll actually repeat it in
Speaker 6:  simultaneously throughout the house. That's why you get very robust. But
Speaker 6:  they're all single bands so you're dependent upon the radio frequency and
Speaker 6:  a and a lot of homes. That's a challenge if you've got brick or steel,
Speaker 6:  you're trying to get from one end of the home to another. And so that's really
Speaker 6:  the uniqueness of it. 'cause we use the copper is our main and we use
Speaker 6:  the the radio as a kind of a backup or, and and
Speaker 6:  that's where we're able to simulcast. So every signal goes out over both
Speaker 6:  mediums.
Speaker 2:  So both over the wires and wireless.
Speaker 6:  And wireless all synchronized. So
Speaker 2:  It's kind of like, I guess for people who aren't familiar with the
Speaker 2:  X 10, it's sort of like having a hardwired and a mesh
Speaker 2:  wifi internet network in your home. Right? Like the reliability of
Speaker 2:  hardwired the flexibility of wireless.
Speaker 6:  Correct.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And this is for your smart lighting. So your light switches, your
Speaker 2:  lamps, everything is working over dual band
Speaker 2:  technology. So this makes it more reliable In theory.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Extremely, extremely reliable. Because if,
Speaker 6:  if you have a little bit of a challenge, you can have some challenges with
Speaker 6:  power line with some noise or something, the radio's gonna get the signal
Speaker 6:  there and if vice versa. So you really get
Speaker 6:  this pairing of both signals coming to the device and
Speaker 6:  the device is smart enough to know it's received the same signal twice. It
Speaker 6:  doesn't act on it, two times it 'cause they're all synchronized. So it
Speaker 6:  has two opportunities to get the signal and that's what the strength and
Speaker 6:  that's really the hallmark of the technology is its reliability. Right.
Speaker 6:  And then just the, the overall simplicity of the network and how you
Speaker 6:  set up devices and it, from the get go, it's set up. If
Speaker 6:  you want to connect two devices together, it's just as simple. Go wire
Speaker 6:  in, take your existing wall switch out, put the Insteon wall
Speaker 6:  switch in, you wanna plug the lamp module And to have those two connect just
Speaker 6:  press and hold the button on on the sending device and press and hold the
Speaker 6:  button on the receiving. They're now connected now they now talk.
Speaker 2:  And you don't even need the app or even a hub or anything. It just works.
Speaker 2:  No, that, okay. So this sounds great and this sounds like the type
Speaker 2:  of smart lighting technology everyone would want in their home. So why
Speaker 2:  did it all fall apart?
Speaker 6:  Well, you know, with a, you know, you could consider smart home a startup
Speaker 6:  company if you go back to the, when it first began. And
Speaker 6:  it's a real challenge for a lot of companies. As you grow and you develop,
Speaker 6:  the leadership team often needs to change 'cause the skill sets to really
Speaker 6:  launch a new company are different than ones maybe to grow the company. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I think that's a little bit what they, they fell into, the founder
Speaker 6:  did a wonderful job developing the company and growing it. But I think
Speaker 6:  in the end that became kind of an achilles heel for them and and their
Speaker 6:  ability to be able to, to thoughtfully grow the company, they overextended
Speaker 6:  themselves.
Speaker 2:  Then in 2017, I believe it was bought by another
Speaker 2:  user?
Speaker 6:  No. Essentially taken over by the shareholders.
Speaker 2:  Oh, okay. So
Speaker 6:  Rob, Rob Lowness was a shareholder. So a couple of the shareholders took
Speaker 6:  over the company.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And this was in 2017.
Speaker 6:  Right. Okay. And that's where they kind of scaled the company back from being
Speaker 6:  a whole home automation, selling all the variety of products and really started
Speaker 6:  to scale the company to focusing on the Insteon products only. So
Speaker 6:  over a course of year or so, they kind of phased out the other products just
Speaker 6:  to focus on the Insteon.
Speaker 2:  So Rob takes over and we've got what, five
Speaker 2:  years until 2022, where one
Speaker 2:  day all of a sudden without warning
Speaker 2:  someone flipped the switch. Yes. Just to overextend
Speaker 2:  that metaphor.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, but that's exactly what he did. Exactly What
Speaker 2:  Happened. That's exactly what you did. Yeah. What, okay, so tell me what
Speaker 2:  caused the sort of the demise of the company at that
Speaker 2:  stage?
Speaker 6:  So I, I think there's a number of things. This marketplace is an interesting
Speaker 6:  one. It has some peculiarities to it and you really need to understand the
Speaker 6:  marketplace. And I think that was part of their challenge, really understanding
Speaker 6:  the marketplace and what's happening in the market. And he took the
Speaker 6:  company in a different direction and yeah, once again,
Speaker 6:  overextended the company. So they ran into, again, they, he ran 'em
Speaker 6:  out of, ran 'em outta money and that's really what took place.
Speaker 6:  And so then he just closed the doors one day, let
Speaker 6:  the employees go and then close the doors and turned off. What,
Speaker 6:  what everyone relates to on this is there's all these hubs that, like
Speaker 6:  we mentioned, you can't, you don't need one, but lots of people have on,
Speaker 6:  so you can get internet connectivity and
Speaker 2:  You don't need a hub for Insteon, but you can use a hub.
Speaker 6:  Right. Okay. And that's, if you want to use your phone to turn the
Speaker 6:  lights on and off, you want to use Alexa or Google or
Speaker 6:  you know, HomeKit or any of those kinds of things. You need some bridge to
Speaker 6:  the internet. And so that's what that's for. And also you can set up some
Speaker 6:  routines and timers and some, some things like that using it. So
Speaker 6:  famously what transpired is the users found out that something had
Speaker 6:  happened when their little hubs have a red and green light and all the hubs
Speaker 6:  turned red one day.
Speaker 2:  Oh it's kind of like a scene out of a movie sci-fi movie.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 2:  No. Just blinking red, red blink of death.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There was no heads up. Which is just in these days doesn't make a lot of
Speaker 6:  sense. You've seen companies have had a challenge, but they usually will
Speaker 6:  get out an email or something to everybody, Hey sorry, we're gonna have to
Speaker 6:  close up and give them some notice. But there was really no notice
Speaker 6:  and that's what made everyone so upset. Yeah. It just one day in April, I
Speaker 6:  think it was April 22nd when everything just turned off and
Speaker 6:  without warning, without understanding what you know. So that's why everyone
Speaker 6:  got very frustrated very quickly.
Speaker 2:  And now you are an user. So did your hub go red? Oh
Speaker 2:  yes it did. And what did you do?
Speaker 6:  So I called so the, like Dan Craig was still with the
Speaker 6:  company. Well he had just been let go obviously 'cause all the employees
Speaker 6:  had been let go. So I called and talked to a couple of the employees that
Speaker 6:  I know 'cause a number of 'em worked for me when I was there too. And so
Speaker 6:  I called them and said, what's going on? What's happened? And they explained
Speaker 6:  that the company went bankrupt and he just shut it off. And I was involved.
Speaker 6:  I still am with an investment group here in Orange County. And so I
Speaker 6:  was just kind of curious to learn. And so I actually reached out to see if
Speaker 6:  I could just learn what was going on with no intention at that
Speaker 6:  point of buying the company.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you hadn't sort of formed a plan like, okay, now's my
Speaker 2:  chance. I'm back in, back in the game, gonna buy the company.
Speaker 2:  So, okay, so the hubs are shut off. Everyone is thinking
Speaker 2:  it's done. And I know when you, once you decided to
Speaker 2:  relaunch the site, you said a small group of passionate users had brought
Speaker 2:  it together. So can you talk me through how this little group came together
Speaker 2:  and what, what you did and how you decided that you were gonna pull together
Speaker 2:  and resurrect the Insteon Smart home?
Speaker 6:  So when I, I talked to the trustee of first of all the trustee that was
Speaker 6:  now, so what happens in an A, BC bankruptcy, it's kind of interesting. A
Speaker 6:  new company is formed in L in California. It's an LLC called an
Speaker 6:  A-B-C-L-L-C. And basically all the assets of the company are transferred
Speaker 6:  over to that, that new LLC. Right. And the trustees then
Speaker 6:  put in charge of selling the assets. Okay. Not trying to get the company
Speaker 6:  back would've just selling the assets.
Speaker 2:  Right. I think you mentioned this when we chatted before that Right. This
Speaker 2:  was something very unique to Silicon Valley. Right, right. 'cause so many
Speaker 2:  startups would just disappear. Yes. And like
Speaker 2:  no one would know what to do with the furniture or Right, that's
Speaker 2:  exactly right. There was no one around, unlike most brick and mortar companies
Speaker 2:  where this, you can go knock on a door and say, Hey, you know, pay my
Speaker 2:  bill. They just evaporate. So this isn't very unique
Speaker 2:  bankruptcy. So someone just comes in and takes over
Speaker 2:  and then tries to sell whatever they can find.
Speaker 2:  Like literally lift up the cushions and see what's underneath. Okay.
Speaker 2:  And so you, this is where you came in.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right. That's when I started talking to them and
Speaker 6:  I said, well what are you looking to sell the company for? And they gave
Speaker 6:  me a number And I said, well, we're not, no, my group's not interested, we're
Speaker 6:  not interested. And kind of, that was the end of it. And then they
Speaker 6:  kept calling me and saying, make an offer, make an
Speaker 6:  offer. I go, I, I can't make an offer. I'm not gonna, that's not gonna.
Speaker 6:  And they go, no, make an offer. I go, no, I'm not gonna insult you. And they
Speaker 6:  just kept bugging me. And I think what they knew is that I knew the people
Speaker 6:  at the company And I had the ability, not that I'm a bright guy, I
Speaker 6:  knew the people that could help bring the company back. Yeah. Quickly. It
Speaker 6:  would be very difficult for anybody else to resurrect a company
Speaker 6:  as quickly as we were able to do it. I put this group together, it was the
Speaker 6:  CTO gentleman was head of manufacturing force
Speaker 6:  in our products are manufactured overseas. The marketing person
Speaker 6:  is, was those triad that I brought together. That was the band of US four.
Speaker 6:  And now since added some additional people that knew all the things to do
Speaker 6:  to get the company back up and running. Yeah. And so that's why we're able
Speaker 6:  to do it very quickly. So they were smarter to understand I could actually
Speaker 6:  bring some value to it. So I, I made 'em an, if they pushed
Speaker 6:  me enough, I may have an offer that I thought they would absolutely refuse.
Speaker 2:  They didn't. Okay. So this is how you do it, you low ball.
Speaker 6:  I was really taken aback when they said yes, we'll accept that.
Speaker 6:  And now I understand why. 'cause they weren't gonna get anything for the
Speaker 6:  company. 'cause there weren't a lot of physical assets, there weren't a lot
Speaker 6:  of product or whatever. There just wasn't a lot of value to, you know, the
Speaker 6:  patents and everything at value. But someone else would have to come and
Speaker 6:  figure out how to do that. How do you, you know, like I said, I had the father
Speaker 6:  of Insteon alongside of me. So he knows the technology. We had all the pieces
Speaker 6:  together and, and they're all very passionate. The one thing is all
Speaker 6:  the employees there and, and myself included at the time, we were very
Speaker 6:  passionate about what we were doing and very disappointed to see
Speaker 6:  where the company had head. So, and still everyone's very passionate about
Speaker 6:  we're doing this 'cause you know, yes, it's a job and things, but really
Speaker 6:  doing it. 'cause we feel passion and a lot for our customer base. We have
Speaker 6:  a very unique customer base.
Speaker 2:  Well, and what about you Ken? I mean, did you not have a job?
Speaker 2:  Oh, you
Speaker 6:  Like I was retired.
Speaker 2:  Oh, you were retired. Okay. So that is when you wanna, you wanna
Speaker 2:  go and buy a smart company. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So you're on a beach in Hawaii.
Speaker 6:  Oh yes.
Speaker 6:  Famously it still amazes me that you can be on the beach on a cell phone
Speaker 6:  and buying a company. It's, it's just kind of, I,
Speaker 6:  I'm a tech guy, but it still boggles my mind that you can have all that
Speaker 6:  transact while you're sitting on a, a beach there. And it, it's kind of
Speaker 6:  a fun story. It was a vacation we'd previously planned with my wife
Speaker 6:  and the transaction is taking longer, is they typically do
Speaker 6:  with lawyers and documents and things. And, And I said, you know,
Speaker 6:  everyone, I'm losing customers every day 'cause their hubs are turned off.
Speaker 6:  And I said, I I know I gotta turn these back on. So I talked
Speaker 6:  to the team and they said, yeah, we know exactly what to do. We can have
Speaker 6:  'em turned on tomorrow. There's one company we have to talk to
Speaker 6:  and have them flip the switch. And I had to pay 'em a little bit of money.
Speaker 6:  And I said, you know, even though I don't own the company now, I just know
Speaker 6:  I'm losing people if this is gonna take another week or so, I just can't,
Speaker 6:  I can't stand that. Yeah. So I actually decided to just bite the bullet
Speaker 6:  and turn the hubs on. And that was on a Tuesday. The
Speaker 6:  lights all turned green and the social media started lighting up.
Speaker 6:  Oh my gosh. Is yours on? Mine's on. Oh this is great. Who's doing this? Who's
Speaker 6:  behind? Anyone know who this is? Oh, this is awesome. This is great.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that was all, that was Tuesday, Wednesday. Who
Speaker 6:  is the evil person that's turned these on?
Speaker 2:  I remember our headline was like, somebody has turned
Speaker 2:  the lights back on, but who that, you know, someone's
Speaker 2:  running your smart home. But yeah. Okay. So tell us what happened.
Speaker 6:  So there, yeah, so all the, the, the conspiracy theories came up of
Speaker 6:  blaming all sorts of people trying to get into the homes. And I was under
Speaker 6:  non-disclosure at that point so I couldn't come and say anything.
Speaker 2:  Oh. So you're just sitting there going, ah,
Speaker 2:  everyone's freaking out And I can't say anything.
Speaker 6:  So luckily on Thursday we're finally able to sign the agreement
Speaker 6:  and then we could put out the email saying who we were and why we'd done
Speaker 6:  it. And we're happy to have it back and look forward to growing
Speaker 6:  the company. I gotta tell you one side note just about, and it goes back
Speaker 6:  to the, this fantastic customer base I have. Yeah. So on a on
Speaker 6:  Friday I get a call from one of our, my now customers
Speaker 6:  didn't know who it was or anything, how he got my cell phone, I don't know.
Speaker 6:  And he goes, Hey, what's the address for the company? And I'm like,
Speaker 6:  I don't, I I don't have a, so I gave him my home address, which home address,
Speaker 6:  which made my wife real happy. She goes, you know how many people are upset
Speaker 6:  with the previous owner though? I don't want our address. I go, I didn't
Speaker 6:  know what to do. Oh. So I gave it to him. So we get
Speaker 6:  home couple days later, I think it was Monday or Tuesday, and here's a letter
Speaker 6:  from this gentleman and his wife, handwritten letter. Thank you so much
Speaker 6:  for bringing this back. I really appreciate it And I hope this will
Speaker 6:  help. Maybe you can celebrate or something. It was a check for $2,000.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow. And
Speaker 6:  I said, is there something, I wrote 'em back, is there some I have a little
Speaker 6:  bit of product and yeah. Can I give you something or whatever. Nope. Don't
Speaker 6:  want anything. Just thank you so much. And that's the specialness of the
Speaker 6:  user base and that's what keeps us all going because we, we have such great
Speaker 6:  installed base, we call it our family or a community and really believe in
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So how long was it between lights turning off
Speaker 2:  to Lights turning back on
Speaker 6:  April 22nd to June 8th. Okay. So it was quite a long time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And now they, they were able to use their devices, right? It
Speaker 2:  wasn't like, yes we are in darkness, it's just they'd lost some function
Speaker 2:  and Correct. Potentially felt like they were no longer gonna be able to
Speaker 2:  buy new product or have see any advancements or
Speaker 2:  improvements come to the product. Okay. So you've bought a
Speaker 2:  smart home company. This took, it sounds like about six
Speaker 2:  weeks to sort of,
Speaker 6:  You're right,
Speaker 2:  Turn the lights back on. So what's the next step? What did you have to do?
Speaker 2:  Because obviously there's got to have been a lot of concern
Speaker 2:  from that in-store base saying what's happening and
Speaker 2:  you know, how do you win back Customer trust, how do you rebuild a
Speaker 2:  brand after this type of kind of, you know,
Speaker 2:  how do you, how do you raise the Phoenix from the flames here?
Speaker 6:  Well the first part is, is the easiest one. Just be honest and truthful and
Speaker 6:  upfront and you know, I, we scheduled Zoom meetings,
Speaker 6:  which all our customer base was invited to attend and we'd
Speaker 6:  get several hundred each one of the times I do that. And just be
Speaker 6:  candid, take questions, live questions for them and just be
Speaker 6:  honest in what we're doing and tell 'em what our challenges are and how we're
Speaker 6:  gonna grow the company. So I mean the first thing for to do was to get our
Speaker 6:  products remanufactured. So getting the manufacturing lines
Speaker 6:  back up again, contacting our, the previous or the, the contract
Speaker 6:  manufacturers were making them and start to give 'em orders and get the products,
Speaker 6:  you know, underbuilt. But that, that took, you know, three or four months,
Speaker 6:  just once you get the orders, takes three or four months with shipping and
Speaker 6:  everything to get that up. So that was a key part of ensured everybody. We
Speaker 6:  we're, we've got the products, we've got the important ones already on order.
Speaker 6:  And then we also find as we built out the whole family of products. 'cause
Speaker 6:  now we, we have about a hundred SKUs and as we've been adding
Speaker 6:  them in, that's one of the things where I engage the community. Say, okay,
Speaker 6:  I've got these products, we've got this going, what's the next one you want
Speaker 6:  me to, to go spend time? 'cause I wanna be thoughtful in growing the company.
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna financially overextend it again, which has been done before.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I've been very open with everybody. That's what we're doing and
Speaker 6:  that's why we're easing all the products. And now, you know, three years
Speaker 6:  later just about all the products are are back in manufacturing and we,
Speaker 6:  we have 'em back in stock. The other part then was related to the,
Speaker 6:  the hubs and really a belief is we sat down and
Speaker 6:  talked about it and this is, I think we're gonna see this across the marketplace,
Speaker 6:  but I really felt it was important that the app and the hub
Speaker 6:  be a self-sustaining business. And I, I realize that a lot of the
Speaker 6:  competition, a lot of people out there today, they
Speaker 6:  subsidize the app through hardware sales. And
Speaker 6:  I, I just don't think that's a sustainable business. As long as you keep
Speaker 6:  con growing your hardware and stuff, you can get away with that for a while.
Speaker 6:  And I think we're gonna find a lot of the manufacturers now And I think even
Speaker 6:  Amazon's talking about it with Alexa and stuff of starting to have
Speaker 6:  levels of price for it. So make it very affordable. But it
Speaker 6:  also then enables us to independently invest in the app. 'cause
Speaker 6:  they had not been investing in the app. So yeah, the app was free,
Speaker 6:  it was being subset of hardware, but they weren't spending any money to develop
Speaker 6:  the app. So the app would been stagnant for a couple years. And, and
Speaker 6:  so we've been taking that, that revenue and have been investing in improving
Speaker 6:  the app, adding new features to the app and building that that
Speaker 6:  back out. And for the most part people have been accepting of that and understanding
Speaker 6:  why we're doing that. And the assurance to them is it's not gonna just shut
Speaker 6:  down again one day. Right. The lights aren't gonna turn red.
Speaker 2:  So when you say of that, so you, you instituted a subscription, is that,
Speaker 2:  is that right?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Subscription. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And for what, what do you need the subscription for? Like can you use
Speaker 2:  the devices without the subscription or?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. As I mentioned, you don't need a hub, you don't need any kind
Speaker 6:  of computer module like, and that is unique to Insteon. I think almost
Speaker 6:  every other needs some kind of controller to be able to even set
Speaker 6:  up devices. We can go into some of the particulars, but you can do a lot
Speaker 6:  of advanced features without any kind of hub.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But now if you want the hub and you want the app for that kind
Speaker 2:  of control with your phone control with Voice. Voice. Right. Presumably
Speaker 2:  like with Amazon Alexa or Google Assistant, you
Speaker 2:  need the app and the hub. Yes. And how much does that cost Now
Speaker 6:  The app is $39 a year and the hub is
Speaker 6:  $99 with one year of free subscription. So I include one
Speaker 6:  year with the subscription with the purchase of a new hub. Okay. And
Speaker 6:  then's $39 a year. There's a, if you buy two years, you get it for a little
Speaker 6:  bit less.
Speaker 2:  And what does that get you?
Speaker 6:  So it gets you a, a number of things. One of the things is we back up your
Speaker 6:  configuration. So if you ever have a problem, you can get
Speaker 6:  a new hub and we can repopulate the hub. So you have a backup of your
Speaker 6:  configuration, you can see your configuration, you can download it,
Speaker 6:  it allows you also, you can do setup instead of press press,
Speaker 6:  you can do the setup from the app. You just say connect these two devices
Speaker 6:  together. You can do that. You can set up timed events and
Speaker 6:  then as we mentioned you, you get voice, you get, you know, phone connections
Speaker 6:  so you can control, you also can get alerts now. So you can get an alert
Speaker 6:  that the water you, the water sensor's gone off and you can get an alert
Speaker 6:  sent to your phone. So, or the door's been open, right. So you can all, you
Speaker 6:  get the alerts. So all those kind of features coming and we're looking at
Speaker 6:  additional features in the future coming. So we're
Speaker 6:  continuing to add things to the app as well
Speaker 2:  Now. But these were features that previously they use as had
Speaker 2:  without having to pay. So how did that go down with the user base?
Speaker 2:  Because that's generally not well received.
Speaker 6:  Well a again I think that we have a special install base and
Speaker 6:  when I explained to them And I was very honest with them that this needs
Speaker 6:  to be a self-sustaining business. You, you just can't subsidize it long
Speaker 6:  term. And particularly we had no hardware to even sell if we wanted to do
Speaker 2:  That at that point. Right. At that point. Right. 'cause you were still ramping
Speaker 2:  up the supply chain. Right? Right.
Speaker 6:  Exact Exactly right. So I think they, they appreciated the honesty
Speaker 6:  Fort Wright and they also now appreciated the investment. 'cause now they're
Speaker 6:  seeing that the app is actually getting better. So they're not just
Speaker 6:  putting, they're seeing the app improve. Yeah. I don't have to raise the
Speaker 6:  hardware prices just to subsidize that so I can keep the hardware prices,
Speaker 6:  which is the vast majority of your cost is gonna be through hardware. Right.
Speaker 6:  Versus you know, the app, you know, it's a one one time a year fee. It's,
Speaker 6:  you know, not that great. I mean $39 isn't gonna break anybody so to speak.
Speaker 6:  But, but you do get the pushback, oh wait, I can get this from free before.
Speaker 6:  And I said Yeah but understand that's also partially why the
Speaker 6:  company had to shut down. Right. Because they didn't have the revenue coming
Speaker 6:  in to support it. And I don't want that to happen again. I don't want there
Speaker 6:  to be an issue. I wanna be able to run the, you know, continue the hub businesses
Speaker 6:  a self-sustaining business
Speaker 2:  Then. That's interesting. We're seeing this happen more and more with hardware
Speaker 2:  smart home companies that they're adding subscriptions. Do you really feel
Speaker 2:  like that is the only sort of long-term sustainable
Speaker 2:  business model for the smart home as like recurring subscriptions? And if
Speaker 2:  so, why is that? Why can it not just depend on hardware?
Speaker 2:  Well
Speaker 6:  It, it's, it's an interesting thing. So the lighting control, we have a little
Speaker 6:  bit of unique position, right. Because as I mentioned, you're gonna continue
Speaker 6:  to add products to the home and grow the home. So you get continue for that
Speaker 6:  user, it's gonna continue to get hardware sales and so you can
Speaker 6:  justify it, potentially justify subsidizing the app. But if you,
Speaker 6:  you go and look at the apps, the most other home automation
Speaker 6:  devices in the home are single unit. Maybe you have two
Speaker 6:  thermostats, probably not. You probably have one thermostat. I just
Speaker 6:  put in a water sensor, a leak sensor at the, at
Speaker 6:  the main, you know, I'm gonna buy one of those for the house. There's only
Speaker 6:  one pipe I can connect that to. So if you look at that, they're gonna get
Speaker 6:  a one time hardware sale from me and then supposedly now they're gonna
Speaker 6:  gimme this free app for the rest of my life. And it's, you
Speaker 6:  can see it's not sustainable. Yeah. It, it becomes a little bit of a pyramid
Speaker 6:  scheme of sorts. You gotta keep getting the, the next user that's gonna put
Speaker 6:  in that water sensor to pay for my free service that
Speaker 6:  I'm getting and
Speaker 2:  Oh, the smart home is a pyramid scheme. Yeah. I like it.
Speaker 2:  But that,
Speaker 6:  And I think it also, this helps too. It puts, it's incumbent
Speaker 6:  upon the manufacturers and for us we gotta add real value with the
Speaker 6:  hub too. And in the app. Yeah. We gotta continue to add value to it and
Speaker 6:  if it doesn't deliver value, then okay, I understand then you shouldn't be
Speaker 6:  using it. And there are other solutions. There are other companies that
Speaker 6:  provide apps to control our, so you don't have to use us either. And some
Speaker 6:  of them are free.
Speaker 2:  Did you find that there was much of a drop off from the user base once you
Speaker 2:  added the subscription model? Or, or were most people kind
Speaker 2:  of happy to, to pitch in so to speak, seen as you had bought the
Speaker 2:  company for them? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  A large, a large portion of them continued with us the,
Speaker 6:  the renewal rates. 'cause we've now, this is our third year
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Of renewals. The renewal rate's very high. So I'm really pleased with
Speaker 6:  that. So the most common thing, if the renewal doesn't happen, it's,
Speaker 6:  I moved houses, I've told the new homeowner how to go get it and I'll be
Speaker 6:  buying this with my new house that I've bought. That's our, our biggest 'cause
Speaker 6:  we do, if you don't renew, we ask you why. And that's our biggest one is
Speaker 6:  I moved homes.
Speaker 2:  So because you run a smart home company and you manufacture overseas, I
Speaker 2:  do have to ask how has the last six months or so
Speaker 2:  been in terms of getting products?
Speaker 6:  It's all I can do to keep smiling. It's been, it's been horrific.
Speaker 6:  Oh it, it is just, I feel bad as I talk
Speaker 6:  to other, particularly small businesses like mine. I mean we're not that
Speaker 6:  small but we're still small compared to some of the, the big companies out
Speaker 6:  there. It, it's tough 'cause you can't plan, I don't, I don't know from
Speaker 6:  one day to the other what's gonna happen. So it sound a little bit of a,
Speaker 6:  a kink in, in my plans for this year. 'cause I, I want it to be more
Speaker 6:  aggressively marketing and things And I, you know, right now I'm just focused
Speaker 6:  on getting product back in and solving some of those kind of problems. But
Speaker 6:  we do have plans for a big relaunch of the brand
Speaker 6:  and company still this year.
Speaker 2:  I know Insteon was an original launch partner with Apple HomeKit, but as
Speaker 2:  I understand it doesn't work with Apple anymore.
Speaker 2:  Correct. So obviously right now in the Smart Home Matter
Speaker 2:  and Thread, which is another protocol that can be used for
Speaker 2:  lighting is kind of the the hot new thing. Is
Speaker 2:  it some is matter something that Inste is, is looking at because that would
Speaker 2:  help with interoperability?
Speaker 6:  No, absolutely. And, and matter's an interesting,
Speaker 6:  you know, capability and we'll be adding matter capability.
Speaker 6:  It'll be an interfacing into matter. One of the challenges is
Speaker 6:  for matter products. 'cause they go across the, the hope is to go
Speaker 6:  across multiple manufacturers, But that means you have to bring the feature
Speaker 6:  set down to lowest common denominators. So I think what we're gonna see,
Speaker 6:  for the most part, you're gonna see the, you know, the, the lutron's,
Speaker 6:  the in stones, whatever, they're gonna continue to exist 'cause there's just
Speaker 6:  too, too many things you can do that you're not gonna be able to do with
Speaker 6:  matter. But you'll have an interface into matter so that
Speaker 6:  you can then interconnect. And where the matter becomes is those people that
Speaker 6:  are gonna develop the apps to really be able to control the home. So that,
Speaker 6:  that's the other part of matters. Someone's gotta develop the app and if
Speaker 6:  you're not selling the hardware, then back to my thing, the matter apps
Speaker 6:  are gonna have to be subscription based 'cause otherwise they don't have
Speaker 6:  any revenue. But, and, and Apple and HomeKit. And I think that
Speaker 6:  becomes important. So I plan, we'll we'll get back to
Speaker 6:  connection with HomeKit. Is there Apple's now trying to get back into this
Speaker 6:  marketplace and we'll be there to support that. So we have plans
Speaker 6:  that's on the roadmap and under, In fact under work right now to be able
Speaker 6:  to bring that, you know, that capability back in.
Speaker 2:  So you were retired three years ago when you
Speaker 2:  bought a smart home company. So what do you see as the future for the
Speaker 2:  smart home company and your role in it? Are you in know, I'm sure you'd
Speaker 2:  like to get back to the beach in Hawaii at some point.
Speaker 6:  My wife certainly would.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Just so I, I'd like to see, you know, I'd like to see the, you know,
Speaker 6:  next couple years it, the company double or triple in, in in size,
Speaker 6:  which I think is very doable and makes it a nice sized business. You know,
Speaker 6:  I've got a good team of people that they're taking more and more of a role
Speaker 6:  in running the company, which is great. And I see that evolving and then
Speaker 6:  someone taking, you know, my day-to-day kind of responsibilities and,
Speaker 6:  and I'll kind of just, you know, go to maybe an advisory, you know, kinda
Speaker 6:  level with the, with the company and, and help it continue to grow
Speaker 6:  from that standpoint.
Speaker 2:  Do you think it's possible that it would be a company that
Speaker 2:  might get purchased? Like would you look to sell it or do you feel like it
Speaker 2:  needs to stay in its own?
Speaker 6:  No, I I I think that would be certainly open to do it to the right people
Speaker 6:  that really, yeah, my commitment is to the customers And I, yeah. If I felt
Speaker 6:  someone had a passion and, and, and like I said, the team, yes
Speaker 6:  they do it for a salary, but that's not why they're doing it. They're doing
Speaker 6:  it 'cause they really care about the customers. I know it sounds corny and
Speaker 6:  it, you know, it's hard to believe, but it really is true. Everyone really
Speaker 6:  wants to do and really cares about the customer. So if I could find some
Speaker 6:  of that same passion and they're willing to continue to thoughtfully
Speaker 6:  grow the company, then I'd be happy to step back some and let a younger person,
Speaker 6:  so to speak, you know, take on the role I have. But
Speaker 6:  that's the, the critical part to it. So next couple years, you know, hopefully
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna be able to do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. Well, And I guess, you know, the reason I ask that question is
Speaker 2:  because Insteon users have obviously been through a lot.
Speaker 2:  So what is their kind of reassurance here that this isn't gonna happen
Speaker 2:  again? Why should they stay committed to the company? Why should new
Speaker 2:  people invest in product from Insteon? What's kind of
Speaker 2:  assurances, can Insteon offer that this isn't gonna happen again? Is there
Speaker 2:  some kind of open source option for the technology so that they would have
Speaker 2:  options if this happened again? Or are you just a hundred percent sure this
Speaker 2:  is not gonna happen again?
Speaker 6:  I'm a hundred percent sure
Speaker 6:  I, I'm, I'm really committed to, like they said, yes. I mean, I think what
Speaker 6:  the previous company did, they could have as an example. They, they
Speaker 6:  could have started a subscription and kept all the hubs working. If that
Speaker 6:  was, it was a cash flow issue, why you didn't do that, I don't understand
Speaker 6:  that could have kept things going. You certainly could license the technology
Speaker 6:  of the products out to somebody else from that standpoint
Speaker 6:  and, and barring some other unforeseen circumstance. I mean, you know,
Speaker 6:  tariffs going to 400% and no one wants to pay for the product. I
Speaker 6:  I, I see a bright future for the company. And, and again, it's
Speaker 6:  transparency. I mean, and that's my commitment. And I, In
Speaker 6:  fact, I have it over here in the desk here, our values and, and the first
Speaker 6:  value here is transparency to the customer base. Yeah. And telling 'em what's
Speaker 6:  going on and not hiding from them. Let 'em, let 'em know and assuring them
Speaker 6:  we're profitable, we're making a profit. Haven't had to put money into
Speaker 6:  the company or not extended in any financial
Speaker 6:  shape. And so that's the commitment. But I, I think that's for all of it.
Speaker 6:  And I'm trying to be accessible too. I mean, I, I
Speaker 6:  take phone calls, I call customers back, which I think is important because
Speaker 6:  that's how you get to hear what's really going on. It's always,
Speaker 6:  it's always amazing to me when I call a customer And I just say, this is
Speaker 6:  Ken from nc, I saw your email and whatever. I just wanted to learn a little
Speaker 6:  bit more about what it, it's, it's funny to see their reaction when they
Speaker 6:  go, wait, wait a minute. You're the ken that sends out the Ken emails.
Speaker 6:  You're the, that's you. I go, yeah. Oh my gosh, I'm sorry to take your time.
Speaker 6:  I go, no, no, that's, this is, I learned this at Hewlett Packard. You gotta
Speaker 6:  talk to your customers. The CEO of HP would do the same thing. And he, that's
Speaker 6:  what he taught me. You gotta talk to the customers, you, you'll get hidden
Speaker 6:  from the truth of what's going on. So I said, you guys are doing me a service
Speaker 6:  by telling me what's on your mind and what's concerning you.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. Well it's been a journey for you, Ken,
Speaker 2:  and I'm really glad that you could come on and, and talk us through it. It,
Speaker 2:  it really does kind of shed a light on the whole industry in a way and help,
Speaker 2:  I think hopefully help people understand what's happening in this industry
Speaker 2:  and how hopefully things are looking up. Because
Speaker 2:  smart lighting really does make a big difference. I know in my family, when
Speaker 2:  we go to a hotel or something, my husband's like a Alexa, turn the lights
Speaker 2:  off. I'm like, it's not gonna work here hun. It's something, it is
Speaker 2:  a luxury, but it is one of those luxuries that becomes a necessity and, and
Speaker 2:  really does add a lot of value. So I'm glad to see that you were able
Speaker 2:  to, to bring Insteon back and what's, what's next for the company. I
Speaker 2:  understand you've recently relaunched the website for Insteon
Speaker 2:  rebranded. So just tell us a little bit about what's changed and what the
Speaker 2:  future is here for the technology and the product.
Speaker 6:  Well, I think with the, the rebranding of the company, you'll see a new logo
Speaker 6:  from us, which really reflects the values of the company and how we're moving
Speaker 6:  forward. So I encourage everyone to go check it out. The website is a
Speaker 6:  complete
Speaker 2:  a supersized Vergecast Hotline where I will be joined by
Speaker 2:  a special guest and we'll be answering
Speaker 2:  We are back And I have a very special guest with me for
Speaker 2:  a very special, super sized extended Vergecast Hotline
Speaker 2:  where we answer all your burning questions about smart lighting.
Speaker 2:  Richard Gunther is going to join me to help answer a whole bunch of questions
Speaker 2:  on this topic, which is a topic I get asked about all the time
Speaker 2:  and it's kind of a hard one to write about unless I was gonna write like
Speaker 2:  a 5,000 word essay, right? Because everyone's home setups
Speaker 2:  are so unique. So I thought one of the best ways to help
Speaker 2:  all of you out was to get the guy I go to when I have questions
Speaker 2:  about smart lighting on to help me answer all of your
Speaker 2:  questions. So a quick bit of background on Richard. He's a
Speaker 2:  blogger and podcaster and the host of three shows, The Smart Home
Speaker 2:  Show, home on and Entertainment 2.0
Speaker 2:  and he's obsessed with smart lighting. Fair enough. Plus his day job
Speaker 2:  is as a product experience consultant. So
Speaker 2:  it's like literally his job to make things easier to use. So
Speaker 2:  welcome Richard, and thank you for joining me.
Speaker 10:  I'm very glad to be here. I always love talking about lighting
Speaker 10:  perhaps a little bit too much.
Speaker 2:  Great. Okay, so I'm gonna, we have a like quite a lot of questions
Speaker 2:  here. I'm not sure how many we'll get through, but we're gonna kick it off
Speaker 2:  with one that seems deceptively easy, which is
Speaker 2:  quite a common theme here. It's like, oh but surely that's simple.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, okay, so the first one is from Cole Kennedy and
Speaker 2:  his question is, I've always wanted to have my lights
Speaker 2:  gently, gradually brighten in the morning. Any idea if
Speaker 2:  this is possible via home kit or do I have to create it
Speaker 2:  in the Hue app? Basically I really want an
Speaker 2:  exploration on how others automate their lights.
Speaker 2:  Well, Cole, you've come to the right place.
Speaker 10:  It's funny, for the most part, most of the big ecosystems
Speaker 10:  don't just support this natively. So if you're thinking about
Speaker 10:  your home app on either Google or Apple, this isn't
Speaker 10:  something they just have available that you can do. You usually need the
Speaker 10:  product's own app to do this. Hue does have a
Speaker 10:  mechanism for doing this and, and a routine, or I think it was a
Speaker 10:  lab for a while where they would allow you to set
Speaker 10:  at the length of time that you wanted the light to come on the color,
Speaker 10:  stuff like that. And you know, it, it could be up to say
Speaker 10:  30 minutes time. I wake up a little bit faster
Speaker 10:  than that. I used to do this in my home 10 years ago or more
Speaker 10:  with basic Insteon products. This is something that Insteon had built
Speaker 10:  into their solution right from the beginning that you could have
Speaker 10:  it take up to eight minutes for a light to come on to full,
Speaker 10:  which is enough to, it gets you past that jolt of
Speaker 10:  light in the morning. If you have the lights automate automatically.
Speaker 10:  But I think generally you're gonna find that for the most part, you need
Speaker 10:  to rely on a manufacturer's own app to do this.
Speaker 10:  Recently you posted how the newer hub from
Speaker 10:  ikea, And I always get this wrong, I think it's,
Speaker 2:  I'm going with whatever you wanna say 'cause I'm not even gonna try,
Speaker 10:  Is going to work as basically a matter controller
Speaker 10:  and IKEA is one of the systems that has this capability.
Speaker 10:  So there's a possibility, we don't know this yet, but there's a possibility
Speaker 10:  that the IKEA hub could do this for other
Speaker 10:  lights in your home, which would be really cool.
Speaker 2:  That would 'cause that is the main frustration with this right now is that
Speaker 2:  yes, the answer to his question is you do have to use the Hue app
Speaker 2:  to do this. Apple Home doesn't support it yet, which is
Speaker 2:  frustrating and surprising. You would expect this to be something you could
Speaker 2:  do. Apple Home does have adaptive lighting, which is that
Speaker 2:  changing the light throughout the day. Right? But it's not the same thing
Speaker 2:  as gradually turning on in the morning. Right? It's just changing the tone
Speaker 2:  of the light. Exactly. It doesn't adjust the brightness, it just changed
Speaker 2:  the tone. Yep. Which is, it seems like a a small thing you would
Speaker 2:  and one day maybe Apple Home will support this, but yeah, it's frustrating
Speaker 2:  that you have to stick with one brand. And this is something I've come across
Speaker 2:  because I love using this feature for my kids to get them
Speaker 2:  sort of going in the morning, like slowly turn the lights on. And
Speaker 2:  so I just have, I've defaulted to having HU bulbs in their rooms because
Speaker 2:  they're the ones that do this best. There are other bulbs that do it, but
Speaker 2:  again, you're always gonna have to be with one ecosystem, which with
Speaker 2:  lighting as we will discuss, gets complicated. You don't really want to
Speaker 2:  be locked into one brand. It does. And yeah, this is exciting
Speaker 2:  with the whole, the new Matter controller feature coming to more
Speaker 2:  hubs and potentially being able to use the features that are more
Speaker 2:  specific to the what you want to do in the smart home. I mean, IKEA is very
Speaker 2:  much focused around lighting, so this is something they offer. So I'll be
Speaker 2:  really interested to see if that's gonna be possible because In theory
Speaker 2:  you'll be able to connect any matter compatible light bulb to the
Speaker 2:  IKEA hub and then set whatever routines and options it
Speaker 2:  offers on those bulbs. So yeah, stay tuned. This may
Speaker 2:  get easier
Speaker 10:  Hopefully.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so because Cole, you did ask how others
Speaker 2:  automate their lights, we are gonna do a quick rundown of how Richard
Speaker 2:  And I automate our lights in our homes. So Richard,
Speaker 2:  why don't you go ahead and give us a kind of rundown on what you have set
Speaker 2:  up and why. Yeah, why is always the kind of interesting part. I think it
Speaker 10:  It is, it is. So I'm primarily focused around HomeKit.
Speaker 10:  When HomeKit became more robust, I moved away
Speaker 10:  from Amazon as my ecosystem and
Speaker 10:  primarily worked with HomeKit. Now, before I used to have all different
Speaker 10:  apps controlling a bunch of different stuff and I've always been an advocate
Speaker 10:  for trying to get things on the same platform if you can.
Speaker 10:  And now home kit's pretty good for that, but there are still
Speaker 10:  a few holdouts companies like Ring and some others
Speaker 10:  still don't offer devices that work
Speaker 10:  necessarily directly with Home Kits. So I also use HomeBridge,
Speaker 10:  which is one of those things where, you know, bake your own raspberry
Speaker 10:  pie server or throw it on a NAS that you have in your
Speaker 10:  basement or something like that. If you're that much of a geek and it
Speaker 10:  lets you connect some things to Home Git that otherwise wouldn't be accessible.
Speaker 10:  So I use that and all of my scenes and all of
Speaker 10:  my automations are through HomeKit.
Speaker 2:  You, you run everything on HomeKit, which is using the home app on your iPhone
Speaker 2:  U,
Speaker 10:  Using the Apple home ecosystem primarily with the home app.
Speaker 10:  That's what I use as my day-to-day. But my secret
Speaker 10:  sauce to setting this all up is a lesser known
Speaker 10:  app called Controller for HomeKit. This is an independent
Speaker 10:  developer's app that ties into your Apple home
Speaker 10:  ecosystem and lets you see and control
Speaker 10:  far more about your Apple Home devices
Speaker 10:  than Apple's own home app does.
Speaker 2:  Ah, right. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  So Apple's about making stuff simple, so they hide a lot of stuff.
Speaker 10:  This app Controller for HomeKit helps you see
Speaker 10:  all those other facets or attributes of your
Speaker 10:  devices, which could be things like ramp rate,
Speaker 10:  for example. The Leviton switches allow you to
Speaker 10:  adjust how long, how many seconds it takes for
Speaker 10:  a light to come on when you flip that switch or when you start a scene
Speaker 10:  with it. And you could set that with, in the case of Levitin switches up
Speaker 10:  to 25 seconds. It's not an enormous amount of time,
Speaker 10:  But that flexibility is really nice and has its uses for
Speaker 10:  different seams. The lighting control in my house is
Speaker 10:  largely done through switches and for that I have a
Speaker 10:  combination of Leviton switches, keypads,
Speaker 10:  dimmers. They have a really
Speaker 10:  good motion dimmer one of the few in
Speaker 10:  the market where you can get a smart dimmer with a motion sensor built into
Speaker 10:  it and either use them together or independently. I love that
Speaker 10:  Lutron is an old stalwart in the
Speaker 10:  community and And I heavily rely on their stuff. I've also
Speaker 10:  tested and reviewed a bunch of their things. I have some
Speaker 10:  in Ave matter based switches. Inav is a third party
Speaker 10:  that creates switches for systems that are
Speaker 10:  compatible with matter or compatible with ZigBee or Z-Wave.
Speaker 10:  And I also have some Insteon switches
Speaker 10:  through my home. I've had Insteon stuff for years and years
Speaker 10:  and while it doesn't tie into everything else that I use
Speaker 10:  right now, it's really good for point solutions.
Speaker 10:  So for example, I have closets with indoor
Speaker 10:  closet door sensors that as soon as I
Speaker 10:  open the closet door, the light inside the closet goes on
Speaker 10:  and things like that are really helpful for being able to remember
Speaker 10:  not to leave a light on if you have a light in your closet or something
Speaker 10:  like that. Now, for lighting bulbs, color
Speaker 10:  lighting in particular, I think it was you, I think I can blame you Jen,
Speaker 10:  for getting me hooked on the cube play sink
Speaker 10:  system. Ah, which is the mechanism
Speaker 10:  for synchronizing the lights in a room with
Speaker 10:  either what you're seeing on your TV or on your computer
Speaker 10:  or music that's playing. It allows you to synchronize video
Speaker 10:  with ambient color throughout a room. So in my family room
Speaker 10:  I have a bunch of those hooked up to my TV And
Speaker 10:  I also have a, a bunch of outdoor accent lighting from
Speaker 10:  Hugh 'cause they are one of the few vendors that came out early
Speaker 10:  with outdoor lighting.
Speaker 2:  So how do you make everything work? Like are you doing
Speaker 2:  like motion sensors, routines, schedules,
Speaker 2:  you know that that's kind of, that's always the tricky part. It is. Of the
Speaker 2:  smart lighting, it's the motion sensors seem like the solution but they are
Speaker 2:  not always Yep.
Speaker 10:  No, that, that's exactly right. So, you know, I mentioned motion sensors,
Speaker 10:  they work in certain cases. I use motion sensors in places
Speaker 10:  like my pantry and my laundry room. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Places that I'm gonna be walking in and out of where my hands might be full
Speaker 10:  And I don't wanna have to think about whether the light is on or not.
Speaker 10:  It's just gonna happen automatically. Same with some closets.
Speaker 10:  My primary bedroom closet for example, has a motion
Speaker 10:  sensor in it. I think that works in
Speaker 10:  some cases, not in others. There's sometimes where
Speaker 10:  it's hard to tune a motion sensor or have a motion
Speaker 10:  sensor in the right place to be able to turn
Speaker 10:  lights on. So I use that mostly for utility
Speaker 10:  spaces. Sometimes I even have just dumb switches with motion
Speaker 10:  sensors built into them for like my utility room.
Speaker 10:  Or we have a storage room that has a light in it as well.
Speaker 10:  I don't need anything fancy for that. I don't, it doesn't matter if I can
Speaker 10:  monitor whether that light is on or not. So I can just use
Speaker 10:  a plain old motion light for stuff like that. Elsewhere
Speaker 10:  in the house though, I, I do need things like
Speaker 10:  routines for lighting to come on at night or
Speaker 10:  maybe off in the morning or off when we go to bed. I have a
Speaker 10:  go to bed routine where I constantly hear from Siri
Speaker 10:  telling me that she wasn't able to turn something that I had asked
Speaker 10:  off.
Speaker 2:  Always.
Speaker 10:  There's always something.
Speaker 2:  So you just say when you, you you go, Hey s right, it's
Speaker 2:  time to go to bed or
Speaker 10:  Goodnight or I'm going to bed or, it's very flexible. Okay. Then it triggers
Speaker 10:  in what you can say triggers Exactly. Yeah. And, and then that triggers
Speaker 10:  a good night scene for me and that good night
Speaker 10:  scene I'm constantly updating. 'cause every time I
Speaker 10:  add a new device I usually wanna make sure that that's also a part of
Speaker 10:  what I'm turning off at night. Right. I also
Speaker 10:  do have a, a couple of scenes and automations
Speaker 10:  where we just have lights come on, whether we're home or not, just
Speaker 10:  to make it look like we're home for security purposes.
Speaker 2:  Oh, security things. Yeah. That's great. And that, do you automate all of
Speaker 2:  this through Apple or
Speaker 10:  You All of it through Apple. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Do you also use buttons at all so that you don't have to use voice control?
Speaker 10:  Oh yeah. Oh yeah. I, I'm, I'm a big, big proponent
Speaker 10:  of physical controls. Yeah. There isn't any
Speaker 10:  light in my house that can't somehow be controlled with a button
Speaker 10:  somewhere or a switch somewhere. I'm a big fan of keypads.
Speaker 10:  We're starting to see companies come out with
Speaker 10:  keypads that can be programmed to trigger a scene. That's a, a great
Speaker 10:  use. I, I have a keypad for example in my
Speaker 10:  butler's pantry. One for coffee time, one for drinking
Speaker 10:  time, one for cleanup time and so
Speaker 10:  Nice. Those are, those are very helpful to just get all the right lights
Speaker 10:  on for the right use of the space.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Well before we jump into my setup, is there anything else you wanted
Speaker 2:  to call out that we hadn't mentioned about your setup? Well it sounds like
Speaker 2:  you've got it pretty dialed in there. You feel like it's, it's working the
Speaker 2:  way you want. Is it just tweaks for like when you add things or
Speaker 2:  do you have any major issues that you're still trying to fix?
Speaker 10:  I have occasional issues Every once in a while my
Speaker 10:  Hue devices don't want to fully behave on home kit
Speaker 10:  and that's a pretty well known problem. You occasionally
Speaker 10:  have to kind of disconnect them and reconnect them to home kit to make them
Speaker 10:  work properly. So I have some problems with those. Every once
Speaker 10:  in a while I'll just have a scene randomly stop working
Speaker 10:  And I have to troubleshoot what's going on. Oftentimes it's wifi related
Speaker 10:  and I did a recent episode of The Smart Home Show
Speaker 10:  about using smart products on wifi
Speaker 10:  and some of the ways you can avoid problems there. I should probably take
Speaker 10:  some of my own advice
Speaker 2:  And no, that was a great episode. I listened to it and we'll include it in
Speaker 2:  the show notes because it's a real kind of, it starts with like wifi 1 0 1
Speaker 2:  but then goes to like how to set up wifi for your smart home
Speaker 2:  properly. So definitely listen to that. Excellent. Okay, great.
Speaker 2:  Well I'm gonna just quickly run through mine because mine is
Speaker 2:  pretty unusual and I'm mainly because, well I have two issues
Speaker 2:  that make it different. One is I'm always testing new stuff so that
Speaker 2:  throws everything out the window half the time in terms of
Speaker 2:  automations and making things work smoothly. But the other big
Speaker 2:  issue I have is I do not have neutral wires in most of
Speaker 2:  my home. Ah. 'cause my home was built in the early
Speaker 2:  sixties. I do have two rooms that were recently
Speaker 2:  remodeled, which do have neutral wires. But this is a big issue
Speaker 2:  in the smart home, especially if you want to use smart switches because they
Speaker 2:  require a neutral wire. And there's all sorts of
Speaker 2:  technical electrical details we could go into but I'll, I'll
Speaker 2:  gloss over it for now. But basically there are very few smart
Speaker 2:  switch lighting solutions that don't require neutral wires. There are a couple
Speaker 2:  And I have tried them. One of them is from Leviton. I use that in my
Speaker 2:  daughter's bathroom, but it requires a little bridge plugged
Speaker 2:  in nearby and that works relatively well. It's just an on off
Speaker 2:  switch. And the reason I use it's 'cause she never turns her light off. So
Speaker 2:  I have it set on a schedule through the Leviton app to turn off after an
Speaker 2:  hour. Yep. Or I can also through smart home control, I can ask
Speaker 2:  to turn it off because I can see it from the living room. So when I'm watching
Speaker 2:  TV and the lights on up there, then I don't have to go all the way up the
Speaker 2:  stairs. So those kind of like conveniences, that's one of the big things.
Speaker 2:  The main thing I use smart lighting for in my house is that convenience.
Speaker 2:  Especially from for the family's perspective because my house is
Speaker 2:  quite open. So when we're sitting in the living room the, you know, hey
Speaker 2:  s trigger movie time and we always, we still say trigger because
Speaker 2:  I taught my husband years ago when we first
Speaker 2:  got smart home devices, we had a wink hub and when it connected to
Speaker 2:  Amazon's assistant you had to use the word trigger to
Speaker 2:  get it to work. And he's been trained so well that he still
Speaker 2:  uses that. You don't have to use that phrase but it's just funny that it's
Speaker 2:  still there for him. But yeah, you know one using
Speaker 2:  the words movie time to one of our smart assistants turns off all of
Speaker 2:  the lights, dims a couple areas so that it's, we're not in pitch black.
Speaker 2:  You know that those kind of solutions like your goodnight scene are what
Speaker 2:  makes smart lighting so great for me. So my main
Speaker 2:  control method like yours is Apple Home Kit. Primarily
Speaker 2:  because I love the control center on iPhone. It's just so easy
Speaker 2:  just being able to swipe down and hit a button to turn off a light
Speaker 2:  rather than having to use voice. Voice is great for those routines and
Speaker 2:  scenes but not for individual control so much. Right. We
Speaker 2:  did use Amazon's assistant primarily for a long time
Speaker 2:  because it worked with everything. But since
Speaker 2:  matter I have got to the point where almost everything in my
Speaker 2:  home currently can be controlled through Apple Home
Speaker 2:  because of matter. So that, for example, my living room
Speaker 2:  kitchen is all open plan. I have the Lutron Casser smart
Speaker 2:  switches everywhere because of the neutral wire issue. That's
Speaker 2:  the other brand that does not require a neutral wire. Right. So
Speaker 2:  even though we remodeled our kitchen recently, but I still put Lutron
Speaker 2:  in because I wanted to have the same switches. This is
Speaker 2:  another thing you don't re, you know it's nice to have the same controls
Speaker 2:  in all rooms of the home. So I have Lutron Casser smart switches 'cause they
Speaker 2:  also control decorative light fixtures 'cause I wanted
Speaker 2:  nice lights in my living room. I didn't want, oh this is actually in my kitchen.
Speaker 2:  I have like gold pendant lights. Nice. Yeah. Yeah. Well they're brass
Speaker 2:  kind of, you know, I wanted something sort of more interior designer
Speaker 2:  and not like govi, no offense to Govi
Speaker 2:  but you know those kind. I wanted something that looked nice in my kitchen.
Speaker 2:  Right. Rather than the sort of RGB lights. And that's where you
Speaker 2:  really do need to use smart switches. Even hue stuff. They have
Speaker 2:  fixtures which are nice but they're still like black.
Speaker 2:  There's very little kind of interior design happening
Speaker 2:  with smart light fixtures, which is a shame.
Speaker 10:  Very contemporary. Very Scandinavian.
Speaker 2:  Yes, exactly. And then the one sort of
Speaker 2:  exception to the rule I have in my kitchen is I have one Aqara H
Speaker 2:  two dual switch which uses ZigBee or thread, which is interesting. You
Speaker 2:  can choose between the two. Either one connects it to Apple home
Speaker 2:  and it's a dual switch because the way my kitchen was wired,
Speaker 2:  I have lights above my sink and under cabinet lightings that go
Speaker 2:  into the same circuit and have to have, and
Speaker 2:  there aren't very many smart switches out there that have that dual option.
Speaker 2:  True,
Speaker 10:  True. 'cause in the old days that would just go to those small switches
Speaker 10:  that would kind of stick through what would normally be used for an
Speaker 10:  electrical outlet. Right. And you just have one switch on top of the other.
Speaker 10:  Those Aqara switches are beautiful spelt devices
Speaker 10:  that are also incredibly powerful.
Speaker 2:  One thing I really wanted for my under cabinet lighting was color
Speaker 2:  lighting. And I wasn't able to do that because when I remodeled
Speaker 2:  my kitchen there were no good options for hardwired
Speaker 2:  under cabinet LED. Color changing lighting. There are
Speaker 2:  now some GE sink has one. And then yeah so
Speaker 2:  the living room is mainly bulbs. I have hue bulbs, well actually I just switched
Speaker 2:  them out. I have a CARA bulbs now in the living room.
Speaker 2:  But thankfully those now work through matter. And then I have two
Speaker 2:  dumb LED bulbs connected to a luteum casita switch.
Speaker 2:  I have nano leaf panels on the wall And I have a Life X smart lamp for
Speaker 2:  like ambient lighting. Again, everything there works now through Apple Home,
Speaker 2:  thanks to matter. Nice. And then the rest of the house, I
Speaker 2:  mentioned my kids' bedrooms earlier, that's hue lighting. And then
Speaker 2:  my bedroom has dumb bad word, I'm sorry,
Speaker 2:  non-smart LED eight can lights that are
Speaker 2:  BR forties. I do not know what was in my builder's mind. Wow. When
Speaker 2:  he did this. Wow. Be, I know
Speaker 10:  Those are massive.
Speaker 2:  I know they're huge. It's like a runway in my bedroom when the lights are
Speaker 2:  a full brightness is crazy. But I have
Speaker 2:  those connected right now to a gen one brilliant war switch,
Speaker 2:  which is a touchscreen wall switch. And that's where I also,
Speaker 2:  I do have a neutral wire in this room 'cause it's newer. So I use this
Speaker 2:  one to test different switches quite often. Motion detection is
Speaker 2:  quite useful for me in this one. I like to have the lights turn on as I walk
Speaker 2:  in as long as I can adjust the timing. 'cause there's nothing worse than
Speaker 2:  like a cat walking past at 2:00 AM and Yep. Turning your lights on.
Speaker 2:  So yes I do adjust when those can turn on. And, and then
Speaker 2:  on my bedside table lamps I have, I'm testing two hue
Speaker 2:  lamps right now. They have the twilight and the table lamp and they are
Speaker 2:  actually awesome. The twilight especially for those kind of sleep
Speaker 2:  wake up routines we were talking about earlier. Yes. They kind of take it
Speaker 2:  to the next level right from the bulbs. So, and then in my
Speaker 2:  bathroom I have a very complicated setup. I have four
Speaker 2:  hue bulbs in my vanity, which you know, the vanity has like four
Speaker 2:  lights controlled by a tipi link. Tapo
Speaker 2:  matter on off switch because you cannot put LED
Speaker 2:  bulbs SMART LED bulbs on a dimmer right. Switch because they'll go nuts.
Speaker 2:  So it's an on off switch. And then I also have the fan and the two regular
Speaker 2:  light fixtures in the room or controlled by Tapo. So I have four
Speaker 2:  Tapo smart switches in there and those all matter now. So again,
Speaker 2:  I can control all of that through Apple Home. And I also can
Speaker 2:  control the tone of the lights, which is very important when
Speaker 2:  you are using vanity lights because you want really bright light Yep. In
Speaker 2:  the mornings when you're doing makeup or getting ready. But when you walk
Speaker 2:  in to go to the loo at 2:00 AM you want it to be in really dim. So
Speaker 2:  that unfortunately I really wanna get that set up with a motion sensor because
Speaker 2:  that's obviously a nice feature when you walk in the room at night. But I
Speaker 2:  have not managed to get it to work properly mainly because something keeps
Speaker 2:  going wrong and it will turn off and my husband said to me if if the
Speaker 2:  the lights turn off in the bathroom on me one more time I'm gonna rip them
Speaker 2:  out the wall. So
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I get that every once in a while.
Speaker 2:  Gotta do some work there.
Speaker 2:  But yes, throughout the house I do have a few areas I
Speaker 2:  use motion sensors but as you mentioned those specific
Speaker 2:  use cases is where I find it most helpful. So I also have a hue bulb and
Speaker 2:  a hue motion sensor in my laundry room. As you mentioned. That's something
Speaker 2:  that you do and that works really well 'cause you can use Hue adaptive
Speaker 2:  lighting feature where you just press a button
Speaker 2:  in the app and it will automatically schedule the light to turn on at different
Speaker 2:  temperature based on the time of day. So if I walk into the laundry room
Speaker 2:  at 2:00 AM not something I do regularly, it will come on at a dimmer
Speaker 2:  light. Right. Whereas when I walk in at 8:00 AM it comes on nice and bright
Speaker 2:  so I can see what I'm doing. Yep.
Speaker 10:  What are you doing for outside lighting?
Speaker 2:  Yes. So that is an area I've been testing a
Speaker 2:  lot of new stuff because you mentioned Hugh was the main player in
Speaker 2:  this space for a long time and they were kind of the only player. But recently
Speaker 2:  a lot of people have moved into this space. So I actually right now have
Speaker 2:  the nano leaf outdoor string lights around my patio and the life
Speaker 2:  X string lights around my porch. And they're
Speaker 2:  great. They're so fun. Again, during holidays you can change the colors
Speaker 2:  and then, but generally we just have them on the, you know, a nice sort of
Speaker 2:  warm tone. So it's lovely to sit out at night under them.
Speaker 2:  And then I have, I actually have some ring motion sensing
Speaker 2:  activated lights along the path, but
Speaker 2:  mine are battery powered. I bought, actually got them a long time ago. They
Speaker 2:  recently, I think they have solar powered ones now. Yep. The battery power
Speaker 2:  means that half the time they're dead And I haven't gotten around to
Speaker 2:  put the 1500 D batteries back into them. I need to get them
Speaker 2:  working again. Yep.
Speaker 10:  I remember those very well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that was their first ones that came out I think. And then I
Speaker 2:  recently added, and I've been testing the ai.ai.is
Speaker 2:  the name of the brand. And they have little solar
Speaker 2:  powered path lights and those are colorful as well. They're Bluetooth
Speaker 2:  though, which has been a bit of a pain. Mm. Because this is the issue, once
Speaker 2:  you put things in the garden, connectivity can become a problem.
Speaker 2:  Yep. And then I have floodlight cameras, so like a ring floodlight
Speaker 2:  cameras, I, I test a lot of different floodlight cameras so that that's the
Speaker 2:  security lighting. And then just a week or so ago I
Speaker 2:  installed a new device from Govi, which is
Speaker 2:  something I had never come across before. It's basically like a street lamp.
Speaker 2:  It's a smart street lamp that you can stick in your garden. It's huge.
Speaker 2:  It's like 10 foot tall and it has this awesome
Speaker 2:  big kind of canopy and you can have lights that go up, but you can also have
Speaker 2:  lights that go down and it's all color changing. When I turn it on at night,
Speaker 2:  my whole backyard is like lit up. Yeah. It's, it's,
Speaker 10:  It's a lot. Cool. It's a lumm if I remember correctly.
Speaker 2:  It's a lot, a lot of lumens. Yes.
Speaker 2:  But I have definitely restrained from the permanent outdoor lighting
Speaker 2:  thing that everyone's doing on the houses. Yeah, me too. I think
Speaker 2:  Govi and Nano Leaf all have those. GE sink I think also has a,
Speaker 2:  an option there And I just can't get into
Speaker 2:  that. It just seems like a bit too much for me.
Speaker 2:  So.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, well I, I look at that as like I look at smart fridges, right?
Speaker 10:  It it, my house is gonna be there forever. Forever. This technology
Speaker 10:  is gonna be outdated in five or six years probably. So
Speaker 10:  yeah, do I really want to invest the time to install something quote
Speaker 10:  permanently? I don't know how I feel about that.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So thanks for the rundown. Hopefully some of that
Speaker 2:  will give you some inspiration call from your
Speaker 2:  question of how others automate their lights. But we're gonna move on to
Speaker 2:  another question about smart lighting. And this is from Ty
Speaker 2:  from Oregon and he's actually called in and left us a voicemail. So we're
Speaker 2:  gonna listen to that now
Speaker 11:  I've urge team, I've been doing the smart home thing for a while now
Speaker 11:  and Home Assistant is my hub for all the stuff. It makes
Speaker 11:  life so much easier. I have the house where I want it, but
Speaker 11:  realized that I might be setting myself up for some future headaches if
Speaker 11:  I ever wanna sell. I have a whole bunch of different system thread
Speaker 11:  where I can get it wifi where I can't. And I'm
Speaker 11:  currently running gov recessed LED lights,
Speaker 11:  LIFX overheads Modern Forms fans with light
Speaker 11:  attachments, Shelly Relay switches, as well as a
Speaker 11:  bunch of casa switches that I've turned into Smart scene controllers
Speaker 11:  if I ever wanna leave this place. Am I just
Speaker 11:  absolutely hosed. Thanks for the time. I appreciate it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  this is a very common issue when it comes to the smart home and it's becoming
Speaker 2:  a bigger and bigger issue as the smart home matures and more and more people
Speaker 2:  have smart homes and more and more people are moving from smart homes.
Speaker 2:  And this is actually something that I've written about in the past so that
Speaker 2:  we have a whole article on The Verge about how to move your smart home. And
Speaker 2:  I know Richard, you did a couple episodes of your Smart Home Show podcast
Speaker 2:  dedicated to this exact question. Correct. So go listen to those
Speaker 2:  for more details. We'll we'll include some links, but for
Speaker 2:  now, what, what would your sort of first response to this
Speaker 2:  question be other than what a cool lighting setup you have? Ty, I'm
Speaker 2:  impressed. I impressive. Very impressed.
Speaker 10:  I I, I, you know the, the how hosted are you thing? I think it really
Speaker 10:  depends on like what you want to have happen to all of that
Speaker 10:  stuff. When you move, I'm assuming you'll want to take some of it with
Speaker 10:  you. Other stuff that's built in like
Speaker 10:  thermostats and doorbells and things like that you probably don't want to
Speaker 10:  take with you. You'll probably leave those behind. So the biggest
Speaker 10:  thing that I learned the last time
Speaker 10:  that I did this And I ended up transferring a bunch of accounts
Speaker 10:  over to make this easier and now I do this this way
Speaker 10:  in my new home is I created a house
Speaker 10:  email address.
Speaker 2:  That's exactly what I say to do in my article. Yeah, I think Stacey
Speaker 2:  Higginbotham was the one who came up with this idea. I
Speaker 10:  Think it was
Speaker 2:  Stacy. It was Stacy. So props to Stacey, it's such a good idea. Yep. Sorry
Speaker 2:  you, you keep explaining. Well and
Speaker 10:  So I, for my ring account and for my
Speaker 10:  Chamberlain account for the garage door and for my Nest
Speaker 10:  account actually Nest account, yes. But now
Speaker 10:  with Google you can't really do that anymore. But for things that are more
Speaker 10:  or less permanent, I, for all of those, I created the accounts using the
Speaker 10:  house email address. And the reason for that was that when I moved from
Speaker 10:  my last house, I just wanted to sign that stuff over to the next owner.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And I didn't want to have to worry about how do we transfer these
Speaker 10:  outta my account and then they have to figure it all out to set it all up
Speaker 10:  again. What a hassle would that be? So it, it was
Speaker 10:  a lot easier if it was just on a house account. And then there is the
Speaker 10:  undoing of things that you want to take with you. And that in
Speaker 10:  itself can take a lot of time. Don't underestimate what
Speaker 10:  effort that can be because you may have routines and and
Speaker 10:  scenes and stuff like that that you'll wanna probably capture.
Speaker 10:  'cause if they're useful to you, they might be useful to you in a new
Speaker 10:  home and a new setup. Mm. So that
Speaker 10:  requires a fair amount of planning. But seriously, if
Speaker 10:  you've invested in Life Ex and Govi
Speaker 10:  and other bulbs that are a lot more expensive than just your average LED
Speaker 10:  bulb, take 'em with you. You don't, you don't wanna be leaving that kind
Speaker 10:  of stuff behind.
Speaker 2:  Just go to a Home Depot and buy a few, you know, inexpensive, decent
Speaker 2:  LEDs and swap 'em back in and take those with you. I, I agree.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. But you know, there are some
Speaker 2:  studies that say, you know, the smarts features in homes can
Speaker 2:  help sell it. So if you are kind of setting the home up, showing
Speaker 2:  it off with the smart features in, then obviously those are likely
Speaker 2:  need to convey or be part of your sales process.
Speaker 2:  So I did check in, so you mentioned Ty, that you use Home
Speaker 2:  assistant And I did check in with PA who is the founder of
Speaker 2:  Oh great. And CEO of home assistant about what he would
Speaker 2:  recommend in terms terms of moving your system to someone
Speaker 2:  else because as he points out, home assistant is
Speaker 2:  all local. So In theory and his answer is you
Speaker 2:  can just hand over the password and username
Speaker 2:  to the new owner and they can just change it
Speaker 2:  to their own and everything should just work, it should just
Speaker 2:  switch over. However, should, there's definitely
Speaker 2:  a should in there. There isn't like an official transfer method he said,
Speaker 2:  but the should is if any of the products that you're using with home
Speaker 2:  assistant are cloud dependent, which they could be like the
Speaker 2:  Govi and the Life X could, you could be using with wifi
Speaker 2:  or in the cloud. Although both of them now have matter support.
Speaker 2:  But if they are cloud dependent then you're gonna have to transfer somehow
Speaker 2:  that account. And that's where things get a little tricky. And he said, you
Speaker 2:  know, that would mean that, you know, some sort of authentication is gonna
Speaker 2:  be required that you'd need to share. And this is where having set them up
Speaker 2:  originally on a house email account would make life a lot easier
Speaker 2:  for you. But Paolos did say to us about this question
Speaker 2:  that he said, this is something that opens standards will solve
Speaker 2:  because they're all local. And just to clarify that, that means
Speaker 2:  that your devices are working locally in your home and not dependent
Speaker 2:  on the internet. So they work just like your standard door lock would like,
Speaker 2:  you wouldn't have to worry about transferring ownership of your door lock
Speaker 2:  or any other, most of the other things that you would leave in your house
Speaker 2:  when you sell it to someone. And this is something that things like
Speaker 2:  matter and home assistant brands and systems that are
Speaker 2:  working locally without cloud dependencies should make easier
Speaker 2:  because they're just gonna become part of the infrastructure of our home.
Speaker 2:  It doesn't mean you won't have an internet connection because there are benefits
Speaker 2:  to that, but you don't have to have the internet connection. Right,
Speaker 10:  Right. Yeah, exactly. Exactly. I think that's a,
Speaker 10:  a really optimistic solution. I think the,
Speaker 10:  the biggest thing that concerns me about that is that I'm assuming if you've
Speaker 10:  put this much time into your home assistant environment, you've probably
Speaker 10:  created some automations that are specific to
Speaker 10:  your household's use of the space. Yeah. So
Speaker 10:  those may be jarring or undesired by a
Speaker 10:  new homeowner. So the, one of the other things that you should make sure
Speaker 10:  you do is talk with the buyer during the
Speaker 10:  purchasing process. Once you have that contract signed, find out
Speaker 10:  do they want you to keep this stuff there? Do they want to,
Speaker 10:  you know, remove some of it. If they're ultimately gonna remove it anyway,
Speaker 10:  then why not keep the assets? And
Speaker 10:  I would suggest turning off most of your
Speaker 10:  automated stuff for them to then determine
Speaker 10:  which of those routines make sense for their lifestyle.
Speaker 2:  Yes. So, I dunno if you remember Richard a while back, I contacted you because
Speaker 2:  a, a colleague at The Verge brother had just moved into a new house that
Speaker 2:  had all inste on, but they had no idea of
Speaker 2:  what was happening or how to use it. And like the lights would just turn
Speaker 2:  on at random times in the day and the shades would raise and, and they didn't
Speaker 2:  know what to do. They had no idea. Right. And at this point that company
Speaker 2:  was no longer really in business. So they're, they're back as as we've recently
Speaker 2:  discussed. Yep. But yes, they were, this is, if you're gonna leave stuff,
Speaker 2:  please tell the person that you're selling the house to how to use it
Speaker 2:  because you're just setting them up for a really bad experience. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Otherwise, yeah. Excellent. Okay, wonderful.
Speaker 2:  Well thank you. That was, appreciate that. Call Ty.
Speaker 2:  Hopefully we helped a little bit there, but right now we have
Speaker 2:  to go to a break and we are gonna have more of your questions when we come
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  We are back with Richard Gunther. Thank you Richard for joining us. I have
Speaker 2:  a few more questions for you. Alright, so let's dive right in.
Speaker 2:  Okay, the first one, another, this is the reverse of the
Speaker 2:  story that we just answered, which is, this is from
Speaker 2:  Nicholas Martin. This is another email he sent and I'm gonna run through
Speaker 2:  what he said. So I'm planning to buy a house in the coming months and I've
Speaker 2:  started thinking seriously about the smart devices I'd like to install. Right
Speaker 2:  now I live in a rented apartment so I've kept things fairly simple when it
Speaker 2:  comes to lighting. I use Philip Hugh Bobs in the main rooms, hue switches
Speaker 2:  and sensors and I've installed hue switches on top of
Speaker 2:  the existing ones, which is far from ideal, especially for guests.
Speaker 2:  And I'd also really like to make sure that if my network hue bridge
Speaker 2:  or border router, so that would be the thread, border router goes down,
Speaker 2:  my lights still work like normal. And that's where things start
Speaker 2:  getting tricky. It feels like the issue of how smart home
Speaker 2:  devices behave during technical failures doesn't get much coverage.
Speaker 2:  And then from what I've seen on Reddit and increasing number of people are
Speaker 2:  opting for smart switches over smart bulbs, this seems like a
Speaker 2:  promising approach but I'm worried it might mean losing the flexibility of
Speaker 2:  RGB lighting unless I use a decoupled smart switch that
Speaker 2:  always stays on. But if I go that route, wouldn't the switch
Speaker 2:  stop working properly in case of a smart home failure? I've read about
Speaker 2:  ZigBee and Matter binding as possible solutions, but this all feels
Speaker 2:  way more complicated than it should be for something as basic as turning
Speaker 2:  the lights on and off. And that's why I'd love to hear your take. Do
Speaker 2:  you think the better approach is Smart switches or smart bulbs or maybe
Speaker 2:  some kind of hybrid setup? And if so, how would
Speaker 2:  this work? The eternal question bulbs or
Speaker 2:  switches? Yeah. Richard, if you were starting from
Speaker 2:  scratch, which would you go for and why?
Speaker 10:  You And I have both written about this in the past and I'm, I'm
Speaker 10:  on team switch and that's
Speaker 10:  primarily because most of my lighting is dimmable
Speaker 10:  but not color changing. Yeah. It gets more complicated
Speaker 10:  when you want color changing as you indicated with your question
Speaker 10:  regarding RGP lighting. And that's a problem that
Speaker 10:  frankly even in high, high-end custom
Speaker 10:  installations has not been
Speaker 10:  solved in a way that I think is user-friendly.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. We still have this problem where there's on off and
Speaker 10:  then there's switching between different color modes and how do
Speaker 10:  you handle that in the space of one switch And
Speaker 10:  lots of companies are trying it. I don't think anyone's really nailed it.
Speaker 10:  Well now if you have smart bulbs and the
Speaker 10:  primary thing that you want do with a switch is just
Speaker 10:  be able to control it and dim it, then yes, the switches that have a
Speaker 10:  smart bulb mode, there are a couple vendors putting those
Speaker 10:  out. I know zoos has them in a valley has them, those
Speaker 10:  are both for Z-Wave. GE
Speaker 10:  Sync has this capability, the Lutron Aurora
Speaker 10:  is an example of that. That may be one of the things that you're using when
Speaker 10:  you talk about having a controller over your existing switch.
Speaker 10:  It's a clever device but you're right, you're
Speaker 10:  dependent on your smart home system
Speaker 10:  working to make that all work properly. That's a
Speaker 10:  different question. Let's get to that in a second. But I'm curious where
Speaker 10:  you are on team switch versus bulb.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so it's, it's been an internal problem in my home for sure. And as
Speaker 2:  I mentioned, I actually have some smart bulbs connected to a switch so
Speaker 2:  you can connect hue and color changing smart,
Speaker 2:  any smart light bulb to a switch that is smart as
Speaker 2:  long as the switch that is smart is just on and off, it's when you want to
Speaker 2:  dim that you get into issues. Mainly there's a
Speaker 2:  a whole electrical reason but it, the way a dimming
Speaker 2:  system works is changing the level of power to the light
Speaker 2:  and when you do that you mess with the power and and you get flashing.
Speaker 2:  I've had a light switch, a smart light switch from Caer Fry. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Because I had a, it connected to an A Hue LED bulb
Speaker 2:  and then you have the horrible flickering when you're trying to control them.
Speaker 2:  So it's just never a good solution that way. It's okay if you're just using
Speaker 2:  a smart switch in most cases. That's the situation I have in my
Speaker 2:  bathroom. But the problem there is I have to control 'em two different ways.
Speaker 2:  So I have the, you know, turn on bathroom switch and then I
Speaker 2:  have a just vanity lights as
Speaker 2:  different phrases that I can use to talk to my smart assistant to get what
Speaker 2:  I want, which is not ideal. So I'm really interested in
Speaker 2:  these switches that have smart bulb modes. I haven't been able to
Speaker 2:  try any and that's why I got quite excited. When you mentioned you have elli
Speaker 2:  switches because I understand that they're one brand that does this. Yep.
Speaker 2:  But it sounds like you haven't set those up with color changing bulbs yet.
Speaker 10:  I have not tried that yet. That's something that I still want to do, but
Speaker 10:  yes, that is possible. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And then a carrot is another brand I mentioned when I was talking about the
Speaker 2:  ceiling light. So after I reviewed the ceiling light, they have come out
Speaker 2:  with a smart switch that can control their
Speaker 2:  bulbs specifically. And this is again where you get into the
Speaker 2:  smart lighting cabal where even really if you
Speaker 2:  stick with one brand, generally you might, you will get solutions like this.
Speaker 2:  So a carer does have switches that have smart bulb mode
Speaker 2:  for their bulbs and their light fixtures. Unfortunately my smart ceiling
Speaker 2:  light is in a room that does not have neutral wires so I cannot use
Speaker 2:  their smart light bulb switch. So
Speaker 2:  it feels like this is a problem that still hasn't been solved, especially
Speaker 2:  because you don't want necessarily to always use one brand.
Speaker 2:  One of the great scenarios for Nicholas here is that
Speaker 2:  he is moving into a new home and that starting from scratch,
Speaker 2:  I'm so jealous. I would love to start from scratch,
Speaker 2:  just do it all over. 'cause I think today there are better
Speaker 2:  solutions. I think one of them in this scenario
Speaker 2:  would be choosing a brand like in AVE or a carer that
Speaker 2:  has smart bulb mode and doing both. Because if you want a color changing
Speaker 2:  lights, you want to keep using your HU bulbs but you don't want to keep
Speaker 2:  using their remotes which work fine. And that's what I have in my kids'
Speaker 2:  rooms are the remotes, that's how they control their lights. But it's not
Speaker 2:  as he mentions, not great for guests. And it is, it's just not
Speaker 2:  an ideal solution. I wish Hue would partner with someone maybe to
Speaker 2:  come, I mean they do have the run less wire switches, but those don't,
Speaker 2:  they also don't help with the color changing. You want to be able to
Speaker 2:  control the light changing as well, the color changing. And so then they
Speaker 2:  have, you know, buttons. This is another area that buttons are good. But
Speaker 2:  yeah, I think what I'm hoping we're gonna see, and he mentions
Speaker 2:  here matter binding And I, this is
Speaker 2:  definitely future casting. This is not something that's really ready yet.
Speaker 2:  And I know Richard, that you're gonna have some thoughts on matter binding.
Speaker 2:  But what this is gonna do essentially is
Speaker 2:  allow you to bind a switch to a light
Speaker 2:  locally. And this addresses your other question about
Speaker 2:  reliability. So what will happen is that the light switch
Speaker 2:  and the light bulb, and this could be multiple light switches and multiple
Speaker 2:  light bulbs will have like a local almost wire,
Speaker 2:  invisible wire connected to each other. And that will be
Speaker 2:  sort of permanently ingrained in their memory. And even if your hub goes
Speaker 2:  down, your internet goes down, anything goes down other than the power,
Speaker 2:  they will still be able to control each other. So the you flip the switch,
Speaker 2:  the light will turn on. And this is something that's part of matter. It's
Speaker 2:  also something that is part of the ZigBee standard. And I actually checked
Speaker 2:  in with the CSA, which runs matter about this. And the Chris Lare,
Speaker 2:  the CTO said, you know, the major value here of binding these
Speaker 2:  devices together is that is speed and reliability. Yep. So the
Speaker 2:  switch talks directly to the light, it's instantaneous versus
Speaker 2:  say like a button, which would then have to talk to a hub and then maybe
Speaker 2:  check rules on the cloud and then reply and tell the hub
Speaker 2:  to contact the light. Yep. So all of this could take, you know, less than
Speaker 2:  a few seconds or under a second, but still not as fast as flipping a light
Speaker 2:  switch, which is what we need. Right. So
Speaker 2:  it's an exciting thing. It's not something that we've seen any brands
Speaker 2:  adopt yet a Kara has said that they're looking into it, but it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be a while I think until I, if this is even gonna be a
Speaker 2:  solution. But what what is great about it is if it works in matter,
Speaker 2:  you wouldn't need to use the same brands. So In theory,
Speaker 2:  if your Phillips Hue bulbs worked with Matter binding and
Speaker 2:  you're a Kara Smart Switch worked with Matter binding, you could bind them
Speaker 2:  together and that feels like a future. I'm excited for
Speaker 2:  Richard. Throw cold water over me. No,
Speaker 10:  I, I agree. I agree. I, I just think we're okay. I think
Speaker 10:  we're a far way out for that. I mean we, we do have this
Speaker 10:  same sort of thing, insig B and frankly it's
Speaker 10:  not dissimilar from how Insteon products work with each other. They
Speaker 10:  directly communicate with each other without the need for that hub to trigger
Speaker 10:  each other. So it is promising it could solve
Speaker 10:  a lot of these problems. You mentioned Aqara in your hybrid
Speaker 10:  situation I think, yeah, the best product that Aqara offers
Speaker 10:  now to help with this problem is their
Speaker 10:  four button scene controller. So they have a
Speaker 10:  scene controller that has a switch in it that allows one of the
Speaker 10:  buttons to be a switch and control the actual load. So turning it
Speaker 10:  on or off and then the other three buttons
Speaker 10:  can be set to trigger any matter scene. So
Speaker 10:  that could be different styles of using the light, different
Speaker 10:  colors or different moods that you want to set so that you
Speaker 10:  have one to turn it on and then the others could
Speaker 10:  trigger those scenes. You could even have those scenes potentially
Speaker 10:  also turn the light on if you didn't wanna have to manually turn it on first.
Speaker 10:  So there's some options for you we're just not
Speaker 10:  fully there yet. No,
Speaker 2:  No. So in the interim, Nicholas, I I mean you keep
Speaker 2:  your HU bulbs, bring 'em along, they work with Matter and
Speaker 2:  yes switches right now I think it sounds like maybe
Speaker 2:  the Aqara switches with the scenes could be a good way of controlling some
Speaker 2:  of the devices or in AVE switches with their smart
Speaker 2:  bulb mode. Now those work with any smart bulbs. Correct. Those aren't just,
Speaker 2:  they don't, 'cause Inno Valley doesn't make their own bulbs so Correct.
Speaker 2:  Those would work with any smart bulbs.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it, it works with whatever smart bulb is Move is working with your
Speaker 10:  controller system of choice, which would either be something through ZigBee
Speaker 10:  Z-Wave or Matter.
Speaker 2:  And then of course the other solution if you're handy or you're getting an
Speaker 2:  electrician to do all of this is the relays that we talked about earlier.
Speaker 2:  And those would connect your smart bulbs through regular switches to any
Speaker 2:  smart platform that you like. Shelly being one of the options that a Cara
Speaker 2:  also has relays too. So hopefully there's some solutions
Speaker 2:  there for you Nicholas. And we are going to jump to another question.
Speaker 2:  This one is another, another Hue and
Speaker 2:  Aqara one. This one is another bit bit of a head scratcher
Speaker 2:  and it's an interesting one to kind of follow on from this last question.
Speaker 2:  This is from Simon Salvin and this is his question is I have
Speaker 2:  Hue Lighting and a Cara Wireless switches. These are all
Speaker 2:  set up through the Apple Home app and the switches can be temperamental at
Speaker 2:  times. I see. I can add the Hue bridge to Aqara
Speaker 2:  via matter, which I'm thinking could give me greater control setup in the
Speaker 2:  Aqara app. Would you advise this and would this still keep all
Speaker 2:  the lights in the home app for controlling certain lights without
Speaker 2:  switches and automations already created? Although
Speaker 2:  I have the Aqara M two hub, he points out
Speaker 2:  and he asks should I be able to pair the Hugh hub to that
Speaker 2:  without matter. I'm sorry, this one is quite complicated
Speaker 2:  and I'm, I did reach out to a carer just to make sure we got this one
Speaker 2:  right. Yep. And you know, this goes to what we talked about before
Speaker 2:  about how matter can sort of help you integrate smart lighting
Speaker 2:  from different brands. Because what a carer has done recently and
Speaker 2:  the same as Ikea as we mentioned at the top of the show, is they've become
Speaker 2:  matter controllers which allows you to add any matter
Speaker 2:  devices to their ecosystem. Just as you add the huge bridge
Speaker 2:  to your Apple home ecosystem, you can add anything to
Speaker 2:  a carer and now IKEA and control through their app
Speaker 2:  rather than through Apple Home. The question is here though, can you
Speaker 2:  connect a Hub Bridge to an a car matter controller? You can definitely do
Speaker 2:  that through Matter, but you can't, I'm afraid Simon do it with the
Speaker 2:  M two hub, it only works with the M three hub and
Speaker 2:  this is where matter has been a bit difficult for people because there
Speaker 2:  had been hope that much of the support from older devices would exist
Speaker 2:  with matter. But unfortunately that has not been the case and a lot of companies
Speaker 2:  have come out with newer devices like a car has come out with its M three
Speaker 2:  hub, which does support being a matter controller. The M
Speaker 2:  two hub supports matter but not as being a controller.
Speaker 2:  I'm getting into the weeds a little bit here, but if you do this, if you
Speaker 2:  connect your HU Bridge to the matter controller, a car matter controller,
Speaker 2:  you'll be able to control the HU Lights in the A Carra home app
Speaker 2:  and automate them with a Cara's excellent automation engine.
Speaker 2:  But you cannot then control them via
Speaker 2:  Apple Home. If you just integrate them into a carra
Speaker 2:  you to control them in Apple Home, you would need
Speaker 2:  to generate a matter code in the Aqara Home
Speaker 2:  app and use that code to add the hub bridge to Apple
Speaker 2:  Home. This is using matter's multi multimin feature
Speaker 2:  that we haven't touched on, but this is one of the, the things that makes
Speaker 2:  matter interoperable. It allows you to use
Speaker 2:  any matter device with any matter compatible platform,
Speaker 2:  which is great for smart lighting, especially if you live in a house
Speaker 2:  that's divided.
Speaker 2:  Yep. So your spouse has an Android phone and you have an iPhone
Speaker 2:  and he wants to talk to Google and you want to talk to Siri. And this is
Speaker 2:  one of the great features of Matter, although it's been a little spotty
Speaker 2:  to start with, it does seem to be getting better. And I've found recently
Speaker 2:  when I've tried adding matter devices from one
Speaker 2:  ecosystem to another that it has started to work a lot more
Speaker 2:  smoothly, which is, which is exciting. Is this something that you've spent
Speaker 2:  much time doing or do you just stick everything with Stick with everything
Speaker 2:  in Apple Home?
Speaker 10:  I'm trying to keep most everything in Apple Home, but one thing
Speaker 10:  that I did wanna address here is, you know it, it's easy to get frustrated
Speaker 10:  that the hub that you've invested in isn't necessarily gonna
Speaker 10:  support the new features before anyone gets
Speaker 10:  conspiratorial about that. That's almost always because of the
Speaker 10:  capabilities of the chip set in the hub. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  For this controller capability it does require,
Speaker 10:  you know, more horsepower if you will to use an old fashioned term
Speaker 10:  and some of the old chips just can't support that. So yeah,
Speaker 10:  while some vendors were able to say, oh yeah, our current chip set will
Speaker 10:  support adding our devices into the matter
Speaker 10:  ecosystem, they weren't necessarily capable enough
Speaker 10:  to be a controller, which means stuff like running those routines
Speaker 10:  and making all of those connections. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. And like the M two does support matter as a bridge,
Speaker 2:  it's just not gonna be a controller. Right. And that's the, and this is something
Speaker 2:  that we're only starting to see recently is companies turning their
Speaker 2:  hubs into controllers and it's gonna be interesting to see, 'cause
Speaker 2:  you know, In theory you could set everything up now in your smart home
Speaker 2:  with a carer or IKEA and not need to use Apple or Google or
Speaker 2:  Amazon if you don't want, which may appeal to people, especially
Speaker 2:  as you can do all of both of those systems work
Speaker 2:  locally. They both rely heavily on ZigBee And I, Cara does
Speaker 2:  have thread and Ikea it sounds like is also gonna be working
Speaker 2:  with Thread so that it, it's nice to have these options, especially if you're
Speaker 2:  only interested in lighting. I think if you don't need all of the other stuff.
Speaker 2:  And these, as we've pointed out, IKEA and Aqara do have pretty
Speaker 2:  powerful automation systems for lighting. So it's exciting
Speaker 2:  to see this. This is kind of one of the reasons behind matter too. So it's
Speaker 2:  exciting to see that with companies start to do this. I think the other one
Speaker 2:  that has done it is Flick, have you had much experience with Flick devices?
Speaker 10:  You know, I had used Flick in its first
Speaker 10:  generation and just haven't kept up with it as it's evolved.
Speaker 10:  It's grown into something quite powerful actually.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And their latest device is a dial. And this is something that I really
Speaker 2:  want to see more of in smart lighting because having that that you said
Speaker 2:  earlier, the physical controls are so important, they still are
Speaker 2:  like, I think it's important to remember that when you have smart home and
Speaker 2:  smart lighting, that doesn't mean you don't need switches anymore, right?
Speaker 2:  It's just that your switches can now do so much more. Potentially
Speaker 2:  they, they, yes, potentially. And being able to sort of dial up
Speaker 2:  the light and brightness but also be able to press a button and turn
Speaker 2:  to your movie time scene or have everything turn to the colors of your favorite
Speaker 2:  football team with just a tap. Those kind of features with physical
Speaker 2:  controls, you know, what makes smart lighting really fun, I think. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Excellent. Okay, so I think we've got time for one more quick one, which
Speaker 2:  is along the same lines as we've been talking about here. Now that we dived
Speaker 2:  into matter. I managed, we managed to get quite far without too much matter
Speaker 2:  chat, which David would be proud of. But the
Speaker 2:  last one here is from Res Gore and
Speaker 2:  he wanted, he's asking about thread border routers. So I'm looking for
Speaker 2:  a thread border router to improve my matter smart home setup.
Speaker 2:  Is it still worth buying something like the Google Nest Mini
Speaker 2:  two from 2020 given that it's already more than
Speaker 2:  four years old? I'm unsure if Google plans to launch a newer version.
Speaker 2:  The reason I ask is that a few of my matter enabled devices aren't
Speaker 2:  controllable via Apple HomeKit and considering series
Speaker 2:  current limitations, I'm hesitant to invest in a home
Speaker 2:  pod mini. There's so many things we could unpack from that.
Speaker 2:  First of all, is Nest making any more hardware? And second of all, what's
Speaker 2:  going on with Siri, right? But the very first question answer I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  give you is no, do not buy a Google Nest mini two. Don't, don't, don't, don't.
Speaker 2:  Mainly because it's not a thread border route. So it will not help
Speaker 2:  if you're gonna go by any Google device right now to help with your
Speaker 2:  thread network. And this is, we mentioned earlier, thread is a smart home
Speaker 2:  protocol. A lot of lighting runs on it. It's one of the main
Speaker 2:  protocols used by Matter. Google has
Speaker 2:  a number of different devices and we'll include a link into the show notes
Speaker 2:  for the ones that are matter controllers and thread border routers.
Speaker 2:  But my suggestion would be to buy the Google TV streamer 4K,
Speaker 2:  which is their most recent product. So it is newer, it's not five years
Speaker 2:  old and it also doubles as a great streaming device.
Speaker 2:  I've been using it, wrote a review of it, which we will also link in the
Speaker 2:  show notes and it's a perfect solution even
Speaker 2:  if you have a device you'd like to use for your tv now you could just plug
Speaker 2:  this in and use it as a thread border router. It doesn't have smart speaker
Speaker 2:  capabilities though, So if you were looking for something that you could
Speaker 2:  talk to and the best option right now would probably be the Nest
Speaker 2:  Hub two. So the one that is not quite as old,
Speaker 2:  I think that's like 2023. That is also a thread border
Speaker 2:  router. What would you suggest here, Richard? Do you think
Speaker 2:  having more thread border routers will help his Matt Smart Home
Speaker 2:  set up?
Speaker 10:  Honestly the, the thing that concerns me is that it sounds like
Speaker 10:  current control is
Speaker 10:  through, well, I don't know, I can't tell if control is through
Speaker 10:  Apple Home or Google Home. And so that's one of the things
Speaker 10:  that's, that's hard to understand because they mentioned both
Speaker 10:  the Home pod and the Google Nest Mini, I'm not
Speaker 10:  sure what ecosystem they're hoping to
Speaker 10:  stay in. Yeah, I understand the hesitation to drop 99 bucks
Speaker 10:  on a HomePod mini. One thing that you might
Speaker 10:  want to consider is looking on eBay or on
Speaker 10:  marketplace for folks that are getting
Speaker 10:  rid of old home pod minis, I, I think you, oh yeah,
Speaker 10:  it's not that hard to find this stuff secondhand and you can do
Speaker 10:  a full wipe and then incorporate them into your
Speaker 10:  home. I, I mean you mentioned the 4K streaming
Speaker 10:  device, that's a hundred dollars investment. That's the same price that
Speaker 10:  is as the HomePod mini, but
Speaker 2:  It does more. It does,
Speaker 10:  It does. And I love Google tv. I'm a big fan. So if that's something yeah.
Speaker 10:  That you have in your home and and might wanna upgrade, that could be the
Speaker 10:  perfect answer.
Speaker 2:  And it does. I said it doesn't have a speaker in it as a, it's not like a
Speaker 2:  smart speaker, but you can use the remote to talk to the Google
Speaker 2:  assistant and control smart home devices through that. It also has
Speaker 2:  a great little smart home panel that will pop out while you're watching tv,
Speaker 2:  compress a button and control your devices through that. But yes, I agree.
Speaker 2:  The idea here is you've got two ecosystems and which ones do you wanna be
Speaker 2:  in? And I use both of these ecosystems. So you know, and this is again
Speaker 2:  where matter is helping because I, you know, you can have everything in both
Speaker 2:  and control one thing using your Google TV remote
Speaker 2:  and say, trigger my movie scene. But then you can also do that on your
Speaker 2:  iPhone through your Apple Home app or through the control panel.
Speaker 2:  It's nice to be able to have that flexibility. We're starting to see more
Speaker 2:  and more of that with matter. But just to wrap up the thread
Speaker 2:  question here, having a thread border router is important
Speaker 2:  for your matter set up. If you do not have one, I recommend getting one
Speaker 2:  because if you do not have a thread border router, you cannot use thread
Speaker 2:  devices in your smart home. You can use matter over wifi, but you cannot
Speaker 2:  use thread devices. And there are a lot of great new thread devices out there,
Speaker 2:  especially in the smart lighting space. And you only need a
Speaker 2:  thread one thread border router technically more will help because they
Speaker 2:  create, they're part of a mesh network and if one goes down, the other one
Speaker 2:  will pick up. So to the point about failures in the smart home,
Speaker 2:  having more than one thread, border router will help. But
Speaker 2:  you do not need to have a thread border router from the smart home platform
Speaker 2:  that you are using. Right. But yes, if you're using Apple Home and you add
Speaker 2:  a Google Home streamer, you are adding a thread border router
Speaker 2:  to your network, whether or not it is an Apple home device. So
Speaker 2:  you are, you are supporting your, your network and you're making it stronger.
Speaker 2:  One of the problems with thread border routers right now is when you add
Speaker 2:  a new one to your home, it could create its
Speaker 2:  own network, which would not help you. The good
Speaker 2:  news is that Apple and Google are some of the companies that have actually
Speaker 2:  done a good job at connecting their networks together. So
Speaker 2:  you probably would be fine in this instance, it's Amazon and
Speaker 2:  eero and smart things that are still a little
Speaker 2:  lagging in terms of making one healthy board router
Speaker 2:  thread network when you add your devices. So as I've written
Speaker 2:  about recently, this is something that all of the thread manufacturers
Speaker 2:  are working on. And with the one do four release, which is
Speaker 2:  out now by next year, I'm told this
Speaker 2:  shouldn't be a problem anymore. So as has been the theme of this
Speaker 2:  episode, just wait and everything's gonna get better.
Speaker 2:  But I thank you so much, Richard, for your time and expertise.
Speaker 2:  It's been really fun having you on. And any last pieces of
Speaker 2:  advice you'd like to leave for our readers when it comes to smart lighting?
Speaker 2:  Sorry for our listeners.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I, I, I think the, the thing that I would
Speaker 10:  just say is, you know, if you're hearing all of this
Speaker 10:  and you're thinking, geez, maybe I should just wait till I do anything.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I don't know that you really need to go that far. I think there are
Speaker 10:  some good solutions out there that are not universally but
Speaker 10:  largely compatible with most of the ecosystems and with matter.
Speaker 10:  And so it's a really good place to start and most of the devices that are
Speaker 10:  available now are going to, you know, take you
Speaker 10:  many years into the future. Yeah. The thing that I would be
Speaker 10:  cautious of is that inclination to say,
Speaker 10:  oh, but here on Amazon I can get four of those bulbs for the same
Speaker 10:  price as this one from Hugh or Govie or
Speaker 10:  name the more well-known vendor. There's a reason
Speaker 10:  they're so inexpensive and in my
Speaker 10:  experience, a lot of those lower price,
Speaker 10:  lesser known brands are not gonna last as well or not gonna
Speaker 10:  future as well. And you'll be fighting
Speaker 10:  more problems than solving them.
Speaker 2:  Very good advice. Yes, it's worth investing a little bit of money into smart
Speaker 2:  lighting. It pays off in dividends and far less headaches when it comes to
Speaker 2:  setting everything up and troubleshooting in my experience. So, yep.
Speaker 2:  Wise words. Richard, very much appreciate your time this week. Thank you
Speaker 2:  so much.
Speaker 10:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's it for The Vergecast today. To read more about today's topics,
Speaker 2:  check out the show notes or go to The Verge dot com. As always, if you
Speaker 2:  have thoughts, questions, feelings, smart home dilemmas,
Speaker 2:  you can always email us at vergecast at VERGE dot com or keep calling
Speaker 2:  the hotline. 8 6 6 VERGE one one. We love hearing
Speaker 2:  from you. Send us all your thoughts and questions and ideas on what we should
Speaker 2:  do on the show. We do a hotline question every week. So keep
Speaker 2:  'em coming. And if you like what we do here, please consider buying
Speaker 2:  a paid subscription. Also, follow us on our new follow channels on The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. This show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer,
Speaker 2:  Travis Laak, and Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The Verge Production
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Jake
Speaker 2:  Kakis and the team will be here on Friday to talk about the news, And I will
Speaker 2:  be back next Tuesday. Thanks for listening.