# Transcript
ID: 6fd9c152-a36c-43f2-a2ba-6686578bf254
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6998921338757792904/1921209760047744989/s93290-US-6031s-1758880400.mp3
Description: After more than five years of backing and forthing, secret meetings and loud screeds, it appears the fate of TikTok in the US has finally been decided. Maybe. There are still a lot of unknowns, but we're pretty sure we know the bones of the deal — and we know which of President Trump's allies stand to benefit the most. Before we get to all that, though, David and Jake run through some big news in future gadgets, including the long-awaited-and-maybe-happening combination of Android and ChromeOS and the possibilities for a touchscreen MacBook. Then, The Verge's Liz Lopatto joins to talk TikTok. And Trump. Then, in the lightning round, the three hosts talk through Jimmy Kimmel's return, Nvidia's money problems, a surprising AmEx perk, and much more.
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 4:  To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of all of the apps being
Speaker 4:  like all of the other apps and all of the devices being like all of the other
Speaker 4:  devices. Yeah, it's 2025 and everything is the same. I'm your
Speaker 4:  friend David Pierce. Jake Kakis is here. Hi Jake.
Speaker 5:  Hey, what's going? I love when everything is the same. It, you can switch
Speaker 5:  between everything and you don't notice. It's great. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  From now on there is Gadget and there is app. And those are the only two
Speaker 4:  things we're gonna talk about from, from now on. Yep. And who makes them
Speaker 4:  is irrelevant. It's all the same. We're gonna talk a lot about this, but
Speaker 4:  we should say right up top here, it's 10 o'clock in the morning and we don't
Speaker 4:  typically record this podcast in the morning, but right now it's 10 o'clock
Speaker 4:  in the morning. You And I have some meetings later, so we're recording a
Speaker 4:  few hours early. This has some implications for some news we're about to
Speaker 4:  get to, but also the vibes are just different. Jake, can we, how, how are
Speaker 4:  you feeling at 10 o'clock in the morning making a podcast? What
Speaker 5:  David is quietly trying to say is that I just told him I
Speaker 5:  haven't had any caffeine that I, I just have been going all night
Speaker 5:  long and I'm, I'm plowing into the podcast studio ready to roll.
Speaker 5:  So I'm either gonna fall asleep or be like a little delirious on edge.
Speaker 4:  Jake is the, the 10 x coder of The Verge who just rolls
Speaker 4:  72 straight hours and, and like hacks. Bank of
Speaker 4:  America. That's, that's Jake. That's the vibe I want everyone to assume Jake
Speaker 4:  has on The Vergecast at all times.
Speaker 5:  Vergecast am, let's go. Really
Speaker 4:  What's upsetting me is I'm drinking coffee during The Vergecast and it's
Speaker 4:  just really throwing me off. But anyway, we have a lot of news to talk about
Speaker 4:  in a little while. We're gonna talk about the TikTok deal, which I think
Speaker 4:  annoyingly between right now as we're recording this. And when you hear this,
Speaker 4:  it seems like President Trump is going to issue and sign an executive order
Speaker 4:  outlining the deal that we have been hearing pieces about
Speaker 4:  for a long time. For there to be some kind of change with
Speaker 4:  TikTok And I, I say that vaguely because this is
Speaker 4:  still where we are. So Liz Lippa is gonna come on and we're gonna go through
Speaker 4:  it because I think even not knowing the executive order, I think we know
Speaker 4:  what this is going to be and what it's gonna mean already. So if we're
Speaker 4:  dead wrong, we'll be dead wrong. But I don't think so. I think we know what
Speaker 4:  this is gonna be. So we'll, we'll talk about it and then obviously come to
Speaker 4:  the verse.com for all of our coverage once the executive order comes out.
Speaker 4:  We also have a lot of gadgets to talk about. We're gonna do a lightning round,
Speaker 4:  which is still called the lightning round. Despite the, like I would say,
Speaker 4:  surprising enthusiasm of the thunder round fans
Speaker 5:  Back, bring it back.
Speaker 4:  I believe two things. I believe that all of you are Jake's burners And
Speaker 4:  I believe that all of you love the thunder round. And I think that is good
Speaker 4:  and beautiful and someday I'll die and Jake can have the thunder round.
Speaker 4:  Until then, Jake, we have a lot of gadget news to talk about. Oh,
Speaker 5:  It's been a weirdly busy week for
Speaker 4:  Gadgets. It has. So the theme of the week, I would say
Speaker 4:  is like gadgets that have been rumored for decade
Speaker 4:  or decades maybe inching closer
Speaker 4:  to becoming true. And let me, let me just run down the list and then we're
Speaker 4:  gonna kind of hit this one by one. There were a bunch
Speaker 4:  of new rumors and speculations and timeline guesses and supply
Speaker 4:  chain sources about both a foldable iPhone,
Speaker 4:  which the, the general consensus seems to be is going to be
Speaker 4:  basically two iPhone errors just stuck together, which is
Speaker 4:  kind of what we thought having seen the iPhone air. We
Speaker 4:  continue to hear more about touchscreen max, which Apple has been saying
Speaker 4:  pretty loudly for a very long time, is not a thing they're interested in,
Speaker 4:  seems to be a thing they're interested in. Seems like it's real, seems like
Speaker 4:  it's coming. We have a bunch of new reporting, particularly from the information
Speaker 4:  about what open AI is doing with Johnny Ive and the, the
Speaker 4:  io co-brand thing that they're up to. Interesting new hardware coming
Speaker 4:  there. But where I wanna start is with a rumor that you And I have been covering
Speaker 4:  legitimately, I think damn near our entire journalism careers. Oh
Speaker 4:  yeah. Oh yeah. Which is the combination of Android
Speaker 4:  and Chrome os. Google makes two very successful operating
Speaker 4:  systems. One is Android, which runs on phones and TVs and like
Speaker 4:  devices everywhere. One is Chrome os, which runs on Chromebooks.
Speaker 4:  The middle of those two things. The overlap of the Venn diagram
Speaker 4:  is the sort of thing that Google has been talking about for
Speaker 4:  forever. And we've heard a bunch of different tries at
Speaker 4:  it. I think there's, we've even seen some evidence of real progress trying
Speaker 4:  to combine Android and Chrome os. But this week
Speaker 4:  the news was that Rick Oslo, who runs all of this stuff, he runs devices,
Speaker 4:  he runs Android. He is, he's the person in charge of all of the requisite
Speaker 4:  parts to make this happen was at a a Qualcomm event
Speaker 4:  talking to I believe Christiano Amon, the CEO of Qualcomm.
Speaker 4:  And he said, and I'm quoting, in the past we've always had very
Speaker 4:  different systems between what we're building on PCs and what we're building
Speaker 4:  on smartphones. And we've embarked on a project to combine that. We are building
Speaker 4:  together a common technical foundations for our products on PCs and desktop
Speaker 4:  operating systems. Jake, how many times would you say we've heard someone
Speaker 4:  at Google say roughly that in the last 10 years?
Speaker 5:  It feels like it's like every other year because they, they, they say it,
Speaker 5:  they're like, we're doing this, it's happening. Chrome Android would be pretty
Speaker 5:  interesting. A year goes by, they're like, I have no idea what you're talking
Speaker 5:  about. Chrome OS is a wonderful operating system. It's gonna keep going.
Speaker 5:  And, And I, they keep forgetting and it feels like
Speaker 5:  maybe they're like, no, no, no, it's real. I, I believe it is real this
Speaker 5:  time. Why I make this make why? I don't
Speaker 5:  know, because they've said it twice in a row. Like that's honestly it like,
Speaker 5:  like every other time they just immediately forget. Like they're, the the,
Speaker 5:  and it's, it's usually in the past, I feel like it's been like whispers too
Speaker 5:  where it'll be like a, it feels like they have like intentionally
Speaker 5:  leaked this where they're like, Ooh, something interesting's coming. And
Speaker 5:  we're like, it's gonna, it's real. It's happening. And then they're like,
Speaker 5:  we, we have one operating system. I don't do we have like,
Speaker 5:  this feels like it's real. They ought on stage there. There's a CEO up there.
Speaker 5:  It feels legitimate also. Somebody said, where's this
Speaker 5:  quote? Yes, I've seen it. It is incredible. Honestly, actually that's,
Speaker 5:  that sounds like what you say about like some ancient
Speaker 5:  relic.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. It also
Speaker 4:  That's the inner Jones coming home from a crusader. It's like I've seen it's,
Speaker 4:  it's incredible.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it is. And it's it, but this is just Chrome os
Speaker 5:  that has the Android branding on it instead.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay, so this is what I wanna talk about. So I think there are, there
Speaker 4:  are two paths forward for this combination, which I, I agree.
Speaker 4:  I think is real and and key difference
Speaker 4:  I think is plausible this time, right? And this is a lot of stuff we've talked
Speaker 4:  about. Arm chips have gotten very good to the point that you can, you can
Speaker 4:  run a desktop class experience on top of arm, which is a huge
Speaker 4:  deal if you want to take Android and not
Speaker 4:  completely rebuild it from scratch for desktop PCs, you want something that
Speaker 4:  actually like works and is good. I think all of the actual technical
Speaker 4:  underpinnings to do that exist, right? Like you can run an ARM-based laptop
Speaker 4:  successfully. This is like, it's not an accident that they're doing this
Speaker 4:  with Qualcomm, which is leading that in a big way in the like Windows and
Speaker 4:  Android space. But we're getting to the point where the tech to make this
Speaker 4:  work In theory kind of works, which was not the case for a long time. But
Speaker 4:  there are sort of two paths here. One is basically we are going to
Speaker 4:  use sort of the base level Android kernel as the
Speaker 4:  infrastructure for all of the rest of this. So rather than having to build
Speaker 4:  two full complete tech stacks, we'll have Chrome os,
Speaker 4:  which runs on top of some very base infrastructure of Android. And we'll
Speaker 4:  have Android, which runs on top of the very base infrastructure of Android.
Speaker 4:  That is like really terrific corporate synergy. That doesn't matter at all
Speaker 4:  to anybody, right? Like fine, build it however the hell you want. No,
Speaker 4:  it's, that won't change anybody's actual experience of using the product.
Speaker 4:  The other future and the one that Google has sort of poked it
Speaker 4:  wanting to do for a very long time and has even tried some ways to do, is
Speaker 4:  actually building a single user facing operating system that is both
Speaker 4:  Android and Chrome os. So that whether you're using a laptop or a
Speaker 4:  phone or a television, you are using the same operating system with
Speaker 4:  the same apps that do the same things everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Which is the dream. That
Speaker 4:  Is the dream, right?
Speaker 5:  Like that's what you want. Yes. You want to just move from one device to
Speaker 5:  the next and everything follows along. And it's
Speaker 5:  sort of, it, it's tough for, for Google because they really, I mean
Speaker 5:  Chromes is wonderful, But that, that is not like a thing that they have,
Speaker 5:  right? Like in the same way that Apple can, you know, move
Speaker 5:  your phone calls seamlessly onto your Mac. Like that is an incredible
Speaker 5:  experience. It's completely seamless and
Speaker 5:  Google just doesn't have that. I are they gonna get that with Chrome os
Speaker 5:  merged with Android? I don't know that they will,
Speaker 5:  but that's like a possibility. And I think that's what what they want to
Speaker 5:  pitch here, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's why you do it, right? Is to be able to do that kind of thing.
Speaker 4:  And this is Samir Samat who runs Android, I
Speaker 4:  think this was in July of this year, a couple of months ago,
Speaker 4:  basically said those things, I think it was to lance you off
Speaker 4:  a tech radar about this stuff, about why they're wanting to do this stuff
Speaker 4:  to actually make it easier for your devices. Not to just do
Speaker 4:  things themselves, but to communicate with each other. And I think this is
Speaker 4:  a thing Google has spent a lot of time on, even just simple things like
Speaker 4:  Fast Pair with Android, right? Like Google wants to take all of
Speaker 4:  the stuff that Apple does with Apple products and let you do it with other
Speaker 4:  products. And I think that is In theory a really powerful idea.
Speaker 4:  Like if, if you can make something that is that sort of,
Speaker 4:  you know, connected between devices and everything works everywhere and everything
Speaker 4:  is optimized, but also transferable, like that's
Speaker 4:  the, it's the right idea. That is the thing that we should do. And actually
Speaker 4:  Google is better set up than almost anybody to do it just by virtue the fact
Speaker 4:  that it runs Android and everybody already supports Android. The thing
Speaker 4:  is, we have seen what it looks like when Google tries to do
Speaker 4:  something as simple as run Android apps on Chrome os and it, it both
Speaker 4:  doesn't work and is a bad idea. And I like, I cannot emphasize the
Speaker 4:  extent to which those are two different things, right? Like, not only do
Speaker 4:  the, are the apps slow and messy and not optimized for the big screen, it
Speaker 4:  just kind of sucks. Like running an Android app on a Chromebook
Speaker 4:  is a bad user experience. It's nice that it exists, but it is a
Speaker 4:  bad user experience. And this is where it's like, I
Speaker 4:  just, I think Google is maybe now for the first time
Speaker 4:  reckoning with how hard a project it actually is to make something that
Speaker 4:  works everywhere. And it is a full reboot of Chrome OS in particular,
Speaker 4:  not just, we have to make it so that we can run Android on larger screens.
Speaker 4:  Like we, that's fine, but that's a totally different thing.
Speaker 5:  What's fascinating to me is that this, at this moment, this
Speaker 5:  project both feels more possible than ever, right? I think, I think that
Speaker 5:  they can probably pretty easily get to a pretty decent
Speaker 5:  product and it also feels less important than ever,
Speaker 5:  right? Decks, which is Samsung's desktop version of
Speaker 5:  one OS or one ui, whatever, you know, their version of
Speaker 5:  Android is. That's been around for years, right?
Speaker 5:  It, the idea of putting an, like putting Android
Speaker 5:  into a desktop environment is not new. There's already like traces of that
Speaker 5:  in Android. Yep. So, okay, they're gonna put Android on a, a laptop.
Speaker 5:  Great. It has windowing, it has apps, it has a browser. I'm sure I can use
Speaker 5:  it and it'll be a completely reasonable experience. The same way that I'm,
Speaker 5:  I can use iPad OS as a desktop and it's a completely reasonable experience.
Speaker 5:  Turns out there's still a million tiny little things that get in the way
Speaker 5:  of it being a really great seamless experience.
Speaker 5:  And I, the desktop also just feels like it is not
Speaker 5:  the environment where people are looking for something like new and exciting
Speaker 5:  and interesting and different at this moment and
Speaker 5:  right. Are they, I I am curious what the competitive
Speaker 5:  purpose of this product is going to be. Right? Chrome OS had a very specific
Speaker 5:  purpose, right? Laptops are expensive. Chromos came in,
Speaker 5:  they're very cheap, they're very affordable. They go into schools, they're
Speaker 5:  people's first laptop, they're super easy, they're light, they go, your ghost
Speaker 5:  is going on the browser anyway, just use it. What is the point of Android
Speaker 5:  as a laptop? I don't know.
Speaker 4:  I don't either. And I, I think this is the thing that I am
Speaker 4:  increasingly hung up on because again, I, I like, I start
Speaker 4:  at this process and I'm like, okay, if you take all the things that I like
Speaker 4:  about Android, right? The, the huge app ecosystem, the
Speaker 4:  portability, the good battery optimization, like take all that stuff and
Speaker 4:  give me full desktop class Chrome.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, sick, that is, that is pretty close to all of the things that I
Speaker 4:  want. But then it's like, okay, well what, what hardware do I wanna
Speaker 4:  run that on all day? Do you want a thing that looks like a touchscreen
Speaker 4:  laptop? Should it be a detachable thing? Should it be like a tablet with
Speaker 4:  a great keyboard attachment? And and all of a sudden
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh, actually this bet that Google, and as
Speaker 4:  we're gonna talk about it in a minute, apple are making, is that actually
Speaker 4:  everything should do, everything means
Speaker 4:  by default, whatever piece of hardware you buy is going to make a bunch of
Speaker 4:  compromises on a bunch of weird usability things. And the idea of
Speaker 4:  a laptop that runs Android apps sounds good,
Speaker 4:  but kind of falls apart as soon as you start using it. Which anybody who
Speaker 4:  has used Chromos in recent years can tell you. And then on the flip
Speaker 4:  side, like if, if I had full honest to God desktop class
Speaker 4:  Chrome on my phone, I don't think that would change anything about my experience
Speaker 4:  using an Android phone. No. And so I I'm, I'm just stuck in this place where
Speaker 4:  it's like, yes, I want this thing. And I think the idea of saying we want
Speaker 4:  make it easier for you to do things like move
Speaker 4:  files between devices and move, take a phone call on your computer
Speaker 4:  and then move it to your phone. Like all of these sort of little usability
Speaker 4:  things, I think make a lot of sense. But the idea that there is some
Speaker 4:  huge new idea about how we use our devices at the end of this road,
Speaker 4:  I used to believe that, And I'm kind of less and less convinced of it all
Speaker 4:  the time.
Speaker 5:  I, I, I think I agree with you, right? Do I
Speaker 5:  think they can do this? Do I think that it'll be a completely reasonable
Speaker 5:  experience? Absolutely. It's, it's, it's basically there.
Speaker 5:  It's not, I I don't think it is going to be a huge challenge for 'em to make
Speaker 5:  this happen, but as far as I can see, I don't see a world where this ends
Speaker 5:  up as anything other than, okay, now I have an option of getting
Speaker 5:  a Dell Premium plus with Android instead of Windows.
Speaker 5:  And I think for the average shopper, why are you gonna get it with
Speaker 5:  Android?
Speaker 4:  I do wonder if all of these companies are still hell bent on the
Speaker 4:  idea that if we can just do all of this right.
Speaker 4:  Tablets will become the thing I really like. I I really do think that, I
Speaker 4:  think, I think Apple continues to believe that if we can just
Speaker 4:  turn these three knobs the right way, everybody will
Speaker 4:  want an iPad as their main computer because it is so versatile, because it
Speaker 4:  can do so many things. Because it is kind of the, the, you know,
Speaker 4:  it's 80% of a phone and 80% of a computer. And that is like a very powerful
Speaker 4:  idea. They're like, if we can just solve these little things, we can just
Speaker 4:  do the menu bar, right? We'll put the stoplight in the thing and we'll let
Speaker 4:  you window that's gonna make you wanna use it as your main computer. And,
Speaker 4:  and it goes to what you said, it's, it's that, and then it's a million little
Speaker 4:  things about how I use these devices and live my life. And
Speaker 4:  Android is even wor, I mean, nobody has ever made an Android tablet that
Speaker 4:  has been compelling to anyone.
Speaker 5:  About a month ago, my MacBook just like suddenly died. And so I was
Speaker 5:  like, you know what? I'm gonna do it. I'm gonna use my iPad. And, and you
Speaker 5:  know, I was on the iOS 26 beta, so I had all the new
Speaker 5:  windowing stuff, the beauty of Liquid Glass.
Speaker 5:  I got a keyboard, I got a mouse all good. And yeah,
Speaker 5:  all it like, it, it is, it's incredible how close the experience gets,
Speaker 5:  right? I have Windows, it, it has multiple displays.
Speaker 5:  I'm using a mouse and keyboard, I'm tabbing between apps
Speaker 5:  and then they're just basic keyboard shortcuts that don't work. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Right. There's basic ways of controlling files that
Speaker 5:  I'm just like not capable of. And it's just these like little things every
Speaker 5:  like, you know, 30 seconds that are slowing me down a
Speaker 5:  little bit and a little bit and a little bit. And I, I think like
Speaker 5:  with Apple, I, I, I sort of see that a little bit more, right?
Speaker 5:  There are so many people who are iPhone first, it
Speaker 5:  makes sense to, to make a desktop that is very familiar to them
Speaker 5:  with Android, you know, the, the, there is a
Speaker 5:  default version of that for PCs And I think it is just Windows.
Speaker 5:  And I, I think if you are a Windows user, I don't know that you're looking
Speaker 5:  to change. I don't know what you're going to get out of this.
Speaker 4:  What's interesting is, I think, I think your your your point about how
Speaker 4:  there are a lot of people who like their first experiences than iPhone. I
Speaker 4:  think it's globally vastly more true with Android, right? Like there are
Speaker 4:  that's true Many more people who only have one device who use Android than
Speaker 4:  who use iOS. Like that's just true. But I think we're
Speaker 4:  also at a point now where like, I, I actually think Google might have had
Speaker 4:  a much better shot at this the first time it tried to do it, you
Speaker 4:  know, that were 10 years ago. But I think you, you look at it now and it's
Speaker 4:  like this, this whole sort of globe filled with people who
Speaker 4:  came online in like the, the late aughts and early
Speaker 4:  2010s that like huge rush of the smartphone market.
Speaker 4:  Those people now have entrenched behaviors. We've been doing this a long
Speaker 4:  time now. Yeah. The idea that there are, we can like retrain everyone how
Speaker 4:  to do new things was way more true 10 years ago than
Speaker 4:  it is now, right? Like I, the the example people always give me, And I really
Speaker 4:  like, is the, the Cordy keyboard, like the Cordy keyboard is, is bad
Speaker 4:  in, in every meaningful way. It is not the optimal keyboard
Speaker 4:  layout except we've all been using it for this long and it's not worth the
Speaker 4:  hassle to switch. And so I think this kind of thing where it's like, okay,
Speaker 4:  what if my laptop is, is also just a
Speaker 4:  collection of apps that, And I don't have a files
Speaker 4:  app and where do I download things like that stuff is entrenched now.
Speaker 4:  And, and even for the people for whom it was not, when Google first started
Speaker 4:  thinking about this, it is now. And so all this stuff like
Speaker 4:  Google did write about Chrome os, which has put everything in the browser
Speaker 4:  and make everything that, that actually runs against all of the things that
Speaker 4:  they're trying to do with Android. And so these things have just been so
Speaker 4:  far apart now that I think even if you can successfully put them together,
Speaker 4:  I don't know that that's actually the user behavior people are looking for.
Speaker 5:  Well, and to your point, you know, there, there absolutely is like a good
Speaker 5:  reason to be able to plug your Android phone into a
Speaker 5:  monitor and boom, now it's a desktop experience, right? If that's your only
Speaker 5:  device, that's, that's amazing. Sure. That's a, that's a huge upgrade for
Speaker 5:  the average person. What drives me crazy here is it's like, oh, okay, so
Speaker 5:  Google wants to do, wants to be able to do what Apple does where you can
Speaker 5:  seamlessly move between your phone and your laptop,
Speaker 5:  but they don't have, they don't control the operating system. So
Speaker 5:  somehow they need a piece of software that is on every single computer in
Speaker 5:  the world that allows you to move stuff from Android to your computer. Oh
Speaker 5:  wait, that's Google Chrome. Yeah. Everyone uses it just
Speaker 5:  Right. I don't understand why to this day
Speaker 5:  there is basically no, I, I mean I can't think of any communication between
Speaker 5:  my Pixel and Google Chrome, right? If Google Chrome could send
Speaker 5:  my notifications from Android, what an upgrade that would be, right?
Speaker 5:  If Google Chrome could take my calls from my Android phone, what, why can't
Speaker 5:  it do any of this? The, this is what is mind-boggling to
Speaker 5:  me.
Speaker 4:  I do think it's possible that you might have just pretty neatly described
Speaker 4:  the ideal outcome of this combination. Because like, if, if you take
Speaker 4:  it, it is Android, but it is the exact Chrome that runs
Speaker 4:  on your computer, which is essentially what ChromeOS is, right? Like it is,
Speaker 4:  it is an op a kind of janky file system built around
Speaker 4:  the full feature and arguably the best version of the Chrome
Speaker 4:  browser. And if you just, if you just do that
Speaker 4:  on top of Android in such a way that it is, it actually communicates
Speaker 4:  between devices, that would be amazing. It, like anybody who
Speaker 4:  uses Desktop Chrome on two computers can tell you, even that sucks,
Speaker 4:  right? Like, if, if I have a tab on my computer And I wanna look at it
Speaker 4:  on my other computer, there's a strong chance that's not gonna work the way
Speaker 4:  that it's supposed to. But like,
Speaker 5:  This
Speaker 4:  Is the thing, the idea, you're right about the idea it's
Speaker 5:  Close, it's, it's that that is their operating system. Yes. Right. Why
Speaker 5:  I don't understand, I don't understand why Chrome is so
Speaker 5:  siloed in that way when there's so much power
Speaker 5:  they could add to it and they, they have just like done nothing
Speaker 5:  there. And instead we've just for, for again, like for
Speaker 5:  a decade heard about how Android and Chrome OS might come together,
Speaker 5:  And I, it's just, it is fully unclear to me what problem this solves other
Speaker 5:  than perhaps simplifying some engineering structure
Speaker 5:  inside Google.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Yeah. If thi if this is a way to lay off a bunch of now redundant
Speaker 4:  end engineers, then that sucks And I don't care. Right?
Speaker 4:  I think I, it remains to ve seen, but Google is certainly, I think you're
Speaker 4:  right, making enough noise about this, that if they don't
Speaker 4:  ship something, it's gonna be the most embarrassing version of this. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yet
Speaker 5:  I, I think we are going to get a couple of like iffy
Speaker 5:  Android laptops and then we are going to forget about this. Yeah. That is
Speaker 5:  my, this might be shortsighted prediction, But that, that is what this feels
Speaker 5:  like. Well in
Speaker 4:  The context of all of this is Google made a big effort
Speaker 4:  in the Pixel book line, made a couple of really great devices and then stopped
Speaker 4:  making them. Yeah. And, and this would be, I mean just the, the
Speaker 4:  50000th pivot for Google's hardware ambitions. So like,
Speaker 4:  we'll see, let's talk about Apple for a second. On, on the topic of
Speaker 4:  convergence touchscreen MacBook, does this, does this
Speaker 4:  do anything for you? It seems, it seems real. I think we're gonna get it.
Speaker 5:  I, okay. I always thought people were ridiculous. They'd be like, oh my God,
Speaker 5:  I've been using my iPad so much that I started swiping on my MacBook. Ha
Speaker 5:  ha ha. And then I did it the other day and I'm just like, oh, shoot, they're
Speaker 5:  all right. A hundred percent right. It's just,
Speaker 5:  I I think when Apple started with this position
Speaker 5:  that they were like, it doesn't make sense to have a touchscreen and a laptop.
Speaker 5:  Like they're, they're, they're basically Right. It is true. It's
Speaker 4:  Not. Yeah. The gorilla arm thing is real. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It is real. And I think back, back in the day, it's like, yeah, like
Speaker 5:  that's not a standard mode of interaction. And nowadays I think it's, it's
Speaker 5:  just so expected that it's actually weird that the MacBook doesn't have that.
Speaker 5:  And I think like particularly as new users start to try these things
Speaker 5:  out, like is it's kind of just bewildering. Why, why wouldn't you?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. My experience has been, I use my computer
Speaker 4:  really differently when I'm just using it versus when it's like a social
Speaker 4:  thing, if that makes sense. So like
Speaker 5:  That's very true.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If I'm, if you And I are doing something together, being able to
Speaker 4:  reach out and scroll the page or, or that we can both do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Is is actually like cool and valuable and important. And
Speaker 4:  I've been thinking about this a lot because we've been, we spent the summer
Speaker 4:  house hunting and so like my life was just sending Zillow links back and
Speaker 4:  forth to my wife and really being able to sit there and like
Speaker 4:  scroll around and tap on things and, and move stuff around together is really
Speaker 4:  valuable. And it's like, there, there's a piece of the iPad experience that
Speaker 4:  is really nice that it is like a device you can put on the table in front
Speaker 4:  of two people and sort of use together in a way that a laptop is
Speaker 4:  not that at all. Like, I, you And I cannot use a laptop together in any
Speaker 4:  kind of like functional way. So just,
Speaker 4:  just for that reason alone, I think a touchscreen Mac
Speaker 4:  becomes really interesting.
Speaker 4:  There is a way in which everybody overshoots this and
Speaker 4:  it becomes hugely problematic, right? That like, suddenly it's like, okay,
Speaker 4:  what we actually want on the Mac is to run all of your iPad apps in
Speaker 4:  a native feeling way on the screen. And that's where the whole
Speaker 4:  like, do you really wanna sit there and draw on a screen with the
Speaker 4:  stylus on a, on a floppy laptop? Like that's a bad idea. So
Speaker 4:  it's like, there, there are a lot of ways this could go sideways, but I think
Speaker 4:  just the, the basic theory of it is exactly a Mac, but it has
Speaker 4:  a touchscreen. I'm actually into way more so
Speaker 4:  than like, let's figure out the exact middle of iPad and Mac for all the
Speaker 4:  reasons we were just talking about.
Speaker 5:  Completely agree. That's that's all I want. I just want to occasionally be
Speaker 5:  able to scroll a webpage with my finger, like that's which I is
Speaker 5:  not revolutionary, but I also don't think this tech is that expensive or
Speaker 5:  hard for them to implement at this point in time. It, it just, why
Speaker 5:  not? They've also, I think if you look at what they've been doing on the
Speaker 5:  iPad to make the iPad a little bit more Mac like, but work with touch, it's
Speaker 5:  like they, they've, they've got the user interface figured out. They can
Speaker 5:  bring this to the Mac. It's not gonna be that hard at this point.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And there's like, by the time there's a menu bar and the
Speaker 4:  stoplight menu on an iPad, you've run out of excuses to be like, oh, the
Speaker 4:  toch targets. Like, no, I don't, no one cares. It's gonna be fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Last thing we should talk about here before we get away from future gadgets
Speaker 4:  that may or may not exist. So interesting reporting this week from the
Speaker 4:  information about what OpenAI and Johnny Iver up to
Speaker 4:  suggesting that basically you, you can look at this news
Speaker 4:  a couple of ways. One is they have a bunch of really interesting ideas. They
Speaker 4:  might be building a smart speaker to put Chacha PT into. They might be developing
Speaker 4:  AI glasses, they're thinking about a voice recorder, they're thinking about
Speaker 4:  a pin.
Speaker 4:  That's one way of looking at it. Big ambitions, interesting project. They're
Speaker 4:  doing lots of hardware. The other way of looking at it is none of them have
Speaker 4:  any idea what to do. So they're just trying everybody else's ideas. They're
Speaker 4:  gonna build all of the things and put JY bt into it and be like, is this
Speaker 4:  anything? It's it's one of those,
Speaker 5:  No. Yeah. This is, I would say this is does not inspire confidence, right?
Speaker 5:  I I think like when, when they came out and it's like, you know, Johnny and
Speaker 5:  Sam, they're like, we've, we've got a vision. We understand what the future
Speaker 5:  of AI hardware is and all those other guys are fools. And if they, they keep
Speaker 5:  up that vision, maybe I'll believe them. But this, this reporting suggesting
Speaker 5:  that they're tinkering with a bunch of different things. No one has any idea,
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. That we are just going all the way back to the Alexa
Speaker 5:  era where Amazon was just like, Alexa in a clock.
Speaker 5:  Alexa in a fridge Alexa. Yes. And, and
Speaker 5:  you're like, I, I guess a And it, yes, it,
Speaker 5:  it does make sense to put Chay bt in some sort of hardware.
Speaker 5:  Is it going to be more revolutionary than an Echo speaker?
Speaker 5:  I'm not, I'm not sure if there is something out there. And it sure seems
Speaker 5:  like maybe they don't either.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I remember when the IO news first came out that Johnny,
Speaker 4:  Ivan Open AI were working on some hardware together. There were, there were
Speaker 4:  a lot of sort of different pieces of, of information out there. And
Speaker 4:  a lot of folks arrived at sort of the same basic idea of what these
Speaker 4:  two were probably making together, which was like a, a little
Speaker 4:  sort of, I don't know, portable sized speaker that you, you
Speaker 4:  can, that has a doc that you put it into when you're at your desk and you
Speaker 4:  can use it that way. It can be a, a home speaker that you talk to or you
Speaker 4:  can like, you know, clip it to your body and wear it around your neck or
Speaker 4:  something. So like the idea is that it is a little, a little speaker
Speaker 4:  microphone device that then attaches to a bunch of different things. It becomes
Speaker 4:  a bunch of different other things. Interesting idea, like you said, been
Speaker 4:  done a thousand times by a thousand companies integrating Google Assistant
Speaker 4:  and Alexa, like Harman Cardin is out there making this stuff. Yes. You know
Speaker 4:  what I mean? Like that it's just, it's not smart speakers are an
Speaker 4:  old idea and they've been a very successful idea, but they're not, this is
Speaker 4:  not some like, hugely new novel swing at the
Speaker 4:  hardware. And then to look at it and just say, okay, AI glasses, voice
Speaker 4:  recorder pin. Do you know what those three things are? Those are the only
Speaker 4:  ideas anybody else has about how these things are supposed to work. Like,
Speaker 4:  there, like you said, there are, there is nothing hugely novel
Speaker 4:  here, except I do think it's possible that this
Speaker 4:  combination of Johnny Ive and the love from team
Speaker 4:  and all of the, like access they'll have to OpenAI
Speaker 4:  means they can do it better. Right. And if there, there's a, there's a real
Speaker 4:  lesson in like, apple spent a lot of time doing other people's ideas a lot
Speaker 4:  better than the rest of them. Maybe that's it. But this, like you said, this
Speaker 4:  does not fill me with like gleeful joy about big new
Speaker 4:  ideas they have.
Speaker 5:  Well, and that's where it gets really interesting, right? Okay. Let's say
Speaker 5:  they make the, the nicest hardware in the market
Speaker 5:  for smart glasses. And let's say that chat GBD continues
Speaker 5:  to be the best AI assistant. Th both of these things seem
Speaker 5:  very, very plausible to me.
Speaker 5:  Does that still mean anything if they cannot get native access to your
Speaker 5:  phone? Right. Likes Great question. Ultimately that is still where
Speaker 5:  all your data lives. And if they're going to make a brand new
Speaker 5:  platform from scratch, even if you are the company behind chat GPT,
Speaker 5:  that is still a big uphill battle. And the AI era
Speaker 5:  has very much been a moment of upstarts being able to break
Speaker 5:  through by being able to do a bunch of things that these smartphones could
Speaker 5:  do without relying on them. But as soon as you
Speaker 5:  become a piece of hardware, you need to be able to do more for people.
Speaker 5:  You need to be able to do things that obfuscate
Speaker 5:  their phone. And it is not clear if they will be able to
Speaker 5:  do that in a way that, you know, apple will, even if they don't have
Speaker 5:  the best AI assistant
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They can connect to the internet. Like it's, yeah, it's such a simple
Speaker 4:  thing, right? Like I I, they don't charge me extra to connect to the internet
Speaker 4:  is going to be a big hurdle for anyone other than your phone maker
Speaker 4:  to climb. I totally agree. And so we, we shouldn't dwell on this 'cause we're
Speaker 4:  gonna have actually a lot to talk about in this space next week. Amazon's
Speaker 4:  having an event, I believe on Tuesday where we think they're
Speaker 4:  gonna reveal like whatever the next generation of Alexa hardware
Speaker 4:  is. This has been teased for a while. Panos Pane is up to stuff. We'll see
Speaker 4:  what they're doing. The Google Gemini Smart
Speaker 4:  Home stuff is all kicking off next week. So this idea of like non
Speaker 4:  phone devices doing AI things is
Speaker 4:  spinning up in a pretty big way. And I think we're, we're gonna see a lot
Speaker 4:  of new ideas about how all of this stuff works or we're gonna see that actually
Speaker 4:  no one has any new ideas about any of this stuff works,
Speaker 4:  but that's coming next week. So we, we should, let's, let's come back to
Speaker 4:  all this open AI stuff in a week and see who is actually having the most
Speaker 4:  interesting theories about any of this. We need to take a break because
Speaker 4:  we have TikTok stuff to talk about. And we cannot let this first cast be
Speaker 4:  19 hours long. So we're gonna take a break. We're gonna get Liz
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Liz Lipato ISS joining us. Hi Liz.
Speaker 11:  Hey, how's it going guys?
Speaker 4:  Liz, show us the cat. This is, this is the only reason you're here. Show,
Speaker 4:  show us the cat.
Speaker 11:  Oh, okay. Here's Jevs.
Speaker 5:  Oh, hey Jevs.
Speaker 11:  She's a good girl.
Speaker 4:  Jevs is going to be responsible for the low grade rumbling you hear for the
Speaker 4:  rest of this podcast. That's
Speaker 11:  Chiefs. Yeah, so she is, she is a little disgusted
Speaker 11:  with me and has moved from my lap to my feet where that's now where she's
Speaker 11:  sitting. So you may not hear the purring.
Speaker 4:  I like this for her. Alright, so you're here to talk about TikTok. And again,
Speaker 4:  just to, just to timestamp us right now a little bit, it is 11 o'clock
Speaker 4:  in the morning on Thursday. And this is not normally
Speaker 4:  an important piece of information, but I, there is a decent chance that between
Speaker 4:  now and when you hear this or watch this, there will have been
Speaker 4:  a executive order from the Trump administration from the White House about
Speaker 4:  a TikTok deal. But I think, and Liz, you, you should correct me if I'm wrong,
Speaker 4:  right up at the top, I think we know enough about what is about to happen,
Speaker 4:  that we can talk about it. It feels like we've, we've gotten most of the
Speaker 4:  information about whatever we're gonna know
Speaker 4:  that we can talk about it. Do you agree with that?
Speaker 11:  I also wanna add something to the timestamp, which is that it, okay, eight
Speaker 11:  o'clock in the morning And I have had a bunch of caffeine on an empty stomach,
Speaker 11:  so I feel beautiful and I'm gonna live forever
Speaker 4:  Peak, Liz, let's go,
Speaker 11:  Let's go. So here's the thing. We have some details about the deal, right?
Speaker 11:  Like we, we know that there's a consortium, it's like Oracle
Speaker 11:  Andreesen, Horowitz, Susquehanna International Group.
Speaker 11:  I think maybe even like the Murdochs are involved somehow,
Speaker 11:  and like Bite Dance retains around 20% and gets
Speaker 11:  diluted. We know,
Speaker 11:  gosh, what else do we know? We know that like the algorithm gets moved or
Speaker 11:  changed away from Chinese control. Question mark, question mark,
Speaker 11:  question mark. 'cause wasn't that the valuable thing? Question mark, question
Speaker 11:  mark, question mark. Let's
Speaker 4:  Put a pin in that because I would argue that is actually not a thing we know
Speaker 4:  and is hugely important. So let, let's come back to that. Phenomenal at,
Speaker 4:  at the end here. But
Speaker 11:  Like, even if none of this is permanent, I still think we're pretty
Speaker 11:  justified in talking about it because I just wanna do like a quick speed
Speaker 11:  round because we've been talking about the divestiture of
Speaker 11:  TikTok for like five years now at least. So how many
Speaker 11:  previous buyers do you guys remember go? Ooh,
Speaker 5:  I I feel like there was like a possibility of Microsoft at one point.
Speaker 4:  Oracle came up the first time. Yeah, that's another one. I know there was
Speaker 4:  another one, but those are the only two that are immediately coming to mind.
Speaker 5:  Perplexity pretended they were gonna buy it, I think. Oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  perplexity. Did Pinterest ever make a
Speaker 11:  Bid? My personal favorite was Walmart.
Speaker 11:  Oh, that's
Speaker 5:  Good.
Speaker 11:  So just with that background in mind,
Speaker 5:  This is a very serious Yeah. Venture.
Speaker 11:  We're gonna discuss this deal. I, I, I hesitate to tell you how serious
Speaker 11:  it is because like, honestly, I don't, I don't know. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So, okay. Can you give us the like
Speaker 4:  62nd version of the last five years? Because it, it's, as
Speaker 4:  we get to something that might seem like the end of this
Speaker 4:  story, I think it's useful to go back to the beginning of this story, which
Speaker 4:  started in the first Trump administration. Can you just walk us through it
Speaker 4:  a little bit?
Speaker 11:  Okay. So we have this like panic about China that's like
Speaker 11:  coming up in, you know, during the first Trump administration. And this
Speaker 11:  Chinese app has a hole on the nation's youngsters and it's
Speaker 11:  terrifying. And who knows what they're doing with their data,
Speaker 11:  which like PS for every like country outside of the US
Speaker 11:  is what the US is doing with Facebook and Instagram
Speaker 11:  and any, all of these other apps, but whatever, whatever. So there's
Speaker 11:  legislation that it has to be sold or it's gonna get banned and then it's
Speaker 11:  not sold. And we have these sort of like procession of investors
Speaker 11:  that we had talked through, right? You know, the, the
Speaker 11:  maybe deals with Microsoft and Walmart and
Speaker 11:  Oracle And I, I'm probably missing a couple.
Speaker 11:  And anyway, Donald Trump comes into office as we hit the deadline.
Speaker 11:  And if I remember right, TikTok actually, it's pulled from a bunch of
Speaker 11:  app stores because it's like not legal to have
Speaker 11:  TikTok in your app store anymore. And so
Speaker 11:  then we enter this bizarre territory of like,
Speaker 11:  Donald Trump's like, well, we're gonna extend the deadline And
Speaker 11:  I promise nobody's gonna prosecute anybody for this
Speaker 11:  so you can put it back in the app store. 'cause I guess in the intervening
Speaker 11:  years he's changed his mind about TikTok and he loves it now, I don't know.
Speaker 11:  And so we've had this deadline that just keeps getting pushed back and
Speaker 11:  pushed back. It's like 90 day deadlines where it keeps being
Speaker 11:  like another 90 days. Another 90 days,
Speaker 11:  which like, by the way,
Speaker 11:  I don't know that that's legal either. Like, I don't know that that is
Speaker 11:  how
Speaker 11:  anything works in this country, but it seems to be how things work in this
Speaker 11:  country now.
Speaker 11:  Cool. So that's where we are, is this, you
Speaker 11:  know, like this deadline has come up, it's been pushed back another time
Speaker 11:  and we're getting these details of like, this time it's real. This time
Speaker 11:  we have this consortium investors
Speaker 11:  and we're, we're really gonna get it done. We're gonna get some stuff signed.
Speaker 11:  And then most recently we've heard about this Oracle deal with this consortium
Speaker 11:  of investors,
Speaker 4:  Right? So the the biggest thing I wanna talk about with you in particular
Speaker 4:  is this consortium of investors. Because I think I I,
Speaker 4:  in a certain way, if, if the Trump administration had just sold
Speaker 4:  TikTok to Microsoft, which is like an insane sentence to say out loud,
Speaker 4:  but if that had just happened, I think I would, I would understand the dynamic,
Speaker 4:  right? It's like whether this solves the problem that
Speaker 4:  Congress is worried about or that everyone claims they're trying to solve
Speaker 4:  debatable, and we should talk about that. But it it, like one big company
Speaker 4:  buys this other big company is like, I, I understand that this feels
Speaker 4:  different and it feels like it's being done differently. And specifically
Speaker 4:  this group of people that are going to be in charge of this app
Speaker 4:  now, which like you mentioned includes Oracle, which is run by
Speaker 4:  the one of the richest people in the world. Larry Ellison, who is a very
Speaker 4:  long standing friend of Donald Trump.
Speaker 4:  There's also Andreesen Horowitz, which is run by people like
Speaker 4:  Mark Andreesen who have been very loud supporters of Donald Trump, silver
Speaker 4:  Lake, like lots of these organizations that are very Trump friendly.
Speaker 4:  This all just feels like it is, it is just
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump giving TikTok to his friends. And I don't, I
Speaker 4:  don't know how else to put it other than that, but I, I just like, how are
Speaker 4:  you looking at the sort of power dynamics at play here?
Speaker 11:  Welcome to the gangster tech era, baby. Like that's what we're looking at,
Speaker 11:  right? We've talked about this a little bit. All of these tech mos
Speaker 11:  who have been cosing up to Donald Trump, because he's been very clear that
Speaker 11:  if you're his friend, he'll do stuff for you, but if you're not his friend,
Speaker 11:  he will hurt you. And so we've watched
Speaker 11:  Jeff Bezos basically got the Washington Post.
Speaker 11:  We've seen Elon Musk donate an insane amount of money to his
Speaker 11:  campaign and then like literally go into the White House and work from
Speaker 11:  there for a while. We've seen Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 11:  do some of the most humiliating like dances I
Speaker 11:  think I've ever seen to convince Donald Trump. He's really maga
Speaker 11:  he's really serious about manhood, guys. And so, you know, this
Speaker 11:  is, this is, we're watching these guys jockey and like they were all at
Speaker 11:  the inauguration. And one of the things that I think is really interesting
Speaker 11:  is that they all have different needs and different things they want from
Speaker 11:  the administration. Those needs conflict. And so
Speaker 11:  one of the things that I'm kind of keeping an eye on with the Ellison
Speaker 11:  sale is his relationship
Speaker 11:  with Facebook because the biggest competitor for
Speaker 11:  Facebook, I guess Mark's calling it meta now, I'm sorry,
Speaker 11:  I should say meta
Speaker 4:  Sure
Speaker 11:  Is TikTok, like TikTok is
Speaker 11:  meta's entire argument that they are not engaging in a
Speaker 11:  monopoly and they shouldn't be broken up. And so there's,
Speaker 11:  there's something interesting happening there that I think we're gonna continue
Speaker 11:  to see as, as, as this deal goes forward.
Speaker 11:  Obviously Andreessen Horowitz has positions with both
Speaker 11:  meta and its should this deal go through its major
Speaker 11:  competitor TikTok? That's fascinating.
Speaker 11:  But beyond that, I mean, it is a really clear signal that if you're friends
Speaker 11:  with Donald Trump, you get stuff. And I expect that
Speaker 11:  there's going to be sort of some more jockeying to like have private dinners
Speaker 11:  with Donald Trump to get more things, especially as we're watching, you
Speaker 11:  know, the Google antitrust trial part, whatever taking place
Speaker 11:  where we're trying to determine like whether, you know, it's
Speaker 11:  even feasible to break Google up, like what the remedies are, those things.
Speaker 11:  IIII think it's a pretty strong signal that we're gonna see
Speaker 11:  some court intrigue. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's also this very perverse thing happening with the ownership where
Speaker 5:  we're going from TikTok, which is a, you know,
Speaker 5:  ostensibly standalone company that is owned by another Chinese company,
Speaker 5:  which therefore has, you know, pressures on it from the Chinese government
Speaker 5:  to TikTok, which is ostensibly a standalone company owned by a bunch
Speaker 5:  of conservative pals of Donald Trump, which
Speaker 5:  was only allowed because the conservative US government
Speaker 5:  made it happen. And so, listen, I'm not trying
Speaker 5:  to draw a line between China and the US being the same
Speaker 5:  in those respects, but we do still end up with a version of
Speaker 5:  TikTok that is going to be heavily influenced by its backers
Speaker 5:  and its backers have a very specific point of view in this case.
Speaker 11:  You know, it's funny that you mentioned that Jake, because Rupert
Speaker 11:  Murdoch's involvement reminds me of a previous Republican administration
Speaker 11:  where Rupert Murdoch got a fast tracked citizenship in order
Speaker 11:  to buy more US TV stations.
Speaker 11:  I think that was Reagan. So this is not the first time that we've
Speaker 11:  seen a Republican administration favoring a media
Speaker 11:  environment that is potentially very friendly to them. And I think given
Speaker 11:  what we've seen with Elon Musk's ownership of what the company
Speaker 11:  that used to be Twitter now
Speaker 11:  XI think there's a, a a, a good reason
Speaker 11:  to be sort of skeptical about what these investors are going to do to
Speaker 11:  TikTok. Well,
Speaker 4:  And I think this is where the Ellison become, I think the, the sort of
Speaker 4:  central figures in this story, right? Because you it at the same time this
Speaker 4:  is happening, you have
Speaker 4:  David Ellison, Larry's son by all accounts with
Speaker 4:  this essentially the oversight and financial backing of his father
Speaker 4:  buying Paramount, getting control of CBS
Speaker 4:  news rapidly overhauling all of
Speaker 4:  the ways that they think about everything apparently in process to
Speaker 4:  acquire Barry Weiss and the free press and put Barry Weiss in some
Speaker 4:  meaningful charge of CBS news, which will change the ideological bent of
Speaker 4:  CBS news in a pretty immediate and huge way. Also
Speaker 4:  bidding for Warner Brothers discovery, which would put them in charge of
Speaker 4:  CNN. So you have the same company which rolls up
Speaker 4:  to the same person in charge of TikTok,
Speaker 4:  C-B-S-H-B-O-C-N-N, and then
Speaker 4:  doing all of these giant deals with AI companies. It's, so you, you, we've
Speaker 4:  essentially put one person who is a
Speaker 4:  long-term friend and supporter of Donald Trump in charge of the media,
Speaker 4:  like in a, in a real and straightforward way, in a way that never
Speaker 4:  would've been possible until right now with this president.
Speaker 11:  There's also one more Ellison that I, I think the
Speaker 11:  media has forgotten about, and it's Megan Ellison who owns Anna
Speaker 11:  Perna pictures, right? So that's one more arm of the sort of
Speaker 11:  media octopus we're talking about. Look, this
Speaker 11:  is the sort of thing that William Randolph Hurst would've like
Speaker 11:  loved. Like, this is, this is,
Speaker 11:  you know, yes. Really remarkable stuff. And
Speaker 11:  in a different era we might be talking about antitrust, but obviously that's
Speaker 11:  not going to move forward under Donald Trump. It's one of the reasons the
Speaker 11:  tech moguls preferred him. So I do think that that is a really
Speaker 11:  fascinating thing that Larry Ellison in his old age has
Speaker 11:  decided to be William Randolph Hearst. I don't know where that goes.
Speaker 11:  And
Speaker 11:  I do think it's also interesting because one of the ongoing
Speaker 11:  complaints that the tech industry has had about media
Speaker 11:  is that the media is too hard on tech. There's too
Speaker 11:  much negative reporting, there's too much investigative
Speaker 11:  journalism. We're constantly badmouthing 'em. We're not their
Speaker 11:  friends.
Speaker 11:  And to be real, you know, I don't know that
Speaker 11:  the media should be anybody's friends, but especially friends of the powerful,
Speaker 11:  I firmly believe that part of the job is
Speaker 11:  comforting the afflicted and afflicting the comfortable.
Speaker 11:  But that is, that has been the ongoing complaint since, I
Speaker 11:  don't know, since Theranos, I think
Speaker 4:  Was, was the media wrong about Theranos?
Speaker 11:  No. Yeah, that's, that's the problem. Like, as we're
Speaker 11:  watching this media environment change and be owned by a tech mogul
Speaker 11:  and a group of people who've been very vocal about how they
Speaker 11:  don't like the way that reporting on their investments is tanking their
Speaker 11:  investments, I begin to wonder separately
Speaker 11:  from the political implications about the defanging
Speaker 11:  of the American news media when it comes to doing critical
Speaker 11:  reporting on one of the most important industries in our country.
Speaker 4:  All of this stuff is just happening so simultaneously that it's almost bizarre.
Speaker 4:  Like, you, you can't really look at this stuff and not also think about what's
Speaker 4:  going on with Jimmy Kimmel and, and Disney. And there's just this
Speaker 4:  like, it's, it's not even quiet shift. It is, it
Speaker 4:  is a naked loud shift in how the government has decided
Speaker 4:  to treat the media and to bend it to its own particular
Speaker 4:  will. And
Speaker 4:  the Kimmel thing is like, is and isn't working for the government. I would
Speaker 4:  say Jimmy Kimmel came back to huge ratings, like
Speaker 4:  spent a lot of time talking about free speech, but then like a lot
Speaker 4:  of people in America didn't see that because companies like Sinclair and
Speaker 4:  Nexstar who either have business dealings or political alignment with the
Speaker 4:  Trump administration continue to not air it. And so we're, we're just in
Speaker 4:  this place of like, all of this stuff has moved so
Speaker 4:  quickly and so aggressively that I feel like we're, I I'm
Speaker 4:  still trying to wrap my head around how gigantic that particular
Speaker 4:  shift has been. And, and this is the reason I keep bringing this up in the,
Speaker 4:  in the course of TikTok is like, we spent five years being like, TikTok
Speaker 4:  is the future of the media, right? This is how young people get information.
Speaker 4:  This is how young people get news. This was the thing that everybody was
Speaker 4:  so worried about in the first place all the way back in 2020. The
Speaker 4:  idea that this is a crucial information source for young people.
Speaker 4:  And one of the big inciting events was, was October 7th. And this question
Speaker 4:  of what information are people getting about what's happening in Gaza
Speaker 4:  with Israel and Palestine? What, what are they understanding about
Speaker 4:  this situation and how are they responding? And the, the question of like,
Speaker 4:  are people seeing pro-Palestine stuff or pro-Israel stuff
Speaker 4:  on TikTok was like a big part of what people were debating about
Speaker 4:  how quote unquote, China is controlling the
Speaker 4:  information flow to people in the United States. That became this whole big
Speaker 4:  thing. And what is actually happening is that has spiraled out into the rest
Speaker 4:  of the media and is now coming crashing back to TikTok five years
Speaker 4:  later. And it's just, it, it is
Speaker 4:  like, maybe to some extent this is like the crowning of TikTok is like, yep,
Speaker 4:  TikTok is the media now, so we're also gonna give it to Larry Ellison.
Speaker 11:  You know, it's interesting to me
Speaker 11:  how every Republican accusation turns into a confession
Speaker 11:  because for years now they've been complaining about PBS
Speaker 11:  and, and, and NPR as state media
Speaker 11:  and you know, those are partially federally funded. So much
Speaker 11:  so that like there we're now seeing public radio stations shutting
Speaker 11:  down because their funding has been cut by the federal
Speaker 11:  government. But
Speaker 11:  you know, those were operations that I think were operating as in good faith
Speaker 11:  as best they could, and they were decentralized and local and
Speaker 11:  usually produced for a local community's needs.
Speaker 11:  And what we're getting instead is a massive
Speaker 11:  sprawling super corporation owned by Larry Allison who is one of
Speaker 11:  the president's biggest supporters, so it's privatized
Speaker 11:  state media, which, you know, that's not really new.
Speaker 11:  I mean, that's a big part of how Sylvia Berlusconi kept control of
Speaker 11:  Italy for so long was that he was a media mogul.
Speaker 11:  So maybe we we're, we're in our burse era. I don't know.
Speaker 11:  But yeah, I definitely think this is partially the crowning of TikTok. And
Speaker 11:  I also think it may be the end of TikTok because as,
Speaker 11:  as, as I understand it, there is a possibility
Speaker 11:  that people will have to switch to a new app. And
Speaker 11:  we all know that like as soon as you introduce that kind of friction,
Speaker 11:  people then make a decision and they may not download it.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I'm so glad you brought this up because I think, Jake, I think
Speaker 4:  you mentioned this the last time we were talking about those sort of, will
Speaker 4:  they, won't they of TikTok and, and you made a ship of thesis
Speaker 4:  reference, which is basically like, if, if you take every part of TikTok
Speaker 4:  and change it, but you still call it TikTok. Is it still TikTok? And this
Speaker 4:  is where I think also the question of what happens to the algorithm becomes
Speaker 4:  really important, right? Because the algorithm at the center of TikTok has
Speaker 4:  been one of, if not the biggest
Speaker 4:  question, it was a big part of the reason it got banned, right? The, the
Speaker 4:  sort of two arguments against TikTok are, it is an app collecting a lot
Speaker 4:  of data on US users, which I find completely
Speaker 4:  non-credible because like if you, if you wanna collect a lot of data on US
Speaker 4:  internet users, there are actually infinite ways to do it that are easier
Speaker 4:  than creating a really successful social media platform. I don't like, I
Speaker 4:  don't buy that at all. The idea of TikTok as
Speaker 4:  really important, really powerful disseminator of information with a
Speaker 4:  really, really well tuned and magical feeling algorithm that
Speaker 4:  a lot of people have responded to super real and has also become
Speaker 4:  a big part of the underlying debate about what's gonna happen here. So
Speaker 4:  this, I would say at this point, 11:21 AM on Thursday morning,
Speaker 4:  the thing we don't know is the fate of the algorithm. And there's been a
Speaker 4:  bunch of reporting kind of on both sides. One says the,
Speaker 4:  the TikTok us, whatever this new thing will be called, will
Speaker 4:  license the algorithm from by dance and from
Speaker 4:  China. What that means, who knows, there's also a world in which
Speaker 4:  they basically get a copy of the algorithm as it currently exists and then
Speaker 4:  sort of fork it and go from there. And then there's a version of it that
Speaker 4:  is essentially like they have to rebuild this whole thing from scratch. It
Speaker 4:  just gets to be called TikTok and they get to keep the 170 million United States
Speaker 4:  users in any of those cases. It seems very clear to me that the
Speaker 4:  TikTok people in the United States experience will be
Speaker 4:  completely meaningfully different from day one than
Speaker 4:  the TikTok they have been experiencing so far. Jake, am I, am I like
Speaker 4:  overstating this? Whether it's, it might be a new app, which I think would
Speaker 4:  be a, a huge gating factor for a lot of people, but like
Speaker 4:  TikTok controlled by Oracle is inevitably
Speaker 4:  going to be different than TikTok controlled by, by dance. And the, the extent
Speaker 4:  to which it'll be different, I think remains to be somewhat seen depending
Speaker 4:  on what the algorithmic control actually looks like. But
Speaker 4:  it is going to change in a big way immediately.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Well, I think it is number one, optimistic to assume that a Trump press
Speaker 5:  conference is going to be clarifying on this fair.
Speaker 5:  However, like a hundred percent right? This is going to
Speaker 5:  meaningfully change TikTok, TikTok is not going to be the same, and
Speaker 5:  any one of these changes would be a big deal. Will the US users have access
Speaker 5:  to tiktoks from foreign users at all that 'cause that's a huge
Speaker 5:  chunk of content and a huge chunk of variety that you won't gain access to.
Speaker 5:  I don't know, maybe it's just some dudes over in Turkey who are
Speaker 5:  splicing clips of like the equalizer together,
Speaker 5:  right? Like I don't, I don't know that,
Speaker 4:  Is that what you watch on TikTok? Jake? Be honest.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I'm not finished yet, but Right. But it'll
Speaker 5:  find me in the algorithm, right? But like the TikTok algorithm is
Speaker 5:  everything and if it's gonna have less content and their
Speaker 5:  algorithm is gonna be changing and like, not for nothing, if the algorithm
Speaker 5:  is, I don't know, like getting some, getting some nudges from these new investors,
Speaker 5:  things might be changing, right? And there are a million
Speaker 5:  alternatives to TikTok at this point. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I I go back and forth on this and I think on the one hand,
Speaker 4:  a thing that is different now than it was five years ago is that TikTok is
Speaker 4:  not the only kind of game in town on this front. Like to some extent
Speaker 4:  reels has done a very good job of just ripping off TikTok
Speaker 4:  Pixel by pixel. YouTube is attempting to do the same thing
Speaker 4:  to, I would say varying levels of success. But the idea
Speaker 4:  of TikTok, I think is less sort of uniquely
Speaker 4:  Powerful as it once was. At the same time, these other companies
Speaker 4:  have had five years now to build a thing that is
Speaker 4:  compelling to people as TikTok. And they have just utterly failed to
Speaker 4:  do it like it is TikTok is, if anything, more
Speaker 4:  culturally central than it has ever been. And so I think I
Speaker 4:  spent time a couple of years ago being like, okay, well, like
Speaker 4:  TikTok hasn't as a lead in building a really great, really compelling algorithm,
Speaker 4:  but a it's publishing a lot of information about how it works in order to
Speaker 4:  satisfy US regulators, but it's also
Speaker 4:  just like these leads don't last forever. Other companies catch up, things
Speaker 4:  are gonna change. No one has caught up. TikTok is still winning in a, in
Speaker 4:  a big, huge important way despite all of this chaos. And so
Speaker 4:  I, I think in some ways it is more high
Speaker 4:  stakes than ever and it's more unbelievable than
Speaker 4:  ever that Oracle will just show up and keep doing as good a job. I just like,
Speaker 4:  it just seems impossible to imagine to me.
Speaker 5:  Well, I, I, I mean, and that is the question, right? If, if it is an app
Speaker 5:  that is merely named TikTok, but it has less content than TikTok and a
Speaker 5:  worse algorithm than TikTok, what you're just describing is Instagram reels.
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah, okay. Like, will will people continue to use that? Like
Speaker 5:  probably will it grow in the same way? Will it be as culturally important
Speaker 5:  in the same way? I'm not sure. And And I I the fact that
Speaker 5:  Oracle and Larry Ellison and all these folks are, are going to have like
Speaker 5:  a lot of say in it and they a lot of cash to make back from it, like
Speaker 5:  things are going to change.
Speaker 11:  I also wanna add, you know,
Speaker 11:  there are a bunch of people who have businesses
Speaker 11:  that are based largely on TikTok content, right?
Speaker 11:  So you change the algorithms so that like,
Speaker 11:  in any way, you alter this in any way, so that TikTok is less
Speaker 11:  compelling. All of those content creators go someplace else because
Speaker 11:  they still need to make money. Like there is this real
Speaker 11:  important constituency of people because most people don't
Speaker 11:  post, you know, we're freaks like people who
Speaker 11:  post are freaks. Like we're, that's not most of the internet.
Speaker 11:  And so these people who are essentially like the TV channels of
Speaker 11:  TikTok, the professionals,
Speaker 11:  what happens if it's not as compelling to them because that is
Speaker 11:  again, more lost content. And you know, they do have options,
Speaker 11:  right? Like they, there is YouTube shorts, which I'm sure like
Speaker 11:  Google can figure out how to make that more compelling if they think about
Speaker 11:  it for a minute and can actually make a decision through all the layers
Speaker 11:  of the bureaucracy there. You know, there's Instagram
Speaker 11:  reels. If you think that Mark Zuckerberg isn't going to take advantage of
Speaker 11:  this confusion, you haven't like paid any attention to Meta ever.
Speaker 11:  And then there's also of course the possibility that, you know, something
Speaker 11:  else springs up. So, you know, there is also like the potential
Speaker 11:  for throwing the door open to some competitor we haven't imagined
Speaker 11:  yet.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it seems, I think I it to the extent that this is like a,
Speaker 4:  a super shortsighted strategy on, on
Speaker 4:  all sides here, I think it is useful to point out that both
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump and Larry Ellison are in their eighties and are, are probably
Speaker 4:  not spending a ton of time worrying about the long-term future of TikTok,
Speaker 4:  but I, yeah, I think we're, we're in this phase where it, it just seems
Speaker 4:  very hard to me to imagine that TikTok just keeps
Speaker 4:  being TikTok at the end of this. And it is like there,
Speaker 4:  I I can't figure out what it is. And I think part of what will be so interesting
Speaker 4:  about this transition is figuring out what it was that Bite dance was
Speaker 4:  doing that is so hard to replace because everybody else has been trying to
Speaker 4:  reverse engineer this for five years and no one has done it. And I think,
Speaker 4:  Liz, you're right that Mark Zuckerberg and Co are
Speaker 4:  pouring probably more energy into it with more success. Like reels is working
Speaker 4:  to the point that like, it's pretty clear that reels is the future of meta
Speaker 4:  in a really important way. That company is all in on reels as a thing.
Speaker 4:  Reels is not as good as TikTok. It's just not, And I could not sit
Speaker 4:  here and explain to you why. And I think it's gonna be really interesting
Speaker 4:  to see these very powerful, very rich people try to figure
Speaker 4:  that out in real time before everybody gets bored and goes somewhere else.
Speaker 4:  Because I think the, the timeline to pull that off is short
Speaker 4:  and high risk.
Speaker 11:  I have one other thought here, which is, again, related to Rupert
Speaker 11:  Murdoch. I know this is shocking for you guys that I have Murdoch thoughts,
Speaker 11:  but you may remember we're old enough to remember
Speaker 11:  MySpace, which was for a time a really promising
Speaker 11:  social media platform. It was a place where people were, were especially
Speaker 11:  discovering music, right? Like much like TikTok and then
Speaker 11:  Rupert Murdoch bought it and Facebook happened
Speaker 11:  and MySpace died.
Speaker 11:  And there are any of a number of reasons why that could have
Speaker 11:  happened, right? One of them was maybe the way that Facebook got rolled
Speaker 11:  out, one of them was that Facebook was easier for people to interact with
Speaker 11:  because you didn't have to have any skills to like enter your, you
Speaker 11:  know, details into what was essentially like a skinned spreadsheet
Speaker 11:  just being real. Yeah. But you know, like there was this sort of market
Speaker 11:  for people to be able to make their own website without having to like learn
Speaker 11:  any kind of HTML or any other sort of coding skills. And that was like the
Speaker 11:  market that Facebook won.
Speaker 11:  And so I am not saying that Rupert Murdoch's
Speaker 11:  involvement in this deal is a bad oven because maybe it's not.
Speaker 11:  But on the other hand, you know, the, the track record with
Speaker 11:  social media companies for him is not great.
Speaker 4:  Do you guys ever follow MySpace Tom on Instagram? MySpace, Tom
Speaker 4:  did life correctly, sold his company to
Speaker 4:  Rupert Murdoch for a ton of money and is now just like a world
Speaker 4:  traveling photographer that nobody ever hears about. And it is like my guy
Speaker 4:  crushed it. He was everybody's best friend on MySpace and then just disappeared
Speaker 4:  off the face of the earth with all of his money. And I just wanna say congratulations
Speaker 4:  to MySpace, Tom, for absolutely getting one over on Murdock. He
Speaker 4:  could have been sitting in front of Congress right now answering questions.
Speaker 4:  Seriously. This is, this is, yeah. Yeah. I would rather have, I would rather
Speaker 4:  be an Instagram photographer, frankly.
Speaker 4:  All right. I think we, we should we, we can leave this alone, Liz, you're
Speaker 4:  gonna have to come back when we have more answers, which will be never
Speaker 4:  actually Liz's. Just quickly do this before we, we take a break.
Speaker 4:  I, if you just had to vote right now, real or not real, this is
Speaker 4:  happening or this is not happening. Liz, is this happening or is this not
Speaker 4:  happening? The TikTok deal once and for all.
Speaker 11:  You know, I think this one might happen. I mean, maybe I'm making a fool
Speaker 11:  of myself and somebody's listening to this like Friday on their laughing,
Speaker 11:  but that's what I'm hoping for. I mean, that would be, that would be great.
Speaker 11:  It wouldn't be the first time I've been wrong. But the reason I
Speaker 11:  think this one is happening is because it is Donald Trump's
Speaker 11:  cronies and we do see, you know, this pattern which expresses
Speaker 11:  itself through like him pressuring people to, among other things,
Speaker 11:  bring charges against Jim Comey
Speaker 11:  of, of basically, you know, the imperial presidency. And
Speaker 11:  you know, this, this sort of mafioso idea that like if
Speaker 11:  you're with me enough, you get some of the spoils of
Speaker 11:  American Empire. So that to me suggests that this deal is real.
Speaker 11:  If it weren't Larry Ellison, I'd be a little more skeptical, but
Speaker 11:  I, I think that Donald Trump probably owes Larry Ellison pretty
Speaker 11:  big at this point.
Speaker 4:  Jake, what do you think? I think, think this
Speaker 5:  Is real. My suspicion though is it's probably still gonna be several
Speaker 5:  more months before any of this actually happens. And my suspicion is
Speaker 5:  also that a bunch of things are going to change in that time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think, I think I, I tend to agree, I think this is going to happen.
Speaker 4:  I believe it was on September 16th that Trump delayed another 90 days,
Speaker 4:  which I think is telling the, the ban that clearly is
Speaker 4:  not a ban and was never a ban. And this is all transparently illegal and
Speaker 4:  ridiculous. I think a deal will get done.
Speaker 4:  I think it's important to say, I don't think it will solve anybody's actual
Speaker 4:  problems with TikTok. Like if you were a person who believes in the national
Speaker 4:  security risks of TikTok, there is nothing that we've learned so far that
Speaker 4:  suggests to me that is going to get better. It might be a different group
Speaker 4:  of people issuing propaganda at you. Hooray.
Speaker 4:  I don't know. This is, this is just what we're doing now. But anyway, this
Speaker 4:  is, I think, I think you're both right, that we are certainly not done talking
Speaker 4:  about whatever the machinations of this deal are going to be. And Liz, I
Speaker 4:  also, I'm gonna need you to work on a Larry Ellison impression that I would
Speaker 4:  like you to debut on The Vergecast at some point in the near future.
Speaker 11:  So you feel that, okay, but I'm gonna need a yacht. So
Speaker 11:  if I can just expense a yacht, that would be great.
Speaker 4:  That's true. It does it, it will feel disingenuous if you're not doing it
Speaker 4:  from a yacht.
Speaker 5:  Neli will approve that. We can't, we have to be
Speaker 5:  responsible
Speaker 4:  As Neli always says, we will compromise our journalistic integrity, but only
Speaker 4:  for boat money. So if you want to give us boat money, get at us.
Speaker 4:  Liz, we, you stick around and do some lightning round with us real fast before
Speaker 4:  we get
Speaker 11:  Out. Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 4:  Good. All right, we're gonna take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  speaker update. And it's a new party speaker from Anker, the company that
Speaker 4:  you know of as the one who makes all the cool giant batteries that everybody
Speaker 4:  carries around. Anker has made a series of projectors that
Speaker 4:  are very cool. This one is a projector inside of a
Speaker 4:  party speaker, and it is the greatest thing I've ever seen. I want you both
Speaker 4:  to just imagine a rolly suitcase that you would roll through an airport.
Speaker 4:  And then I want you to put four detachable speakers
Speaker 4:  inside of it, each one looking like something that TSA would have
Speaker 4:  a lot of thoughts about if you were to roll this through the airport. And
Speaker 4:  then I want you to imagine right in the middle, a little, a little thing
Speaker 4:  that opens up to reveal a projector. It is, this is
Speaker 4:  an all in one rolly party speaker
Speaker 4:  surround sound projector. And it is the greatest idea I've ever heard in
Speaker 4:  my life. It's gonna cost $5,000. It's called the Sound Core
Speaker 4:  Nebula X one Pro. You can get it on Kickstarter now for
Speaker 4:  $3,000, which is somewhat alarmingly an incredible
Speaker 4:  deal. But this is the single most ambitions and terrific party speaker
Speaker 4:  I think I've ever seen. And I will not be buying it, but I love to pieces
Speaker 4:  that it exists.
Speaker 5:  I I cannot get behind Eli's love of a, of a typical
Speaker 5:  party speaker. This thing on the other hand, fully into it, yes,
Speaker 5:  you listen five grant, you can't put a price on this kind of convenience.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 4:  Can. It's 5,000 bucks. That's the beauty of it.
Speaker 11:  So I I do have a question about the specs here. Okay,
Speaker 11:  is there a disco ball?
Speaker 4:  So, okay, I'm actually very glad you brought this up. I will see the one
Speaker 4:  distinct failing of this thing is there don't appear to be multicolored lights
Speaker 4:  anyway, which I think you could actually argue
Speaker 4:  makes it not a party speaker at all. It's just, it's potentially just a very
Speaker 4:  large speaker.
Speaker 4:  And that is, that's a real shame. Anker like attempted to make a thing that
Speaker 4:  is serious and that is a, a huge mistake. I don't believe it will do
Speaker 4:  any cool lights at you at all. And I find that incredibly upsetting.
Speaker 4:  But you know, for $5,000, there's only so much you can get. My favorite thing
Speaker 4:  about this is there's a graphic on their Kickstarter page that says, it shows
Speaker 4:  the, the Nebula and like a 16.7
Speaker 4:  foot screen and it's like this is
Speaker 4:  $3,698 versus the traditional cost
Speaker 4:  of a $4,000 projector, $200 wireless microphones, which
Speaker 4:  why $3,000 Dolby Atmos speakers, a hundred dollars projector
Speaker 4:  stand and a $2,000 inflatable screen, which is apparently the other
Speaker 4:  option for if you wanna like watch movies in your backyard. And that's
Speaker 4:  $9,000. And this, I would say is Anker just really
Speaker 4:  understanding how real people live their real lives And I respect them for
Speaker 4:  that. Anyway, that is your party speaker update for the day.
Speaker 4:  Liz, you're up next. What's your first lightning round?
Speaker 11:  So, oh God, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 11:  Brendan Carr. Gentlemen, I'm, I'm,
Speaker 11:  please, let's hear your thoughts on Brendan Carr. Just the name. 'cause
Speaker 11:  I saw some faces.
Speaker 4:  Are we doing a neli free episode of America's number one podcast with own
Speaker 4:  podcast? Brendan Carr is a dummy. Is this, is it time?
Speaker 11:  Look, if anybody was gonna do it in the substitute for Neli on Brendan Carr
Speaker 11:  as a dummy, who, who else was it gonna be? We're
Speaker 4:  Thrilled
Speaker 11:  To have you. So, you know, he's got this ongoing war on the first amendment
Speaker 11:  that he mostly seems to be winning. And the latest
Speaker 11:  iteration of this is
Speaker 11:  threatening
Speaker 11:  Disney because he doesn't like
Speaker 11:  something that Jimmy Kimmel said. Disney yanking
Speaker 11:  Jimmy Kimmel.
Speaker 11:  And then consumer outcry, Disney
Speaker 11:  reinstating Jimmy Kimmel, Brendan Carr being
Speaker 11:  like, it wasn't a threat really. I
Speaker 11:  was just saying things on this conservative podcast who knew
Speaker 11:  that anybody would take it seriously.
Speaker 11:  Kimmel by the way, is still not being aired on a number of networks
Speaker 11:  because Sinclair and Nexstar, they have a blanket ban
Speaker 11:  on him. So good luck to Jimmy Kimmel out there.
Speaker 11:  One of the things that happened, of course is the Streisand effect. So Kimmel
Speaker 11:  came back to huge ratings and just spent the entire episode
Speaker 11:  making fun of Donald Trump. And now the president is threatening him
Speaker 11:  directly. So that's cool. So that's, that's our, Brendan
Speaker 11:  Carr is a big dummy update is that he has just
Speaker 11:  platformed Jimmy Kimmel in a huge way. Congratulations Brendan.
Speaker 11:  Can
Speaker 4:  I, can I just read you the thing that, that Donald Trump posted on truth
Speaker 4:  social about this, which I think to me is like just a perfect
Speaker 4:  encapsulation of what the Trump administration is trying to
Speaker 4:  do and why everyone who is giving into it is a doofus. Can I
Speaker 4:  just read you this truth social post. A thing I truly hate doing on this
Speaker 4:  podcast is reading truth social posts out loud. But can I just read this
Speaker 4:  one to you?
Speaker 11:  I not only do I want you to read it, I want you to read it in your best
Speaker 11:  Donald Trump impression
Speaker 4:  That I will, I will not be doing that. That will, that will, I will get fired
Speaker 4:  for different reasons if I'm doing that. But here, lemme just read this to
Speaker 4:  you. It says, I can't believe a b, c fake news gave Jimmy Kimmel his job
Speaker 4:  back. The White House was told by a BC that his show was canceled. Something
Speaker 4:  happened between then and now because his audience is gone and his talent
Speaker 4:  was never there. Why would they want someone back who does so poorly, who's
Speaker 4:  not funny and who puts the network in jeopardy by playing 99% positive Democrat
Speaker 4:  garbage? He has yet another arm of the DNC and to the best of my knowledge,
Speaker 4:  that would be a major illegal campaign contribution. So just quick pause
Speaker 4:  for David commentary. All of that is bananas
Speaker 4:  nonsense craziness. But is like normal bananas, nonsense craziness coming
Speaker 4:  from President Trump. Like the White House is told by a BC that his
Speaker 4:  show was canceled, I'm sure is not a real thing.
Speaker 4:  The his audience is gone, his talent was never there. Very funny in context
Speaker 4:  of what you just said, Liz, which is that actually what President Trump did
Speaker 4:  was give Jimmy Kimmel the biggest audience maybe he's ever had. All
Speaker 4:  of this is very funny. So then what he says is, I'm, I'm back to
Speaker 4:  quoting the President of the United States, which just feels like a relevant
Speaker 4:  thing to say, I think we're gonna test a, b, c out on this. Let's see how
Speaker 4:  we do. Last time I went after them, they gave me $16 million. This one
Speaker 4:  sounds even more lucrative. A true bunch of losers let Jimmy Kimmel rot in
Speaker 4:  his bad ratings. I just, anytime you are sitting in a conference room
Speaker 4:  from now until the end of the Trump administration, I want you to read out
Speaker 4:  loud. Last time I went after them, they gave me $16 million. This one
Speaker 4:  sounds even more lucrative. And I the,
Speaker 4:  if you give him what he want, he will come after you for more over and over
Speaker 4:  and over. This has been the story. He put it on truth social that
Speaker 4:  what he wants from you is either fey or money, and ideally
Speaker 4:  both the end, he thinks all of the late night hosts are mean to him. And
Speaker 4:  so he wants to cancel their shows and get money from them. Anything you think
Speaker 4:  is not one of those two things is wrong because he's the president of the
Speaker 4:  United States and he's posting about it on truth social. Like it's just,
Speaker 4:  it's right there in front of you. This is what they're trying to do.
Speaker 4:  That's it.
Speaker 11:  So I just, I the thing that I wanna add here, because
Speaker 11:  I think all of that is correct, David, is that also this
Speaker 11:  man has the glassies of Glass Jaws because if you
Speaker 11:  just say no
Speaker 11:  and you just don't do it, he pivots,
Speaker 11:  he goes and bullies somebody else. And
Speaker 11:  it would be really nice if anybody
Speaker 11:  who thinks of themselves as a leader of anything, like
Speaker 11:  let's say the Democratic party let perhaps a
Speaker 11:  CEO of some kind, maybe a university president
Speaker 11:  were to observe this phenomenon and just
Speaker 11:  say no,
Speaker 4:  What a, what a concept. Like you'll, you'll notice John Oliver,
Speaker 4:  who I think has done a terrific job of like
Speaker 4:  the thing he said, which is the four words you say to somebody who is bullying
Speaker 4:  you. Like, this is, fuck you, make me really interesting.
Speaker 4:  Trump is not spending a lot of time posting about how bad John Oliver
Speaker 4:  is. Truly fascinating. Hmm. I suspect he is probably going to tell
Speaker 4:  one of the elephants to do something about it if and when they own the company
Speaker 4:  that runs John Oliver's show. But that's a whole different story.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Meanwhile, I really like, I I'm glad you brought this up, Liz
Speaker 4:  And I I think we should just briefly make sure we do not let Brenda Carr
Speaker 4:  off the hook for backtracking so hard and
Speaker 4:  so aggressively and so like cowardly
Speaker 4:  on the whole easy way or the hard way thing. Because at the beginning of
Speaker 4:  this, he went on Benny Johnson's YouTube channel and said about the Kimmel
Speaker 4:  thing, we can do this the easy way or the hard way. And it is very clear
Speaker 4:  what that means. My guy has been out here threatening to get rid of everybody's
Speaker 4:  broadcast licenses at the drop of a hat. Like if you, if you wear the wrong
Speaker 4:  color t-shirt, he's like, I'm gonna take away your broadcast license, I don't
Speaker 4:  like it. And then this time he is, he gave this really
Speaker 4:  long meandering answer about how actually the
Speaker 4:  FCC shouldn't have to be involved at all.
Speaker 4:  And this is the easy way is that they just solve this problem for themselves.
Speaker 4:  And the hard way is somebody files an FCC complaint and
Speaker 4:  it's just like, Brendan, if you're, if you're gonna be this guy, be this
Speaker 4:  guy, don't like woos out the minute somebody cancels Disney
Speaker 4:  Plus because you're an idiot. Like, ugh. I almost like, I like
Speaker 4:  him less than I ever have. Now I
Speaker 11:  Will say this, for some of the other people that we make fun of on the show,
Speaker 11:  at least they have the courage of their convictions
Speaker 4:  Commit to the bit. Yes. Yeah, I agree.
Speaker 4:  All right, well that's, yeah, this week's version of Brendan Carr's dummy,
Speaker 4:  I'm very angry about this whole situation and we're, we're gonna have to
Speaker 4:  do more of this because it is all increasingly tied together
Speaker 4:  in ways that feel worse and bad all
Speaker 4:  of the time. Jake, give us something else to talk about. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Temperature to, to, I'm gonna take the temperature down.
Speaker 5:  Maybe it depends if you just bought a new iPhone, there's headlines bound
Speaker 5:  on the internet about Scratch Gate, which is
Speaker 5:  this allegation that the, the new iPhone 17 pro
Speaker 5:  can be very easily scratched. The new models,
Speaker 5:  they have two types of material on the back of the phone. There's a,
Speaker 5:  there's the ceramic shield coating on a portion of it,
Speaker 5:  and then there's anodized aluminum. And if you scratch
Speaker 5:  stuff all over it, it it, it gets all dusty and, and it
Speaker 5:  looks bad. And there's all these photos of, from the Apple Store where people
Speaker 5:  are like, all these things are like getting nasty after just a day. And then
Speaker 5:  separately, there's this all, all this stuff about how like the edges are
Speaker 5:  susceptible scratches. David, I'm curious if you have seen any of these videos,
Speaker 5:  any of these photos? I, my, my
Speaker 5:  quick to, I I think this is all extremely overstated
Speaker 5:  and unimportant.
Speaker 4:  I can't believe you, you started this by saying the temperature is going
Speaker 4:  to go down. Scratch Gate is real. Jake, is it Scratch
Speaker 5:  Gate all
Speaker 4:  Real exclamation point? I No, I do,
Speaker 4:  do I think the fact that you can scratch your phone is a bummer and is a
Speaker 4:  real thing. Yes. Do I think this is like,
Speaker 4:  you know, everyone is canceled because of Scratch Gate? Probably not. Like,
Speaker 4:  the thing I think is sort of fascinating is the tech woven cases, Apple's
Speaker 4:  like new material ca seem to be fabulous. All of the tests of them have been
Speaker 4:  very good. People are really impressed with how they look and how they're
Speaker 4:  holding up the fine woven was a disaster and tech woven seems to be pretty
Speaker 4:  good. But I have gotten like a shocking number of
Speaker 4:  signal messages and emails and tips and all kinds of stuff from people being
Speaker 4:  like, I went to the Apple store and all of the display models are scratched
Speaker 4:  to bits and there seems to be like, it seems to be
Speaker 4:  real.
Speaker 5:  So I haven't scratched the phone myself, but I, you know,
Speaker 5:  wa I, I watched the Jerry rig everything video, he goes at that thing with
Speaker 5:  some, some coins and some pics. Most of it apparently is
Speaker 5:  material transfer from the scratching object onto the phone that you can
Speaker 5:  just wipe off. There's, it's a video. He just wipes the stuff off. It's fine,
Speaker 5:  it's fine. Just wipe off the phone. I don't know. I haven't tried. Maybe
Speaker 5:  it gets worse. Travis, our producer in the, he is shaking his head.
Speaker 5:  He thinks I'm dead wrong on this. So listen, the title
Speaker 4:  Of this episode is going to be Scratch Gate, exclamation Point, scratch Gate.
Speaker 5:  Listen, if I'm wrong, send me some videos of
Speaker 5:  wiping off the back of an iPhone. It doesn't come off. And I will, I will
Speaker 5:  acknowledge that I have aired here,
Speaker 5:  but if not, put a case in your phone, it'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  Liz, are you a case person?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I am. But I just wanted to say there is a real scandal here that I
Speaker 11:  feel no one is covering in the media. So I'm, I'm gonna take my position,
Speaker 11:  you know, 'cause I feel, I feel morally obligated
Speaker 11:  to speak for the iPhone mini people. As someone who recently
Speaker 11:  replaced the battery on her iPhone mini because the bones are too big.
Speaker 11:  I just want, you know, there are a lot of us out here who have small hands
Speaker 11:  and the phones are too large. And it would be so nice
Speaker 11:  if the mini came back like every five years or so, every time I need to
Speaker 11:  buy a phone. That's all
Speaker 4:  Agreed a hundred percent. I think all of the people who love the
Speaker 4:  iPhone Air would've loved it more if it was smaller And I think it would
Speaker 4:  suddenly be everybody's favorite phone. I think the, the thing about this
Speaker 4:  that is actually a bummer to me is I think we just
Speaker 4:  continue down the road of needing to baby our phones. And I
Speaker 4:  think, I think everyone needs to spend more time building phones that
Speaker 4:  we don't need to worry about. And just the idea that my phone
Speaker 4:  might get gross because I throw it in my bag or have it in my
Speaker 4:  pocket is a bummer. And, and these things are just
Speaker 4:  too mature and too important to be
Speaker 4:  that kind of thing. And we're making real progress on like, my screen doesn't
Speaker 4:  shatter if I look at it wrong. Like, that's great And I think that's awesome.
Speaker 4:  But e every single time this happens, it's like two steps forward and one
Speaker 4:  step back. We've invented a new way to screw up your phone And I just think
Speaker 4:  that's a bummer,
Speaker 11:  David. The phone gets gross because your hands are filthy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean we are the gross ones. It's really
Speaker 11:  Right. The call is coming from inside the house, man.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, that's, that's fair. I can't really disagree with that. If you
Speaker 4:  want to rant and rave to Jake about Scratch Gate, please call the
Speaker 4:  hotline. It's six six version one one. Nothing would make me happier than
Speaker 4:  playing a bunch of angry Scratch Gate voicemails at Jake on next week's episode.
Speaker 4:  So please call with all of your feelings about Scratch Gate.
Speaker 4:  My next one, Liz, I picked this specifically because I want to talk to you
Speaker 4:  about it for a minute. I have been sort of against my own
Speaker 4:  best interests, fascinated by these like digital writing tools for
Speaker 4:  forever. I have garbage handwriting, I don't write ever. And yet every time
Speaker 4:  Live Scribe is like, we've built a, we've built a smart notebook, like I
Speaker 4:  will spend $75 on it this time it's
Speaker 4:  Mont Blanc, which came out with what I can only describe as
Speaker 4:  like a pretty simple digital ink
Speaker 4:  screen thing and a digital pen. The difference is it is
Speaker 4:  modeled on a Mont Blanc pen and importantly It costs
Speaker 4:  $905. It's called the Mont Blanc digital paper.
Speaker 4:  It's a writing tablet. And what I wanna know is, Liz, you are the verges
Speaker 4:  preeminent pen and paper scholar. What do you make of these things? Is this
Speaker 4:  a good idea? Are you gonna buy a Mont Blanc e Inc tablet?
Speaker 11:  No, first of all, because I have a bunch of bottles of like
Speaker 11:  real ink, like actually real ink to use
Speaker 11:  up. Wow. But I will say as somebody who spends
Speaker 11:  too much time thinking about fountain pens, Mont Blanc is pretty well known
Speaker 11:  in the Fountain Pin community for being incredibly
Speaker 11:  overpriced.
Speaker 11:  Interesting. And if you are interested in quality pens, there are
Speaker 11:  a lot better options out there. It's sort of more of a
Speaker 11:  status symbol than like a real leader in making
Speaker 11:  good pens. And in particular, you know, the, the
Speaker 11:  sort of consensus seems to be that like the peak for Mont
Speaker 11:  Blanc was like, I don't know, the 1960s or the
Speaker 11:  1970s. So if you are thinking about a Mont Blanc pen, like you should go
Speaker 11:  on eBay and get a used one and or a lot of them have been refurbished. And
Speaker 11:  because these are fountain pens and not like modern technology,
Speaker 11:  they're durable and they don't crumble
Speaker 11:  after five years and they're meant to last forever. And if you take care
Speaker 11:  of them, they will. So that's sort of the, the pen and ink
Speaker 11:  take on Mont Blanc.
Speaker 4:  That is good to know. I think when we publish this, I would say the overwhelming
Speaker 4:  reaction was A, this is ridiculously expensive and B I'm not
Speaker 4:  sure I trust Mont Blanc to be a good steward of a digital writing
Speaker 4:  system for a very long time. And I would say I agree with both of those things
Speaker 4:  and yet I look at this thing and I'm like, maybe that would make my handwriting
Speaker 4:  better. Like maybe, maybe, maybe I'll take handwritten
Speaker 4:  notes forever and everything will be lovely. David,
Speaker 11:  Can I pen enable you? Can I, can I send you a fountain pun?
Speaker 4:  I literally, I was thinking about this. You you picked up that thing of ink
Speaker 4:  And I had this moment of being like, literally if you handed that to me,
Speaker 4:  I would have absolutely no idea what to do. I was like, I like,
Speaker 4:  okay, this is, I'm never gonna touch this again. I'm gonna put it down on
Speaker 4:  my desk and try not to spill it. But yes, please, nothing would make
Speaker 4:  me happier than becoming like a, everything about my personality suggests
Speaker 4:  that I should be a real weirdo about pens. So I'm, I'm in, let's, let's
Speaker 4:  make this happen sometime. Let's do it. All right. Speaking of back to you,
Speaker 4:  Liz, what's your, what's your second lightning round?
Speaker 11:  It's time to talk about ai. So
Speaker 11:  Nvidia has, oh God invested in open ai
Speaker 11:  and it's, here's the thing, I, you know,
Speaker 11:  I I I have this obsession with
Speaker 11:  how this, this, the money is going here
Speaker 11:  because I just, I, it mm mm If there's just
Speaker 11:  something that feels
Speaker 11:  weird to me about Nvidia investing in so many
Speaker 11:  companies that buy Nvidia chips, like people are handing the same
Speaker 11:  $5 back and forth and it wasn't just, you know,
Speaker 11:  open ai, it's core weave too. And there's like this whole ecosystem
Speaker 11:  that Nvidia is investing in that then turns around and buys a bunch of
Speaker 11:  Nvidia products. And then OpenAI of course has
Speaker 11:  its investments in a number of companies that are dependent on the open
Speaker 11:  AI platform. And there's just this, it's like a
Speaker 11:  brats nest of money and
Speaker 11:  investments. And I feel
Speaker 11:  that this is maybe the best, the best way to like look at it
Speaker 11:  and think about it. This, this partnership which like
Speaker 11:  feels kind of vague. Like the partnership, which was announced Monday, says
Speaker 11:  that OpenAI is going to build and deploy at least 10 gigawatts
Speaker 11:  of AI data centers with Nvidia systems.
Speaker 11:  And Nvidia intends to invest
Speaker 11:  100 billion in AI as each gigawatt is deployed.
Speaker 11:  So like, I wanna be clear about how open this is about being
Speaker 11:  completely circular. Like this is like in the, the text of the deal.
Speaker 11:  I am bewildered by this because it feels like I'm watching
Speaker 11:  it. It feels like I'm watching like a, a, a spring, like start
Speaker 11:  to wind up and get tighter and tighter and tighter.
Speaker 11:  Which, you know, I maybe, maybe,
Speaker 11:  maybe I'm just being paranoid, but given
Speaker 11:  how much of the current economy is dependent
Speaker 11:  on AI and AI investment, which is
Speaker 11:  substantial by the way
Speaker 11:  I am, I'm wondering that like, this seems like a pretty fragile ecosystem
Speaker 11:  if everybody is constantly, you know, winding
Speaker 11:  money up with each other. What happens if one part of that
Speaker 11:  system fails?
Speaker 11:  So just putting that out there that this is yet another
Speaker 11:  sort of winding of the crank of what appears to me
Speaker 11:  to be a feedback machine. Let's see how it goes.
Speaker 4:  There was a great Wall Street Journal story this week
Speaker 4:  and the headline was, Nvidia has a problem colon too much money.
Speaker 4:  And that is like, if, if that is not an indication of like the
Speaker 4:  strangeness of this moment that we're in, I don't, I don't know what is,
Speaker 4:  'cause I think you're right that not only is is the bet on
Speaker 4:  ai, the thing that is propping everything else up, but it is like specifically
Speaker 4:  Nvidia, I saw somebody characterize the Nvidia open AI investment as
Speaker 4:  Nvidia giving open AI a $100 billion Nvidia gift card,
Speaker 4:  which I like very much and feels about right. And it is
Speaker 4:  just like, it is, it is wild how much of this whole race
Speaker 4:  is tied up in this one company. And that's not to suggest that
Speaker 4:  like, it, it is on its own. Like I've called in open AI a house of cards
Speaker 4:  that's about to collapse And I still kind of believe that Nvidia doesn't
Speaker 4:  seem to be that Nvidia seems to just be doing great and have just made a
Speaker 4:  lot of correct calls all in a row. But it is still weird
Speaker 4:  that everything is so tied up in this one company, which is now just like
Speaker 4:  pouring all of the money that it has back into the rest of the industry because
Speaker 4:  it doesn't know what else to do with all of this money. It's just wild.
Speaker 11:  So I want to recap some very recent history, which is
Speaker 11:  not tech history in which you may be unfamiliar with,
Speaker 11:  but one of the driving forces of the 2008 financial
Speaker 11:  crisis was the shadow banking system. There were all these money market
Speaker 11:  funds, which worked kind of like a savings account,
Speaker 11:  but not really that had more money
Speaker 11:  than they knew what to do with in terms of investments. And that was what
Speaker 11:  drove the demand for mortgages. That was like the, the initial thing winding
Speaker 11:  the crank. And so seeing that
Speaker 11:  Nvidia has more money than it knows what to do with and watching
Speaker 11:  it make some of these investments. I mean, maybe I just have
Speaker 11:  like great financial crisis, PTSD
Speaker 11:  since that happened, you know, very early in my career and very early
Speaker 11:  in my adulthood.
Speaker 11:  But I don't like the parallel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, listen, it's not, we're not saying it's the same thing, it's just that
Speaker 4:  it has all the same characteristics, you know what I mean?
Speaker 11:  Anyway, TBD Yeah, let's see how this goes.
Speaker 4:  No, I think the, the, yeah, all of the money
Speaker 4:  is like, I'm, I'm increasingly like, I really like your, your, your
Speaker 4:  characterization of it as everybody's just passing the same $5 around. And
Speaker 4:  I think if you look at it like that, it makes a lot of what's happening in
Speaker 4:  AI seem sort of absurd. And I think that is probably
Speaker 4:  the correct way to be looking at all of this right now. The the stakes are
Speaker 4:  super high and it is all nonsense all at the same time. Somehow.
Speaker 11:  I can't speak to like the tech end of AI because I
Speaker 11:  am a technology normal. I'm like the only technology normal we employ besides
Speaker 11:  our features editor. I think listen,
Speaker 4:  You, you already showed us the thing of fountain pen ink on your desk. Like
Speaker 4:  we get it. We're,
Speaker 11:  We understand, but I gotta say I
Speaker 11:  don't understand the financial end of AI or how it ever makes
Speaker 11:  money because the thing about software is that you make a thing once and
Speaker 11:  then you copy it infinity times and you make infinity profit.
Speaker 11:  And we know from streaming that as, you know, if you're, if you have
Speaker 11:  something that requires servers as more people use it, like you have to
Speaker 11:  invest more, more stuff. And the only
Speaker 11:  explanation I've heard for how AI makes money is like, it like
Speaker 11:  mysteriously gets much cheaper and better very fast. Like, which to me
Speaker 11:  is like the underpants gnomes explanation of how AI makes money.
Speaker 11:  Like, it, it, it just mysteriously happens because what I
Speaker 11:  I kind of see happening is like, if this is a big, if by the way, given
Speaker 11:  AI's current capabilities, but if AI does become an important part
Speaker 11:  of the business world or people's personal lives and we,
Speaker 11:  we have to scale all these data centers up, that's, that's
Speaker 11:  just so expensive that I don't, I don't understand
Speaker 11:  how this works financially.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, if you do tell us, but I won't believe you. Please
Speaker 4:  just in case you're wondering,
Speaker 11:  Email me. We, we would, Liz at The Verge tell me how it works financially.
Speaker 11:  I would love to, like, seriously, I'm not kidding. Like, email me,
Speaker 4:  Please help my family is starving. Like,
Speaker 4:  all right Jake, you're up last, what's your, what's your second lightning
Speaker 4:  round? Okay, David,
Speaker 5:  I both of you quickly, how much would you pay for a dark mode theme
Speaker 5:  on your favorite app?
Speaker 4:  You know, I'm the wrong person to ask this question.
Speaker 5:  Is the answer $900 a year? No.
Speaker 4:  No it isn't. I can tell you that.
Speaker 5:  Well then American Express's new platinum card
Speaker 5:  is not for you. They recently raised the price on
Speaker 5:  their platinum card. It costs $895 a year,
Speaker 5:  which as is a little more than the $0
Speaker 5:  that I prefer to pay for a credit card. But to make it a
Speaker 5:  more appealing offer, they said, Hey, we've got a new app feature.
Speaker 5:  They have a quote premium theme and it
Speaker 5:  turns the, the app from I think a dark blue to
Speaker 5:  black
Speaker 4:  Wait, this is now like a, a cardholder perk. They're like, okay, you get,
Speaker 4:  you get points at restaurants, you get insurance when you rent a car,
Speaker 4:  which by the way, one of the best reasons to get an Amex is rental car insurance.
Speaker 4:  And you get dark mode in the Amex app.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you get dark mode. But only if you pay for like one of their finest
Speaker 5:  cards.
Speaker 4:  God, I hate things. Okay, I'm looking at this picture And I will say
Speaker 4:  the app looks sick.
Speaker 4:  Like they're
Speaker 5:  Not, listen, they're not wrong. The, you, you get all these points, you get
Speaker 5:  dark mode. What's not, what's the complaint about you? You'll, you'll make
Speaker 5:  that $900 a year back in terms of pleasure to your eyes.
Speaker 4:  This is, this is literally, ugh, the platinum app experience introduces
Speaker 4:  a new premium theme. I'm reading their press release with latent dark modes
Speaker 4:  that match device settings. The redesigned overview screen brings together
Speaker 4:  welcome bonus progress tracking and account setup tasks in one dashboard.
Speaker 4:  You know what this is like, this is like when, when BMW is like, we'll
Speaker 4:  make your car slightly faster but only for $500. This is
Speaker 4:  awful. This is like,
Speaker 5:  This is,
Speaker 4:  Honestly, this is some like Silicon Valley on HBO shit in the worst
Speaker 4:  possible way.
Speaker 5:  I, I a hundred percent am in support of this. I love this. I think this is
Speaker 5:  ludicrous. I think this just fully lays out how ludicrous
Speaker 5:  the entire credit card situation is. I it's love
Speaker 5:  great. It's great. I love it. I'm sold
Speaker 4:  A short welcome video, an updated card art, make the experience premium from
Speaker 4:  the start. This is the worst. This, no, this makes me hate things.
Speaker 4:  I have a, I have a free American Express card that I'm now gonna have to
Speaker 4:  get rid of because I hate this so much.
Speaker 5:  All your friends will know that you've got the cool card when you open up
Speaker 5:  the, the Amex app and it's all black and you're like, they're like, wish
Speaker 5:  I could have that.
Speaker 4:  No. All of your friends know you have the cool card because it's heavy and
Speaker 4:  metal and makes a sound when you performatively throw it on the table. That's
Speaker 4:  what I'm paying for.
Speaker 5:  No, but you don't use the card anymore because you're tapping to pay. It's
Speaker 5:  true. So you have to open it up, look your point balance in front of your
Speaker 5:  friends, be like, oh boy, all these points I've got from spending too much
Speaker 5:  money that I don't have on hotels. And they'll be like, wow,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Hate so much that you're exactly correct. That somewhere there was a meeting
Speaker 4:  where they were like, how, how are our members gonna communicate their status
Speaker 4:  in a digital world? And somebody was like, make the app black. And they were
Speaker 4:  like, you're a genius. You're promoted $900 a year. This
Speaker 4:  sucks. I don't like it at all.
Speaker 11:  I, I I,
Speaker 11:  So you know how spam emails are
Speaker 11:  frequently misspelled so as to make sure that it finds
Speaker 11:  the most credulous target.
Speaker 11:  This is that. But for credit cards, like the person for
Speaker 11:  whom $900 is nothing
Speaker 11:  to spend on a display is the person
Speaker 11:  they want to have that card. Like the person for whom
Speaker 11:  $900 is peanuts is, is exactly the
Speaker 11:  person they want to have that card. So I do think that there is like,
Speaker 11:  there's some status signaling going on. I'm sure there's like a bunch of
Speaker 11:  I bankers who are like going to be getting this on the first day
Speaker 11:  so that they can whip it out when they go to whatever the
Speaker 11:  hotspots are. Now in New York, I haven't lived there in quite some time,
Speaker 11:  so I was gonna say Cipriani, but I don't even know if that's still open.
Speaker 11:  But like, you know, this is not just
Speaker 11:  status signaling. It's, it's it's selection. It's customer
Speaker 11:  selection.
Speaker 4:  It is. I will, I all of that is true. And I will say this, this suggests
Speaker 4:  that American Express only made one mistake in this whole thing, which is
Speaker 4:  that the background should not be black. It should be gold and it should
Speaker 4:  be, it should, your phone should be so shiny when you go to pay
Speaker 4:  with your sick premium card. 'cause who's gonna notice dark mode?
Speaker 4:  Dark mode just looks like dark mode. But if, if my phone glows gold, like
Speaker 4:  when Trump mobile does this, it's gonna be gold and it's gonna blow your
Speaker 4:  mind. You're gonna love it.
Speaker 4:  Also, somebody sent me an email saying that the Trump
Speaker 4:  mobile website now lists a bunch of refurbished Samsung and iPhones
Speaker 4:  as made in the USA, which Trump mobile has just gone
Speaker 4:  full nonsense. And that website and product are maintained by
Speaker 4:  no one. And it's all made up.
Speaker 5:  I believe the phone is supposed to ship this month. So looking forward to
Speaker 5:  receiving hours.
Speaker 4:  If you got one, I would, I would, I want to hear from you. I wanna meet you
Speaker 4:  in person And I have a, I have, we have a lot to talk about. Alright. But
Speaker 4:  all that is for another show for now. It is, it is time for us to go. We've
Speaker 4:  gone way over as we are want to do renting. Carr is a dummy. Appears to be
Speaker 4:  back in just full force. I hate it. But
Speaker 4:  this is what we do here now. We have a lot coming up next week,
Speaker 4:  so stick around. We're gonna talk about smart home stuff. Like I said, Amazon
Speaker 4:  has the big Echo event coming up next week. Google's doing some stuff. Presumably
Speaker 4:  there will be more TikTok stuff to talk about. So Jake, Liz,
Speaker 4:  we'll be back. We're gonna do more of this for now. That is it for The Vergecast.
Speaker 4:  If you have questions or thoughts about all of this, if you wanna buy TikTok,
Speaker 4:  let us know. Vergecast at The Verge dot com is the email. 8 6 6 VERGE one
Speaker 4:  one is the hotline. The Vergecast is the production of The Verge and the
Speaker 4:  Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer,
Speaker 4:  and Travis Uck. We will be back next week and we will see you then.