# Transcript
ID: 75dcdca2-706b-49a2-873d-521e755708d5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1947417319411678354/-3268684220910368855/s93290-US-4819s-1750154549.mp3
Description: It's a small miracle that a bunch of us managed to get our heads out of Mario Kart World long enough to make a show about the Switch 2. But that's what we did! First, we chat with The Verge's Andrew Webster about his review, and why it feels like the Switch 2 is both everything we wanted and somehow still a little underwhelming. (Or at least just... whelming.) After that, The Verge's Ash Parrish tells us about her adventures traveling with the Switch 2, plus her recent time with the new Asus ROG Xbox Ally, and what she's learning about the future of consoles. Finally, The Verge's Sean Hollister helps us answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline all about console prices: why they keep going up, and whether they'll continue to be worth it.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Rainbow Road. I'm m your
Speaker 2:  friend David Pierce, And I am bad at Mario Kart World. I just need to get
Speaker 2:  that off my chest. I've been playing Mario Kart like most of my life in various
Speaker 2:  iterations, And I've usually been pretty good at it. I wouldn't say I'm like
Speaker 2:  a, you know, speed running champion of Mario Kart, but I'm pretty good at
Speaker 2:  it. I could beat most people and now all I can do is come in like 13th
Speaker 2:  over and over and over and over again. And it is
Speaker 2:  devastating. But now I have discovered I'm in, I, I care
Speaker 2:  so deeply about being good at this game that I think the only thing you will
Speaker 2:  find me doing for potentially several weeks or months, he's
Speaker 2:  playing Mario Kart World. If you wanna play with me and beat me because you
Speaker 2:  will let me know, I'm here for it. I am ready. I am
Speaker 2:  coming for you Mario Kart World. Anyway, today on the show we are gonna
Speaker 2:  talk actually all about the Nintendo Switch too. That's all
Speaker 2:  we're doing today. We're gonna talk to Andrew Webster who reviewed the device
Speaker 2:  for us. We're gonna talk to Ash Parrish, who has been using the device and
Speaker 2:  has been testing a lot of the games, has a lot of thoughts about how this
Speaker 2:  is going. We're also gonna talk about some other handheld console news, but
Speaker 2:  we'll get to that later. Then we have a hotline question about the switch
Speaker 2:  two. I'm telling you, we're just doing switch two stuff today. We've had
Speaker 2:  the thing for a while. We have some thoughts about it. It's switched two
Speaker 2:  time here on The Vergecast. All of that is coming up in just a second. But
Speaker 2:  first I'm, I'm gonna play more of this stupid game that I can't stop playing.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna come in 13th and then we're gonna do this. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Andrew Webster is here. Hi Andrew. Hello. I
Speaker 2:  feel like I have dragged you here to talk about the switch several times
Speaker 2:  against your will now and I'm very excited to have you back. So thank you
Speaker 2:  for doing this.
Speaker 4:  Of course. I always, always here to talk Nintendo.
Speaker 2:  So let's talk about the review process As much
Speaker 2:  as I, I want to talk about how you feel about this thing, but this has been
Speaker 2:  an interesting gadget to review for you over the
Speaker 2:  last week or so. What, what have you been up to? How has this thing been
Speaker 2:  going for you?
Speaker 4:  Well, yeah, it's been weird 'cause you know, normally
Speaker 4:  you get things ahead of time and then we can
Speaker 4:  play around with it and then publish something that lets people know whether
Speaker 4:  they wanna buy it or not. But Nintendo did not do that
Speaker 4:  and my unit showed up two days late. So I've just spent
Speaker 4:  every waking moment that wasn't covering one of
Speaker 4:  the four live video game events that happened over the past week.
Speaker 4:  You know, playing Mario Kart and no mansky and
Speaker 4:  figuring out what virtual game cards are.
Speaker 2:  So what were the first games you installed? Like what was first thing? I
Speaker 2:  mean, I assume Mario Kart World was first. Yeah, because it was the first
Speaker 2:  one everybody
Speaker 4:  Did. It was Mario Kart World and then Fortnite and
Speaker 4:  Nomad Sky were like the two two ones. 'cause I feel like those, especially,
Speaker 4:  I put in a number of hours that I won't say publicly.
Speaker 4:  So like I can really tell the difference. And they both like struggled
Speaker 4:  hardcore on the first switch. So they're pretty notable upgrades.
Speaker 2:  So I want to come back to this 'cause I think the, the, the Fortnite of it
Speaker 2:  all, I actually think might be a really telling way to distinguish the
Speaker 2:  new Switch. But let's talk about this thing as just a, a piece of hardware
Speaker 2:  first. You, you've spent a lot of time on the first switch And I think the,
Speaker 2:  the question we talked a bunch about in the run up to this thing is
Speaker 2:  what do we want a better switch to be? And there are, there are a bunch
Speaker 2:  of things that could be including some sort of wildly different idea about
Speaker 2:  what a Nintendo Switch console might be or look like or do.
Speaker 2:  And instead we got a thing that is just like a full rev of specs in in most
Speaker 2:  ways, I would say Pure as a piece of hardware. What, what
Speaker 2:  have you felt about it so far? Does it, does it feel like they got the thing
Speaker 2:  right in just trying to make it better across the board?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's like, I, I don't say this in like a bad way. It's good enough.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, it's what they needed to do. I've written about this thing like
Speaker 4:  at many different points, including before it came out and every time I was
Speaker 4:  just like, it's a switch, but better. And finding new ways to say that is
Speaker 4:  difficult, But that really, even after spending, you know, an entire week
Speaker 4:  with it, it's a switch but better.
Speaker 2:  So what, what about it jumps out to you as better? Like what are the sort
Speaker 2:  of most noticeably better things?
Speaker 4:  I mean just the way games run is like a huge difference. Like we talk about
Speaker 4:  Mario Car World and like developers Indo had said
Speaker 4:  that, you know, when they were developing this game for the Switch, they
Speaker 4:  were like getting scared 'cause it's not gonna work on it. And you play it
Speaker 4:  on Switch two and it runs beautifully. You know, I was
Speaker 4:  doing like four player split screen and this game is like so
Speaker 4:  chaotic, you know, everything explodes. You have like two bullet
Speaker 4:  bills at the same time while you're getting hit with a blue shell. And like
Speaker 4:  all that stuff's happening on your TV at the same time and it runs great.
Speaker 4:  Like it's just not a game that would be possible in the other switch. And
Speaker 4:  yeah, and like Fortnite, you know, our colleague Charles wrote about
Speaker 4:  like when he played it on the switch too for the first time 'cause he only
Speaker 4:  played it on the switch. It was like, holy shit, this is like how you people
Speaker 4:  have been living. Like he bought all these skins and they That's so funny.
Speaker 4:  He could actually tell who they were on the new hardware 'cause they just
Speaker 4:  were like polygonal trash before.
Speaker 2:  I feel like that's the same as like if you've been playing Fortnite only
Speaker 2:  on your phone for the last decade, you're like, yeah, this game is fine,
Speaker 2:  but like what's the, yeah, what's the fuss about about Fortnite? And then
Speaker 2:  you get, you get the full Fortnite experience and you're like, oh, this is
Speaker 2:  actually kind of sick.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, you know, you're still grading Nintendo on a curve. It doesn't
Speaker 4:  look as good as a PS five or whatever, but like it looks very good and
Speaker 4:  especially in portable mode, you know, it's, it's Fortnite.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So this, this is a dumb question and
Speaker 2:  you're better equipped to answer than I am. And one of the things I've been
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out about the switch to is
Speaker 2:  games look dramatically better And I can't figure out whether that's
Speaker 2:  because I have the old like OG pre O
Speaker 2:  led switch and So I'm actually upgrading like a couple of
Speaker 2:  generations of display or if it is because
Speaker 2:  there's just so much more processing power that actually the games themselves
Speaker 2:  are able to be made to look better. And So I,
Speaker 2:  but I just keep staring at the screen being like, I can't believe how much
Speaker 2:  better this looks even for like games that I played on
Speaker 2:  the old switch.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like the, the screen is obviously better, although like I, I mentioned
Speaker 4:  this on a review, but like I do miss the O lead, like it was, it's much
Speaker 4:  more vibrant, but you know, the screen is better, but it, I think it is
Speaker 4:  more the, the processing issue. You know, it's not
Speaker 4:  the screen that makes the eShop actually usable for once where you
Speaker 4:  can input codes and it doesn't take half an hour. Fair. So
Speaker 4:  yeah, it's, it's like, you know, Nintendo is not
Speaker 4:  a, a company like to make beefy consoles, but this is like, you
Speaker 4:  know, I can play cyberpunk and it looks good even in portable mode.
Speaker 4:  You know, that game was a disaster when it first came out on like previous
Speaker 4:  gen consoles and it runs great on the switch. I mean it's, it's not the
Speaker 4:  latest open world game, but it's a big thing and it's a big technical test
Speaker 4:  and it, it works great.
Speaker 2:  Have you run into anything that feels like it's pressing up against the edges
Speaker 2:  of what the Switch two can do? So
Speaker 4:  The only, like stuff that's looked bad for me is doing,
Speaker 4:  so there's like a new feature called Game Share where it's like
Speaker 4:  with one copy of the game you basically like stream it to someone
Speaker 4:  who's nearby. So like me and you were hanging out, we can play it and
Speaker 4:  well, me and my kids were playing this game called Survival Kids, which is
Speaker 4:  exactly what sounds like it looked fine. But then my wife And I were playing
Speaker 4:  split fiction, which is kind of like AAA ish quality game
Speaker 4:  and like she was on the, the old switch, I was on the switch too and like
Speaker 4:  it looked terrible. So I think that's stuff, but that's, I
Speaker 4:  think that's more of like a streaming issue than like a hardware issue. But
Speaker 4:  yeah, you know, I'm the kind of person who drives around Myocar world and
Speaker 4:  like takes pictures of all the signs. Sure. So I notice things that probably
Speaker 4:  people don't notice, but like, you know, some of that stuff looks a little
Speaker 4:  fuzzy or low res, but nothing like huge that
Speaker 4:  normal people would notice, I don't think. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it does feel like Nintendo in general is pretty well calibrated
Speaker 2:  to like having enough power to do what it needs to do without having
Speaker 2:  tons of headroom, which I think is potentially
Speaker 2:  sort of problematic as you get to like the eighth year of a console cycle.
Speaker 2:  But in these first runs it's, I I can't remember a Nintendo experience where
Speaker 2:  I have felt like something was sort of underpowered on the first day. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And Nintendo just does a good job of that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And the only other thing they have is like a bunch of quizzes. So,
Speaker 4:  you know, if that didn't run well or we're in trouble. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair.
Speaker 2:  What, what do you feel about the, the joycons, the controllers? I know everybody
Speaker 2:  has had a lot of feelings about potential drift issues again because
Speaker 2:  they're not Hall effect joysticks, but I am
Speaker 2:  certainly no controller expert. What, what has been your JoyCon experience
Speaker 2:  so far?
Speaker 4:  Again, they're just like a little bit better. Like I think being bigger
Speaker 4:  helps 'em, especially when you're like, you know, splitting 'em apart and
Speaker 4:  having two people using them, it makes a big difference. You
Speaker 4:  know, we'll have to find out if drift becomes an issue. The mouse thing is
Speaker 4:  like, fine. I was playing Civ for a while and it's like,
Speaker 4:  it works, but it's not the most comfortable way to to to hold a
Speaker 4:  controller on your thigh moving it around. So it's kinda like the,
Speaker 4:  they're they're pretty similar to the console as a whole where it's just
Speaker 4:  like, you know, they made it slightly better. I will say the magnet thing
Speaker 4:  is very satisfying to like snap them in and out.
Speaker 2:  It is, yeah. And in a way that I, going back to the, the original switch
Speaker 2:  now, it feels that mechanism always felt sort of fragile. Like I was
Speaker 2:  gonna accidentally break the thing you had to sort of slide it into
Speaker 2:  on the edges and then the whole thing was gonna fall apart. This feels, it,
Speaker 2:  it feels like it's gonna come out in the way that like my AirPods always
Speaker 2:  feel like they're gonna come outta my ears, but they never do. And so far
Speaker 2:  it's, it's, I have not had one problem with like detaching when I
Speaker 2:  didn't want it to, even though it, it feels like it should be flimsier than
Speaker 2:  it actually seems to be.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Honestly the same with like the kickstand. Like the kickstand is like,
Speaker 4:  seems like it should be flimsy. It's like a cutout you, but it's like
Speaker 4:  the sturdiest of all the models I've seen so far.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah, it's good. So is there anything about the hardware that has been
Speaker 2:  disappointing to you?
Speaker 4:  I think I, I don't wanna buy, what are they
Speaker 4:  called? Micro SD express card for it. Yeah. But like
Speaker 4:  the games are bigger now and so it takes up, even though they gave you more
Speaker 4:  space, like if cyberpunks like 50 gigs, that's like
Speaker 4:  a fifth of your console already. Yeah. So I've already been like
Speaker 4:  deleting and moving things around a weekend.
Speaker 4:  So I mean that's just the nature of like having bigger games but like, you
Speaker 4:  know, in comparison to a PlayStation or Xbox where I don't do
Speaker 4:  that as much and the games are even bigger, it's, it's pretty annoying and
Speaker 4:  the battery life is not as good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What, what have you experienced so far? I think we've, the, the coverage
Speaker 2:  we've done, it seems to suggest that people are having pretty
Speaker 2:  mixed but generally not super impressive experiences with
Speaker 2:  the battery.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think the low end Nintendo says is like two hours and that's like,
Speaker 2:  That's pretty
Speaker 4:  Bad if you're playing, if you're, I I think it really depends what you're
Speaker 4:  playing. If you're doing like, like the game share stuff seems to really
Speaker 4:  take the battery something big like cyberpunk really seems to do it. If
Speaker 4:  I'm just like messing around in free row and Mario Kart, it seems okay. But
Speaker 4:  I think like the really intensive games seem to really drain it and
Speaker 4:  hit that lower end that they're, they're saying.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean I think I, I feel like the, the switch,
Speaker 2:  the switch one
Speaker 2:  was normally somewhere in the like five hour range for kind of normal
Speaker 2:  use for a lot of people and that felt fine. Two is tough. Yeah. Two is not
Speaker 2:  enough battery
Speaker 4:  That's like, you know, wouldn't get me to San Francisco on a flight so.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Yeah, it's, it's pretty rough.
Speaker 2:  The the storage thing I, I tend to agree I think is kind of odd and
Speaker 2:  256 gigs is fine, but even going up
Speaker 2:  to like five 12 chain goes from, I am sort of
Speaker 2:  constantly managing which games I have on my console to like most people
Speaker 2:  would probably just be able to have all of the games they're actively playing
Speaker 2:  available and it's like, there's just, that's the one hardware upgrade that
Speaker 2:  it feels like Nintendo just didn't quite push far
Speaker 4:  Enough. Yeah. And I think part of it is like their games are like super optimized.
Speaker 4:  They're tiny. Right. But like every third party if you know Cyberpunk Street
Speaker 4:  Fire six, even like Yakuza, which is like a PS four
Speaker 4:  game is like 40 gigs, which is, you know, pretty, pretty good size for a
Speaker 4:  device like this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What's your normal setup? How do you play? Are you a dock
Speaker 2:  guy with a controller? Are you all handheld? What's your, what's your move?
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 4:  Work around everyone else, man. Okay. If, if the TV's free then I'm using
Speaker 4:  the TV otherwise, but I did spend like, you know, we had a nice
Speaker 4:  weekend up here and I spent like, you know, a lot of time on the couch in
Speaker 4:  the backyard just playing cyberpunk. It was nice.
Speaker 2:  I mean that's, that's the dream. Yeah. Right in the backyard playing cyberpunk
Speaker 2:  is like a, a life I can get ready for. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I, I, I rarely do tabletop just 'cause it's, I don know, I find I, I'm not
Speaker 4:  a fan of like the split controller thing and not bring a thing with me.
Speaker 4:  I tested a bunch for the, the mouse controls but I, I'm not
Speaker 4:  a PC gamer so you know, it's kinda lost on me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. How have you felt about the overall like size and weight
Speaker 2:  of the thing and especially in handheld mode actually holding the thing.
Speaker 2:  So
Speaker 4:  Like I thought it would bother me 'cause like when you put it up next to
Speaker 4:  a switch, like it's a pretty big difference. But like it's,
Speaker 4:  I have not really had any issues.
Speaker 4:  I, I passed it to my, my 12-year-old 'cause she's put in like a lot of hours
Speaker 4:  in Pokemon. Just if she could see a difference and
Speaker 4:  two hours later she came back to, I like had to grab it away from her 'cause
Speaker 4:  she wouldn't give it back. And she like, you know, tiny little hands
Speaker 4:  didn't have any issues with this big thing. So I think, you know,
Speaker 4:  mileage varies obviously, but for me it's been, it's been fine. And
Speaker 4:  whether she just wants extra screen time or actually doesn't have a problem
Speaker 4:  with it, you know, my daughter seemed all right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So do you find yourself slightly disappointed
Speaker 2:  with the idea that it is just a better switch because you, you seem
Speaker 2:  slightly disappointed by the idea that there's not some bigger swing in this
Speaker 2:  console.
Speaker 4:  I don't know. I think what we need to see is like Nintendo making
Speaker 4:  those swings. I think with the experiences, I think if they just continue
Speaker 4:  doing like this form factor in this style of hardware,
Speaker 4:  that's fine. If they don't get complacent in the other areas,
Speaker 4:  like world is like a very interesting expansion of Mario Carr. You can't
Speaker 4:  just, they realize we can't just like add more levels like we did before.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna try this new thing. Donkey Kong weirdly seems like a very
Speaker 4:  interesting platformer where you can like deform the terrain and do
Speaker 4:  all this kind of crazy stuff. But like I feel like we need to see more of
Speaker 4:  that stuff. Like the equivalent of like a Labo kind of thing because
Speaker 4:  yeah, like the hardware is like a tough thing to make
Speaker 4:  those swings on and Nintendo is in like a very comfortable position that
Speaker 4:  they obviously don't wanna mess with. But you know,
Speaker 4:  I think the issue comes with them being too comfortable on the software
Speaker 4:  side, which we don't know enough about yet. 'cause there's like only
Speaker 4:  a couple switch to exclusives. The other big stuff coming is like, you
Speaker 4:  know, cross-platform stuff like Metro and Pokemon. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I am, I'm part of the reason I ask is I've been torn about how
Speaker 2:  to feel about this too. 'cause I think I've been saying all along that like,
Speaker 2:  give me the, the thesis of the original switch all the way back to
Speaker 2:  2017. I think that was the correct way to think about what
Speaker 2:  gaming should be. Just like make the processor and the wifi faster And
Speaker 2:  I will be happy and like
Speaker 2:  check and check right. That that stuff has worked. But I think a
Speaker 2:  lot of people have had the experience of like, I played the switch for a
Speaker 2:  long time and then I got a switch too and just immediately settled into
Speaker 2:  it and it's like it doesn't, I don't know if this is your experience too.
Speaker 2:  I just kind of stopped thinking about it as a new console almost immediately.
Speaker 2:  Which on the one hand sort of a huge victory, right? Like the, the upgrade
Speaker 2:  process is pretty smooth. The the thing works pretty well. I haven't turned
Speaker 2:  on my switch one since 10 minutes after I started working with the Switch
Speaker 2:  two. The whole thing just like flips and still feels like
Speaker 2:  a switch only better. And there's part of that that's like great nicely
Speaker 2:  done, perfectly executed job by Nintendo. And then there's part of me that
Speaker 2:  is like, I spent $500 on this thing and it feels more or less like the old
Speaker 2:  thing. And So I don't, I don't know what I wanted Nintendo to do to
Speaker 2:  make this feel sort of weird and wild and different. But the
Speaker 2:  company's so good at doing that most of the time when it does it that
Speaker 2:  it's almost you, you almost feel it when it's not sort of mind
Speaker 2:  blowingly new in some way. Yeah. And I don't know how
Speaker 2:  Nintendo is even supposed to split those two things simultaneously, but I
Speaker 2:  did feel that little bit of like, this is it even though it's exactly what
Speaker 2:  I wanted. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's, I mean and it honestly is the same across
Speaker 4:  every console platform at the moment as they become more like smartphones
Speaker 4:  where they're just like steady upgrades. Like the PS five has a
Speaker 4:  great controller and stuff looks better, but it's the same thing. I,
Speaker 4:  the first thing I did was play Fortnite on it to compare it to the PS four.
Speaker 4:  So it's like Nintendo is stuck in that space where it's like we wanna
Speaker 4:  keep this audience but like how do we keep them interested? I think, I think
Speaker 4:  the, the real thing will be when we see the next
Speaker 4:  Zelda and or Mario and see like what they do to
Speaker 4:  take advantage of the hardware. 'cause obviously Mario card's like the big
Speaker 4:  game in terms of sales. But I think those are the two showcase
Speaker 4:  franchises Nintendo has, I think SDO probably be a while 'cause they just
Speaker 4:  put one out last year. But like, you know, part of what made the switch
Speaker 4:  work was it launched with Breath of the Wild, right? And it was
Speaker 4:  like, you know, not only did we make an open world Zelda, but hey
Speaker 4:  you can like take it on a plane, which is like a pretty good sales
Speaker 4:  pitch Mario karts like, you know, a crowd pleaser game. But it doesn't have
Speaker 4:  that same impact especially in terms of selling.
Speaker 4:  What's different about the hardware?
Speaker 2:  Do you have a theory on what that might look like on the switch to like the,
Speaker 2:  what could be the equivalent of the now you can take it on a plane.
Speaker 4:  I mean I think if I knew what it was then it would be a boring thing for
Speaker 4:  Nintendo. I think the thing they need to do is like the Nintendo thing where
Speaker 4:  it's like, I didn't even think of this, you know, Mario Karts a little
Speaker 4:  bit of that. Like I wouldn't have expected 'em to make an open world cart
Speaker 4:  racing game And I would not have expected Donkey Conk to
Speaker 4:  be like a tent pole 3D platforming game. But those are still, you know, it's
Speaker 4:  Mario Kart and Donkey Kong. Like they need, I think a Zelda And
Speaker 4:  I, Mario that does something that shows you, hey, this couldn't exist before.
Speaker 4:  I don know if they're waiting to have like more of an install base or what
Speaker 4:  the plan is there, but I think one of those needs to do something
Speaker 4:  that I wouldn't have thought of. 'cause that's like what Nintendo is. They
Speaker 4:  do the things you don't think of and you're like, wait, this
Speaker 4:  is great and it makes perfect sense, so why didn't someone think of it?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you think it's possible that part of the answer there is to
Speaker 2:  kind of keep increasing the line of accessories? Like I just look at the,
Speaker 2:  the Piranha game chat camera that, that Nintendo
Speaker 2:  announced, which I didn't buy. I bought the boring one And I like really
Speaker 2:  regret it. It was sitting right next to the Piranha one And I should have
Speaker 2:  bought the Piranha. But I, I've always wondered why Nintendo doesn't sort
Speaker 2:  of go further down that road. It's like there's the, there's the Mario Kart
Speaker 2:  wheel, there's the plant and there's not that much else.
Speaker 2:  But like, if you're gonna embrace this modular thing, there's a huge
Speaker 2:  potential sort of way you could do all kinds of different
Speaker 2:  sorts of controller and camera stuff and make more stuff outta game chat.
Speaker 2:  And I don't know, a a deep long road of accessories Nintendo could go down.
Speaker 2:  Do you think, is that part of where it goes from here? Like
Speaker 2:  similar-ish base but new-ish ideas about how to
Speaker 2:  accessorize it?
Speaker 4:  Maybe. I mean they, they like they've done that in the past. Like some of
Speaker 4:  the biggest We games were like we Fit, which had its own,
Speaker 4:  what was it called? The balance board for, for exercising on, right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think it does sort of
Speaker 4:  fragment things in a way. So like, I think a good example is like a
Speaker 4:  ring fit adventure that came up for the switch, which was like, it just came
Speaker 4:  with like a wheel, like an exercise ring, but you
Speaker 4:  slotted the JoyCon controller. And so it's like, I think finding ways to
Speaker 4:  do that would make sense. So it's like a cheap pack in with with
Speaker 4:  a thing as opposed to like, you know, you need to need to buy an $80 controller
Speaker 4:  to, to play this game. Which severely fragments
Speaker 4:  what what you can do. Maybe there's something with like the Mouse they can
Speaker 4:  do with that when they finally make Mario Paints. I don dunno, but
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. What have you, what have you seen in some of the new sort of
Speaker 2:  digital game ideas? Like there's the new thing where
Speaker 2:  you can like kind of share games across consoles and then there's the, the
Speaker 2:  streaming stuff you were talking about. But it seems like, at least from
Speaker 2:  what I can tell, the basic interface of the switch too is like essentially
Speaker 2:  the same thing as as the last one. But they seem to have some new ideas about
Speaker 2:  how to sort of manage and share and move games around.
Speaker 2:  Has that stuff worked for you?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it seems okay. It's like it takes a
Speaker 4:  minute to wrap your head around that they're sort of trying to treat digital
Speaker 4:  games as if you have a physical card and it has to be in one switch and not
Speaker 4:  in the other. But I think actually in particular in my household where we
Speaker 4:  have like now I guess five switches, it's a actually
Speaker 4:  a way to keep track of things the way before it was pretty convoluted.
Speaker 4:  This is not necessarily less convoluted, but I think once you think of
Speaker 4:  it in the weird way that Nintendo wants you to, that these are actual
Speaker 4:  cartridges, it
Speaker 2:  Basically like turns the digital game into like a, an actual physical
Speaker 2:  object that you move from place to place Exactly. Is kind of the idea. Right.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  So like, you know, when I installed Super Mario
Speaker 4:  Wonder on the Switch too, I was like taking it out of my OLED
Speaker 4:  switch basically, but digitally, so
Speaker 4:  probably depends on the circumstances, but I think, you know, in a household
Speaker 4:  with a bunch of switches and kids, it's actually a way to share things that
Speaker 4:  make sense. It just, you know, it's weird in an Nintendo way that like,
Speaker 4:  it takes a minute to wrap your head around.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. That makes sense. And I think to me it seems like
Speaker 2:  that goes back to the same sort of thing that it's like Nintendo is
Speaker 2:  making a bunch of decisions here that that kind of individually make
Speaker 2:  sense, right? Like I get, I, I would rather just be able to have all my games
Speaker 2:  everywhere all the time. But I, I can understand why that doesn't really
Speaker 2:  work that way. And moving games between consoles is
Speaker 2:  traditionally terrible. So I'm like, okay, this is slightly convoluted, but
Speaker 2:  I get why Nintendo is doing it this way. This this sort of makes sense.
Speaker 2:  But then again it it all falls into this like yeah. It just, it just kind
Speaker 2:  of works and you kind of stop thinking about it. Yeah. Zone by the way, have
Speaker 2:  you, is everybody else in your family clamoring for a switch too now? Like
Speaker 2:  is it once they get the new one is, does the old one seem like
Speaker 2:  junk?
Speaker 4:  No. In fact we've already, like Pokemon Violet has already like jumped back
Speaker 4:  and forth between the two systems. Interesting. My kid plays whatever is
Speaker 4:  free. So I, And I think that speaks to like,
Speaker 4:  first of all, it makes it good if you're up if you have a family and you're
Speaker 4:  upgrading to switch to, 'cause they're fine with the, with the old one. So
Speaker 4:  that, that's like a positive for us. But yeah, I think it speaks to,
Speaker 4:  to this like thing of it not being that
Speaker 4:  different or exciting where it's like, I see all this stuff.
Speaker 4:  I, I honestly don't think my 12-year-old noticed much of a difference when
Speaker 4:  she spent 10 hours playing Pokemon Violet. So.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. That's that's very fair. So it seems like a
Speaker 2:  big part of the kind of open questions about the Switch to are
Speaker 2:  going to be the games that come the rest of this summer. And I think
Speaker 2:  we're due for a pretty serious run of stuff over the next couple of months.
Speaker 2:  Right. I remember the, we, we saw that direct in whatever that was like
Speaker 2:  April with a pretty, we ca we all came outta that thinking that was a pretty
Speaker 2:  strong set of launch ish games.
Speaker 2:  Is there anything you're looking at in particular being like, okay, this
Speaker 2:  is, this is gonna start to be the test of where you can really push this
Speaker 2:  thing. Obviously I think Donkey Kong bonanza is the, is the obvious one.
Speaker 2:  Is there anything else?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's an original from Software Game, which is the
Speaker 4:  student that makes Elvin Ring and Dark Souls and all that stuff like exclusive
Speaker 4:  to the Switch too. And I think like that is a
Speaker 4:  wild thing to just like say out loud that they're making a game exclusive
Speaker 4:  for the Switch two in addition to like putting Elden ring on it. And I think
Speaker 4:  actually both of those, like I think Elden ring's a very, very good technical
Speaker 4:  test, but I think a game that only exists on the Switch two from that
Speaker 4:  studio, which is like the most hardcore of, you know,
Speaker 4:  big game studios will be like a, a really good sign
Speaker 4:  if it's good that, you know, 'cause that's, that's
Speaker 4:  obviously third party game support has always been like a place that Nintendo
Speaker 4:  has struggled with and there's lots of cool stuff we're talking about at
Speaker 4:  Launch here, but they're all, they exist elsewhere. You know, split
Speaker 4:  fiction, cyberpunk Straight Fire Six are all games I can play on my
Speaker 4:  PlayStation. And So I think showing something that is only on the switch
Speaker 4:  to from a studio like that is like a real statement of intent
Speaker 4:  as long as it, you know, is good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well and to that point actually, I think one of the things I've been
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out with the switch to kind of throughout this whole launch
Speaker 2:  process is whether it is more
Speaker 2:  directly in competition with the Xbox and PlayStation than it has been before.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think, and we've talked about this over the years, like there's,
Speaker 2:  there's the Xbox and the PlayStation which are kind of playing the same game,
Speaker 2:  so to speak, right? And then Nintendo has just always been over here And
Speaker 2:  I think most people thinking about what console to buy are
Speaker 2:  probably not debating do I buy a PlayStation or do I buy a switch?
Speaker 2:  Right? Like you, you, you, you either use them in complimentary ways or you
Speaker 2:  kind of are one or the other. But it feels like, again, especially with a
Speaker 2:  lot of the games you're talking about now, coming to the Switch two, which
Speaker 2:  has this huge performance increase, it can do all this other stuff. It is
Speaker 2:  getting like split fiction is is a good example. That's the kind of game
Speaker 2:  that I don't think I would've expected on the switch the first go round.
Speaker 2:  But now it's here and we're gonna get these other AAA games and this stuff
Speaker 2:  is gonna start to be big. Like, do you think the Switch too is more
Speaker 2:  sort of next to the Xbox and PlayStation than Nintendo
Speaker 2:  has been in the past?
Speaker 4:  I mean, it is at the moment, but even the games we're talking about again,
Speaker 4:  they're like not new. You know, GTA six isn't coming to
Speaker 4:  the Switch too. I can say that pretty confidently.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 2:  Actually a big deal. I had not thought about that until you just said that,
Speaker 2:  But that is, that is a meaningful immediate difference. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I think, I think this is like a thing that actually happens a lot with antenna
Speaker 4:  consoles at Launch where they like get a bunch of third party developers
Speaker 4:  to make games for them or like ports of games that exist already
Speaker 4:  and they look great. But what'll like, shorten that gap is like shortening
Speaker 4:  the time between when these games are actually on the switch. You know, when
Speaker 4:  does Cyberpunk come out? Like three years ago? And that's like a showcase,
Speaker 4:  technical showcase for a Nintendo's new console. Right? Yeah. Fair. Which,
Speaker 4:  you know, it's, it's great, but like the Witcher four is probably not
Speaker 4:  gonna be like launch initially on the Switch too. It'll
Speaker 4:  be some sort of weird cloud game three years later.
Speaker 4:  So I think it's like maybe closer than it's ever been, but there's still
Speaker 4:  like a definite gap there.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah. So you're still, you're still buying this thing because you wanna
Speaker 2:  play Mario Kart, not because you're excited to play the best
Speaker 2:  new high-end games from studios around the industry.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like a, it's like a bonus. Yeah. That you get to do those other
Speaker 4:  things. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. Have you done any of the like retro game QB stuff? I,
Speaker 2:  I realized this morning that that's a part of this I have not dug into at
Speaker 2:  all. How is, how is that side of things? I
Speaker 4:  Mean they're, they're they're getting Q capes, they're great. That is like
Speaker 4:  the most unheralded Nintendo console. Yeah. It's like they have like
Speaker 4:  a great selection. F zero is like the fastest
Speaker 4:  racing game and
Speaker 2:  Shocking amount of enthusiasm in our comments for Yeah. For F zero.
Speaker 4:  Well it's also like Nintendo, it's forgotten it existed except for a weird
Speaker 4:  offshoot that's like Battle Royal. Yeah. Like wind
Speaker 4:  waker obviously rules and people finally respect that it looks
Speaker 4:  good. And so Caliber was like such a weird
Speaker 4:  fighting game where they put link in it. So I, I I think the game queue
Speaker 4:  games look great. I do think it's a little weird that it's like a switch
Speaker 4:  to exclusive thing. I guess I get it's a reason to sell, but I don't see
Speaker 4:  why those games couldn't run on a switch.
Speaker 2:  I also just find it very funny as a marketing exercise. Yeah. To be like,
Speaker 2:  Hey, the reason to buy our new console is to buy, is to play games from our
Speaker 2:  decades old console that most people don't think about that much anymore.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then barely sold as well. Yeah. But you know, if they put
Speaker 4:  double dash on there, then it's all worth it.
Speaker 2:  I do it. Nothing would be funnier than Double Dash being
Speaker 2:  like a bigger hit than Mario Kart world that everybody's like, actually all
Speaker 2:  I want is double Dash we're good. Forget the rest of this Open world stuff.
Speaker 2:  If
Speaker 4:  They could add like a double dash moat to world, that would be, that would
Speaker 4:  actually, I would redo my That's a great idea. Best Mario Card ever headline
Speaker 4:  for this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that is a very good idea. So, all right, so last question and then
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna let you go. I think the, the big open question, I think of
Speaker 2:  the switch to, and this seems to be kinda the overall reaction is not like,
Speaker 2:  is it, is it a good console or is it better than the switch? Like I think
Speaker 2:  we, we both sort of figured it would be, and it seems like it pretty clearly
Speaker 2:  is it's the price, right? It's the, it's the, is this
Speaker 2:  thing worth 450 or $500 depending on which version of it
Speaker 2:  you buy?
Speaker 2:  How, how easy or hard have you found it to reckon with? Like, what is
Speaker 2:  this thing at, you know, the, the $300 it used to be versus the $500 it is
Speaker 2:  now?
Speaker 4:  I think it depends on how long you've had a switch for.
Speaker 4:  Okay. If you bought a switch in 2017, then like it makes so much sense.
Speaker 4:  Like you need a new one. It's like you, this thing has been chugging
Speaker 4:  and it's a little bit more, but like, what's your other option? Like
Speaker 4:  you want to stay in this ecosystem. It makes a lot of sense. If I had just
Speaker 4:  bought a, like an ol lead last year, then I probably would not wanna upgrade.
Speaker 4:  Or I would wait until, you know, a few of those games actually come out
Speaker 4:  and you know, they sold out of them mostly. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  like doing really well. So I think, I think that's the case for a lot of
Speaker 4:  people, but I think Nintendo was also happy for that person
Speaker 4:  to have bought us last year and then wait three years and buy the
Speaker 4:  ole Switch too. So it's expensive. I'm glad they didn't go up
Speaker 4:  further after all that nonsense happened. Yeah. The day that
Speaker 4:  they showed off their console, which is pretty wild. But
Speaker 2:  It could have gotten truly ugly Yeah. There for a while. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The timing of it isn't great, but I do think, you know, it
Speaker 4:  doesn't seem to be an issue that is like really stunting its growth
Speaker 4:  at least initially.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, fair enough. Yeah. I think the the like would it be nice if it were
Speaker 2:  cheaper? Of course. But I also think it seems increasingly like this
Speaker 2:  is just what these things cost. Like are we right to be mad
Speaker 2:  that games are starting to cost $80? Yes, of course. Absolutely. I
Speaker 2:  don't think it's gonna change the fact that games are $80. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's also, you know, like $110 Canadian, so it's much worse here.
Speaker 2:  That's true. Fair enough. All right, Andrew,
Speaker 2:  congrats on finally finishing this thing. I'm assuming this means you're
Speaker 2:  never gonna play the switch to again. You're, you're done. No more, no more
Speaker 2:  games for Andrew. I mean, this is the end of your switch to a journey.
Speaker 4:  I am just going to disappear into no Man's Sky as soon as this
Speaker 4:  thing is done with.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which is now you get to go do that for fun instead of for journalism.
Speaker 2:  Yes. 'cause our jobs are very weird.
Speaker 4:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Ash Parish is here. Hi Ash.
Speaker 5:  Hi.
Speaker 2:  From your childhood home.
Speaker 5:  Yes. This is where Baby Ash grew up from when I was
Speaker 5:  about 16 to when I was about 19. So maybe not that
Speaker 5:  long. Love this for you. But we've had this house for like 20
Speaker 5:  plus years now. So
Speaker 2:  The most important question I have for you is, did you bring the switch with
Speaker 2:  you?
Speaker 5:  I absolutely did. A funny story about that is I went to the
Speaker 5:  midnight release of the Switch. I went to a physical GameStop to pick it
Speaker 5:  up and immediately after I got my switch I got on the road
Speaker 5:  and drove to Indiana. That's a five hour ride if
Speaker 5:  you're, you know, driving kind of fast. So I could
Speaker 5:  leave my dog with his grandmother while I went to Summer
Speaker 5:  Games Fest. But I had the switch with me. That was a long day. That was a
Speaker 5:  very long day.
Speaker 2:  That is a long day. So you've actually had, I would say like the the
Speaker 2:  sort of ideal potential switch experience already,
Speaker 2:  which is you've gotten to play it in a bunch of places. The the, like the
Speaker 2:  whole idea of this thing right is it's supposed to be equally at home, like
Speaker 2:  on a, on a big screen in your living room or like on the go in a
Speaker 2:  hotel room or wherever. How I have not traveled with this
Speaker 2:  thing at all yet. It has sat in its dock right there next to me every single
Speaker 2:  second I have owned it. So how does this thing travel
Speaker 5:  So it travels well with one big caveat.
Speaker 5:  First of all, I feel like I'd need a traveling case for this, which is not
Speaker 5:  something that I felt like I needed with my regular switch. I'll throw that
Speaker 5:  in the bag and keep it going and I've never had any issues. But one thing
Speaker 5:  I've, I've noticed with the switch too is like I put it in my, my
Speaker 5:  carry-on bag And I feel like I, I get this nervous feeling like I should
Speaker 5:  be protecting this. And I, when I pulled it out of
Speaker 5:  my bag to play it on the plane, I noticed that the left JoyCon
Speaker 5:  thumbs stick was not as responsive as I was used to
Speaker 5:  it being. And the right one was a little bit more responsive And I think
Speaker 5:  it may have gotten jostled or squished where the, the JoyCon may have gotten
Speaker 5:  pressed in. I managed to work it out, so it feels fine now, but I'm like,
Speaker 5:  okay, yeah, this we, we need some kind of protection because I just can't
Speaker 5:  have this out raw dogging life. Other than that,
Speaker 5:  like it's really good. I had took a picture and
Speaker 5:  I'll, and I'll put this in my blog that I write about how this switch travels
Speaker 5:  of it, sitting with the little kickstand on
Speaker 5:  those tray tables on a plane and just like sitting with it, holding it like
Speaker 5:  that. Like I thought that felt really good and I've never used, you're not
Speaker 5:  able to really do that with the original switch because the kickstand is
Speaker 5:  so thin and flimsy.
Speaker 2:  It's awful. That's, that's the word you're looking for. It's, it's awful.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is the whole thing on the switch. It goes for the
Speaker 5:  kickstand, it goes all the way across the body of the switch and it's very
Speaker 5:  tight when you like adjust it and that feels really good. So I'm sitting
Speaker 5:  on this plane, it, the kickstand is up like the, are still attached
Speaker 5:  to the unit and I'm holding it in my lap or like on this desktop thing. And
Speaker 5:  it actually felt really comfortable And I really, I really like that. I'll,
Speaker 5:  I'll have a picture for you. The battery life kind of leaves
Speaker 5:  a lot to be desired. I did see that Nintendo put out a statement that,
Speaker 5:  you know, it may just be, you may just be a glitch. I don't know about that,
Speaker 5:  but I noticed that it seems to draw a lot of power when it's
Speaker 5:  in idle mode. Mm. But it, I haven't really used it all that much
Speaker 5:  while I was at Summer Games Fest. I pulled it out a couple times to play
Speaker 5:  like when I was in my hotel room or I hadn't plugged it in And I noticed
Speaker 5:  that the battery life kind of drained even though it hadn't been like
Speaker 5:  on, on a lot. And I was really like, oh that's, that's different. I'm not
Speaker 5:  used to it. Kind of like degrading over time like that even though I hadn't
Speaker 5:  been using it. And the big thing, the the, the
Speaker 5:  glaring issue for me is that it does not pair with my
Speaker 5:  Bluetooth headphones. I have a pair of JVC just like
Speaker 5:  cheapo headphones that kind of like hang around my neck. They're like wireless
Speaker 5:  earbuds but they don't pair, I don't know why. I've tried in all different
Speaker 5:  kinds of configurations. My earbuds work with everything else.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna test it with my mom's EarPods later to see if it's just a
Speaker 5:  me issue or if it's like a thing or it's just a my switch
Speaker 5:  issue. I don't know. But I was really looking forward to being able to like
Speaker 5:  listen to the music. 'cause I was playing a hundred line last Defense Academy
Speaker 5:  on the plane And I was really looking forward to like being able to, you
Speaker 5:  know, use my earphones with it And I couldn't. And I was really upset about
Speaker 5:  this. So hopefully it's just like a me issue and not a switch
Speaker 5:  issue.
Speaker 2:  There are some really weird connection limitations I've
Speaker 2:  discovered on this thing that are the sort of thing that's like
Speaker 2:  probably fine in, you know, actual use. Like the,
Speaker 2:  the thing where you can only have two wireless controllers connected at a
Speaker 2:  time, but, but a pair of joy cons counts as two.
Speaker 2:  So it's just like,
Speaker 5:  Oh that's weird. It's,
Speaker 2:  It's super weird. It's weird. And, and the reality of it is like, okay, what
Speaker 2:  are the odds you're likely to be, have to have both a pair of joy cons and
Speaker 2:  a separate controller that you all wanna use wirelessly all at the same time.
Speaker 2:  Probably relatively small but not zero and it's not like a hard technology
Speaker 2:  problem to solve.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. One thing I will, that I just remembered, I
Speaker 5:  remember seeing that the, the switch had two USBC ports And
Speaker 5:  I was like, well why do we need two? And I real, I found the use case
Speaker 5:  for the two two. So because the battery was having such an issue, I had a
Speaker 5:  battery pack with me and because it wasn't picking up my
Speaker 5:  earbuds, I had some earphones that take A-U-S-B-C connection.
Speaker 5:  I was able to plug in the charger on the bottom and then plug in my headphones
Speaker 5:  on the top And I'm like, ah, that's smart. Because if I did, if it only had
Speaker 5:  the one I, I would have to choose between either listening or charging the
Speaker 5:  thing. So I thought that was actually okay. Nintendo, you got me on that
Speaker 5:  one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, that's pretty good. That is, that is something. So one other
Speaker 2:  travel question. Yeah. And then I'll move on from this. 'cause I think one
Speaker 2:  of the things that frustrated me a little bit of the original switch was
Speaker 2:  that the, the one of the like canonical ways you're supposed to do it was
Speaker 2:  exactly what you're describing, right? You like put prop it up somewhere
Speaker 2:  with the, the kickstand out, you take out the joycons, you hold the joycons
Speaker 2:  in both hands and you play with it detached that way. And I always felt like
Speaker 2:  the switches screen was just, just a little too small. Too small for that
Speaker 2:  to work. Yeah. And I know the switch too screen is bigger, but I've only
Speaker 2:  been able to test that in sort of like hokey ways sitting here at my desk.
Speaker 2:  Like how does it do on the, like the, the, the thing you just described,
Speaker 2:  like I wanna play this sitting in an airplane seat is like the dream. And
Speaker 2:  with the original switch it never quite hit for me. Does it work with the
Speaker 2:  switch too? Is it bigger enough?
Speaker 5:  It is bigger enough. It feels really good. Like
Speaker 5:  even in the hands, like it feels good. Like this feels more natural to me
Speaker 5:  than the switch, which kind of like, you're kind of close like this because
Speaker 5:  it is so small. But this, you're able to like relax a little bit and like,
Speaker 5:  you know, take that tension outta your shoulders as you play. And that makes
Speaker 5:  a big difference. I really enjoy that part. I haven't yet tested
Speaker 5:  it where I've got 'em, the two joy con slotted into the controller and then
Speaker 5:  like the switches away from me from a distance. But I plan on testing that
Speaker 5:  later when I try teaching my mom how to play with the switch too, to see
Speaker 5:  nice, you know, how accessible family wise the system
Speaker 5:  is. But yeah, I I think it'll be good. I think it'll be really good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, that's very exciting. I think that just adding that next thing
Speaker 2:  goes a long way for me. So what have you been playing? I think you're,
Speaker 2:  you're, you've been testing this thing like you, you were one of the first
Speaker 2:  people on our team to get a hands on with it in particular. You've like covered
Speaker 2:  all the games. What, what was like the first stuff you dove into when you
Speaker 2:  got your switch to Mario
Speaker 5:  Kart? Well, baby, like one of the things that I really was trying to
Speaker 5:  get going at Summer Games Fest was to get a bunch of people
Speaker 5:  like, you know, my colleagues at other outlets, we've all are trying our
Speaker 5:  best to get a switch to some of 'em had it delivered so they didn't have
Speaker 5:  'em with them, but some of them had them with them and just get together
Speaker 5:  this big Mario cart knockout tournament going and it just, we couldn't
Speaker 5:  make it work unfortunately. But Mario Kart is so
Speaker 5:  much fun to play on the Switch too. Like, I'm
Speaker 5:  not a Mario Kart person. I'm really not an online gamer
Speaker 5:  person, like multiplayer gamer, just, I just don't do that. But playing
Speaker 5:  Knockout Online was like the first thing I did when I turned on the system
Speaker 5:  and it was so much fun. Even though I lost pretty badly,
Speaker 5:  those people are no joke. I've also been playing, but
Speaker 5:  that's like the only like new certified switch two game that I had had. I
Speaker 5:  So on that
Speaker 2:  Front Yeah, go ahead. Before I, I'm curious like what, what do you make of
Speaker 2:  this like gentle backlash there has been to Mario Kart world being like
Speaker 2:  the launch title? I feel like the thing that I've heard, the sort of
Speaker 2:  most negative piece of, of reaction I've seen to all of the Switch stuff
Speaker 2:  is the like, oh, it's just a better switch, which we can come back to. But
Speaker 2:  I find completely ridiculous because that is exactly what I wanted. Hooray.
Speaker 2:  It's a better switch. But there is this thing where it's like people don't
Speaker 2:  think Mario Kart World is enough to be this sort of launch title
Speaker 2:  for a new console. What do you, what do you make of that?
Speaker 5:  I honestly, I feel it. I really do. Yeah. Because when you're on a plane,
Speaker 5:  right, the most fun part about Mario Kart is the ability to play
Speaker 5:  online with other people, right. When you're on a plane, you know, you don't
Speaker 5:  really have that. I mean, you could pay for wifi if you want and try to,
Speaker 5:  you know, do it that way, which I don't know why you would do that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Gotta help you. So I'm on plane help in this like, you know, bubble and I'm
Speaker 5:  like, damn, I wish I had like a chunky 60 hour RPG that I could play right
Speaker 5:  now. Which is why I turned, I didn't play Mario Kart And I turned back on
Speaker 5:  a hundred Line last Defense Academy, which is like this dang ropa like
Speaker 5:  RPG kind of thing because that's, that's what I wanted in that situation.
Speaker 5:  And there was just nothing there that could like scratch that itch because
Speaker 5:  I've already played the Zelda, I don't wanna play it again. I know that it
Speaker 5:  looks really beautiful. Like it looks like it was supposed to, you know,
Speaker 5:  all those years ago. Like now I don't wanna do that again. I don't wanna
Speaker 5:  rehash that. I want something new. And I really wish that there was some
Speaker 5:  kind of, I don't know, like Mario hint, hint that I
Speaker 5:  could have been playing while I was, you know, with no internet signal. Otherwise
Speaker 5:  I would've been playing Mario Kart. So
Speaker 2:  You that's a really interesting point. I hadn't even really thought about
Speaker 2:  that. That like, for all that there is to do in Mario
Speaker 2:  Kart world, it doesn't feel like that big a game.
Speaker 2:  Like it's very fun And I will play a ton of it, but it doesn't feel
Speaker 2:  sort of epic in scope. The way a lot of these like launch like Breath of
Speaker 2:  the Wild was a perfect example. It was like nobody could believe how epic
Speaker 2:  in scope that game was at the time. And so maybe, maybe the expectations
Speaker 2:  for like, it, it doesn't just have to be a game that's fun that I'm going
Speaker 2:  to play a lot. It has to like, you want something that sort of, you wanna
Speaker 2:  make a statement feels demonstrably different. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This, that's fair. This is a, it's a nice statement, it's an okay statement.
Speaker 5:  It's a fun statement, but it's not like the kind of statement that you should
Speaker 5:  be punching people in the face with with the launch of your new console.
Speaker 5:  Right. When I pre-order my Switch, I also put a pre-order for Donkey Kong
Speaker 5:  Bonanza because for some reason I thought that would be a, a launch title
Speaker 5:  because if it was like we wouldn't, we would have be having a totally different
Speaker 5:  conversation. 'cause I would be talking all about Donkey Kong because that
Speaker 5:  was my game of the show damn near when I was
Speaker 5:  doing the Switch to experience back in April. Like that was the game I wanted.
Speaker 5:  And I was really disappointed to find out that that wasn't a launch title.
Speaker 5:  Like what that would've been the seller. Like that would've been the thing
Speaker 5:  that would've been the thing that would've satisfied me on my plane ride.
Speaker 5:  But I, I guess I have to wait for that.
Speaker 2:  I know, I, I was a little surprised because they even set that one up like
Speaker 2:  it was going to be Yeah, yeah. The one like you And I talked After that,
Speaker 2:  that Nintendo direct and it was like, okay, this is the game
Speaker 2:  for this console.
Speaker 5:  So I guess we have to wait a little bit, but yeah. Yeah, I guess that's,
Speaker 5:  that's what we gotta do. Nintendo does things on their own time and
Speaker 5:  we gotta wait for them, let them cook. They usually don't disappoint us.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see how it goes when Donkey Kong Bonanza launches.
Speaker 2:  I mean that is true. The, the, they usually don't disappoint us. Thing is
Speaker 2:  the only part of me that is like a little willing to be patient is like,
Speaker 2:  usually it's worth it. Usually. Yeah. It'll be okay.
Speaker 2:  So what else have you been playing?
Speaker 5:  So it's just been pretty much those two, believe it or not,
Speaker 5:  like when I'm at Summer Games Fest, I don't have a lot of time to play video
Speaker 5:  games because I'm, you know, dodging protests and,
Speaker 5:  you know, going from appointment to appointment to appointment appointment.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I'll have a little downtime at the end of the day and I'm trying
Speaker 5:  to get through this, this RPG 'cause I'm really interested in the story
Speaker 5:  and it's, it's kind of fun. But that's pretty much it for right now.
Speaker 2:  What are you, what are you excited to play? What's out that you're like itching
Speaker 2:  to get into? Hmm.
Speaker 5:  What is the thing is what is out? Like I do wanna play the
Speaker 5:  welcome tour because I saw something in that game. I
Speaker 5:  know people right now are, did you ever
Speaker 2:  Think you would say the sentence out loud, no, I wanna play the welcome tour.
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 5:  I didn't. But there was something that I saw that like sparked an interest
Speaker 5:  in me when at the switch to experience that is like, I wanna learn more about
Speaker 5:  this device in my hands. And I think that was a good way to, to
Speaker 5:  impart that information. Like there's this thing where it teaches you about
Speaker 5:  like HDR and like frame rates. Like yes I know what a frame rates
Speaker 5:  is And I know what happens when frame rates are low, but I never really
Speaker 5:  understood the technical details behind like frame rates and why things
Speaker 5:  appear differently. And welcome Tour got into that And I was like, oh, that's
Speaker 5:  interesting. I could learn some things that I didn't already know about this
Speaker 5:  And I don't have that game yet and that's on my list of things to do. Maybe
Speaker 5:  I'll go download it after I'm done talking with you So I can talk more about
Speaker 5:  it. But I was really interested in that. I, And I like those little mini
Speaker 5:  games, like those little warrior aware esque mini games. I think they could
Speaker 5:  be really fun and a really nice way to introduce the switch
Speaker 5:  to my mom. So yeah, I think that is what I'm gonna do when I get off the
Speaker 5:  call with you. That's the game we'll play together instead of animal crossing.
Speaker 5:  Oh, And I did transfer my animal crossing island over from my switch
Speaker 5:  one to my switch two to see how easy that was. And that was a relatively
Speaker 5:  seamless experience. So people who are really precious about their animal
Speaker 5:  crossing islands, don't worry, you can save all your stuff. It's not a big
Speaker 5:  hassle.
Speaker 2:  I will say that was one of the things I was most pleasantly surprised by
Speaker 2:  was how easy it was to go from switch one to switch two.
Speaker 2:  Mine was slightly messy because I have it as it turns out, two Nintendo accounts
Speaker 2:  with the same email address. Oof. Which just breaks everything. I don't even
Speaker 2:  know how that happened, but I was, it was just a mess. But once I, once I
Speaker 2:  sorted that out, it was like, it's like a 10 minute process. All my stuff
Speaker 2:  got moved over and it was like I haven't had to touch my original switch
Speaker 2:  since, which has been awesome.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Very surprised by that. What do you, what's your sense of
Speaker 2:  sort of where on the spectrum this goes between like slightly better switch?
Speaker 2:  I barely even notice a difference all the way to like complete
Speaker 2:  brand new Nintendo console generation.
Speaker 5:  I'm kind kind of in the middle because of the situation we talked about before,
Speaker 5:  which is the games. Like, okay, if I had more games that
Speaker 5:  are not just ports from the switch one to the switch two, like more original
Speaker 5:  games to play, I think we would be having a different conversation. But there
Speaker 5:  aren't that many Switch two exclusives out right now. Right? There's Delta
Speaker 5:  Run, but I gotta be honest, like I was an under tail girly. I was not a Delta
Speaker 5:  in person. I know that people are freaking out and having a really great
Speaker 5:  time with the new chapters that were released with the switch to, but even
Speaker 5:  then, that doesn't feel like a switch, an exclusively
Speaker 5:  switched to experience that's, you know, it's gonna be on both consoles.
Speaker 5:  So I, I'm, I'm waiting for the games man. Like
Speaker 5:  when the games I think will tell me what, or how much more
Speaker 5:  powerful this system is. And until then, you know, we're, we're just
Speaker 5:  dealing with the cool camera and the voice chat and
Speaker 5:  you know, trying to see how many different kinds of camera inputs the switch
Speaker 5:  can take, which I've seen people are my colleagues in Slack, like, you know,
Speaker 5:  connecting their weird cameras to it and whatever. And that's fun. Almost
Speaker 5:  bought one myself And I didn't, but we'll see. It looks like, and
Speaker 5:  from what I've heard from other people, the camera really enhances things,
Speaker 5:  especially Mario Cart because you can see your friend's face, it gives you
Speaker 2:  Like, it's pretty fun. The thing where it's like their, their little head
Speaker 2:  sort of bobbing above the car is pretty great.
Speaker 5:  Gives it a little, I don't know, an extra as a qua that
Speaker 5:  enhances that fun. But I don't have that stuff yet. We'll wait. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So what, what do you think will make a switch to game a
Speaker 2:  switch to game this? Because again, if it's, if it's just a slightly better
Speaker 2:  switch, there is a world in which the thing that we
Speaker 2:  get is slightly better games, right? Everything runs a little faster. I
Speaker 2:  mean, this has been my experience so far. It's like the, the single biggest
Speaker 2:  upgrade is just that everything is faster. Yes. Which is not
Speaker 2:  a $500 upgrade all on its own, but it has been like a real meaningful, like,
Speaker 2:  quality of life improvement in my experience with this console. Every menu
Speaker 2:  is faster, everything loads faster. Like it's, it's just a vastly faster
Speaker 2:  thing. Is it possible that that's
Speaker 2:  the extent of it or it is your sense that like from what we've seen from
Speaker 2:  games that have and have not launched yet, that there is going to be something
Speaker 2:  you can do in these games that feels sort of meaningfully different even
Speaker 2:  from the Switch one?
Speaker 5:  The only answer that I can think of is Nintendo finding a
Speaker 5:  way to hit us in the face with their new JoyCon technology.
Speaker 5:  So like the little mouse thing, like they had drag and drive, which was the
Speaker 5:  three V three wheelchair basketball thing. But that for me left a lot
Speaker 5:  to be desired. It was Metro Prime four, which probably will be the game
Speaker 5:  that like makes everybody go, damn, this is a switch too. I didn't really
Speaker 5:  like it all that much. Maybe I need to have more time with it in order to,
Speaker 5:  you know, really get in the groove of things because I did not play the first
Speaker 5:  three Metro primes and I'm more of like a side scrolling
Speaker 5:  metro girly versus like the first person metro girly. Like I tried to play
Speaker 5:  those Metro Prime games and they, when they re-released them on the switch
Speaker 5:  and they kind of just didn't hold me. So I'm hoping that, you know, with
Speaker 5:  more time with Metro Prime four, I can see the vision there, but I'm
Speaker 5:  really waiting, like Nintendo's always done these really cool gimmicky things
Speaker 5:  that yeah, they look silly and whatever, but they also really work. They
Speaker 5:  were really fun. Like we had that with the Joycons, with like Nintendo Switch
Speaker 5:  Sports and Ring Fit Adventure, those kinds of things. Right. That's what
Speaker 5:  makes this console feel different from your Xboxes and your PlayStations.
Speaker 5:  I'm waiting on that, but I am really, I really cannot conceive
Speaker 5:  of how they make those mouse controls fun because the little bit I saw of
Speaker 5:  it was not fun for me and kind of painful.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. It, it does seem like that thing could be really cool
Speaker 2:  or it could be very like Microsoft connecting in that it's
Speaker 2:  like a nifty thing that exists in three games. Exactly. And that's fine as
Speaker 2:  far as it goes, but it's not, no one's gonna remember the connect
Speaker 2:  as like the thing that made the Xbox work. You know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  I trust Nintendo's innovation a little bit more than I trust
Speaker 5:  Microsoft's and PlayStations, which makes me sound like one of those, like
Speaker 5:  Nintendo fanboy per people. I am not, I am platform
Speaker 5:  agnostic. Can I take it with me on the go? Yes. Okay. I'm in.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's a good segue, David.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Wait, last thing I, I am curious about your controller setup.
Speaker 2:  I just bought a pro controller for the Switch two and I'm feeling
Speaker 2:  a lot of feelings about it because it's very good and it was also $85 and
Speaker 2:  that fills me with rage. Every time I look at it. I What's your, what's your
Speaker 2:  setup?
Speaker 5:  My setup is I have not put this thing in a dock yet. 'cause I don't particularly
Speaker 5:  care about it. That's not how I play these games. That's not how I used my
Speaker 5:  switch one either. This was in my hand, in my lap at all times. Okay. And
Speaker 5:  I am very satisfied with that experience so far. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I, I buy that
Speaker 5:  I will try it for sake of, you know, whatever, to have something to
Speaker 5:  compare it a against, but like, I just don't care. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And you haven't found it like heavy or bulky? I think I've seen a surprising
Speaker 2:  number of people be like, this thing is enormous And I, I mean at least to
Speaker 2:  me that has not felt true.
Speaker 5:  No, it's pretty much the same. It's a same profile as
Speaker 5:  the, the Steam Deck to me with like, it's thinner so it feels
Speaker 5:  better in the hand. It doesn't like give me claw hand the same way the the
Speaker 5:  Steam Deck does because your hands are in this like weird, they can't quite
Speaker 5:  close like this like they would around a, a controller, nor are they like
Speaker 5:  this where they're more relaxed. It's just like this middle part that makes
Speaker 5:  me, you know, my hands cramp up. I hate it, but it feels really natural
Speaker 5:  in my hands. It feels, it feels like it should have because like I can, you
Speaker 5:  know, stretch out my shoulders and relax versus being real close when you
Speaker 5:  are with the smaller original switch.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I, I, that's definitely been my experience too. The, the little
Speaker 2:  bit I've played with is just like sitting on the couch or like up in bed
Speaker 2:  or whatever, like I have not experienced it as heavy once. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  think part of it is like I do a lot of like lying in bed holding an iPad
Speaker 2:  above my face and that I'm constantly worried I'm gonna like drop on my
Speaker 2:  head, but this is normally like sitting in my lap and I have my arms propped
Speaker 2:  up somewhere. And I don't know, this just doesn't feel like a problem to
Speaker 2:  me the same way
Speaker 5:  I just had this vision of you of like playing a switch like this and I'm
Speaker 5:  like, I would drop that on my head. I would have like blunt force trauma
Speaker 5:  every day if I played.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I have, I have dropped iPads on my face. I like asked. That's terrible.
Speaker 2:  iPads plural. I have dropped on my face over years.
Speaker 5:  Oh no, no. And those things are heavy. No, you don't want that going on your
Speaker 5:  skull. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's not, I don't recommend it. It's not a good time. You mentioned the
Speaker 2:  Xbox and the, the other handheld news of the week
Speaker 2:  was a new Xbox e handheld console that you
Speaker 2:  also got to try. Yeah. That a bunch of people have sent to me as a like,
Speaker 2:  potentially interesting way. I was on this podcast a while ago being like,
Speaker 2:  dear God, just give me a device I can play FIFA on. And that device
Speaker 2:  eventually became the switch and
Speaker 2:  it's, it's fine. It's not the best version of it, but it's fine. But then
Speaker 2:  I look and it's like, oh, we've been waiting for Xbox handhelds for forever.
Speaker 2:  This is kind of maybe starting to happen. It
Speaker 5:  Is, it is happening. I, So I was at the Xbox
Speaker 5:  event at summer Game Fest. They had hands-on, so
Speaker 5:  it was really a hands-on with gears of War Reloaded. So they're doing
Speaker 5:  another remaster of Gears of War Congratulations. Sure. And they had
Speaker 5:  the game on like every different kind of console that it can run so you can
Speaker 5:  compare. So they had it on an Xbox, they had it on a PlayStation, they had
Speaker 5:  it on a pc, they had it on one of the vanilla R
Speaker 5:  allies and then they also had the ROG
Speaker 5:  Xbox Ally X, we gotta talk to Microsoft. We
Speaker 5:  gotta sit 'em down and be like, dude, you gotta suck at naming things. You're
Speaker 5:  making this so unnecessarily complicated. I just,
Speaker 5:  I hate the naming convention that they just seem to stick with.
Speaker 5:  But I played Gears of War Reloaded on the
Speaker 5:  original Rogue Ally and then I went over to the Xbox R
Speaker 5:  Ally and the difference, like
Speaker 5:  I, I put that thing in my hand and I'm like, I need this, I need this device
Speaker 5:  really, because the way that it's set up is it has like the,
Speaker 5:  the, the handholds like extend away from the console so it feels
Speaker 5:  more like you're actually gripping a controller versus the Steam Deck
Speaker 5:  where it's just like this flat rectangular profile. And that little bit of
Speaker 5:  difference met so much because I could curl my hand more naturally.
Speaker 5:  And I, I have just, like I said, I, I have this like claw hand situation
Speaker 5:  with the Steam Deck where after a couple of hours of play, like my hand cramps
Speaker 5:  up And I, And I hate the way that it feels, but this, even though I'd only
Speaker 5:  got to play with it a little bit, it felt so much better. And everybody that
Speaker 5:  I was with in my little play testing pod said the same thing. Like, oh my
Speaker 5:  God, this feels incredible. Same weight as like a Steam Deck.
Speaker 5:  Like it performed really well. Like I, I went from the original
Speaker 5:  ally to the new Ally playing gears of war And I felt like my, my, I improved
Speaker 5:  a little bit with my shooting and whatever. Okay. Like I don't like first
Speaker 5:  person shooters, but I do like gears because I think that's more my speed
Speaker 5:  in terms of, you know, shooting like those cover base shooting versus like
Speaker 5:  the twitchiness of like a Call of Duty. And I, I felt like I got better and
Speaker 5:  I'm like, oh this is, this is kind of sexy and like you, I've been waiting
Speaker 5:  for a, a game pass device essentially. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  am not smart. So I don't know how to mod my Steam Deck to do all that.
Speaker 5:  Like, you guys can do that. Go with the grace and favor of the Lord. That
Speaker 5:  is not for me. Give me a device that is all there So I don't have to
Speaker 5:  think about that. And if that is satisfied by this Xbox
Speaker 5:  R no ROG ally Xbox, no, I've still got it wrong for
Speaker 5:  whatever, you know what I'm talking about. If that device can satisfy that
Speaker 5:  itch, it's day one for me.
Speaker 2:  If I'm thinking about this right, it's basically like a, a normal sort of
Speaker 2:  handheld console that is like growing an Xbox controller, is that? Yes.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  Kind of. It's not, it doesn't like super protrude out, but it protrudes out
Speaker 5:  just enough that your hand can kind of close on it like a fist versus holding
Speaker 5:  it like this and that, that that little difference is a lot.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I like that. So, And I would assume the, from what I understand of
Speaker 2:  most of these consoles, the biggest thing people want from an Xbox
Speaker 2:  version of this as opposed to just a normal handheld console is better
Speaker 2:  software, right? Like the, the thing everybody on our team keeps telling
Speaker 2:  me is the problem with all of these handheld consoles is Windows yes. That
Speaker 2:  like you can build all the great hardware you want and Windows will just
Speaker 2:  ruin it for you. All you need is a good home screen and then just play the
Speaker 2:  games. And it is wild how hard that is with Windows
Speaker 5:  Take an Xbox, you know, like they had that big plastic cube
Speaker 5:  thing that they molded and that reveal video just like take a
Speaker 5:  Xbox series s or X or whatever and put a screen on it and just
Speaker 5:  give that to me. Give me the Xbox interface, don't mess around
Speaker 5:  and try to make it fancy with Windows. I know they have to do that because
Speaker 5:  this is also gonna be a device that plays third party stores as well. So
Speaker 5:  there's gonna be some
Speaker 5:  shenanigans with the software that I'm gonna have to be able to navigate.
Speaker 5:  But if you just, just, where is the Xbox in a handheld form? We have a
Speaker 5:  PlayStation in a handheld form, we have a switch in a handheld form, we have
Speaker 5:  a PC in a handheld form. Why is it so difficult for Xbox to make an Xbox
Speaker 5:  in a handheld form? Like I I, I really don't understand the disconnect there.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that's starting to change in a meaningful way? Like it's, it's
Speaker 2:  clearly not an accident that they put this thing out there in front of people.
Speaker 2:  Is it, is, is 2025 the year of the handheld Xbox
Speaker 2:  finally? Do you think?
Speaker 5:  We'll see it really depends on how
Speaker 5:  well everything runs on that Xbox Ally. Like we
Speaker 5:  really have to see more of that interface, that ui. There's this
Speaker 5:  whole thing about whether or not a game is Xbox play anywhere or if it's
Speaker 5:  something that you have to stream through the cloud because this is not a,
Speaker 5:  you can't just boot up an Xbox Ally I believe and just play whatever
Speaker 5:  Xbox Games you have. You're, you're probably streaming them. They don't play
Speaker 5:  them natively. I mean, unless they have like a specific designation that's
Speaker 5:  a big problem. I think what consumers want, especially consumers like me
Speaker 5:  who are kind of like on the low tech side where we don't, you know, do modding
Speaker 5:  or anything like that. We just want the same experience we have at home in
Speaker 5:  our hands. And the other two can do that. Why can't Xbox?
Speaker 2:  Right. I do think you just made an incredibly compelling argument for the
Speaker 2:  switch too. All of that is like, there are the, the, the
Speaker 2:  end of this road for the handheld Xbox I think is probably pretty great and,
Speaker 2:  and Game Pass makes a lot of sense. Like you cans, you can see where it
Speaker 2:  might go, but right now it's like, oh, would you like to look at a long checklist
Speaker 2:  to see if you can play your games or would you like to buy a switch to Exactly
Speaker 2:  correct. I it, that seems easy to me right now. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  it feels like there's some real catching up to do there for almost everybody
Speaker 2:  else trying to play this game
Speaker 5:  For some reason Xbox likes to make things needlessly complicated. It it don't
Speaker 5:  gotta be that hard buddy, just put the console in my hand.
Speaker 5:  It's real. Make that happen and you'll it's real and you'll literally print
Speaker 5:  money. Put it in my hand, print money
Speaker 2:  Xbox Series X with a screen, give it to me. This is it.
Speaker 2:  All right, well Ash, you are home. You have a mom to go teach about the switch.
Speaker 2:  Keep us posted on how this goes. Do the welcome tour and let me know if it's
Speaker 2:  worth the $10. I have not spent the $10 on principle, but like
Speaker 2:  if it's worth it, I'll, I'll do it. So keep me posted. Okay,
Speaker 5:  I will definitely do that.
Speaker 2:  All right, thank you for being here. We gotta take a break. We're gonna come
Speaker 2:  back with more switch stuff. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast hotline as
Speaker 2:  always, the number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. You can email vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. We got a whole bunch of stuff coming up this summer to do
Speaker 2:  so. Send us all of your questions for now. We're talking switch
Speaker 2:  today. We have a question about the switch.
Speaker 6:  Hey there, Vergecast, this is Scott calling from Australia.
Speaker 6:  My question's about the switch to mainly about
Speaker 6:  considering the economics and the pricing because this is the first time
Speaker 6:  we've seen the most recent generation where it hasn't gone down in
Speaker 6:  price. The switch kept the 2 99 price point. Other consoles are
Speaker 6:  staying the same or going up and now the switch to is also
Speaker 6:  a, a bump up from previous consoles. I'm just wondering
Speaker 6:  this is the first time it's ever happened and might this be the last
Speaker 6:  generation of consoles that we see for some time until
Speaker 6:  there's some kind of streamlining on the economics of making
Speaker 6:  manufacturing cheaper again or cost of living changes.
Speaker 6:  We've kind of peaked out on the, I think what the hardware does generally,
Speaker 6:  but I don't really know how much more we can do with
Speaker 6:  hardware and pricing with upgrades if this pattern
Speaker 6:  of keeping the prices the same for seven years continues. So curious
Speaker 6:  what you think. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Alright. If ever there was a Sean Hollister coated VERGE cast hotline question,
Speaker 2:  this is it. Sean Hollister, thanks for being here.
Speaker 7:  Hi, thanks for having me. Oh my goodness.
Speaker 2:  I feel like we have to talk about this in two pieces, right? There's the
Speaker 2:  like at least what do we do with the economics of consoles and then there's
Speaker 2:  the, is this the last console, which is like a mind bending thing that we
Speaker 2:  should talk about, but I'm just curious to how you're thinking
Speaker 2:  about the price of all of this. We talked a little bit about it with Andrew
Speaker 2:  and Ash, but the, like I had not thought about until we heard this question
Speaker 2:  that the thing where the price of the console stayed
Speaker 2:  consistent or even went up over time is
Speaker 2:  genuinely weird and unusual in the history of gaming. Yeah. What do you
Speaker 2:  make of where we are at this moment?
Speaker 7:  Oh gosh, I feel like there are two camps here, two very, very vocal
Speaker 7:  camps. One of them is, hey, every time Apple
Speaker 7:  introduces a new iPhone, the price of previous
Speaker 7:  iPhones goes down in price, right? They're like, let's pass that savings
Speaker 7:  along to you. They're like, yes, please give your old iPhones to other
Speaker 7:  people who, who need them so that everybody could be on iPhone please,
Speaker 7:  folks who couldn't afford the latest and greatest now afford the last year's
Speaker 7:  model. Let's do it that way. And that way it seems like every year
Speaker 7:  you can get more for your money. And the other camp
Speaker 7:  is console prices and game prices have been
Speaker 7:  pretty stable for a very, very long time. They've gone up
Speaker 7:  a little bit here and a little bit there. I mean it was certainly a shock
Speaker 7:  when they announced the PlayStation three at 590, 90 US dollars, right? Giant
Speaker 7:  enemy crab. That was this ridiculous moment for a lot of people.
Speaker 7:  How could it possibly cost so much? But they've actually been relatively
Speaker 7:  stable. The switch is a seven,
Speaker 7:  8-year-old console that's now being replaced with a new version.
Speaker 7:  And me personally, I think I'm more in the, in, in the first camp in the,
Speaker 7:  you should get more for your money seven years later because I would
Speaker 7:  expect that the switch would get this much better in that amount
Speaker 7:  of time at the same price. But for those who have been
Speaker 7:  seeing how weird it is, these prices have stayed so stable.
Speaker 7:  This is an opportunity, a kind of a once in a many generation
Speaker 7:  opportunity for these companies to finally charge more money because they
Speaker 7:  have the tariffs going on, the the threat of
Speaker 7:  of of inflation everywhere. They can say, well, it costs us
Speaker 7:  more now we can finally afford to charge you a bit more too.
Speaker 7:  And I kind of wanna resist that, but I also see where the others are
Speaker 7:  coming from.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's tricky. It does seem like, on the one hand it is
Speaker 2:  certainly true that there are, you know, different economic headwinds facing
Speaker 2:  these companies. Like we weren't sure what the switch to was gonna cost
Speaker 2:  for a while there. I don't think Nintendo knew what it was gonna cost for
Speaker 2:  a while there. And yet I think about the, the price of games
Speaker 2:  which has gone sort of inexorably upwards over the last several years. And
Speaker 2:  it really does feel like for good and evil
Speaker 2:  simultaneously, these companies are poking at the
Speaker 2:  edges of what people are willing to pay more than ever. And I think there
Speaker 2:  is just this sense that games are expensive and they have
Speaker 2:  huge, huge audiences And I think a lot of these companies have figured
Speaker 2:  out they probably could make more money from them. And you could feel about
Speaker 2:  that however you want, but in a, in a, like in a shareholder
Speaker 2:  capitalism era, like of course they're gonna raise prices. So I think it's
Speaker 2:  like, it, it's both a bummer and makes perfect sense to me. All at the same
Speaker 2:  time
Speaker 7:  In the Tendo 64 era games cost 60, 70, even
Speaker 7:  $80 sometimes. Yeah. In Tendo 64 we're talking about like what,
Speaker 7:  95, 96 for Nintendo 64. And to find out that
Speaker 7:  people are angry about that, it irks a lot of people inside game
Speaker 7:  companies where like our budgets have ballooned. Our, our, our players have,
Speaker 7:  you know, there's so many more players now we have to like, we have to build
Speaker 7:  all this extra content for them. The graphics level, there's so many more
Speaker 7:  things you have to do for them, but it's really about
Speaker 7:  what consumers will take. At the end of the day, it's about what are we willing
Speaker 7:  to pay? And many companies, you know, they've
Speaker 7:  decided that in order to fund these bigger budgets, they're going to have
Speaker 7:  to fund big packs of DLC. They're gonna be like, we have to have all these
Speaker 7:  other things for you to purchase these DLC, these HD texture packs.
Speaker 7:  It's now $10 for each of these switch two games to get the advancements there.
Speaker 7:  That might have been a free patch on a PC game like five years ago. Now they're
Speaker 7:  like, okay, well we're gonna charge you a little bit more there too. And
Speaker 7:  the nickel and dimming effect of this co of companies charging you more for
Speaker 7:  all of these little things that grs on us too. But we
Speaker 7:  seem to be more willing to accept that, you know, death by a thousand
Speaker 7:  cuts than we are by all at once. Now games are $80 now games are
Speaker 7:  $90.
Speaker 2:  It is true. It's, it's a good point. I had not, I I've probably spent
Speaker 2:  more in like $5 increments,
Speaker 2:  like by a vast margin than I have just on more expensive consoles, right?
Speaker 2:  Like the, the the way that they bleed you is, is the micro transactions.
Speaker 2:  That's where the real money is selling you the console the first time
Speaker 2:  is not how these companies are going to make most of their money going forward.
Speaker 2:  And that that's probably bad. Like you could, you could maybe argue
Speaker 2:  that each of these things should be a thousand dollars and then there shouldn't
Speaker 2:  be any micro transactions inside of games and that might be a better world
Speaker 2:  to live in. But that is in no way the world we live in and is not where
Speaker 2:  we're headed.
Speaker 7:  It isn't. The price of the switch to is really complicated that when you
Speaker 7:  get into this idea that like, is this, is this like the end of consoles as
Speaker 7:  we know them now that we're seeing like the prices go up so dramatically.
Speaker 7:  I wanna push back on that a little bit before we get to the second part about,
Speaker 7:  is this the end of consoles? So the switch to price
Speaker 7:  is, is very intriguing because in the
Speaker 7:  United States it's coming at a time when we
Speaker 7:  can see the existing switches stay on shelves at lower prices.
Speaker 7:  And we can see that the PlayStation five is like a pretty good deal
Speaker 7:  compared to a switch two. And that is just not the case over
Speaker 7:  in Japan. Over in Japan where they are also having to sell a lot of these
Speaker 7:  switch toss over there. The PlayStations are all
Speaker 7:  ridiculously more expensive. Sony has raised the prices of PlayStations
Speaker 7:  three times over there. Oh wow. And they've raised them almost the rest of
Speaker 7:  the world except for the United States. The United States is like the one
Speaker 7:  outlier where Sony's like, we'll keep the prices fine over
Speaker 7:  there because we really, really care about that audience over in Japan.
Speaker 7:  There's this almost a sense of gratitude towards Nintendo for this price
Speaker 7:  that's only like a certain amount more than the original switch because it's
Speaker 7:  not anywhere near as bad as what you'd have to play for a PlayStation over
Speaker 7:  there. And because of the way the exchange rate is
Speaker 7:  working right now, if Nintendo brought out the switch
Speaker 7:  to in Japan at kind of like the price that
Speaker 7:  we would be seeing over here for inflation, people would
Speaker 7:  descend on Japan and buy all those and bring them to other places and do
Speaker 7:  all kinds of weird arbitrage because you can just get so much more
Speaker 7:  in Japan for your dollar right now because of the exchange rate.
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting. So what, what do you make of this? Is this the
Speaker 2:  last console thing? Because I think there is a, there is a version of
Speaker 2:  the story here that says these things are going to get more expensive but
Speaker 2:  you're going to buy them much less often, right? Like already
Speaker 2:  the the console generations are, are pretty far apart. And
Speaker 2:  if we're gonna get to the point where most of the money is in games and most
Speaker 2:  of the money is in live service stuff, maybe we hit the point where
Speaker 2:  either the console becomes something you replace the way you replace like
Speaker 2:  a car or it becomes sort of irrelevant altogether and this just
Speaker 2:  stops being like a, a piece of really expensive hardware that you buy.
Speaker 2:  But I think our caller here is basing this on the theory that
Speaker 2:  maybe we're maxing out the technology available for video games.
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna go on a limb and guess that you do not think that is true.
Speaker 7:  I I I definitely don't, but it really depends on the company.
Speaker 7:  Microsoft seems to have already decided that that
Speaker 7:  was the last full Xbox where, you know, the, the Xbox series
Speaker 7:  X and SI mean they've already decided that that is the last time
Speaker 7:  they put out a box and the box is the only thing they've
Speaker 7:  decided very, very clearly that Xbox
Speaker 7:  that that you're, that you're streaming is a big chunk of that, that you're
Speaker 7:  going to pay for a subscription service to stream your games. That you're
Speaker 7:  gonna be able to play them on Windows systems that look and feel like Xbox
Speaker 7:  that you're going to, that they're, they're going to merge these things into
Speaker 7:  what's going to be one seamless al Does that mean they stop selling a box?
Speaker 7:  I don't think so, right? But they've already decided that it's going to be
Speaker 7:  just one part of their strategy. Over on the PlayStation side of
Speaker 7:  things, what we think is happening, what the rumors seem to be pointing to
Speaker 7:  is it becomes a continuum where the next
Speaker 7:  big PlayStation entry is not like a PlayStation six that
Speaker 7:  replaces the PlayStation five as a one-to-one. Maybe it's going to be a PlayStation
Speaker 7:  handheld. Hmm. Maybe it's going to be, you know, we, we've got a PlayStation
Speaker 7:  portal streaming device there. But the idea being there that
Speaker 7:  we'd already seen with the PlayStation four, the
Speaker 7:  PlayStation four pro, the PlayStation five, the PlayStation five pro
Speaker 7:  that we've reached a a, a kind of a PC graphics card
Speaker 7:  level of purchasing where you pay for the amount
Speaker 7:  of power you want to have and you play all
Speaker 7:  the same games on it with different levels of power. So if you get the PS
Speaker 7:  five pro, those games are gonna look the best and if you get the PS five,
Speaker 7:  they're gonna look a little bit worse. And if you get the PS four pro a little
Speaker 7:  bit worse, but they all basically play the same exact games, many of
Speaker 7:  which you could play on PC with different levels of graphic power too. The
Speaker 7:  next entry there might be the PlayStation five handheld
Speaker 7:  or the PlayStation 5.5 or whatever you wanna call this in between
Speaker 7:  step where instead of them going to a full PlayStation six, they shrink
Speaker 7:  down the amount of performance that you have to maybe, maybe
Speaker 7:  it's a PS four pro level of performance or maybe it's PS like a a
Speaker 7:  PS five light level of performance, but you can now take it with you, like
Speaker 7:  you take a switch with you and you got a couple hours apply on those same
Speaker 7:  PS five games. I think that's the direction that's going.
Speaker 2:  What that does suggest then is that maybe we're headed to a
Speaker 2:  point where we're used to these consoles being
Speaker 2:  kind of step function improvements performance wise, right? Like the PS four
Speaker 2:  to the PS five And I guess especially the PS three to the PS four was like
Speaker 2:  a huge like super computer leap in,
Speaker 2:  in performance. And what I was gonna ask you coming
Speaker 2:  in was like, okay, we've had this big run of graphic cards from Nvidia and,
Speaker 2:  and we're in this like sort of newly invigorated space
Speaker 2:  of PC gaming in a lot of ways, but it also sort of seems like that
Speaker 2:  is is hitting a plateau in some ways where like
Speaker 2:  the, the games are only so good and the, the chips are only so good and they,
Speaker 2:  they kind of run at different speeds. But maybe what it sounds like is actually
Speaker 2:  what's gonna happen is there's going to continue to be the sort of top of
Speaker 2:  the line thing, but because it's not the only thing
Speaker 2:  anymore because you don't have to just buy the fancy one because there are
Speaker 2:  other ones available now that maybe what happens is the top
Speaker 2:  of the line thing doesn't improve as fast. Does that make
Speaker 2:  sense? Like if you have this whole spectrum, you don't have to make the next
Speaker 2:  thing the best thing because it's just gonna be the the one for the people
Speaker 2:  who want the most fancy thing.
Speaker 7:  I think that's very much right. I don't know if it's because it has
Speaker 7:  to be that way or because the companies want it to be that way if it has
Speaker 7:  to be that way now in this moment, in this
Speaker 7:  geo-economic climb with tariffs and
Speaker 7:  supply chain issues and all kinds of things that were previously figured
Speaker 7:  out all of a sudden not being figured out or, or if it has to be this way
Speaker 7:  because Nvidia and a MD see all the profit in generative ai. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And they wanna put all of the manufacturing resources toward that and very
Speaker 7:  little towards gaming. If it has to be that way right now and it
Speaker 7:  could change back to the step function later. I think there are a
Speaker 7:  lot of people both inside the companies and us gamers who would
Speaker 7:  like it to go back to step change. But there are a lot of benefits to the
Speaker 7:  incremental cycle. I mean, in the world of PCs, there are new graphics cards
Speaker 7:  every two to three years. People don't buy new graphics cards every
Speaker 7:  two to three years. Right? Though not unless they are the diehards. You can
Speaker 7:  wait 5, 7, 8, 10 years before you buy your
Speaker 7:  next graphics card and all of a sudden all of your games look amazingly better
Speaker 7:  and they run it smoother Frame rates the same games that you had a decade
Speaker 7:  ago. We're starting to see the benefits of that in handhelds as
Speaker 7:  well with the Steam Deck and some of these Windows platforms where some people,
Speaker 7:  it's been so long since they've been in PC gaming
Speaker 7:  that those same games they played a long time ago look better on this
Speaker 7:  handheld than they did on their last desktop pc.
Speaker 7:  That's how long some people wait now because that is possible in pc
Speaker 7:  And I would love for that to be possible in console
Speaker 7:  two for a very long time. It was impossible because of
Speaker 7:  backwards compatibility concerns. I mean, if you tried to develop a
Speaker 7:  game for the PlayStation three's cell processor, which was
Speaker 7:  infamously difficult to develop for and required, you know, this
Speaker 7:  very specialized hardware and then you go to the PlayStation four and
Speaker 7:  you, you're like, okay, well I'm gonna play all my PS three games on that,
Speaker 7:  right? It was like, no, you, you would need so much brute force horsepower
Speaker 7:  to do that, sell stuff on this new X 86 chip that's more
Speaker 7:  like a, a Windows machine. But now that all the consoles
Speaker 7:  and all the handhelds are using the
Speaker 7:  same underlying chip architecture, they're basically all
Speaker 7:  playing PC games more or less. You could kind
Speaker 7:  of have a world where you just say, I'm willing to spend this much money
Speaker 7:  for this much horsepower and my stuff will play on it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Which, which actually seems like on sort of both parts
Speaker 2:  of the question here, a good outcome, right? You, you end up in a position
Speaker 2:  where I, I'm not forced to buy the thing that is getting relentlessly more
Speaker 2:  expensive because I don't, I don't need the most powerful highest end
Speaker 2:  thing I'm able to sort of scale down to fit both my budgets and my needs.
Speaker 2:  But also it means you can get lots of different variations of
Speaker 2:  the thing rather than just being like, here is the new Xbox, take it or lead
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 7:  You absolutely can. And that's what we're seeing with Nintendo. Nintendo
Speaker 7:  says, here's the switch too, by the way. We are also still selling
Speaker 7:  three other models of Switch. You don't wanna pay, you know,
Speaker 7:  450 for a switch too. We've got our switch ole, we've got our switch and
Speaker 7:  we've got our switch light and they're all there ready for you to play
Speaker 7:  relatively the same game. Now we don't know if Nintendo's gonna turn around
Speaker 7:  and be like, actually 90% of our switch two library, all of these
Speaker 7:  new games we're developing will only be playable on switch two. Right? And
Speaker 7:  they make a big break there and, and then people who are, you know,
Speaker 7:  kind of forced to upgrade from Switch on the Xbox
Speaker 7:  side of things, you don't have to worry about that. Probably on the future
Speaker 7:  PlayStation side of things, you don't have to worry about that as much because
Speaker 7:  there will be streaming to fill in some of the gaps. But
Speaker 7:  none of these are anywhere near as open as PC
Speaker 7:  where I'm like, okay, games I have 10, 20, 30 years ago
Speaker 7:  still play on a modern PC and often weigh
Speaker 7:  the heck better because of everything that's happened in between with
Speaker 7:  horsepower and monitors getting better and so on.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, fair enough. All right, well this actually made me feel better. This
Speaker 2:  was, this was very exciting. Thank you for doing this Scott. I hope this
Speaker 2:  helped. Sean, thank you as always. Of
Speaker 7:  Course. Thanks so much.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for the show today. Thank you to everybody who came on
Speaker 2:  to talk to me and thank you as always for listening. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  questions, feelings, switch to games you're liking and wanna tell us about,
Speaker 2:  thoughts about the battery life. We've been hearing really mixed things about
Speaker 2:  battery life, anything on your mind about the switch to or really anything
Speaker 2:  in general hit us up. Vergecast at The Verge dot com is the email
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one is the hotline we absolutely love hearing from you.
Speaker 2:  It's the single best part about doing this show and we're gonna keep covering
Speaker 2:  this thing like all summer, keep it locked on The Verge for all of Andrew's
Speaker 2:  coverage. His review of the device, all the stuff Ash has been writing about
Speaker 2:  her experiences and the games, all this stuff. There's a huge run of
Speaker 2:  games coming this summer for the Switch two And I think it might change how
Speaker 2:  a lot of people feel about the console for better or for worse. So
Speaker 2:  keep it locked and tell us everything that you're experiencing about the
Speaker 2:  Switch two as well. This show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon
Speaker 2:  Kiefer and Will Pour The Vergecast is VERGE production and part of the Vox
Speaker 2:  Media podcast network. Neli, And I'll be back on Friday to talk about all
Speaker 2:  of the other tech news happening because the tech news, it just keeps happening.
Speaker 2:  You would think it's summer, but it just keeps happening. Also, I should
Speaker 2:  say that at some point here in the near future, one or both of Neli
Speaker 2:  And I are just going to sort of mysteriously disappear to go have kids.
Speaker 2:  These things happen without a lot of notice sometimes, so
Speaker 2:  we'll, we'll try and, you know, make the transition as seamless as possible,
Speaker 2:  but if we suddenly disappear, don't worry. We will be back
Speaker 2:  until then, we'll see you next time. Rock and roll