# Transcript
ID: 9bb250ee-5986-4dac-a342-b3b36dac277e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-760365368435605779/-6594410650717155186/s93290-US-6074s-1755857389.mp3
Description: It’s Pixel week. Jake, Vee, and Allison are chatting about all things Google. First, there’s the Pixel 10, 10 Pro, 10 Pro XL, and 10 Pro Fold, which get a mix of hardware upgrades (dust-proofing on a foldable!) and downgrades (a worse camera on the Pixel 10?) and a ton of new AI features, including Magic Cue and Pro Res Zoom, which puts AI right inside the camera app. Next, there’s the Pixel Watch 4, Fitbit’s AI fitness coach, the Pixel Buds 2A, and a tease of Google’s next smart home speaker. Finally, we wrap it up with the Thunder Round and a discussion of Hank Green’s Focus Friend, Ricoh’s GR IV, Netflix’s new content strategy, Masimo’s attempt to sue over the Apple Watch again, and most importantly, Chipotle’s drone delivery.
Speaker 5:  Hello and Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of things that look
Speaker 5:  like photos, but may or may not actually be photos.
Speaker 5:  I'm Jake Kanakas, executive editor of The Verge. Neli and David remain on
Speaker 5:  parental leave. They'll be back later this year with me in the studio today,
Speaker 5:  the song. Hi. And from Seattle, we've got Allison Johnson.
Speaker 5:  Hello. And Allison is hosting Tuesday's Vergecast episode
Speaker 5:  two. So tune in for that. It's gonna be a good time. That's
Speaker 2:  Right. Yep. My first episode,
Speaker 5:  I'm very stoked, very exciting. Today
Speaker 5:  is P Pixel Extravaganza. We've got a ton of Pixel stuff to talk about, like
Speaker 5:  literally like too many Pixel things to talk about.
Speaker 5:  Nonstop series of announcements on Wednesday at the Made by
Speaker 5:  Google event. It was four Pixel, 10 models, some
Speaker 5:  new earbuds, some new smart watches, ton of
Speaker 5:  ai, way too much ai, VNL got a chance to play with all this stuff. Before
Speaker 5:  we talk about the phones, we have to talk about the event because
Speaker 5:  this is, this is the single weirdest
Speaker 5:  I'm stoked. Announcement event. Traumatized. You know, can I say
Speaker 5:  the first episode that I think we were doing without Neli
Speaker 5:  and David? Yeah. I believe began with UV
Speaker 5:  going to the same venue for
Speaker 5:  same,
Speaker 2:  Same place, different venue,
Speaker 5:  Same place. Okay. Same place, different venue and, and saying,
Speaker 5:  that was a chaotic time. I don't wanna do this again. And now Google has
Speaker 5:  made you go back Yeah. To the Brooklyn Navy yard. I
Speaker 6:  Was not pleased finding out I was at the Brooklyn Navy Yard. I was like,
Speaker 6:  really? Guys? Really, really, it was slightly
Speaker 6:  better organized though. It's, it was at this place called Steiner Studios,
Speaker 6:  which is a movie studio, which, you know, really should have like clued to
Speaker 6:  us before what this event was gonna be like. Because
Speaker 6:  I, I just remember like when in the runup some like inside baseball and the
Speaker 6:  runup to this, we were like, what is this event gonna be? And Google will
Speaker 6:  be like, it's a surprise. It's a surprise, guys. And I was like, but why
Speaker 6:  does it have to be in Brooklyn Navy Yard? And they were like, ah,
Speaker 6:  well it's a surprise. And I was like, oh my God guys, really?
Speaker 6:  For real, for real, for real. Off the record, you can't tell me nothing.
Speaker 6:  And they're like, we want, it's a surprise. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  okay.
Speaker 5:  It was a surprise.
Speaker 6:  It was a surprise. It, it was a surprise. So
Speaker 5:  For folks who didn't watch this event, normally I, I think everybody
Speaker 5:  knows what a what a, you know, a keynote looks like the executives get up
Speaker 5:  on stage, they kind of do a deep dive. They talk to you about the ins and
Speaker 5:  outs of the phones, and then
Speaker 6:  You stuff, there's a Bento box after the end.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's a Bento box. Yeah. It's, you know, it's pretty nerdy. It's
Speaker 5:  for us, it's for fans. It's like it is to tell you
Speaker 5:  about the ins and outs of these products. Google didn't
Speaker 6:  Do that. No, they did not. No,
Speaker 5:  They did not.
Speaker 6:  What, what did Google do? Google ushered a bunch of us into this
Speaker 6:  little studio and you know, there was
Speaker 6:  an applause sign up in the rafters and there was a warmup
Speaker 6:  comic. And he was like, Hey guys, are you guys
Speaker 6:  pumped for Pixel phones? Look at you nerds with your
Speaker 6:  laptops on your thing. And you love phones, don't you guys? But I need you
Speaker 6:  to get loud for Jimmy Fallon. He's
Speaker 6:  backstage. Is this all you're gonna give for Jimmy? Is this the energy you
Speaker 6:  have for Jimmy? What publication do you work for? And I'm sitting there going
Speaker 6:  like, what the fuck is happening?
Speaker 6:  Where am I, I, what is
Speaker 6:  happening? And so then, you know, Jimmy Fallon comes out and he
Speaker 6:  is joined by Rick Olow, and they sit on a
Speaker 6:  couple of comfy couches and I'm in the front row for this. And I look up
Speaker 6:  And I'm like, oh my God, there's a teleprompter. And I can read
Speaker 6:  everything they're going to say before it happens.
Speaker 6:  What is happening? And then all of a sudden Jimmy would be like, tensor and
Speaker 6:  clapping his hands like a seal. We're
Speaker 7:  Gonna talk about tensor chips, we're gonna talk about IP numbers.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, I, I feel like I'm in an episode of
Speaker 6:  Wandavision because I don't know, like if you've never
Speaker 6:  been in any kind of filming situation, you kind of really have to be like,
Speaker 6:  keyed up. You have to be like, rah, just had a Red Bull and
Speaker 6:  here's my energy. Because any energy that's in studio that
Speaker 6:  feels way too much is hopefully like, it's not hopeful, but
Speaker 6:  it, it is gonna get like diluted and filtered when it finally
Speaker 6:  gets across your screen. But like when you're in the studio
Speaker 6:  audience, you're like, oh my God, it's hitting me in the face. All of this
Speaker 6:  energy that's happening, all of the artifice and the stage
Speaker 6:  ness of it. And I was just like, oh my God.
Speaker 6:  Cody Rigsby from the Peloton instructor who was very famous and was
Speaker 6:  on Dancing with the Stars is there, and he's going like,
Speaker 6:  Hey girl, let's do a workout. And I was like, no, no, please.
Speaker 5:  So they like, they, they basically made a fake episode of The Tonight Show.
Speaker 5:  Right. They made a, but it was all about
Speaker 6:  Fake episode.
Speaker 5:  The Pixel Buds. They had, they even had like special guests. They
Speaker 6:  Had special guests, they had a
Speaker 5:  QVC segment. They pre-filed videos. Like it was Yeah, there, there was a
Speaker 5:  q right
Speaker 6:  There, there was a segment where they're there. And I was like, I'm either
Speaker 6:  watching Good Morning America or QVC as they go through the entire lineup.
Speaker 6:  They're making a lot of digs at like Apple. At one point,
Speaker 6:  one of the Googlers was like, we can say the A word.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, oh my God. It was, were we for real? Yeah. Right now what
Speaker 6:  is happening? What is happening?
Speaker 5:  So we saw what we saw. Steph Curry, Alex Cooper, the Jonas Brothers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Kareem from Subway Takes, yeah, they have, it was a big list.
Speaker 6:  The, the Jonas Brothers made a music video on their Pixel phone. It was very
Speaker 6:  much like a, well, they do shot on iPhone. What about shot
Speaker 6:  on Pixel? And I was like, oh God, okay, here we
Speaker 5:  Are. So I think what's like, interesting about this, and maybe a little confusing
Speaker 5:  about this is like, I, this is clearly meant for a bigger audience, but like
Speaker 5:  Alison, I'm curious, having watched this remotely, like is
Speaker 5:  this, did you think that this is a thing a normal human would watch? Like,
Speaker 5:  like I I, I'm curious like if this actually is gonna connect with people
Speaker 5:  more than a traditional keynote would. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I mean, I think we all get that. We're like, this event
Speaker 8:  wasn't for us. They had the embargo lift an hour beforehand.
Speaker 8:  So like all, all of us nerds could see the
Speaker 8:  specs, talk about it, think about it. And then there was this Jimmy
Speaker 8:  Fallon thing. Like I know that logically I was still
Speaker 8:  sitting there watching it just, just like cringing. You know?
Speaker 8:  It was like the thing you said to me about the, the energy
Speaker 8:  level.
Speaker 8:  It, it felt very keyed up watching it. Oh,
Speaker 8:  well, from
Speaker 6:  Across the country me was more keyed up in studio. Yeah. There's a lot of
Speaker 6:  tech journalists who, who, who I am friends with. And we were all just looking
Speaker 6:  at each other like, the the fuck is going on. Yeah. And then I, one of,
Speaker 6:  one of, before the warmup comic was just like, and just so you guys know,
Speaker 6:  once filming starts, you cannot get up to pee. And then
Speaker 6:  one of my journalist friends messaged me and he was like, oh my God, they
Speaker 6:  were serious. I have to pee. And they would not let me go. Okay,
Speaker 8:  First they, first they came for our water bottles first
Speaker 6:  They came for water bottles. Now,
Speaker 8:  Now we can't pee. Oh my
Speaker 6:  God. Now we can't pee. And I was, I, I felt
Speaker 6:  honest to God, like I was in the Twilight Zone and that I was losing it.
Speaker 6:  I I I just, you know. Yeah. Between the flashing applause signs that
Speaker 6:  went off every time Jimmy made a joke,
Speaker 6:  he, he there he could not find the Pixel device that he was not wowed by.
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 5:  It was Marquez pointed out in a tweet that at one point he is
Speaker 5:  holding The Pixel fold upside down.
Speaker 6:  He, it was for my story. It
Speaker 5:  Was from your, yeah, yeah. That was, yeah. And just
Speaker 8:  Thrilled, like, so excited to look at that upside. Oh my god. Wax phone
Speaker 6:  IP numbers first I was like, IP numbers,
Speaker 6:  doesn't he mean IP addresses? But I think he was actually talking about the
Speaker 6:  dust and waterproofing IP numbers.
Speaker 6:  So I I I was not convinced that Jimmy knew
Speaker 6:  actually what a big deal it is for IP 68 on a foldable.
Speaker 6:  I, I was not convinced. And I was like, there's no way
Speaker 6:  on earth Jimmy Fallon is that excited about tensor chips, this's
Speaker 5:  The thing. Let us be excited about IP. Yeah. Right. Someone
Speaker 5:  is, it's not Jimmy. He can't encroach on our space like
Speaker 5:  that. Right. So, okay. Do you think, like, do we think,
Speaker 5:  do you think that they will try this again, right? Because like the, the
Speaker 5:  keynote has been changing, right? Like Apple sort of invented this format
Speaker 5:  and then more recently Apple has already kind of shifted away from it with
Speaker 5:  their pre-made videos, which are maybe like halfway between a traditional
Speaker 5:  keynote and like a Hey everybody watch this big long commercial.
Speaker 5:  Like, do, do we think that Google keeps trying this?
Speaker 6:  I mean, you know, I did talk to a lot of Googlers on the ground, some of
Speaker 6:  which, you know, fans of the show will know and you know,
Speaker 6:  everyone was very curious to know what the reaction was. And I felt bad
Speaker 6:  because I was processing it in real time And I was like, it sure was a show.
Speaker 6:  And, and the thing that I kept hearing over and over again was that they
Speaker 6:  were trying to reach a new audience and I'm not sure they know what that
Speaker 6:  new audience that they're trying to reach is because like, who
Speaker 6:  exactly is this for? It's not for us. I know it's not for us like the tech
Speaker 6:  nerd and the tech journalists, I do think it's for a new
Speaker 6:  audience, but I'm like, who? Because the grandmas are not gonna
Speaker 6:  stream this at 1:00 PM on Wednesday, even though they might
Speaker 6:  like Jimmy Fallon and then the kids on
Speaker 6:  TikTok are 100000% not gonna stream this live, even if
Speaker 6:  they like the subway take sky and call her daddy. So
Speaker 6:  who is this for?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It sort of feels like, like the late night format
Speaker 8:  lately is so, you know, Mia talked about this on her episodes
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Is like built to get those little TikTok clips
Speaker 8:  out of whatever's happening. And I don't know
Speaker 8:  if that there was anything that happened that would be interesting
Speaker 8:  in a different context. Like none of that I, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  That's actually really interesting. Yeah. Like maybe this was just designed
Speaker 5:  to get a bunch of viral TikTok moments. Like that's, I
Speaker 6:  Think, I think it, you know, like, And I get it to it and my piece, but I
Speaker 6:  think they're just realizing that, you know, in the jobs era,
Speaker 6:  they needed media to create the buzz. They needed the,
Speaker 6:  you know, traditional outlets. They needed the diehards to create that buzz
Speaker 6:  online to talk about the products. And now they can just skip us entirely
Speaker 6:  in some, not entirely because of course we were invited. They want us to
Speaker 6:  talk about these products, but like they can also go
Speaker 6:  around us a little bit and go straight to the people online, through the
Speaker 6:  relationships that they have with these viral influencers, through the relationships
Speaker 6:  that they have with these celebrities. And you know, it's been really interesting
Speaker 6:  to see the reaction on, on online about what
Speaker 6:  people thought because you know, there, there were some Apple fan boys who
Speaker 6:  were like, oh my god, Google's so cringe. Like the apple is so much better.
Speaker 6:  And then the Google fan boys going like, no, this was so much more entertaining.
Speaker 6:  And just like a mix of people who would like, I hated that. That was awful.
Speaker 6:  Why? Where are my specs? Where are my bento boxes? Who, who what?
Speaker 6:  Then people going like, you guys broke NDA. I'm like, no, we didn't actually,
Speaker 6:  it just was set for an hour before the thing.
Speaker 5:  Well, and that's, that's sort of the secret here, right? Yeah. Like Google
Speaker 5:  it, you know, I I, we're not here to, we're not complaining that Google like
Speaker 5:  didn't like left us out, right? Yeah. They like, they, they, they didn't
Speaker 5:  leave us out, right? No, we, we, we were briefed. We got hands ons and we
Speaker 5:  were able to run that stuff before this event. And I think that sort of is
Speaker 5:  the secret here, right? They can talk to media with
Speaker 5:  one hand and then talk to exactly the audience with the other. And I think
Speaker 5:  they're sort of redefining the keynote. It's like, we already talk to the
Speaker 5:  media, why do we need to do this thing? And it's, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's weird because those things were also for, for fans. Yeah. And now it's
Speaker 5:  like, it's not quite the fans. It's not like I don't, I don't think it's
Speaker 5:  was for the fans.
Speaker 6:  No, I don't think it was for the fans. It was for someone else. Whether
Speaker 6:  they know who that someone else is. I, I'm not sure because I felt like
Speaker 6:  there was a little bit of mixed messaging throughout a lot of like, come
Speaker 6:  on over leave the iPhone messaging and they're like, you know,
Speaker 6:  I forget who exactly said it, but they're like, we're done with the green
Speaker 6:  bubble conversation. I'm like, well I'm glad you guys are done with it. The
Speaker 6:  people in the real world are not done with
Speaker 5:  That Does sound like conversation. Does that sound done with that conversation?
Speaker 5:  But yeah, it was wild. So lots of stuff announced.
Speaker 5:  Obviously the headliners were the phones, Alison,
Speaker 5:  there were four of them. Can you give us the highlights here?
Speaker 8:  Four phones. We've got the regular Pixel 10 still
Speaker 8:  7 99. That's great. Pixel 10 Pro
Speaker 8:  9 99 Pixel 10 Pro XL. God,
Speaker 8:  there's so many. That one technically not more expensive, but
Speaker 8:  there is no longer 128 gigabyte option.
Speaker 8:  So it's 1199. And then of course The
Speaker 8:  Pixel 10 Pro Fold 1799
Speaker 8:  expensive phone. The, the kind of
Speaker 8:  higher level, they look exactly as frigging same as last year's phones.
Speaker 8:  Like they're just get that outta the way. I, you can't tell the
Speaker 8:  difference unless you're, you work at Google, but on the
Speaker 8:  inside they all have tens or G five, which is a
Speaker 8:  moderately big deal first chip that is made by
Speaker 8:  TSMC and not Samsung. So there's a lot of interest in like how
Speaker 8:  that's gonna shake out. And they have
Speaker 8:  Q2,
Speaker 8:  our national nightmare is over. We finally have
Speaker 8:  proper Q2. The magnets are here. Yes, the magnets, the charging scene,
Speaker 8:  everything is built into the phone. You don't need a case.
Speaker 8:  So I think those are, and without
Speaker 8:  getting into ai, which we will, those are the high
Speaker 8:  level. Like here's why these are new phones.
Speaker 5:  So, okay, this is really interesting. The, the, the pro models feel like
Speaker 5:  they are basically the same phones, right? Slightly brighter
Speaker 5:  display, slightly bigger battery, new chip. Right. But they look the
Speaker 5:  same. It's the 10 and the fold
Speaker 5:  that have the biggest differences. And
Speaker 5:  both of them are like really interesting ones. So the, the 10 is maybe where
Speaker 5:  I wanna start, right? The Pixel 10 is getting a third camera
Speaker 5:  for the first time. It's getting a telephoto, but they're downgrading
Speaker 5:  both of the other cameras in the process, which I think is
Speaker 5:  such a fascinating trade off because it,
Speaker 5:  the, the differentiation between the lines, I guess I, I
Speaker 5:  don't know where it is now. Like if you look at them, they look identical.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But if you care a lot, there's a pretty big difference.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I think it just says a lot about where Google
Speaker 8:  thinks it can get away with enhancing stuff in
Speaker 8:  software and where you just need the hardware. So Yeah, typically the regular
Speaker 8:  Pixel phone just has the ultra wide in the main camera.
Speaker 8:  Part of the kind of sales pitch was you get the
Speaker 8:  same like big sensor nice lens as
Speaker 8:  the pro phones, which was cool. But yeah, they added that
Speaker 8:  five times telephoto camera, which is
Speaker 8:  the same one is on The Pixel fold, not the same one that's
Speaker 8:  on the pro phone. It's like what
Speaker 8:  does a pro phone mean is completely like
Speaker 8:  confusing this time around. But yeah, they did kind of like
Speaker 8:  downgrade the hardware on the main Pixel on the
Speaker 8:  main camera and the ultra wide because I think
Speaker 8:  they're just like, we'll, just software it,
Speaker 5:  Which like at the, so it's, I think it's the same cameras as on the nine
Speaker 5:  A, which admittedly like, they're not bad cameras. They're good
Speaker 8:  Cameras. Yeah, yeah, they're fine. And Google gave me
Speaker 8:  some kind of fluffy answer about how magical and special
Speaker 8:  the camera hardware is, even though it is probably just the same
Speaker 8:  as on the nine A. Yeah. It just, if you
Speaker 8:  look across the series just at camera specs, it's, it gets
Speaker 8:  more confusing because you've got the most expensive model, the
Speaker 8:  fold $1,800, you get kind of worse
Speaker 8:  cameras. And then there's the pro models, the slab
Speaker 8:  phones, those get you the best cameras and then you kind of
Speaker 8:  take another step back on the regular
Speaker 8:  models. It's, it, it's a little confusing. I think I've
Speaker 6:  Turned into that gif of the lady who's just really confused
Speaker 6:  as math symbols float around her head. That's just me, me right now.
Speaker 8:  That is Google trying to just like, what is a pro phone?
Speaker 8:  They, the only reasonable explanation last time around was it had a
Speaker 8:  telephoto lens. 'cause that's what all three had. That
Speaker 8:  doesn't exist anymore. I don't, I'm accepting any answers. That makes sense.
Speaker 5:  Right. So now, now The Pixel 10 has more
Speaker 5:  differentiation from the nine A or, or,
Speaker 5:  or you know, probably the eventual 10 A because there's three cameras instead
Speaker 5:  of two. But it is true if you're just like, if you're in the store and you're
Speaker 5:  like, should I buy The Pixel 10 or The Pixel 10 Pro? Like they, they
Speaker 5:  look identical. Which like, I don't know. I get is is this
Speaker 5:  compete with the baseline iPhone, which doesn't have
Speaker 5:  that third lens? I don't know.
Speaker 8:  I I know, I think Google loves being like, look what we do that the
Speaker 8:  iPhone doesn't, like Samsung has the telephoto on, its
Speaker 8:  on its regular. So maybe it's more trying to offer some
Speaker 8:  purity there. And I, I like, I I like
Speaker 8:  a de a dedicated telephoto. So I think it's a good
Speaker 8:  change. I'm gonna try it out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a really interesting trade off. So that's on the low end and then
Speaker 5:  the high end, the fold maybe like the most single
Speaker 5:  most exciting upgrade.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  They made a fully dust resistant foldable. It is
Speaker 8:  IP 68 rated. As we heard Jimmy Fallon
Speaker 8:  excitedly,
Speaker 6:  I don't IP numbers. I believe that he plagiarized
Speaker 6:  you. He was like beforehand. They,
Speaker 8:  That's
Speaker 6:  My conspiracy theory. He, that's my conspiracy theory.
Speaker 8:  He learned about dust resistance on foldables about 10 minutes
Speaker 8:  before you went into that. But it's a big deal. I
Speaker 8:  talked to, so Samsung has kind of gone into
Speaker 8:  like, we're making a foldable really thin with its
Speaker 8:  last fold phone, which was cool. Still not quite dust
Speaker 8:  resistant. Had an IP 48 rating, which means it's, you
Speaker 8:  can't poke it with a little needle or something.
Speaker 8:  The 68 means full dust sand, bring it to
Speaker 8:  the beach, it's gonna be okay. Probably with all the
Speaker 8:  usual disclaimers of IP ratings. And
Speaker 8:  once they leave the factory, they degrade over time.
Speaker 8:  Like blah blah, blah. That's true of all, all IP ratings on
Speaker 8:  devices. But it's a new hinge. It's a
Speaker 8:  gearless hinge. I think Google's like kind
Speaker 8:  of, they could be playing it up a little more. Maybe I'm just
Speaker 8:  super invested in this, but I'm like, I wanna hear more about
Speaker 5:  No, but you're right as possible. There's like two directions they can go
Speaker 5:  here and one is the Samsung route where they go thinner, thinner, thinner.
Speaker 5:  And like, don't get me wrong, the,
Speaker 6:  The, that was a nice thin foldy phone.
Speaker 5:  It wa it was a very impressive,
Speaker 6:  It was very impressive.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Very nice.
Speaker 5:  And, and you look at that and you go, if, if everybody else is bigger than
Speaker 5:  this, like they lost. And then I look at the, at The Pixel
Speaker 5:  fold And I, I'm like, okay. It, you know, yeah, it's a little chunkier, but
Speaker 5:  it like promising that level of security on a device that
Speaker 5:  expensive that is seemingly pretty fragile. Like
Speaker 5:  that's actually a pretty smart area to run at
Speaker 5:  instead of racing to be as thin as
Speaker 5:  you can go before you get
Speaker 6:  There. Yeah. I still think that the best way to sell these phones is to
Speaker 6:  find the tech journalist in the, in the event. Yes. Who is blogging
Speaker 6:  from their Pixel fold. And I sat, I ended up sitting next to
Speaker 6:  Sam from Eng Gadget who was doing that with the Pixel fold, like the older
Speaker 6:  one. And I was just, oh my god, last time it was Allison.
Speaker 6:  This time it's Sam. Oh my god, do I need one? Because
Speaker 6:  I was having trouble with the wifi again, because it's a tin can
Speaker 6:  in i in the Brooklyn Navy artist deja vu. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  oh my God, they're having no problem with these foldy phones.
Speaker 6:  Maybe that's, that's this, they don't need these keynote events. They just
Speaker 6:  need to find the one tech journalist in the thing while all everyone else
Speaker 6:  is suffering going like, oh my god, can you get wifi in here? And the one
Speaker 6:  journalist with The Pixel fold or the Samsung fold just blogging away
Speaker 6:  super fine, having no issues. And I was just like, damn,
Speaker 6:  do I need a Foldy phone? This is the only two times that I've wanted a Foldy
Speaker 6:  phone. It
Speaker 5:  Is also the only two use cases I've ever heard for foldy fold. Like,
Speaker 5:  don't get me wrong, I am obsessed with them. I want one, I
Speaker 5:  have no idea what I would do with it. And this is this, you're, you're like,
Speaker 5:  you can blog the heck out of anything you want. You
Speaker 6:  Can glog the
Speaker 5:  Heck. You know what that is our job. We've,
Speaker 8:  I press like a dream is
Speaker 6:  Like AI have seen these things handle many of finicky
Speaker 6:  CMS. So I'm just saying that they, they're
Speaker 6:  great for journalists.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Forget Jimmy Fallon.
Speaker 5:  So we talked a bunch about the cameras already, but we have, there's a lot
Speaker 5:  more to talk about with these cameras because the zoom
Speaker 5:  gets a little
Speaker 6:  So freaky. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  A little interesting. Gets a little interesting.
Speaker 8:  So the, we need like a sound, the alarm, like
Speaker 8:  break glass in case of emergency. Like, so
Speaker 8:  they put AI in the camera is the short version.
Speaker 8:  This is only on,
Speaker 5:  We need to pipe in neli screaming. Like do we not have like a
Speaker 5:  soundboard for this? I
Speaker 8:  Know. I can kind of hear it in my own head. Yeah. So
Speaker 8:  this is only on the, the pro in the Pro XL
Speaker 8:  and it's only in this feature called ProRes Zoom,
Speaker 8:  which is kind of digital zoom. It's when you get past 30 x
Speaker 8:  all the way up to a hundred. So typically like
Speaker 8:  garbage territory of like, you're not getting a good photo from that. There's
Speaker 8:  just not enough information for any kind of processing to do anything with
Speaker 8:  it. So Google was like, what if
Speaker 8:  we put generative AI in here and had it try to
Speaker 8:  figure out what you're taking a picture of. And
Speaker 8:  so that happens on device. It's in the
Speaker 8:  right in the camera. It, you can see it running
Speaker 8:  after you take the photo and it does retain like the original photo you
Speaker 8:  took. So you do know something is happening
Speaker 8:  does not work on people. So like, thank God
Speaker 6:  The demo was really wild. Like it's because we both, it's good. We were
Speaker 6:  at the demo and like we were at Google's office and they took us out on the
Speaker 6:  balcony and they're like, do you see that White House across the river?
Speaker 6:  Boop took a picture and they were like, Allison, would you like to take a
Speaker 6:  picture of the, the museum over there that's like really far away.
Speaker 6:  Whoop took a picture. V do you wanna try that water tower
Speaker 6:  took a picture. It the, the thing they don't tell you is that you like really
Speaker 6:  need a steady hand because
Speaker 8:  Oh, it's hard. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's really hard. It like mo like if you move
Speaker 6:  a millimeter well you're not in focus anymore and you just have to like
Speaker 6:  it, you really need a steady hand, right.
Speaker 5:  Because you're at 100 x controlling this like super tiny. It's a,
Speaker 6:  There's like a little picture and picture window so that you can just like
Speaker 6:  tap to refocus on the place that you wanna take a picture of. It was weird.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 5:  I, I, last night I watched like every YouTube video of this that I could
Speaker 5:  find and it was blowing my mind be
Speaker 5:  right because there was, I think, I think it was Pet Pixel had one
Speaker 5:  where they were, I think they were zoomed in like past 50 x on this like
Speaker 5:  boat way out in the harbor. And they show the original
Speaker 5:  and it's like, fine, just the grain and ugly.
Speaker 5:  And then boom, there's the AI version.
Speaker 5:  And if you had, if you had not told me AI was involved, I would've been like,
Speaker 5:  oh, okay. Just some nice camera processing. Like, it, it, I like
Speaker 5:  compare. I was like trying to, I was doing a spot. The difference between
Speaker 5:  them, I'm like, where did it invent something? Where did it screw up? And
Speaker 5:  I could not find it. Yeah. And okay, look, obviously this is early, you know,
Speaker 5:  there's one one image I saw, but it just looked like a cleaner,
Speaker 5:  crisper version of what you're actually seeing. Like it looks like it is
Speaker 5:  really just fixing it, cleaning it up.
Speaker 5:  It's wild.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I totally agree. I talked to Isaac Reynolds who heads up
Speaker 8:  The Pixel camera team And I was, I was like, okay,
Speaker 8:  what are you doing here? AI in the camera. What is a photo? Like, put him
Speaker 8:  through the gauntlet of questions and he was really like, you know,
Speaker 8:  know this is an algorithm. Like we've, in a similar
Speaker 8:  way we've used in the past. It's just really good at like
Speaker 8:  getting rid of the artifacts that you would see from the, the
Speaker 8:  upsampling and the, you know, image processing
Speaker 8:  pipeline in that, you know, his claim is that is not gonna do
Speaker 8:  anything you wouldn't expect from a camera. 'cause that's where I'm like,
Speaker 8:  what is it gonna invent stuff? Is it gonna, you know,
Speaker 8:  put different things that weren't there, like lochness monster out there.
Speaker 6:  It was like a weird, you know, because there were instances where we're getting
Speaker 6:  pictures of people versus like the things and and, and the
Speaker 6:  buildings or the architecture or whatnot would be kind of unnaturally clear
Speaker 6:  for something taken that far. And then the people would just be blobs. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I get why they're not doing the people that's like very important that
Speaker 6:  they're not doing the people. But that, that was the one thing that I was
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 8:  This is a blob. Yeah, it
Speaker 5:  Does. So there'll be a blob within your crispr Yes. Everything else. Oh,
Speaker 5:  that's okay. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's weird,
Speaker 5:  Right? I guess they, because that would be creepy at a minimum.
Speaker 5:  Like you're at like a hundred x Geez. Okay. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right. Creepy at a minimum dangerous.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. In a different context.
Speaker 5:  This is is wild. It's,
Speaker 5:  I'm curious where it goes from here. Yeah. And if it's, if it is
Speaker 5:  like limited to this zoom function, 'cause this like got my
Speaker 5:  mind racing on whether I'm like, okay is like the future of The Pixel camera.
Speaker 5:  Just everything gets like diffusion
Speaker 5:  and they use this to, right. Like why not enhance details elsewhere? Right.
Speaker 5:  They know what they, they know what a, a proper DSLR photo is supposed to
Speaker 5:  look like. Forget portrait mode. Why don't they just like, can they just
Speaker 5:  diffusion it?
Speaker 6:  I mean there were so many camera features that
Speaker 6:  like when Alice And I were getting the demos, I was just like in my head
Speaker 6:  like, you know, you're smiling to be polite in, in, in person and in your
Speaker 6:  head I'm going like, Hey Ray, everything
Speaker 6:  is, what is a photo? Oh no. Okay. Oh God. Oh
Speaker 6:  no. Oh. Like that, that was in my head
Speaker 6:  happening at the time. It's very impressive. But at the same time, if you're
Speaker 6:  thinking, if you are contemplating what is a photo there,
Speaker 6:  there's just a lot of screaming that's going on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and In fact, actually, now that I say it, there are other parts
Speaker 5:  of the camera where it is inventing photos. So there's this new camera coach
Speaker 5:  thing and it invents photos and tells you to go take them, right?
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 8:  This is, yeah. Yeah. Did
Speaker 5:  You get to demo this? Yes.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, we did. And it, you kind of get into the camera coach
Speaker 8:  mode, so it's separate and then I, I believe
Speaker 8:  you take a photo and it, it invents some like
Speaker 8:  potential photos you could take like with
Speaker 6:  That would be better. Yeah. So it's nagging your natural photo taking ability
Speaker 6:  too. It's just
Speaker 8:  Right. But, and importantly you pick one and then it takes you
Speaker 8:  through the steps. It's like, okay, well now get down lower or
Speaker 8:  compose it this way and you end up with your photo
Speaker 8:  and the, the AI one gets thrown away. But it is like
Speaker 8:  you're seeing that little glimmer of like, okay, what's coming next
Speaker 8:  if this is what you're doing right now.
Speaker 5:  Right. It's so interesting. It's like you, I have to go take it, but like,
Speaker 5:  actually you already made it. You like Yeah, it's already here. Like, do
Speaker 5:  I, did I need to take it? Yeah. I mean, I would prefer to take it. I I
Speaker 5:  I will say like the, the camera coach thing seems like one of those
Speaker 5:  very impressive, like, AI is crazy. Look at all these things. It can do,
Speaker 5:  can analyze the scene live and it takes you how to like, take it. I don't
Speaker 5:  know who's gonna use it or why I don't wanna use it. It do, they
Speaker 6:  They told us it was for like, people who are intimidated by photography or
Speaker 6:  who take like really crappy pictures but want like that Instagram worthy,
Speaker 6:  like cool looking picture and learning about composition and lighting
Speaker 6:  Okay. And how to do that stuff. But it's also like
Speaker 5:  They should have thrown a gnarly flash on the back of this thing
Speaker 5:  and, and forced it to be on at all times. Yes. If they wanted to
Speaker 5:  appeal to, to like they, nobody's trying to take
Speaker 5:  Instagram photos anymore. No, this isn't happening.
Speaker 6:  That's why it's a coach. Right. This is because they're, they're like, this
Speaker 6:  is for beginners. It's not for people who already know how to do the photography
Speaker 6:  stuff. And I, you know, And I, I was the model for Allison's
Speaker 6:  demo and boy did I get a quad workout because it kept
Speaker 6:  telling me to like do a dynamic pose or whatnot. Or like Allison threw the
Speaker 6:  thing was telling me to do that. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Why did you be dynamic?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I did. My, my legs were hurting, so thanks ai.
Speaker 5:  Okay, last thing in the, about the cameras
Speaker 5:  last big thing is it is building in
Speaker 5:  credentials saying it's tagging them as ai. Yeah. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  When you do these, I guess not the camera coach, but if you're doing the
Speaker 5:  zoom, if you're doing the crazy zoom thing, it's gonna tell you in the metadata
Speaker 5:  that is ai,
Speaker 8:  Right? Yeah. And, and oh, more importantly like, yeah,
Speaker 8:  I talked to Isaac and it's tagging
Speaker 8:  every photo you take with the camera, not just the AI ones.
Speaker 8:  If there's, there's no AI used, it just says something like taken
Speaker 8:  with a camera. It'll say something like, if you took, why
Speaker 5:  Does that have to be established? Well,
Speaker 8:  Well
Speaker 5:  Here's the alternative because
Speaker 8:  What is the photo? We live in a dys dystopian future
Speaker 8:  where no, yeah. It's like
Speaker 5:  There's no such thing as a photo that is not taken by a camera. Right? Am
Speaker 5:  I, is there something I'm missing here?
Speaker 8:  So, okay, so the, the rationale for this is
Speaker 8:  if you only tag the things that are ai, then it gives the
Speaker 8:  appearance that the untagged thing is real,
Speaker 8:  which may not be the case. Okay. Okay.
Speaker 5:  We just,
Speaker 8:  We just don't know if it's AI or not. So this is a little
Speaker 8:  bit of like, Google's going to set the good example and
Speaker 8:  hopefully every, you know, Instagram will have all kinds of tags
Speaker 8:  about this was taken with the camera and
Speaker 8:  we will see how, how that pans out. But I, I
Speaker 8:  appreciate that they're doing it And I, I get it.
Speaker 8:  It's weird,
Speaker 5:  You know, sometimes this word is a photo question is like impossible to
Speaker 5:  answer and other times I'm like, yeah, it's a camera. It's like it's,
Speaker 5:  was there a camera like Yes. Yeah. That if it wasn't taken with a camera,
Speaker 5:  I feel very confident. It feels like unimpeachably not a photo. If
Speaker 5:  vergecast at The Verge dot com email me if you can figure out
Speaker 5:  what a photo is that's not taken by a camera.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's not Well it's
Speaker 6:  Just a picture.
Speaker 5:  It is
Speaker 6:  But we wouldn't call it a photo. We
Speaker 5:  Just wouldn't call it. Yeah, yeah. Oh gosh. Okay. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is a, a photo realistic painting that
Speaker 5:  it's not, it's not,
Speaker 6:  It's a picture. A picture versus a photo is gonna be
Speaker 6:  okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is, it's
Speaker 8:  A robot's memory of a tree that it saw
Speaker 8:  one time. I'm just saying
Speaker 6:  We should do a, what is a photo package and just have everyone on staff contribute
Speaker 6:  and lose our minds collectively. And just let that live
Speaker 6:  online.
Speaker 5:  That's the end state of The Verge. Yeah. 'cause all of us become
Speaker 5:  hermits afterward
Speaker 8:  After we we'll be released, we can
Speaker 6:  Rest. We'll just, you know, we'll we'll do this one last, what is a photo
Speaker 6:  package and then all of our souls will be released to Valhalla and
Speaker 6:  we'll retire.
Speaker 8:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  The other thing we have to talk about here is Magic Q, which is like the,
Speaker 5:  maybe the flagship feature from the AI standpoint, at least as
Speaker 5:  Google is pushing it. Alison like, is this thing actually going to be help?
Speaker 5:  Like this is their attempt to make I ai actually
Speaker 5:  maybe potentially useful.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And it's, the demos we saw were really
Speaker 8:  interesting, but they were on rails. So just, just to explain,
Speaker 8:  this is sort of a contextual, always
Speaker 8:  their AI that can kind of
Speaker 8:  prompt and autofill things that might be relevant. So the,
Speaker 8:  I think demo everybody saw was a friend text you
Speaker 8:  like, Hey, do you have the details about our dinner
Speaker 8:  reservation tonight? And Magic hu will
Speaker 8:  kind of take that and go to your Gmail and come
Speaker 8:  back with, you know, the relevant details In theory
Speaker 8:  that it's like the name of the restaurant and it'll, it'll
Speaker 8:  kind of present that as a thing. You can just potentially
Speaker 8:  like paste into the conversation.
Speaker 8:  So there's a, a little bit, it's, I I think
Speaker 8:  it was described to us as ephemeral
Speaker 5:  That is like concerning. They're like, we're not storing all of your
Speaker 5:  data forever. We, we, we know all of it. We just might not,
Speaker 5:  we just might not hang onto this is like, this is the dream, right? Like
Speaker 5:  this is, I mean this sort of gets at what, what Apple was trying to problem
Speaker 5:  with Siri where it's like it knows everything. It sees everything it surfaces
Speaker 5:  for you at the right time.
Speaker 5:  It's not, it's not entirely clear. Like I love the pitch of this, right?
Speaker 5:  Like those are the things that are super annoying to like juggle and look
Speaker 5:  up. Can it actually pull that stuff up? Can it do this in
Speaker 5:  every app? Yeah. Is it just like these select googly moments? No,
Speaker 8:  But it is a handful of like Google apps, like
Speaker 8:  Gmail calendar messages. It is in
Speaker 8:  Gboard. So it can kind of
Speaker 8:  work a little bit outside of just those core apps where
Speaker 8:  if you were looking at something in Chrome and it senses you went to
Speaker 8:  a shopping app, it's like you Oh right. That's you open up Amazon. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That's the example we got. It can suggest text in Gboard that you
Speaker 8:  might wanna paste in. It is all happening on device,
Speaker 8:  which is good from the scary privacy
Speaker 8:  perspective and it incorporates some of like
Speaker 8:  some of your very recent activities. So like in that example of
Speaker 8:  something you were looking at
Speaker 8:  and, and sort of feeds that into what you might
Speaker 8:  see as suggested activities, but it's not
Speaker 8:  saving those for super long. I, we didn't get exacts
Speaker 8:  on any of that, but just enough to feel like
Speaker 8:  maybe this isn't too scary,
Speaker 6:  It's cool if it works. The question is is like, is it gonna get the
Speaker 6:  right reservation? What if you're someone who's like a social butterfly
Speaker 6:  and you're meeting some of the same people in the same group
Speaker 6:  chats, but in different group configurations. Like can it handle that?
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's interesting too because Google sort of already like has
Speaker 5:  pieces of this individually within apps, right? Where it's like
Speaker 5:  there's stuff with this that you can just hard code Gmail already
Speaker 5:  surfaces your flights at the right time. It started doing this thing
Speaker 5:  that honestly I find very annoying. But it's like, it'll be like, Hey, you've
Speaker 5:  got a package coming and we're gonna put the package thing up so you know
Speaker 5:  that your package is coming today. Right? So it's like already reading
Speaker 5:  your emails, it's figuring out when you need them and surfing the right moments.
Speaker 5:  It's like being able to do that, take it to another app,
Speaker 5:  read what's happening in the app, give it to you at that time. Like that
Speaker 5:  is, that's a lot of juggling to do. And it's
Speaker 5:  like, okay, flights got it. That's a good use case. This feels like a thing
Speaker 5:  that they've probably programmed a few specific things for And I
Speaker 5:  maybe it expands over time. Like I, I think the idea is
Speaker 5:  fascinating and it's just not clear to me if they can actually execute this.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It, it'll be interesting like one to try it out and
Speaker 8:  see if it actually works outside of these demos. And two, like
Speaker 8:  it sort of gets at that thing of are they just gonna
Speaker 8:  circumvent us going into apps? Are app developers
Speaker 8:  gonna love that? Like, ooh,
Speaker 6:  In the engagement economy, that's gonna be interesting.
Speaker 8:  I know like, ooh, they can, the, I mean presumably app developers
Speaker 8:  can just be like, no, we're not gonna open this up to magic queue.
Speaker 8:  You know, if that ever became an option. But yeah, I wonder,
Speaker 8:  I sort of wonder what the limits are on something like this,
Speaker 8:  but it's gotta work first. So
Speaker 5:  I, I'm really curious. They also have this like daily hub thing that like
Speaker 5:  pops up with like a bunch. Like here's all the stuff for you to do today.
Speaker 5:  And I, I'm like, I'm super interested in what this is actually capable of.
Speaker 5:  'cause it keeps, it's like, here's all this stuff on your calendar today.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, oh, okay. That would actually be really interesting for me
Speaker 5:  because I, like, I use Google Calendar a little bit at work,
Speaker 5:  but most of my life is in tick tick the to-Do app
Speaker 5:  and if it can't access tick tick, then it's actually just like useless to
Speaker 5:  me.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. They, and this is kind of a version of something
Speaker 8:  Samsung has, they call it like the now brief
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. That I have found to be just completely useless.
Speaker 8:  Honestly.
Speaker 6:  Honestly, the funny thing is that it feels like they sort of also took this
Speaker 6:  from smartwatch features, which are morning report. And like you wake up
Speaker 6:  on your smartwatch first thing in the morning and it tells you the weather,
Speaker 6:  it tells you what Yeah. Workout you're having next and it tells you everything
Speaker 6:  on your calendar. So
Speaker 8:  I I like that honestly.
Speaker 6:  Like I I honestly don't think it belongs on your phone. I think it belongs
Speaker 6:  on something like that. That's Yeah. My, I'm biased but that's my
Speaker 6:  take on that.
Speaker 8:  We'll see.
Speaker 5:  I wanna make sure we talk about one more important thing on the phones,
Speaker 5:  which is that there's some magnets.
Speaker 6:  There are magnets. Oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  You touched touched on this a little bit, but
Speaker 5:  Chee two is real. It's happened. It's the, the only
Speaker 5:  other phone was the HMB skyline, which is more of a punchline
Speaker 5:  than a actual product.
Speaker 5:  I This is great, right? Like this is, I know it is, is exactly MagSafe now
Speaker 5:  it's on Pixel Buds. They build it into the actual phones. A bunch of accessories
Speaker 5:  did like is there, is there more to this? It's just good. It's like they
Speaker 5:  did it, it works.
Speaker 8:  I think so. It,
Speaker 6:  They said it in the, in the show they
Speaker 8:  Said Jimmy, Jimmy is
Speaker 6:  So MagSafe and Apple stuff and, and Jimmy Fallon was
Speaker 6:  like, can't we say the A word? So that's why he said that.
Speaker 6:  So yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'll say like, this is, I I, there's a lot of stuff I'll
Speaker 5:  criticize Apple for like keeping locked down And I, I
Speaker 5:  marvel at the fact that they opened up Mag safe to the Q
Speaker 5:  ecosystem and this seems right now most seems good for
Speaker 5:  Android. Yeah. Like I I assume this helps all their partners who make all
Speaker 5:  these accessories. 'cause they're gonna get to sell a whole lot more of 'em
Speaker 6:  And there's so much money. Yeah. In And I, I think they're just like, they
Speaker 6:  weighed the pros and cons. 'cause in my mind Apple just has like a bunch
Speaker 6:  of supply chain people and like those math nerds who are like
Speaker 6:  the pros and the cons of how much money gets into our pocket by making it
Speaker 6:  open versus closed. And they just did the beepboop bop math and they were
Speaker 6:  like, oh, we get get so much more money for like opening it up. Mm.
Speaker 6:  Let The Pixel have the mag safe or whatnot. That's just like how
Speaker 6:  I think it went my computer very
Speaker 8:  Meanwhile Green Bubbles, they're like,
Speaker 8:  seems like all downside.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That one's still not happening.
Speaker 5:  All right, we gotta take a break when we're back, we're gonna talk all about
Speaker 5:  the wearables.
Speaker 6:  the first one 'cause it was a first gen device. And then the third one came
Speaker 6:  out And I was like, we're done catching up guys. We we're, we're here now
Speaker 6:  we have arrived third time's the charm. And so I was like, oh yeah,
Speaker 6:  so like, what are you gonna do next year for the fourth? And then they were
Speaker 6:  like, how about we blow your mind with
Speaker 5:  Ai?
Speaker 6:  And that's, which
Speaker 5:  Is honestly what no man wants to hear.
Speaker 6:  No one wants to hear that. Yeah. But it was actually like a substantive update
Speaker 6:  when I was writing my hands-on. I was just like, oh Jesus Christ, I forgot
Speaker 6:  about this feature. Oh Jesus Christ, I forgot about that feature. Oh, I
Speaker 6:  get, I have to do two separate hands ons because there's
Speaker 6:  also an AI coach that's coming and that deserves its own 1200
Speaker 6:  words of, of talking about. So it, it was a lot.
Speaker 5:  Right? So, okay, so there's like a mix of things going on here. There's a
Speaker 5:  bunch of like small but meaningful hardware updates, right? It's the, the
Speaker 5:  screen is 50% brighter. So
Speaker 6:  There's, there's a domed display. So you know
Speaker 6:  the glass is domed because they have this little, what they call a rain droplet
Speaker 6:  design. It looks like a little bead of water on your wrist. And that's their
Speaker 6:  design ethos. So that display is, the glass is domed and now the
Speaker 6:  display, the actual display underneath is also domed. And that
Speaker 6:  enables a, a couple of different things. It's 50% brighter, 3000 knits
Speaker 6:  and then it, it's the bezels are 15% thinner than the last
Speaker 6:  generation and the active display area is 10% larger.
Speaker 6:  So like, just by making it domed they did all of that stuff
Speaker 5:  Like that sounds very silly but it's actually like a very meaningful
Speaker 6:  It is. And then like we, I got the chance to look at like The Pixel
Speaker 6:  two, three and four side by side with the flashlight on so that I
Speaker 6:  could see like the difference between both the brightness and the bezels.
Speaker 6:  And I'm like, if you look at the progression of it, it is quite impressive.
Speaker 6:  So that was just like, oh nice nice hardware guys. Yeah. Good,
Speaker 5:  Good job. So, so some some like meaningful hardware improvements also, like
Speaker 5:  dual frequency GPS you like satellites os
Speaker 5:  repair. Well we can talk about the repairability a little bit more later,
Speaker 5:  but it, there, it's more repairable than any other watch.
Speaker 5:  And then there's the ai, the AI is all the other stuff, right?
Speaker 6:  There's, there's just like so much on there. There's like,
Speaker 6:  well like the Samsung watches, the Gemini is now on the wrist, but
Speaker 6:  also like you have smarter contextual
Speaker 6:  replies so that you know, in, so, so one of the things about
Speaker 6:  smart replies on the smart watches, like someone texts you and you can just
Speaker 6:  go boop and and quick reply back and usually they're pretty canned responses,
Speaker 6:  right? They're like, yes, no on my way.
Speaker 6:  And like when I was talking to the Pixel Watch team, they're like, you know,
Speaker 6:  most of the time people only use it about 30% of the time for conversations.
Speaker 6:  It's not that helpful. So now that the, there's like an
Speaker 6:  on-device LLM model on there, it will context give
Speaker 6:  contextual replies based on what was was texted back. It was like, oh, so
Speaker 6:  someone texted you about a game. It could be like, yay, I am really happy
Speaker 6:  we won. And like that's the response that you get to send back. And it's
Speaker 6:  not limited to the default messages app. So if you use
Speaker 6:  a different one like WhatsApp if you use, I don't know if that's signal 'cause
Speaker 6:  there's privacy stuff there, but like cacao talk, which all my Koreans know,
Speaker 6:  that is the, the text messaging apple of choice for Korea and Korean
Speaker 6:  Americans. And you know, you'll be able to have those contextual
Speaker 6:  replies from that. And so that's like one of the many
Speaker 6:  ways that AI can be used on the wrist. And as I've written before
Speaker 6:  though, using a on the wrist is just a little, is a little weird.
Speaker 5:  I it it's like on one hand for a smartwatch, I think those
Speaker 5:  contextual replies could legitimately be like pretty
Speaker 5:  useful. Yeah. 'cause you do not wanna be typing, but Alison you just spent
Speaker 5:  a week using your watch as your main
Speaker 5:  device and you did a bunch of typing on it And I think it was okay.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And maybe it is a little bit of pride for me 'cause I'm like, I'm not
Speaker 8:  using those canned responses or you know, even if they are
Speaker 8:  like pretty close to what I wanna say, that, you know,
Speaker 8:  I'm like, this is my profession robot don't come for me.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, I could see how it, it's just when you're initiating the
Speaker 8:  conversation, I'm like texting my husband on my way home. I don't know how
Speaker 8:  AI knows that I wanna do that, but I can see it being useful
Speaker 8:  and maybe I'll just like get over my hangup with auto reply
Speaker 8:  stuff.
Speaker 5:  I've gotten really into voice to text on text
Speaker 5:  messaging. I'm, I'm, now I'm like, I don't feel like typing, like if, if
Speaker 5:  this is oh, voice memos are anywhere, I'm not doing a full voice memo. Oh
Speaker 5:  no, I'm straight up voice to texting. I sh maybe I should voice because it,
Speaker 5:  and it seems like an insane person. 'cause I'll send like three
Speaker 5:  paragraphs oh
Speaker 8:  My god, of text
Speaker 5:  Like to somebody just because I'm like, I've just been talking for like two
Speaker 5:  minutes straight. I don't wanna type up,
Speaker 6:  I'm saying try voice memos next. Like Mia turned me onto
Speaker 6:  voice memos and now sometimes I'm like, I ain't typing this show. I just
Speaker 6:  send like a two minute message. If
Speaker 5:  I got a voice memo from somebody, I would feel like that was a threat I would
Speaker 5:  like, it's what did I do?
Speaker 8:  I'm like, I gotta put in earbuds now to to no,
Speaker 6:  Usually there's like a text, there's usually a transcript too in case you
Speaker 6:  can't like actually play it. But I don't know, I I've been, I, I had those
Speaker 6:  thoughts and now I'm on that. Now I'm on the voice
Speaker 6:  memo train. But also with, with this new Gemini
Speaker 6:  on the wrist thing, you can raise to talk
Speaker 8:  And I'm into that talk to
Speaker 6:  The thing. But it, it was interesting because you know, oh, I think a lot
Speaker 6:  of the people I were talking to were saying like, oh God, another gesture
Speaker 6:  that you have to do unnaturally. Like,
Speaker 6:  and actually it's a lot more subtle. Like if you do that, it won't
Speaker 6:  actually bring up Gemini just
Speaker 5:  Like, like raise your wrist up to your,
Speaker 6:  Like if you do it to like, if you're like a power ranger when you're doing
Speaker 6:  the move. Yeah, yeah. And like you're trying to talk into your wrist communicator.
Speaker 6:  It's not gonna do it. So you have to do it like, just like naturally and
Speaker 6:  it'll do it. And I was like, oh that's interesting that,
Speaker 6:  you know, 'cause there's a lot of movement that happens with hands, especially
Speaker 6:  if you're like me and you're just doing hand gestures all the time. So having
Speaker 6:  to find out when people are actually wanting to talk to Gemini was a lot
Speaker 6:  of work that they put into it that I was surprised to find was actually
Speaker 6:  like, oh, I don't have to do a crazy exaggerated moment
Speaker 6:  because I'm so used to after 10 years of testing wearables, doing things
Speaker 6:  like flick pinch and like moving like I'm a power ranger
Speaker 6:  because of how
Speaker 6:  wonky these gestures have been over time. And that one was just one where
Speaker 6:  it was actually quite fluid And I was like, oh that's surprisingly good.
Speaker 5:  So the, the other big thing here, And I couldn't quite figure this out,
Speaker 5:  it, there's this Fitbit AI health coach, which is the other like big
Speaker 5:  part of this announcement. It's huge. And I guess I'm curious like is that
Speaker 5:  the Pixel Watch feature or is that just like these two teams are? That's
Speaker 5:  all. Okay, so this is all, all Fit fits, fits
Speaker 6:  And Pixel watches. So it's not gate kept to the Pixel Watch four. It
Speaker 6:  is all Pixel watches and all Fitbits will get this Fitbit AI coach
Speaker 6:  when it rolls out in October though, you have to be a Fitbit premium member
Speaker 6:  in order to, they are gatekeeping it because, well, you know, AI is
Speaker 6:  expensive to run and this health coach
Speaker 6:  is, so my caveat is, is that I've tested a lot of
Speaker 6:  AI health coaches and a lot of AI health and fitness features. I have
Speaker 6:  yet to like a single one. And I walked into this demo
Speaker 6:  being like, this, this better be good buddy.
Speaker 6:  Like this better be some like, here we go again.
Speaker 6:  Friend And I walked out like cautiously, I won't say optimistic,
Speaker 6:  but curious about it. Like they felt, it felt very thoughtful.
Speaker 6:  The Fitbit app is gonna get a complete, it's gonna get blown
Speaker 6:  up completely and completely redesigned. There's a dark mode coming for all
Speaker 6:  the Fitbit people who've been wanting it for a long time. But generally
Speaker 6:  speaking, this AI coach is going to be built into every
Speaker 6:  single nook, cranny, and corner of the Fitbit app.
Speaker 6:  And you're gonna be able to talk to it to give like
Speaker 6:  insights. And you know, I asked
Speaker 6:  Sandeep
Speaker 6:  and Sandeek whatchamacallit, Andy Abramson and
Speaker 6:  Rishi Chandra. Like this was a, this was like a table of very like skeptical
Speaker 6:  journalists grilling these dudes. Just like, you know,
Speaker 6:  I, I went out And I said, you know, these have been capped in obvious level
Speaker 6:  summaries. Just saying like, you did a workout. Thanks. Like I,
Speaker 6:  I can see that in my metrics. So like how are you gonna be different about
Speaker 6:  it? And the answers I got were pretty
Speaker 6:  thoughtful. Like just, you know, it is going to reference your weekly
Speaker 6:  patterns versus your daily patterns, but you can ask it about your
Speaker 6:  long-term patterns. 'cause one of the things was I asked Aura, like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  what's my average hours of sleep for this year?
Speaker 6:  And it would be like, girl, we can't do more than a month. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  you're useless. That's not helpful. That's not helpful. Why do I have five
Speaker 6:  years of Aura data if you can only do a month's worth? And they're like,
Speaker 6:  no, you'll be able to do that with this. It is chatty. I saw the chat
Speaker 6:  logs.
Speaker 5:  I thought, I thought this was so, so interesting. Yeah. And you asked them
Speaker 5:  about this, you're like, yeah, bro, why is in this shorter? Yeah. And they,
Speaker 5:  they were like, we tested and people didn't like it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And they were like, well, we tested it to be shorter, but if you have an
Speaker 6:  LLM do it in three sentences, you don't get anything useful
Speaker 6:  from that. 'cause it's just summering summarizing it so that it's so generalized
Speaker 6:  as to be useless. And I was like, huh. Interesting.
Speaker 6:  So they are right now going for like pretty in depth, like
Speaker 6:  really long things. And then the idea is for it to be
Speaker 6:  conversational and adjust. So like
Speaker 6:  I've had problems where I get injured or it's really hot outside
Speaker 6:  And I have a tendency to be a Type A
Speaker 6:  overachiever and push through the pain, which is not good for you when you're
Speaker 6:  exercising. I've gotten injured a lot over the last few years doing
Speaker 6:  that. And so now you can go talk to this AI and be like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  I tweaked my knee. I can't really do this exercise
Speaker 6:  program that you've done for me. And I'll be like, okay, cool. Let's adjust
Speaker 6:  it and it'll adjust it for you. Which is sort of like the first time that
Speaker 6:  we're actually seeing
Speaker 6:  moving from just a static summary to going like, cool
Speaker 6:  information. Thanks for, for giving it to me. Let me adjust that for you
Speaker 6:  and I'll check in with you a week later to see if you're ready to get back
Speaker 6:  to your regular routine. Which is like, that's what we've been asking for
Speaker 6:  kind of.
Speaker 5:  Right. It feels like everything else has just been, we're not gonna
Speaker 5:  change the existing app. We're not gonna add any new features. But like,
Speaker 5:  hey, here's some ai like, it, it will just summarize. We can already tell
Speaker 5:  you. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's like bolted on.
Speaker 5:  And this feels like they're taking, or at least they're, they're trying to
Speaker 5:  take the maximalist approach, which is like, we're gonna plug all of your
Speaker 5:  data in and we're gonna give you an essay back. Yes. And
Speaker 5:  the whether it works, that's an open question
Speaker 6:  We're we're gonna see.
Speaker 5:  But, But that is, that is like the step that needs to happen. Right? If
Speaker 5:  you want actually good results from the ai, if you want the
Speaker 5:  AI to actually be useful, it needs to have all your data.
Speaker 6:  And that's, that's the, the, the kind of part that I'm somewhat like
Speaker 6:  Hmm. About, you know, because you gotta hoover in a lot.
Speaker 5:  What about handing over your health data?
Speaker 6:  A lot of your health data? And the thing, the thing that they've pointed
Speaker 6:  out to me is that when Google acquired Fitbit
Speaker 6:  regulatorily for that sale to go through, they had to agree to the EU to
Speaker 6:  keep all of the Fitbit data siloed out of the Google data because it
Speaker 6:  was health data. So they are actually obligated to
Speaker 6:  keep those data silos separate. Doesn't mean people trust it doesn't mean
Speaker 6:  you should trust it if you are, if you're like a maximalist
Speaker 6:  about data privacy, security. But it is like a lot of data that
Speaker 6:  they're gonna be asking for. And the they're, they're starting out with fitness
Speaker 6:  and sleep. They have ambitions for it to be everything.
Speaker 8:  I was gonna ask if you think there's like a play with the journal app
Speaker 8:  that we saw on the phones. I, but if there's like
Speaker 8:  no crossover, I think, I know you have some I think so some feelings about
Speaker 8:  the journal app.
Speaker 6:  I don't think AI should be in journals. I don't. I the
Speaker 6:  don't keep the, the AI out of journals you're
Speaker 6:  journaling is not complicated and it's not supposed to be easy. This is,
Speaker 6:  we keep the AI out of the journals.
Speaker 5:  We Yeah, we didn't, we didn't touch on this up top, but for, for some
Speaker 5:  confusing reason, one of the new Pixel features is a
Speaker 5:  journal app. Yes. It's a journal app with some, with AI prompts.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So you'll write journal entries in this AI app
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 6:  it'll prompt you based on what you've written before for new prompts. So
Speaker 6:  it's just like, Hey, why don't you write about your feelings for a test that's
Speaker 6:  coming up next week. And then, you know, you'll write and you can read summaries
Speaker 6:  of the entries that you've written and there's a little calendar and it it's
Speaker 6:  little emoji. Yeah. Summarizing your emotions.
Speaker 6:  You get like a re based what you've written.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's like a smiley face or just kind of like, huh, you didn't have
Speaker 8:  a smiley face date.
Speaker 5:  I feel like you shouldn't be able to lose at journaling. That feels like
Speaker 5:  it is antithetical to like, it's
Speaker 6:  Supposed to. Like there's
Speaker 8:  Of streaks too. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It, it's, it's, I I saw that And I was just like,
Speaker 6:  I think you should have a hard time with a blank page. 'cause that is the
Speaker 6:  point of journaling. But yeah, no, I am with you Allison on
Speaker 6:  that conspiracy theory about like linking those two things
Speaker 6:  for, 'cause they do have ambitions beyond just fitness and sleep. Yeah. Those
Speaker 6:  are just like the natural easy on ramps for this kind
Speaker 6:  of AI health coach feature. But they do wanna get into
Speaker 6:  nutrition. They do wanna get into like, overall health
Speaker 6:  advising And I was just like, let's, let's run it up on the line
Speaker 6:  of medical tech and wellness, a line that I've written about and is getting
Speaker 6:  increasingly blurrier to my internal fear and horror.
Speaker 6:  So there's, there's a lot there that I'm just like,
Speaker 8:  Ah,
Speaker 6:  Ah,
Speaker 5:  It's all colliding
Speaker 8:  Sums it all up. Yeah, it
Speaker 6:  It, it is, but it's the greater point. The the big issue with
Speaker 6:  wearables is that it generates this boatload of data
Speaker 6:  and the average person is just like, okay, cool. I don't know what to do
Speaker 6:  with this like mountain of metrics that you've given me. And so the problem
Speaker 6:  they're trying to solve here is giving you useful actionable context if you're
Speaker 6:  trying to lose some weight, get healthier,
Speaker 6:  be able to run a marathon, like just whatever your goals are, just having,
Speaker 6:  you know, the, the phrasing and the framing they used is like Steph
Speaker 6:  Curry who is actually partnering on this thing and
Speaker 6:  giving feedback and his team is like going like, yeah, you should do this.
Speaker 6:  Not so they're like actually partnering on this particular feature together.
Speaker 6:  But Steph Curry has a whole team of people helping him parse his
Speaker 6:  athletic and health data. What if we democratize that with
Speaker 6:  AI for you?
Speaker 5:  I, I mean listen, I would love if Steph Curry's people gave me some notes,
Speaker 5:  that would be great. I feel like we're not getting notes at that level
Speaker 5:  from, from the Fitbit app.
Speaker 6:  At least not at first that that's their goal. Whether they can get there
Speaker 6:  is a totally different story, But that, that is their kind of
Speaker 6:  like roadmap for that particular feature. And to be fair,
Speaker 6:  it's one that's Garmin's pursuing Apple has Workout Buddy,
Speaker 6:  which is like nowhere near this level of ambition because
Speaker 6:  where, where's the new improved series? You kind of need that for that to
Speaker 6:  happen. But I do think they're thinking about that as well. I
Speaker 6:  think all of these companies are thinking down this route. This is just the
Speaker 6:  most ambitions And I think thoughtful implementation that I've
Speaker 6:  seen as to something that actually tells you something and
Speaker 6:  isn't just a stapled on summary regurgitated book report.
Speaker 5:  No, I think you're right. And And I think between the Fitbit changes that
Speaker 5:  are coming in October, between that and the Pixel Watch four
Speaker 5:  updates, like there's a pretty opinionated series of products here And
Speaker 5:  I think the last piece of this that we saw is some of the
Speaker 5:  hardware changes and the one we didn't talk about yet is the repairability
Speaker 5:  coming to the watch, which is sort of like a total surprise curve
Speaker 5:  ball here.
Speaker 6:  Yes. 'cause The Verge has done some real stress
Speaker 6:  testing. We are apparently famous within that product team
Speaker 6:  for destroying two screens of the first two Pixel watches.
Speaker 6:  Both unintentionally, we dunno how it happened.
Speaker 5:  Listen, listen, it's not on us. And we didn't know. I don't, I don't think,
Speaker 5:  you know,
Speaker 6:  I am, I like, I've had some people go those things broke. Like I've had some
Speaker 6:  people in my Pixel two watch review. Like there is no way You don't
Speaker 6:  know how this happened. I am telling you on the record right now, I cooperated
Speaker 6:  with every step of Google's investigation into how it happened and we were
Speaker 6:  all baffled, like just completely baffled. I was like, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  this
Speaker 5:  Sounds like agents like swarmed your house,
Speaker 6:  Try. Yeah. It sounds like they arrested you. Oh, oh no, they came in person
Speaker 6:  and they were like, we're gonna take this and do, do some tests on it. And
Speaker 6:  I was just like, please pass
Speaker 5:  The polygraph.
Speaker 6:  He's still here. I was like, please tell me there's like conspiracy theories
Speaker 6:  that my cat did it. I he was a baby. I don't think he could have done it.
Speaker 6:  He, listen, he didn't have teethers yet, so
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So apparently we are famous for having done that in,
Speaker 6:  in some capacity, but what I was told is that
Speaker 6:  they really want these devices to last a long time. So they want it to
Speaker 6:  last a long time for people to have and repair. Making it
Speaker 6:  repairable was just one part of that. If you take the, the straps off and
Speaker 6:  you look into the little lug his area, there's little screws. There's little
Speaker 6:  screws and you can unscrew it and if you take it off, it actually
Speaker 6:  kind of what they said is the insides have been redesigned to kind of look
Speaker 6:  like a bento box. So
Speaker 5:  It all comes through a circle. It all comes back full circle. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Alright. There's open the bento box from the event and they put it in the,
Speaker 6:  The Pixel, Pixel Watch,
Speaker 8:  Put it in a watch,
Speaker 5:  You open it up, there's a little update sheet inside it. It tells you what
Speaker 5:  features it has.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And yeah, so the idea is that the display and the
Speaker 6:  battery will be repairable and replaceable. So,
Speaker 5:  Which is really impressive for a watch,
Speaker 6:  Especially one where people were just like breaking the screens left and
Speaker 6:  right. That is one of the,
Speaker 5:  When you say people, the other than us, pretty, pretty, pretty
Speaker 5:  specifically
Speaker 6:  Us, but also other, we didn't do it with the Pixel Watch three n Knock on
Speaker 6:  wood, we're not gonna do it with our Pixel
Speaker 5:  Watch. I mean, try us.
Speaker 8:  Oh, can I, can I say my favorite watch feature this year? Yes.
Speaker 8:  Is the new charger the new proprietary charger?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Which I know you're all annoyed by it. The watch goes
Speaker 8:  on it like it's sleeping on a pillow. It looks like it,
Speaker 8:  it's like it charges on its side and it just looks like it's
Speaker 8:  sleepy and it's taking a little rest once you
Speaker 6:  Said that, And I put it in all my hands on And I'm pretty sure I credited
Speaker 6:  you and at least most of my mentions of it across the thing. But I
Speaker 6:  was just like, once I, once she said it, I couldn't unsee it And I was like,
Speaker 6:  that's so cute.
Speaker 8:  It's just a tired little gadget. I'm so
Speaker 6:  Tired.
Speaker 8:  I'm, I'm sorry. You need like another watch charger
Speaker 6:  That is really annoying. This is the third proprietary charger in four watches.
Speaker 6:  So that's not ideal from an e-waste perspective,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of
Speaker 8:  Progressive. It's, yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's just like, guys come on. But I actually like
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 5:  No, that makes sense though too. Especially if like, you're putting that
Speaker 5:  up beside your bed at night. If now you've gotta look locked. It's, no, it's
Speaker 5:  all right. There's something there. I see it. On the topic of Repairability
Speaker 5:  that was on the only repairable gadget they announced the
Speaker 5:  other new piece of hardware, I think the final new piece of hardware
Speaker 5:  Pixel Buds two A. Yes. Which, what's
Speaker 5:  repairable here? It's, it's they, can you replace the battery
Speaker 6:  On that? Yeah. So there's the, the case and there's the little insert inside
Speaker 6:  the case. You can pop that out and replace the battery.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Okay. Yeah. So it's the battery in the case, not in the buds, which
Speaker 5:  would be kind of Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's intense. Yeah, yeah, yeah. So it's the case battery that you can just
Speaker 6:  pop it out, replace it. That's, that's pretty cool. They
Speaker 6:  added, so here's another thing. There's like a big thesis with all of
Speaker 6:  these devices and it, the thesis is Gemini and AI basically
Speaker 6:  because these budget buds got the tensor chip
Speaker 6:  and why would they have a tensor chip?
Speaker 5:  Why not? Why not
Speaker 6:  Future AI baby? Like that's just like, you can just
Speaker 6:  see that they're going like, we're gonna need i
Speaker 6:  everything to have AI in it.
Speaker 5:  Sometimes I I think you're people are
Speaker 5:  genuinely like, we're doing this because we think it's gonna be cool. We
Speaker 5:  think people are gonna like it. And sometimes I think people are like, my
Speaker 5:  boss really wants us to say ai. Yeah. And that's what that feels like.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I feel like someone's like, they're, they're gonna love it. They're
Speaker 5:  gonna like, I'm gonna get a promotion if I, if I put Gemini like on this
Speaker 5:  box five times and like what,
Speaker 5:  like, you, you could already talk to Google on these. Like, what, what, what,
Speaker 5:  what do I need these Pixel Buds two A to Gemini for me?
Speaker 6:  I, you know, I think they're just kind of future proofing for down the, down
Speaker 6:  the road for whenever it is that they have like AI based
Speaker 6:  sound audio features, you know? Yeah. Like, like, I mean
Speaker 6:  it's interesting because the original a series buds where like
Speaker 6:  $99, they were the kind of, you know, cheaper version.
Speaker 6:  Now they're 130, so they're $30 more expensive, but they also
Speaker 6:  have a NC and transparency mode, which they didn't have before.
Speaker 5:  Right. Noise cancellation is actually like a pretty meaningful upgrade here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's
Speaker 6:  A pretty meaningful,
Speaker 5:  It's it's actually not, I was looking at the comparison page between the
Speaker 5:  Pixel Buds two A and the Pixel Buds two Pro.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, I, it feels sort of like Google is like searching
Speaker 5:  for places to, to make the two pro different, that like the
Speaker 5:  difference in the noise cancellation is that they're like the Pixel
Speaker 5:  Buds two Pro has active noise cancellation with, with
Speaker 5:  Live Seal 2.0 and the Pixel Buds two A is active
Speaker 5:  noise cancellation with Live Seal 1.5. And I'm like, what is, what is
Speaker 5:  Live Seal? I like, I don't know if I have the name right, but it's like you're
Speaker 5:  searching here, you're searching for like, which is great. It's great if
Speaker 5:  the Pixel Buds two A are like getting closer to pro level
Speaker 5:  features. It does not have wireless charging in the case.
Speaker 6:  No, that was annoying. That
Speaker 5:  Was, that's that was like, that's a rough one. I'm that's, yeah, once you're,
Speaker 5:  once you're living that wireless charging lifestyle, it's hard to go back.
Speaker 6:  It is. But it, it's funny because when it, Allison And I went to this content
Speaker 6:  capture before the event, it, like, if you looked at
Speaker 6:  the displays, it was like phones, watches, and
Speaker 6:  in the corner right over there are The Pixel ones. We're like, where
Speaker 6:  are they? Where are The Pixel one? They're like, oh, they're in the corner.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I like, and, and And I when I was like, so what's, what's new? And
Speaker 6:  they're like, oh, A and C and you can talk to Gemini on it. And like the
Speaker 6:  talking point was like, and you can talk to Gemini on it. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  couldn't you talk to Gemini on it before? And they're like, but you can talk
Speaker 6:  to Gemini, you can really talk to Gemini on it now.
Speaker 6:  It was like, okay, so, okay, so the ai ai is
Speaker 6:  the thing
Speaker 5:  And the, you know what, my big problem with literally all of Google's products,
Speaker 5:  I can't find a way to talk to Gemini, you know? Yeah. They make it so
Speaker 5:  hard
Speaker 6:  To access that data and they're like, you know, these, these, these devices,
Speaker 6:  unlike your phone, they live on you. And so these are the different
Speaker 6:  pathways in which we can talk to ai, AI in your ear,
Speaker 6:  AI on your wrist, AI in your pocket. And I was like, oh my God.
Speaker 6:  Okay, new, new meaning to ambient computing, which is
Speaker 6:  the whole thing that they were kind of talking about when
Speaker 6:  they introduced The Pixel phone. So I guess this is what they
Speaker 5:  Meant. And speaking of Gemini being literally everywhere,
Speaker 5:  they, they did potentially, we think they teased one other
Speaker 5:  product here, which is just in the middle of a
Speaker 5:  video of where they were demoing some stuff. They kind
Speaker 5:  of just, like, there's a, there's a, a weird little gadget that looked like
Speaker 5:  a next Gen Nest hub Nest mini Google
Speaker 5:  Home Mini what it was, there was a little gray orb with
Speaker 5:  like a blue ring around it that was, was talking to them with
Speaker 5:  Gemini and it looks like a new Nest smart speaker, which they, those things
Speaker 5:  haven't been updated in forever. Forever. And they announced also on Wednesday
Speaker 5:  that they're finally bringing Gemini to smart speakers in the home,
Speaker 5:  starting in October. But like, Alexa plus is gonna be like slow rollout.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. We'll see. Have you guys tried using
Speaker 5:  like Google Assistant lately? Oh
Speaker 6:  Yes. It's in my home because
Speaker 6:  we had a Smart Home package last year And I was a first time homeowner,
Speaker 6:  so Jen Tuy like held my hand and walked me through my first
Speaker 6:  smart home. Oh, amazing. And she decided that it was gonna be a nest in Google
Speaker 6:  Smart Home. So I talked to Google Assistant on the daily Oh. For my
Speaker 6:  little broken Jan Smart home.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You know what? It's so it breaks half the time.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's not great. We, our 4-year-old has learned how to
Speaker 8:  get Google to say the weather and the way he just yells at it
Speaker 8:  is he is like, Google say, what's a weather today? So
Speaker 8:  I think he's using it as much as we are.
Speaker 5:  He has gotten it to be more functional than I have. I I,
Speaker 5:  this weekend I was like, Hey Google. What? Oh, I'm so sorry to literally
Speaker 5:  every listen. Yes, but this weekend I was like, yo, what is the weight of
Speaker 5:  an iPad? Air seems, I feel like that's manageable. It was just
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know what a question is. I don't know what an iPad is. Like
Speaker 5:  what do like it, it would like, it like had a meltdown. Oh no mine. It just
Speaker 5:  like, didn't know what to do with this.
Speaker 6:  Mine is sexist because I will ask it to turn on the
Speaker 6:  kitchen lights or whatever and it'll listen and my spouse will do it and
Speaker 6:  it won't, it just does not register. And like we trained their
Speaker 6:  voice on it too, so it's like rude.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Only listens to me. So they are just like, I don't know why
Speaker 6:  we gotta talk to this robot and I'm just gonna pull up the app and control
Speaker 6:  it from, from the phone. So it it is, it's, yeah,
Speaker 6:  well
Speaker 5:  Get ready for October. 'cause they're gonna sell some new robots that will
Speaker 5:  maybe they, I I truly think they're like, we gotta be careful
Speaker 5:  we can't put Gemini in 'cause we'll lose some Google Assistant features.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, no, no. Like half broken Gemini cannot be worse
Speaker 5:  than this. Like, these things just do not function anymore.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, it's gotten really bad lately. I, I gotta agree with
Speaker 6:  you. And there'll be times where the, the wake word,
Speaker 6:  I won't say it, but I'm sorry
Speaker 5:  Again,
Speaker 6:  The wake word will just activate out of nowhere. I don't know what
Speaker 6:  I'm like, am my, is my house haunted? Because it'll just like go bing, boom
Speaker 6:  ba and, and and oh, it'll say things. I've been on calls
Speaker 6:  with sources and it just acts up because I have a, a nest hub by my
Speaker 6:  desk and to, to look at the doorbell and it's like, oh
Speaker 6:  cool. I just have a rogue smart speaker.
Speaker 5:  Mine, mine. Every time I talk to my cat, mine's like, you're talking to me,
Speaker 5:  right? I'm like, well,
Speaker 6:  Do they have similar names?
Speaker 5:  I no,
Speaker 6:  I,
Speaker 5:  I'm looking forward to seeing any movement here on, on making
Speaker 5:  these things more usable Again. I I think like we, we don't really know,
Speaker 5:  but yeah, I'm, I'm hoping that a lot of these features come to the older
Speaker 5:  ones just 'cause there's a huge install base there and that product is obviously
Speaker 5:  not what it once was. Alright, we've got to take a break when we get back.
Speaker 5:  The thunder round returns new. Improved, better than ever.
Speaker 5:  Get ready for it.
Speaker 5:  disposed of the lightning round. That thing is over. It's
Speaker 5:  stale. It's done with, they could never get to all the stories. So I have
Speaker 5:  given Eric Gomez our producer, the Power of Thunder to make sure that we
Speaker 5:  can get through all of the important stuff that we wanna talk about. We're
Speaker 5:  gonna do five stories, five minutes each when we're getting close to time.
Speaker 5:  Eric's gonna give us some rolling thunder that's playing us off. And if we
Speaker 5:  go too far, we will be struck down
Speaker 5:  by a sound that is, is related to
Speaker 5:  lightning but is distinctly not lightning because that is not part
Speaker 5:  of this new world. Again, we're working on it, we're working on
Speaker 5:  the intro, we're working on the segment. It's gonna get better each week.
Speaker 5:  Okay, first up the what have we got?
Speaker 6:  We have beans. So Hank Green released
Speaker 6:  this app called Focus Friend and it is kind
Speaker 6:  of a po Pomodoro timer. It is kind of a distraction
Speaker 6:  free situation. And our good friend Zach Brown
Speaker 6:  wrote Hank Green's Focus Friends swapped my screen time for Bean Time
Speaker 6:  And I love this app so much. I downloaded it recently
Speaker 6:  and continuing my theme of using the brick for TV time.
Speaker 6:  I am using the Bean app for reading time
Speaker 6:  and guys, I got through four books this week. How that is,
Speaker 6:  that is insane. What I got through four, four books this week. I've gotten
Speaker 6:  through seven books this month. Do you? It's amazing. Do you read a
Speaker 6:  physical book? Are you on a Kindle? I am on physical books. I'm on Kindles,
Speaker 6:  I'm on my phone. I'm on my gosh, audio books. I'm on like different
Speaker 6:  formats at all time. Are you,
Speaker 5:  You doing audio and physical book like simultaneously? No. Like how
Speaker 6:  Else you through books? It all makes sense.
Speaker 5:  This is not happening.
Speaker 6:  I can't tell you read four books. So
Speaker 5:  That is not You're two Xing an audio book
Speaker 6:  While you're reading. No, that's not what I'm doing. But so like the
Speaker 6:  issue I I've had is just like being way too addicted to
Speaker 6:  my phone. Like I think this is a universal problem at this point in time
Speaker 6:  And I just, as soon as a notification comes up, I get into panic mode, like,
Speaker 6:  oh, I have to answer it immediately or someone's gonna hate me.
Speaker 6:  But no, I, I put the bean timer on the Focus Friend,
Speaker 6:  my Bean, you can name your bean. His name is B Bbo, my, my bean
Speaker 6:  name Bbo. And so bla bo the concept is that
Speaker 6:  bla bo is a radioactive beam that has been like
Speaker 6:  injected into your phone and he lives there now. And bla bo's great passion
Speaker 6:  in life is knitting, but Bbo can't knit if you're on your phone
Speaker 6:  and being distracted. So you put this little timer on and
Speaker 6:  then B bbo knits for the time that you are not on your
Speaker 6:  phone. And when B BBO is done, he has either knitted
Speaker 6:  socks if you're on the free version like me or scarves if
Speaker 6:  you choose to pay or whatnot. And then depending on the amount
Speaker 6:  of socks or scarves that B lvo or your bean, whatever you wanna name,
Speaker 6:  it has knitted. You can decorate his little
Speaker 5:  Room. It's so nice. Oh my. It's all bean. I, I'm looking at the art and it's
Speaker 5:  like, it's so delightful. I should also say disclosure, Hank
Speaker 5:  Green is gonna cohost decoder next month, which also
Speaker 5:  promo Hank Green is gonna cohost decoder next month. But this app is just
Speaker 5:  like, it, it feels, it has like animal crossing vibes where it's just like
Speaker 5:  kind of quaint and delightful and you just decorate stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You, it's like animal crossing vibes mixed with a Pomodoro timer, which
Speaker 6:  if you don't know, a Pomodoro timer is based on like the little tomato kitchen
Speaker 6:  timers. You go for 25 minutes of focus time
Speaker 6:  on a single task, then you take a five minute break, you do that four times
Speaker 6:  and then you get a 15 minute break. It's like a productivity thing. I use
Speaker 6:  it a lot. It helps me get started on projects I don't wanna do.
Speaker 6:  So that mix just really worked for my brain
Speaker 6:  with reading. And so every morning now
Speaker 6:  I've become a morning person through sheer force of effort because no one
Speaker 6:  can interrupt your morning. They can always interrupt and derail your evening.
Speaker 6:  No one can interrupt your morning if you get up really early.
Speaker 8:  My 4-year-old wants a word.
Speaker 6:  Ah, well I, it's true, but like, so my cat
Speaker 6:  loves cuddle time on the couch in the morning. Oh. So I put bbo the bean
Speaker 6:  timer on, I get the cat.
Speaker 8:  Oh my gosh. I open up
Speaker 6:  A book and for, oh my gosh, 30 minutes to 45 minutes before work
Speaker 6:  I uninterrupted reading.
Speaker 8:  That's so beautiful.
Speaker 6:  And that is how I got
Speaker 5:  Four books, books this week as the single most zen thing I've heard in months.
Speaker 5:  Beautiful. I beautiful.
Speaker 8:  I have a question. What kinds of stuff can you decorate blower blows
Speaker 8:  room with?
Speaker 6:  There's so, you know, because I do it in such short time
Speaker 6:  intervals and BBO is not the fastest knitter, I've only
Speaker 6:  been able to buy a shelf, but you can buy a shelf. I think there's a
Speaker 6:  chair course had, there's a, it's 75 socks for a shelf,
Speaker 6:  but oh dang. He just got a little pink shelf today. I'm very proud. BBO
Speaker 6:  has a a a a shelf to, you know, and it's, it's, it's about the
Speaker 6:  process because every time I take time to read I'm helping
Speaker 6:  LBO and it socks.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Can he put, can he eventually put stuff on the shelf? Is there like
Speaker 8:  little plants he can get?
Speaker 6:  I think so. Honestly, his sock. I, I need to read more so
Speaker 6:  that PBO can have his little socks. Oh, okay. 'cause I'm not report back.
Speaker 6:  Sorry. Hank Green. I have limited funds. I'm not buying the pro version
Speaker 6:  for the scarves.
Speaker 5:  I So wait, what do you, what? Why do you get scarves? The scarves? What,
Speaker 5:  what's,
Speaker 6:  I think scarves are a higher value in, I've seen knitters
Speaker 6:  get mad about this online uhuh 'cause they're like, socks should be higher
Speaker 6:  value than the scarves. And I was just like
Speaker 5:  Either or two actual knitters
Speaker 6:  I have tried and absolutely not, I cannot do it. It's
Speaker 6:  just knit pearl. I can't do it. My friend is a great knitter, not me. But
Speaker 6:  yeah,
Speaker 5:  Hank Ian should, should know that he should, he should be more serious about
Speaker 5:  the relative value of the knitting that this beam does.
Speaker 6:  I'm here for P lbo, I'm here for pl bo to knit socks while I read
Speaker 6:  and sit with a cat just purring on me every morning.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Honestly, I'm here for B lbo. The scientific accuracy concerns me and I'll,
Speaker 5:  I, okay. There's
Speaker 8:  A bean in your phone. There're worried about the value. There's
Speaker 6:  A, there's a bean that lives in my phone who likes to
Speaker 5:  Knit. Listen, listen. The,
Speaker 5:  okay, Allison, what have you got? Okay.
Speaker 8:  Okay, I'll go with the Ricoh GR
Speaker 8:  four. We're going to the camera world got a price.
Speaker 8:  So it was announced earlier this year. This is a beloved
Speaker 8:  like camera nerds camera. It's been like
Speaker 8:  1 million years since they announced a new one. The
Speaker 8:  GR three was 2019, so it's
Speaker 8:  been like coming and in the works this fall,
Speaker 8:  they announce the price and it is
Speaker 8:  $1,500.
Speaker 8:  The previous version was $900. So
Speaker 8:  that's a bummer and sort of
Speaker 8:  is giving me Sony RX one R
Speaker 8:  vibes. Where
Speaker 6:  Is this all tariffs?
Speaker 8:  What the hell? I I know. That's what I feel. It's
Speaker 5:  A little tariffs
Speaker 8:  Because I will, you know, the PS five went
Speaker 8:  up in price this week, so it feels a little bit
Speaker 8:  like maybe this is a tariff thing happening here. But yeah,
Speaker 8:  the arcs one are also not updated in
Speaker 8:  like a long time. 2015 was the last one.
Speaker 8:  And then that famously Sony just outta the blue was like, we're making a
Speaker 8:  new one and it's five grand.
Speaker 5:  I I had not like, heard much about the,
Speaker 5:  the GR three i, I like did not know that was a camera.
Speaker 5:  And then I think, you know, during the X 100 craze, it was
Speaker 5:  like the go-to comparison and it's, it's fascinating because
Speaker 5:  it really is like a, it's like a different take on
Speaker 5:  the same kind of idea where it is, it is an AP
Speaker 5:  PSC sensor. So you've got a big sensor in a compact camera,
Speaker 5:  but it's even more compact. You can actually pocket this thing, well it
Speaker 5:  depends on your pocket, but like big pockets more so than the XX 100. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But there's no viewfinder, which like is a bummer. It's like a different
Speaker 5:  style of shooting. But you know, it's, it like if
Speaker 5:  you wanted a point and shoe that takes fantastic photos, like this is,
Speaker 5:  this has really been the camera and at 1500 you're buying a
Speaker 5:  very, very different type of product.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly. I feel like it's kind of flown under the radar a little
Speaker 8:  bit, especially in the, the shadow of the X 100.
Speaker 8:  But it, it is really like a camera person's camera where it's kind
Speaker 8:  of the one that, you know, back at deeper review would, would just be like
Speaker 8:  talked about and like, oh yeah, the Ricoh gr is so nice. You know,
Speaker 8:  the camera
Speaker 5:  People love the Ricos.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's, I it has that, that following. It's a smaller
Speaker 8:  following than the Fuji film. But
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's probably it though because like the Fuji film, I feel
Speaker 5:  like the Fuji film is like, you're not a photographer but you, you kind of
Speaker 5:  aspire to be. And this is like, you spend your day lugging
Speaker 5:  around enormous lenses, fiddling with all kinds of dials and
Speaker 5:  you're like, thank goodness I can just like hit one button and take a good
Speaker 5:  photo. Yeah. Like that. It's, it's bringing it all down to
Speaker 5:  like the size of something normal. Also. Interesting.
Speaker 5:  I think what, like a couple weeks ago, Fuji raised their prices.
Speaker 8:  Oh
Speaker 5:  That they, they experie is the same thing. Yeah. A couple weeks ago they
Speaker 5:  raised prices on some of their, one of their cameras went up $800.
Speaker 5:  This is absurd. Fortunately the, the the X
Speaker 5:  106 went up merely $200.
Speaker 5:  So I think, I think it's at, ooh, was it's at 1700 now, maybe
Speaker 5:  800. 1800.
Speaker 8:  Can you buy one
Speaker 5:  Now? No, it's, it's 1800 now. I think they're like
Speaker 5:  In stock ish. I I, I think like the last I checked on Reddit,
Speaker 5:  it's like, you're, you're not waiting so long anymore. Okay. If you, I
Speaker 5:  think I hundred so 1800. So it's that thing's still more expensive. And
Speaker 5:  also, this is what's wild about Fuji that, so they, they
Speaker 5:  announced their price hike like two weeks ago and just this week they're
Speaker 5:  like, we're gonna have to raise our prices again. Oh my God. They're
Speaker 5:  gonna, so at the end of the month they're, they're like, we we're not, and
Speaker 5:  we're not selling you, but like,
Speaker 5:  buy it now. Buy it now. Like Right. These things, things are not going great
Speaker 5:  for the camera companies. Is this,
Speaker 6:  This is rough. Like, I mean, there's such uncertainty with the
Speaker 6:  tariffs, right. Because we never know if they're on or if they're off or
Speaker 6:  if they're fully on or off again. 'cause it's, you know,
Speaker 6:  we need a crystal ball for that. But when they do hit,
Speaker 6:  I really do feel like I'm being punched in the face. Like they,
Speaker 6:  this, this, these are significant price hikes. Like, I mean
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right, right. The, the PS five went up 50 bucks this week.
Speaker 8:  I feel very righteous because I bought mine a couple months
Speaker 8:  ago. I was like, we got it, we gotta get on this. Gotta lock. This is
Speaker 8:  is only going up. So save 50 bucks right there.
Speaker 5:  Every company just needs to be blaring tariff sale. It's our normal
Speaker 5:  price. We cannot promise it will last.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I,
Speaker 6:  yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm very excited to see how this camera has, has
Speaker 5:  improved because at this price, it's, it's a very different
Speaker 5:  prospect than it once was. Yeah. But I think particularly given the,
Speaker 5:  the, you know, craze around the X one hundreds
Speaker 5:  speaking as somebody who owns one, like I, I wanna see more competition in
Speaker 5:  this space. Yeah. We need to see more of these like a PSC, bigger
Speaker 5:  sensors coming into smaller cameras. It's great. I love
Speaker 5:  it. I wish it wasn't 1500 bucks. Same. Yeah. It's a lot. Whoa,
Speaker 6:  Whoa. Oh my god. Got it. That one got me. Nailed
Speaker 5:  It. Okay. So Netflix is changing, and
Speaker 5:  this is, I think like we've talked about this a little bit in the past, but
Speaker 5:  they're sort of at the end of an era. I'm gonna paint like a little bit of
Speaker 5:  a picture here. Right. A lot of their biggest serious swim winding down.
Speaker 5:  Right? We Squid game just wrapped up, what, two months
Speaker 5:  ago, the final season of Stranger Things about to hit and
Speaker 5:  we're starting to see this programming shift, right? So earlier
Speaker 5:  this year they started bringing episodes of Miss
Speaker 5:  Rachel to the platform. Okay. Alright.
Speaker 5:  They just announced that Mark Rober, one of the biggest YouTubers is getting
Speaker 5:  a Netflix series also this week.
Speaker 5:  The Duffer Brothers who make Stranger Things and who previously had a
Speaker 5:  big deal at Netflix to make a whole bunch of new shows and Stranger Things
Speaker 5:  spinoffs announced they're going to join Paramount in a couple years.
Speaker 5:  And so that to me tells me like their Headspace
Speaker 5:  is somewhere else. Right? Hmm. Netflix for the longest time, they
Speaker 5:  were like, had something to prove we're premium,
Speaker 5:  we can do great stuff. And now the Duffer brothers are like,
Speaker 5:  Hey, Paramount's gonna give us a big sack of cash. And they're
Speaker 5:  like,
Speaker 5:  Stranger, this
Speaker 6:  Is
Speaker 5:  Pretty good. But like, okay.
Speaker 6:  Right. Like
Speaker 5:  A, I I am curious like, are you seeing
Speaker 5:  this when you're watching Netflix? Like, what I feel like increasingly
Speaker 5:  I, like I subscribe for those big shows that
Speaker 5:  are basically wrapped up And I have not started a new Netflix series in a
Speaker 5:  while.
Speaker 6:  So the difference that I'm seeing is that Netflix
Speaker 6:  is going hard on Korean stuff. Mm. Like they are
Speaker 6:  bringing so many KDRs over that I'm just like, shit, I
Speaker 6:  can't cancel my Netflix subscription. Wow. Where am I gonna get my
Speaker 6:  KDRs from? And then, you know, then they had K-pop demon
Speaker 6:  hunters like explode. I, I don't think Netflix
Speaker 6:  was prepared for K-pop demon hunters and what a massive phenomenon that's
Speaker 6:  been. But I was like, maybe you should have like Squid games did
Speaker 6:  bongos for you. The Glory was huge on your, your platform as well.
Speaker 6:  And then, you know, K-pop demon Hunters is
Speaker 6:  apparently destroying the, the, the billboard charts and the Han
Speaker 6:  moon has been sealed or whatever. So they, they apparently
Speaker 6:  greenlit two more K-Pop demon hunters movie, possibly a live action and
Speaker 6:  possibly a series. Oh my God. Going on all of this. They
Speaker 5:  Just pounced on that. They
Speaker 6:  Just, 'cause it's the first Netflix thing where the movie, the
Speaker 6:  the viewership has gone up over time. Wow. So they're like,
Speaker 6:  holy guacamole. What do you mean? It's, it's like, I still think
Speaker 6:  it's like the number one movie on Netflix
Speaker 5:  Right now keeps, this is really like the only Netflix movie that I've heard
Speaker 5:  people discuss after the movie came out. I feel like, I feel like everything
Speaker 5:  else you're like, did you see they're doing this? And then it's just done.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's the extent of it. It's, yeah, this just keeps going.
Speaker 6:  And like Korea is all on k-pop demon hunters right now.
Speaker 6:  Samsung was just like, we're gonna get on this. And at Samsung Galaxy unpack,
Speaker 6:  they were just blaring the soundtrack. Alison can for can Attest. I went,
Speaker 6:  oh my God, K-Pop Demon Hunters,
Speaker 8:  No idea what I was listening to. And v explained it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I I to your point, I do think
Speaker 6:  they're just going like, screw prestige. We'll just go
Speaker 6:  in on KDRs, which are produced super cheaply overseas. Let's
Speaker 6:  get in on the YouTubers, which have a built-in audience. Let's just, it's
Speaker 6:  kind of just like what Google did and they're just like, we're gonna find
Speaker 6:  different distribution. Like, you
Speaker 5:  Know what I, I think there's something there, right? It's like the traditional,
Speaker 5:  you know, prestige stuff. Like, that's expensive. It's risky and
Speaker 5:  everyone makes fun of you when you do a bad job. But like, they can
Speaker 5:  pump out however many reality shows they want. And actually, like, there's
Speaker 5:  a pretty big audience for that stuff. And they don't all have to be winners.
Speaker 5:  They can syndicate or bring in a ton of K
Speaker 5:  dramas. They, they can see if it's any good. They can make deals for this
Speaker 5:  stuff. They don't. Right. They don't have to take on as much risk. And I
Speaker 5:  think the YouTubers, you're right, like there's a built-in audience there.
Speaker 6:  It just makes sense. And like they're doing a lot of weird live stuff too.
Speaker 6:  Like, I was watching ev everybody's live with John Malaney And I was like,
Speaker 6:  I didn't know this was a thing.
Speaker 5:  I, I signed up and said I could watch the first episode because
Speaker 5:  I'm like, oh, this is crazy. They're doing a talk show with John Mullaney,
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be live. And then at the top of the first episode he is like,
Speaker 5:  we actually did this last year. I'm like, what? I have the same
Speaker 6:  Reaction done this, I have the same reaction. I was like, what?
Speaker 6:  I didn't know they did this last year live. It's not,
Speaker 5:  They're work, they're working on learning how to promote this, I guess.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They're, but like to your point, Netflix feels different
Speaker 6:  from what it used to be.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's clearly in a new era it is figuring things out. Right?
Speaker 5:  They're doing like the, the big fights to, there's a
Speaker 5:  lot more here and it's like the, the, the future shape of Netflix
Speaker 5:  is very different. And as somebody who, I
Speaker 5:  dunno enjoyed quite a few of those like prestigious series I did, you know,
Speaker 5:  a little bummed. But
Speaker 6:  Listen, you can just watch 40,000 k dramas. All of them are 15
Speaker 6:  episodes. They kind of drag around episode 10 where you're like, get on with
Speaker 6:  it, but then it's done and there's like 4,000 of them.
Speaker 5:  Well this is what I've learned. I need to watch K-Pop Demon Honors to prepare
Speaker 5:  for K-Pop Demon, hers two, three and the live action movie.
Speaker 6:  What I will say is the soundtrack is a banger.
Speaker 5:  May I'll start there. Alright. The what have you got
Speaker 5:  next?
Speaker 6:  So this is a sequel from last week's corporate shenanigans. Mm.
Speaker 6:  So we have a little mini corporate shenanigan sequel
Speaker 6:  where Massimo maker of medical tech devices,
Speaker 6:  mostly Pulse Oximeters, is now suing US customs
Speaker 6:  for allowing Apple to have a workaround from the Apple
Speaker 6:  Botch import ban. And I just think that is Chef's
Speaker 6:  Kiss. I love corporate beef over patents. It's so
Speaker 6:  like, as a puny human who like worries about paying
Speaker 6:  bills that I'm just like, ha these
Speaker 6:  numbers that they're talking about are fake. But also
Speaker 6:  the pettiness, I live for the pettiness of this. They're like, well we can't
Speaker 6:  get Apple, so well get you and your little dog do
Speaker 6:  us customs.
Speaker 5:  This, this is so good because Apple, right. Apple went to customs
Speaker 5:  and they're like, this is good. Right? Like we f like we, we, we snuck it
Speaker 5:  in. We figured something out and customs give 'em the Okay. Yeah. And so
Speaker 5:  they can't sue Apple or maybe they're already suing Apple. They're,
Speaker 6:  They've already sued Apple like five times.
Speaker 5:  They're mad at customs. And so like, I, I guess, I guess we'll Sue
Speaker 5:  customs. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're like, we don't like this customs. You were out of pocket
Speaker 6:  doing that. Also, we didn't find out about this until Apple announced
Speaker 6:  it. What the heck? So it was just, I I was just looking at
Speaker 6:  that and I'm like, oh, my show's on.
Speaker 8:  They're just lashing out. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm once again begging everyone to make these
Speaker 5:  sensors useful. Like, this is, again, this
Speaker 5:  sensor was missing from the Apple watch for a year and a half
Speaker 5:  and no one complained.
Speaker 6:  No. Well, like four people in my comments complain. 'cause
Speaker 6:  I'm the wearable lady and so they're, if they're gonna complain to anybody,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be me. But most people did not miss this sensor
Speaker 6:  whatsoever. And you just have Massimo being over here
Speaker 6:  like, this is our thing. You can't do this. And
Speaker 6:  meanwhile I'm sitting here going like, guys, your patent expires in 2028
Speaker 6:  like
Speaker 5:  This. I guess this really is their, their last hurrah. Like they've got
Speaker 5:  to,
Speaker 6:  They've, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  Just, they've gotta get it now or they've got nothing. They're,
Speaker 6:  I feel like they're at this point that I was like, we're in too deep. We've
Speaker 6:  made a stand. We can't let, we can't like,
Speaker 6:  like what, what was the thing they say at the end of Brave Braveheart? Just
Speaker 6:  like, that's how I imagine them just yelling the, the Braveheart thing going
Speaker 6:  into battle. They're like, for glory or whatever my crappy Scottish accent
Speaker 6:  is. But you know, just, that's how I imagine Massimo and just being like
Speaker 6:  blood oxygen. So yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'm happy for them. I'm glad they're continuing the beef. Allison,
Speaker 5:  we, the last week we decided are these events
Speaker 5:  shenanigans or are they serious? What is your read in the Moss most situation?
Speaker 8:  I maybe a little bit of both. I think it, it makes sense if
Speaker 8:  they're, they gotta make the most out of this patent and they're just gonna
Speaker 8:  throw a fit with everybody and make it everybody
Speaker 8:  else's problem.
Speaker 5:  This is, I I think I'm with you where it's like this is, they're,
Speaker 5:  they're dead serious, but it is absolutely futile.
Speaker 5:  They're gonna get nowhere
Speaker 6:  Stupid. I mean, apple has so much money, so nobody
Speaker 6:  knows what Massimo is except for like this Apple
Speaker 5:  Will invent new court systems if it has to. It
Speaker 6:  Apple will be like, okay, bet we'll find a different workaround
Speaker 6:  aside from this work. We have time, we have money bet we're gonna just
Speaker 6:  not do this. So it's just like, I feel like they're just doing this
Speaker 6:  on principle. They're like, we're gonna stand on business, on blood
Speaker 6:  oxygen, this thing that people do not care about extensively.
Speaker 6:  And we are just gonna beef until the sun. It's Kendrick
Speaker 6:  Lamar energy and
Speaker 8:  You gotta respect it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I, I, 2025 is the year of the hater,
Speaker 6:  so I gotta respect it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's good. Okay. Excited to see where this goes next. And how
Speaker 5:  many more lawsuits are filed before the patent expires in 2028,
Speaker 6:  20,000. Keep
Speaker 5:  Keep it locked on The Verge. We will have nonstop wall to
Speaker 5:  wall apple patent coverage. That's our promise to you.
Speaker 6:  B
Speaker 5:  Allison, take us home. What do we got?
Speaker 8:  Okay, this is the most important news you'll hear all week.
Speaker 8:  Chipotle is starting drone
Speaker 8:  delivery.
Speaker 8:  This is an article in an, on a blog called Deli.
Speaker 8:  And they're okay. It's only in like Dallas I think right now,
Speaker 8:  but they're calling
Speaker 5:  Texas now Dallas.
Speaker 8:  I know.
Speaker 5:  Come on. Come on.
Speaker 8:  They're calling. Well, it's a partnership with a company called Zipline.
Speaker 8:  I don't know what that is. They have drones, but they're calling it
Speaker 8:  Chipotle.
Speaker 5:  No. Yeah, yeah. That I, that I'm, that I'm not on board with. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yes. But can you imagine like chips and guacamole
Speaker 8:  reigning down from heaven, just literally
Speaker 6:  It's, it's like cloudy with a chance of burritos. I love it.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yes. This, this increases my chance of ordering Chipotle like 10 x.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I absolutely,
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 8:  I just wanna, and like you could, could stick outside, could DoorDash it
Speaker 8:  or whatever, but like knowing that it would come from the sky
Speaker 8:  from a drone, like no, no other human would have to know
Speaker 8:  that I am ordering a burrito at whatever hour it
Speaker 5:  Is. I mean, on the other hand, all your neighbors can be like, Hey Allison,
Speaker 5:  I saw a small aircraft land in your yard. Yeah. Like what was that important?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I'd be like, oh, you know, UFOI, I don't know.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, you, you order just like in the
Speaker 8:  Chipotle app, it looks like,
Speaker 8:  oh, maybe you need a zip line app too. I dunno what this is.
Speaker 8:  Chipotle staff place your meal in a zipping point
Speaker 8:  and then a zip picks it up,
Speaker 8:  takes off and hovers around 300 feet and then
Speaker 8:  it lowers your Chipotle bag to your, I
Speaker 8:  don't know, front porch, backyard. It's a little gross thinking
Speaker 8:  about my food just kind of sitting in my yard. But
Speaker 6:  Listen, I'm just imagining Tim Robbins in
Speaker 6:  Shawshank Redemption, just, it's rainy. He doesn't feel like cooking.
Speaker 6:  And then he orders this Chipotle and he goes outside in the rain and goes
Speaker 6:  on his knees and goes Al Pastor Burrito.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And then it just like launches down
Speaker 6:  from the drone into his mouth. That's, that's my dream. Okay.
Speaker 5:  I legitimately though, this is my question. Can this thing operate when like,
Speaker 5:  you know, a little rain if, because it was raining if I'm hungry last night.
Speaker 5:  Last night it was storming. Yes. My fridge was empty And
Speaker 5:  I am like, I am gonna the grocery store and I'm like, I'm not, I'm not order
Speaker 5:  delivery. You can order delivery. These guys are on e-bikes. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  not the right time.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. That is tough.
Speaker 5:  If I can send a drone out that drove might crash, but
Speaker 5:  I would get a burrito if it, it didn't, you get a, which is a pretty good,
Speaker 5:  there is a Chipotle in like a two block radius of me.
Speaker 6:  It wouldn't have
Speaker 5:  To far could, a burrito
Speaker 6:  Could make it would not be that make
Speaker 8:  It, they could throw it, they could just throw it to your front stoop,
Speaker 5:  You know. Yeah. Yeah. That's a next step. But
Speaker 6:  You know, I think I get why they're doing it in Dallas and not New York City.
Speaker 6:  Could you imagine everyone who's hungry in New York City getting their
Speaker 6:  Chipotle burrito drone and just like, how do you deliver it to
Speaker 6:  an apartment? Is it the drone gonna like fly outside your fire, fire, escape,
Speaker 6:  and then
Speaker 5:  Throw Okay that
Speaker 8:  You open the door, the window and you grab it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like that. Could you just imagine that, that
Speaker 8:  That would be perfect.
Speaker 6:  That would, that would be something just like an army of,
Speaker 6:  an army of drones with Chipotle
Speaker 6:  burritos in New York City. Just descending like a swarm of burrito bees.
Speaker 6:  If
Speaker 5:  Food delivery can go right into my window,
Speaker 5:  I mean that's, that's the epitome of laziness. I, it's all over
Speaker 5:  it. Can't get better than that.
Speaker 6:  I'm here. Screw through a eye. Why are we not inventing this?
Speaker 5:  We need to focus on the important technologies.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Drone burritos. There
Speaker 8:  Is, so there is a limitation.
Speaker 8:  It can carry orders up to 5.5 pounds.
Speaker 5:  That's like a burrito. Yeah. Like that's not right.
Speaker 8:  It's like a
Speaker 6:  Chipotle burrito.
Speaker 5:  Those are hefty burritos. Yeah. Yeah. They, okay.
Speaker 5:  That is not going far.
Speaker 8:  I've seen my husband order at Chipotle and that is weighing
Speaker 8:  at least five pounds. It's a lot.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He gets all this stuff. Okay. They should have started with a different
Speaker 5:  restaurant. Chipotle was not the place for it.
Speaker 8:  It's a little too heavy. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that's it for The Vergecast. Stay tuned. Alison is hosting on Tuesday.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be a really good show. She's talking about cameras.
Speaker 5:  Cameras, is that right? Cameras and phones. I more cameras. I love cameras.
Speaker 5:  I love cameras and phone. If you like what we do here, the best way to support
Speaker 5:  us is to get a subscription to The Verge at The Verge dot com. It's a very
Speaker 5:  good website. We all work there. But we'd love to hear your questions and
Speaker 5:  feedback. Let us know what you want us to talk about. Email us vergecast
Speaker 5:  at VERGE dot com or give us a call. 8 6 6 VERGE 11
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and Box Media Podcast network.
Speaker 5:  Our show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Ke, Travis Lar Chuck and Andrew
Speaker 5:  Marino. We'll see you next week.