# Transcript
ID: ea6ddfbb-193b-4ce3-aff2-b81a17d42ff3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2721834373325362072/9067088996932765627/s93290-US-6452s-1742177608.mp3
Description: Big tech companies are forever making promises about the future. And you might (or might not) be surprised how often they don't come true. On this episode, Nilay and David start by discussing the good and bad of Apple's new iPads and Macs, before diving into the supposedly AI-powered, all-powerful Siri that is delayed indefinitely. Maybe this whole "AI will fix everything" plan wasn't such a good one. After that, The Verge's Andy Hawkins joins to discuss what's going on with Tesla: why sales are down, how the perception of the company has shifted as Elon Musk's job description has changed, and how it happened that President Trump did a Tesla sales pitch on the White House lawn. Everything's computer, you know? Finally, in the lighting round, the hosts discuss Brendan Carr's ongoing shenanigans, Jay Graber's sartorial burns, the future of Pokemon Go, and much more.
Speaker 5:  Hello everyone with Vergecast. The flagship podcast is being forced to buy
Speaker 5:  a Tesla by the United States government. Which Tesla will the
Speaker 5:  government force you to buy The triangle or the round one?
Speaker 6:  Can I get a roadster out of this? Like, do you feel like if I play my cards
Speaker 6:  right, I can at least get a Roadster?
Speaker 5:  The Roadster is more vaporware than full self-driving. I just wanna be a
Speaker 5:  hundred percent clear about this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I agree with that.
Speaker 5:  All the Teslas in the world will drive themselves before the next Roadster
Speaker 5:  comes out. Even the ones that don't have the hardware to support full
Speaker 5:  self-driving, they will get the ability to drive themselves before the next
Speaker 5:  Roadster comes
Speaker 6:  Out. I agree with that. They don't even talk about the Roadster anymore.
Speaker 5:  No. They put one in space and they're like, well, we're good with that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Why? It's the the literal final
Speaker 6:  frontier of the roaster as we have gone to space with,
Speaker 5:  Have you seen this unreliable triangle? Let's do it. I
Speaker 5:  just wanna alert everyone to the fact that just before we started the show,
Speaker 5:  David said that he had too many Tads open on his computer and his computer
Speaker 5:  was freaking out. And David, I want to remind you, you are the
Speaker 5:  world's foremost proponent of only having eight gigs of RAM on your Mac.
Speaker 6:  I will just say 16 is better.
Speaker 6:  This is my, my great take from the last couple of
Speaker 6:  years of, of my life and gadget reviews. I now have
Speaker 6:  16 gigs of RAM on this M four Mac mini that I bought last
Speaker 6:  fall. It's better. Yeah. That's, that's, that's the takeaway.
Speaker 6:  I still think eight is basically fine. Mostly because most people are not
Speaker 6:  tab monsters the way that I'm a tab monster. But If you can
Speaker 6:  get 16, it's life is good here.
Speaker 5:  I disagree. I think most people are tab monsters. Yeah. I think most Macs
Speaker 5:  are used as Chromebooks.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I totally agree with that. I think most computers are, are just
Speaker 6:  browsers now, which is like, makes it all the funnier that Google has
Speaker 6:  sort of botched the Chromebook thing so badly because like the thesis was
Speaker 6:  exactly correct, which is that most people just wanna do web stuff on their
Speaker 6:  computer all day. And yet Chromebooks are awful at that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What if we made this cheaper and it still didn't have enough rent?
Speaker 5:  My, my advice for everybody is that it, it kind of, your CPU and your GPU
Speaker 5:  don't matter unless you they matter to you. Well, you know, If you are the
Speaker 5:  sort of person for whom those things matter, you've already self-identified
Speaker 5:  and be free. Yeah. Run with the alphas, go nuts.
Speaker 5:  But for most people, the number you should care about is ram.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I totally agree. I think it goes RAM storage,
Speaker 6:  C-P-U-G-P-U, everything else. Yeah. It's like how I would stack
Speaker 6:  rank that for most people
Speaker 5:  It's, there's a, a number of people who think GPU should be hired on CPU
Speaker 5:  me, but that's like a new phenomenon. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I think that's, that's a reasonable case to be made depending on what
Speaker 6:  you do on your computer. But in terms of like what makes your computer
Speaker 6:  feel smooth and fast and good so that you don't like, think about your
Speaker 6:  computer a lot. That's, that's still how I would rank them.
Speaker 5:  And you and you're still in that ranking. Going with eight gigs is enough.
Speaker 6:  Listen, I, I have an M four mini that I sit here and use every day. And I
Speaker 6:  have an M1 air that is my travel computer.
Speaker 6:  Eight gigs of RAM works just fine
Speaker 6:  as long as I don't make it do anything complicated.
Speaker 5:  Well, I still have a tab open with the M four max, max Studio
Speaker 5:  2199.
Speaker 5:  You know, I'm just thinking about it every, as, as many Americans know, I've
Speaker 5:  been thinking about buying a new computer.
Speaker 6:  We have one. People are excited about it.
Speaker 5:  They are. We and we should talk about that. We have reviews of all the new
Speaker 5:  Mac stuff, the M four MacBook Air, sort of a half review
Speaker 5:  of the M three Ultra Mac studio, which is really
Speaker 5:  interesting. Some of the Ben early benchmarks are interesting. We should
Speaker 5:  talk about that at length. And Chris is gonna keep reviewing that stuff.
Speaker 5:  He's got a bunch of ideas about AI reviews there, which is interesting. And
Speaker 5:  then David, you reviewed the new iPad here. I did as punishment. I,
Speaker 6:  I really, one day I just want Apple to just sneak
Speaker 6:  something weird into an iPad just to see if people notice anymore.
Speaker 5:  So we should talk about all that. Apple's delaying the new Siri. David, you
Speaker 5:  wrote a piece about just AI and gadgets in general that I want to talk about.
Speaker 5:  We, we've seem to have gotten way out over our skis in the tech industry
Speaker 5:  with ai. Andy Hawkins gonna join us. We're gonna talk about Tesla.
Speaker 5:  Andy's gonna show up with a government issued Tesla. Then we got a
Speaker 5:  lightning round. Brendan Carr won't shut, he won't shut up.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say an F on there. That's illegal now in
Speaker 5:  Brendan's America. And we got some other, I guess talk about that later round.
Speaker 5:  It's a, it's a show. We got a whole, we got a whole Vergecast in front of
Speaker 5:  us. What's, do you wanna start quickly with reviews and then talk about Siri?
Speaker 5:  Sure.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think we can do this quickly because this is sort of
Speaker 6:  a fascinating case of Apple doing just precisely exactly what
Speaker 6:  you would think Apple would do. And I think in one case
Speaker 6:  with the M four MacBook Air, that is terrific news,
Speaker 6:  right? Like Antonio de Beto on our team reviewed it and basically it's like
Speaker 6:  this is the computer that you would hope it would be battery
Speaker 6:  lasts a really long time. Performance is good. It, it throttles when it
Speaker 6:  gets hot when you tax it too much because that's what MacBook airs do. But
Speaker 6:  most people who buy an air aren't doing that kind of stuff anyway.
Speaker 6:  The sky blue is like whatever. Even in Antonio's photos, it's often hard
Speaker 6:  to tell whether it's sky blue or silver, depending on the light. It's just
Speaker 6:  a computer. But it is like this thing is now a hundred dollars cheaper
Speaker 6:  and it's great. And that is like fabulous news, right? And there are like
Speaker 6:  little bits that you can quibble with about the screen quality and whatever,
Speaker 6:  but like it isn't awesome computer for a hundred dollars less than it was
Speaker 6:  before. And that's awesome. And then on the iPad I come out of this, I'm
Speaker 6:  like, oh, it's it sure.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Like this is like an the most iterative upgrade in
Speaker 6:  a long run of incredibly iterative upgrades on the iPad. And like is it
Speaker 6:  still good? Yes. But If you bought an
Speaker 6:  iPad like since
Speaker 6:  Covid, you don't need this iPad.
Speaker 5:  We actually got a bunch of really interesting feedback to the last episode
Speaker 5:  where we talked about how long iPadOS last and a number of people
Speaker 5:  said that they overbuy the iPad because they want it to last
Speaker 5:  a decade. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which I would say tracks generally with my overarching gadget advice, which
Speaker 6:  is I think everybody should buy the best thing they can afford,
Speaker 6:  even if it's more than they need. And then keep it as long as humanly possible.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I think that's a perfectly rational way to handle an iPad. And If
Speaker 6:  you do that, you can probably squeeze a decade out of
Speaker 6:  an iPad without trying too too hard. Yeah. In many cases, like the thing
Speaker 6:  that goes away is you start to lose app support because like one by
Speaker 6:  one streaming apps will stop supporting it and you'll just sort of
Speaker 6:  piece by piece lose your iPad's ability to do stuff.
Speaker 6:  But like If you just dig out a 2015
Speaker 6:  iPad right now, it will still do the basic things that it does
Speaker 6:  pretty successfully. Which is awesome 10 years ago.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well it's, it's the ba it's you gotta overbuy, right? So we had people
Speaker 5:  who are like, I'm, I'm buying an iPad Pro in the hopes that it'll last a
Speaker 5:  decade. I think you buy the base model, it's a reasonable assumption that
Speaker 5:  that thing will have a shorter life than If you buy a pro model
Speaker 5:  or an air or something. Here it, it's the iPad Air, right,
Speaker 5:  that we're talking about upgraded has the M three. I would guess that this
Speaker 5:  thing will last you maybe not a decade, but seven years, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think that's reasonable
Speaker 5:  That that feels right. And the only thing that might change that is if
Speaker 5:  there's some sort of paradigm shift in how much
Speaker 5:  compute you need to do something. Right? I'm not sure
Speaker 5:  what that is. Apple hasn't come up with it in a long time. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  Like iPad apps have not gotten more complicated. That whole application model
Speaker 5:  has not allowed more complicated apps
Speaker 5:  really to exist. I mean there are some, I I don't wanna, I don't wanna underplay
Speaker 5:  it. There are some very intense iPad apps, but it's not,
Speaker 5:  it's not the ecosystem.
Speaker 6:  No. And there's really nothing. It was actually really funny testing the
Speaker 6:  M three because there are so few apps out there that are
Speaker 6:  willing to push the boundaries of the thing specifically because
Speaker 6:  lots of people own iPadOS, lots of people own older iPadOS. So actually if
Speaker 6:  you're a developer, you shouldn't really target
Speaker 6:  like the bleeding edge new technology. So there are a few that do because
Speaker 6:  they have to, because they're trying to do really complicated like 3D image
Speaker 6:  rendering stuff in real time. That is just hard. And you can like feel it
Speaker 6:  because the iPad gets warm as it's working. But for the most part,
Speaker 6:  like even some of the most intense intensive
Speaker 6:  games I'm using at max settings, you can tell they made
Speaker 6:  this and they tested it on like an iPad mini. And so
Speaker 6:  it's like if you're gonna make something that works across this whole lineup,
Speaker 6:  you just can't target the really intense stuff, which is good news because
Speaker 6:  by the, you know, by the end of a seven year lifespan of one of these things,
Speaker 6:  it will be down at the bottom of that spectrum. But it'll still be supported.
Speaker 6:  But for right now it's, it's even the M three is
Speaker 6:  overkill for most things. Yeah. And that's next to the M four, which
Speaker 6:  is now almost a year old and is still overkill for almost everything.
Speaker 5:  I wanna issue a very specific feature request, bug
Speaker 5:  report
Speaker 5:  accusation of pure hypocrisy, whatever it is. However you wanna, the
Speaker 5:  game Dream Light Valley, which I don't think your child is old enough to
Speaker 5:  play, but which is a very big game for 6-year-old girls.
Speaker 5:  They say it works and thus
Speaker 6:  You,
Speaker 5:  It's my whole life. It's a popular game. It's
Speaker 5:  supposed to work on bass model iPad and it does not, you know, it does work
Speaker 5:  on my phone.
Speaker 6:  Oh, you're screwed. That sucks.
Speaker 5:  Lemme tell you how plane rides with my child have gone recently.
Speaker 5:  She is playing Dream Wide Valley on my phone and I am using YouTube
Speaker 5:  kids on her app
Speaker 5:  just watching whatever weird stuff we've downloaded in the background.
Speaker 5:  It's great and I love it. And if the whole point of Apple having total
Speaker 5:  control over that store is making sure that the
Speaker 5:  listings are accurate and this listing says it works on the baseball
Speaker 5:  iPad and it absolutely doesn't. And you can find very confused parents
Speaker 5:  on forum across the internet saying, why did you lie to me?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's a lot of that going around right now. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, listeners out there at Apple or Disney, two of America's most
Speaker 5:  important corporations, just help me out guys,
Speaker 6:  Just fix this one thing.
Speaker 5:  Just make it run on the base model iPad or, or change the listing so
Speaker 5:  other people don't end up like me on a plane watching YouTube kids
Speaker 5:  on a base model iPad and a Rainbow case.
Speaker 6:  I mean the Wiggles are doing stuff, it's fine. They're, they're around.
Speaker 5:  Let's talk about the studio. The studio's really interesting. Like I said,
Speaker 5:  I'm just goading myself into paying 2200 a computer on the theory
Speaker 5:  that the marginal cost, which at this in this case is like
Speaker 5:  a thousand dollars more than I would spend on a Mac Mini will make that
Speaker 5:  computer last five more years. That's what I'm convincing myself of
Speaker 5:  because I do keep my Macs for a very long time once I get 'em set up. I don't
Speaker 5:  like to monkey with them. Yeah. It's very hard to perceive the difference
Speaker 5:  year to year with Mac, as we can tell from MacBook Air. But what's really
Speaker 5:  interesting is Chris Welch has the M three Ultra, which is the top config,
Speaker 5:  the M three Ultra means it just has a lot of GPUs. It's basically four M
Speaker 5:  threes all put together using their interweaving technology to make the
Speaker 5:  chips work as one Ultra fusion I think it's called. And it's really interesting
Speaker 5:  because the single core performance of the M four max is higher than the
Speaker 5:  single core performance of the M three Ultra. But If you need all the GPUs
Speaker 5:  or the multi-core performance, obviously the M three Ultra is gonna gonna
Speaker 5:  do it for you. And that, that's fairly unusual for
Speaker 5:  an Apple product line.
Speaker 6:  I, I'm sort of torn on it because on the one hand, the people who are specking
Speaker 6:  this thing out at that level are going to know which one
Speaker 6:  they need more, right? Like if, if I'm doing a lot
Speaker 6:  of graphical heavy image rendering or like
Speaker 6:  one of the examples Chris Walch used is, is crushing huge
Speaker 6:  data sets of medical information. Like whatever, that's the kind of stuff
Speaker 6:  you're like, okay, I need the GPU cores and the sort of single thread CPU
Speaker 6:  cores are less important, but he makes the point in his piece and I think
Speaker 6:  he's right. That minute to minute fastness
Speaker 6:  of your computer actually depends a lot on the single
Speaker 6:  core performance of your CPU except this stuff
Speaker 6:  is so beyond what most, what any of that will
Speaker 6:  require anyway, that it does feel like this is an interesting benchmark.
Speaker 6:  But I suspect even If you were to flip the results, most people would not
Speaker 6:  perceive any difference at all. But it is, I think I I I made a joke
Speaker 6:  last week about Apple sort of muddying understanding of this
Speaker 6:  by making the M three Ultra more powerful than the M four max. And I
Speaker 6:  got a bunch of people who are like, well the last generation pro models are
Speaker 6:  more powerful than the current generation regular models. I'm like, sure,
Speaker 6:  whatever. This is confusing. Like there, there is a, this, this
Speaker 6:  is not a simple thing that you can just ladder up in the buttons
Speaker 6:  of apple's buy process and figure it out that way.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, it is, it's an interesting quirk of how Apple puts these things
Speaker 6:  together that this is the case, that what they seem to be able to ramp is
Speaker 6:  GPU more easily and sort of linearly with more
Speaker 6:  chips than C, which is kind of fascinating
Speaker 5:  Because they are just fusing them together. Well,
Speaker 6:  Right. It
Speaker 5:  Still, I mean, and that's, I'm not saying that's easy, that's very
Speaker 5:  hard and they haven't yet been able to really do it with the force. Right.
Speaker 5:  But it is the case that what they're, they're doing is they're creating one
Speaker 5:  giant virtual C-P-U-G-P-U monster out of
Speaker 5:  individual ones, which is a lot. I mean that's a lot of how the ship
Speaker 5:  industry has developed over time. But it makes sense that the big
Speaker 5:  multi-core parallel processing workloads would benefit from that approach,
Speaker 5:  whereas it just doesn't seem like they're, they're motivated to do it on
Speaker 5:  the M four side yet, or, or they figured it out.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It also just strikes me as a slightly harder problem, right? Like if
Speaker 6:  to take, to take one thing that is designed to work in
Speaker 6:  parallel and shove more parallel at it is just
Speaker 6:  an easier math problem to solve than like how do you make the thing spin
Speaker 6:  faster? Right? Which is not what it's doing, but is like still the metaphor
Speaker 6:  in my head of how A CPU actually works. It just spins around really fast.
Speaker 5:  There's a hamster in there just running, just running
Speaker 6:  Inside. Yeah. It
Speaker 5:  Just spins around. It just juiced the hamster man. Just pour some prime on
Speaker 5:  it and see what happens.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Chris Welch tested a, what was it, a $9,000 eight
Speaker 6:  $8,000 studio. Did it make you want a studio more?
Speaker 5:  It made me very confident that the M four max
Speaker 5:  base configuration with only one upgrade, which is to get a
Speaker 5:  terabyte of storage, is almost a perfect price
Speaker 5:  performance computer. I see that. That's 2200. I am not saying it's cheap.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's a very expensive computer. Especially 'cause the base M
Speaker 5:  four mini is like $600, right? Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  it's a huge jump. But am I convinced that that computer will sit at my desk
Speaker 5:  for a decade and I won't be mad about it for a very long time? Yeah. I'm
Speaker 5:  pretty convinced of that. Yep. And it has a faster SD card slot, which matters
Speaker 5:  to me. It has Thunderbolt five ports, which I don't think the mini
Speaker 5:  has. Like there's just a bunch of like future proofy stuff
Speaker 5:  that I, you know, is it worth that much more money? Maybe not.
Speaker 5:  But if I end up buying a new computer every four years instead of
Speaker 5:  every 10, like maybe that adds up. Yeah, it probably doesn't. It probably
Speaker 5:  still doesn't. But you know, there's inflation in tariffs, the prices go
Speaker 5:  up, you gotta get in there while you can.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. How many Mac mini, like how quickly would you have to rev your Mac
Speaker 6:  mini before it hits the price? I guess it's like four
Speaker 6:  Mac minis If you just keep buying base Mac Minis.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But to buy, you have to assume that Apple is going to, someone should
Speaker 5:  help us. Someone make a model, someone make like an Excel model of this.
Speaker 5:  Of what, 'cause you I'm never gonna buy the base model Mac
Speaker 6:  Mini. That's true.
Speaker 5:  Right? I'm, I'm gonna add to the Ram, I'm, I'm probably gonna add to
Speaker 5:  the storage. I want the 10 gigabit nick.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So you're buying at least the a thousand dollars Mac mini. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then you're like, well I'm just gonna buy, yeah. I wanna buy a 22 Mac
Speaker 5:  studio to run email. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  Occasionally turn the D Haze slider up in Lightroom and we'll call it a day.
Speaker 6:  That's the stuff right there.
Speaker 5:  I will say the only AI workload I, I regularly do is the new
Speaker 5:  AI powered de-noise and Lightroom. Hmm. And it is magic and it is
Speaker 5:  very slow on my current Intel powered iMac. And so even just
Speaker 5:  speeding it up is like worth it. Yeah. Do I need this computer to speed it
Speaker 5:  up? I do not, but do I do I think I can make the argument to myself.
Speaker 5:  Let's, let's wait a couple more weeks and find out. The most interesting
Speaker 5:  thing about the M three Ultra Max Studio is that it is powerful enough
Speaker 5:  If you spec it with enough RAM to run an AI model, like deep seek R
Speaker 5:  one locally, which we have noting really seen from other consumer
Speaker 5:  computers that you have to, you can run some of these models locally, but
Speaker 5:  you need to build a giant power hungry
Speaker 5:  desktop PC with a giant power hungry card. And then to scale it, you need
Speaker 5:  to network the cards together and you kind of just get very expensive, very
Speaker 6:  Fast. Yeah. There was a bunch of stuff on Hacker News a couple of weeks ago
Speaker 6:  about people sharing their, like somewhere between
Speaker 6:  3030 $500 builds
Speaker 6:  to run deep seek locally. And even that was like very exciting that they
Speaker 6:  had figured out a way to do it relatively easily. The idea that this is just
Speaker 6:  an off the shelf thing that can do it is a pretty big deal. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And, and like Nvidia just launched a whole line of computers designed to
Speaker 6:  do this kind of stuff and I'm, I'm, I suspect that will be more powerful
Speaker 6:  for some of this stuff because it's designed for this stuff. But like
Speaker 6:  this is the kind of thing that Apple is doing in the AI world that I actually
Speaker 6:  think is interesting.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But they're not doing it.
Speaker 6:  Unlike everything else Apple is doing the
Speaker 5:  AI world. They've just, they've just gotten themselves a computer with enough
Speaker 5:  memory and enough processing cores to run a Chinese model
Speaker 5:  that might be banned by the Trump administration locally.
Speaker 6:  Love it.
Speaker 5:  Perfect. So Apple's lead and ships have gotten to to point their lead in
Speaker 5:  software AI development, Pok potentially sending them even farther back.
Speaker 5:  So Chris is gonna finish reviewing the, the Mac studio.
Speaker 5:  I will just con continue looking at this shopping cart with a 22 hour Mac
Speaker 5:  studio in it for weeks. We'll keep covering that. There's not much to say
Speaker 5:  about the macro care. You can just go look at the benchmarks and see If you
Speaker 5:  wanna buy, like the only thing we're saying is jump by the base model, spend
Speaker 5:  a little bit more money. Yeah. Like we're saying buy more RAM and more storage.
Speaker 5:  It'll be fine. But the big news out of Apple
Speaker 5:  is they officially announced in a name statement to John
Speaker 5:  Gruber that they're gonna delay Siri or the AI
Speaker 5:  powered Siri. That is the thing that everyone wants. And David, you have
Speaker 5:  like a lot of thoughts about this.
Speaker 6:  I do have a lot of thoughts about this. I think Apple
Speaker 6:  deserves a lot more shit for this than they're getting to be completely honest.
Speaker 6:  So let me, let me just read you the whole quote. This is John Gruber got
Speaker 6:  this I think over the weekend. Oh, can
Speaker 5:  I just say this, by the way, John's a friend. People know we go in each other's
Speaker 5:  shows, we've talked for years, we've known each other forever. Initially
Speaker 5:  he was like, why are you doing this background policy where you insist on
Speaker 5:  naming all the spokespeople? And he has totally come around recently. So
Speaker 5:  he has a statement from Apple, it's named, which I'd just say little victory,
Speaker 5:  little victory for journalism here. Anyway, carry
Speaker 6:  On. So this is from Jacqueline Roy at Apple who we all
Speaker 6:  know. And she says, Siri helps our users find what they need and get things
Speaker 6:  done quickly. And in just the past six months, we've made made Siri more
Speaker 6:  conversational, introduce new features like type two Siri and product knowledge
Speaker 6:  and added an integration with chat GPT. We've also been working on a more
Speaker 6:  personalized Siri, giving it more awareness of your personal context as well
Speaker 6:  as the ability to take action for you within and across your apps. It's going
Speaker 6:  to take us longer than we thought to deliver on these features. And we anticipate
Speaker 6:  rolling them out in the coming year. That is essentially Apple saying,
Speaker 6:  we've been lying to you since last May. Yep. Like that just is what it is.
Speaker 6:  Like the, this is the, the flagship feature of the
Speaker 6:  iPhone 16 was Apple intelligence and the flagship feature of Apple
Speaker 6:  Intelligence was this new series we've been saying all along that there's
Speaker 6:  a bunch of like window dressing and stuff going on. There's Jen Moji, there's
Speaker 6:  like the writing tools, there's the terrible notification summaries, but
Speaker 6:  like the thing, the thing that everybody thinks of when they think about
Speaker 6:  AI period and Apple Intelligence specifically, is this better, sir,
Speaker 6:  the Siri that can use your apps for you, the Siri that knows more about you,
Speaker 6:  this like multimodal Siri that can search the world and understand about
Speaker 6:  you. And Apple is basically like, oh, nevermind, we didn't do that.
Speaker 6:  Buy our phones next year. Maybe I'll get it then. Like, this sucks. And this,
Speaker 6:  and like Apple, apple pulled an ad from its YouTube channel that it
Speaker 6:  had with Bella Ramsey that was showing a feature on an iPhone 16 that
Speaker 6:  doesn't exist. Like I don't, I don't know how to be clearer about that. Like
Speaker 6:  that phone could not do that thing in that ad. And
Speaker 6:  it is like, it is wild to me.
Speaker 5:  By the way. It was, she asks it, who did I have like coffee or lunch
Speaker 5:  with at this restaurant?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. She's at a party and somebody waves to her and she's like, oh, it's
Speaker 6:  that. And she like goes around the corner and she's like, who did I have
Speaker 6:  coffee with a couple of weeks ago at whatever place? And it gives her the
Speaker 6:  name and then she goes around and says hi to the person. You know what can't
Speaker 6:  do that is Siri. And so, and this is just like this, it's
Speaker 6:  so indicative of everything that is happening right now in all of
Speaker 6:  the Apple universe, but really the gadget universe in general, like
Speaker 6:  everyone made this bet that AI was going to just magically make
Speaker 6:  your whole technological life better. And that all they had to do
Speaker 6:  was give you a thing with a chip that was powerful enough to do a the
Speaker 6:  AI stuff. And then the AI stuff would sell the gadgets. And
Speaker 6:  we are so, so, so very far away from that world existing. And
Speaker 6:  I, I mean, if I were a betting man, I don't think the coming year is even
Speaker 6:  gonna come true for Apple here. We anticipate rolling them out in the coming
Speaker 6:  year is not a thing Apple says on the record, really ever Apple,
Speaker 6:  like generally refuses to acknowledge that it's making
Speaker 6:  products in the future. Like,
Speaker 5:  Well, they've already announced this one. They can't say it's in delayed
Speaker 6:  Indefinitely. That is true. We
Speaker 5:  Anticipate rolling this out in the coming year is about as indefinite
Speaker 6:  As it gets. Right. But also the, the mere existence of this
Speaker 6:  statement to anyone is a thing Apple
Speaker 6:  traditionally doesn't do. And this is like for, for Apple to
Speaker 6:  acknowledge that it is having problems and is delaying
Speaker 6:  something, is a big deal and is indicative of something going deeply,
Speaker 6:  deeply wrong. Yeah. With Siri. So
Speaker 5:  I agree with you that they, we should be more critical of this. And don't
Speaker 5:  worry, we, we will be, I I'll just point out the timing does make a little
Speaker 5:  bit of sense because it's March WWC comes
Speaker 5:  up in June, they gotta get the invites out. They gotta prep everybody. They
Speaker 5:  gotta figure out whatever they're gonna announce. And if what they don't
Speaker 5:  deliver is any set of hooks
Speaker 5:  for developers to participate in the new series, they're called App intents.
Speaker 5:  If this stuff isn't ready, they need to be well clear of it by
Speaker 5:  wwc. So you, you throw this out in March, you can spin up whatever's
Speaker 5:  gonna happen in June. Sure.
Speaker 6:  But think ahead to ww DC one of two things is gonna happen. Either
Speaker 6:  Apple is going to essentially pretend that none of this exists because
Speaker 6:  it doesn't, which is weird because they launched it all a year ago.
Speaker 6:  Or Apple is going to relaunch the same thing it launched a year ago.
Speaker 5:  That's what they're gonna do.
Speaker 6:  That's so weird.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be but ever so slightly more real. Right? Like last year they
Speaker 5:  were showing concept videos, which Apple never does this year. They're gonna
Speaker 5:  be like, we've worked with, there are Shazam which
Speaker 5:  they own, or like
Speaker 6:  Open DoorDash.
Speaker 5:  It's always DoorDash, it's always poor DoorDash. The most commoditized company
Speaker 5:  in history is gonna be DoorDash. Right. We've worked with Uber
Speaker 5:  and we've done all this stuff the same as Amazon just did. And actually the,
Speaker 5:  the comparison that should make Apple feel bad is the
Speaker 5:  comparison to Amazon. Yeah. Which had exactly the same problem and
Speaker 5:  exactly the same perception in the market of its voice assistant. It's four
Speaker 5:  timers in music and then they hired Panos Fane. They've
Speaker 5:  had their own share of problems along the way that's been well reported.
Speaker 5:  But, you know, Panos launched the product, he showed it to
Speaker 5:  people, Jen Tui talked to it, it's gonna That's true. Arrive in some way,
Speaker 5:  shape or form. And they've talked about what they needed to do to build it,
Speaker 5:  which is create this big orchestration layer where
Speaker 5:  you talk to Alexa with natural language and it figures out what to do and
Speaker 5:  then it can do, it will see to some level of execution.
Speaker 5:  Apple doesn't appear to have built any of that yet. Or if they have,
Speaker 5:  they just took a hard look at it and said, this isn't ready. We're delaying
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 6:  Right. Well, and I mean, you look at the first half of
Speaker 6:  the statement and it's, it's like in just the past six months we've made
Speaker 6:  Siri more conversational, introduced new features like type two sir and product
Speaker 6:  knowledge and added an integration to chat GT Do you know anyone who thinks
Speaker 6:  Siri is better today than it was six months
Speaker 5:  Ago? No. Siri is substantially worse
Speaker 6:  Before. I totally agree. I honestly believe it has, it has gone significantly
Speaker 6:  backwards in both its ability to even understand you,
Speaker 6:  but also like to do useful things.
Speaker 6:  It it punts to chat GPT for things that don't make any sense. Yeah. And like,
Speaker 6:  and it's, it's a, that integration is kind of flaky in my experience. Like
Speaker 6:  it just, the whole thing sucks. And so to the extent that we're seeing this,
Speaker 6:  it's bad, which makes it not surprising that it might even be worse than
Speaker 6:  we know. So,
Speaker 5:  You know, it's really interesting is to just think about this on, on the
Speaker 5:  long arc, right? Siri launched when we
Speaker 5:  started The Verge. A weird thing Oh yeah. To think about. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  iPhone four s with Siri came out in 2011. That's when we were sitting around
Speaker 5:  our first office in, in Union Square
Speaker 5:  basically in Manhattan. It was tiny. The bathrooms were right next
Speaker 5:  to the office. It wasn't great. And I remember sitting in that conference
Speaker 5:  room, the first Siri launch, and we were like covering as fast as we could.
Speaker 5:  And If you were, remember how that series solved problems?
Speaker 5:  They had done the voice assistant so that you could talk to it.
Speaker 5:  And then they had actually built like what amounts to a very primitive
Speaker 5:  orchestration layer. So sometimes Siri is gonna do the math locally. Sometimes
Speaker 5:  it's gonna kick out to Wolf from Alpha. Right. Do you remember how often
Speaker 5:  Siri to kick to Wolf and Alpha? Oh yeah. And sometimes it would kick to other
Speaker 5:  services and they had built this like, you know, If you just like sort of
Speaker 5:  look at it abstractly, they had built primitive versions
Speaker 5:  of all the things that they need now. Like, we're gonna accept the
Speaker 5:  input, we're gonna figure out what to do with it. We're gonna go out to another
Speaker 5:  service and we're gonna come back to you with some kind of answer or response
Speaker 5:  or something. And it, it worked, it didn't work as well as it
Speaker 5:  should, but kind of the promise was they would add more and more services
Speaker 5:  on the backend and that orchestration layer would get smarter and smarter
Speaker 5:  and then voice recognition would improve and all that would just sort of
Speaker 5:  get better over time. And instead what Apple did was they kind of just like
Speaker 5:  let it go. Like I don't know why they just let it go, but they just
Speaker 5:  let it go. This is also basically what happened with Alexa. Here's
Speaker 5:  this voice assistant, we're gonna build all these skills. You're gonna talk
Speaker 5:  to it. The skills are gonna fire or you're gonna learn how to talk to the
Speaker 5:  skills and they just let it go. Like it just didn't happen for them.
Speaker 5:  I think what everyone got confused about was one part of that
Speaker 5:  equation got so much better. Right. AI and LLMs made the
Speaker 5:  natural language input so much better. Yes. That everyone else
Speaker 5:  assumed that all the other parts were had also gotten better. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And then they didn't like, they just didn't like
Speaker 5:  the LLMs hallucinate. They get things wrong. They, they go haywire.
Speaker 5:  So you have this system where the input has
Speaker 5:  substantially changed and everyone sees a paradigm shift. That's what all
Speaker 5:  the CEOs have told man cutter. It's a paradigm shift. 'cause the input has
Speaker 5:  changed. And the history of computing is these big inputs that change
Speaker 5:  or input methodologies that change. And then computers change. We eat mice
Speaker 5:  and keyboards, scroll wheels. Everyone knows the Digital Crown was a
Speaker 5:  revolutionary computer on the Apple Watch. That's why they announced the
Speaker 5:  Digital Crown the way they did with the Apple watch. Yeah. Apple knows that
Speaker 5:  changing the input changes the nature of your relationship to computers.
Speaker 5:  So they fake it even when they don't have it, they, they make sure to mention
Speaker 5:  it. Yep. Multi-touch. Obviously everyone thinks
Speaker 5:  it's voice now. 'cause LMS can do voice at this level, but underneath that
Speaker 5:  is nothing. Right. And so they haven't built this layer where you can
Speaker 5:  actually, where where it's good at going to order the Uber, they have to
Speaker 5:  do a bunch of business deals basically. Or they have to build an agent
Speaker 5:  or in the case of Rabbit fake having an agent until they actually build an
Speaker 5:  agent. Yeah. And click around on a website. And I don't think, I, I wonder
Speaker 5:  if the problem for Apple is as much the building, the
Speaker 5:  orchestrator or the API hooks or whatever as it is getting
Speaker 5:  all of the app developers to participate in a way that makes everybody money.
Speaker 6:  I think Apple's theory was that
Speaker 6:  developers would solve this for them. Right. That by virtue
Speaker 6:  of Apple being Apple. And we talked about this when, when
Speaker 6:  Fancy Siri first came out, when Apple Intelligence was first launched at
Speaker 6:  wwdc was like, if if there's any company on earth
Speaker 6:  that can marshal enough of its developers to play this particular
Speaker 6:  game, it's Apple. Right? And so I actually, I actually think it is, it is
Speaker 6:  yet again, more damning the fact that Apple has not been able to pull this
Speaker 6:  off because Apple is able to point at its developers and
Speaker 6:  say, Hey, we put this weird thing on the home screen, you have to support
Speaker 6:  it. And they do. That is what Apple has done forever. And it keeps working
Speaker 6:  like the dynamic Island exists because Apple is like, look, here's a,
Speaker 6:  here's a round thing. You figure out what to do with it and people do.
Speaker 6:  And so Apple's big idea was I think was that
Speaker 6:  this would solve itself because they would give people app intense and
Speaker 6:  and they would plug in and everything would be fine. That again,
Speaker 6:  misses that orchestration middle that you're talking about. That is actually
Speaker 6:  very complicated. But I think also, this is
Speaker 6:  just anecdotal having talked to developers, but I've talked to a lot of developers
Speaker 6:  who don't understand and are not excited about the idea of
Speaker 6:  Siri just abstracting their app away. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean I keep calling this the DoorDash problem. And you can actually understand
Speaker 5:  by thinking about why these companies support the dynamic island and why
Speaker 5:  they're not excited to support a sir that makes their app
Speaker 5:  disappear. So let, let's say you're the CEO of, of Uber, David, Mr.
Speaker 5:  Steve Uber please.
Speaker 6:  He, my father.
Speaker 5:  It's obvious why you would support the dynamic island. 'cause somebody uses
Speaker 5:  your app and then they close it and then the operating system
Speaker 5:  is like, remember that app?
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's
Speaker 6:  The logo sits there.
Speaker 5:  The logo sits there. Yeah. And there's a constant status
Speaker 5:  con communicated about your app. And then the only thing that a user can
Speaker 5:  do with that is open your app again. So there's a perfect
Speaker 5:  feedback loop, a perfect incentive match between Yep. I want to communicate
Speaker 5:  constant status and when the user wants to do anything, they can just bop
Speaker 5:  back into my app and I can show them another ad or upsell them on Uber Eats
Speaker 5:  or whatever it is I wanna do. Great. I I wish
Speaker 5:  any CEOs of any airline companies would like understand this message. Yep.
Speaker 5:  But like it's a perfect incentive match between the needs of the
Speaker 5:  operating system, the needs of the user, and the needs of the app develop.
Speaker 5:  You say to Siri, I need a car ride to the airport and
Speaker 5:  Siri just decides to like, fire off the Uber request. Well, you
Speaker 5:  haven't touched the app at all. Right? Right. Like the app intent has abstracted
Speaker 5:  your app away. And so you run Uber, you run DoorDash, suddenly you don't
Speaker 5:  get an ole opportunity. You don't get the chance to
Speaker 5:  show an ad or say put something else in your cart or even remind people that
Speaker 5:  you exist. And then your rates start to fall. Like the amount of revenue
Speaker 5:  you're making falls because now you're just, the only thing you're competing
Speaker 5:  on is telling Siri how cheap your service is. And that's great for the user
Speaker 5:  perfect incentive match for the user. My robot Butler has picked the
Speaker 5:  cheapest car to the airport for me. Right. But none of the app developers
Speaker 5:  wanna be in that game. And I, I think this is, this is true of the Apple
Speaker 5:  model, but it's true of the Amazon model. I asked Panis about it, you didn't
Speaker 5:  have a great answer for it. I asked the CO of rabbit about it and he was
Speaker 5:  like, well no one's paying attention to us. Which is actually a great answer,
Speaker 5:  right? Sure. In its way a great answer. Like he's like, we're not big enough
Speaker 5:  to be a threat, we're just gonna build the thing until no one can say no
Speaker 5:  to us in its way a great answer. But everybody has the
Speaker 5:  DoorDash problem, which is why would DoorDash play this game that eventually
Speaker 5:  results in their destruction? I don't think Apple has a great answer for
Speaker 5:  developers right now at all. For anything. Yeah. Right. Their answer is put
Speaker 5:  in-app purchases in your app so we can take 30%. Yeah. And like that's,
Speaker 5:  no one's happy about that. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Apple has become a very extractive
Speaker 6:  company and I actually think all of that is, is stacked together. Right?
Speaker 6:  Like I think Apple has burned a lot of its goodwill with the way that it
Speaker 6:  has thought about things like in-app payments that has cost
Speaker 6:  it trust with developers who are now wondering about things like app
Speaker 6:  intents where they're like, okay, I I I
Speaker 6:  just talk to developers all the time who are less and less convinced every
Speaker 6:  day that Apple is actually caring about what is good
Speaker 6:  for them as a developer. And there is a sense that Apple is now in this
Speaker 6:  to get what it feels it deserves from the success of its devices.
Speaker 6:  And that is 30% of every single thing that happens. And so you,
Speaker 6:  you burn all that goodwill and then you say abstract your app away, don't
Speaker 6:  worry. We'll take care of it for you. And that just that sales pitch becomes
Speaker 6:  really hard to make to developers.
Speaker 5:  Right. And it doesn't track at all with the idea that this is a paradigm
Speaker 5:  shift where we'll reset the balance of power and everyone will make more
Speaker 5:  money and there'll be new winners and losers and now it's, I think, I think
Speaker 5:  it's just a tough sell all the way around.
Speaker 6:  It also doesn't work. Like I feel like I have to, I, I feel like I'm taking
Speaker 6:  crazy pills. Not saying this more often. It doesn't work. This technology
Speaker 6:  is bad. There are like things that are cool and interesting about it,
Speaker 6:  but the fact that the most sophisticated thing anyone has developed is this
Speaker 6:  thing will go click around a Chrome browser for you is not
Speaker 6:  success. This thing is these things are bad. And I
Speaker 6:  think I am absolutely fascinated to see what the new Alexa
Speaker 6:  is going to be because to its credit, I think Amazon has actually done a
Speaker 6:  lot of the work that we're talking about. They've made the deals, they have
Speaker 6:  worked very hard it seems on this orchestration layer of figuring out what
Speaker 6:  goes where they're integrating different models, they're integrating with
Speaker 6:  different partners. Like they ha they have pulled all the right pieces
Speaker 6:  into one place in a way that I think is, is potentially very exciting.
Speaker 6:  It might still be bad. Yeah. Like it really might still be bad because this
Speaker 6:  is a really hard problem and no one yet is close to making
Speaker 6:  this work. Like forget all the business incentives. It just doesn't work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean Amazon might have the right pieces, but they might all be misshapen
Speaker 5:  might not fit together and then the picture is bad. Like that's
Speaker 5:  sort of what that puzzle might be like. We don't know. We have to use it.
Speaker 5:  But you know, I asked Pantos in the same conversation, do you think the orchestration
Speaker 5:  layer is something that everyone will land on the same solution? Or is this
Speaker 5:  like a moat? Like is this an advantage that you have? And he was very confident.
Speaker 5:  This is an advantage. Like we have spent our time
Speaker 5:  figuring this thing out because it's what we need to make everything else
Speaker 5:  work. And you can just see that everyone else to figure like Google could
Speaker 5:  pull on stuff like the, who did I have a meeting with at this cafe a week
Speaker 5:  ago? That's, that's information that's in my Google calendar. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like Gemini should, by all rights, be able to just do that on
Speaker 5:  a pixel phone. And Google hasn't flipped that switch yet. They're very close
Speaker 5:  to flipping that switch. Yeah. Very, very close. You can, you can see
Speaker 5:  that they're coming right up on it because they do have all of your data.
Speaker 5:  They are less worried about you talking to the cloud than Apple
Speaker 5:  in like very specific ways.
Speaker 5:  They're, they're Google. They're like, ask us a question. Here's an answer.
Speaker 5:  Maybe the robot made it up or maybe this is actually a person you met with
Speaker 5:  at the cafe a week ago. Who knows. But we're gonna all gonna have a good
Speaker 5:  time. They haven't flipped the switch yet 'cause I don't think they think
Speaker 5:  it's good enough yet. And I, I'm just looking at this and I'm saying everyone
Speaker 5:  is confused by this input method. Everyone is confused by the fact that
Speaker 5:  you can talk to the computer and the computer can do a reasonably good job
Speaker 5:  of talking back to you. And now we all think the paradigm shift is here.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And it's like, oh wait, the computer lies a lot. So like Sam
Speaker 5:  Altman was saying, Che has gotten better at creative writing this week and
Speaker 5:  maybe it has, like I I read some of the, the demos and it's like, yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  a little less stilted than me for, it's still not good at like running
Speaker 5:  my life. Right? Like I think Addie Robertson on our
Speaker 5:  team said, it writes like a 2010s blogger, which hits me to my core
Speaker 5:  is because that that is what I am
Speaker 6:  To be fair, that's probably what it's trained on. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's the most, I mean, I've written millions of words in the 2010s.
Speaker 5:  There you go. Good. Thank you. You're welcome everybody.
Speaker 5:  But like that's improving the part where it's age agentic is not
Speaker 5:  improving. Right. I saw my, at the, at the Amazon event, I saw
Speaker 5:  Mike Krieger from philanthropic, formerly Instagram, former me of Artifact.
Speaker 5:  We've talked a bunch and he was laughing. He's like, it's very
Speaker 5:  funny that every time someone says agentic to you, you just say, you mean
Speaker 5:  clicking around on a website? Because that's, they all know that's what
Speaker 5:  they're doing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's what it is.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. Are there any products you, I mean, I know you talked a bunch
Speaker 5:  of hardware makers. Are there any any products that are close outside of
Speaker 5:  Amazon sounding like they're close?
Speaker 6:  No. Like, and, and I think this is the thing that I have come to find so
Speaker 6:  sort of alarming is like, there's, there's one set of AI
Speaker 6:  features that I I I would think of as like features. You'd never notice
Speaker 6:  that just make things better in your devices. Like we saw a
Speaker 6:  ton of this at CES, right? That it was like, what if we used generative AI
Speaker 6:  to
Speaker 6:  better map your living room so that your Roomba can get around a little faster.
Speaker 6:  Like that's a terrific and real use of ai. They can use it to like
Speaker 6:  your, your lights can do a better job of matching the mood of the
Speaker 6:  music that you're listening to. That's like a real thing AI can do. And that's
Speaker 6:  a good use of it. That's not AI as a product. That's like
Speaker 6:  AI as an underlying technology enabling a feature feature.
Speaker 6:  Everything I see that is like AI as a top line reason
Speaker 6:  for this thing to exist is a problem. And, and I, this is like, that
Speaker 6:  was the thing that made me write this piece is like, we're at this point
Speaker 6:  now where everyone has decided that AI is finished and they're building
Speaker 6:  gadgets. That would be great if AI was finished and AI is not
Speaker 6:  finished and AI mostly sucks and thus so do these gadgets. And,
Speaker 6:  and so I mean you you look at like the, it's the smart home stuff. I think
Speaker 6:  that is probably the easiest, right? We were like, we've talked on the show
Speaker 6:  a million times. Ambient computing is the thing, right? This is all anybody
Speaker 6:  talks about like the, and that is purely AI
Speaker 6:  enabled, right? Like that's how we get there. Tons of data, tons of context
Speaker 6:  sensors abound. And it just like understands who I am and where I am and
Speaker 6:  what I'm doing and I can just have a computer and an assistant that's around
Speaker 6:  me all the time. That is pure ai.
Speaker 6:  Do any of those things exist or work? And so what you've had instead is
Speaker 6:  Amazon basically hasn't launched like a meaningfully new
Speaker 6:  Echo product in at least a year and a half, maybe
Speaker 6:  longer because this company has been so captured by this idea that
Speaker 6:  we have to do AI in order to make any gadgets any good
Speaker 6:  because AI is the only reason gadgets should exist. And Apple just keeps
Speaker 6:  shipping shit that they're like, eh, it does Apple intelligence. Like we
Speaker 6:  get like briefings to explain new Apple devices every time there's a new
Speaker 6:  Apple device. And I'm sure you've gotten them too, but like over and over
Speaker 6:  it's just the same Apple intelligence demos on different screens. Like
Speaker 6:  this is a problem. It all of these things exist in service
Speaker 6:  of AI that doesn't exist. So what is the point of any of these gadgets right
Speaker 6:  now? And it's just starting to drive me insane. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's funny 'cause AI driving the gadgets again, I would, I
Speaker 5:  would put that in the category of we made Multitouch and now we
Speaker 5:  think smartphones should all look this way. So the whole industry has built
Speaker 5:  Blackberry storms,
Speaker 5:  right? Like that's kind of what this feels like. Like we're new Windows Mobile
Speaker 5:  6.5, so it it's a resistant touchscreen and that honeycomb
Speaker 5:  grid, but it's still Windows mobile. Yeah. It's not even Windows phone. You
Speaker 5:  know, it's like this was by the way in the annals of like
Speaker 5:  VERGE and Eng Gadget history, some nuclear stuff where we were like,
Speaker 5:  this is still Windows mobile. They just added resistive touchscreen support.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 5:  that's where we're at, right? Yeah. Like we made this new interface where
Speaker 5:  someone OpenAI showed off a new interface and everyone was like, we can build,
Speaker 5:  we, what the consumers want is poking these screens. And no one
Speaker 5:  thought about the software underneath it except for Apple. And then a little
Speaker 5:  bit later Google and then you had iOS standard and we don't have those
Speaker 5:  products yet, right? We have chatt, which people love, and then we have a
Speaker 5:  bunch of coding products and I, we, we've gotten some notes from people who
Speaker 5:  are like, you're not paying attention to what's happening on the software
Speaker 5:  development side. The these are very useful tools in software development.
Speaker 5:  Great. But the consumer paradigm shift
Speaker 5:  that all of these companies are betting on does not exist yet.
Speaker 6:  Right? I, yeah, I, the, the thing I keep saying to people when I talk to
Speaker 6:  is like, I think the, the B2B
Speaker 6:  implications of AI are huge and real and,
Speaker 6:  and present, right? Like there are so many ways in which
Speaker 6:  companies are using AI to do interesting stuff. Some of it I find hugely
Speaker 6:  problematic, but some of it is really interesting. None of that is
Speaker 6:  regular people things. And I'm like, I am here asking
Speaker 6:  you about regular people things and those are just
Speaker 6:  the lies that people tell to make themselves sound more interesting than
Speaker 6:  they are. Yeah. That's what this is right now.
Speaker 5:  I'll say as we've been talking, another part of the story that we were gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about his flip flopped.
Speaker 6:  Oh Lord.
Speaker 5:  So Apple announced this delay of Siri or AI powered Siri
Speaker 5:  that led to some rumors that their smart home display, which
Speaker 5:  felt like an iPad on a stick, would also be delayed. Because
Speaker 5:  what enables that product is being able to just talk to it, right? And
Speaker 5:  now there's rumors that it could still ship this year,
Speaker 5:  okay? But instead of having the new Siri, it will have this rumored big design
Speaker 5:  overhaul for iOS and macOS that people have been talking about.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. So instead of the thing that would make it useful,
Speaker 6:  they're gonna ship it with the thing that makes it pretty and call it an
Speaker 6:  upgrade.
Speaker 5:  You know, I don't wanna, this
Speaker 6:  Is what we do here. I will say everything that I have heard about the
Speaker 6:  new iOS designs, I'm actually very excited about. Like there are all these,
Speaker 6:  all the reporting from Mark Erman and others is that it's gonna be more vision
Speaker 6:  ProE, which means much more sort of colorful and glassy and
Speaker 6:  spatial and kind of three dimensional. And I'm into that iOS,
Speaker 6:  the iOS seven aesthetic is long in the tooth and deserves to
Speaker 6:  die. So fine. That is not the same thing as
Speaker 6:  Siri,
Speaker 5:  Right? The paradigm shift is not translucency, it's not making
Speaker 5:  swinging windows. Windows arrow glass is very much the aesthetic of
Speaker 5:  the mission
Speaker 6:  Product. Yep.
Speaker 5:  But look, the kids today don't even know what I'm talking about. All right.
Speaker 5:  You didn't have to live through Windows Vista and it's fine. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  think it's beautiful.
Speaker 6:  My hottest take is Aass w was not all wrong. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Aass vindicated will be our headline. Three people will understand it,
Speaker 5:  Tom Warren, it will explode. And then we'll just move on with our lives.
Speaker 5:  Alright, we gotta take a break. We've, we've talked about this to death.
Speaker 5:  If you have a, a solid use case
Speaker 5:  for how AI has changed a consumer gadget, you let us know. I, I'll offer
Speaker 5:  you just one. I think my daughter is very into space recently
Speaker 5:  and we just sit there with my iPhone talking to chat GP about space almost
Speaker 5:  every night. It's fun. But that is not the gadget, right?
Speaker 5:  That's just a, it's just an app on a phone,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. That's that's the thing, right? Like what,
Speaker 6:  what in here goes beyond app on a phone or
Speaker 6:  chatbot in my browser? Beat that and I will have a really fun
Speaker 6:  conversation with you about AI gadgets
Speaker 5:  Also. None of this companies make any money. All right, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 5:  Hopefully by the time we come back, all the AI companies will figure out
Speaker 5:  a revenue model. But in the meantime, you're gonna listen to these ads. We'll
Speaker 5:  be right back.
Speaker 5:  What is going on with this company. You wrote a story, the headline is just,
Speaker 5:  Is Tesla cooked? It's a good headline. And just based on
Speaker 5:  the reader reaction to it, it seems like a lot of people would like the answer
Speaker 5:  to be yes. And a significant number of people believe the answer
Speaker 5:  is yes. Yes. What's happening here? Well, I think sort of the,
Speaker 5:  the, the top line issue that, that, that
Speaker 5:  we're dealing with here is that the, the, the company had a
Speaker 5:  huge spike in its share price. Immediately after the election. It went
Speaker 5:  up like something, like a ridiculous amount to a point where I think in
Speaker 5:  December, individual stock shares were selling for like over
Speaker 5:  four 50 bucks in incredible, right? The, the
Speaker 5:  investors were clearly rewarding Elon Musk for making what they saw was
Speaker 5:  the, the, the right bet in the election. Trump was, Trump won.
Speaker 5:  And so therefore Tesla needed to be, and Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  specifically needed to be rewarded. But then we started to see
Speaker 5:  a couple of things. First, the, the company reported its end of the year
Speaker 5:  earnings. And it was kind of shocking and pretty sobering
Speaker 5:  that their sales were down. Not a lot, but
Speaker 5:  essentially they were flat. And for a company that is
Speaker 5:  supposed to be on this exponential growth projection,
Speaker 5:  I think that that was pretty surprising to a lot of people. And then the
Speaker 5:  Elon of it all as Neli, you like to say, sort of came crashing
Speaker 5:  down and he was put in charge of this Doge project and
Speaker 5:  just basically started vandalizing the federal government
Speaker 5:  shutting agencies down, firing people, you know, barging into
Speaker 5:  places where he wasn't allowed to go and, and sort of
Speaker 5:  trampoline the constitution in, in the process.
Speaker 5:  And that sort of gave rise to obviously a groundswell of
Speaker 5:  anger and opposition. I think a lot of people, especially people who
Speaker 5:  consider themselves progressives and, and democrats and liberals were sort
Speaker 5:  of, kind of despondent and depressed after the
Speaker 5:  election really kind of found this, the a way to focal fo
Speaker 5:  fo focus their anger
Speaker 5:  in January. And then in February we saw this protest
Speaker 5:  movement take root and people were demonstrating outside of Tesla showrooms.
Speaker 5:  And then sort of separately to that, you know, all those protests were pretty
Speaker 5:  peaceful. But separate to that, there's been lots of reports of vandalism
Speaker 5:  cars being vandalized, superchargers being set
Speaker 5:  on fire. Someone took a, a few shots at a, a Tesla showroom
Speaker 5:  in, in Oregon. I took a few shots. You mean fired a gun at
Speaker 5:  Yes. Bullets were fired at the showroom in Oregon. They didn't like go on
Speaker 5:  Instagram live and start talking shit. They had fired a gun at the show.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Shots fired as Musk himself said in an interview recently, he talked,
Speaker 5:  he said that he, he with a, with a, a big grin on his face. He thought that
Speaker 5:  that was a really good joke when he said shots fired. So then
Speaker 5:  the, the stock started to slide. It had already been going down since January.
Speaker 5:  It took a steep drop earlier this week. One of the, one of the
Speaker 5:  biggest drops that we'd seen in over five years to the point that
Speaker 5:  I think had its Nader, that that, you know, it had essentially shed 50% of
Speaker 5:  its value. The company itself lost around
Speaker 5:  $800 billion in valuation, which is just
Speaker 5:  a staggering number when you consider how highly valued Tesla was at that
Speaker 5:  point. And Musk himself lost around a hundred billion dollars off of his
Speaker 5:  net worth. Poor guy.
Speaker 6:  Still
Speaker 5:  The richest man in the world. Don't worry about him, he's gonna be fine.
Speaker 5:  But what I think we're, what we're seeing now and, and is, is now
Speaker 5:  a concerted effort by the government and namely by, by
Speaker 5:  Trump to prop Tesla up. He's, he's,
Speaker 5:  you know, sort of bringing the cars to the White House and they're having
Speaker 5:  themselves, whatever that that was, that we saw
Speaker 5:  on the lawn outside. So some have called it, you know, sort of like an
Speaker 5:  infomercial for Tesla, essentially on government property.
Speaker 5:  And, and he's talking about,
Speaker 5:  you know, going after people who vandalize or deface
Speaker 5:  Teslas with terrorism charges now. So it's clear that, you know,
Speaker 5:  Trump and the administration are interested in bringing sort of the full
Speaker 5:  force of the federal government behind Tesla to protect Tesla
Speaker 5:  and to make sure that it is not subject to the whims of, of the market.
Speaker 5:  I guess,
Speaker 6:  You know, what's fascinating about this to me, Andy, you and I have talked
Speaker 6:  a few times, I think we've actually, the three of us have talked a few times
Speaker 6:  on this show about the, one of the strange things about Tesla is trying
Speaker 6:  to figure out what of the Tesla
Speaker 6:  vibes are about Tesla and what is the Elon of it all. And that
Speaker 6:  those two things have always been really hard to pull apart. Like there's
Speaker 6:  a company that for a long time was way ahead of the game and very successful
Speaker 6:  and has kind of lost its lead over time. And then there is the Elon of it
Speaker 6:  all. And I think it seems very clear to me that the thing that has happened
Speaker 6:  over the last 10 days in particular is that it is just about the Elon of
Speaker 6:  it all now. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Wait, no, I disagree. No, I, I disagree. Not in like a big way.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But, but just on one element, which is that the Elon of it all
Speaker 5:  for Tesla was what propped up the meme stock bubble
Speaker 5:  of the stock price, right? Sure. So Elon says all the cars
Speaker 5:  will drive themselves, I'm gonna do a robo taxi, and everyone believes him
Speaker 5:  or they don't believe him, or they think, well, the man landed two rockets
Speaker 5:  at the same time. Of course he's gonna pull this off and then the stock price
Speaker 5:  goes up because people think it's gonna pay off. Right? And I think what
Speaker 5:  has happened very recently is the bloom is so fully off the rose.
Speaker 5:  And even If you want to believe Elon, it's
Speaker 5:  undeniable that he's not paying attention to the company
Speaker 5:  because he's, he's set up in the Secretary of
Speaker 5:  War suite at the Eisenhower executive office building with a gaming PC with
Speaker 5:  RGB lights. That's a real thing. You can go look at the picture. It is very
Speaker 5:  funny to see that computer in that office,
Speaker 5:  and there's no way he's paying attention to Tesla. And so even people who
Speaker 5:  are nominally like pro Elon or impressed by Elon
Speaker 5:  are like, dude, pay attention to your company and the cars aren't gonna
Speaker 5:  drive themselves unless you pay attention to your company. And then you can
Speaker 5:  see the multiple is coming down off the stock, and then you can see the sales
Speaker 5:  are falling. And then you can see the sales are falling even more sharply
Speaker 5:  in Europe, for example, where doing
Speaker 5:  heel Hitler gestures is not taken with the same amount of, he's just trolling
Speaker 5:  sort of responses in this country in this moment for whatever insane reason.
Speaker 5:  So you've just got this, like the Elon of it all has
Speaker 5:  always been the dreams will come true.
Speaker 5:  And I think now those things are just, they're, they're pulling apart. So
Speaker 5:  I'm not saying I disagree with you, David, I'm just saying like,
Speaker 5:  there's nothing inside of Tesla that makes it more than a car company anymore.
Speaker 5:  The best example of this I can give you is Mark Kelly,
Speaker 5:  Senator Mark Kelly Elon called him a traitor the other day
Speaker 5:  on Twitter. So Senator Kelly went to Ukraine, he said, we stand with Ukraine,
Speaker 5:  this is all about democracy. Elon responds to that by saying, you are a trader.
Speaker 5:  And then today in the capitol building, reporters
Speaker 5:  asked Senator Kelly, are you gonna sell your Tesla? And he said, well, it's
Speaker 5:  a great car. It's pretty cheap on the inside, though. I love the acceleration.
Speaker 5:  I don't get to drive much. I'm, I'm looking into selling it. And
Speaker 5:  he was just able to evaluate the car, not everything the car
Speaker 5:  represents or everything the car might mean, or robo
Speaker 5:  taxis. He just said the truest thing. I'm presuming this is a model three,
Speaker 5:  the truest thing you can say about a model three, which is it accelerates
Speaker 5:  really fast and on the inside it's a little bit cheap there
Speaker 5:  that that stock price, you don't get 1200 times
Speaker 5:  your valuation and stock price against. It's very fast and a little cheap.
Speaker 5:  That's a Camaro. We
Speaker 6:  Are barreling towards a moment where buying a Tesla is
Speaker 6:  like buying stock in truth social. Sure. That it is. Like,
Speaker 6:  it is, it is such a political animal now. And I think, I mean
Speaker 6:  this was true when, when the election happened, like you're talking about
Speaker 6:  Indy, like this company hit a record high after the election, not
Speaker 6:  because it sold more cars, but because Elon Musk won
Speaker 6:  the election. Like that, that is just a thing that happened. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 6:  everybody assumed he would use that to Tesla's benefit and he didn't. He
Speaker 6:  used it to destroy America. But that's, that, that was the, that
Speaker 6:  was the assumption then. And I think, and for me that was the moment
Speaker 6:  that any question of like, is this, is this company or is the perception
Speaker 6:  of this company about cars or is it about politics just
Speaker 6:  flipped entirely like this, this is a company about politics
Speaker 6:  and it shouldn't be. And it is, and it's weird that it's, I think
Speaker 5:  What's also really fascinating too is that, you know, sort of like trying
Speaker 5:  to make a bet as an investor or someone who wants to play the stock
Speaker 5:  market on Elon Musk used to be a pretty easy bet that
Speaker 5:  would, that would pay off for, for a number of years. You could
Speaker 5:  invest in Tesla and assume and see returns on that investment because
Speaker 5:  of the way that the stock market treated that company. Not as a regular car
Speaker 5:  company as what Eli was saying, but as something that's
Speaker 5:  sort of, you know, about robotics and artificial
Speaker 5:  intelligence and self-driving cars and energy management and, and
Speaker 5:  honestly saving the world. Right? For a long time he was framing the, the,
Speaker 5:  the mission of Tesla as being one about saving the world.
Speaker 5:  And I remember the last
Speaker 5:  investor day that they had a couple years ago, he talked about very plainly
Speaker 5:  about how it's not that hard to, to take all of
Speaker 5:  these gas powered devices off the, off the road and replace them with
Speaker 5:  clean energy powered devices. And he framed it very clearly as
Speaker 5:  an effort to save the world. At the same time that that was going on. He
Speaker 5:  was also in the process of trying to buy Twitter. And we,
Speaker 5:  we saw sort of like throughout that whole process about how his, his
Speaker 5:  viewpoint and his worldview became slowly very much informed by
Speaker 5:  conspiracy theories and, and, and hard right politics. And
Speaker 5:  then it became sort of clear after a while After that that he wasn't really
Speaker 5:  interested in running Tesla anymore. He didn't, he didn't, he didn't want
Speaker 5:  to just be like a car salesman. He wanted to be
Speaker 5:  sort of the guy who was on the vanguard of, of ai this AI revolution that
Speaker 5:  we're seeing. And then now it seems like that's not really even
Speaker 5:  of interest to him anymore. Now he wants to be the co-president, which, I
Speaker 5:  mean, like, can you blame the guy, like who wants to go from being a car
Speaker 5:  salesman to like, maybe I'll make robots to now like I am, like co in charge
Speaker 5:  of like the, the biggest richest country in the world. Sure. Like, I can't
Speaker 5:  really see like, you know, how that that argument doesn't really
Speaker 5:  pan out for him. So, you know, maybe he's not interested in Tesla anymore.
Speaker 5:  Maybe he's not even really interested in robots. Maybe he's more interested
Speaker 5:  in, in just being sort of like this iron fisted ruler of the country.
Speaker 5:  I just don't see how that's gonna sell them anymore. Cars. Like at the end
Speaker 5:  of the day, Tesla, the, I think the reason that Tesla take down protests
Speaker 5:  have succeeded and I think they are a success. I don't think you end
Speaker 5:  up doing an infomercial for Teslas and the White House lawn unless the
Speaker 5:  protests are having impact. I don't think you see the stock price dropping
Speaker 5:  unless the protests are having an impact. The reason is
Speaker 5:  that's an incredible point of leverage, right? You, you make these cars toxic
Speaker 5:  to own. The cyber truck in particular has become a toxic car to own.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And some people are quite happy about that. Like I'm as somebody
Speaker 5:  who has a big, loud, stupid car, like, I get it, I understand why people
Speaker 5:  like big, loud, stupid cars,
Speaker 5:  but you see the videos of people spray painting them
Speaker 5:  and putting stickers on them. There's a great video I sent to Andy, which
Speaker 5:  is pure Andy Hawkins bait today, which was somebody parked a cyber truck
Speaker 5:  in a bike lane in New York City and a guy picked up a city bike
Speaker 5:  and rode it off the cyber truck like a ramp, like down the
Speaker 5:  windshield to just, because it was in the bike lane in the way in. That's
Speaker 5:  very good. Like there's something on that. That's that's beautiful. Great.
Speaker 5:  I I I appreciate some funny protests in that
Speaker 5:  way, but the products themselves, to your point, David, they now symbolize
Speaker 5:  a politics, right? And that's not gonna keep sales up.
Speaker 5:  No. And so you end up with this weird situation
Speaker 5:  where Trump is at the White House sort of like
Speaker 5:  dunking on Joe Biden complaining about the economy and then turning around
Speaker 5:  and being like, this car is beautiful. And it was just a weird scene.
Speaker 5:  I will say that I watched it, it's about, it was 35 minutes long, somewhere
Speaker 5:  around that. And just to get through it, I, I watched it two x speed on YouTube
Speaker 5:  and watching Elon and Trump talk at two x speed is like an out of body experience.
Speaker 5:  I, I don't recommend it, but I also think everybody should experience at
Speaker 5:  one time, didn't he say everything is computer?
Speaker 5:  What a, what a good tee up. That just was. Andy, I have three clips I would
Speaker 5:  like to play for you three Perfect. From this perfect. Just, there
Speaker 5:  were so many moments during this, but I just, I just pulled out a couple
Speaker 5:  that I would just like to play for you very quickly that I think neatly summarized
Speaker 5:  the deep strangeness of this event. Here's the first one.
Speaker 13:  Wow.
Speaker 13:  Thank goodness. I was side that's beautiful down front. This is a different
Speaker 13:  panel than I've had. Everything's computer.
Speaker 5:  So that's Donald Trump getting into the car. He sits down in the driver's
Speaker 5:  seat after like 10 times a red model. S pla it's a red model s right? And
Speaker 5:  he, he says many times that Joe Biden could never basically, like, he couldn't
Speaker 5:  get into this car, he doesn't even know what Teslas are. And then he gets
Speaker 5:  in and he just, he sort of waves around and he goes, everything's
Speaker 5:  computer. And I really believe the verges official tagline now should be
Speaker 5:  everything's computer. I feel very validated because years ago when we hired
Speaker 5:  Andy to cover cars, I was like, here's the deal. Everything's computer. Can
Speaker 5:  we make t-shirts that say everything's computer? Like why is The Verge cover
Speaker 5:  cars? Because everything's computer. I, I feel like I have to note though
Speaker 5:  that a big reason why Musk sup reportedly turned away
Speaker 5:  from Joe Biden and the Democrats is 'cause he didn't get invited to a White
Speaker 5:  House summit during the Biden administration that was supposed to bring all
Speaker 5:  the automakers in to talk about electric vehicle policy. And, and they
Speaker 5:  snubbed Musk because supposedly because he doesn't allow unions in his
Speaker 5:  at Tesla and Biden was a very pro-union president. So, and
Speaker 5:  that was something that he really kind of wore as like a chip on his shoulder.
Speaker 5:  Musk finally got his, his White House summit and he got it all to himself.
Speaker 5:  And I think that I, I hope he feels good about that. No, I I think he felt
Speaker 5:  like Donald Trump went wandering towards the model y and he had to be like,
Speaker 5:  no, no, no, come back. Look at the cyber trunk. Which is a real thing that
Speaker 5:  happened. Okay. I have a, I have another clip to play for you. This is, they're
Speaker 5:  sitting in the car and Trump continues to just sort of marvel at the existence
Speaker 5:  of a car. It seems like, like you get the real sense that Donald Trump may
Speaker 5:  never have driven a car in his life.
Speaker 13:  It's, it's, it's like, it's like driving a golf car basically. It's very
Speaker 13:  simple. It's very simple. So it's, it's literal like boat park that goes
Speaker 13:  really fast. There's no gears. This is really amazing.
Speaker 5:  It's like driving a golf cart that goes really fast, I think is like not
Speaker 5:  the sales pitch. Elon Musk thinks it might be. I also have to say there's
Speaker 5:  no gears is a ridiculous thing to say in 2025.
Speaker 5:  It's hard to buy a car worth a manual transition in 2025, calling it a golf
Speaker 5:  cart. I mean, that's just talking to Trump in his language, right? I mean,
Speaker 5:  that that is probably the only vehicle that he drives that's so crazy. His
Speaker 5:  life. You don't think Trump has gas powered golf carts at in Mar-a-Lago?
Speaker 5:  No. They're, they're too loud. You gotta you gotta have quiet when you're,
Speaker 5:  when you're hitting your terrible bunker shots. David, I will say that I
Speaker 5:  have to register a, a fact check on you. I know Donald Trump has driven
Speaker 5:  a car because there is at least one video of Donald Trump driving
Speaker 5:  a car that I Was it the one where tell he was sitting in the firetruck and
Speaker 5:  did the woo woo gesture? No, no, no, no. Okay. Because that doesn't count.
Speaker 5:  It's him. I believe the video was taken by Barron Trump, a young Barron Trump.
Speaker 5:  He's riding around in a Rolls Royce driven by Donald Trump. Melania is in
Speaker 5:  the passenger seat and they're listening to Blank Space by Taylor
Speaker 5:  Swift. This is a real video. You can go look it. Amazing. Interesting. But
Speaker 5:  I will say that rolls, I'm looking at the video right now. It ha it does
Speaker 5:  have analog gauges. So everything is not
Speaker 5:  computer, but now it is. Everything's so that was Donald Trump drove that
Speaker 5:  car and then this car, and that's a, it's a big change from a, from a rolls
Speaker 5:  to this. I could see how that would, that would blow mind. Do you think?
Speaker 5:  I don't, there is a, a sequence of that video where people keep telling him
Speaker 5:  to start the car and then you hear one of the photographers say, start the
Speaker 5:  engine. And like, I couldn't see Elon's face, but I could see Trump's
Speaker 5:  face and he just didn't like, none of that made any sense. Like, you
Speaker 5:  can't start a Tesla. There's no, there's no key to turn,
Speaker 5:  there's no engine. Someone somewhat famously, no engine.
Speaker 5:  I would, the whole situation was confused. All right, what's the third one?
Speaker 5:  All right, I have one more, I'm just gonna play it for you. Thank
Speaker 14:  You all very much. I love Tesla.
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's the whole clip.
Speaker 5:  That's not great.
Speaker 5:  Did you say teslar Tesla? Yeah. And that's right. I spelled it TI think
Speaker 5:  S-L-U-R-R is combining Tesla with the word slur, I think is very appropriate
Speaker 5:  in this moment. Yeah, that's about right. Straight. You did not run any of
Speaker 5:  clips of Donald Trump just sort of behold the cyber truck.
Speaker 5:  He was like, can you imagine what kind of brains in this guy's head? I know
Speaker 5:  he, he at one point like double tapped the side of it and was like, what
Speaker 5:  a great deal. Yeah, because Yolan was like, it's bulletproof and Trump goes
Speaker 5:  as though he's gonna test it out. Yeah. It was really something. But
Speaker 5:  if your test of something, whether or not something is bulletproof is like
Speaker 5:  wrapping on it twice. You're gonna believe everything is bulletproof.
Speaker 5:  It was weird. It was a weird event, a weird moment. It was again,
Speaker 5:  scattered with questions about whether there'd be a recession,
Speaker 5:  about whether Trump needed the notes in his
Speaker 5:  own hand that had the prices of Teslas listed on it. Weird
Speaker 5:  all around.
Speaker 6:  He went on a long rant about Columbia University at one point. Like yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's
Speaker 5:  Another first Amendment disaster that's unfolding. But that's
Speaker 6:  Kind of my point. All this is so tied up together now that it is like,
Speaker 6:  and maybe this was the inevitable outcome of Elon Musk becoming so
Speaker 6:  entrenched in our government, but like, I don't know. I I look around my
Speaker 6:  neighborhood now and there there are everyone who has a Tesla.
Speaker 6:  I live in a very like liberal area and
Speaker 6:  overwhelmingly I'm starting to see Teslas with some version of the, I
Speaker 6:  bought this before Elon Musk went crazy sticker, including on cyber
Speaker 6:  trucks, which debatable. Yeah, that's
Speaker 5:  Not a choice for you. Although they did announce the cyber truck 500 years
Speaker 5:  ago. That's fair.
Speaker 6:  That is, it was the first car ever invented and then they shipped it. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, I just, I don't see how this goes back either.
Speaker 6:  It really feels like we are at a place where the protests feel
Speaker 6:  like they're gonna continue to get worse because this thing is becoming increasingly
Speaker 6:  politicized and that what Trump and must give decided is that
Speaker 6:  actually politicizing it is a way to, to
Speaker 5:  Ban it. No,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, it's either to sell more cars to Republicans ideally who
Speaker 6:  traditionally have not been the people who buy electric cars or who
Speaker 6:  cares juice the stock price, right? Like it, it it, you turn Tesla into a
Speaker 6:  meme stock for Republicans, which has made Donald Trump an awful lot
Speaker 6:  of money over the years. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I I think Tesla like Neil, I said it's been over inflated. It's a
Speaker 5:  meme stock, it's overvalued, it's, it's, it's traded more,
Speaker 5:  you know, sort of at a similar level as, as tech stocks are and not as a
Speaker 5:  car car stock. And I think that a lot of people assumed
Speaker 5:  that taking a face plant on robot taxis or the
Speaker 5:  optimist robots, you know, falling down a flight of stairs or something
Speaker 5:  like that was gonna be what sort of ultimately deflated. And I don't think
Speaker 5:  anyone really assumed that it was gonna be this sort of like
Speaker 5:  politicization that we're seeing in Musk taking such a prominent role in
Speaker 5:  the administration. But I think that that's, that is ultimately what is going
Speaker 5:  to bring, bring Tesla sort of back, back down to earth is this this hyper
Speaker 5:  political environment that we're in now. Yeah. You never thought it would
Speaker 5:  be the fundamentals of the car sales would bring it back down to earth. Right.
Speaker 5:  Like that, that seemed insulated because of the
Speaker 5:  promises about robot robotaxis and all that other stuff. By the way, the,
Speaker 5:  the best sticker on a cyber truck situation is the couple
Speaker 5:  who wrapped their cyber truck white and put a Rivian logo on the back of
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 6:  So good.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god, that was so good. And then they discovered that they became a
Speaker 5:  meme and had to go on Reddit and like try to like laugh it off and explain
Speaker 5:  themselves and nobody bought
Speaker 6:  It. Well and their explanation was we sold our other Tesla,
Speaker 6:  but we can't sell this one. No one will take it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I've seen videos. Yeah. I have a weird TikTok algorithm. I
Speaker 5:  I I have a lot of like car dealerships on the phone negotiating
Speaker 5:  deals on my TikTok feed and I've watched a lot of car dealership
Speaker 5:  guys like totally make low ball offers for cyber trucks. Mm.
Speaker 5:  And then basically, you know, the person's like, no. And they're like, call
Speaker 5:  me back. This is the number you're gonna get. Like at, at some point you're
Speaker 5:  gonna call me back and I'm gonna give, I'm gonna give you $60,000 to the
Speaker 5:  cyber truck. And that is, that's just bad news. Now are a
Speaker 5:  bunch of car dealerships trying to artificially lower the price of cyber
Speaker 5:  trucks by making TikTok videos? Potentially. But you can, you
Speaker 5:  can see the dynamic for that car in particular is getting worse.
Speaker 5:  And I think some people like the attention, there's a cyber truck in Westchester
Speaker 5:  where I live that is spray painted and a lot of people believe the owner
Speaker 5:  spray painted it himself
Speaker 6:  Oh wow. As a, as a like defense mechanism.
Speaker 5:  As a defense mechanism as a way to get pictures of his truck on Instagram.
Speaker 5:  No one knows. Yeah. But like that we're entering the second phase, you know,
Speaker 5:  where people are like, oh, you're doing it for clout. And it's like, that's
Speaker 5:  weird. That's a weird outcome. Yeah. A lot of, I know a lot of small business
Speaker 5:  owners bought cyber trucks to like wrap with like their, the name of
Speaker 5:  their business if like they had like a, like a small solar company or like
Speaker 5:  a, a coffee shop or something like that. And, and now we're starting to see
Speaker 5:  a lot of them sort of reverse on that and you know, take the wrapping, take
Speaker 5:  the wrapping up because they know put
Speaker 6:  Their competitors' logo on it instead. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We should talk just briefly, we, we talk a lot about the first amendment
Speaker 5:  on the show, Tesla take down is the name of the protest. It's pretty loosely
Speaker 5:  organized. Like I don't, there's not a head of Tesla take down, you know,
Speaker 5:  it's certainly not like command, it's just like a command system, you know,
Speaker 5:  it's like an army. People are just showing up Tesla dealerships and protesting
Speaker 5:  at certain times, like organized on social media like you do. Trump is basically
Speaker 5:  saying this is gonna be terrorism, we're gonna prosecute this. Mike Johnson,
Speaker 5:  the speaker of the house said the house would start investigating these protests.
Speaker 5:  The police are out in force at Tesla dealerships. Now there's an incredible
Speaker 5:  picture, I believe a store in Chicago with just a line of
Speaker 5:  police officers in front of it last weekend, which is just incredible, right?
Speaker 5:  There's a video of a cyber truck in New York being guarded by six
Speaker 5:  police officers, which is very funny in its way the politicization
Speaker 5:  is running right into the weird first amendment environment, right? Where
Speaker 5:  yes, we talk a lot about free speech. Elon says he is a free speech absolutist,
Speaker 5:  but If you protest a Tesla, the dealership, the full power of the
Speaker 5:  state's police force will be there to greet you. There's something
Speaker 5:  weird there. I it hasn't broken yet, right? Like there aren't
Speaker 5:  you, no one's been arrested for protesting at Tesla dealership yet. And I
Speaker 5:  don't think you should burn down the charging stations, but we're in a
Speaker 5:  real fuzzy place. How do you think that's playing out, Eddie? Well, I mean
Speaker 5:  we've already saw this week ice agents detain and disappear
Speaker 5:  a pro-Palestinian activist for, you know, basically for no
Speaker 5:  crime at all, but for, you know, speaking out in support of, of Gaza. So
Speaker 5:  it's, it's not a very huge leap to
Speaker 5:  go and, and start doing the same for people who are speaking out against
Speaker 5:  Tesla. I mean, I I I think that, you know, what, what Trump is saying specifically
Speaker 5:  is people who are vandalizing and are doing
Speaker 5:  things that are considered to be violent and and dangerous are,
Speaker 5:  are potentially going to face some of these charges. Whether or not that
Speaker 5:  extends to the people who are peacefully protesting, I don't think we've
Speaker 5:  seen yet. I don't, I don't think that that was necessarily what he was saying.
Speaker 5:  It's hard to parse what, what Trump says too much. And I know that
Speaker 5:  Musk has made claims on X about how these
Speaker 5:  protests are, are AstroTurf and are being funded by,
Speaker 5:  you know, Soros or whomever else, you know, sort of are the, the, the enemies
Speaker 5:  that lurk in his brain. So I don't really know how this is, I I think like
Speaker 5:  if anything, the protesters are probably now even more motivated to turn
Speaker 5:  out at the locations now that they know that they're on
Speaker 5:  Trump and, and Musk's radar, you know, I think that a lot of this was about
Speaker 5:  getting their attention and now that they know that they have his attention,
Speaker 5:  I I think we'll see something of an escalation at least in numbers,
Speaker 5:  which I think is going to cause I think a lot of disruption and, you know,
Speaker 5:  police overtime,
Speaker 5:  salaries are gonna go up. So, you know, it's, it's gonna be really kind of
Speaker 5:  interesting to watch. And I know that the, you know, in talking to some of
Speaker 5:  the, the local organizers and some of the people who are promoting the protests
Speaker 5:  online on Blue Sky are, are adamant about, you know,
Speaker 5:  this is a peaceful protest. You know, we, we might occasionally like get
Speaker 5:  arrested peacefully for occupying space, but we're never going to be defacing
Speaker 5:  or vandalizing. That's not the, the mission of this movement. The mission
Speaker 5:  is to cause Tesla's sales numbers to go down and to
Speaker 5:  hurt Elon Musk's net worth and stock price. That's all that they're interested
Speaker 5:  in doing. So I think if they can sort of hold that line, it'll
Speaker 5:  really, I think, sort of be on the, on the other side to really
Speaker 5:  kind of escalate things if they want to. I will know that Trump has called
Speaker 5:  the boycott movement an illegal boycott, which is not a thing which tracks
Speaker 5:  right, which is not a thing also tracks with Elon saying it's illegal to
Speaker 5:  not advertise on x I'm just saying the police are coming to your house and
Speaker 5:  you're gonna buy a Tesla that seems very, it's the, the end
Speaker 5:  result of America that what, what color do you want
Speaker 5:  and how much of your personal income do you have to give up to the government
Speaker 5:  in order to receive your Tesla? Is the only question that's, that's how,
Speaker 5:  that's the end state of Doge. We're gonna, we're gonna fund social security
Speaker 5:  by forcing a brand to buy Tesla somehow now it's gonna be good. Alright,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna see what happens this weekend. It feels like the protests are
Speaker 5:  getting louder, right? Like the protesters have gotten the validation they
Speaker 5:  need from the White House, like it's working. They're, they're, they're bothering
Speaker 5:  the people in charge. That usually means it gets louder.
Speaker 5:  I'm very worried about the free speech environment of America, as every listener
Speaker 5:  of the show knows that dynamic is something we're watching very closely.
Speaker 5:  But in the meantime, let us know If you Tesla starts driving itself
Speaker 5:  or If you are the person who spray painted your own cyber truck for attention.
Speaker 5:  I'm dying to talk to you Andy. Thank you so much man. Thanks.
Speaker 5:  Thanks guys.
Speaker 5:  recording, we recorded this on a Wednesday, Wednesday earlier than usual
Speaker 5:  for various calendar reasons, but as we were recording, Chris Welch broke
Speaker 5:  the news that Sonos in an all hands meeting has canceled its
Speaker 5:  streaming video player, which was called Pinewood.
Speaker 6:  Oh that's sad. Pinewood. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So this was Sonos big push, right? It's next big
Speaker 5:  market under the previous administration was streaming video. They had
Speaker 5:  a deal with some advertising company, they were to link everything together.
Speaker 5:  Presumably there would be some AI talk that's just the way things go. And
Speaker 5:  they would have a stream video player. And now the new interim CEO,
Speaker 5:  who I suspect will become the permanent CEO Tom Conrad says
Speaker 5:  a push in the video is off the table for now and the team is being reassigned
Speaker 5:  to other projects because they gotta turn around the company. This
Speaker 6:  One's really interesting 'cause I would say clearly the correct call
Speaker 6:  for Sonos, Sonos has had a brutal year. And what
Speaker 6:  it needs more than anything is to get back to proving
Speaker 6:  it can do the thing that it does really well. And so
Speaker 6:  like forgetting everything else and being like, oh, do you remember how we
Speaker 6:  made speakers that you love for 20 years? We're gonna get back to making
Speaker 6:  speakers that you love is the right call.
Speaker 6:  This is a bummer though. Like I think,
Speaker 6:  I wouldn't say I had super high hopes for this thing working the way that
Speaker 6:  Chris in particular has reported that it was gonna work. The,
Speaker 6:  the like all encompassing universal TV guide
Speaker 6:  thing. Really hard to pull off. Sonos has done a really
Speaker 6:  interesting job of trying to bring various voice assistants together
Speaker 6:  over the years and has not really had a ton of success with that. Like
Speaker 6:  I just, I I would've been very curious to see
Speaker 6:  Sonos try this. And I'm a little sad that we're not gonna get to see them
Speaker 6:  try, but I think Tom Conrad is probably right to kill this project.
Speaker 5:  Sonos has a statement in the story. We don't comment on our
Speaker 5:  roadmap, but as been previously announced, we have a longstanding relationship
Speaker 5:  with the Trade Desk, which was the software provider for this
Speaker 5:  rumored stream box. We have a longstanding relationship with the Trade Desk
Speaker 5:  and that relationship continues. W weird, weird statement.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what to make of that. Yeah, maybe there'll be some advertising
Speaker 5:  and other Sonos products, but I agree with you. They need to focus, they
Speaker 5:  need to make that app great. You can see how launching another product to
Speaker 5:  a hostile user base was not a great idea. Also, I think
Speaker 5:  the headphones don't pan out the way they want it to. The, I think they're
Speaker 5:  just, they're just buttoning up.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, and I think if I'm Sonos, the thing to focus on
Speaker 6:  a is obviously software first, but I think Sonos should go out
Speaker 6:  and like rev the headphones and try to make the ace a real
Speaker 6:  hit because I think they could have been like, by all accounts, they're good.
Speaker 6:  They were a little too expensive, they didn't really have a thing, but they're
Speaker 6:  very good headphones. Every time we talk about it, I hear from people who
Speaker 6:  are like, I have the ace and I love them, but because the Ace
Speaker 6:  shipped at the same time as this terrible app, all Goodwill that
Speaker 6:  might've come to the headphones just got eaten alive by the bad stuff that
Speaker 6:  happened with the app. So if I'm Sonos, it's like, okay, this product wasn't
Speaker 6:  a miss this thing we, we weren't wrong about this. We just have to get back
Speaker 6:  to doing this correctly and then go worry about other
Speaker 6:  stuff. But there's like, there's room to go try and do headphones well
Speaker 6:  and successfully before you go try and do video,
Speaker 6:  which is a much more competitive, maybe not more
Speaker 6:  competitive, but also very competitive and very different market.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This dumb feedback on the Ace, I think it's very hard to market
Speaker 5:  headphones. It looks so much like every other headphones.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's right. Like I But but like If you were putting
Speaker 6:  Sonos odds of doing a very good job over time, wouldn't you say it's
Speaker 6:  more likely that Sonos will eventually figure out how to make genuinely great
Speaker 6:  differentiated headphones than a set top box?
Speaker 5:  Yes. But my caveat is I don't think I'm
Speaker 6:  So surprised you even had to think about that.
Speaker 5:  I think it is really, really hard to make genuinely great differentiated
Speaker 5:  headphones when most of those headphones connect to
Speaker 5:  an iPhone. And Apple makes it very, very, very hard to
Speaker 5:  out innovate any of the AirPods products on the iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'll give you that.
Speaker 5:  That's, that was my hesitation is like, yeah, there's a, there's a natural
Speaker 5:  instinctive answer and then there's the reality, which is the TV
Speaker 5:  space is space. There's more opportunity in it. Yeah. It's more of a free
Speaker 5:  for
Speaker 6:  All. Yeah, that's fair. I'll give you I, but like, it's not like TV is a
Speaker 6:  wide open space with easy games to play.
Speaker 5:  Well hopefully they just focus on the speakers. Tom Conrad interim, CEO,
Speaker 5:  who again, I think we all suspect we come to the, the full-time CEO Welcome
Speaker 5:  on these shows. Any anytime you want, Tom. We, we've known Tom forever,
Speaker 5:  so come on. We'll, we'll we'll talk Pandora for a while and then we'll move
Speaker 5:  on to Sonos. How's that? Yeah. Used to anytime used to be at Pandora. All
Speaker 5:  right, it's time. It's time. David.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. America's favorite podcast within a podcast.
Speaker 5:  This one's gonna be wonkier than, than Normal.
Speaker 6:  That is a high bar, my friend.
Speaker 5:  It's time for Brendan Carr's dummy. Everyone, everyone's favorite.
Speaker 5:  So Brendan Carr, as some of you know, I don't know why you're listening to
Speaker 5:  this video now. Brendan Carr is the chairman of the FCC under Donald
Speaker 5:  Trump, a notoriously hostile presence
Speaker 5:  for the First Amendment in freedom of speech in this country. This man wants
Speaker 5:  to regulate speech on every wire and wireless transmission he can
Speaker 5:  get his hands on. It's not subtle and he does it by
Speaker 5:  wrapping himself up in the cloak of defending free speech, which is just
Speaker 5:  pure hypocrisy. I will say this at the top of this segment. I'll say it at
Speaker 5:  the end of the segment. I know Brendan listens to our show. I know he gets
Speaker 5:  Google alerts for his name. I know it. You're welcome.
Speaker 5:  Come on Brendan, come on the show. Try to defend yourself. You won't 'cause
Speaker 5:  you're a coward. But the, we've sent the emails, you've been invited on
Speaker 5:  decoder show up. I'm just, I'm just saying. So this
Speaker 5:  week Brendan,
Speaker 5:  our little man, Brendan sent a letter to YouTube
Speaker 5:  asking if YouTube TV discriminates against faith based programming.
Speaker 5:  And then he on XI have received complaints that Google's YouTube
Speaker 5:  TV is discriminating and it's faith based programming. These concerning
Speaker 5:  allegations come at a time when American Public Discourse has experienced
Speaker 5:  an unprecedented and unacceptable surge in censorship.
Speaker 5:  I am asking Google for answers. So there's like four things that
Speaker 5:  just aren't true in that by using the power of the state
Speaker 5:  to censor Google. Yeah. So this is all based on what appears to be
Speaker 5:  one complaint from one channel,
Speaker 5:  great American family, which apparently is a face based channel.
Speaker 5:  It's distributed on FUBU and slinging on DirecTV Stream on Hulu.
Speaker 5:  Here's the thing about this. You can get
Speaker 5:  some of these, you can get some content from this company on YouTube,
Speaker 5:  right? YouTube is just wide open. You just, you just put stuff on
Speaker 5:  YouTube. People do all the time. They're not on YouTube
Speaker 5:  TV because YouTube TV is a cable company.
Speaker 5:  And to get on YouTube tv, you have to negotiate rates and carriage
Speaker 5:  with YouTube the same way that you would've to negotiate rates and carriage
Speaker 5:  with DirecTV proper, with Comcast,
Speaker 5:  with Spectrum, with any other cable company you can think of.
Speaker 5:  By the way, I should disclose here that Comcast is an investor in rock media,
Speaker 5:  a parent company. I do not have great relationships with cable companies.
Speaker 5:  So take that for what it's worth. But I know how cable companies work
Speaker 5:  and my coverage of them over the past decade has led them to hate me.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, that's about right. That's how it goes. But I do know how they work
Speaker 5:  'cause I've covered them a lot. Here's the thing about, about Brendan Carr.
Speaker 5:  He has no power over YouTube TV zero.
Speaker 5:  He doesn't have power over YouTube either. Even though he keeps fronting
Speaker 5:  like he wants it, he keeps saying he's gonna, he personally will
Speaker 5:  reinterpret section two 30, which he has no authority to do.
Speaker 5:  But he keeps saying it keeps threatening it and now he's threatening YouTube
Speaker 5:  tv. And the lack of power over YouTube TV
Speaker 5:  is actually even more obvious,
Speaker 5:  right? His lack of power over the internet is you have to,
Speaker 5:  you have to jump through a bunch of hoops to explain it, right? You have
Speaker 5:  to say, well, yes, it's a federal communications commission. Yes, they have
Speaker 5:  some authority to regulate wireless services, they
Speaker 5:  allocate spectrum to star, like all this stuff, all this internety stuff.
Speaker 5:  But they don't have the authority to regulate the content on Instagram, which
Speaker 5:  is why it wants to reinterpret section two three, right? You have to like
Speaker 5:  wind your way to it, right? You have a difference. Yes, they regulate the
Speaker 5:  ISPs, but not really 'cause they got rid of net neutrality. Like you have
Speaker 5:  to construct this argument for why he doesn't have the power. But he,
Speaker 5:  the answer is because the FCC gave away the power here. The FCC
Speaker 5:  never had the power before. So If you think about why the FCC regulates cable
Speaker 5:  companies at all, there's a very wonky word for cable companies and satellite
Speaker 5:  companies, MVPs, multiple video programming distributors. I'm sorry,
Speaker 5:  I told you it was gonna get wonky. So the cable companies at the
Speaker 5:  outset, at the very beginning of cable, you had all these people in like
Speaker 5:  rural America who were getting crap network
Speaker 5:  broadcasts at their house. They would put up big antennas and then like,
Speaker 5:  you know, the CBS affiliate from the big city would like kind of come in
Speaker 5:  and it would be bad. So the original cable companies were kind of like
Speaker 5:  renegades, right? They would set up their own big antennas and then
Speaker 5:  run wires to all the houses in these rural areas. And they were basically
Speaker 5:  stealing the signals. And the history of cable is full of these big characters
Speaker 5:  who are basically doing piracy at scale, right? Weird.
Speaker 5:  Like that's just a weird history. And now they're big monopoly monoliths
Speaker 5:  and they hate me. But the history there is kind of like these like
Speaker 5:  Wildcats, like big, big colorful characters
Speaker 5:  setting up like community cable systems. Do you know how sometimes they
Speaker 5:  call cable cat tv? Yeah. Like, do you ever see that on the input on all tv?
Speaker 5:  That's community access television. And that's because is it really? I didn't
Speaker 5:  know that. That's fun fact. And that's because some guys would be like, screw
Speaker 5:  it. We're setting up a big antenna and running wires to everyone's house.
Speaker 5:  So this is where it came from. And the FCC is like, wait,
Speaker 5:  we regulate broadcast. And so the broadcast stations
Speaker 5:  are saying, hold on, you're, you're free writing on us. You're charging people
Speaker 5:  for access to our signals. The FCC gets involved and we end up in
Speaker 5:  this huge system where the FCC manages things. Like who
Speaker 5:  gets to retransmit, what stations, who gets to
Speaker 5:  bundle, what stuff? A big arbitration framework for
Speaker 5:  if some cable network wants to rerun a b, C programming, but A B, C
Speaker 5:  won't give them a license to it unless they pick up like a, B, c family and
Speaker 5:  the Disney channel. Now we have like a weird contract dispute. The FCC manages
Speaker 5:  all that, and that's all built out of these Wildcats basically
Speaker 5:  stealing broadcast signals and running them over wires to people's houses.
Speaker 5:  So you have this whole framework for all this built up. Okay,
Speaker 5:  fine. And that's, so the FCC has some authority over like traditional
Speaker 5:  MVPs, your direct TVs, your dish networks, your cable companies.
Speaker 5:  YouTube is not that. YouTube TV very
Speaker 5:  specifically is not that, right? They're, they're, they're a virtual MVPD,
Speaker 5:  which is a horrible name, but it basically means they're a cloud service,
Speaker 5:  right? So YouTube, the internet. The internet. So YouTube, so YouTube and
Speaker 5:  Google start YouTube tv and they're like, well, If you want to be
Speaker 5:  on our thing that feels like cable, you can be show up at our door. We we'll
Speaker 5:  cut you a deal. And the reason they were so cheap to begin with is they didn't
Speaker 5:  have all of this baggage of the traditional cable companies, right? All these
Speaker 5:  like pre-negotiated deals and they had immediate national
Speaker 5:  distribution, right? They didn't have to dig trenches and set up antennas,
Speaker 5:  right? They were running over the internet, right? So the FCC never had authority
Speaker 5:  over it. Like, it just is not the thing, like
Speaker 5:  there's, there's no part of YouTube TV where they're like capturing
Speaker 5:  signals from the air and rebroadcasting them. And you need this whole retransmission
Speaker 5:  consent regime. This is all like complicated telecom law
Speaker 5:  stuff, right? That no one cared about. 'cause YouTube TV is different and
Speaker 5:  new and they're allowed to pick and choose what channels they put on their
Speaker 5:  cable service the same way that, I don't know, whatever preloaded
Speaker 5:  Samsung fast TV service is allowed to pick and choose whatever
Speaker 5:  channels show up when you turn on Samsung TV for the first time. And that's
Speaker 5:  the market at work, right? In the, in the most direct way that is the free
Speaker 5:  market at work. How, what channels do you get for your 80 bucks a month for
Speaker 5:  YouTube TV that goes up every month is a decision YouTube gets to make in
Speaker 5:  the free market and consumers can decide whether or not to pay for it. So
Speaker 5:  you end up with should great American family
Speaker 5:  be on cable systems? In a time when cable systems were
Speaker 5:  the dominant provider of video services, the FCC
Speaker 5:  had this like interest, it wasn't really played out, it wasn't really flushed
Speaker 5:  out, right? The interest was based on how do people get the broadcast networks,
Speaker 5:  it's the cable systems, are the cable systems running well because they,
Speaker 5:  they're such a monopoly provider of information. The FCC is like, all right,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna make sure the bundles are equal, blah, blah, blah. YouTube is
Speaker 5:  not that. YouTube operates in the YouTube TV operates in the, the biggest,
Speaker 5:  most vibrant market of video programming services that has ever existed
Speaker 5:  in world history. If you want great American family, you know what you can
Speaker 5:  do? You can leave YouTube TV and sign up for fubu, any of
Speaker 6:  The other ones
Speaker 5:  Like that, right? Like in one second on your phone, you can just do it.
Speaker 5:  You can sign up for Sling or Hulu. You can maybe pay them directly.
Speaker 5:  There's no, there's no plausible interest for the
Speaker 5:  United States government to regulate the market in this case. And what
Speaker 5:  makes it particularly galling is at the same, in
Speaker 5:  the same breath, Brendan Carr is saying, list
Speaker 5:  every regulation I should remove. So the market is more vibrant. You know
Speaker 5:  what regulation you should remove Brendan yourself, you should
Speaker 5:  stop meddling in the free market of information on the
Speaker 5:  internet. You should go away.
Speaker 6:  Well, and he's not even pretending in any meaningful way that this is about
Speaker 6:  free markets, it's just about speech. Yeah. Like the whole YouTube
Speaker 6:  TV thing is not, he's not accusing YouTube TV of being a monopoly or
Speaker 6:  abusing its power against, its just pure censorship discussion.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He's, he wants to put pressure on Google to moderate YouTube,
Speaker 5:  like big YouTube the way that he wants. And so the way he's gonna do that
Speaker 5:  is by saying Google is unfairly discriminating against its faith based programming
Speaker 5:  on YouTube TV over which he has zero and I mean
Speaker 5:  truly zero authority, right? In a way that it is
Speaker 5:  easier to make an argument that he has authority over the internet. I
Speaker 5:  don't, he doesn't. But it is actually easier to make that argument
Speaker 5:  because he had, he could in another world, would have had
Speaker 5:  authority over the ISPs. But YouTube TV is a thing that
Speaker 5:  exists outside of the f SEC's, historic frameworks for
Speaker 5:  how cable companies are regulated in a way that he, he should, and there's
Speaker 5:  competition, right? Like you, you can just get Comcast,
Speaker 5:  dude, like, it, it exists. Like it's there, it's right there for consumers.
Speaker 5:  If they want these channels, they can switch away from YouTube tv. And if
Speaker 5:  there exists any of that market competition, it is completely
Speaker 5:  inappropriate for the government to step in and say, I want information,
Speaker 5:  I want you to answer to me. Especially at the same time where
Speaker 5:  it just, in like in a different tweet, he's like, what regulations do I need
Speaker 5:  to get rid of to make the market more competitive?
Speaker 6:  Fire yourself.
Speaker 5:  Like I, it's just, it is, it is the most blinding
Speaker 5:  hypocrisy from this fan week in and week out, and all of it is
Speaker 5:  incoherent and all of it only serves to increase his
Speaker 5:  own power as opposed to making the markets more efficient, to making the
Speaker 5:  networks more trusted. That would be a, that, that's a good goal, right?
Speaker 5:  You want more Americans to perceive that the information networks that they
Speaker 5:  exist in are unbiased or delivering more fair or accurate information. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Or that the processes by which content is taken down or removed or has
Speaker 5:  fuddled are fair and understandable. Like those are all good things,
Speaker 5:  but he's just about power. And you can see it in the course of two tweets.
Speaker 5:  He's like, I'm demanding this private company over which I have no authority
Speaker 5:  answer to me. Also, I think the market should be more open and have less
Speaker 5:  regulation. Well, dude, solve your problem. Get rid of yourself, or come
Speaker 5:  on decoder, I'll fire you on decoder.
Speaker 6:  I will say I really enjoyed, I very rarely enjoy a company
Speaker 6:  response to something. But this one I very much enjoyed from
Speaker 6:  Audrey Lopez at YouTube who said, we welcome the opportunity to brief the
Speaker 6:  f CCC on YouTube TV's subscription service and the strategic business decisions
Speaker 6:  we make, we make based on factors like user demand, operational costs, and
Speaker 6:  financial terms that a bunch of other stuff, which is just a long way of
Speaker 6:  saying we don't have this because no one wants it.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 6:  If, if there were a market reason for us to have this channel, we'd have
Speaker 6:  this channel. I mean, this is like every time we get a carriage dispute,
Speaker 6:  right? Like I find carriage disputes really fascinating for exactly this
Speaker 6:  reason, because it is purely about a company
Speaker 6:  with content that people want trying to get a
Speaker 6:  distributor to pay as much as possible for it. And the distributor, it's
Speaker 6:  like perfect supply and demand economic bargaining. And I find
Speaker 6:  it so fascinating. And in this case, like it's actually just YouTube is like,
Speaker 6:  no one wants this and we'd have to pay them for it. Why would we pay them
Speaker 6:  for it? Yeah. It's just that simple.
Speaker 5:  And it's funny 'cause in a different, if I described to you how cable company
Speaker 5:  negotiations work up at the FCC, I think most of our younger
Speaker 5:  listeners or viewers on YouTube would be utterly perplexed
Speaker 5:  that the government is involved. Yeah. Right? That they're o there used to
Speaker 5:  only be three major broadcast networks the entire country and people set
Speaker 5:  up antennas, and then when the cable company showed up, the government showed
Speaker 5:  up and said, you have to carry the broadcast networks.
Speaker 5:  Weird. That's just a weird thing that's embedded in the history of our telecom
Speaker 5:  law, that we have these things called must carry provisions. And because
Speaker 5:  of the must carry provisions, the broadcast networks can get bigger and have
Speaker 5:  more channels and demand other channels get carried by these cable companies.
Speaker 5:  And you end up in this situation where the United States government is resolving
Speaker 5:  a dispute about the tennis channel. This is a real thing
Speaker 5:  that happened. That's
Speaker 6:  Awesome.
Speaker 5:  And that just doesn't happen on the internet.
Speaker 6:  I do think everyone should be required to watch tennis. So I'm, I'm, I'm
Speaker 6:  actually good with
Speaker 5:  That one. But you just, you see that kind of stuff play out in the history
Speaker 5:  of telecom because there was so much scarcity, right? So the government had
Speaker 5:  this interest in saying, okay, we've, we've got these three big national
Speaker 5:  broadcast networks, we know they touch everyone in the country. The cable
Speaker 5:  companies have to carry them, right? That's a lot. Like, that's a big
Speaker 5:  step into what the government says about the information you receive.
Speaker 5:  And that made sense in the, in the previous era. It makes no sense in the
Speaker 5:  modern era. And I, I think most people, if, if we showed up and said
Speaker 5:  to YouTube, you have to carry Mr. Beast. Like most people
Speaker 5:  are like, what are you talking about? Right? Like, that doesn't make any
Speaker 5:  sense. Right. You can go, I just see Brendan trying to bring us back to that
Speaker 5:  era, but doing it incoherently and without any
Speaker 5:  point except his own power. Yep. So like I said, Brendan, I know you listen,
Speaker 5:  I know you're gonna get the Google alerts. Here's one for you Brendan. Brendan
Speaker 5:  Carr is a coward. That's just the thing I say on the show every week. You
Speaker 5:  can come onto coder, you can defend this stuff. You can try to make it make
Speaker 5:  sense. I'll give you the shot. I, I'm just well prepared
Speaker 5:  and I know you so good luck. But you're welcome anytime you want.
Speaker 5:  All right. We we got a, we need a, we need a pal Clean David.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All right. I have, I have three more for you and then we're gonna get
Speaker 6:  outta here. Yeah. Thing number one, TikTok did a
Speaker 6:  thing I think is sort of interesting, which is everybody is forever
Speaker 6:  trying to come up with ways to like make their platforms less
Speaker 6:  horrible for teenagers. And basically TikTok now
Speaker 6:  has a sort of, it's a parental control thing that essentially
Speaker 6:  starts to wind you down off of TikTok starting at 10:00
Speaker 6:  PM So it gives teens a reminder that's basically like it's late get off and
Speaker 6:  then starts to play you out. Essentially. It's like the Oscar's music where
Speaker 6:  it just like plays you off the stage of TikTok. I think this is a great idea
Speaker 6:  and I think this is a thing that I would also, like for me, an adult who
Speaker 6:  should not be looking at TikTok after 10:00 PM but I think,
Speaker 6:  like, I've been talking to a lot of people about the, the sort
Speaker 6:  of regulatory environment about this stuff for years. And Lauren Finer does
Speaker 6:  a really good job of covering a lot of that stuff for us and
Speaker 6:  watching all of these platforms, just like flail to figure out features
Speaker 6:  to make themselves a slightly better experience, especially for young
Speaker 6:  users, is just really complicated and really interesting. And I actually
Speaker 6:  think this is like a smart idea from TikTok that it's just like, we're just
Speaker 6:  going to make it harder and harder for you to use this app because you should
Speaker 6:  go to bed.
Speaker 5:  It's time for bed. Totally hard,
Speaker 6:  Not totally hard, but harder. And I'll, I'll take that.
Speaker 5:  I think a lot of parents would accept the hard 10:00 PM curfew on, on
Speaker 5:  a TikTok account
Speaker 6:  Probably.
Speaker 5:  But Casey Newton had this great line about TikTok this week, writing
Speaker 5:  about this. He said, TikTok is now in quantum super positioned,
Speaker 5:  there's a TikTok that's illegal. That's
Speaker 6:  Good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then there's a TikTok that exists in is shipping features for teens in
Speaker 5:  America.
Speaker 6:  I would say, I forget about the TikTok band like every three days, you know
Speaker 6:  what I mean? Yeah. It's like I just, I just sort of look around and I'm like,
Speaker 6:  oh, right. TikTok iss gonna get banned. Like it's
Speaker 5:  Banned. It's well, it's banned.
Speaker 6:  That's true. It's technically
Speaker 5:  Banned. The laws passed. Yeah. The Supreme Court said it was constitutional.
Speaker 5:  Donald Trump is just not enforcing it.
Speaker 6:  I know we've talked about this already, but the, the first week of April
Speaker 6:  when all the tariff stuff comes crashing back down and the TikTok ban
Speaker 6:  delay ends is like, it's gonna be weird times in America.
Speaker 6:  We might not, the government might be closed by the, like, who stuff's gonna
Speaker 6:  get real weird here. Thing number two that I just think is really interesting
Speaker 6:  is Niantic, the company that makes Pokemon Go and a bunch of other
Speaker 6:  stuff sold all of its gaming business to Scopely,
Speaker 6:  which is a like old social gaming company that I think is now owned by
Speaker 6:  some Saudi government company thing that
Speaker 6:  I don't pretend to totally understand, but I, I just have been
Speaker 6:  obsessed with Niantic for like years. Pokemon Go, I think remains like the
Speaker 6:  most interesting ar experiment anyone has done yet and was a huge
Speaker 6:  giant hit. And then they tried to do it a bunch more times and none of it
Speaker 6:  worked. Yeah. No one cared. There was like the Harry Potter game that people
Speaker 6:  were really excited about. There was the, the one with the characters with
Speaker 6:  the flowers coming outta their head that I can't remember the name of, but
Speaker 6:  like Niantic was like way out in front of this idea of like, what, how do
Speaker 6:  we make stuff that is fun on top of the real world and just never,
Speaker 6:  it turns out it was just Pokemon and they just never, they just never found
Speaker 6:  the next thing.
Speaker 5:  Well, they never found the next thing and they never figured out what to
Speaker 5:  do with the enormous amount of data they collected from all those PokemonGo
Speaker 5:  users. Like Right. Nantec was building a world map and they were clever
Speaker 5:  to the point where if they found a place where they didn't have
Speaker 5:  sufficient data, they would put Pokemon there and then people
Speaker 5:  would go and map that location. And I don't think that anyone figured out
Speaker 5:  what that was for. Like it was very clever, like in that way it's like, do
Speaker 5:  you know Go is secretly data collection? And it's like, yes, what's gonna
Speaker 5:  happen? And
Speaker 6:  There's some of that stuff. Niantic still owns some of that. Yeah. Like it,
Speaker 6:  it kept a couple of its games and a bunch of the mapping stuff. So
Speaker 6:  it's the Yeah. The thing they've been saying, which is basically where like
Speaker 6:  building an ar map of the world is now their
Speaker 6:  only move left, which is really interesting. Like I, there was a
Speaker 6:  Pokemon Go was just like floated forever until they figured out the next
Speaker 6:  thing and now they like really have to go figure out this next thing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I, I don't know what it's gonna be, but we'll see. All right. I have
Speaker 6:  one more for you. Well, I have one and a half. Okay.
Speaker 6:  The one
Speaker 6:  is that home assistant now supports matter, and I know this is big for you,
Speaker 6:  so I just wanted to give you a moment. I'm very this, to really talk about
Speaker 6:  this.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's certified. They, I think it was, it was like
Speaker 5:  not officially supported before. I mean that's basically what Paul was telling
Speaker 5:  us and he said it's now officially supported. The certification was
Speaker 5:  complicated. It's a cherry on the cake. That's the quote.
Speaker 5:  This is good. I I have a home assistant green box now just sitting here.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm thinking about swapping out my home bridge for home assistant only
Speaker 5:  because we have these very complicated smart vents that open
Speaker 5:  and close to try to make all the rooms in the house the same temperature.
Speaker 5:  It's like the podcast studio I'm sitting here isn't, is in our attic. So
Speaker 5:  in the winter it's very cold up here, but I don't wanna run the heat and
Speaker 5:  burn out the family. So we have these vents that open and close and home
Speaker 5:  assistant can run them locally instead of going to the cloud.
Speaker 6:  Oh, all right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, none of this has anything to do with matter. I'm just saying you can
Speaker 5:  see how Home Assistant is like, there's a server in my house that runs everything.
Speaker 5:  Having official matter integration, that's all of that stuff run locally
Speaker 5:  and I think that's cool, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Home assistant continues to be
Speaker 6:  more impressive, I think, than I gave it credit for for a long time. I was
Speaker 6:  always like, home assistant is like the raspberry pie of the smart home world.
Speaker 6:  It's like, it's a thing for people who want to tinker and that's about it.
Speaker 6:  And they're like pushing further and further down into just like, put this
Speaker 6:  in your house, that'll be fine. I think that's pretty
Speaker 5:  Powerful. You wanna, I I I, we talked about Amazon and
Speaker 5:  Apple and all their smart home stuff and on AI stuff and a all of that kind
Speaker 5:  of requires you just believe that those services will run in the cloud and
Speaker 5:  be reliable for you, right. For a long time. And home assistance. Like what
Speaker 5:  If you just had a computer in your house that was there?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That just only did those things. Yeah. Yeah. I'm into that.
Speaker 6:  And then last one, did you see Jay Grabber's t-shirt? I
Speaker 6:  truly the greatest thing that happened all week
Speaker 5:  And now that I think Blue Sky's gonna sell it. So Zuckerberg wore a shirt
Speaker 5:  at Meta Connect, right? That said,
Speaker 6:  I believe so. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It said Zucker nothing in Latin. And so Jay Grabber's shirt at at South
Speaker 5:  by Southwest said, man C which mean a world without Caesars.
Speaker 5:  And now they are fully selling that shirt.
Speaker 6:  Spectacular. I have no notes. They were giving away stickers. I think that
Speaker 6:  said the same thing at South By Extremely Good
Speaker 5:  Is good. We're still working at Feder years. It's very complicated.
Speaker 5:  Accepting the fire hose of incoming social media content.
Speaker 5:  If you federate a quick post,
Speaker 5:  it's not small. It turns out turning your, your website into a social network
Speaker 5:  moderation challenge is abound. Yeah, but we're we're, we are still focused
Speaker 5:  on it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There's something that And Blue Sky One, I will say one deeply fascinating
Speaker 6:  thing that happened this week was X had a huge outage
Speaker 6:  and everybody went to Blue Sky. Yeah. Like all the, it was
Speaker 6:  X went down right as NFL Free Agency started, and it just
Speaker 6:  like that flipped to Blue Sky. And I thought that was so interesting that
Speaker 6:  like my threads did not get more exciting, but all of a sudden, like a million
Speaker 6:  sports reporters I know were just appearing in Blue Sky.
Speaker 6:  And Mina Kimes, who works at ESPN, had this like starter pack of
Speaker 6:  blue sky sports people and that blew up. And it was like, yet another, like
Speaker 6:  Blue Sky has, has the juice kind of moments that it's like every time X gets
Speaker 6:  a little worse, blue sky gets a little better and X gets a little worse a
Speaker 6:  lot. And so it was, it was just another one that
Speaker 6:  it's like Blue sky's. Blue Sky's for real.
Speaker 5:  All right. Can I add one? It it's Trump related, but in the funniest way.
Speaker 6:  All right. I'll allow,
Speaker 5:  Mia wrote about this this week. There's a Trump official
Speaker 5:  ibel, I believe in one of the offices that's firing everybody, like in the
Speaker 5:  Office of Personal Management. She is also a very, very bad
Speaker 5:  fashion influencer. And she's been doing Get Ready with me
Speaker 5:  in the Office while she's firing people.
Speaker 5:  It's very bad, but like very bad in a way that is just
Speaker 5:  indicative of how everything else is bad.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. She's like, I need, she needs a side hustle too. She's like, I don't
Speaker 6:  know, maybe I'm gonna get fired by Doge one of these days, so I gotta got
Speaker 6:  outta side hustle. But it's very good. It's, it's pretty bad. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  Pretty bad. And Mia's Post is, is scathing and, and the best,
Speaker 5:  in the best possible VERGE way. So I encourage people to read.
Speaker 6:  This is the thing that I saw somebody just like posted a link in Slack and
Speaker 6:  it was like, you, you could tell the, like the Mia Siren had just been activated
Speaker 6:  and Mia just came in and was like, I know what to do with this. That's
Speaker 6:  good stuff.
Speaker 5:  M had a great line. She referred to her outfits as Sears catalog esque.
Speaker 5:  Oof. It's rough. Brutal. That's rough. Every
Speaker 5:  now and in our policy desk just let's, let's let's it out and you can see
Speaker 5:  it. All right. That's it. We've gone way over. This episode's been six hours
Speaker 5:  long. I think I was in a fugue state talking to Brendan car this week. That
Speaker 5:  was yesterday. That's
Speaker 6:  What the people come for.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's what we saw here. Brendan, you're you're welcome. Anytime.
Speaker 5:  Thank you to Andy. Poor Andy. Every time I talk to him lately I'm like, so
Speaker 5:  what disaster are we talking about? Thanks Andy, for coming on.
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's for Cast Rockwell.
Speaker 7:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 7:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE
Speaker 7:  one one. The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media
Speaker 7:  podcast network. Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and
Speaker 7:  Brandon Keefer. And that's it. We'll see you next week.