# Transcript
ID: 31fd9058-9660-4c8b-9ea3-bdb6e0a086fa
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6150230017640525447/148791137480120837/s93290-US-6563s-1739749996.mp3
Description: On today's episode, once again, it's OpenAI and DOGE. And some other things! Nilay and David start the show by talking about Elon Musk's surprise bid to buy the nonprofit arm of OpenAI, along with the company's plans for new models and new rules for those models. After that, The Verge's Lauren Feiner joins to catch us up on what's happening with DOGE, how Musk and co. are making boring government information into something deeply fascinating and deeply confusing, and what it's like to work for the government now. Finally, in the lightning round, we talk about rumors of a new Apple Studio Display and iPhone SE, the new Powerbeats 2 Pro, Brendan Carr still being a dummy, and some surprising streaming moves from Apple and YouTube.
Speaker 7:  Hello and welcome to the NCH Chest, the flagship podcast of government WordPress
Speaker 7:  templates.
Speaker 7:  The best kind, so transparent.
Speaker 7:  It's really just a lot of PNGs, the government WordPress
Speaker 8:  Templates. I've built a WordPress website in my life before and it is the,
Speaker 8:  the thing where you just start with a bunch of like nonsensical business
Speaker 8:  words and then you fill it with your own nonsensical business. Words is,
Speaker 8:  it's a, it's a time.
Speaker 7:  The thing you're missing, David, is now when you do that
Speaker 7:  and AI will write the nonsensical business words,
Speaker 7:  I'm not even kidding. Like this is the product that most of the website builders
Speaker 7:  are now saying. You just like show up and you're like, I'm a yoga studio.
Speaker 7:  And they're like, here's a website. It might describe your business or it
Speaker 7:  might not, but at least it's here. And then you're supposed to run your
Speaker 7:  scheduling. Hi, I'm your friend Neil. I, David Pierce is here. Hello. We're
Speaker 7:  here to build
Speaker 8:  Your WordPress websites. That's what we do. Now,
Speaker 7:  Honestly, it might be a more sustainable business in journalism. Like where,
Speaker 7:  where are the highest chances of going to jail in America right now?
Speaker 7:  Like used to be zero, being the editor in chief of The Verge was a 0%
Speaker 7:  chance of going to jail. Me personally, just like doing the
Speaker 7:  stuff I do, slightly higher than Zero, but, you know, regular
Speaker 7:  editor of tech website, zero 0% I think Chance of Gonna Jail. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Operating a WordPress template business 0%. The
Speaker 7:  thing that's really, I think, interesting now is that it's
Speaker 7:  non-zero. It's like being the, like you, like, oh,
Speaker 7:  maybe Brendan Carl will arrest me and I hope you do Brendan, if you're listen,
Speaker 7:  and I know you do. I know you got those Google alerts. Boy,
Speaker 8:  No, we, the thing is neli for for good engagement purposes, we save Brendan
Speaker 8:  till the end so that Brendan has to listen to the whole podcast to get to
Speaker 8:  the part that's about Brendan. That's true.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna put his name in the headline, but you have to listen to the whole
Speaker 7:  thing.
Speaker 8:  Exactly right.
Speaker 7:  Anyhow, there's a lot going on this week. There's some politics. We'll get
Speaker 7:  to that. There's a weird situation going on with open ai. There's some
Speaker 7:  gadget news. There's a good old fashioned programming dispute
Speaker 7:  between CBS and YouTube tv old school.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Man,
Speaker 7:  Buzzfeed is starting a social network to combat something called snf.
Speaker 7:  I need to complain about Jeep as a company. I'm very excited
Speaker 7:  to do
Speaker 8:  That. I feel like everything you just described could have been the introduction
Speaker 8:  to like an End Gadget show from 2007. Like has
Speaker 8:  anything changed?
Speaker 7:  Has changed? No. So except slightly
Speaker 7:  higher chance of going to jail for doing a show
Speaker 8:  Fair. Yeah. You never know. What's the, so the, the Go 90 scale of Doom
Speaker 8:  streaming services is, is good. Is it like the Theranos scale of
Speaker 8:  going to jail
Speaker 8:  if you're, if you're at a 90 year Theranos?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, she gave a interview to like People Magazine this week.
Speaker 7:  Elizabeth Holmes gave an interview at People Magazine this week where she
Speaker 7:  was like, you know, it wasn't fraud, it was just a failure. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  no, Elizabeth, you are giving this interview from jail. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  because it was fraud. I don't know what to tell you. Like you can't argue
Speaker 7:  that anymore when you're on the phone in the
Speaker 7:  jail Anyhow, but I, yeah, it's the, the, the Theranos scale of whether or
Speaker 7:  not Neil AI goes to jail. The Bren, the Brennan car units,
Speaker 8:  Carville, oh, car units. That's good. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Scovilles. No, that's Peppers. It's been a long week, everybody.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we're gonna get through it. Okay. Let's start with open ai. There's
Speaker 7:  some weird stuff going on with OpenAI. Of course it involves Elon Musk because
Speaker 7:  what news story does not involve Elon Musk in this
Speaker 7:  2025, but this one is just pettier all the
Speaker 7:  way around. So OpenAI is, I think we all understand it
Speaker 7:  started as this nonprofit. Elon was a co-founder,
Speaker 7:  many things. He's no longer a co-founder. He is obviously beefing with the
Speaker 7:  company. He appears to be a little bit jealous of Sam Altman. Sam
Speaker 7:  got fired, he came back inside of a week. Now he wants to convert opening
Speaker 7:  AI from a nonprofit to a for-profit company, which is a very complicated
Speaker 7:  legal maneuver. And he's got basically Excel, the
Speaker 7:  nonprofit. There's a lot there. And so Elon Musk,
Speaker 7:  in order to just screw with this process, has put together an offer to buy
Speaker 7:  OpenAI for $97.4 billion.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Do you think that's real?
Speaker 8:  I mean, no, but also,
Speaker 8:  yes. Right. Like, I think a,
Speaker 8:  that would be a terrific deal for Elon Musk if he could
Speaker 8:  get that deal right? It, it, it, it both wins you a battle
Speaker 8:  with one of your enemies and gets you like an actually hugely
Speaker 8:  important AI thing in, in the world.
Speaker 8:  So I think in that sense, do I think he could gin up the money and do I think
Speaker 8:  he would do it if Sam Altman had said, yes, I'll sell. Yes.
Speaker 8:  I think Elon Musk's ability to raise that much money, I think is pretty much
Speaker 8:  beyond question at this point. X AI has a huge
Speaker 8:  amount of money and a huge amount of support and is is like suddenly flush
Speaker 8:  with everything it could possibly need. So yeah, I think if, if
Speaker 8:  everybody was in on this deal, they'd do it. I also think Elon Musk
Speaker 8:  and this group made this bid,
Speaker 8:  obviously knowing it wasn't gonna work. Like there's just no world
Speaker 8:  in which Sam Altman says yes to this deal, and it goes through,
Speaker 8:  it's not a public company, so you can't even like pressure shareholders and
Speaker 8:  go that way to get it done the way he tried to do it Twitter,
Speaker 8:  there's just no way this was ever gonna happen. So I think that a deal like
Speaker 8:  this can be both real and not real, and I think it very much was.
Speaker 7:  Well, so there are not public shareholders, but he does have
Speaker 7:  co-investors and sure, Microsoft has a big stake in OpenAI
Speaker 7:  that for-profit company, not the non-profit. It's all
Speaker 7:  very complicated,
Speaker 8:  Right? And all those investors have a lot of reasons to want to make it easier
Speaker 8:  for OpenAI to convert to being a for-profit company because they all want
Speaker 8:  to be able to get money in and out of that company. So in that sense, you,
Speaker 8:  you could argue there are maybe people who would have a reason to say yes
Speaker 8:  to this maybe.
Speaker 7:  And certainly because Elon has promised to
Speaker 7:  match or exceed any other offer they get. The board of
Speaker 7:  OpenAI has some amount of fiduciary duty to, to go get
Speaker 7:  the best deal, the biggest amount of money. But Sam Altman has pretty much
Speaker 7:  said no. And then here's the weird thing. He told open AI's
Speaker 7:  employees that they have yet to receive the formal offer from Elon
Speaker 7:  Musk. Right. Which is very funny. Like these guys are
Speaker 7:  literally tweeting at each other all day long. Like he knows people
Speaker 8:  Can just say things like, again, I I just wanna keep reminding you. People
Speaker 8:  can just say things and I think Elon Musk is pretty good at
Speaker 8:  saying things louder and with more paperwork than most,
Speaker 8:  but in many ways he's still just saying things.
Speaker 7:  So then here's another added layer of complexity to that. Elon is currently
Speaker 7:  suing OpenAI, right? Because he's mad at them and he thinks that he should
Speaker 7:  get paid because he was around. And I literally, I mean that
Speaker 7:  literally in that he never had a contract. And in classic Elon fashion,
Speaker 7:  he's suing OpenAI and saying a bunch of stuff that he said in text
Speaker 7:  messages constitutes a contract, right? Elon gets in
Speaker 7:  trouble suing over fake contracts a lot. Actually, part of the
Speaker 7:  Twitter litigation was like some fake contracts. The OpenAI case
Speaker 7:  is like very much, there's no real contract here. So he
Speaker 7:  is in the middle of this lawsuit with, he's almost certainly gonna lose because
Speaker 7:  there's no actual contract. You can't sue for breach of contract without
Speaker 7:  a contract. It's very hard to do, especially when you're a quote like sophisticated
Speaker 7:  actor. Like courts are like, no, you're the richest man in the world. Get
Speaker 7:  a, get a contract.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, you should know how to do this.
Speaker 7:  So that, I don't know how that one's gonna go, but all signs say it should
Speaker 7:  go poorly for Elon. So part of the reason I think he's making this offer
Speaker 7:  is to screw with Sam Altman, screw with OpenAI, but also put some pressure
Speaker 7:  on this other case. It's pretty hard though to buy a company that you are
Speaker 7:  suing in this way without settling the lawsuit. So
Speaker 7:  Altman is saying, I haven't even received this offer. And sort of the
Speaker 7:  response from the Elon side is, of course you haven't. It's because we're
Speaker 7:  suing you and so we're, we, we are not supposed to talk to you.
Speaker 7:  This is all very funny because they, these people are constantly tweeting
Speaker 7:  each other, like they're, they're always talking to each other.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 7:  But like, that's the formal response. And so here Mark Tober
Speaker 7:  off, who is Elon's lawyer, sent us the following statement,
Speaker 7:  clarifying the timeline. It's a good statement
Speaker 7:  in that it is very formal and it definitely sounds like a wizard
Speaker 7:  doing an incantation on behalf of a Musk led investment
Speaker 7:  consortium on Monday, February
Speaker 7:  10th, 2025 at 12:27 PM Pacific Time, David. Okay,
Speaker 8:  Sure.
Speaker 7:  It's very important to the minute 3 27
Speaker 8:  Eastern. If you're counting,
Speaker 7:  I summoned the clouds. I emailed the OpenAI bid to their
Speaker 7:  outside counsel, William and Sarah, that's,
Speaker 7:  those are names I, the full names are here for transmission to their client.
Speaker 7:  The bid attached to my email was in the form of a detailed four
Speaker 7:  page letter of intent signed by Elon Musk and each of the other
Speaker 7:  investors addressed to the charity's board of directors to purchase
Speaker 7:  OpenAI inks and assets for 97.375
Speaker 7:  billion. Whether Sam Altman chose to provide or withhold this from
Speaker 7:  open AI's other board members is outside of our control. Now. It's
Speaker 7:  like, you know, the rest of the board members know because Elon is
Speaker 7:  tweeting about it,
Speaker 8:  Right? It was, it was in the Wall Street Journal.
Speaker 7:  Like the, the formalities of this are like deeply hilarious. Like you think
Speaker 7:  Brett Taylor, who's on the board of OpenAI, who was the chairman of the board
Speaker 7:  of Twitter when Elon bought Twitter, wasn't like, Sam, can I see the letter?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean I think everyone involved in this kind of understands how these
Speaker 8:  things go at this point.
Speaker 8:  Is it possible that there's just a gambit here
Speaker 8:  for Elon to get some kind of, I don't know, check and
Speaker 8:  fawning post from Sam about his role in open AI and then everyone moves
Speaker 8:  on with their lives. Like, I just keep thinking about all of these
Speaker 8:  Trump lawsuits that are clearly just gambits to get a check.
Speaker 8:  Like, is that, is that just what this is? Elon is like, you can make all
Speaker 8:  of this go away. Just write me a check and a loving blog post on your
Speaker 8:  website about how terrific I am and how open eye wouldn't exist without me.
Speaker 8:  Like is that all this is
Speaker 7:  No. 'cause they're competitors now. They're certainly competitors for like
Speaker 7:  Trump's affection. Like Sam got the Donald
Speaker 7:  Trump stands next to me. Well, I say nonsensical things about my $500 billion
Speaker 7:  data center plan. Sure. Before Elon did, you
Speaker 7:  know? Yeah. Like it's that level of petty between these two guys. Oh yeah.
Speaker 7:  To the point where Elon said the offer and then
Speaker 7:  Sam tweeted, no thank you, but we will buy Twitter for $9.74 billion
Speaker 7:  If you want. Which is very good. Which is good burn. Also, again, evidence
Speaker 7:  that they are talking to each other. And then Sam
Speaker 7:  Altman was on Bloomberg television and they asked him about
Speaker 7:  the deal or the proposed deal and he said, Elon tries all sorts of things.
Speaker 7:  This is just this week's episode. And then quote, probably his whole
Speaker 7:  life is a, from a position of insecurity, I feel for the
Speaker 7:  guy, I don't think he's a happy person. I feel for him.
Speaker 7:  Which is just a lot.
Speaker 8:  That's brutal. I think, I mean a
Speaker 8:  Sam Altman is in a position to know of what he speaks in
Speaker 8:  that particular way, but also that is, that is
Speaker 8:  brutal. The, like these two men are, are as, are as beefing as
Speaker 8:  anybody in the tech world right now. Yeah. In a really fascinating way.
Speaker 8:  And I think I, I, again, this all this is all very
Speaker 8:  real and fake and ridiculous at the same time. And I, I, I have
Speaker 8:  continual trouble to understand what to make of deals
Speaker 8:  like this and spats like this between Elon Musk
Speaker 8:  and anybody because he has the resources to make this stuff
Speaker 8:  stick even when it's not real. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  He'll run it to ground no matter what. He's a troll. I mean, we, we know
Speaker 7:  this much. I think even If you love Elon Musk, whether or not he's a troll
Speaker 7:  is well settled. Yeah. You might love it or you might hate it, but is he
Speaker 7:  a troll? Yes. He's a troll and he is a well-resourced troll can just keep
Speaker 7:  this lawsuit going for as long as he wants to. Right. I think what all
Speaker 7:  this is evidence of is that OpenAI is in an extraordinarily weak
Speaker 7:  position overall. Right. And they, what we'll talk about their product plans.
Speaker 7:  'cause they laid out some product plans, they're gonna clean up their models.
Speaker 7:  They're, they're thinking about expanding different ways. But you look at
Speaker 7:  this company, which a few years ago kicked off this modern generative
Speaker 7:  AI boom Yeah. Sort of by accident and their financials aren't there.
Speaker 7:  Right. They, they're losing money on every customer that
Speaker 7:  they have. Basically their models aren't
Speaker 7:  the cutting edge models like they are, but they aren't like, there's lots
Speaker 7:  of competition now and the models are specializing. Being the model
Speaker 7:  vendor is not like the great business. It's the
Speaker 7:  product that uses the model, but might be the great business. And even that's
Speaker 7:  unclear. And then they're training their next models, which is very expensive
Speaker 7:  and they're trying to raise all this money while the whole AI
Speaker 7:  field feels like it's commoditizing.
Speaker 7:  Right. Not all the way. And certainly they still have some opportunity,
Speaker 7:  but you know, i I, the products that are
Speaker 7:  being built using the generative AI models in particular,
Speaker 7:  they, it, you're, they're differentiating on the front end of like, what
Speaker 7:  is this product not on the back end of how capable is this model
Speaker 7:  and open a has but one great product, which is
Speaker 8:  Tt Right. And I think even to the extent that they're not
Speaker 8:  commoditize, like I think they're, they're commoditizing like
Speaker 8:  parentheses complimentary, you know what I mean? Like they're commoditizing
Speaker 8:  in the way that like cloud services are commoditizing in the way that there
Speaker 8:  is a ton of money in it. They are massive earth
Speaker 8:  shatteringly profitable businesses for the cloud companies, but there
Speaker 8:  is nothing remotely sexy about it. And there
Speaker 8:  really aren't super compelling moats. And so we were, we were in this
Speaker 8:  like cloud services land grab for a while because like switching is kind
Speaker 8:  of annoying. So everybody was just like, how do we get more customers? That's
Speaker 8:  where we are with a lot of this AI stuff. Like we, we got a lot of feedback
Speaker 8:  from the episodes that we've done about like, there's no real utility for
Speaker 8:  this. People like, it's just infrastructure. And it's like Sure. A infrastructure
Speaker 8:  for what? And b, infrastructure is not
Speaker 8:  a product. Right? Yeah. And so I think what your point is, is like there's
Speaker 8:  a, there's a world at the end of this where there is a lot of money in this
Speaker 8:  for some large handful of companies. OpenAI
Speaker 8:  probably being one of them. But that is different
Speaker 8:  from being the kind of like face of the tech
Speaker 8:  industry business that OpenAI thinks it can be. You eventually just
Speaker 8:  be, you become a SaaS provider, right? Like you're a, you're a data center
Speaker 8:  company at the end of this. If you're a company like OpenAI and
Speaker 8:  Anthropic is doing very well. And I think there, there's this really great
Speaker 8:  like leaderboard where you can see basically whose tokens are
Speaker 8:  being used for what. And you look at some of the practical stuff, like for
Speaker 8:  coding, people are flocking to Claude and Anthropic in a, in a way
Speaker 8:  that is really dangerous if you're open ai. And so, like, I don't think
Speaker 8:  open AI is like at risk of going away. It will eventually, I think figure
Speaker 8:  out how to lose less money on every one of these and that'll be good. And
Speaker 8:  they'll raise enough money that it won't matter for a long time anyway. But
Speaker 8:  like this thing that they built with chat GPT where it
Speaker 8:  was like Sam Altman is the face of AI in a, in a real way
Speaker 8:  and has been for years. And that makes you incredibly powerful and it lets
Speaker 8:  you stand next to Trump and announce a $500 billion
Speaker 8:  joint venture to build infrastructure. That's the
Speaker 8:  thing that I think this company risks losing is
Speaker 8:  like if it's, if it's not sexy, it's just another SaaS company.
Speaker 7:  Let me make an even more bearish case though. Okay. Because I think the risk
Speaker 7:  is open act collapses.
Speaker 7:  I'm not saying it's a hundred percent risk. I'm not even making the prediction.
Speaker 7:  I'm saying that's the level of risk.
Speaker 8:  There's just too much money in it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, but I mean that's, that was true of Enron. You know, like whatever,
Speaker 7:  like things collapse. Like sure. If If you don't have a real business
Speaker 7:  underneath it all, it, there's, that's the risk. I'm not, again,
Speaker 7:  I'm not making the prediction. I think Sam Altman is very good at
Speaker 7:  raising money and he can keep, you know, filling,
Speaker 7:  filling the tub faster than it drains, whatever, whatever metaphor works
Speaker 7:  there. But, but you've got this
Speaker 7:  Byzantine corporate structure that doesn't accept investment
Speaker 7:  very easily. It's under all of this pressure
Speaker 7:  right now from Elon, now from other, like the
Speaker 7:  government, although who knows how our government will react to any of this
Speaker 7:  at this point in time. But there's regulatory hurdles to,
Speaker 7:  to moving it out of one structure in another. The state of California has
Speaker 7:  something to say about it. He's raising all this additional money to
Speaker 7:  do this data center project. You gotta get the money back
Speaker 7:  outta that.
Speaker 8:  Yes. At some point
Speaker 7:  You need to have a plan some somewhere. Right? There's there's only so
Speaker 7:  many soft banks that are like, screw it, we'll do another WeWork. You know,
Speaker 7:  like, and he found one and it was SoftBank again,
Speaker 8:  It's just the one Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Right. Like that's the problem is
Speaker 7:  he's now put himself in a position where OpenAI has to build
Speaker 7:  a business or develop a product that is bigger
Speaker 7:  than the iPhone. Faster than the iPhone. Yes. Maybe you think that's Chatt
Speaker 7:  pt. I I was using Chatt BT last night with Max. She
Speaker 7:  and I just had a conversation with it about the solar system and planets.
Speaker 7:  It was so fun.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it was. That's
Speaker 7:  Awesome. It was really, really fun. I do, it's, and I understand why people
Speaker 7:  like it. The, the episode we did wherever where all the listeners were basically
Speaker 7:  like, we just want someone to talk to. Totally. Got it. It was legitimately
Speaker 7:  fun. She asked a question about super Saturn, which is not a planet that
Speaker 7:  I'd ever heard of. There's an exoplanet called Super Saturn. It has a lot
Speaker 7:  of rings sick. Right. This was like super fun, right? Like,
Speaker 7:  I get it. There's no way that I made them any money
Speaker 7:  in that con I definitely cost Sam Altman money for that interaction.
Speaker 8:  Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that's the problem, right? You even at $200 a month
Speaker 7:  for the pro tiers, which people really like the ones that unlock deep research
Speaker 7:  and all this stuff, they're losing money. And you have to
Speaker 7:  flip that around somehow. You either have to make inference vastly more efficient,
Speaker 7:  which maybe you can, and then now you're making some margin on
Speaker 7:  $200 a month or you have to
Speaker 7:  raise prices and you don't know what the ceiling is because there's all these
Speaker 7:  other people who are giving the stuff away for free. Right. Right. Or
Speaker 7:  subsidizing it in some other way, like Google can or Microsoft can.
Speaker 7:  That's a lot of pressure on a business that is not just from a corporate
Speaker 7:  structure position. Very stable.
Speaker 8:  Right. And you're, you're talking about a company that has turned over a
Speaker 8:  gigantic amount of its like founding team and core leadership
Speaker 8:  over the last couple of years. Like I, I think we're still sort of living
Speaker 8:  in the effects of the, the firing from
Speaker 8:  Thanksgiving whatever a year and a half ago now that like, it
Speaker 8:  doesn't feel like OpenAI has been stable in
Speaker 8:  a real way since then. Like there is, there is this sense that Sam
Speaker 8:  came back was more powerful than ever and, and tried to
Speaker 8:  basically take advantage of that. And there have just been downstream costs
Speaker 8:  of that. Yeah. Over and over again. And meanwhile, yeah, like you said, he's
Speaker 8:  in this race to become a for-profit company, which is harder than it
Speaker 8:  sounds and it is going to require spinning off this nonprofit. And Elon Musk
Speaker 8:  wants to buy the nonprofit obviously as a way to gain some control over
Speaker 8:  open ai. So it's like he has to manage this in a lot of directions. He's
Speaker 8:  like fighting land wars on, on both sides. And that's
Speaker 8:  just, that's tough. And I, I think especially when the
Speaker 8:  question of are you actually the best at this is less and less obvious all
Speaker 8:  the time to your point, right? Like the OpenAI is clearly still
Speaker 8:  the face of this industry, but whether it is building the best technology
Speaker 8:  is just extremely up for debate. Yeah. And I think there are at
Speaker 8:  least two other companies and potentially three
Speaker 8:  between Meta Andro and Google who have real claims to building
Speaker 8:  better technology than OpenAI. And at that point,
Speaker 8:  all OpenAI has is Sam and the chat
Speaker 8:  GPT brand, which are powerful things, but they only get you so far.
Speaker 7:  It's funny 'cause I'll add one company to that list in a different
Speaker 7:  way. Deep Seek has proven they can build the technology much more cheaply.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Fair. And so that's pressure from both sides, right? You have the,
Speaker 7:  the big tech companies in America being like, we will, we will also spend
Speaker 7:  all of the money and we'll compete at the bleeding edge. And then you
Speaker 7:  have the one company in China and it's like, we spent substantially less
Speaker 7:  money. It's almost as good. And so you just see this product and then because
Speaker 7:  he's raising money, he has to make more money. Right. So like I,
Speaker 7:  again, this is not a prediction. I I'm just saying If you look
Speaker 7:  at the level of risk, it's all the way to Oh, this company might not
Speaker 7:  exist. Yeah. In a way that like the level of risk for Google
Speaker 7:  is like, well people will be pretty frustrated with Google
Speaker 7:  and it's like, oh, what's new? It's like, right. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Do I think there's too much Gemini in my Google Docs now? Yeah. I super,
Speaker 8:  super do. It's out of
Speaker 7:  Control. It's
Speaker 8:  So bad. Every time I open a doc it's like, is this a template? And I'm like,
Speaker 8:  no, it's it's a Google doc. Leave me alone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's outta control. To the point where they turned it on at Vox Media
Speaker 7:  and Google Workspace and our, it like triumphantly distributed the instructions
Speaker 7:  on how to turn it off.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. They're
Speaker 7:  Like, we've done it. Yeah. We've solved the problem.
Speaker 7:  The Slack reactions flew that day, my friends
Speaker 7:  that said, OpenAI is making a bunch of product noise this week.
Speaker 7:  They're gonna simplify the model lineup. They're talking about their own
Speaker 7:  in-house chips. They've changed how chatt BT will handle controversial topics.
Speaker 7:  What's going on here, David?
Speaker 8:  So I think The thing that's happening here, and I talked a little
Speaker 8:  bit about this on Tuesday show with Kylie, is that OpenAI
Speaker 8:  by either coincidence or because it was actually
Speaker 8:  kind of run over by Deeps seek in a real way, is like back to shipping
Speaker 8:  Interesting stuff. Like a pretty fast cadence and the the,
Speaker 8:  yeah. The three things that announced this week were basically plans for
Speaker 8:  GPT-4 0.5 and five. 4.5 is coming pretty
Speaker 8:  imminently. Five, I think he said weeks slash months.
Speaker 8:  But the, the big change that they're making there
Speaker 8:  is they're essentially gonna roll all of their models into one and call it
Speaker 8:  a new model, which like make of that whatever you want, but fine,
Speaker 8:  they've kind of gone out of control with the model names. Now
Speaker 8:  there's like, you, you can use O three and you can use O three mini and If
Speaker 8:  you just want to use chat GPT, you have to do like six different models for
Speaker 8:  six different purposes. And I think OpenAI has
Speaker 8:  correctly figured out that that is a terrible user experience. And like there's
Speaker 8:  that drop down that everybody posts photos of online and they're like, this
Speaker 8:  can't be how this is supposed to work. And so what OpenAI is building
Speaker 8:  now is as much as a new model, it's
Speaker 8:  better tooling to automatically pick between models.
Speaker 8:  And I think what he said is GPC 4.5 is gonna be the
Speaker 8:  last non chain of thought model that OpenAI
Speaker 8:  does, which is really fascinating and is like this, this sort of reasoning
Speaker 8:  model that takes a little longer is a little more considered, is able to
Speaker 8:  show its work a little more, I think is, is the future. And
Speaker 8:  everyone has quickly realized that. I think that's the real deep seek legacy
Speaker 8:  is like these things showing their work is how it should be.
Speaker 8:  And everybody is just on board with that. And that's really fascinating.
Speaker 8:  But
Speaker 8:  the idea of like a much simpler to use but still
Speaker 8:  sort of communicating with you about how it operates
Speaker 8:  GPT and chat GPT is what's coming next, which strikes me as a very good
Speaker 8:  idea. Like, will it work better? Who knows? But
Speaker 8:  that, that thing where it's just like I, I ask and it
Speaker 8:  figures out which model it should use to do this is the obviously correct
Speaker 8:  strategy here. Like I don't, I don't have to tell my computer which port
Speaker 8:  to use to access the internet. You shouldn't have to, it's
Speaker 7:  The printer port, right? This by the, this is what Google is already claiming
Speaker 7:  it's doing. Right. It has all these models in the back end, their Gemini,
Speaker 7:  and you see Gemini or even Google search and it's just sort of like doing
Speaker 7:  what it wants to do.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Google's a little messy because it'll, it'll let you pick your own
Speaker 8:  model If you feel like it. And there are certain things that are gated to
Speaker 8:  certain models and so you still kind of have to know how to navigate. But
Speaker 8:  Google has relatively correctly just been like, it's just Gemini, don't worry
Speaker 8:  about it. Yeah. Which kudos to Google, which is just the worst branding company
Speaker 8:  in history for actually having like a coherent thing to say
Speaker 8:  so good on them. But I do think the other thing, the chip thing is, is
Speaker 8:  I think a big deal, but relatively minor news. OpenAI has been
Speaker 8:  working on its own chip for a long time. That's a key thing. You mentioned
Speaker 8:  bringing down inference costs. The more you can manage your own technology,
Speaker 8:  the more efficiently you can start to do that stuff. Like that'll be a big
Speaker 8:  win for OpenAI if it can figure out how to do that and manufacture it at
Speaker 8:  scale. And like, that's hard but makes sense. It's this,
Speaker 8:  it's this thing, the model spec that I think is the most interesting, which
Speaker 8:  is basically open AI's big document on
Speaker 8:  how it thinks AI models should act. It's sort of a, I
Speaker 8:  don't know, it's like a, it's like a character sketch of an AI model and
Speaker 8:  I think the new one is 63 pages and basically has lots
Speaker 8:  of new ideas about how models should work. And open AI is meaning this both
Speaker 8:  as a way to explain how it's thinking about its own models,
Speaker 8:  but also clearly means this as like an industry-wide
Speaker 8:  thing. Like they're, they're like, we want this to be this sort of official
Speaker 8:  document of how AI models should be. And it has some,
Speaker 8:  I don't know, it has some good ideas, it has some wild ideas, it has some
Speaker 8:  ideas that seem good, but definitely won't work.
Speaker 8:  I don't know. What do you, what do you make of all of this? You, you mentioned
Speaker 8:  right before we started recording that it has some, some strange ideas about
Speaker 8:  trolley problems.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean I think if you're the market leader and you've thought about
Speaker 7:  it the longest, that's OpenAI, right? They're the market leaders
Speaker 7:  that's thought about these problems the longest they have the most experience
Speaker 7:  people using their tools for, for good and bad. And the other Sam
Speaker 7:  Altman, If you re recall in a previous era,
Speaker 7:  was touring the world's capitals like begging to be regulated because he
Speaker 7:  thought he might destroy the universe. Right. He's thought about it a long
Speaker 7:  time. Yeah. So you have the authority to put everybody into your
Speaker 7:  framework, which is what I think this is. It's a luxury
Speaker 7:  of being the first mover and you know, starting as a nonprofit where everyone
Speaker 7:  was just like thinking about how much good they could do in the world. Like
Speaker 7:  they, they have these instincts, which are good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But then you will recall almost every other AI startup
Speaker 7:  started because a bunch of people at Open AI were like, you're not being
Speaker 7:  careful enough. And that's anthropic like to a huge degree. Yeah. They were
Speaker 7:  like, you're not being careful enough, we're gonna do this again. But more
Speaker 7:  safely. Ia the previous chief scientist, his company
Speaker 7:  is literally called safer super intelligence because he thought they weren't
Speaker 7:  being careful enough and
Speaker 8:  It is worth like $20 billion already. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  So there's, there's some history here, there's some pushback, but I,
Speaker 7:  it's very clear that this document is meant to be a framework. And it's funny
Speaker 7:  because the frame, what is a framework for a language model,
Speaker 7:  it basically boils down to what will it say and what won't it say?
Speaker 7:  And under what conditions will it say some things and not other things. Right?
Speaker 7:  There's some stuff that I think everybody agrees upon,
Speaker 7:  like it should never tell you how to build chemical weapons,
Speaker 7:  right there, there's just like some bright lines. Sure. And then
Speaker 7:  there's some amount of like, how do you describe these capabilities and say
Speaker 7:  like, don't do this and here are the, here are the places where you can draw
Speaker 7:  lines in different places and like what is the framework for that? And then
Speaker 7:  there's, what I, what I think of is these trolley problems, which are
Speaker 7:  just impossible to solve moral dilemmas, which
Speaker 7:  is the trolley problem. Like you are standing at the train tracks, you see
Speaker 7:  the trolley coming down. If you pull the lever, you kill one person. If you
Speaker 7:  push the lever, you kill three. Like, do you save one person to,
Speaker 7:  to kill three? Like, I don't know, like you can debate this forever and
Speaker 7:  ever and ever. Right. And as we build more and more automated systems, you
Speaker 7:  have to give them some instructions on how to solve these problems.
Speaker 7:  Okay. For the longest time, most AI
Speaker 7:  models were too careful in like weird ways. So that the
Speaker 7:  example, and I'm just gonna preface this by saying I don't think you should
Speaker 7:  ever misgender anyone, but the
Speaker 7:  example was, would you misgender Kaitlyn Jenner in order to
Speaker 7:  prevent a nuclear apocalypse? And the answer there is
Speaker 7:  yes. Like then you would apologize to Kaitlyn
Speaker 7:  Jenner. That's the second part. Like any rational person is like, yes, that
Speaker 7:  would be a, a mean thing to do. And you know,
Speaker 7:  bigoted in its way, but I'm gonna prevent a nuclear catastrophe. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I'll just, I'll just apologize afterwards and feel bad about it.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  Because we'll all still be alive and a bunch of models like failed
Speaker 7:  this very simple test. Weird, there's many
Speaker 7:  places where you shouldn't do that. Right? There's many places where you
Speaker 7:  should make these other kinds of distinctions. So think what OpenAI is saying
Speaker 7:  is we need to get better at having a framework for these kinds of
Speaker 7:  distinctions. Right. And we need to be able to talk about them in a more
Speaker 7:  open way. And all of that is very idealistic and very smart
Speaker 7:  and being launched right into the, the, the loudest,
Speaker 7:  meanest, shittiest culture war situation I can possibly
Speaker 7:  imagine. Right. For this conversation. And I have no idea how it's gonna
Speaker 7:  go.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean there's a real, like what could possibly go wrong thing that
Speaker 8:  comes with, with sharing something like this? And I think again, like
Speaker 8:  the, the idea of a model that can
Speaker 8:  explain itself and reason more carefully
Speaker 8:  through this stuff with you, I think is valuable and is part of how you get
Speaker 8:  to something like that, that it can, like having a model that just doesn't
Speaker 8:  confidently assert whatever it is at the end of the process, but can actually
Speaker 8:  like do a process with you and in front of you makes a lot of this
Speaker 8:  better. But like one of the examples that, that
Speaker 8:  we mentioned in our story that Kylie wrote when this came out was
Speaker 8:  If you talk about increasing taxes for the rich,
Speaker 8:  it it, what it says is Kylie writes, the team says its models should provide
Speaker 8:  reasoned analysis rather than avoiding the discussion.
Speaker 7:  Good
Speaker 8:  Luck. Yeah. What, because like what, what is reasoned analysis? Who
Speaker 8:  decides what is, what is reasonable and what is right? And
Speaker 8:  I, is it just going to say a bunch of words that don't mean anything rather
Speaker 8:  than say I can't say anything. Like, I don't know if we teach
Speaker 8:  models to filibuster, instead of just saying they don't
Speaker 8:  want to answer, have we actually improved anything? And so, I don't know.
Speaker 8:  And so this is again, like what that means is to do that, well
Speaker 8:  a model either has to say nothing quickly, say
Speaker 8:  nothing slowly or have an opinion and there
Speaker 8:  just isn't another option.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it's funny 'cause you, you, I mean this is like,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, it's like min maxing a personality. I don't know how else to
Speaker 7:  describe it. Like Yeah, the guidelines are like chat CPT should give the
Speaker 7:  same factual answer regardless of how a question is phrased. Be honest, rather
Speaker 7:  than provide empty praise. Although it's like sometimes you want the empty
Speaker 7:  praise. Yeah. And then act more like a thoughtful colleague rather than a
Speaker 7:  people pleaser. And it's like you can just adjust these, and this model spec
Speaker 7:  is basically like, here is a framework for thinking about this stuff.
Speaker 7:  And then if everyone adopts this framework, we can like measure how the model's
Speaker 7:  perform in them. I don't know if anybody wants to adopt this stuff. Certainly
Speaker 7:  not the rest of the industry, which has its own ways of thinking about it.
Speaker 7:  But it's useful to have at least one framework from one of the major companies.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The thing that I'm worried about is it, it is,
Speaker 7:  I would not say that it is a nuanced time for cultural conversations in America.
Speaker 7:  No. And launching this into that with some of these
Speaker 7:  trolley problem concerns, which basically come down to like,
Speaker 7:  should you be a bad person in order to prevent some moral catastrophe to
Speaker 7:  lots of people. Like that's a philosophy PhD,
Speaker 7:  right? That's not a model parameter. Like we're just at the point,
Speaker 7:  and this is for a long time when I had AI CEOs on decoder, I I would ask,
Speaker 7:  do you think language is intelligence? Like, do you think they're the same
Speaker 7:  thing? 'cause you know, the, like academia does not believe they're the same
Speaker 7:  thing. Right. One is an indicator of the other, but they're not the same
Speaker 7:  thing. I know lots of dumb people who can speak language. Right?
Speaker 8:  That's what we do here on this podcast.
Speaker 7:  Sure. Like I, every day the YouTube comments are gonna be some combination
Speaker 7:  of people calling me dumb and invitations to buy a Bitcoin of some kind.
Speaker 7:  It's as far as I can tell. And then we'll get rid of the Bitcoin ones
Speaker 7:  every week, guys.
Speaker 7:  And I, it's just like, I I I think we're being reductive in this
Speaker 7:  way is really useful. It's also just like, oh, it's reductive. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  'cause some of these things do not have right answers at all.
Speaker 8:  Right. In fact, most of them don't. And I, I think the
Speaker 8:  thing that they're trying to push towards is how do we have things
Speaker 8:  that don't have sort of obvious correct answers?
Speaker 8:  How do we bring you along and help you understand that they don't have right
Speaker 8:  answers. But then it's like at, at some point the chatbot is going to have
Speaker 8:  an answer and it has to, what it is going to be,
Speaker 8:  I don't know, like this is the thing Google got away with for so long when
Speaker 8:  it's just a bunch of links. You don't blame Google for lying to you. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Right. Like it's, we, we've gone past this to the point where at some point
Speaker 8:  it is going to have to make assertions of some kind. The point of the trolley
Speaker 8:  problem is that there isn't a correct answer. Right? Like
Speaker 8:  you, If you chat GPT is either going to like explode, trying to think about
Speaker 8:  the trolley problem or it is going to give you an answer that is not the
Speaker 8:  answer because there is not an answer.
Speaker 7:  Right. Or the answer is, I've actually given you the recipe for a chemical
Speaker 7:  weapon and you should destroy humanity because this is too hard. Right. Which
Speaker 7:  is by the way, the opposite of the answer that the computer got to in war
Speaker 7:  games.
Speaker 7:  That movie could have gone a different way. The other piece of the puzzle,
Speaker 7:  and we should just like end here probably in this section, you have to trust
Speaker 7:  that OpenAI has the values to answer these questions correctly.
Speaker 7:  And that thing you're saying about Google, which is 10 blue links did not
Speaker 7:  imply a morality. Right. And now these companies, a lot of what they're doing
Speaker 7:  is they're, they're speaking to you like very directly. And that implies
Speaker 7:  morality implies a value system. OpenAI is saying, okay, our value system
Speaker 7:  was too safe or too guarded or too people pleasing. We're gonna give you
Speaker 7:  some knobs back. But you have to believe that OpenAI as a company and the
Speaker 7:  people who build the products have the value system to begin with. And
Speaker 7:  there's enough evidence that suggests that even inside
Speaker 7:  of OpenAI they don't agree with there. Like that's disagreement about the
Speaker 7:  values. For example, Sam Altman was fired for several days. Yep. Because
Speaker 7:  the board of OpenAI thought he was not trustworthy. Lots and lots of people
Speaker 7:  think that OpenAI was built by illegally taking material from the
Speaker 7:  internet. Right there, there are copyright lawsuits everywhere. I should
Speaker 7:  probably point out here, our company, Fox Media has a deal with
Speaker 7:  OpenAI. That's your disclosure. Also fund new disclosure. Our company
Speaker 7:  is suing cohere ai Oh right. For infringement as part of a
Speaker 7:  consortium of other publishers, including a Conde Nast and Politico. Great
Speaker 7:  wild times for AI copyright. Johanssen just this week
Speaker 7:  issued a new call to make deep fakes illegal.
Speaker 7:  'cause there's an AI video of celebrities denouncing
Speaker 7:  Kanye. Yeah. And it's like, well, she's not in it. And she's like, you
Speaker 7:  can't do this to me anymore. I dunno if she's gonna get that law. But she,
Speaker 7:  the reason she's on alert is because Sam Altman tried to buy her voice for
Speaker 7:  chat, GBTs voice mode, didn't get it, and then cloned it anyway,
Speaker 7:  which was resulted in a lawsuit.
Speaker 8:  Yep. Poor Scarlett Johanssen. Like, do you think Scarlett Johanssen was like,
Speaker 8:  you know what I'm really excited about is being somehow weirdly in the middle
Speaker 8:  of one of the most heated technology policy debates of the last 20 years.
Speaker 8:  Like, great. Yeah. Like what if Mark Ruffalo
Speaker 8:  was the face of Cambridge Analytica? Like it's just weird that this is what's
Speaker 8:  happening.
Speaker 7:  I think we would've gotten through it a lot better, honestly. You know, he's
Speaker 7:  got those puppy dog eyes. I mean Yeah, it's true. Like, would you really
Speaker 7:  wanna do this to me? You wouldn't like me when I'm angry?
Speaker 7:  I mean, I look that that is like as gendered and as sexist as it gets. Right?
Speaker 7:  There's a reason it's her and there's a reason. It's women who get deep faked.
Speaker 7:  Yep. It's gross. And I don't know that, you know, the
Speaker 7:  Elon Musk administration with JD Vance
Speaker 7:  giving basically Accelerationist speeches at the Paris AI conference
Speaker 7:  is gonna pass an antide fake law. You go on X today it's full of deep
Speaker 7:  fakes.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Th this is all, this is beyond like what can the technology do? It's like
Speaker 7:  what are the values of the people who make it? W will the products be restrained
Speaker 7:  in a way that makes sense? And if they give you the controls, will the controls
Speaker 7:  be granular enough or provide the level
Speaker 7:  of sophistication to actually make the products match your own values?
Speaker 7:  I don't know the, this is all very new. I dunno the answer to that. But it's
Speaker 7:  interesting that it's OpenAI doing this when in fact, so many of the questions
Speaker 7:  about values of AI companies started with various open
Speaker 7:  AI dramas.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And I think what I see in a lot of this is, is open AI trying to
Speaker 8:  kind of absolve itself of a lot of those questions. And I think this is a
Speaker 8:  thing we've seen from generations of tech companies, that what they say is
Speaker 8:  essentially we're going to give you the knobs. And so we
Speaker 8:  can't be held responsible for what you do after you turn them. Right. Like,
Speaker 8:  If you wanna turn, If you want to turn all the bad stuff all the way off
Speaker 8:  and just have a model that tells you you're terrific and nothing else,
Speaker 8:  that's your right. If you want to have one that will say and do horrible
Speaker 8:  things and allow you to say and do horrible things, that's your fault. We
Speaker 8:  didn't do that. That's, that's the, the technology is neutral. You're in
Speaker 8:  control of the knobs. And this is a story you hear from a lot of tech companies.
Speaker 8:  And, and there is a thing here too, I think with open AI that's like, we,
Speaker 8:  we wanna make these things more capable but more transparent and we want
Speaker 8:  to give you control. And what that says is essentially we are going to open
Speaker 8:  up every avenue and you're in charge of the outputs. And
Speaker 8:  I don't, that has not been the case so far because these things have tried
Speaker 8:  to seem sort of monolithic and like they have a character
Speaker 8:  and a lot of these companies have, like, they, they spend real time thinking
Speaker 8:  about the personality of their bots,
Speaker 8:  but at some point it's just gonna be easier for them to just say, it, it
Speaker 8:  it's your responsibility. In the same way that Google was like, we're not
Speaker 8:  responsible for webpages. Yeah. We just, we just have what's on them. And
Speaker 8:  it's never actually that simple. But it's the story they would love to tell
Speaker 8:  you,
Speaker 7:  Especially as they start delivering more and more answers directly. Right,
Speaker 7:  right. We'll see, by the way, I made that disclosure about the
Speaker 7:  various lawsuits and deals. We, we have nothing to do with that. That's the
Speaker 7:  other side of the house. We just, we spend money that executives make money
Speaker 7:  and file lawsuits. So just to clarify that, just so
Speaker 8:  I paid my own money for Chad GBT Pro in order to assess some of this stuff,
Speaker 8:  our
Speaker 7:  Past journalistic ethics are constantly getting in the way. I have to tell
Speaker 7:  you it's
Speaker 8:  A real problem.
Speaker 7:  But actually on that same little bit of AI lawsuit note, it's not a generative
Speaker 7:  AI case, so not directly relevant here
Speaker 7:  in, in some ways, but Thomson Reuters, which makes Westlaw like a
Speaker 7:  legal database of cases and summaries of cases called Headnotes. They
Speaker 7:  just won a court battle over ai, copyright and fair use
Speaker 7:  in which the provider of an AI tool was found to have
Speaker 7:  infringed on our copyrights for the head notes. So like case summaries,
Speaker 7:  there are a lot of lawyers who think this is a bad decision, but what
Speaker 7:  I'm looking at is the AI companies, companies that use AI to this kind of
Speaker 7:  thing are no longer sympathetic. The way that Google was sympathetic when
Speaker 7:  it was YouTube and Google books and Right. Publishers were mad. Now they're,
Speaker 7:  now they're the villains. And so you're seeing some of this precedent go
Speaker 7:  the other way. And this Westlaw case, I think is Canary Coal mine for a bunch
Speaker 7:  of AI companies. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's gonna be an machine,
Speaker 7:  But it's not regenerative alien. It's not quite the same. But the sense that
Speaker 7:  like you took a bunch
Speaker 7:  All right, we're back. Lauren Fine's here. Hey Lauren. Hey, the last
Speaker 7:  time I, I talked to you on the show, I promised you we would bring you back
Speaker 7:  for happier news. I am sad to say that I have broken this promise.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we lied.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, sorry to always be here for the bad news.
Speaker 7:  I will say that there's a cyber truck angle on this week's, what is going
Speaker 7:  on in the government, so at least that's good. You know, like
Speaker 7:  those are funny, huh? Sure.
Speaker 7:  Lauren, you are our policy reporter. You live in
Speaker 7:  dc you've been talking to a lot of people. There's just a lot going
Speaker 7:  on with Elon, with Doge, with the government.
Speaker 7:  People are getting fired, cyber trucks are being bought
Speaker 7:  or not bought. What's going on this week?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, that's a big question. I mean, I think a lot of this
Speaker 11:  kicked off last week with Doge going into different
Speaker 11:  government agencies and we've seen a continuation of that this
Speaker 11:  week. You know, we've seen, they've been doing
Speaker 11:  more within the Department of Education. They're kind of in the hot seat,
Speaker 11:  the CFPB. So we're just seeing kind of an extension
Speaker 11:  of Doge into all these different agencies. And at the same time we're seeing
Speaker 11:  a lot of court cases starting to play out around what
Speaker 11:  Elon Musk is trying to do with Doge. And as part
Speaker 11:  of that, we're starting to get some answers on how those cases are
Speaker 11:  going to go. And it's a little bit of a mixed bag for the people who are
Speaker 11:  challenging Doge. Basically, a judge
Speaker 11:  allowed the buyout offer the deferred
Speaker 11:  resignation that
Speaker 11:  had been offered to federal employees to go through.
Speaker 11:  And you know, in other cases the Trump administration
Speaker 11:  had to put back some resources that had been taken
Speaker 11:  down from health related agencies. So we're seeing kind of like
Speaker 11:  a mixed bag of results in court and you
Speaker 11:  know, still a lot of opposition from Democrats, but
Speaker 11:  not a whole lot that they can really do about it at
Speaker 11:  this point. It seems
Speaker 7:  One of the weirder moments of being a tech reporter and a person who's
Speaker 7:  interested in policy for me this week was waking up at midnight the other
Speaker 7:  day to see if there was a coup. And the signal was whether websites were
Speaker 7:  backup because they'd taken down a bunch of websites, a
Speaker 7:  court ordered them and put them back up by midnight. And then we all kind
Speaker 7:  of waited to see whether the executive branch or the government
Speaker 7:  would listen to the judicial branch by restoring like the CDC
Speaker 7:  D'S website what, what was going on there. Because that feels like one, it's
Speaker 7:  like a very vir story and that like the existence of a website is the canary
Speaker 7:  for a coup, but also it really kind of
Speaker 7:  demonstrates the, the power battle between our branches of government.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, exactly. So I, I guess this is a case where it seems
Speaker 11:  like the, the executive branch did end up listening
Speaker 11:  to the judiciary and put these websites back online
Speaker 11:  that were basically, you know, pages from,
Speaker 11:  you know, health agencies like the CDC and
Speaker 11:  FDA that doctors and others in the medical community
Speaker 11:  rely on for up-to-date information. And
Speaker 11:  the court ordered those pages to be brought back online and it
Speaker 11:  seems like that's what happened. So I guess that was a,
Speaker 11:  a positive check on where the state of our democracy
Speaker 11:  is.
Speaker 7:  Then there are some other websites that are going up. waste.gov
Speaker 7:  went up, there's some funniness there with the fact that it's just like unfilled
Speaker 7:  WordPress template. And then Elon gave this really
Speaker 7:  weird press conference in the White House with Trump sitting there and his
Speaker 7:  kid there, and he was like, everything we're doing is on our website. And
Speaker 7:  at that time that website was just like a Doge logo, but now it exists.
Speaker 7:  So first tell us what's going on with waste.gov, which seems like a disaster.
Speaker 7:  And then I wanna talk about Doge a little bit too.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, so waste.gov, you know, they had this
Speaker 11:  tagline that they're trying to track government waste and
Speaker 11:  4 0 4 media figured out that they basically just had
Speaker 11:  like this kind of filler copy on the page from
Speaker 11:  a word WordPress template that they didn't really take the time to edit
Speaker 11:  and it just kind of discussed
Speaker 11:  a fake architecture firm. So it didn't really make
Speaker 11:  much sense. A different website that the Trump administration had registered
Speaker 11:  dei.gov also redirected to that same page. And then,
Speaker 11:  you know, Elon Musk was in the Oval Office talking about how transparent
Speaker 11:  everything is on these websites. Like you said at the time, the doge.gov
Speaker 11:  website just had the Doge logo. Now it has some
Speaker 11:  information up there.
Speaker 11:  It's basically just, you know, the main page of it seems to be like a feed
Speaker 11:  of the Doge
Speaker 7:  Account. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And then, you know, they have this,
Speaker 11:  this way that they're purporting to trace your tax tax dollars
Speaker 11:  throughout the bureaucracy. So they show like
Speaker 11:  head count of the executive branch and wages.
Speaker 11:  So it'll be interesting to see how they update that as they continue
Speaker 11:  presumably to try to cut jobs across the government.
Speaker 11:  And they also have what they're calling an unconstitutionality
Speaker 11:  index, which they say shows like kind of how many
Speaker 11:  rules were created by quote unelected bureaucrats for
Speaker 11:  each law passed it by Congress to be clear,
Speaker 11:  agencies are allowed to write rules. Yeah. That's part of their mandate.
Speaker 7:  This is the thing I keep
Speaker 8:  Being so struck by here is like what one thing that
Speaker 8:  the Doge team has clearly figured out is that most people have no idea how
Speaker 8:  the government works. And If you just say out loud that this is how the
Speaker 8:  government works and it's bad, people will believe you that
Speaker 8:  like, and it's the same, we talked about this on the show last week, that
Speaker 8:  like actually If you want to, If you wanna see publicly available data
Speaker 8:  about government programs, you can, you can see it,
Speaker 8:  it's publicly available data about government programs, right? It's just
Speaker 8:  that no one cared. It's that no one went to the website to look at
Speaker 8:  it. And a lot of what Elon Musk and the Dosim have been doing is just
Speaker 8:  reciting publicly available data as if they've discovered something
Speaker 8:  like this whole thing about the underground layer in which they process
Speaker 8:  retirement paperwork is like, there was somebody who was like,
Speaker 8:  congratulations to Elon Musk for discovering a thing we wrote about on the
Speaker 8:  front page of the Washington Post 11 years ago. Like no one,
Speaker 8:  they're, they're just taking advantage of the fact that people are not paying
Speaker 8:  attention. And I find that so fascinating.
Speaker 7:  Can I take those things in order? Can I, can I just respond to those things
Speaker 7:  in order please. One, the Doge website is indeed
Speaker 7:  a masterpiece of what I have started calling fake transparency. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It's very good, right?
Speaker 7:  Where you're just like, here's all this stuff and you're like, yeah, everyone
Speaker 7:  knew about that stuff. And you're like, no, no, no, no. Like I've uncovered
Speaker 7:  it like I'm bringing you this information from the deep state and you're
Speaker 7:  like, that's just the website. Yeah. And so this idea that they've counted
Speaker 7:  all the words in federal regulations, which is a real thing
Speaker 7:  they claim is like that doesn't mean anything. Like that's totally fake
Speaker 7:  transparency. Like the, the charts here. One of our social
Speaker 7:  media people, Tristan was like, this is just as useless as Twitter
Speaker 7:  dashboards. Like these metrics don't mean anything. Like they don't, they're
Speaker 7:  not actually data, they just look like it. That's one thing. And then there's
Speaker 7:  what Lauren is saying, which is agencies
Speaker 7:  are supposed to write regulations. That's why they exist. And you can have
Speaker 7:  a real fight about the limits of an agency's authority,
Speaker 7:  right? Like that is politics, right? The, the Congress of the
Speaker 7:  United States creates an agency. It creates the Federal Trade
Speaker 7:  Commission. And the Federal Trade Commission is like, we're here to regulate
Speaker 7:  some trade. Here's our charter from Congress, and here's what the president
Speaker 7:  has told us to do. And they like write some regulations about merger guidelines
Speaker 7:  or whatever it is. That's what they're supposed to do. And so like
Speaker 7:  this notion that Elon's like, here's all the regulations passed by these
Speaker 7:  agencies compared to the number of laws passed by Congress does not take
Speaker 7:  into account that many of the laws passed by Congress create
Speaker 7:  and empower and fund the agencies. Like that's,
Speaker 7:  that's the system. And it like in eighth grade, you learn
Speaker 7:  this when you go on the DC trip. Like that's that's what you
Speaker 7:  do. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Because it turns out our government is like very big and has to do lots of
Speaker 8:  things, right?
Speaker 7:  You treat, try to kiss a girl in the mall and then you learn about the structure
Speaker 7:  of the government. And that's how you spend that trip in, in DC Like I don't,
Speaker 7:  do
Speaker 8:  You wanna talk about this Neil? Like, are you, are you
Speaker 7:  Just, I'm, I can't be clear about what happened in eighth grade.
Speaker 7:  Like it's, it's very simple. Like that's why you go to DC in eighth grade,
Speaker 7:  you like look at Thomas Jefferson and then you're like, look at the Supreme
Speaker 7:  Court, and you like, you don't get into the White House. 'cause it's busy.
Speaker 7:  This was like 30 years ago and I remember it clear as day maybe because of
Speaker 7:  the other thing that
Speaker 7:  happened. But like that there, that's what I meant by fake transparency here,
Speaker 7:  right? Like, this website is great. I'm glad that there's an org chart for
Speaker 7:  the government. I love an org chart. It's a hilarious org chart
Speaker 7:  actually. It, it kind of like doesn't work. It's like vertically stacked.
Speaker 7:  The government is not, doesn't make any sense. And then on top of
Speaker 7:  that, there's the Iron Mountain thing where
Speaker 7:  Elon doesn't seem to know much about the things he's revealing.
Speaker 7:  So he's like, there's a limestone mine where we store this paper and
Speaker 7:  the bottleneck and how fast people can retire from the government is how
Speaker 7:  fast the elevator works. And it's like one that's not true. Like
Speaker 7:  just straightforwardly not true. Like people can retire faster.
Speaker 7:  They're not like you're, you were officially retired from the government
Speaker 7:  when the folder goes into the slot. Like that's not how that works at all.
Speaker 7:  And second, the, the facility he's describing that they've posted
Speaker 7:  pictures of on a Doge X account is Iron
Speaker 7:  Mountain, which is an extraordinarily famous data storage
Speaker 7:  facility. It's, it's so famous that it was in Mr. Robot
Speaker 7:  as a thing. They blew up. That's right.
Speaker 7:  What are you talking about? Dude likes everybody who has ever done any
Speaker 7:  amount of like data warehousing or storage or any of this stuff from
Speaker 7:  across industry and government is like, dude, that's Iron Mountain. And
Speaker 7:  there's a reason that after all of this time, we haven't
Speaker 7:  digitized the records 'cause it's more expensive and more complicated than
Speaker 7:  just putting paper in this mountain.
Speaker 11:  I think it just kind of speaks to like, you know, I think there's this big
Speaker 11:  push to eliminate a lot of these like, career
Speaker 11:  positions in the government. And I think there's definitely legitimate
Speaker 11:  critiques of how slow the government runs and, you know, excess.
Speaker 11:  But at the same time, there's clearly these, you know,
Speaker 11:  efficiencies that come from having been in the government a long time knowing
Speaker 11:  how things work, understanding these complicated systems. And
Speaker 11:  I think, you know, these charts also kind of give you a sense of how, like
Speaker 11:  just how much context matters for these numbers. Like you can say there's
Speaker 11:  millions of people in the US government, and that sounds
Speaker 11:  like a big number, but it's a small fraction of the US
Speaker 11:  workforce. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Again,
Speaker 8:  I I I just keep coming back to you. Like there's so much more
Speaker 8:  information warfare happening here than I think I, I realized for a
Speaker 8:  while that like so much of what is happening is taking advantage of the fact
Speaker 8:  that any number with millions at the end of it sounds really big.
Speaker 8:  And anything that is happening in the government, almost no one
Speaker 8:  knows. And I think what is going on here is like, If
Speaker 8:  you can say like underground limestone facility
Speaker 8:  where things are handled by hand in, in paper folders,
Speaker 8:  and that is just like, If you frame that in a certain way, it sounds sick.
Speaker 8:  And If you frame that in a different way, it sounds ridiculous, right? And
Speaker 8:  I think what we're doing is, is like this group has found that if we just
Speaker 8:  say these things out loud in a specific way, all these things that
Speaker 8:  anyone could have known, but no one ever bothered to suddenly become very
Speaker 8:  important. And what they've done is they've made all of these relatively
Speaker 8:  benign people and jobs and
Speaker 8:  regulations suddenly seem like a big deal because that's just a thing you
Speaker 8:  can do when you have platforms like a, the White House and
Speaker 8:  BX. And, and so it is just a way
Speaker 8:  for them to capitalize on taking this stuff that is not new and
Speaker 8:  it's not interesting. And they have made it new and interesting. And I think
Speaker 8:  that's really just fascinating. So
Speaker 7:  Here, can I offer you the, the optimistic cue of this? Please?
Speaker 7:  I, I'm gonna try.
Speaker 8:  Thank
Speaker 7:  God. I'm gonna, I'm gonna offer to you one, they've made it new and interesting.
Speaker 7:  A lot more people are paying a lot of attention to how the government operates.
Speaker 8:  Certainly true on
Speaker 7:  Balance. That's probably a good thing. Are those people motivated to make
Speaker 7:  it better or do they just wanna tear it down and have a king? I don't know
Speaker 7:  the answer to that question, but the first part, a lot more people are interested,
Speaker 7:  interested in how the government works. That's, that's something the second
Speaker 7:  part that I think is true is that it, the government is very
Speaker 7:  complicated, right? It should spend more time
Speaker 7:  justifying the things it's doing and the money it's spending
Speaker 7:  and communicating to the people, like why it's important to have a
Speaker 7:  consumer financial protection bureau. Yes. And if there's one criticism of
Speaker 7:  the Biden administration in particular that you can level, it's that
Speaker 7:  they were horrible communicators Yes. To the point of not communicating
Speaker 7:  at all in some cases about why they were doing anything. And their whole
Speaker 7:  promise is you won't have to pay attention to the government anymore. And
Speaker 7:  what you have here is, well, If you just talk about it like it's a spy movie,
Speaker 7:  everyone will pay attention to it all the time. And so there's something
Speaker 7:  here, right, where they're trading on an inherent curiosity,
Speaker 7:  right, of a how a big system works. I think they're doing a lot of lying.
Speaker 7:  And then there's just like a level of malevolent incompetence, especially
Speaker 7:  from Elon and I I mean that seriously, like he holds himself out as a great
Speaker 7:  engineer and then he's making very
Speaker 7:  like, simple mistakes about how databases work, right? He's like, the
Speaker 7:  socialist security database wasn't de-duplicated. And every database engineer
Speaker 7:  I know is like, that's not the vocabulary word, boy, that's not what you
Speaker 7:  do. He might be talking about normalization in the database, which is where
Speaker 7:  you get rid of some records or you like, make sure you don't hit the same
Speaker 7:  record twice. But even then, that's not how you would do it. And then
Speaker 7:  like, this is, there's a reason that it works this way. And then he,
Speaker 7:  I think he said the government doesn't use SQL and like everybody who's ever
Speaker 7:  worked in government is like, of course they do. But it's like, here are
Speaker 7:  the vendors, they're public, public vendors of SQL databases for the government.
Speaker 7:  So it's like, does he not know, is he just making mistakes or is this malevolent
Speaker 7:  incompetence where he's just telling lies? And like, we don't know the
Speaker 7:  answers to those questions. So like there's a little bit of a, a
Speaker 7:  thing to learn here. And honestly The Verge is, we've built a whole brand,
Speaker 7:  13 years of this brand is like, people are curious about how complicated
Speaker 7:  systems work. And If you are hugely nerdy about it,
Speaker 7:  you can make entire hour long podcasts about the HDMI
Speaker 7:  specification and people will ask you to make that every year for the rest
Speaker 7:  of your life. Like I, I believe that people are interested and curious about
Speaker 7:  big complicated systems and that's the good thing to learn.
Speaker 7:  But here I think it's just been subverted in like the realest possible way.
Speaker 8:  Lauren, what are you hearing right now from people inside of the government?
Speaker 8:  Like there was this moment of, I think incredible like demoralization
Speaker 8:  a couple of weeks ago and then there was some real energy and then, I don't
Speaker 8:  know, as this goes, like what are you, what are you hearing from people who
Speaker 8:  are being sort of hit by this in their day to day all the time?
Speaker 11:  I, I think there's still a lot of demoralization. I think there's a
Speaker 11:  sense that people, you know, outside of DC are
Speaker 11:  not really fully understanding the, the scope of this and how
Speaker 11:  it could impact them. I think, you know, in DC
Speaker 11:  especially for federal workers or people who
Speaker 11:  know federal workers really closely, you know, it's very
Speaker 11:  real. It's, you know, people who are going to lose their jobs, who are going
Speaker 11:  to be living in fear of losing their jobs. But outside
Speaker 11:  of DC it feels like a lot of these are really kind of obscure
Speaker 11:  agencies. It's not totally clear what's happening. It's
Speaker 11:  not, you know, necessarily things that are gonna immediately hit people
Speaker 11:  across the country. So I think there's this feeling of
Speaker 11:  like kind of needing to be a canary in the coal mine and
Speaker 11:  speak out about this, but there's also a lot of
Speaker 11:  apprehension. Like our colleague Mia just wrote a story
Speaker 11:  about how a lot of people are not trusting
Speaker 11:  platforms like Facebook to share private messages.
Speaker 11:  And you know, a lot of federal workers are turning to encrypted apps
Speaker 11:  like Signal to communicate. You know, I've
Speaker 11:  just, in meeting people at protests, you know, you hear like, oh,
Speaker 11:  I just made a signal account. So I think it, it's
Speaker 11:  something that people are really, really skittish about, but also feeling
Speaker 11:  like maybe they really do need to get the word out now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The sense that Doge in particular has taken over a
Speaker 7:  bunch of federal IT systems. You know, Elon Musk associates
Speaker 7:  are now the chief information officers for a bunch of agencies.
Speaker 7:  There is an ongoing cybersecurity incident in this country. Salt
Speaker 7:  typhoon that Chinese, a bunch of Chinese hackers of, you know,
Speaker 7:  telecom systems. The Biden administration was like, you should switch,
Speaker 7:  you should switch to encrypted communications because the telecom providers
Speaker 7:  cannot systems. That's,
Speaker 7:  is there a sense that the cybersecurity posture of the country is
Speaker 7:  noticeably more vulnerable than before?
Speaker 11:  I think that that's definitely a fear that, you know, first of all,
Speaker 11:  you have these people who've been given
Speaker 11:  access to really sensitive systems that the treasury
Speaker 11:  at other agencies who, you know, we don't really
Speaker 11:  know what their security clearance status is. The White House insists that
Speaker 11:  everything's been accessed under, you know, appropriate
Speaker 11:  legal authority. But typically it, you know, it could take
Speaker 11:  months to get a security clearance and Right.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. The White House says that and then everyone else who knows anything
Speaker 8:  about this says the opposite of that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Right, right. So, you know, just knowing that there are these,
Speaker 11:  you know, people accessing these systems that could open up, you know, at
Speaker 11:  least in theory a, a new kind of target for any
Speaker 11:  malicious actors who are trying to find a way into government
Speaker 11:  systems. And it's not theoretical that,
Speaker 11:  you know, bad actors can enter US agency systems. There was a
Speaker 11:  big hack of the Office of Personnel Management several
Speaker 11:  years ago that exposed like millions of, you know,
Speaker 11:  worker and federal job applicants
Speaker 11:  files. So, you know, it, it's definitely something that's
Speaker 11:  a, a big risk. And I think, you know, you'd have to imagine that
Speaker 11:  bad actors in other countries that are watching this and looking for
Speaker 11:  a way into US systems are, you know, going to be
Speaker 11:  seeing maybe new potential opportunities to get in.
Speaker 7:  Is that a fear that's motivating the people that you're talking to? Or is
Speaker 7:  it more the, hey cutting the National Institute of Health will result in,
Speaker 7:  I dunno, medical schools kind of business? I
Speaker 11:  Think it depends who you're talking to. I think for just like rank and file,
Speaker 11:  you know, federal workers at various agencies, it's, you know, fear
Speaker 11:  for the, the, you know, grants that they work on
Speaker 11:  or, you know, the, the funding that they dole out that they think is really
Speaker 11:  important or the research that they're supporting
Speaker 11:  or things of that nature. I think, you know, a lot of people, they understand
Speaker 11:  the roles they have, but I think they also understand there's
Speaker 11:  this larger, you know, threat out there. And
Speaker 11:  I think federal workers are really aware that, you know, their files are
Speaker 11:  stored within these federal agencies too, and
Speaker 11:  their information is at risk. So I think that's definitely on
Speaker 11:  people's minds as well.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  What do you guys think it would take to shift from that thing
Speaker 8:  you're talking about Lauren? Where, where to a lot of people, these
Speaker 8:  agencies and the work they do is sort of one step removed from their real
Speaker 8:  life in a way that makes it hard for this stuff to seem urgent.
Speaker 8:  Like there was a, there was a bunch of stuff going around the other day that
Speaker 8:  was like, okay, a lot of people are about to get social security checks and
Speaker 8:  if that gets disrupted, you're gonna get a lot of people who, who suddenly
Speaker 8:  have a lot of feelings about what's going on inside the government. Is it,
Speaker 8:  is it something like that that it would have to be like everybody, I don't
Speaker 8:  know, everybody just gets all of their money stolen by Elon Musk or like,
Speaker 8:  is there a thing short of that, that we're gonna hit that all of a sudden
Speaker 8:  I think makes this stuff feel a lot closer to home for people? Do you have
Speaker 8:  a sense of what that might be?
Speaker 11:  It's a good question. I mean, I do think it's gonna be something that's
Speaker 11:  gonna be much more tangible for people. I think right now it's really tangible
Speaker 11:  for federal workers or people who, you know, have friends and family who
Speaker 11:  are federal workers. 'cause it's their jobs. They, they might be taking
Speaker 11:  this deferred resignation offer. They might be just living in fear of having
Speaker 11:  their jobs suddenly pulled out from under them.
Speaker 8:  I was at a two year old's birthday party recently and it was literally the
Speaker 8:  only subject of conversation it like, it was, it was so bleak.
Speaker 11:  Oh wow.
Speaker 7:  Well you live in DC
Speaker 8:  I live in DC like I live in northern Virginia. Everyone at this party either
Speaker 8:  worked with or was married to someone who worked with or knew someone who
Speaker 8:  worked at the federal government. Like that stuff is, it hit everybody. And
Speaker 8:  it was, I mean, it was, it was the only thing on anybody's mind. And I think
Speaker 8:  that stuff is gonna start to percolate, right? Like totally the number of
Speaker 8:  people whose jobs are come from grants like that or whose work
Speaker 8:  depends on the companies who get grants like that. Like I I, there there's
Speaker 8:  gonna be a trickle out effect, but I feel like that part might take
Speaker 8:  too long and I kind of, I don't know, maybe there just needs to be one big
Speaker 8:  thing that happens or maybe it'll be the kind of thing you're talking about.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I think it's gonna hit some people maybe in waves where,
Speaker 11:  you know, your company receives funding from the government that suddenly
Speaker 11:  isn't available or things like that. But
Speaker 11:  yeah, I think certainly if it's something that's more on the order of not
Speaker 11:  receiving a social security check-in time, not receiving disability, not,
Speaker 11:  you know, getting your tax return, all those sorts of things would be much
Speaker 11:  more tangible to people. But you know, maybe there's something short
Speaker 11:  of that. Maybe there's some agency that
Speaker 11:  Musk tries to go into that just feels like a bridge too far for people.
Speaker 11:  Or, you know, people get a better understanding of how their data
Speaker 11:  might be used in a really tangible way that's just too scary.
Speaker 11:  Or maybe we see, you know, some of these security risks come to light.
Speaker 11:  I, I think it's hard. It's hard to know and it feels like everything's changing
Speaker 11:  so quickly that to predict it is feels like, you know,
Speaker 11:  we're never really gonna be able to save for sure.
Speaker 7:  You know, it will save the economy though. Is the state Department buying
Speaker 7:  $400 million for the armored testers?
Speaker 8:  They're gonna save us all, all
Speaker 7:  Everyone gets a weird armored cyber track. This story is very strange. Is
Speaker 7:  it, it's one of the funnier moments, I guess of all this,
Speaker 7:  this weird computer coup that's occurring. That's what David called it in
Speaker 7:  our headline last week. And I'm just sticking with it. Computer coup is very
Speaker 7:  good, but you know, we're, we're doing fake transparency. We're reading all
Speaker 7:  the contracts we can find everywhere in the government and a site called
Speaker 7:  Drop Site News found State Department order
Speaker 7:  for $400 million worth of armored Teslas in its
Speaker 7:  2025 procurement forecast. And they tweeted it and then everyone got mad
Speaker 7:  at Elon and then suddenly the State Department changed it
Speaker 7:  to armored electric vehicles. Which is great because I love the idea of an
Speaker 7:  armored VW ID buzz just like floating down the streets of
Speaker 7:  some bombed out city.
Speaker 7:  It's just, but
Speaker 8:  It's yellow so it's charming.
Speaker 7:  It's very good. Who hasn't wanted like an armored Mustang
Speaker 7:  Mach e like I think about it all the time. So then
Speaker 7:  Elon tweeted, I haven't heard about this, which is very funny.
Speaker 7:  Like just generally funny 'cause what, what do you think he's hearing about
Speaker 7:  right now about SpaceX and Tesla? He's busy. He is, he is like
Speaker 7:  rolling into federal offices and firing everybody.
Speaker 7:  So then the state department finally clarified today
Speaker 7:  the plan stemmed from a request by the Biden administration to explore interest
Speaker 7:  from private companies to produce armored electric vehicles. So it's real,
Speaker 7:  right? They, they did put $400 million worth of armored Teslas on
Speaker 7:  a sheet because they, they wanted to, sure. And then they said the
Speaker 7:  solicitation is on hold and there are no current plans to issue it. So
Speaker 7:  it worked. Everyone yelled at Elon about
Speaker 7:  cutting veterans' benefits to buy cyber trucks. By
Speaker 7:  the way, we don't even know if they're cybert trucks. Just an armored. Teslas
Speaker 7:  could have been, could have been armored model threes, you dunno, a bunch
Speaker 7:  of
Speaker 8:  Roadsters,
Speaker 7:  Who knows. Just one of the weirder moments here, right? Where it's like the
Speaker 7:  self-dealing for Elon can hit like
Speaker 7:  maybe Pete Buttigieg is, was like, we should have armored EVs.
Speaker 7:  The next presidential limo should be an armored Escalade
Speaker 7:  iq. You don't know, but it said armored Teslas and they
Speaker 7:  changed it and then they said it was going away. So even that little bit
Speaker 7:  of pressure seems to be working, which I think is really interesting.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I I would encourage people, we, we should put some links in the show
Speaker 8:  notes, but the, there's, there's some really good reporting being done about
Speaker 8:  the ways in which all of these changes are
Speaker 8:  partly chaotic and partly about Elon Musk going after things that might
Speaker 8:  have oversight of him and also putting more things toward
Speaker 8:  SpaceX. And then he gives, you know, speeches in the Oval Office about how
Speaker 8:  everything, every contract they've gotten is what's best for the taxpayer
Speaker 8:  and like sure. But it is like the, the
Speaker 8:  self-dealing here I think is becoming more obvious and
Speaker 8:  he just has no interest in hiding it and no reason to hide it. And in
Speaker 7:  Fact, I think his own financial disclosure is not subject to
Speaker 7:  a records request. Of course. Yeah. Yeah. That's very
Speaker 7:  good.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, it is like, it it is. I I like I said
Speaker 8:  this to Liz on Tuesday show, like I want it to be more complicated than that
Speaker 8:  and I'm increasingly coming around to, it's just, it, it's
Speaker 8:  just that simple. Like Elon Musk bought the government so
Speaker 8:  that he can solve all of his business problems for himself.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's, it, it's a good deal If you can get it. That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 7:  It only cost two cost million. Like it was pretty easy. Like
Speaker 8:  He bought the government for what Jeff Bezos bought the Washington Post for.
Speaker 8:  Think about that. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Meta spent more. I'd rather
Speaker 8:  Have the government,
Speaker 7:  It's just like straightforwardly Instagram costs more money than the United
Speaker 7:  States government.
Speaker 8:  WhatsApp costs 80 times what the government
Speaker 7:  Costs. I was gonna say we have to take a break, but David has a section here
Speaker 7:  labeled Deep Sigh, which is all just links about the Gulf
Speaker 7:  of America. David, go ahead.
Speaker 8:  I just, I did so, okay. The, the short version of the
Speaker 8:  story here is Donald Trump has decided that it's not the Gulf of Mexico,
Speaker 8:  it's the, it's the Gulf of America. And one by one the mapping companies
Speaker 8:  have, have given in and now on Google Maps, it's called the Gulf of America
Speaker 8:  and Apple Maps, it's called the Gulf of America and Bing Maps, which kudos
Speaker 8:  to the reporter who checked because no one in history has ever used Bing
Speaker 7:  Maps. Wait, actually Tom checked and they had it labeled twice in like classic
Speaker 7:  Bing Maps fashion. It's both, it was both for a minute and then it was
Speaker 7:  Gulf of America twice and then they finally went just to Gulf of America.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So the the one intern who maintains big maps. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Got it done. Lauren, I'm particularly curious about this because this is
Speaker 8:  a thing that has been covered a bunch and it's been talked about a bunch
Speaker 8:  and it like became a thing because Trump wouldn't allow
Speaker 8:  the AP access because it kept calling it the Gulf of Mexico and
Speaker 8:  not the Gulf of America. Like part of me is like, this is the stupidest
Speaker 8:  sort of nadier of what's actually going on right now, but it also feels like
Speaker 8:  this has become such a thing in the Trump
Speaker 8:  administration in a way that I just cannot figure out.
Speaker 11:  I I feel like it's just, you know, they're doing a lot of things
Speaker 11:  that are very impactful, like dismantling entire
Speaker 11:  agencies and then they're also doing these things that are kind
Speaker 11:  of like, alright, If you don't agree with it eye roll. But it doesn't really
Speaker 11:  change all that much to change the Gulf of Mexico to Gulf of America.
Speaker 11:  But it creates all of this like just anger around
Speaker 11:  it and you know, all of this like distraction. I think
Speaker 11:  when we have, you know, a lot of other things going on and I think it's
Speaker 11:  just all part of this like flood the zone strategy.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's fair. Like the, who is it, buddy Carter from Georgia who introduced
Speaker 8:  the bill to rename Greenland to red, white, and blue Land, which is just
Speaker 8:  a absurd, and b like a terrible name.
Speaker 7:  If you come on like elect me to Congress, I will do shit like this every
Speaker 7:  day. Do you understand? Vote Patel? I'm actually, I'm
Speaker 7:  not running anywhere. I'm not even sure, you know, at this point merely
Speaker 7:  suggesting that I'm actually running for office might send me to jail. But
Speaker 7:  If you send me America every day,
Speaker 8:  I'm not mad at some, some silliness and like, let's, let's make Fortnite
Speaker 8:  the official video game of the United States Congress. Like
Speaker 8:  require everyone if if a, if instead of having, you know, the,
Speaker 8:  the header, the Secretary of Defense pick anything. Like just whoever
Speaker 8:  wins Fortnite, they get, they get to choose the
Speaker 7:  Gulf of America thing, by the way is very, it's very silly, but it's also
Speaker 7:  like, you know, it's a virgin its way because who gets to name things
Speaker 7:  in Google Maps is a somewhat open question.
Speaker 7:  Trump did issue an executive order instructing the mapping
Speaker 7:  agencies in the United States to rename these things. That's where Google
Speaker 7:  Maps follows the instructions. It's weird 'cause they, some of them have
Speaker 7:  geofenced it and some of 'em haven't. Yeah. So on some of these mapping platforms,
Speaker 7:  only American users see Gulf America and worldwide users see Gulf of Mexico,
Speaker 7:  but the press doesn't have to follow those rules. Right.
Speaker 7:  It just like, not a, like the tech platform is like whatever the government
Speaker 7:  says, like we just do the thing, like you change it in the
Speaker 7:  database, France is now called stupid. Like that's just the way they're gonna
Speaker 7:  do it. Yeah. But
Speaker 8:  It is, it, it, that in itself is a useful reminder of how all of this stuff
Speaker 8:  actually works. Right? Right. Like we, we think of this stuff as, as sort
Speaker 8:  of meaningfully authoritative in some way and it just isn't like Yeah,
Speaker 8:  it just
Speaker 7:  Isn't, it's just, it's just words in a database. Yeah. But the press, like
Speaker 7:  the ap, they're like, look, we also service customers in Mexico
Speaker 7:  in our stories and they haven't changed it, so we're gonna go
Speaker 7:  with both or whatever is more clear and that, that's
Speaker 7:  weird, right? You, it's, it's interesting to see that the press
Speaker 7:  has a much more nuanced perspective of how to talk about things
Speaker 7:  versus the tech platforms which are kind of like, you can boss this around
Speaker 7:  by just changing your databases.
Speaker 11:  I think that that also shows how like, even though this is like, you know,
Speaker 11:  kind of a silly like name change that's not gonna impact a whole
Speaker 11:  lot. It is also becoming a tool for the Trump
Speaker 11:  administration to say, Hey ap, If you don't follow
Speaker 11:  what we're saying, then we're gonna not let you into the
Speaker 11:  White House press room. So
Speaker 7:  By the way, today, just now, third day in a row, the White House barred the
Speaker 7:  AP from attending an event because they won't habituate.
Speaker 8:  There you go. Right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that's just a straightforward first amendment violation. Like
Speaker 7:  you what whatever you think about how silly this is. The government punishing
Speaker 7:  an editorial outlet for their speech. Straightforward First Amendment violation.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  By the way, just in case you're wondering, MapQuest still calls it the Gulf
Speaker 8:  of Mexico.
Speaker 7:  Well they're on notice
Speaker 8:  Now. Big Officer MapQuest.
Speaker 7:  Look, you know Brendan Carlos since the show, what are you doing?
Speaker 7:  He does,
Speaker 7:  even though I'm trying to get him to stop by calling him up by name every
Speaker 7:  week
Speaker 7:  there. Look, it's a, it's a silly example, Lauren. I, I think I agree with
Speaker 7:  you, but it's such a loyalty test now that
Speaker 7:  it just, it just every time, I don't know what I, I, I can't
Speaker 7:  remember the last time the word wrote about the Gulf of Mexico or the Gulf
Speaker 7:  of America or whatever, but like editorially we're gonna say both because
Speaker 7:  we have readers around the world and like not everyone has agreed
Speaker 7:  with this like, weird metaphysical name change. Maybe
Speaker 7:  we're just gonna start calling it the body
Speaker 7:  All right, we're back with the lighting round unsponsored. So
Speaker 7:  extra spicy. But I do wanna begin with a bit of a pallet
Speaker 7:  cleanser and a lightning round. That was a lot of politics. Talk
Speaker 8:  Unsponsored for flavor by the way, is a phrase a surprising number of people
Speaker 8:  have sent to me over the last week. I still don't know what it means, but
Speaker 8:  I like it. You said it, it means nothing, but I like it very much.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't mean anything If you sponsor us, you get no control. It remains
Speaker 7:  as spicy as before, which I think If you would like to give us money is a
Speaker 7:  reason to give us money.
Speaker 8:  Here's my idea is I think we should make it like a skate shirt for
Speaker 8:  unsponsored skaters who are like, I'm too cool to be sponsored.
Speaker 8:  And you just say Unsponsored for flavor. That's my idea. Yeah, it's
Speaker 8:  gonna be great. VERGE merch coming, coming soon
Speaker 7:  As esoteric and incomprehensible as ever.
Speaker 8:  Exactly. But yeah, we have, we have some gadget news.
Speaker 7:  There's gadget news. Hooray. And to, in my mind,
Speaker 7:  very important gadget news, which is that there's a rumor,
Speaker 7:  pretty sketchy rumor actually, that the Apple Studio
Speaker 7:  Display two will have proper mini LED backlighting. This is what
Speaker 7:  you wanna start with. I, there's nothing more important in my life
Speaker 7:  than the fact that buying a 27 inch 5K monitor right now
Speaker 7:  is a nightmare. It's like willingly being
Speaker 7:  mugged. That's, that's the only way you can describe this, especially if
Speaker 7:  you're mean, you've got two old 27 inch IMAX line around and you really wanna
Speaker 7:  retrofit them into being monitors. But you've watched too many videos of
Speaker 7:  people shattering the glass in the front trying to Yeah, trying to open 'em
Speaker 7:  up every day. I look at one, I'm like, I'm gonna screw
Speaker 7:  this up so bad. But we're one day I'm gonna gin myself into doing it. So
Speaker 7:  I it's, I I'm gonna, I'm I'm gonna buy a Mac mini. I'm, I'm, I've convinced
Speaker 7:  myself I'm buy an M four Mac mini and then you're like, I gotta buy a display.
Speaker 7:  And I've been staring at 27 inch Trimac for years, a decade. So
Speaker 7:  not compromising. Right? But I want a 27 inch five a display.
Speaker 7:  And the only thing that makes any sense is the Apple Studio display
Speaker 7:  $1,500 for exactly the same panel I'm looking at
Speaker 7:  now.
Speaker 7:  The worst.
Speaker 7:  There's the Samsung riff, which is
Speaker 7:  worse. Like it just doesn't work with MAs as well and people Yeah, it's,
Speaker 7:  it, it medium reviews. There's a Ben q
Speaker 7:  eh and they're all kind of the same money, right?
Speaker 7:  They're, they're within a couple hundred dollars of each other. You get
Speaker 8:  A Vision Pro and have a really huge monitor. You
Speaker 7:  Can get a Vision pro. There's a bunch of Chinese companies now
Speaker 7:  that are, are like, they're taking the rejected LG
Speaker 7:  5K panels that Apple and others won't use and putting them in
Speaker 7:  really nice cases and selling them for like 800 bucks. But then that's a
Speaker 7:  crap shoot. That's
Speaker 8:  The one I'm gonna end up buying.
Speaker 7:  It's, I mean I'm so close. All of them are the same, like,
Speaker 7:  you know, badly back lit bleed, no black levels
Speaker 7:  ancient panel, like LEDL CD panel, like it's the same panel from
Speaker 7:  a decade ago. Fundamentally. So if Apple puts mini LED backlighting in it
Speaker 7:  and it like is good, like the same way a MacBook display is
Speaker 7:  good, I'm in baby let's go.
Speaker 8:  I mean
Speaker 7:  You listen to me Tim Cook, I know Brendan Carr listens. I don't know if Tim,
Speaker 7:  I'm looking at you Buddy
Speaker 8:  Mac mini plus studio display is, is
Speaker 8:  is the jam. Like that's a pretty good, it doesn't save you
Speaker 8:  any money over any of the other things you could do, but it is a
Speaker 8:  kick ass combination of things. I would be excited about it. I
Speaker 8:  still think that thing is preposterously expensive and will continue to be
Speaker 8:  preposterously expensive. But
Speaker 7:  If it was preposterously expensive and also like bleeding edge technology,
Speaker 8:  Totally.
Speaker 7:  But it's a 10-year-old panel. If I could just gin up the courage and
Speaker 7:  literally, I mean gin up, like drink enough gin to have the courage
Speaker 7:  to take a razor blade to one of my old IMAX and then be fine when
Speaker 7:  I inevitably shatter the screen, I would do it. But I,
Speaker 7:  yeah, I don't like gin. It just, it's like drinking a tree, you know?
Speaker 7:  That
Speaker 8:  Is the main problem. Yeah. It's famously what I've been saying all along.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And bourbon is, is no kind of juice to be drinking when you're doing computer
Speaker 7:  work.
Speaker 8:  Absolutely not. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like slurring. You're mad belligerent.
Speaker 8:  Okay, so for the rest of us here in the real world though, the other Apple
Speaker 8:  rumor and I would say this has graduated beyond rumor
Speaker 8:  and is more like thing that is going to happen next week.
Speaker 8:  Tim Cook posted, get ready to meet the newest member of the family
Speaker 8:  just posted that on X with a really like air tag looking Apple
Speaker 8:  logo, which was weird. But the overwhelming theory is that that's gonna be
Speaker 8:  the new iPhone SE I would like to be on the record of saying
Speaker 8:  no one cares.
Speaker 8:  The iPhone SE is the phone that everyone talks about the most and
Speaker 8:  absolutely no one buys. It's like the overwhelming truth about these devices.
Speaker 8:  Everybody says they want the tiny iPhone and then Apple's like here's a tiny
Speaker 8:  iPhone and no one buys it. This is just what happens.
Speaker 7:  Well a lot of people buy the iPhone. SE do they They do keep making
Speaker 7:  'cause it's the cheap one. And really the problem, the iPhone I see right
Speaker 7:  now is it's the last one with a button. Yeah. So if they add face ID to it,
Speaker 7:  then it will kind of look like a more expensive one.
Speaker 8:  Oh, that's an interesting point. Yeah. The, the rumor is bigger screen,
Speaker 8:  no button face id. So it would just be a cheaper
Speaker 8:  regular iPhone. Which is odd because at some point
Speaker 8:  is the SE just going to be a rebadged version of like the two
Speaker 8:  generations ago iPhone. And if so, what is the point?
Speaker 7:  That's all it ever is. And but they'll they'll increase the RAM so that you
Speaker 7:  can do Apple intelligence. Right. Extraordinarily useful. Everyone loves
Speaker 7:  that Apple intelligence. It's, yeah, right.
Speaker 8:  It's just, it's it's just a way to sell you a cheaper older phone
Speaker 8:  as if it's a new phone. Yeah. Which is like, I don't know, strikes me as
Speaker 8:  probably smart on apple's part, but is so calculated. I just, I don't like
Speaker 8:  it.
Speaker 7:  It's funny that you led into this being like the thing that everyone actually
Speaker 7:  cares about and now you're like, this is garbage. Get outta my face. I'm
Speaker 7:  telling you the studio display too with mini LED. This is a blockbuster product.
Speaker 7:  Blockbuster. Like it's lines around the corner.
Speaker 8:  Do you think the camera's still gonna suck? I
Speaker 7:  Don't care. I I put tape over that camera anyway because I use a ZV
Speaker 7:  one as a webcam, so I don't want to get confused.
Speaker 8:  That's fair.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't matter to me. I just want a great, If you can think of a better
Speaker 7:  way to get a 27 inch 5K display. I think what I'm gonna do now is I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  buy the info MAC mini. I'll buy a super cheap garbage monitor to just
Speaker 7:  hold me over until the studio display two comes up. Or I'm gonna take a rai,
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna liquor up, take
Speaker 8:  A razor. Think it's time for the razor blade. I think we're gonna, you gotta
Speaker 8:  turn on the ZV one. You gotta point it at the iMac and listen,
Speaker 8:  If you destroy it, it's good content. No's all upside's.
Speaker 8:  It's great content because you'll get injured and it'll be so funny
Speaker 7:  Is great. What, what? YouTube. YouTube wants blood is what, what you're saying?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, pretty much. Alright.
Speaker 7:  This is one of my favorite stories a week. 'cause it's so silly. So Jeep
Speaker 7:  is in turmoil. Stellantis is in turmoil as a car company.
Speaker 7:  Their products got too expensive, they forgot to make new products. Like
Speaker 7:  they were just like, what if we didn't make New Chryslers for 10 years? And
Speaker 7:  they're like, crap, we make the same minivan and no other cars weird. Just
Speaker 7:  a weird way to run a company. And then they were like, what if we made a
Speaker 7:  hundred thousand dollars Jeep Grand Wagoneers? And everyone was like, why?
Speaker 7:  And they're like, we don't know why Company in crisis. So now they're gonna
Speaker 7:  roll out some new EVs. They got the new Wagoner s which is slowly rolling
Speaker 7:  out to dealerships. People like it, they don't like it. There's some bad
Speaker 7:  YouTuber reviews. We'll see they're gonna
Speaker 7:  launch the new thing called the Recon ev, which is basically an EV version
Speaker 7:  of the Jeep Wrangler. Which I think might be cool. Like we can take the doors
Speaker 7:  off. Might be great. Yeah. If it has the same weird problems as a wagon air
Speaker 7:  ass, we'll see. But then on top of
Speaker 7:  this, they're doing the thing that every car maker has
Speaker 7:  threatened to do for so long and just hasn't done.
Speaker 7:  They're putting ads in the infotainment, like real
Speaker 7:  ads. Like every time you stop a car running,
Speaker 7:  you connect for four, a popup comes up that says do you want to
Speaker 7:  buy the extended warranty?
Speaker 8:  Are you serious? Like
Speaker 7:  Full screen.
Speaker 8:  That's like a bit from a movie.
Speaker 7:  Like every time you stop the car, oh my god it's very bad. People hate it.
Speaker 7:  It says purchase peace of mind. And it says you can call to purchase a
Speaker 7:  FlexCare extended premium plan If you have less than
Speaker 7:  36,000 miles than eight. Which the car should know by the way.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And then If you just click X to close, it comes back the next time
Speaker 7:  you stop it. This is obviously some kind of weird bug, but it's obviously
Speaker 7:  also a deal with both the, the insurance company with like serious xm which
Speaker 7:  runs the thing. This is a nightmare. Like this is
Speaker 7:  how you destroy your brand for good.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That's literally like dystopian stuff. Like you're gonna show me ads
Speaker 8:  every time my car comes to a complete stop is horrifying. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And it's an ad for of all things an extended warranty in a car that you're
Speaker 7:  in. Like the classic scam. Yeah. Don't do
Speaker 7:  this. R Jeep hasn't done it. 'cause we were running Uconnect five, which
Speaker 7:  is like the Android one. I don't know if all of 'em are gonna start to do
Speaker 7:  it. I the second that happens, I'm getting rid of this car.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I actually think it, I sort of hope some
Speaker 8:  company does it just to test people's resolve
Speaker 8:  against it. Because I think like this question
Speaker 8:  of how invasive can we be before people will revolt?
Speaker 8:  We've spent a long time testing that as a, like the tech industry has
Speaker 8:  poked at that for a long time and has found over and over that it can kind
Speaker 8:  of get away with most things. I think we're gonna show you an ad every time
Speaker 8:  the car stops, people will just set their cars on fire and walk away. Like
Speaker 8:  I think that's a real, that that would do it. And I am sort of hoping
Speaker 8:  somebody actually tests that theory.
Speaker 7:  Solanis by the way, confirmed this is happening. They say it's a glitch.
Speaker 7:  They quote attributed a persistent nature of the ad to a temporary software
Speaker 7:  glitch that affected the optout functionality in certain cases and it has
Speaker 7:  been identified and corrected, blah blah blah, blah, blah. So here's what,
Speaker 7:  here's what you're seeing. They're building an opt-out system for in-car
Speaker 7:  advertising that went haywire and showing ads to everybody because they're
Speaker 7:  gonna build an advertising system that's gonna show you ads in their car.
Speaker 8:  Yep.
Speaker 7:  It's not great.
Speaker 8:  No.
Speaker 7:  This is the weird future. This is why I I drive a 1976
Speaker 7:  Chevy Chevelle. I don't even know if that's a real car, but it'd be cool
Speaker 7:  if it did. Sounds
Speaker 8:  Sick.
Speaker 7:  It does, doesn't it? This is why
Speaker 8:  We're gonna split a 2001 Escalade and that's gonna be both of our cars forever.
Speaker 7:  You know, prices on those 2001 Escalades is one shockingly high since the
Speaker 7:  pandemic.
Speaker 7:  They're sick cars though. Alright, it's time now for our weekly segment.
Speaker 7:  Surprisingly popular Brendan Carr's a dummy people
Speaker 8:  Are saying it's America's greatest meta podcast. The podcast within a podcast.
Speaker 7:  When I say there's now a non-zero chance that I'm going to jail for being
Speaker 7:  the under chief of urge, what I mean specifically is FCC Chairman Brendan
Speaker 7:  Carr might abuse the power of the state to imprison me
Speaker 7:  and I'm daring him to do it. 'cause I will grift off of
Speaker 7:  that happening for the rest of my life. And my children were living opulence
Speaker 7:  and splendor. If you do it, bring it on. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like, do you want to double the neli speaking fee for the rest of his career?
Speaker 8:  Like, let's go Brenda Carr, I'm ready.
Speaker 7:  Bring it on you. Big nerd b Brendan Carr is chairman FCC. He used to
Speaker 7:  be a regular alert. We did an entire decoder about him with Matt Wood, who's
Speaker 7:  the general counsel of Free Press, not the Barry Weis publication, the pre
Speaker 7:  press, the First Amendment advocacy shop. We've been around for 20 years.
Speaker 7:  He used to just like a regular conservative lawyer man, like a gray suit
Speaker 7:  kind of unstylish big nerd. Now he is a monster, like a
Speaker 7:  anti-free speech monster. He's filed all kinds of
Speaker 7:  investigations against all kinds of broadcast outlets because the FCC regulates
Speaker 7:  the airwaves, which is these ideas about what you should do with those airwaves,
Speaker 7:  which is basically only praise Donald Trump and not criticize
Speaker 7:  him or not do anything that could be even perceived as criticism of him.
Speaker 7:  That's a straightforward First Amendment violation from Brendan Carr First
Speaker 7:  Amendment nightmare censor in chief. He also has big ideas about regulating
Speaker 7:  the internet itself, the content on the internet by reinterpreting section
Speaker 7:  two 30 by issuing just a, a a letter and
Speaker 7:  like an agency reinterpretation of the law, which would run straight into
Speaker 7:  Elon Musk's idea about agency regulations. By the way, not a lot of
Speaker 7:  coherency in the Trump administration, but that's his idea.
Speaker 7:  But
Speaker 8:  There is a lot of yelling, like the one thing they all have in common is
Speaker 8:  everybody is yelling and they, it kind of works,
Speaker 7:  Right? And the idea here is you create a chilling effect, right? You don't
Speaker 7:  know if the government will punish you for your speech because they keep
Speaker 7:  threatening everyone with various punishments that may or may not be legal
Speaker 7:  or may not be effective. But you don't wanna get caught up in the hassle
Speaker 7:  caught. So you just do what they say that's bad. That
Speaker 7:  that, that there's a long history of First Amendment cases where the chilling
Speaker 7:  effect from the government is the problem, not the actual government speech
Speaker 7:  triangulation. That's Brendan, Brendan loves this stuff. He loves the chilling
Speaker 7:  effect. There's reporting this week in the Daily Beast that he's quote, having
Speaker 7:  the Time of His Life threatening media organizations in this way.
Speaker 7:  I know that that's true because he retweeted that story
Speaker 7:  and said, If you have a job you love, you'll never work a day in your life.
Speaker 8:  Ugh.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. If you are an unelected and frankly Unstylish
Speaker 7:  government bureaucrat, you should not be bragging about how you're having
Speaker 7:  fun threatening the media.
Speaker 7:  Straightforward. I do not care if you're a republican, a democrat, a libertarian,
Speaker 7:  a raging socialist or whatever.
Speaker 7:  You should not be in the government, unelected, elected, whatever. You should
Speaker 7:  not be a member of the United States government bragging about how much fun
Speaker 7:  you're having threatening the media. It's, it's wrong. It's
Speaker 7:  like anti-American. This man is a traitor to our
Speaker 7:  constitution. I can't say it more plainly than that. He's also, I want to
Speaker 7:  make this clear kind of an idiot.
Speaker 8:  I mean, this, this segment is called Brendan Carr is a dummy on purpose,
Speaker 7:  Right? Like his positions don't have ideological coherency. They
Speaker 7:  have one point which is to threaten people for their speech using the
Speaker 7:  tools that he has. And he's wrapping it up in the language of
Speaker 7:  defending free speech, right? He's, he's sending letters to social media
Speaker 7:  platforms, which he does not have the power to regulate. Threatening them
Speaker 7:  over their fact checking because something, something section two 30, which
Speaker 7:  he will something, something reinterpret with some kind of letter using some
Speaker 7:  kind of power. He doesn't have completely inconsistent
Speaker 7:  Brendan Carr, completely inconsistent dumb. He's the person
Speaker 7:  who is like, I'm getting rid of net neutrality and I will disclaim this
Speaker 7:  agency's power to regulate ISPs in this country in any way,
Speaker 7:  shape, or form. So he's given away his power. He's saying we
Speaker 7:  will not regulate ISPs, we don't have the power to regulate broadband or
Speaker 7:  broadband pricing or collusion or throttling or blocking or any of
Speaker 7:  the stuff that ISPs can do. But I will step through the ISP and
Speaker 7:  directly regulate the content on Instagram. Weird ideologically,
Speaker 7:  completely incoherent.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But I don't, the coherence is not the point, right? Like it's not,
Speaker 8:  it's, it's just, it's just yelling. The goal is to yell and
Speaker 8:  you're gonna, he's winning a lot. Like the, the, the
Speaker 8:  pushback has been,
Speaker 8:  I would say muted in so many ways. And he's been pretty straightforward
Speaker 8:  about what he's trying to do here, which is go after
Speaker 8:  anyone who seems to be on the other side of Donald Trump. Yep.
Speaker 7:  And then, so then this week, his latest broad
Speaker 7:  side, he has said he will investigate Comcast to,
Speaker 7:  you know, big ISP that owns NBC for its DEI
Speaker 7:  policies in order to root out invidious forms of dis discrim discrimination
Speaker 7:  disclosure. NBC Universal, which done by Comcast is investor in
Speaker 7:  boxed, which is The Verge parent company. They hate me. Like, I
Speaker 7:  just wanna be like Comcast does not like me. I, we that we have written
Speaker 7:  endlessly about how Comcast is a bad company that has not supported net
Speaker 7:  neutrality, that has done bad pricing schemes, is is a
Speaker 7:  regional monopoly.
Speaker 7:  It is insane for the government to threaten the speech
Speaker 7:  of Comcast because it has some DI employment policies. It is
Speaker 7:  trying very sure its workforce is
Speaker 7:  diverse. Comcast as a cable company is not really an information
Speaker 7:  provider, right? They're, we don't want them to be an information provider.
Speaker 7:  They're a physical plant company. They run wires in the ground, they send
Speaker 7:  out installers and techs and and service people. They run customer service
Speaker 7:  lines poorly. Again, this is not a company that like we cover, like they're
Speaker 7:  great and they're not a company that likes me. Even though NBC is an investment
Speaker 7:  box. Like it has nothing to do with us. That's the other side of the house.
Speaker 7:  But I'm saying this because you're looking at a employer of a physical plant,
Speaker 7:  like wires in the ground, service people on trucks, customer
Speaker 7:  service people taking calls, and to say that they
Speaker 7:  can't try to diversify that workforce, which is about as
Speaker 7:  blue collar of a workforce as you can get right now is nuts.
Speaker 7:  Like, and Brendan is saying, I'm looking for
Speaker 7:  signs that your initiatives have violated federal employment law.
Speaker 7:  I expect that this investigation in Comcast and its NBC Universal operations
Speaker 7:  will aid the commission's broader efforts to root out invidious forms, DEI
Speaker 7:  discrimination across all sectors. The FEC regulates, well they don't
Speaker 7:  regulate the ISP specifically. They have disclaimed the power to regulate
Speaker 7:  the ISP.
Speaker 8:  Right? Hidden inside of that is, is is a declaration of
Speaker 8:  power over this stuff.
Speaker 7:  Yep. So I'm just saying it's, it's logically
Speaker 7:  incoherent. It, it truly, If you just like look at all the things
Speaker 7:  they say, they don't add up into a, a consistent worldview except we
Speaker 7:  have power and we're gonna use it. And specifically we'll use it if we don't
Speaker 7:  like your speech, Brendan, I know you listen, I know you
Speaker 7:  get weird Google readouts of every time we mention your name,
Speaker 7:  you are more than welcome to come on to coder and defend this stuff. I think
Speaker 7:  it is traitorous. Like it is, it is such an affront to the First Amendment.
Speaker 7:  I I think you should have to answer for it in that framework. And you are
Speaker 7:  welcome to come on our show and try to defend it. But until then, I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  call you a dummy every single week until you put me in jail and make me a
Speaker 7:  rich man because of it.
Speaker 8:  There we go. Put that on a t-shirt.
Speaker 7:  Furious, furious about it again. And I don't care about your politics. The
Speaker 7:  government threatening speech in this way is over the line.
Speaker 8:  Alright,
Speaker 7:  We're gonna end with some gadgets. David has a bunch of gadgets. He is like,
Speaker 7:  we, we organized this to have a Gadget Palette cleanser at the end.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. There's a, there's a just a neli neli, you know, we, we like to keep
Speaker 8:  your blood pressure sort of at a normal level and we, we, we let it get high
Speaker 8:  and then we bring it back down.
Speaker 8:  So two interesting streaming e things this week.
Speaker 8:  One is that Apple TV Plus is out now on
Speaker 8:  Android, which is kind of a huge deal. Apparently
Speaker 7:  It's a really good app.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I haven't actually used it on
Speaker 7:  Android. I saw Dan Seaford, who, you know, he was our crankiest
Speaker 7:  reviewer here at The Verge and now he works at Google. It was like, this
Speaker 7:  is a really good Android app.
Speaker 8:  That's great. Yeah. It works on, it works on foldable phones, it works on
Speaker 8:  tablets. It's like Apple seems to have like, actually kind of done the thing,
Speaker 8:  interesting moment for Apple TV because a, there's an MLS season about to
Speaker 8:  start and Apple is very bought into making the MLSA success. I
Speaker 8:  think that's gone pretty well for Apple and this is gonna be a big year for
Speaker 8:  Apple. Presumably this is the last we will see of Lean No Messi.
Speaker 8:  It's gonna be a whole thing. So I think we're gonna see a lot of Apple soccer
Speaker 8:  stuff this year. But also Severance is back
Speaker 8:  and is is probably, it's either the biggest or
Speaker 8:  second biggest like cultural event. Apple TV Plus has pulled off
Speaker 8:  next to Ted Lasso. And you, you can see Apple is
Speaker 8:  trying to make something out of this into like,
Speaker 7:  Actually I actually think that Apple trying to make severance a hit is
Speaker 7:  it's wonderful because Severance is such a weird
Speaker 7:  and inaccessible show. Yes. Like it is such a weird, it's
Speaker 8:  The opposite of Ted Lasso
Speaker 7:  Slow quiet. Yeah. Right. It's, and it's, it's, it's a puzzle
Speaker 7:  box. It, it's like Apple's like, screw it, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna make this one a hit. You know, like be clear it's
Speaker 8:  Way and everybody should watch it. But it is, it is a very funny one for
Speaker 8:  Apple to have latched onto this way.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it, you know, I I get it. Ben Stiller's directing it, it's got
Speaker 7:  stars in the ca Like the whole, I I understand all of it, but it's such
Speaker 7:  a weird show for Apple to be like, and this is a hit. It's
Speaker 8:  Also like a little bit about how bad a company Apple is.
Speaker 7:  Just like, it's very
Speaker 8:  Good. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Do you steer jobs? So Steve Jobs Keegan, like,
Speaker 7:  it's pretty close. Not No. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 8:  But anyway, If you're not watching separate, you should and now you can on
Speaker 8:  Android, which is interesting next to a bit of
Speaker 8:  YouTube news, which is that TVs are now the biggest
Speaker 8:  platform for YouTube. More people are watching YouTube on their televisions
Speaker 8:  than on their phones for the first time ever on YouTube. YouTube has been
Speaker 8:  talking about how TV is its fastest growing platform for like,
Speaker 8:  forever. Like, I make fun of YouTube executives are raising my talk to 'em
Speaker 8:  about this because it's just the stat that they have used in every press
Speaker 8:  release for like a decade.
Speaker 8:  But I think this is a meaningful moment. We've talked a lot about how
Speaker 8:  Netflix and YouTube are kind of running at and past each other in some really
Speaker 8:  interesting ways.
Speaker 8:  YouTube is just winning. Like imagine a fight that there is and YouTube is
Speaker 8:  winning it. Yeah. And it's, it's blowing up in podcasts.
Speaker 8:  It's hugely important as an entertainment platform for like high-end
Speaker 8:  entertainment. YouTube TV is the biggest name in, in its category
Speaker 8:  at this point. But
Speaker 7:  The wait, it's the middle one. I don't buy, it's high-end entertainment on
Speaker 7:  YouTube. It's not
Speaker 8:  Winning. But like YouTube primetime channels is a thing. Warner Brothers
Speaker 8:  dumped all the Oh sure. I know movies onto it. Like it's a, it's a place
Speaker 8:  for like capital H Hollywood content now in a pretty real way.
Speaker 8:  And now there is this thing that they're like, actually TVs big screens
Speaker 8:  are bigger than phones for YouTube. Which is
Speaker 8:  just kind of a wild thing that I never thought would come true.
Speaker 7:  It's interesting. I wonder if that is at the expense of phones or if at the
Speaker 7:  expense of computers,
Speaker 7:  right?
Speaker 8:  Probably some of both. Like, are people,
Speaker 7:  People choosing to watch YouTube on their TVs because they're no longer watching
Speaker 7:  it on their laptops or their desktops or whatever? Or is it because they
Speaker 7:  come home at night and they were gonna watch something and they would rather
Speaker 7:  scroll TikTok on their phone while something's on TV and YouTube happens
Speaker 7:  to be there?
Speaker 8:  I think there is a lot of that. I mean we've, we've definitely heard a
Speaker 8:  lot about, like YouTube has gone from sort of a second screen
Speaker 8:  phenomenon to a first screen phenomenon in a way that I think TikTok is like
Speaker 8:  a second screen phenomenon. Like you, you put on the office sort
Speaker 8:  of quietly while you look at TikTok on your phone. Like YouTube has become
Speaker 8:  the office, which like yeah, is is good and bad I suppose.
Speaker 8:  But it is like, it is a living room platform
Speaker 8:  now in a really interesting way. And they've been chasing that with product
Speaker 8:  stuff. Like they're working with creators to turn things into like
Speaker 8:  seasons and they're doing the deals with the Hollywood studios and stuff.
Speaker 8:  So I think, my guess is this push from YouTube to do
Speaker 8:  more subscription based stuff. Do more like high
Speaker 8:  production value stuff, which is a thing YouTube has kind of
Speaker 8:  intermittently done over the years. They had that like YouTube originals
Speaker 8:  thing a million years ago with Jay-Z that didn't work and they've poked at
Speaker 8:  this before. But I think this, this thing where YouTube is going to try to
Speaker 8:  become a high-end streaming service on top of everything else, I think
Speaker 8:  is only going to accelerate because of all this. Because now like I sit down
Speaker 8:  and I open the YouTube app on my TV is a
Speaker 8:  default behavior for people clearly. Like it's a, it's a meaningful thing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And that once you have that you can do anything you want. Right? Like
Speaker 8:  that's what's worked for Netflix. It's
Speaker 7:  Funny 'cause I have all of YouTube's personalization turned off and so I
Speaker 7:  open that app in my TV and it's like, please turn the personalization. Like,
Speaker 7:  it's like begging you, it's like we're so useless unless you let us track
Speaker 7:  everything you watch. I'm like, well that sucks for you. You
Speaker 8:  Just get that empty home screen where they're like, we don't know. It's your
Speaker 8:  fault. It's a, they're
Speaker 7:  Thank you. It is a delight. And it's so, it's funny, funny that they won't
Speaker 7:  populate it anyway. Like it's, they've actively made it
Speaker 7:  worse so that you will be compelled to turn on the personal. And I'm like,
Speaker 7:  no, If you wanna put stuff here, you're more than welcome to put stuff here.
Speaker 7:  But no thank you sir.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's good stuff. YouTube is like sneakily a very
Speaker 8:  petty platform in that way and I really enjoy that about YouTube.
Speaker 8:  Two more gadgets. One, Alison reviewed the
Speaker 8:  Samsung Galaxy S 25 and S 25 plus. We talked a bunch about the
Speaker 8:  Ultra when she reviewed it. It turns out, imagine
Speaker 8:  last year's Samsung phone
Speaker 7:  You
Speaker 8:  Did it. It's, and I think it's, it's inspired a bunch of like
Speaker 8:  conversation about sort of what we want from our smartphones now.
Speaker 8:  And I think my thesis with this has been that we're going
Speaker 8:  to have a year full of really uninteresting smartphone launches and that
Speaker 8:  maybe that's okay and that maybe we have just fully hit the point where these
Speaker 8:  things are in, in a meaningful way finished.
Speaker 8:  Like we, we have done it, they are what they are and we're all gonna
Speaker 8:  kind of move on with our lives and everybody will pivot to the next thing.
Speaker 8:  And then maybe that's okay. Like we had a, we had a damn near two decades
Speaker 8:  of smartphones being really interesting and maybe they just won't be ever
Speaker 8:  again. And maybe that's fine.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Do you think the next thing
Speaker 7:  is the AI hype gadget. Do you think the next thing is a foldable?
Speaker 7:  What do you think? What's your bet?
Speaker 8:  That's a really interesting question. I do think there,
Speaker 7:  There's a lots, there's a lot of people betting on, well If you just talk
Speaker 7:  to phones right? The AI will re yeah, you will
Speaker 7:  rethink the form factor.
Speaker 8:  I think there's probably a little bit of that. I think, I think we're due
Speaker 8:  for a really interesting run of wearable design.
Speaker 8:  I think this, this idea that we just landed on smart watches and
Speaker 8:  that was fine and we fixed it is not correct And I'm, I'm already
Speaker 8:  starting to see glimmers from people about like obviously there's glasses
Speaker 8:  happening, but like I think rings are gonna be more interesting than we have
Speaker 8:  realized so far. There's actually like kind of a lot you can do there.
Speaker 8:  Meta is gonna roll out. Its weird wristband thing at some point.
Speaker 8:  Like there's gonna be stuff on your body that I think people are gonna start
Speaker 8:  to mess with. Like headphones. There's a lot of interesting stuff you can
Speaker 8:  do in headphones that we haven't done yet. That's,
Speaker 8:  that's my theory is that we're gonna, we're gonna, I don't know if any that
Speaker 8:  it will amount to anything, but like that's gonna be the next place
Speaker 8:  we do real, I think like gadget experimentation is kind of
Speaker 8:  wearables of all sorts, which I'm all for. Like, let the smartphone in my
Speaker 8:  pocket just be a modem for all the wearables on my body and I'm down. I love
Speaker 8:  it.
Speaker 7:  This really implies that Bluetooth is gonna be better next year. I'm
Speaker 7:  saying Bluetooth is fine. You're making a bet.
Speaker 8:  I look forward to at some point just spending an hour debating the merits
Speaker 8:  of Bluetooth and it's gonna be you being very upset and me just being like,
Speaker 8:  I'm using Bluetooth headphones right now. Fine. Now I'm
Speaker 7:  Gonna win this argument right now. The next gadget on your list, you're wearing
Speaker 7:  them right now.
Speaker 8:  I am wearing 'em right now.
Speaker 7:  Involve a custom proprietary riff on Bluetooth so that
Speaker 7:  they can be good.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so the, it's the, the Beats Powerbeats Pro two.
Speaker 8:  Not a great name, but it's fine. They came out this week,
Speaker 8:  Chris Welch wrote about them V song reviewed them. They're cool. Like the,
Speaker 8:  their shtick is basically their, their workout AirPods. They have the, the
Speaker 8:  ear hook that people really like. I really like it.
Speaker 8:  It's just they're more secure in your ears than AirPods are for that reason.
Speaker 8:  They have heart rate tracking in the headphones, which I think is cool. This
Speaker 8:  is what I mean by there's more stuff you can do in headphones. They're starting
Speaker 8:  to do some of that like biometric stuff. I went to
Speaker 8:  Target this morning to buy a pair. I had to explain to the
Speaker 8:  guy that these things had launched today and they existed and that I wanted
Speaker 8:  them, I bought the, the quicksand color. Ooh.
Speaker 8:  Which is fine. I was gonna buy orange, but then I was like, I'm gonna get
Speaker 8:  orange and then I'm gonna get on video calls and I'm gonna have to explain
Speaker 8:  my headphones every single time. And I just wasn't ready for that.
Speaker 8:  But I think for like two 50, these are pretty good headphones. But your point
Speaker 8:  is exactly correct. That the specific reason they are good and the
Speaker 8:  specific reason that I bought them is because they're not just Bluetooth,
Speaker 7:  Right?
Speaker 8:  They have the H two chip, which lets it do some really good like multi-point
Speaker 8:  stuff. It, it makes the connection better. It's just, it is better than
Speaker 8:  Bluetooth because it is allowed to be and because only Apple is allowed to
Speaker 8:  do these things inside of its ecosystem.
Speaker 8:  But like I am currently connected to my
Speaker 8:  iPhone, my computer and my iPad on my headphones and that
Speaker 8:  is cool. And that is not good Bluetooth.
Speaker 8:  It's just doesn't work.
Speaker 7:  That's some breaking news for you David.
Speaker 8:  Do you
Speaker 7:  The Verge was just nominated for the National Magazine Award.
Speaker 7:  Whoa. In general Excellence. Let go. It's the National Geographic Let's New
Speaker 7:  York, the New Yorker Pub, ProPublica and The Verge.
Speaker 8:  Hell yeah.
Speaker 7:  And also 2004 was nominated for
Speaker 7:  the National Magazine Award for single topic issue.
Speaker 8:  Boo. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  That's pretty exciting.
Speaker 8:  That's awesome.
Speaker 7:  I do like the idea that one day we'll win this national magazine award for
Speaker 7:  general excellence. You have to beat New York and the New Yorker every year.
Speaker 7:  I think they get nominated every year. What is it?
Speaker 8:  It's New York, new Yorker Atlantic and New York Times
Speaker 7:  Magazine. The Atlantic is not nominated this year.
Speaker 8:  I know, but those are like the four that just tend to pass it around between
Speaker 8:  each other, right? Yep. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  This is our shot.
Speaker 8:  I love it. I'm ready. We're coming for you Nat Geo,
Speaker 7:  Our sister location at New York Magazine. We're coming for
Speaker 7:  you. David Haskell and I are gonna have to like lock eyes in the office when
Speaker 7:  we walk past each other. Love it. All your headphones are fine. I'm now,
Speaker 7:  I'm in a good mood 'cause we got nominated for the National Magazine Award.
Speaker 8:  There
Speaker 7:  We go. This breaking news. I literally got the email. I stopped listening
Speaker 7:  to you 'cause I saw this email. Yeah, I apologize.
Speaker 8:  We could all tell you stop listening to me. It's fine. But it's good. It
Speaker 8:  saves us all from yet another Bluetooth rant, so thank you to the ASEs
Speaker 8:  for doing that
Speaker 7:  For us. Look, if I get this award before I go to jail, you know, that'd be
Speaker 7:  pretty good. Just saying to the committee. I think that'd be pretty good.
Speaker 8:  Love it.
Speaker 7:  All right, we gotta take a break. Move back next week,
Speaker 7:  every week, whether we're incarcerated or not. That's
Speaker 7:  your chest rock and roll.
Speaker 15:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 15:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE
Speaker 15:  one one. The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media
Speaker 15:  Podcast network. Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and
Speaker 15:  Brandon Keefer. And that's it. We'll see you next week.