# Transcript
ID: f01f11ae-0f15-4593-bc70-f80f9c5b886e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6115707810796689148/-2478712901945486417/s93290-US-5653s-1757298633.mp3
Description: It's a big week for the smart home. Jake, Vee, and Jen sit down to chat about all the new tech out of IFA, from robots that carry robot vacuums up stairs to upgrades that turn 10-year-old Hue bulbs into motion sensors. Then, Lauren joins the show to talk about the Google antitrust remedies ruling and what Google is going to have to do to allow more competition in the search market. Finally, the Thunder Round is back and better than ever. We're talking $2,000 smart watches, Amazon yanking a major Prime perk, the Pixel 10 Pro's 100x AI zoom, Instagram for iPad, and drama at the FTC.
Speaker 5:  here today, but got some big news here. David Pierce
Speaker 5:  will be back starting next week. He'll be on the podcast.
Speaker 5:  So tune in, look forward to that today. We've got a great crew though
Speaker 5:  with me for the whole show is gonna be V Song,
Speaker 5:  senior Reviewer at The Verge.
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 5:  And V, you just had a big announcement.
Speaker 6:  Yes, I did. I launched Optimizer, which is
Speaker 6:  our latest newsletter.
Speaker 5:  All it's,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's gonna be a fun time. I will be
Speaker 6:  having several existential crises as I test out
Speaker 6:  text claims to make your life better with whatever app,
Speaker 6:  ai, gizmo, smartwatch, you know, the whole spiel.
Speaker 6:  You know, we're gonna, we're gonna dive into whether these things actually
Speaker 6:  make your life better.
Speaker 5:  I'm so excited for this v's. Already been writing basically a bunch of these
Speaker 5:  on the site. And so if you've been reading her stuff lately, being like,
Speaker 5:  these are wild, these are ridiculous. Like, that's, that's what optimizers
Speaker 5:  is gonna be. It's gonna be really fun. So check it out The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  We've got a lot to talk about today. There is a huge
Speaker 5:  ruling in the Google antitrust case. Lauren Finer, The Verge
Speaker 5:  Senior Policy Reporter is gonna join us later to talk about that. But first
Speaker 5:  we've got Jen Tuey here. She's in Berlin
Speaker 5:  at the Iffa Trade Show. Jen, how's it going? Good,
Speaker 7:  Thanks. Yeah, hot and sweaty. It's like 900 degrees in
Speaker 7:  Berlin,
Speaker 7:  but having a, having a blast checking out all the, the fun gadgets and the
Speaker 7:  robots carrying robots. So it's, it's, it's
Speaker 7:  always a good time here.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I have an important question. How is your hotel
Speaker 5:  room? Is there any smart tech that's,
Speaker 7:  No,
Speaker 5:  It's not. I've
Speaker 7:  Never been in a smart tech hotel. I think they only exist in California,
Speaker 5:  Honestly. Oh, okay. Well that's that We need to make your next trip over
Speaker 5:  to California. Yes. I thought I was hoping that because of efa, you'd, you'd
Speaker 5:  have a, a slightly smarter swankier AI
Speaker 5:  infused hotel. But no, nothing yet. No.
Speaker 7:  Okay,
Speaker 5:  We'll, we'll get there.
Speaker 7:  This, this one can't even do the air conditioning. It's definitely not smart.
Speaker 7:  Oof.
Speaker 5:  It's not good. What floor are you on?
Speaker 7:  I can open my window. That's the nice thing
Speaker 5:  About Europe. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Is Europeans that you open windows.
Speaker 5:  That's, you know what, that's technology. Yes. It's a different kind. That
Speaker 5:  is very
Speaker 7:  True.
Speaker 5:  So Jen is in, in Germany for efa. Iffa is this
Speaker 5:  big European tech show. There's been a lot of stuff going
Speaker 5:  on. Samsung announced a new fe phone and a tablet anchor has a cool new
Speaker 5:  party speaker slash party projector. But Smart Home
Speaker 5:  is the start of the show. It has been for the last few years. There are a
Speaker 5:  bunch of robot vacuums, a lot of smart lights, a big announcement from
Speaker 5:  Phillips Hue that turns its smart bulbs into motion detectors.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna get into all of that. I, I guess, Jen, you've been walking around
Speaker 5:  the show all day. How is it and, and what are people buzzing about?
Speaker 7:  So today was the media day, and unlike, so if it is kind of
Speaker 7:  like CES for Europe, but unlike
Speaker 7:  CES for America and here in in efa, you don't have to go to
Speaker 7:  little boring press rooms. They have their press conferences for all the
Speaker 7:  media on the show floor, but they haven't finished putting their booth together.
Speaker 7:  So we're basically dodging, literally dodging forklift
Speaker 7:  trucks and ladders and like buckets of paint as we try
Speaker 7:  and go and, and check out these press conferences. So I haven't got to really
Speaker 7:  get hands on in too many booths yet because they're
Speaker 7:  still building them. But we got a lot of announcements. So, but it was
Speaker 7:  fun to sort of get a few sneak peeks, you know, round the back of the curtain
Speaker 7:  for some of the booths. So dreamy had a big press conference in their
Speaker 7:  booth today, and that was one of the, one
Speaker 7:  of the more sort of, huh, this is kind of cool, but do we really
Speaker 7:  need it Moments, which was a stair climbing
Speaker 7:  robot. And this is something that has been sort of dear to my
Speaker 7:  heart in the robot vacuum world, you know, robots with
Speaker 7:  various limbs and things that they can
Speaker 5:  Do, like actual, like proper stairs because I feel like it's been announced
Speaker 5:  before proper stairs. And they're like, it can, it's actually just like a
Speaker 5:  bump. You go of a bump know you're right. So this is, this will walk.
Speaker 7:  We've had these levels. We now we're at the B this, so, so
Speaker 5:  What are we talking about here? Legs, treads,
Speaker 7:  Treads. So it's, it's okay. It's actually, they call them arms or, well,
Speaker 7:  there's two companies that have actually released the same robot concept.
Speaker 7:  UFI has one, which you can actually are gonna be able to buy relatively soon,
Speaker 7:  I think next year. And then dreamy has announced its concept
Speaker 7:  and its tracks and they basically fold their
Speaker 7:  sort of arms out from the body and turn into tracks
Speaker 7:  and then track, track, track, track, track up the stairs. So it went up like
Speaker 7:  nine stairs and then stopped, turned around and came
Speaker 7:  down. That's
Speaker 5:  Almost a whole flight of stairs. That's almost,
Speaker 6:  Is there a limit to the number of stairs they can do? Because, you know,
Speaker 6:  I live in a four floor townhouse. It would be nice to have one
Speaker 6:  stair climbing robot instead of four robo vacuums
Speaker 6:  that are limited to each floor. So,
Speaker 7:  So they didn't release specs on the dreamy one, but the UFI
Speaker 7:  one, they did say it can go up to, I think it was up to five flights
Speaker 7:  and they can turn corners and so, you know, and, and do different
Speaker 7:  shapes of stairs. But the way it works is instead of it actually being
Speaker 7:  a robot vacuum, it's just a robot and the robot vacuum gets
Speaker 7:  into it and gets carried up. So it's like a stair lift for
Speaker 7:  your robot vacuum.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. That is so cool
Speaker 6:  and so frightening at the same time.
Speaker 6:  I'm just
Speaker 7:  Waiting for my cat to like, decide, okay, I'm gonna hop on and get, get a
Speaker 7:  ride
Speaker 5:  Up. Okay. Got w So it's, it's a robot for your ro it's a myth. It's a robot
Speaker 5:  for that your robot gets into. Yeah, and that's, I feel
Speaker 5:  like we've gone too far. I think you have
Speaker 7:  To Engineers cleaning our floors. I really do.
Speaker 5:  It's, that's so impressive. The other
Speaker 7:  Thing that thing that gets me is it doesn't clean the stairs. I want something
Speaker 7:  that cleans
Speaker 5:  The stairs.
Speaker 6:  Oh, come on. It's right there.
Speaker 5:  That's next year's robot. It, it will also carry the separate, buy
Speaker 5:  it separately stair cleaning bot as it brings it up.
Speaker 5:  I, so yeah, it's a little crazy. Rob robots are always good for like, truly
Speaker 5:  ridiculous robot technology. It does feel like they really turned a corner
Speaker 5:  this year and have been adding all these limbs and appendages. It's
Speaker 5:  wild. It's not clear that any of them work like amazingly you tested the
Speaker 5:  one with the arm, with the robot arm, right? Yeah. And it was like, eh, it
Speaker 5:  was fine
Speaker 7:  At a vacuum, but the arm was very limited.
Speaker 6:  Well, you know, it's Gen one, it's a gen one arm.
Speaker 6:  Yes. So I I I do, I do have one question about EFA
Speaker 6:  and is it still at Mess Berlin? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Which is a, a, a fascinating building. I mean if you're into brutalist
Speaker 7:  German architecture, then you will love this place. But it's also
Speaker 7:  a maze, which is actually, you know, there's stairs everywhere. So honestly
Speaker 7:  I could have used one of these for me, like a Jen
Speaker 7:  transporter to take me around around the,
Speaker 5:  The conference. That's how they'll really impress us. Yes. So what, what
Speaker 5:  has been your number one thing so far of the show?
Speaker 7:  Well, I, I was very into all the Hue lighting
Speaker 7:  announcements yesterday. They, they did a big event
Speaker 7:  out, not actually in the message, which is probably one of the reasons
Speaker 7:  I liked it.
Speaker 7:  And they did a big event where they announced a ton of new lights.
Speaker 7:  The sort of headline feature for most people is that their products are getting
Speaker 7:  cheaper or, so they've re released a
Speaker 7:  new line of essentials light bulbs that starts at around $15 a bulb,
Speaker 7:  which is still not the least expensive smart bulb you can buy.
Speaker 7:  But
Speaker 5:  Definitely, I mean that's like a quarter of the price, right? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like a hu bulb is 60 bucks.
Speaker 7:  60 bucks. So it's 25 9, 24 99
Speaker 7:  for a single essentials bulb. But if you buy a four pack, it's down
Speaker 7:  to $15 a bulb. So it's, yeah, it's, that's, that's great.
Speaker 5:  That's wild pricing for, for Hue big
Speaker 6:  Change the colors.
Speaker 7:  Yes. So they're all white and color ambiance bulbs, they just have, so they
Speaker 7:  don't dim quite as deep. They have slightly less temperature
Speaker 7:  range and they say that the, while the color accuracy is very good,
Speaker 7:  it's not, they don't, it's not as guaranteed to
Speaker 7:  be match perfectly with all your other hue
Speaker 7:  bulbs in the way that their premium bulbs are. So that, that was
Speaker 7:  kind of nice I think for the market to see that because Hue has always been
Speaker 7:  a very popular product. But the number one complaint I hear from people
Speaker 7:  is it's just so expensive. And now there are all these other products on
Speaker 7:  the market and with Matter, you know, it's much easier. It used to be for
Speaker 7:  Hue, they worked with everyone. So that was a great selling point
Speaker 7:  and maybe one of the reasons you might think to spend more but with matter
Speaker 7:  now most smart lighting bulbs work with most platforms
Speaker 7:  so that they were kind of losing that differentiating factor. I think that
Speaker 7:  probably played into needing to move, you know, have more choice
Speaker 7:  for the, for people. But the really exciting thing for,
Speaker 7:  for me anyway, I'm not sure if this is as exciting for most people as the
Speaker 7:  pricing, but is that they have released a new
Speaker 7:  feature, which is a software upgrade that will go on every HU
Speaker 7:  Bobb made after 2014. So basically
Speaker 7:  second gen on that turns your light bulbs into motion sensors.
Speaker 5:  This is wild. This is,
Speaker 6:  This is what I've wanted this whole year of like
Speaker 6:  building my first smart home in this very vertical townhouse.
Speaker 6:  Like the Cold War my spouse And I have is over the smart lights.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. 'cause I like to use voice and they're like the
Speaker 6:  Google assistant kind of discriminates against their voice and never
Speaker 6:  works even though we've trained it. So they're just like, I
Speaker 6:  gotta pull out an app. What's wrong with a light switch? But you know,
Speaker 6:  if it was a motion sensor and I'm guessing it turns on when you walk
Speaker 6:  into a room or turns off when you leave it, then we don't have to have any
Speaker 6:  fights anymore about turning on the lights.
Speaker 7:  Tagline. This is save my Marriage. Yeah. Philip Hughes saving people's marriages.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 7:  Really, well you could get a motion sensor. EI mean to be fair, you can buy
Speaker 7:  motion sensor. We
Speaker 6:  Could, we could. But you know, it's, it's kind of cool if you don't have
Speaker 6:  to buy multiple devices
Speaker 7:  And motion sensors can be fiddly. It's kind of one of the
Speaker 7:  advantages of this tech is it covers a larger area than say a
Speaker 7:  traditional PIR sensor. But, but there are a few
Speaker 7:  caveats here. You have to have three bulbs in the room
Speaker 7:  in the area. You want the motion sensing because it kind of triangulates
Speaker 7:  and what it's using is RF sensing. So that's something
Speaker 7:  that we've seen with wifi, wireless wifi sensing,
Speaker 7:  ZigBee, Bluetooth. There's some of this in a couple products
Speaker 7:  that use Bluetooth mesh sensing. But this is the first product to launch
Speaker 7:  that uses ZigBee RF sensing and it's a
Speaker 7:  technology developed by a company called Ivani called
Speaker 7:  fy, which I wrote about a, a year or so ago. And we kind of
Speaker 7:  speculated at the time that this might be what Hugh was going to be using
Speaker 7:  for its bulbs because they're obviously one of the most well-known ZigBee
Speaker 7:  based smart lighting lines. And so it use, it's basically just
Speaker 7:  detects disturbances in the radio frequency
Speaker 7:  signals between the bulbs. So that's why you need at least, I think they
Speaker 7:  recommend three to four, which could be a bit tricky and
Speaker 7:  depending on what kind of a room you have and you don't, I
Speaker 7:  asked and they said no, you don't do like, like three in a row. Like if you
Speaker 7:  had track lighting, that's probably not gonna work that well 'cause it's
Speaker 7:  not creating a zone. So there's gonna be a bit of setting up to do,
Speaker 7:  I did test a wifi version of this that whiz, which is
Speaker 7:  Hugh's sister company had for their bulbs
Speaker 7:  and it wasn't super reliable. It would turn
Speaker 7:  on okay. But it was the turning off part that was less reliable.
Speaker 7:  So, but Hugh says that they've worked, they've been working on this for,
Speaker 7:  for a long time, like multiple years
Speaker 7:  specifically sort of fine tuning the reliability aspect. So I'm
Speaker 7:  gonna be really interested to, to try it out because it is
Speaker 7:  the idea that you can take a product you already own
Speaker 7:  and upgrade it to get this kind of function is a
Speaker 7:  great thing for the smart home. Also not having little white
Speaker 7:  boxes and sensors around the house. I mean I have a hue motion sensor so
Speaker 7:  they're great, but like my kid will move it or
Speaker 7:  my husband will get annoyed by the light. You know, it's occasionally it
Speaker 7:  will blink a little LED light and he'll like put it flat on its face so it's
Speaker 7:  no longer sensing motion. But there is one caveat
Speaker 7:  you do have to have the new Hue bridge pro for this to work. Sorry,
Speaker 7:  just got that one in there. No,
Speaker 5:  No, no, that's great. So it, it really is remarkable though. Like I I truly
Speaker 5:  cannot think of another instance where a company went and
Speaker 5:  retroactively added a major feature to
Speaker 5:  10 years worth of products. Yeah. And especially something a
Speaker 5:  as substantially different as this. Like this is a very clever
Speaker 5:  implementation and a very clever new feature and
Speaker 5:  you know, you, you are right. Like there is this important caveat so you
Speaker 5:  do have to have this new hub to enable it. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  it sounds like there's a legitimate reason for that, right? They're not just
Speaker 5:  like PEG gating it.
Speaker 7:  Right? So it is a heavy technical load
Speaker 7:  to process. So what happens is that the bulbs can be firmware
Speaker 7:  updated to support the sort of tech stack of the
Speaker 7:  ified technology with the hue technology sort of mixed in.
Speaker 7:  But they then all they do is detect motion. They don't
Speaker 7:  know what that motion is. And so they send their signals back to the
Speaker 7:  bridge, which processes uses algorithms that have been
Speaker 7:  kind of fine tuned to detect specific types of motion. So
Speaker 7:  there are two use cases for this that Hughes touting. There's motion
Speaker 7:  sensing for turning your lights on and that's free if, if you by
Speaker 7:  the bridge. But it's also been used for security 'cause Hugh has a
Speaker 7:  security suite of cameras and now a new siren.
Speaker 7:  So you could actually use it like a security system. And the security algorithm
Speaker 7:  is different from the motion sensing algorithm. The motion sensing algorithm
Speaker 7:  actually needs to be more precise. But the security, I
Speaker 7:  mean more
Speaker 7:  needs to be quicker. It needs to be super fast. Whereas the security algorithm
Speaker 7:  doesn't need to be as fast, but it needs to be very accurate.
Speaker 7:  'cause you don't want to trigger an alarm for a false alarm. So Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And that they're charging for that's a dollar a month or it's
Speaker 7:  part of their hue secure system. But yeah, that, so the
Speaker 7:  bridge is doing all that processing of the data that the, the
Speaker 7:  radio waves disturbances are sending to the
Speaker 7:  bridge and then it decides what's gonna happen, what's
Speaker 7:  what's been triggered. Were
Speaker 5:  They able to demo any of this for you yet? Yes. Okay. So you actually did,
Speaker 5:  you walked in and saw the lights come on. Yes. Like
Speaker 5:  and so, okay, this is my big question. Like how obviously you have to do
Speaker 5:  a lot more testing to see how reliable it is, but like was it, was it fast?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Was
Speaker 7:  It quite Oh yeah, it was very, it was very fast. The, but I didn't get to
Speaker 7:  see how long it, so for me, as I mentioned is the it turning off,
Speaker 7:  right? Because that's, that's the tricky one. Like I, I get this with my
Speaker 7:  spouse all the time. Like the lights turned off on me And I, you know,
Speaker 7:  I didn't want them to turn off And I was like, well you weren't moving enough.
Speaker 5:  Oh right. Well this is important 'cause you know, you, you say this in your
Speaker 5:  piece, it's motion sensing, it's not presence sensing. Correct. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And So if you are just sitting there, the lights will still turn off on
Speaker 7:  You. Yes.
Speaker 6:  What about
Speaker 7:  Pets? Right? Again, like if
Speaker 6:  I have a naughty little kitty who is zooming
Speaker 6:  around at 2:00 AM and I'm trying to, I mean I want my kitty
Speaker 6:  to see you're doomed.
Speaker 7:  They can see in the dark. No, it is, it's just like having
Speaker 7:  a PIR sensor in that if, if you have a
Speaker 7:  large animal, it will probably trigger it. Like my dog constantly triggers
Speaker 7:  my motion sensors, but there is a sensitivity slider
Speaker 7:  like there is with PIR merchant sensors in the app. So you can
Speaker 7:  adjust sort of fine tune it for your household.
Speaker 7:  So I mean, I say, and the turning off part is to me
Speaker 7:  is quite important because I have often, often have my lights turn off on
Speaker 7:  me while I'm still in a room while I'm still doing something. And that's
Speaker 7:  very frustrating. So that's the part I, I mean they didn't really demo that
Speaker 7:  'cause they're not gonna be like, let's sit here for 10 minutes and wait
Speaker 7:  for the lights to turn off. So I'm looking forward to trying that out. So
Speaker 7:  just
Speaker 6:  Do stretch breaks, do stretches every once in a while and make arm motions
Speaker 6:  and Yeah. And you know, the next time you're a smart watch is like, hey,
Speaker 6:  you've been sitting too long. You can go like, oh yeah, my life time to me,
Speaker 7:  Me,
Speaker 6:  Me a move around. So maybe this is a
Speaker 6:  holistic health and lighting. Shannon, I don't know.
Speaker 7:  Or maybe you could have, we could somehow tie in your smartwatch
Speaker 7:  to your motion sensing te technology to
Speaker 7:  tell you that you are still
Speaker 7:  moving a little bit. Because this is something else I saw a lot
Speaker 7:  of on the show floor today is a,
Speaker 7:  is the sort of holistic home,
Speaker 7:  the holistic smart home, everything feeding data into a central
Speaker 7:  AI powered system. They don't want to say
Speaker 7:  AI agent yet because it's not really agentic, but we, you
Speaker 7:  can see that we could be moving to the point where data that
Speaker 7:  your home takes in can then
Speaker 7:  be processed and,
Speaker 7:  and some sort of intelligent decision could be made to predict perhaps
Speaker 7:  what you might want to do next or what you might want your
Speaker 7:  home to do next. Like you are getting a bit warm,
Speaker 7:  maybe your smartwatch can send that data and your
Speaker 7:  home could decide to turn your AC on for you. I know there's a, there was
Speaker 7:  a lot of that, algae had a whole sort of AI home
Speaker 7:  booth. They actually had an entire orchestra
Speaker 7:  of appliances.
Speaker 5:  Oh my gosh,
Speaker 6:  This sounds so much like, what was it? It's just
Speaker 6:  fresh on my mind because we just had the Pixel event. But this sounds so
Speaker 6:  much like that whole ambient computing thing that Google
Speaker 6:  is always on about and just how everything will be invisible. Yes. And
Speaker 6:  you'll have, this is the conspiracy theory. You'll have all these devices
Speaker 6:  just feeding data to each other and talking to each other and the AI in
Speaker 6:  your home will be the the thread. Yes. Another smart home
Speaker 6:  pun to tie it all together.
Speaker 6:  And so, you know, it, it really, you know, I think back in the day we're
Speaker 6:  like AI ambient computing. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. But now it's just
Speaker 6:  like all starting to fall together
Speaker 6:  into the same piece and hearing this, I'm just like, yeah, I want motion
Speaker 6:  sensors in my lights would be really cool if it talks to my smart
Speaker 6:  watch for those reasons. I mean, I'm sure we could think of a really
Speaker 6:  dystopian use case for it like that. I don't know if you saw the Disney
Speaker 6:  Channel movie, like about the smart home that goes really
Speaker 6:  rogue on the family at one point. But
Speaker 6:  you know, I, I think, I think it sounds great. It would be super
Speaker 6:  convenient for me. Like me personally,
Speaker 5:  This AI stuff does seem to be like it, this is the next frontier for them,
Speaker 5:  right? Yes. That switch bot also had this announcement that they're gonna
Speaker 5:  do an AI hub and it seems like all these companies are going,
Speaker 5:  okay, we put enough stuff in your home. It's
Speaker 5:  kind of complicated, but maybe let, let out, maybe we all mix it
Speaker 5:  around with ai. Yeah. Like it turns into something more coherent.
Speaker 5:  Like that's that's the next move. But we're not sure if it works yet.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's, I think you're right. It's, it's very much about like there
Speaker 7:  is so much capability in the smart home tech world today, but
Speaker 7:  getting people to actually use those capabilities is, is hard because
Speaker 7:  it's a steep learning curve for a lot of things. Even just a motion sensor
Speaker 7:  just to, if you went and bought motion sensor and tried to set it up and
Speaker 7:  get it to work with your home and your routines, it can be frustrating
Speaker 7:  turning the lights on when you don't want it to. Whereas if the home
Speaker 7:  system can manage all of that stuff for you
Speaker 7:  and ideally be able to kind of pull in data
Speaker 7:  from all parts of your home. Not just necessarily for your comfort but also
Speaker 7:  for convenience, for saving energy for
Speaker 7:  safety. Like one of the things this new tech, the sense
Speaker 7:  sensing tech can do, could eventually be good enough to sense if
Speaker 7:  you fell over. So In theory, you know, your home could basically be
Speaker 7:  watching you And I know everyone's going, ah,
Speaker 5:  No, your light, your lights are watching you. It is, it is not creepy. It's
Speaker 5:  just merely a totally different appliance that shouldn't be able to see you.
Speaker 7:  Right. So that's the, that is the benefit of this sort of ambient sensing.
Speaker 7:  But I do see with the AI home bent that
Speaker 7:  cameras are going to be a huge part of
Speaker 7:  using this ambient home being, being proactive
Speaker 7:  because the data that the richness of the data they get from cameras
Speaker 7:  versus the data you get from sensors is just a step above.
Speaker 7:  And so in terms of like, so Switch bots example, they release their
Speaker 7:  ai AI hub and they have a couple cameras
Speaker 7:  that you can use inside or inside the home. They have one pan and tilt camera
Speaker 7:  and they have a video doorbell and they are, they were sort of pitching
Speaker 7:  it like we can, we can see when you, you know, where you've left your
Speaker 7:  phone because we are watching you in the home.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That's a good feature.
Speaker 7:  And then when you can't find your phone, you say, Hey, switch
Speaker 7:  bot, where's my phone? And they'll be like, you left it in the bathroom,
Speaker 7:  we don't wanna camera the bathroom. Then you're three
Speaker 5:  Robot vacuums go and crawl up to the bathroom
Speaker 5:  and grab it with their arm and bring it back to you.
Speaker 7:  Yes. There you go. You've solved it.
Speaker 5:  It's all coming together.
Speaker 6:  That sounds so cool and so scary at the same time. I know like, just like
Speaker 6:  equal parts, like the idea of having cameras in every part
Speaker 6:  of my home watching me, like when you say like, oh it'll tell you where your
Speaker 6:  phone is. I'm like, I need that. 'cause I'm constantly dinging the thing
Speaker 6:  at All Points in time and you know, you're finding the sound, but your cat's
Speaker 6:  sitting on it so the sound isn't accurate. That sort of thing. Air
Speaker 6:  tags don't work well through floors and all of that stuff. So that
Speaker 6:  personally, this is all just personally in my life I would love that. But
Speaker 6:  at the same time, I don't know, I don't want
Speaker 7:  A camera in the cameras. My bathroom. Yeah, I I mean the cameras, you know,
Speaker 7:  ideally though the yeah, you wouldn't do, but if you have a camera at the
Speaker 7:  front door, maybe you have a camera at the back door, maybe you have one
Speaker 7:  in the hallway and then the other sensors could help for
Speaker 7:  you know, the bathroom stuff.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, there's got to be a way to kind of pull all of this together where
Speaker 7:  it feels private and secure. And this was something that Switch Bot was focusing
Speaker 7:  on too, because their hub was entirely local, but they were also using
Speaker 7:  vision learning. So machine vision learning, which
Speaker 7:  is, has to use the cloud because it's such a high
Speaker 7:  processing, you know, it requires a lot of processing
Speaker 7:  power, which the hub can't do. And you would have to pay a monthly
Speaker 7:  fee for those types of things. I can see more and more companies doing that.
Speaker 7:  So using the AI for what the home sees
Speaker 7:  in strategic areas so that, that it can then, you know,
Speaker 7:  so say I've lost my cat, it will know that the, it saw the cat
Speaker 7:  leave through the front door because someone left the door open or, but then
Speaker 7:  the personal data can be more like wearables or sensors
Speaker 7:  in the bedroom or the bathroom. But the key is tying it all
Speaker 7:  together. Yeah. And right now everything is so disparate.
Speaker 7:  Each company is like, you can use all of our appliances, like that's
Speaker 7:  LG with its appliance orchestra. It's like, look, we can make all of these
Speaker 7:  work together, But that means I have to have everything from LG or I have
Speaker 7:  to have everything from Samsung or everything from Switch bot. So
Speaker 7:  that next level is how do we bring all of this together
Speaker 5:  And how, how much is matter and thread helping with stuff like, like is
Speaker 5:  it's a promise
Speaker 7:  It could nothing at the moment.
Speaker 5:  It could Yes, could, could is is an important word. Yes.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's, that's one of the reasons for matter is so that
Speaker 7:  we could have this more, it's an open standard.
Speaker 7:  It provides the platform for the technology
Speaker 7:  to talk to each other. So you could then bring in a
Speaker 7:  Samsung AI home or LGS Faron
Speaker 7:  agent as they call it, and or switch bot hub
Speaker 7:  or something else to connect into the data
Speaker 7:  that matter provides. So you wouldn't necess so matter being any
Speaker 7:  device can work with any platform
Speaker 7:  no matter who made it. So you're not locked into proprietary
Speaker 7:  ecosystems. And that's really the foundation of that was the
Speaker 7:  point of creating matter. So yes, you can see that this could
Speaker 7:  help create that foundation. And then the, the fight
Speaker 7:  now the arms race is who becomes the brain of your home because that is
Speaker 7:  gonna be someone you have to pick. Is it Google? Is it Apple? Is it
Speaker 7:  Alexa, is it lg? Is it Amazon or is it Switch bot?
Speaker 6:  It's just like, I I put up a story over the weekend about how
Speaker 6:  when I talked to Google, they were basically selling the same idea
Speaker 6:  about how the ambient computing world is gonna happen
Speaker 6:  and AI is just gonna be the glue that keeps all of these devices
Speaker 6:  talking to each other and together. So if you win the AI battle
Speaker 6:  and your, in Google's case, Gemini is the, the bot that
Speaker 6:  everybody chooses. Yeah. Then in some ways, like
Speaker 6:  AI is strengthening the product
Speaker 6:  ecosystem. It's like built, it's like putting putty and
Speaker 6:  strengthening the walled gardens as opposed to tearing it down in
Speaker 6:  some way. I
Speaker 7:  Think for the flagship products, definitely yeah, for the phone, the speaker,
Speaker 7:  the watch. But where it's democratized, you know, so
Speaker 7:  it makes buying a light bulb, a $15 hue light bulb
Speaker 7:  now much more approachable or a motion sensor or a present sensor.
Speaker 7:  You know, we saw some cool new present sensors at, in at, on the
Speaker 7:  show floor today or a door lock, you know, all of that now
Speaker 7:  doesn't have to be from one company. That's where you get
Speaker 7:  much more of the democracy and being able to
Speaker 7:  choose what you want to make your home work. But yes, I think the
Speaker 7:  flagship products you are gonna be feel locked in. So 20
Speaker 7:  minutes of Samsung's keynote today was all about
Speaker 7:  AI home. So at CES they called it Home ai, but now
Speaker 7:  they've rebranded and it's now AI Home.
Speaker 6:  It's like, oh,
Speaker 7:  Thinking outside the box there.
Speaker 7:  And it's, yeah, they, it's was all about the Galaxy watch, the Galaxy
Speaker 7:  phone, Samsung Food, which is their
Speaker 7:  meal planning, health, healthy eating resp system
Speaker 7:  app, and then smart things. So bringing all of their pieces
Speaker 7:  together to sort of lock you into that ecosystem. They don't really care
Speaker 7:  which smart bulbs you buy.
Speaker 5:  So Jen, I know the show hasn't even technically started yet, but is there
Speaker 5:  anything else tomorrow else we should Tomorrow
Speaker 7:  Or today? Today's Friday, right? Oh
Speaker 5:  My gosh. Today. Well, as this is airing, the show has started. Just started
Speaker 5:  for you personally. Well it, it's, it's really No, but
Speaker 5:  is there anything else we should be looking forward to throughout efa or
Speaker 5:  is it just gonna be Ai Ai what, what, you know, what's next?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I
Speaker 7:  Think more robots.
Speaker 5:  Robots
Speaker 7:  Always, we always get excited about robots. Always. Yeah. There's, there's,
Speaker 7:  there's some interesting, I did get to play with a robot pet
Speaker 7:  today, which was quite, it was cute. I love,
Speaker 5:  I love the
Speaker 7:  Weird pets. The weird pets.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The pets are so good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. LG has its weird little baby in a bowl pet
Speaker 7:  that it had at CES here. Do you remember that thing?
Speaker 5:  No, that's okay.
Speaker 6:  Was it the Maro? What? I can't remember it was it Maro what it was called?
Speaker 6:  It was like a Japanese one. But
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so that's here. And there's also Switchboard has
Speaker 7:  its AI pet And I saw to, I saw like anime
Speaker 7:  holograms in like a, in a like a
Speaker 7:  canister.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's meant to be
Speaker 7:  A pet. Lots of lots of companion
Speaker 5:  Type things. It's time to shut down Iffa. We have gone too far.
Speaker 7:  It was like an anime character and, and they were like, yes, it's your companion.
Speaker 7:  Like, oh, my daughter loves anime And I got a bit closer. I'm like, I don't
Speaker 7:  think this is for her. No.
Speaker 5:  Was it
Speaker 6:  Like anime
Speaker 7:  Boy? It was Pink
Speaker 6:  Cchu anime? No, no, no. Or was it, was it like Elon Musk? Annie
Speaker 6:  Anime? Oh no. Yeah. Oh no.
Speaker 7:  So yeah, and then there's another robot with an arm that can throw tennis
Speaker 7:  balls for,
Speaker 5:  For
Speaker 6:  Dog. No, that's, that's better. You know, that's better. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I
Speaker 6:  Think I love that robot. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  So there's, there's lots of fun robots, lots of appliances. I always get
Speaker 7:  excited about appliances. I know, that's sweet. And I
Speaker 7:  think there's laptops too, in case people are interested in those.
Speaker 5:  Awesome. Well, I'm, I'm very excited. Everyone should stay tuned to The Verge
Speaker 5:  dot com. We're gonna have a lot more. Jen, thank you so much for hopping
Speaker 5:  on to tell us all about if a, I'll let you get back to the, the
Speaker 5:  Wild Show at in Berlin.
Speaker 7:  Thank you.
Speaker 5:  Alright, we've gotta take a break. When we're back, we're gonna have Lauren
Speaker 5:  Finer talking about the Google Antitrust ruling
Speaker 9:  filed under the first Trump administration. And then,
Speaker 9:  you know, in last August the judge
Speaker 9:  finally said that Google is a monopoly in online
Speaker 9:  search. And that was a huge landmark ruling, the first
Speaker 9:  of these big tech cases by the government. And then there
Speaker 9:  was all this anticipation of like, okay, what is he gonna do to
Speaker 9:  make sure that Google can no longer have this, you know, power grip
Speaker 9:  over this industry? And that leads us up to
Speaker 9:  this past week when the judge finally issued
Speaker 9:  his ruling and said basically Google can't do
Speaker 9:  some contracts, some certain terms in their contracts
Speaker 9:  and they have to share some data to help search competitors
Speaker 9:  get up to speed with them. But basically rejected the largest
Speaker 9:  of the DOJs proposals of how to restore
Speaker 9:  competition to this market,
Speaker 5:  Right? The DOJ like swung for the fences. And they had these, these
Speaker 5:  pretty big asks that that I think the most famous
Speaker 5:  of them was trying to get force Google to sell Chrome.
Speaker 5:  And then like everyone was coming out of the woodwork trying to buy Chrome
Speaker 5:  even though it wasn't for sale yet. And the judge is just like, no,
Speaker 5:  that's absolutely not happening. He, he said the government really overreached
Speaker 5:  too by, by trying to get them to, as a backup maybe
Speaker 5:  have to sell Android.
Speaker 5:  Most of the big asks just didn't happen here. And I think most of the big
Speaker 5:  asks just didn't happen here, right? Like the DOJ didn't get most of what
Speaker 5:  they were asking for.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think that's right. I mean, I think you could definitely look at
Speaker 9:  this and say, hey, the DOJ swung for the fences,
Speaker 9:  you know, put out all of these really big ideas of how to fix this market.
Speaker 9:  And it probably wasn't going to get all of them, but I think
Speaker 9:  it was surprising the extent to which they
Speaker 9:  didn't get so much of what they wanted. You know, the judge really
Speaker 9:  didn't go all that much farther beyond what Google had
Speaker 9:  conceded to. And in some ways having watched
Speaker 9:  Judge MEA throughout both the liability phase
Speaker 9:  and the remedies phase trials, you know, you could see that
Speaker 9:  he was really grappling with what to do here. He's the first out of the
Speaker 9:  gate with one of these rulings in this kind of new era
Speaker 9:  of tech antitrust reform. And he
Speaker 9:  really was, seemed very cautious about, you know,
Speaker 9:  not wanting to create a new problem and disrupt something
Speaker 9:  that's, you know, already set in motion.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's really interesting in his opinion this week
Speaker 5:  he goes into the fact that AI changed
Speaker 5:  how he ended up making this decision. The fact
Speaker 5:  that AI is now seen as a competitor search
Speaker 5:  made him, I think, a little bit more cautious in what he did. Here he has
Speaker 5:  this one quote, he says, quote, much has
Speaker 5:  changed since the end of the liability trial. Artificial intelligence
Speaker 5:  technologies, particularly generative AI may yet prove to be game changers.
Speaker 5:  And then he just says like, flat out the emergence of gen AI changed
Speaker 5:  the course of this case. And so there is this real thing here where
Speaker 5:  I think possibly we could have gotten a much
Speaker 5:  stronger version of these remedies against Google, but
Speaker 5:  for the first time in decades, the first time maybe ever Google
Speaker 5:  actually is seeing some material competition. And I
Speaker 5:  think, you know, v you just did a whole Vergecast episode on this
Speaker 5:  about people's use for ai and
Speaker 5:  search is one of the big ones now,
Speaker 6:  I mean for like, you And I talk pretty heavily about using
Speaker 6:  AI for search because, sorry, Google's, your search
Speaker 6:  kind sucks now, like it's so weird because on
Speaker 6:  the one hand we use Google, the way that we use the
Speaker 6:  word Kleenex to mean tissues, right? Google just means go search something
Speaker 6:  on the internet that's in our vernacular that pretty much would make you
Speaker 6:  think that, hey, this is a monopoly because we don't say, oh
Speaker 6:  go Yahoo, that thing, right? We, we say go Google that thing, but
Speaker 6:  to our, our vergecast discussion,
Speaker 6:  it's not good enough anymore because all of the SEO slop
Speaker 6:  has just changed that game. So it's sort of like, oh,
Speaker 6:  once again, because I've been watching Law and Order And I had to have
Speaker 6:  perplexity tell me what season it was that Fin tu toola cuts off his
Speaker 6:  ponytail.
Speaker 6:  Like AI was actually able to tell me like it told me a wrong answer and
Speaker 6:  someone called me out online and then I looked it up again and then it told
Speaker 6:  me the right answer. So you do have to kind of handhold it a little bit,
Speaker 6:  but it's still telling you what's more likely to be
Speaker 6:  a, an answer when your traditional Google search isn't
Speaker 6:  gonna help you anymore. I had a situation this morning where my fridge
Speaker 6:  was, the ice maker was spitting out clay balls And I was like, what?
Speaker 6:  What is here happening
Speaker 5:  Here? I'm concerned
Speaker 6:  About that. I'm very concerned. Why is my ice maker spinning out clay
Speaker 6:  balls? And then I asked, and Google was not giving me any
Speaker 6:  answers and so I asked AI and they're like, well this is either a sediment
Speaker 6:  issue and you're just gonna have to do a, a lot of work or something's wrong
Speaker 6:  with your, with your thing, and why don't you just empty out the
Speaker 6:  ice bucket? And I was like, oh, I can empty out the ice bucket new homeowner
Speaker 6:  here. I've never had to do appliance maintenance before. And I found out
Speaker 6:  that my spouse had put an eye mask with clay balls in them in the ice maker.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 5:  My God.
Speaker 6:  It had opened up a hole and that's why clay balls were coming out of my ice
Speaker 6:  maker. So I was like, I didn't gimme the right answer in this
Speaker 6:  situation, but it did kind of put me on a path that got me to the right
Speaker 6:  answer for a search and a question that I had, whereas just typing
Speaker 6:  it into Google did nothing for me. So it's
Speaker 6:  like a really, I, I get where the judge is coming from, but also I'm
Speaker 6:  like, come on man.
Speaker 5:  It is one of those ultra specific things. I, I, again,
Speaker 5:  I did the exact same thing. This I was trying to look up, do you remember
Speaker 5:  the chat app Trillian? I just like, I was like, how do I search for
Speaker 5:  a chat app that was popular in 2006 with a weird like Infinity logo
Speaker 5:  and it was just right. Like I I can't Google that, but, but you're right.
Speaker 5:  Like it, it's, it is, it is pretty remarkable that if this
Speaker 5:  remedies trial had been held a y probably
Speaker 5:  a year earlier, certainly two years earlier, we may have ended up in a very
Speaker 5:  different outcome because Google, it, it, it seemed
Speaker 5:  kind of borderline impossible that Google would see material
Speaker 5:  challenge to its dominance in the search industry. So I'm just gonna read
Speaker 5:  out, I I think a, a quick TLDR of how I'm seeing
Speaker 5:  the, the things that they actually have to do. And Lauren, you can tell me
Speaker 5:  if this is is about correct, but here's, here's what the
Speaker 5:  judge is going to require of Google, assuming that this sticks. The
Speaker 5:  judge says that Google has to stop making exclusivity contracts
Speaker 5:  for products like Search Chrome and Gemini. So they can still
Speaker 5:  make default contracts, but they can't say it's the, the exclusive provider
Speaker 5:  of those things. Google has to stop tying some of their
Speaker 5:  apps to the placement or use of other
Speaker 5:  apps on their devices. So they can't be like, if you want Gmail,
Speaker 5:  you have to use Chrome. If you want Gmail, you have to use Gemini.
Speaker 5:  They can't do that anymore. They're gonna have to syndicate
Speaker 5:  some of their search results. And that's like with an asterisk, there's like
Speaker 5:  a, a big subset there and they have to share some of their search
Speaker 5:  index. Is is that about right? Like it's it's a lot of like half measures
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 9:  That's right. And he leaves open some possibility that he
Speaker 9:  could expand some of this in the future. For example, if, you know, he
Speaker 9:  finds that, you know, these remedies aren't actually enough to
Speaker 9:  restore competition, maybe he will look back on the payments part of
Speaker 9:  this or something like that. So there's some options here, but that's basically
Speaker 9:  the extent of what Google has to do if these remedies hold up.
Speaker 5:  Well and actually we should touch on the payments part because that was a
Speaker 5:  big thing at issue here and he's, he thinks, ah, they're fine, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean I, I don't know if he necessarily would say, oh this is totally
Speaker 9:  fine. I think throughout the trial, even the liability phase and the remedies
Speaker 9:  phase we saw, you know, he really felt like the fact that
Speaker 9:  Google was paying Apple, you know, $20 billion
Speaker 9:  to be the default search provider on
Speaker 9:  Safari was pretty indicative that, you know, they,
Speaker 9:  they felt like they needed to hold onto this position even though
Speaker 9:  they keep saying that they're the best. And so he
Speaker 9:  really seemed to kind of hang on to that fact throughout
Speaker 9:  the trial, but at the same time I think he heard from
Speaker 9:  both Eddie Q from Apple and an executive from
Speaker 9:  Mozilla who said, you know, we're, we would basically be pure
Speaker 9:  losers here if you decide that we can't get
Speaker 9:  these payments from Google because Google is still
Speaker 9:  dominant people, our customers are still gonna wanna go to Google
Speaker 9:  and we have to provide that option and yet we'll no longer be able to be
Speaker 9:  paid for it. So I think that was something that he really
Speaker 9:  wanted to consider here and probably drove some of his thinking around
Speaker 9:  whether Google could be able to make these payments. It's
Speaker 5:  Really fascinating. You know, I think the critics of Google
Speaker 5:  are, are pretty upset about this ruling. They think that it's not going to
Speaker 5:  go far enough, at least from what I've seen. But as I was
Speaker 5:  reading the opinion, you know, you do sort of like see how the
Speaker 5:  judge landed here and you start to feel for him in terms of the, the
Speaker 5:  challenge of threading this needle because you look at the,
Speaker 5:  the payments, which were one of the big things at issue here and it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, so may maybe you say, you know what, it is bad for Google to be able
Speaker 5:  to pay to be the default and therefore crowded everybody else. And then
Speaker 5:  you think from the judge's point of view, okay, does it help Google or hurt
Speaker 5:  Google if I ban them from paying Apple
Speaker 5:  $20 billion a year? But Apple sets Google as a default
Speaker 5:  search anyway because Google's the best product. Does it help Google or hurt
Speaker 5:  Google if I ban them from paying Mozilla a bunch of money and then
Speaker 5:  Firefox dies and even more people have to use Chrome and you just keep
Speaker 5:  going through these things and it's like, oh, like he, this
Speaker 5:  is, this is kind of tough. Like how do you make space for
Speaker 5:  competitors without actually hurting the
Speaker 5:  rest of the industry at the same time because all of these companies
Speaker 5:  are just hooked on Google's money and Google,
Speaker 5:  you know, saving them a bunch of cash would actually be a
Speaker 5:  perk for them in some ways.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, definitely. I think, you know, judge Maja talks a lot
Speaker 9:  about, you know, judicial humility and you know, not wanting
Speaker 9:  to kind of take proactive action that will cause more harm
Speaker 9:  or disruption or, you know, pretend that he can know the future.
Speaker 9:  But at the same time I think critics of this decision
Speaker 9:  are saying, you know, he really didn't go far enough and we already,
Speaker 9:  he already found that there's this issue in this market
Speaker 9:  that revolves around how Google has conducted itself
Speaker 9:  and you know, a lot of these critics feel like he hasn't gone far enough
Speaker 9:  and instead did a sort of half measure that says they
Speaker 9:  can't have these exclusivity in their contracts, but they can keep paying
Speaker 9:  heaps of money to be the defaults. Which, you know, already he's kind of
Speaker 9:  found that the defaults act as a way that Google has
Speaker 9:  been able to maintain its monopoly power.
Speaker 6:  So a question I have is like a lot of times with law, and
Speaker 6:  one thing that I've learned just serving in unions is that you can want all
Speaker 6:  of these ambitions things, but you really have to think about enforceability,
Speaker 6:  right? Like when you decide you're gonna do things a new way and you're like,
Speaker 6:  Hey, what if we do it this way? I think one of the challenges that I
Speaker 6:  learned about was how implementable is it
Speaker 6:  actually? So are the things that he's, you know, asking
Speaker 6:  Google to do it, are these things that
Speaker 6:  materially make a difference? Are these things that the government can
Speaker 6:  enforce or is it just sort of like we said that they're doing this here,
Speaker 6:  but actually it's a status quo?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean I think that's kind of the reason why the Justice Department
Speaker 9:  was pushing for a breakup or what they'd call
Speaker 9:  structural remedies in the first place is that, you know, a lot of people
Speaker 9:  who advocate for those kinds of remedies say they're the easiest to enforce
Speaker 9:  because you don't have to monitor it, you don't have to babysit a company,
Speaker 9:  you just break 'em up. You just say CR Chrome can
Speaker 9:  no longer be owned by Google and they have to sell it and they have to break
Speaker 9:  it apart. And obviously that's easier said than done,
Speaker 9:  but you know, once it's done, it's done these
Speaker 9:  behavioral remedies like, you know, having to,
Speaker 9:  you know, not put certain provisions in their contracts or share certain
Speaker 9:  search data. That's something that kind of does have to
Speaker 9:  be monitored for compliance a little bit more. But,
Speaker 9:  you know, I think in this case it doesn't seem like so hard to
Speaker 9:  do that, but I guess the devil will be in the details
Speaker 9:  of how they're, you know, they have to do that if, you know, they
Speaker 9:  actually get to that point.
Speaker 5:  So the, the thing that I think is a little tricky here is I, I sort of
Speaker 5:  see how he lands at we can't ban these payments
Speaker 5:  as for Ali lands at the rest of the remedies and what
Speaker 5:  is required of Google to create competition. It gets
Speaker 5:  a little more complicated I think because he, he actually carves this like
Speaker 5:  pretty narrow path And I don't know that this path is necessarily
Speaker 5:  tied to the ways that Google created its monopoly and
Speaker 5:  enforced its monopoly. And I think that's what a lot of the remedies were
Speaker 5:  about, right? The remedies were Chrome enables
Speaker 5:  Google's monopoly, so we will remove Chrome. Android
Speaker 5:  enables Google's monopoly and so we'll, we'll threaten to remove Android.
Speaker 5:  And kind of as I see it, what he's doing instead is saying,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna create a little narrow path that will allow more
Speaker 5:  competition to bubble up. You're saying that the problem is that Google
Speaker 5:  has such a lead in search that no one else can catch up and compete
Speaker 5:  with them. So I'm gonna give you some basic tools so that these other
Speaker 5:  companies can bubble up and start to create competition. And
Speaker 5:  from my read of the opinion, he, he's basically
Speaker 5:  saying, listen all you other companies, you can have basically
Speaker 5:  a, a map of what Google is doing and, and
Speaker 5:  that's kind of it, right? You, we'll we'll give you some, some supporting
Speaker 5:  stuff. So you'll have a map, like the search index is essentially a map of
Speaker 5:  the internet to let them understand what Google is indexing.
Speaker 5:  They're gonna get some basic search syndication, but they can only
Speaker 5:  syndicate up to like 40% of their, of their search from Google.
Speaker 5:  And that's supposed to sort of help bootstrap them. But the judge is
Speaker 5:  pretty blunt about from there you gotta do it
Speaker 5:  yourself. You can't keep going back to Google and getting more information
Speaker 5:  about how they build their search engine. You need to invest and you need
Speaker 5:  to build a good product, you need to, to compete with them, which is
Speaker 5:  still a pretty big ask of the, of the industry.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think it's important to know that, you know, in antitrust law when
Speaker 9:  it comes to remedy is, you know, the goal here is not, you know,
Speaker 9:  let's undo every anti-competitive thing that Google did up until this point.
Speaker 9:  'cause some of them maybe, are I relevant to the market at this point?
Speaker 9:  The goal is to restore competition to the market that Google has
Speaker 9:  monopolized. So, you know, I think the
Speaker 9:  goal with these remedies is basically to make it so that,
Speaker 9:  you know, rivals really can compete in this market in a way they haven't
Speaker 9:  been able to in, in, you know, decades based
Speaker 9:  on Judge Mata's ruling. So basically
Speaker 9:  they, he is implementing all of this to say,
Speaker 9:  okay, let's give some of these rivals kind of a jumpstart
Speaker 9:  in the way that they haven't been able to do that in
Speaker 9:  years. Because basically delivering valuable search
Speaker 9:  results requires a lot of data, collecting a lot of data requires a lot
Speaker 9:  of users coming to your service and putting in a lot of queries. And
Speaker 9:  if Google is gobbling all those up, then no other company is really getting
Speaker 9:  that. So the goal is to kind of give these other
Speaker 9:  companies a jumpstart in that way. And so that's kind of what he's trying
Speaker 9:  to do here, but at the same time he is kind of limiting that a lot
Speaker 9:  more than what the Justice Department said would be necessary to really
Speaker 9:  get them there by saying, you know, we're not gonna
Speaker 9:  let you have access to this on a periodic basis. You'll just
Speaker 9:  get like one snapshot in time and that should give you a sense of like what
Speaker 9:  Google knows or, you know, saying you can only
Speaker 9:  have some access to some of these features for
Speaker 9:  six years rather than 10. So I think that's kind
Speaker 9:  of how he's tried to like walk this line and
Speaker 9:  he's really wary of making these rivals
Speaker 9:  dependent on Google. He doesn't want them to feel like, okay, we have like
Speaker 9:  a long runway to figure this out and we could just like
Speaker 9:  coast on Google's data. In the meantime he wants them to build
Speaker 9:  up to be their own services.
Speaker 5:  Have you heard from, you know, the Mozillas, the DuckDuckGo, like how they
Speaker 5:  feel about this? Like is this going to be helpful to them?
Speaker 9:  I mean, I think Mozilla is relieved that they will not be
Speaker 9:  losing a huge chunk of their revenue that comes from Google
Speaker 9:  for default payments for Firefox.
Speaker 9:  I think DuckDuckGo was really not happy
Speaker 9:  with this ruling and you know, they ultimately
Speaker 9:  said
Speaker 9:  their CEO Gabriel Weinberg said in a statement quote, Google will
Speaker 9:  still be allowed to continue to use its monopoly to hold back competitors
Speaker 9:  including an AI search. As a result, consumers will continue to
Speaker 9:  suffer. We believe Congress should now step in and
Speaker 9:  you know, if you're calling on Congress to step in at this point after
Speaker 9:  we've seen these bills shot down before, you know, that really feels
Speaker 9:  like a a last resort.
Speaker 5:  So I there's the, there's this takeout there And I I'm curious your thought
Speaker 5:  like it seemed people Google, Google clearly lost
Speaker 5:  the, the lawsuit, right? They were ruled to have a
Speaker 5:  monopoly that is the last thing they wanted. But when it comes
Speaker 5:  to the remedies, it kind of seems like they won. Do, do you agree
Speaker 5:  with that?
Speaker 9:  I do largely agree with that. I mean, basically what the judge
Speaker 9:  granted was pretty much most of what, pretty
Speaker 9:  much all of what Google had proposed that they said we'd be fine with
Speaker 9:  this, which is basically the exclusivity contracts aspect.
Speaker 9:  And then he imposed somewhat more of what the Justice Department
Speaker 9:  asked for in terms of some of the search data and other syndication
Speaker 9:  that he ordered. But really the
Speaker 9:  DOJ lost out on all of its other big ass.
Speaker 9:  So, you know, it's not a total loss for the Justice Department, but it's
Speaker 9:  far short of what they asked for and seems to be far short of what
Speaker 9:  many critics here think would be necessary to
Speaker 9:  restore competition.
Speaker 5:  I wanna ask maybe a bigger picture question. You had this story that ran
Speaker 5:  on Thursday, you said The tech antitrust renaissance may already be over.
Speaker 5:  Can, can you, can you dive into that more? 'cause the, there was, I think
Speaker 5:  this big burst of momentum and energy
Speaker 5:  toward, you know, tearing apart big tech and it seemed like this was
Speaker 5:  gonna be the moment. And I I think you're saying maybe,
Speaker 5:  maybe it fizzled out before it, before it even started.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean I, I started on this beat about six years ago when
Speaker 9:  a lot of this was starting to bubble up. And at the time, you know, there
Speaker 9:  was this kind of feeling around antitrust for a long
Speaker 9:  time that, you know, we should kind of just look at
Speaker 9:  at like prices and do prices go up or down and
Speaker 9:  what does that mean for consumers and we should really be restrained and
Speaker 9:  how we think about antitrust. And that was just
Speaker 9:  beginning to change with things like Lena Khan coming on the scene with
Speaker 9:  a proposal about how we should look differently at markets
Speaker 9:  that aren't necessarily, don't necessarily have a price tag for
Speaker 9:  consumers, like is the case in digital markets a lot of the time, but
Speaker 9:  still have, you know, a lot of power.
Speaker 9:  And you know, she kind of came onto the scene making a
Speaker 9:  argument about how to go after Amazon's alleged monopoly.
Speaker 9:  And then we saw this explosion of interest from
Speaker 9:  lawmakers from outside groups and you know, eventually from the
Speaker 9:  enforcers themselves to actually kind of take this new approach
Speaker 9:  to antitrust. And you know, in 2019
Speaker 9:  we saw the House Judiciary committee start to investigate all
Speaker 9:  of these companies. We saw the DOJ and the FTC begin to look into all of
Speaker 9:  these companies. And all of that has resulted in lawsuits at this
Speaker 9:  point against Google, meta Apple, Amazon. I mean
Speaker 9:  that's just unheard of for at one point in time to have huge
Speaker 9:  monopoly cases against all of these companies. So it was
Speaker 9:  really a milestone. And then, you know, in
Speaker 9:  the last couple years we've seen these cases begin to go to trial
Speaker 9:  and having the initial liability finding
Speaker 9:  from Judge Mea saying that Google is a monopoly in online
Speaker 9:  search. I mean that was just huge. That was such a
Speaker 9:  watershed moment for this movement and seemed to really
Speaker 9:  solidify like, okay, really we can get the courts on board
Speaker 9:  here if we put in the work, if we bring these cases.
Speaker 9:  And I think getting to this point and seeing, okay, yes,
Speaker 9:  we got a court, the Justice Department got a court to find
Speaker 9:  a tech company to be a monopoly, but then he
Speaker 9:  does kind of the bare minimum to
Speaker 9:  remedy it. That is, that's a real setback. And I think it's,
Speaker 9:  it just casts some doubt on how far courts will really be willing to
Speaker 9:  go to address this problem.
Speaker 9:  And, you know, it could be that in a few years it turns out that
Speaker 9:  this was the outlier. You know, there's Google is gonna face the DOJ later
Speaker 9:  this month in its other case that it lost to the
Speaker 9:  Justice Department over its ad tech monopoly. And
Speaker 9:  it's very possible that the judge in that case could say,
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna break up part of Google's ad tech business. And
Speaker 9:  we could see similar more, you know, aggressive rulings in some
Speaker 9:  of these other cases. So it is too soon, soon to know what the
Speaker 9:  arc of history on this will look like. But I think it is just
Speaker 9:  a, a kind of a, a warning to
Speaker 9:  the optimism that's existed in this space that, you know, there's still
Speaker 9:  such a long road ahead and the hardest part may be yet to come.
Speaker 6:  I'm just curious because like you're kind of mentioning that this is a marathon,
Speaker 6:  not like a 5K, just use runner analogies,
Speaker 6:  but, you know, I'm just curious how much of the environmental
Speaker 6:  vibe shift plays into this. Because if this started six years ago
Speaker 6:  then, well, a lot of this momentum and energy started under the,
Speaker 6:  the initial Trump regime and then gained some momentum I guess during the
Speaker 6:  Biden years. And you know, I think everyone would agree that there's been
Speaker 6:  a little bit of an energy change since, you know, the
Speaker 6:  start of 2025. So I'm just curious, like, does that also
Speaker 6:  play into this like fear that the Renaissance might be over before
Speaker 6:  it began because yeah, ostensibly there's a long time before there's
Speaker 6:  another vibe shift maybe, or maybe there'll never be another vibe shift again.
Speaker 6:  So just curious how much that plays into like,
Speaker 6:  thoughts regarding like how this is gonna go with all of these big
Speaker 6:  antitrust cases.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's a great point. I mean, I think it's impossible to ignore the,
Speaker 9:  you know, political influence here and just the way,
Speaker 9:  you know, the political moment has shifted at the same
Speaker 9:  time. It's, it's really interesting and I've written about this a good amount.
Speaker 9:  It, it's been such a bipartisan movement here and
Speaker 9:  it's not that it's like all sides of both parties really
Speaker 9:  care about this, but it's, you know, a certain subset of each party is
Speaker 9:  really invested. And you'll see like, you know,
Speaker 9:  I think at one hearing there was like Matt Gaetz and
Speaker 9:  you know, we'll be saying something that sounds a lot like Elizabeth Warren
Speaker 9:  and so it's just like really perplexing sometimes. But then I think
Speaker 9:  you end up seeing like in this moment, especially amid
Speaker 9:  like all the upheaval we saw earlier this year with Doge,
Speaker 9:  with, you know, mark Zuckerberg coming to the White House
Speaker 9:  right before his antitrust case went to trial,
Speaker 9:  you know, all of this kind of fear about outside influence, corporate
Speaker 9:  influence and just how the Trump administration
Speaker 9:  would conduct itself, his dismantling
Speaker 9:  of different agencies and kind of taking Democrats
Speaker 9:  off the Federal Trade Commission. I think all of that just kind of
Speaker 9:  created this questioning and distrust among, between
Speaker 9:  the parties around all of this. So I don't know that it necessarily
Speaker 9:  undermines the like policy goals that I think are
Speaker 9:  kind of deeply held beliefs, at least within
Speaker 9:  a lot of members of this movement on both sides. But I think it's
Speaker 9:  impossible to ignore the possible influence of that
Speaker 9:  and just kind of the different moment that we're in right now.
Speaker 5:  And I think you're right that at a bare minimum, this is a a a coming back
Speaker 5:  down to earth moment. This is a ev even if we get there,
Speaker 5:  judges are, are typically very cautious in
Speaker 5:  how they approach these remedies. And you know, I I think it
Speaker 5:  says a lot that Google at, at least as of the time we're recording this on
Speaker 5:  Thursday afternoon, Google has not appealed, right? They, they still
Speaker 5:  could, but I I I tend to find that most companies
Speaker 5:  about 30 minutes after an opinion comes down, put out a statement saying
Speaker 5:  this is terrible. This is the worst thing that's ever happened and we are
Speaker 5:  gonna appeal. And, and Google put out a statement that was actually like,
Speaker 5:  you know, the judge, he was very thoughtful in this case. We were just like,
Speaker 5:  not not what you expect to happen. They, they didn't have that one drafted.
Speaker 5:  They, they had to write that one on the fly. So Lauren, what happens
Speaker 5:  next here, right? Thi this still could get appealed,
Speaker 5:  it could eventually be put into, into place. What are we waiting on?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I I think it still is pretty likely that Google Appeals, they said
Speaker 9:  before this came out that they would appeal because basically they
Speaker 9:  had to wait for the remedies ruling to come out to even appeal the underlying
Speaker 9:  liability finding. And Google doesn't like being called a monopolist. It,
Speaker 9:  it probably is going to appeal that part of the ruling,
Speaker 9:  but, you know, we'll, we'll see what happens there. The other thing that
Speaker 9:  could happen is that the DOJ or the states
Speaker 9:  that also brought this case against Google
Speaker 9:  could appeal to get more of the remedies that they were asking
Speaker 9:  for. So we could see appeals from one or both
Speaker 9:  sides here and then that would go up to the appeals court and that could
Speaker 9:  eventually go up to the Supreme Court. So even though
Speaker 9:  a lot of these remedies could go in place soon, you know, they
Speaker 9:  could all be kind of paused while all of this goes on. And it really could
Speaker 9:  be a long time before any of this really comes to fruition.
Speaker 9:  RIP Lauren?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 9:  You know where to find me.
Speaker 5:  Stay tuned. Maybe we will have a GI by the time the
Speaker 5:  the actual remedies come down. All right, we've gotta take a break when we
Speaker 5:  get back. The Thunder Round is back and better than ever, stay tuned.
Speaker 5:  I have to warn you all may come to an end as soon as next
Speaker 5:  week I'm gonna have to fight David Pierce. Two
Speaker 5:  podcasters enter, only one will leave to find out whether
Speaker 5:  the thunder round continues. Listen, if you love the thunder round, if you
Speaker 5:  support the thunder round, I'm gonna need you to email vergecast at The
Speaker 5:  Verge dot com. Tell us how important it's to you.
Speaker 5:  This is the thunder round. Five stories, five minutes each. When we're running
Speaker 5:  outta time, we'll hear some rumbling thunder. When time is
Speaker 5:  up, our producer Travis Sluck will strike us down with
Speaker 5:  a final crash. That means it's time to move on. Alright V
Speaker 5:  you're up first. What have we got?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so my question is, would you pay
Speaker 6:  $2,000 for a smartwatch? Because that's what
Speaker 6:  Garmin is asking from some people. They came out with an announcement
Speaker 6:  this week about the, their flagship Garmin Fenix eight Pro
Speaker 6:  series. So it's like an S year for Garmin. The Fenix is their flagship
Speaker 6:  line and just like how the iPhone used to have an iPhone four, then iPhone
Speaker 6:  four s the S year is just like, ah, that many updates. So they just
Speaker 6:  came out with the S year Pro Garmin
Speaker 6:  Fenix eight and you know, there's some really cool things
Speaker 6:  they finally added LTE and satellite SOS kind of
Speaker 6:  kind of, you have to use the Garmin Messenger app. So it's not like you can
Speaker 6:  have an actual phone number on on your Garmin or
Speaker 6:  a fully like how you would think of a data connection on that.
Speaker 5:  Doesn't the Apple Watch Ultra have that for half the price?
Speaker 6:  It's for $10 and it's 800. You know the, the LTE connection
Speaker 6:  is generally $10 depending on your carrier and the Apple Watch
Speaker 6:  Ultra is $800. But, but they're saying,
Speaker 6:  hold on now the starting price for an OLED display
Speaker 6:  will be $1,200. If you go a
Speaker 6:  slight size up, it'll be $1,300. But if you want the micro
Speaker 6:  LED display, which has a maximum brightness of
Speaker 6:  4,500 knits, which I don't think I've ever heard
Speaker 6:  of any device with a maximum brightness of 4,500
Speaker 6:  knits, you have the privilege and the distinct honor of paying
Speaker 6:  $2,000. And I was just like, you can't convince people
Speaker 6:  to spend $2,000 for a foldable phone that does a lot of stuff.
Speaker 6:  2000 do 2000 do $2,000. Like
Speaker 6:  people were losing their minds over the garments. 'cause Fenix eight being
Speaker 6:  a thousand dollars, $2,000, $2,000
Speaker 5:  For $2,000. This thing better like be 4K. Like I, I better be able to
Speaker 5:  watch like Dolby Vision movies on my wrist
Speaker 5:  like with, with this thing. So I don't what is the
Speaker 5:  outdoorsy use case where you absolutely need 4,500 and
Speaker 5:  it's like, it's like you exclusively hike in the desert with
Speaker 5:  the midday sun directly overhead and you just like can't
Speaker 5:  possibly rotate your wrist enough to like see it. Y
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, it's, it's mostly so you can see things in bright direct
Speaker 6:  sunlight, but it's really funny 'cause I was reading the comments and everyone
Speaker 6:  was just like, what No memory and Pixel trans reflective
Speaker 6:  display, which you know, will let the battery be 4,000 years
Speaker 6:  long.
Speaker 5:  Now the display that bright not
Speaker 6:  Happening. No, no. So the micro lead will be I think about
Speaker 6:  10 day battery life. And for Gar that's pretty good. If you're talking about
Speaker 6:  for, for an Apple Watch or the Pixel Watch or a Samsung watch 10
Speaker 6:  days battery life, holy sign me up Bob. But for a
Speaker 6:  Garmin where they measure the battery life in weeks
Speaker 6:  and months, 10 days, they're like 10 days.
Speaker 6:  Is
Speaker 9:  This supposed to be like a part of the ultralight hiking movement so that
Speaker 9:  like you don't have to bring your phone or your satellite phone, but
Speaker 9:  I don't get how you would be able to rely on this to send all your messages
Speaker 9:  if you are an emergency?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, kind of like basically what they're doing. 'cause it's really hard
Speaker 6:  to negotiate these carrier deals for the smaller, I say smaller brands like
Speaker 6:  Garmin's, a publicly traded company, but it's just, it's not
Speaker 6:  on the scale of like Apple or Google, right? So it's harder for them to
Speaker 6:  negotiate the, the carrier deals. So what they're doing is they're relying
Speaker 6:  on the Garmin in reach satellite communications to bring
Speaker 6:  LTEM to these watches and satellite
Speaker 6:  connectivity. So depending where you are, if you make an SOS
Speaker 6:  call, which is the big appeal of these things, it'll
Speaker 6:  reroute you to the Garmin like response center. So Garmin is gonna be like
Speaker 6:  a middleman in every step of the thing. Your watch won't have its
Speaker 6:  own cell phone number. You can only call other Garmin Fenix
Speaker 6:  eight. So your friend who has also spent over a thousand dollars for Garmin
Speaker 6:  Fenix eight and or the family members that you've badgered
Speaker 6:  into downloading the Garmin Messenger app, which is their proprietary app
Speaker 6:  to enable text messaging more thoroughly on
Speaker 6:  their, on their device. And you know, they introduced that last year
Speaker 6:  I tested it for the Garmin Fenix eight review. I had a friend download it
Speaker 6:  and as soon as I was done with the review, she was like, so the review stuff.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, yeah, she's like, can I delete this app now? So
Speaker 6:  it it's great helps them compete more with Apple
Speaker 6:  and all those stuff. But I can't help but feel like they've lost the
Speaker 6:  plot a little bit for what their users actually want. So $2,000,
Speaker 6:  that's that's my,
Speaker 5:  They have taken the best and worst parts of micro ld, which is really
Speaker 5:  bright and insanely expensive. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Alright. Lauren, what have you got?
Speaker 9:  Okay, so I'm here to deliver some devastating news
Speaker 9:  that Amazon is cracking down on how you share your
Speaker 9:  prime shipping benefits with your friends and family.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, this was, this was huge news in my family because on the
Speaker 9:  day that the Google search remedies ruling came out, my dad
Speaker 9:  said, okay, yeah, but have you seen that you have to stop mooching off of
Speaker 9:  our Amazon benefits? So yeah,
Speaker 9:  basically they're making it so, you know, they, they're kind of changing
Speaker 9:  this invitee program that they had into Amazon
Speaker 9:  family. And under that program you kind of, everyone who's part of that
Speaker 9:  has to be part of the same primary household. So
Speaker 9:  if you don't live with the other person in your family or your
Speaker 9:  friend group that you share a prime account with, you can't kind of share
Speaker 9:  that, those prime benefits. It seems like,
Speaker 9:  from how I'm reading it, that you could still just
Speaker 9:  have, you know, your friend or family member ship you stuff from
Speaker 9:  their account, just do like a different address or you could log in there,
Speaker 9:  but you can't have like your own account and use their shipping benefits.
Speaker 5:  I'm not letting somebody else see my Amazon purchase history. Like
Speaker 5:  I just cannot explain like why I bought like a tarp and like
Speaker 5:  a tomato plant stick and also like 15
Speaker 5:  USBC cables in the same order. Like, it just, it just doesn't add up.
Speaker 5:  I, I had no idea that this was even a benefit that that was allowed,
Speaker 5:  like Netflix password sharing, like, okay, that makes sense.
Speaker 5:  Like these are just computers. Netflix isn't tied to my house.
Speaker 5:  Amazon, pa Amazon is like very singular to me. So I was like, honestly,
Speaker 5:  maybe I'm just outta the loop, maybe I'm just left behind. I didn't realize
Speaker 5:  you are, I I barely even realized you could share it within your household.
Speaker 5:  So I was like, hmm, that
Speaker 6:  No. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I thought I was getting an upgrade. Jake, it's not true
Speaker 6:  Jake, you gotta get on the password sharing at least within your house because
Speaker 6:  oh, you're that, you know, for a while before like
Speaker 6:  tied the knot said holy matrimony, we were paying
Speaker 6:  for our individual prime stuff. And then when
Speaker 6:  we found out that we were basically paying twice while living under the same
Speaker 6:  household, we were like, why are we doing this? Why should we have to be
Speaker 6:  doing this? But I hate that Amazon is basically taking a
Speaker 6:  page out of the streamers book. I mean, come on man,
Speaker 6:  we all got subscription fatigue. Let us have this,
Speaker 6:  let us have our shipping come on.
Speaker 5:  Like the narrative though for subscriptions over the past, what, like two
Speaker 5:  years at this point? And it, like, it was started by Netflix and they were
Speaker 5:  like, we're gonna crack down passwords and like they, they expanded it globally
Speaker 5:  and now it's kind of everyone, like if they haven't done it already,
Speaker 5:  they have announced that they're going to do it. I'm pretty sure it came
Speaker 5:  to HBO, I'm pretty sure it, it came or is coming to Disney Plus
Speaker 5:  and, and Amazon Prime. I I'm gonna say this
Speaker 5:  one actually makes the most sense to me as a thing that
Speaker 5:  feels very focused on a single location. But
Speaker 5:  nonetheless, like these things are expensive and
Speaker 5:  every time another company does a crackdown, it adds another subscription
Speaker 5:  to everybody else. And so it's like each crackdown is hurting
Speaker 5:  the next company that does a crackdown because they're just going to have
Speaker 5:  fewer people who are willing to add a subscription. Like I am, I am
Speaker 5:  tapped out, I have too many things I like when it
Speaker 5:  comes to streaming services. I just like save it up until there's like enough
Speaker 5:  like movies and shows that I wanna watch and then like try to knock it out
Speaker 5:  and like a month or two because I'm like, I can't keep all these going at
Speaker 5:  the same time. This is outrageous.
Speaker 9:  I think it's kinda surprising that they let us like have all these
Speaker 9:  password sharing for as long as they did. And I think once like Netflix
Speaker 9:  decided we're gonna crack down on this and you know, people didn't just leave
Speaker 9:  in droves. I think everyone else was like, all right, I guess we could do
Speaker 9:  it too. Finally.
Speaker 5:  No, that's so true. Like Netflix was willing to take the reputational hit
Speaker 5:  And I guess people actually just like Netflix enough that they're
Speaker 5:  like, well what are you gonna do? I'll pay for some more Netflix.
Speaker 6:  I mean it helps that there's like bundles now, or if you go to a carrier,
Speaker 6:  they'll be like, we'll give you a free year of this and a free year of that
Speaker 6:  and you can now within a one bundle get five different subscription
Speaker 6:  services and you'll save money than if you were subscribing to them all
Speaker 6:  independently. And here's a credit card thing. But I was like, why do we
Speaker 6:  have to do this? Why do we have to jump through all of these hoops? I had
Speaker 6:  a racket going with a bunch of six friends where
Speaker 6:  one person would pay for one service and then put us all as family
Speaker 6:  and everyone was responsible for paying one subscription
Speaker 6:  and we were all just on a big old racket and, and this is
Speaker 6:  like falling apart, but, and so now I'm just like, do I need this service?
Speaker 6:  I don't, I miss my, my subscription racket.
Speaker 5:  I will say some of the companies that have done these crackdowns mm
Speaker 5:  they're not as good as cracking down as they say they are. There's, you
Speaker 5:  know, listen, I, I'm not breaking any rules, but there might be some people
Speaker 5:  on my, my accounts who are, and they have nobody's caught on yet.
Speaker 5:  Alright, next story. Okay, so I
Speaker 5:  have been talking about this, I think the past three weeks. I am
Speaker 5:  obsessed with the Pixel 10 Pros
Speaker 5:  100 X zoom feature. So it has this feature called
Speaker 5:  ProRes Zoom, where when you zoom into a hundred x it will use
Speaker 5:  AI to enhance the image. And I think when we first saw this, I was like,
Speaker 5:  these demo images that I'm seeing seem like incredible. They,
Speaker 5:  they're, they're, they're remarkable. I can't believe they look this good.
Speaker 5:  And then last week I was like, well I'm, I'm maybe seeing a few flaws
Speaker 5:  here this week. I think I'm ready to say I might
Speaker 5:  hate it, I might hate it. So Allison Johnson
Speaker 5:  went out with the Pixel 10 Pro and a cool
Speaker 5:  pix camera that actually has a 100 X lens. And
Speaker 5:  number one, you have to see what this camera looks like. It is this
Speaker 5:  enormous black thing. It is like the size of a limb. It,
Speaker 5:  it's huge because it turns out you need a huge lens to actually get a hundred
Speaker 5:  x. But she did a bunch of side by side photos with the Pixel 10
Speaker 5:  Pro and this actual a hundred x zoom. Okay, so I wanna show
Speaker 5:  you two of the photos that Allison took
Speaker 5:  And I want to hear what, which one you think is better. And this is,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna give you the one that I think is maybe the best
Speaker 5:  presentation from the ai. So here are two photos
Speaker 5:  of the tales of some planes. So here's photo one
Speaker 5:  and it is kind of like blurry and ripy and it
Speaker 5:  almost feels like you can feel the like fumes or something coming out of
Speaker 5:  the back of the jet engines. And here's another one. And I think this one
Speaker 5:  is like crisp and clear, maybe a little smooth. The colors are vibrant.
Speaker 5:  I, I'm curious, do you two have thoughts
Speaker 5:  on which of these two is a better photo?
Speaker 6:  The one that doesn't look like amateur impressionist art?
Speaker 5:  So you're saying, so this one that's currently up between the smooth one
Speaker 5:  with the, the the bold colors. Lauren, do you, do you feel the same? Do you
Speaker 5:  prefer this one?
Speaker 9:  I I think the crisper one is better, but it's a little
Speaker 9:  bit like too, too perfect.
Speaker 5:  So this is, this is the AI one, and this is I think the best case for it,
Speaker 5:  right? It, it is these sort of big, simple objects,
Speaker 5:  big bold colors and it's able to clear them up really
Speaker 5:  neatly and there aren't too many weird artifacts or
Speaker 5:  messy imperfections or fake things. But I went through all of Allison and
Speaker 5:  this is like the single one that I think actually shows off this feature
Speaker 5:  being good. But the one that really broke it for me, there's this photo of
Speaker 5:  the moon that Allison took with the, the Pixel. And I
Speaker 5:  looked at it And I thought, you know, that's a pretty darn good picture of
Speaker 5:  the moon. And it like, it looks sharp, it has this incredible texture
Speaker 5:  on it. And I'm like, it has moon texture, it looks like the moon. This is
Speaker 5:  so cool. And the, the, the moment that I
Speaker 5:  turned against this feature was when I looked at the actual photo of the
Speaker 5:  moon and it's completely
Speaker 13:  Different. All the textures made up. It got, it's, it's not there at
Speaker 13:  all. It was just like, oh yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  Some texture here. So I I I don't know, I oh man,
Speaker 5:  I I was in pretty messy feelings about this 'cause like, it's
Speaker 6:  A different color,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah, it's certainly a different color.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I feel very, very torn because again, I do think like this
Speaker 5:  one photo of the plane's like, yeah, that's, that's pretty good for,
Speaker 5:  for a hundred x like that cleans it up nicely. But this moon photo, I'm
Speaker 5:  like, it just made up a bunch of stuff about the moon. Like that's not,
Speaker 5:  that's not what I want from a camera. And Allison just
Speaker 5:  talked to Mark LaVoy, who he used to
Speaker 5:  work on the Pixel cameras and now works on cameras at Adobe
Speaker 5:  and talk to him about putting generative AI in camera apps. And
Speaker 5:  I don't know, my, the impression I got was that he was kind of
Speaker 5:  uncertain if it was a good idea And I I, yeah,
Speaker 5:  this, this is, this is how I feel. I'm curious, you guys, I I think look
Speaker 5:  through some of the other photos, like do you have thoughts here? Like
Speaker 5:  is this good? Is this evil?
Speaker 6:  It's just why
Speaker 9:  I feel like I have mixed feelings. Yeah, I, I think it kind of just depends
Speaker 9:  what you're going for with the photo. Like if you're trying to like capture
Speaker 9:  the moment that you're in or like, or get like real
Speaker 9:  information from a photo that you're gonna remember, like, I
Speaker 9:  don't know that I'd wanna rely on AI for that because
Speaker 9:  it's like you could just like download a photo of a really good photo
Speaker 9:  of the moon if you wanna know what the moon really looks like or, you
Speaker 9:  know, I feel like some of just like taking photos with your phone is just
Speaker 9:  like capturing the moment. But yeah, this feels like
Speaker 9:  something else.
Speaker 6:  Why are you zooming in a hundred times? Just because you can, like what,
Speaker 6:  what for what reason are we going a hundred times Zoom sometimes
Speaker 6:  is like,
Speaker 5:  It is because I can, to be clear, right? Like I'm excited by that.
Speaker 5:  It just, it just doesn't make any sense. Okay, we could do another like 20
Speaker 5:  hours on, on a hundred x zoom, but we must move on
Speaker 5:  the what have you got
Speaker 6:  In the year of our lawyer 2025. You can finally have
Speaker 6:  Instagram on the iPad. I saw this headline.
Speaker 5:  They did it. They did, they did it did they did it. This is
Speaker 5:  the most impressive piece of, oh my gosh,
Speaker 5:  incredible. Ah, ah,
Speaker 5:  this is the single most impressive piece of engineering that we've seen out
Speaker 5:  of meta in years. Can you believe they managed to do this?
Speaker 6:  It's groundbreaking. I we've only been asking for this
Speaker 6:  since the inception of Instagram over 10 years ago
Speaker 6:  and it's just like, oh cool. Instagram
Speaker 5:  And the iPad are the same age. They're the same age.
Speaker 5:  They could have done it at any point.
Speaker 6:  At any point we could have had a native iPad app
Speaker 6:  that just, you know, blow instead of an iPhone app that just blows up. But
Speaker 6:  then at the same time, so I was reading me a story on it and it's like, it'll
Speaker 6:  prominently feature reels And I was like, that's not what I want. That's
Speaker 6:  not what I want from the iPad Instagram app.
Speaker 6:  But as there it is,
Speaker 5:  This is mind blowing. You open it up and it defaults to reels
Speaker 5:  and if you want to find photos on
Speaker 5:  Instagram, you have to go to a new tab that like,
Speaker 5:  it looks like you're going to find your friends or something. Like it's,
Speaker 5:  it's not a clear photos you need to find, it's buried in a new tab. The
Speaker 5:  photos, the Instagram part of Instagram is now hidden within
Speaker 5:  Instagram.
Speaker 9:  This just screams to me that they just wanted to find another
Speaker 9:  way to distribute reels and they didn't really have interest in an actual
Speaker 9:  Instagram app for iPad.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly it. And it's just like, listen, I'm
Speaker 6:  pitching a news segment called Give the People what they fricking want
Speaker 6:  and don't edit. Like, you know, there's just so many things where
Speaker 6:  it's just give the people what they want. We are asking nicely,
Speaker 6:  please don't put your nefarious agenda into the thing that
Speaker 6:  we're asking for. Give us our chronological fricking feeds back.
Speaker 6:  I, I I was just like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Listen, I will use the Chinese
Speaker 5:  state sponsored, you know, NSA
Speaker 5:  deeply concerned
Speaker 5:  app TikTok for my short form video and Instagram. I would
Speaker 5:  like to stick to photos. That's, that's how I feel.
Speaker 5:  I I'm not, I'm not messing with reels, I'm messing with reels until the
Speaker 5:  day that TikTok gets banned and then I'll open up my iPad
Speaker 6:  Photos and stories. That's, you know, honestly just
Speaker 6:  gimme the stories. I wanna snoop on what my friends are doing and go like,
Speaker 6:  oh, good for her. Or like, Ooh, that's shady. You know, that's what Instagram
Speaker 6:  on the iPad should be for just as it is on the
Speaker 6:  phone. I don't want reels there. Leave me alone. So
Speaker 6:  yeah, I, it it was just like so wonderful and then
Speaker 6:  so cruel, And I say this as someone who hasn't had a fully charged
Speaker 6:  iPad in months, so I'm just saying,
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying this is, it is, this is
Speaker 5:  Meta's approach to the iPad has been bewildering And I realize like,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, I, I realize it takes some engineering resources. I realize
Speaker 5:  like maybe it's, it's probably never gonna be the most popular platform for
Speaker 5:  them, but it is so embarrassing and weird
Speaker 5:  and ridiculous that today, like you, or at least as of yesterday,
Speaker 5:  you opened up Instagram and it was still that tiny little square that that
Speaker 5:  you just like a version of what you'd see on the phone. And the same is true
Speaker 5:  for threads, right? It, I believe it was true for Whatsapp until pretty recently
Speaker 5:  as well too. So hopefully, hopefully this means Threads is next.
Speaker 6:  What do they have against the iPad? Like I'm not a big iPad girly,
Speaker 6:  but like all of our grandparents and all of the children are on iPads.
Speaker 6:  Those are great segments to target. I don't get it.
Speaker 5:  I do think they have beef with Apple meta and Apple definitely have beef,
Speaker 5:  but like taking it out on the iPad is like
Speaker 5:  Apple does not notice that. They're like, they're not like,
Speaker 5:  oh no, but, but Whatsapp for iPad doesn't go
Speaker 5:  full screen. Like that's not, that's not your leverage
Speaker 5:  to getting a better deal in the app store.
Speaker 6:  You're just hurting all the old people with bad eyes, which
Speaker 6:  will be me in a few, like, not even a few years, it's me now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  An old person with bad eyes.
Speaker 5:  I saw your glasses earlier. They are, they're you're already there.
Speaker 6:  I'm already there. My eyes are garbage eyeballs And I was just,
Speaker 6:  you know, I was like, oh I don't have to do the thingy and maybe I'll use
Speaker 6:  my iPad more 'cause I don't have to have all these iPhone apps that just
Speaker 6:  blow up. No, I'm, I'm very upset by this.
Speaker 5:  I know it is finally here and I'm still upset about it because they're using
Speaker 5:  to push reels. RIP tour Instagram,
Speaker 5:  it was already not Instagram anymore but now it's
Speaker 5:  clear where there just lies. Alright Lauren, last one. Take us home.
Speaker 9:  Last one. So yeah, this is just basically shout out to
Speaker 9:  Democratic FTC commissioner Rebecca Kelly Slaughter, who
Speaker 9:  pretty much every day for past several months has said to check a
Speaker 9:  court docket to figure out if she's going back to work.
Speaker 9:  You might recall that Trump tried to fire her
Speaker 9:  and her colleague at the time Alvar Bedoya from the Federal Trade Commission,
Speaker 9:  which he technically isn't allowed to do based on Supreme
Speaker 9:  Court precedent that basically they're trying to challenge
Speaker 9:  this whole case had to play out and you know,
Speaker 9:  the district court judge said you can go back. So she went back
Speaker 9:  and then the appeals court said, wait a minute, we're gonna pause all this
Speaker 9:  while we figure it out. Then she went home and
Speaker 9:  just this week the, the circuit court
Speaker 9:  said, okay, you know what, she can go back to work. We're still figuring
Speaker 9:  out the case but you know, for now, like she's allowed to go back. So
Speaker 9:  yeah, I just can't imagine your life being
Speaker 9:  run by a court docket in this way, But that
Speaker 5:  And very publicly, But that's been the situation. Yeah, she's like finding
Speaker 5:  out in the New York Times if she goes to work in the morning
Speaker 9:  Pretty
Speaker 5:  Much it's, it's like the weirdest snow day imaginable.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that's
Speaker 6:  That's hell, that's real hell I don't think I could do it. She's a
Speaker 6:  strong woman.
Speaker 5:  So ha has, obviously it is, I'm gonna say bad for
Speaker 5:  the FTC not to have a full set of commissioners and very
Speaker 5:  problematic for Trump to fire the Democrats. These are
Speaker 5:  intentionally designed to be be a bar bipartisan commission. Has it allowed
Speaker 5:  them to, you know, go running
Speaker 5:  now that there hasn't been two democrats in there? Or
Speaker 5:  is the FT does that do the FTC commissioners who are left like not even care?
Speaker 5:  Well I
Speaker 9:  Think the thing it changes is not so much like what
Speaker 9:  the, what the commission is actually doing, but just like what sort of insight
Speaker 9:  the public could possibly get into what they're doing. So
Speaker 9:  you know, it, there's three republicans on the commission now, so they were
Speaker 9:  always gonna have the majority, it's a five person panel when it's full.
Speaker 9:  So, and the chair gets to set the agenda. So it's not that
Speaker 9:  the Democrats would be able to kind of change the outcomes of any votes
Speaker 9:  or anything, but they'd have access to the same documents
Speaker 9:  that the rest of the commissioners do. They'd be able to say in their dissenting
Speaker 9:  statements like, Hey, you know, this is why I think this was really wrong.
Speaker 9:  And without that, you know, we will never really know.
Speaker 5:  There's also just like stymies the commission, I, I think one thing that's
Speaker 5:  overlooked, and this is true at the FCC as well, like a lot of what
Speaker 5:  the commission does is boring bipartisan stuff.
Speaker 5:  And that day-to-day work now just grinds to a
Speaker 5:  halt in, in, in some respects when you're down
Speaker 5:  to major leaders and, and so it's like
Speaker 5:  the, the commission is just going to do a worse job of being the Federal
Speaker 5:  Trade Commission. They're going to do a worse job of enforcing the rules
Speaker 5:  that, that universally they agree they want to enforce and
Speaker 5:  you know, it would be nice if this person was allowed to have
Speaker 5:  her job back as, as she is legally allowed
Speaker 5:  to be there.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean I think it al also just arguably makes it so any company that's
Speaker 9:  trying to sue because they didn't like what the FTC told
Speaker 9:  them they have to do gives 'em another thing to say in court. Like, hey
Speaker 9:  look at this is, this is not like the normal course of things.
Speaker 5:  That's fascinating. I'm sure that like any court case, we've got like
Speaker 5:  900 appeals to go for
Speaker 9:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  I'm RIP
Speaker 6:  Lauren.
Speaker 5:  I'm excited to see how it plays out. Alright, that's it for the
Speaker 5:  thunder round. Again, if you love the thunder round,
Speaker 5:  send an email vergecast at The Verge dot com hashtag save the thunder round
Speaker 5:  hashtag
Speaker 5:  David loves the thunder round.
Speaker 5:  Send your emails. Yeah, my, I've love support the
Speaker 6:  Thunder round. I've seen every iteration of the thunder round. I've enjoyed
Speaker 6:  it immensely. We will. So you got my
Speaker 5:  Vote, you have, you have including, listen the thunder round
Speaker 5:  is always new. It is always improving and it will stay that way until the
Speaker 5:  day that it clashes with David Pierce, which will be
Speaker 5:  next week. Alright, that's The Vergecast. I am off
Speaker 5:  to California next week along with V to cover the Apple
Speaker 5:  announcement. Our Tuesday episode of The Vergecast will be pushed to
Speaker 5:  Wednesday as a result. So we can give you some of our oppressions from the
Speaker 5:  event and stay tuned because David Pierce will be
Speaker 5:  back for that episode to chat with us. It's been a blast being your
Speaker 5:  Friday host. I will still be around the show whether the Thunder round
Speaker 5:  survives is another question. Send in your emails
Speaker 5:  if you like what we do here. The best way to support us is to get a subscription
Speaker 5:  to The Verge at The Verge dot com and be sure to sign up for
Speaker 5:  V'S. Newsletter Optimizer while you're there. It's gonna be good. We're
Speaker 5:  all gonna have an existential crisis and feel good about it. Yes, that's
Speaker 5:  what V does best. We'd love to hear your questions and feedback. Let
Speaker 5:  us know what you want us to talk about. Email us vergecast at The Verge dot
Speaker 5:  com hashtag save the thunder round or give us a call. 8 6 6
Speaker 5:  VERGE 11 The Vergecast is a production of The Verge in V Media podcast
Speaker 5:  network. Our show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Ke for Travis large
Speaker 5:  Chuck and Andrew Marino. See you next week.