# Transcript
ID: 1e30aa9c-bcf5-4ba8-b65b-6862aea0dd68
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/736238788160139268/4700897439255355348/s93290-US-5912s-1756690193.mp3
Description: This week on The Vergecast, Chris Niccolls and Jordan Drake of PetaPixel’s YouTube channel join The Verge’s Allison Johnson and Vjeran Pavic to geek out about the last half-decade of camera advancements — the good, the bad, and the Sigma BF of it all.
Then, Allison is joined by Verge News Editor and fellow phone nerd Dominic Preston to help answer a boatload of listener questions from people contemplating which smartphone to buy next. They help navigate the intricacies of living in a mixed iOS/Android household to the best options for someone who wants a headphone jack (spoiler alert: there aren’t many).
It’s a mega-hotline-turned-therapy session for iPhone Mini owners reluctant to let go of their tiny phones in a world where phones come in two sizes: big and bigger.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of small
Speaker 2:  phones that are very tired and just wanna take a little rest. I'm
Speaker 2:  your host, Alison Johnson, and on today's show I'm talking about two of my
Speaker 2:  very favorite things, small phones and weird cameras.
Speaker 2:  First, I'll be joined by some old friends at PetaPixel who are
Speaker 2:  gonna talk to me about what's been happening in the camera industry over
Speaker 2:  the last five years. Then Dominic Preston's gonna jump on and
Speaker 2:  we are gonna tackle a huge pile of listener questions in a mega
Speaker 2:  hotline segment. All that is coming up right after the break,
Speaker 2:  so stay tuned.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I am here with some of my very favorite
Speaker 2:  kinds of people, which is to say camera nerds. I
Speaker 2:  am joined by the faces of PetaPixel
Speaker 2:  YouTube channel. We've got Jordan Drake, of course,
Speaker 2:  you know, co-host, editor, videographer. Hello
Speaker 2:  Jordan.
Speaker 6:  Occasionally show up on camera. Yes. Yeah. Yes,
Speaker 2:  Yes. Important to note.
Speaker 6:  Doing all the posts to make the other person look fantastic.
Speaker 2:  It's the important job. Already
Speaker 6:  Looked fantastic right from the start. I twist a couple
Speaker 6:  knobs, you know, I dial some dials.
Speaker 7:  You're putting polish on a diamond ring. Come on.
Speaker 2:  Oh my goodness. Okay, so this is setting the tenor for our show.
Speaker 2:  Thank you guys. That is Chris Nichols, you know, host
Speaker 2:  hi photographer, kind of man about town. Oh,
Speaker 7:  I appreciate that. Yeah, that's true. That's true. Well
Speaker 2:  Yeah, thanks for coming on. And I'm joined by Veen Pak, who's our
Speaker 2:  supervising producer here at The Verge. Also a camera nerd and
Speaker 2:  tests the weird cameras we get in. Is that fair?
Speaker 8:  I guess some of them are flying. Most of 'em are flying. If you can get him
Speaker 8:  in the US
Speaker 7:  Oh, I see.
Speaker 8:  A lot harder nowadays.
Speaker 2:  Good. If you can get
Speaker 7:  'em those cameras. It's been
Speaker 8:  A big year for weird cameras.
Speaker 6:  We'll have to touch on that. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I, I am so ready to talk about weird cameras. Maybe that's, I'll back up
Speaker 2:  just a little bit and like set the context for how we all know
Speaker 2:  each other. So the two of you are at PetaPixel now, you know,
Speaker 2:  long running photography website. Previously we all worked
Speaker 2:  together at DP Review. So we've been nerding out about camera stuff for a
Speaker 2:  while now. You guys have been doing this for forever, you know, camera store
Speaker 2:  tv. You've got like 15 years of making videos
Speaker 2:  about cameras under your belt. So I have, I have
Speaker 2:  lured you here under the guise of, of hanging
Speaker 2:  out and just like catching up. I feel like we are
Speaker 2:  usually under extreme duress when we all hang out. It's like
Speaker 2:  at a live event we're running around. It's like very sweaty and hard to catch
Speaker 2:  up. Yes. And I've been kind of like out of the camera
Speaker 2:  game for like the last five years And I need a little bit of a
Speaker 2:  refresher on what has happened. So you three
Speaker 2:  are the very people to talk to about
Speaker 7:  This. Nice. Yeah. Well thanks for having us. This is great.
Speaker 2:  I'm so excited. Give me kind of like your
Speaker 2:  takes on, what have been some of the kind of like
Speaker 2:  landmark or standout launches or maybe just
Speaker 2:  innovations like in the camera technology space,
Speaker 2:  you know, in the past maybe five years, like Verin, do you have like a,
Speaker 2:  a first thought on this
Speaker 8:  In five years? What is happening in five years? Olympus went away,
Speaker 8:  but they're still making camera under a different brand. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Fuji became like one of the hottest cameras out there in L 100 and
Speaker 8:  last two have been insanely popular and that's been a lot of
Speaker 8:  fun.
Speaker 8:  We've also just like went all the way back to the two thousands and are now
Speaker 8:  taking photos with like Olympus Mu and oh, oh my gosh.
Speaker 8:  You know, point in truths with a lot of just like high key flash
Speaker 8:  photography and, but no, a lot, a lot more has happened.
Speaker 8:  All of the cameras can out film like incredible video to
Speaker 8:  for
Speaker 7:  Sure. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I think to add on that, yeah, I mean video is certainly a huge thing that's
Speaker 7:  happened in the five years, which makes Jordan happy and me indifferent.
Speaker 7:  And then
Speaker 7:  I would say also another big change is just how everybody's
Speaker 7:  caught up. You know, five years ago there was more variety in how good
Speaker 7:  people's auto focusing was and what their capabilities were. Now I feel like
Speaker 7:  the sensors are all very similar. Everybody's got good dynamic range.
Speaker 7:  Most players have very comparable auto focus now at this point.
Speaker 7:  Everybody's rocking subject detection like, you know, it's kind of like all
Speaker 7:  the trends that one person has started, everybody else has caught up to and
Speaker 7:  jumped on. So yeah, it's kind of a time now where camera
Speaker 7:  design I think is more important and has to be more exciting than anything
Speaker 7:  else.
Speaker 8:  We've definitely fixed the image quality issue like a while ago.
Speaker 8:  A hundred percent. We don't complain about image quality anymore.
Speaker 7:  It's no, it's
Speaker 6:  Forbidden that that's what's so interesting, like the image quality thing
Speaker 6:  is something every year we looked at as the primary thing like oh we got
Speaker 6:  more megapixels, it's better in low light now we're actually seeing the opposite
Speaker 6:  thing happen over the last five. If you look at the higher end cameras,
Speaker 6:  they're like, look, we can make our picture quality a little bit worse in
Speaker 6:  exchange for speed. Mm. Because the speed is gonna be better for that auto
Speaker 6:  focus and burst shooting and all that video stuff that's happening. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of funny. I still look back to cameras, you know, from back when
Speaker 6:  you were working Allison, like a D eight 50 from Nikon and I'm like,
Speaker 6:  that still takes better pictures than even top of the line pro cameras
Speaker 6:  at this point. Oh wow. But the new stuff does way better video, way better
Speaker 6:  focus. Yeah. Much faster burst rates, that kind of stuff. So that's kind
Speaker 6:  of a compromise they've been willing to make. Yeah. These
Speaker 2:  Days. Can someone explain to me what global shutter is? Does that
Speaker 2:  tie into the like speed thing? Like Yes, with the auto
Speaker 2:  focus
Speaker 7:  It does but but I would say in, in our world of
Speaker 7:  photography, only one player has actually incorporated it properly. So
Speaker 7:  you know the Sony A nine three is a very cool camera, has global shutter.
Speaker 7:  It means you can fire full electronic shutter, no rolling shutter issues
Speaker 7:  whatsoever. No flashy problems either. The wibbly wobblies. Yeah
Speaker 7:  none of the, none of the wibbly wobblies and stuff. And of course it unlocks
Speaker 7:  insanely fast burst rates. And Sony of course have fantastic auto focus.
Speaker 7:  So it's very much a purpose built sports and action
Speaker 7:  camera. But you know, kinda like what Jordan was talking about, you do sacrifice
Speaker 7:  a bit of dynamic range, megapixel count, that kind of stuff. Really it's
Speaker 7:  made for a specific goal and that is to get as many shots even
Speaker 7:  with flashes fly. Like it's a great paparazzi red carpet camera, you know,
Speaker 7:  great video capabilities. But we're seeing that also with stack
Speaker 7:  sensors in general, which don't quite get there, but do a lot of what that
Speaker 7:  does. And that's probably another big change in the last five years. Just
Speaker 7:  the proliferation of high quality stack sensors.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And stack sensors like BSI, right?
Speaker 2:  Like there's layers of pixels and
Speaker 7:  Beyond the BSII would say. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I was just gonna say like the BSI is what we saw previously and then the
Speaker 6:  stack sensors, they've just put the electronics right on the chip and that's
Speaker 6:  again giving us that faster readout for that other stuff. But again, a slightly
Speaker 6:  worse image quality than
Speaker 2:  We had before. Okay. That's so interesting that that image quality is
Speaker 2:  like a thing people are fine with kind of
Speaker 2:  sacrificing a little bit.
Speaker 7:  Everybody's kind of caught up to this idea that image quality isn't the be
Speaker 7:  end all 'cause they're all good and now people are, as we've talked about,
Speaker 7:  preferring bad image quality. Right? They're preferring
Speaker 7:  cameras with tiny sensors and they're going analog and, and
Speaker 7:  we've seen a real resurgence of lenses that are
Speaker 7:  designed to look like old vintage lenses along with all the flaws and and
Speaker 7:  failures and issues with those lenses. For a little while there it was
Speaker 7:  like an arms race to get the greatest, latest and greatest
Speaker 7:  mirrorless camera out on the market.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's an arms race to make the image a little bit shittier now is where we're
Speaker 6:  at.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It seemed like it. Yeah. Let's talk about compact cameras
Speaker 2:  'cause I am, I think just as confused as
Speaker 2:  anyone about what is happening. I mean you guys sold compact cameras
Speaker 2:  to people. Yes. Many, many years ago. Brand new all, all of a sudden they're
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Not even used on eBay. It was brand like someone actually came in and
Speaker 7:  gave us $900 for this tiny crappy little camera God. And
Speaker 7:  they loved every second of it and it fit, fit in an Altoids mint container
Speaker 7:  and they were so happy. Oh yeah. Yeah. Those are the days.
Speaker 2:  Verin, what was your, did you have a crappy little digital camera like
Speaker 2:  back in the day?
Speaker 8:  Back in the day I had a lot of Sony cyber shots. Okay.
Speaker 8:  If you gimme like 12 seconds I can grab two of them.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yes please. Hold on. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  It looks like a tape recorder. No, I had one that did that
Speaker 2:  too. I had that. That's like super thin.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, there's that one. There's another one which is probably a year
Speaker 8:  later. Okay. Like these companies we're making cameras like constantly.
Speaker 8:  It
Speaker 7:  Was
Speaker 2:  A lot of fun. So
Speaker 8:  Many. This is maybe
Speaker 7:  The one Oh
Speaker 2:  Oh,
Speaker 7:  Look at that. Yeah, that's the one that Sydnee was rocking. Yeah. That
Speaker 8:  Is beautiful. Yeah, I went back home, I got the Chargers, I got the memory
Speaker 8:  sticks, I got a memory card
Speaker 7:  Reader, Sony memory sticks.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Pro duo as well. Or pro or duo.
Speaker 2:  Remember you're also
Speaker 8:  This still work. There was like another, another Sony camera
Speaker 8:  that I had to use reverse image search to actually find out the real
Speaker 8:  model of it. It was, I don't know how to describe it, I
Speaker 8:  just dunno how to describe it. It was like a tiny little, think about like
Speaker 8:  a pillbox and then you can rotate the lens.
Speaker 7:  Oh yes.
Speaker 8:  The lens was only,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Nikon and Sony did those.
Speaker 7:  So here's a question though. Did you guys actually use those back in the
Speaker 7:  day or did you kind of rediscover them now? Right. Because you know, we
Speaker 7:  sold those in the store and, and we played with all those cameras and tested
Speaker 7:  them out and like yeah they're garbage. Like the menus are terrible and
Speaker 7:  everything's slow and the screens are bad, you know, and the image quality
Speaker 7:  is fun. Sure. But it was funny but the designs were so
Speaker 7:  interesting. Like that was the time where manufacturers would just throw
Speaker 7:  everything at the wall to see what would stick. And it was really exciting.
Speaker 7:  All these wacky, strange designs that you would never, ever take
Speaker 7:  risks on nowadays. Although I would say that, you know, some of the companies
Speaker 7:  are now starting to come around and try some stuff again, which is kind
Speaker 2:  Of cool. Yeah. I wonder how much of the digital camera renaissance is about
Speaker 2:  people discovering that. It's like nice to hold a camera and use
Speaker 2:  you're, when you're so used to using a smartphone. Yeah, the weird
Speaker 2:  factor is pretty good too. But
Speaker 7:  This is just the novelty. Is that what people are loving now? I is like the
Speaker 7:  novelty because we had to, we were, we were in the trenches, you know what
Speaker 7:  I mean? And it was horrible and, and now I think people like rediscovering
Speaker 7:  or like, oh this is so different and it's so like novel. Yeah. But
Speaker 7:  no it was just garbage at the time. But like yeah. Yeah
Speaker 2:  I did carry around my little cyber shot and took pictures of friends and
Speaker 2:  it was just like that was the only, only option, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's just weird to think of it like that. Jordan, you have a camera in your
Speaker 2:  hands out. Yeah, I wanna
Speaker 6:  See it. Yeah. So the last time I saw you Allison, I was waving this thing
Speaker 6:  around. I've put a video out since, but if you look at it, I think this is
Speaker 6:  really cool 'cause this is a Kodak V seven 70 and it is kind
Speaker 6:  of the origin to the smartphone camera solution. Oh. So they had this
Speaker 6:  super thin thing. They're like, well we can't make the zoom any bigger,
Speaker 6:  the lens any wider, any brighter. So they just put two complete cameras in
Speaker 6:  here. So it's, oh my god. A zoom lens and then an ultra wide. And there are
Speaker 6:  two separate sensors in there as well. So it's kind of, they came up with
Speaker 6:  the solution before the smartphone manufacturers did.
Speaker 7:  Well even this, this is my favorite camera, this is the Panasonic GM five.
Speaker 7:  It's the greatest camera of all time. Oh my God. Yes. We just made it. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  we just made a video about it and it our, that was like one of our biggest
Speaker 7:  first day views. Like, it's crazy because everybody loves this
Speaker 7:  stuff. Again, it's, it's like a renaissance. I love
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah. Yeah. Let's talk about weird cameras 'cause I feel like there
Speaker 2:  is kind of a natural like synergy. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  These were all weird.
Speaker 2:  They're all super weird. There was kind of like a,
Speaker 2:  a smooshing where like every camera design sort of like became
Speaker 2:  the same. And I think that's happened with smartphones too. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Yep.
Speaker 2:  But in the very recent past we have seen some,
Speaker 2:  I would say really weird out there kind of camera designs
Speaker 2:  and I'm all about it. Like, I dunno, what
Speaker 2:  is your guys feelings about some of these?
Speaker 7:  I dunno, I think we're gonna fight. I, I don't know. What should we start
Speaker 7:  with? Like, you know, I think it's as an overarching theme
Speaker 7:  I would say. I think it's great that manufacturers are trying different designs.
Speaker 7:  Again, like the Fuji Film X Half is, is a good example of like a
Speaker 7:  really cute, really adorable design with some fun
Speaker 7:  features on it that harken back to the days of nostalgia. And I will admit
Speaker 7:  like a camera like that did make me feel nostalgic for like a couple days
Speaker 7:  and then After that it wore off and I'm like, this isn't really there. Right?
Speaker 7:  Like it's kind of just a basic point and shoot camera with this sort of
Speaker 7:  film experience. But I get it, if somebody hasn't had that, it would be super
Speaker 7:  fun to look at a contact sheet again, whatever. But I, it's, it's fun that
Speaker 7:  the manufacturers are taking these risks but how often do
Speaker 7:  they hit? Right? Because the Sigma BF is another example of something that
Speaker 7:  was beautifully designed. Sigma always make weird cameras. They
Speaker 7:  always have. I've always thought they're kind of trash And I kind of thought
Speaker 7:  this last one was too, it's beautiful trash though. It's really gorgeous
Speaker 7:  trash. Oh no.
Speaker 2:  Beautiful trash. Okay. No ve has something to say.
Speaker 8:  Say about this. We're back to disagree.
Speaker 8:  We can come back to the Fuji bud. Like I gotta, I gotta defend Sigma here.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Honestly, I, I, no, I think about this a lot. The camera that
Speaker 8:  I missed the most is the Sigma bf. Like the one that
Speaker 8:  I'm like, oh man, I wish I had like a little bit more time with it. I
Speaker 8:  really enjoyed using that camera. Wow. Like truly just loved
Speaker 8:  using it. It's like this unibody kind of unibody
Speaker 8:  metal slab of a camera. It is a Sigma
Speaker 8:  full frame camera that does some video that's not
Speaker 8:  really good at it. It has a built-in storage. Doesn't have any
Speaker 8:  card slots, it has a microphone but like you would've never use it.
Speaker 8:  It doesn't have a hot shoe. It can barely take photos in fluorescent
Speaker 8:  light because of the electric shutter. Only you're
Speaker 7:  Selling me on it. Yeah. This is not,
Speaker 8:  I know right. This is just like a list of cons and then
Speaker 8:  there is the, hey, I went to use this for a little while And I
Speaker 8:  absolutely loved it. Wow. I thought the lenses are pretty good and everything,
Speaker 8:  but I thought, you know, we live in a world where film simulations
Speaker 8:  are everywhere. Everyone's try Jelly kind of do it. I thought they did pretty
Speaker 8:  good with those. Yeah. But you know, I really enjoyed
Speaker 8:  how, okay, it has internal storage which makes the camera super fast. Like
Speaker 8:  turning it on, saving the photos. Operations in general just like feel
Speaker 8:  snappy. There's barely any dials on it. Right. You have one
Speaker 8:  main dial. Yeah. But in that dial it's also deep pad.
Speaker 8:  You can kind of like, that's
Speaker 7:  A real problem.
Speaker 8:  You can, you can set the like what you want to change on it left and right
Speaker 8:  and then use the click wheel basically to like change the settings
Speaker 8:  and it all shows on a little sub monitor. And it made me kind of
Speaker 8:  cycle through, you know, two to three options that I would use
Speaker 8:  a lot. And I ended up using them a lot more like the film simulation and
Speaker 8:  crop primarily. And I thought the photos were actually
Speaker 8:  beautiful. I thought as we sure said earlier, the auto focus is like not
Speaker 8:  a problem with these cameras anymore. And I thought they did a pretty good
Speaker 8:  job there as well. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  You said it right there though, Vern. The, the thing is it made you do stuff
Speaker 7:  because the Sigma BF is designed in such a way that you don't have
Speaker 7:  alternative ways to control a camera. And, and one of the things that really
Speaker 7:  drives me crazy as a photographer is if I have a camera or any product, I
Speaker 7:  mean even the iPad makes me mad for the same reason, nothing to do with photography
Speaker 7:  is if there are not multiple ways to control something, you know,
Speaker 7:  logical, intuitive ways. If you're kind of forced to use it a certain way,
Speaker 7:  I find that a little obnoxious. And like the BF has got this weird thing
Speaker 7:  'cause it's got a touch screen, but you only use the touch functions for
Speaker 7:  certain things otherwise you're back to using the dial. And it's
Speaker 7:  kind of, there's a lot of clicking to get through things I felt in stressful,
Speaker 7:  like high-paced scenarios. It's too slow to adjust and get
Speaker 7:  set and get changed. The body's gorgeous. But that, that
Speaker 7:  block of aluminum, I mean they did such a great job machining it, but
Speaker 7:  those edges are so hard and sharp that, and I've been hearing now feedback
Speaker 7:  like people are bumping this camera onto things and chipping chunks off
Speaker 7:  those sharp edges. Like your gorgeous jewelry camera's not gonna look so
Speaker 7:  gorgeous after a while. You know, the, there's no EVF which I
Speaker 7:  is a huge strike for me. I know not people don't care but like
Speaker 7:  when I played with the Panasonic S nine, which is a compact little full frame
Speaker 7:  camera that also was limiting in a lot of ways. But
Speaker 7:  had that same idea, like functionality goes more towards color modes and
Speaker 7:  casual shooting and fun stuff. And then I played with the bf, I was like
Speaker 7:  gimme that S nine back as that thing actually is like a, that thing is a
Speaker 7:  professional monster compared to this. So I mean I get it as a,
Speaker 7:  as a beautiful camera that you wear in your shoulder that can take nice photos
Speaker 7:  and, and that can kind of be navigated once you learn it. Great. But
Speaker 7:  I would never like trust or rely on it to be like an everyday camera.
Speaker 7:  And I feel like Kato Yaki, the CEO just made it 'cause it looks so
Speaker 7:  beautiful and he is like, this is what I wanna carry around myself.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And truly it was my everyday carry. Right. Take photos
Speaker 8:  of stuff that I see around the street. I brought it to a press event, I think
Speaker 8:  it was a Google event, took one photo with And I was like, this is
Speaker 8:  not, this is not it. Let's go this party. So it
Speaker 8:  definitely, this was like, I'm gonna carry it around and bring it places
Speaker 8:  and take pictures of what I see professional setting. Absolutely
Speaker 8:  not. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Jordan did you, was the like video just a non-starter for you and
Speaker 2:  the BF or like what are your BF feelings?
Speaker 6:  I, it basically they're, they're pretty similar to Chris's. Like it's not
Speaker 6:  a great video camera. The microphone thing came up, which is
Speaker 6:  super weird on it. Yeah. To like have Bluetooth support, which I could never
Speaker 6:  get to work anyways. Oh no, there's no IBUs and the rolling shutter on it's
Speaker 6:  really bad. So again, it's those wibbly wobbly situations on it and I'm
Speaker 6:  terrified of it the whole time I'm holding it. I'm like, what is, what if
Speaker 6:  I accidentally put it down thero the wrong way and cut my stomach over? Like
Speaker 6:  it's, there were people who put it in their jacket pockets
Speaker 6:  and they like shredded the inside lining of their jacket pockets.
Speaker 6:  The one attribute it has is whenever I'm doing anything
Speaker 6:  on my own time, I have a camera with me. 'cause we're always testing stuff
Speaker 6:  and everyone ignores me. But this time, the one time
Speaker 6:  I went out with the bf I had like a half dozen people walk up and
Speaker 6:  just be like, that is cool. What is that? Is that, yeah. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  that's the appeal of it. If you wanna meet people and don't like joining
Speaker 6:  clubs, like the BF is a small investment to make new friends
Speaker 6:  but as a photographic tool, I just found it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Very difficult.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It is an unapologetic camera
Speaker 7:  that owes everybody an apology
Speaker 2:  For hurting them physically it sounds like
Speaker 7:  For all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So on the like also unapologetic, but with a different
Speaker 2:  like ethos I think, you know, you brought up the Fuji film
Speaker 2:  half, I'll be honest. I think it's adorable and fun
Speaker 2:  and adorable And I wanna carry it around also not,
Speaker 2:  I don't want it to be the camera I have every single day
Speaker 2:  and look back at photos of my kid in 10 years and be like, yes,
Speaker 2:  sorry sun. These are all like crappy
Speaker 2:  like film stock simulations.
Speaker 2:  So yeah. Chris, what's your take on the Fuji?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, like look, I, you know, I know I kind of sound like no fun nickels
Speaker 7:  all the time, but I've actually come around a lot on film
Speaker 7:  simulation modes of all sorts, right? Like, you know, Lumix Lab, Panasonic
Speaker 7:  did that with Lumix lab and Fujifilm's always done it and, and now
Speaker 7:  Sigma's doing like all the companies are kind of building up on this, make
Speaker 7:  your own preset kind of business. Do your own customizations, make a vintage
Speaker 7:  aesthetic, make a warm tone, you know, anything you wanna do. And I think
Speaker 7:  that's great. And, and actually on the X half I really enjoyed all the silly
Speaker 7:  stuff like the light leaks and you know, all these, all these kind of features
Speaker 7:  that it had. So you've got this tiny little camera with like a cropped
Speaker 7:  sensor down from micro four third size ish, you know, image
Speaker 7:  quality's fine. It's, it's fine. But it's, it's basic. And, and it's
Speaker 7:  this, it's this cute little, I mean it's, the design is beautiful.
Speaker 7:  It works in basically two modes. It's like two cameras at one. So first mode
Speaker 7:  is you have a very basic point and shoot digital camera, but you
Speaker 7:  can do film simulations, you can play around with some of this stuff. The
Speaker 7:  second mode is where it really kind of tries to draw a nostalgic, give you
Speaker 7:  a film shooting experience. So it shoots in a vertical format. I think we
Speaker 7:  should mention that, which is kind of cool right off the bat. Not that it
Speaker 7:  needs to, that's just what it does. Which is adorable. And, and the camera
Speaker 7:  has a thumb winder on it. So you can go into a film mode. You
Speaker 7:  choose a roll of film, like basically a Fuji film simulation. You choose
Speaker 7:  it and you're stuck with it For the next however many shots you're gonna
Speaker 7:  do, you can choose 24, 36, like
Speaker 7:  48, 72. And then at the end of doing that, it
Speaker 7:  develops that role of film. Oh my gosh. It gives you a contact sheet with
Speaker 7:  your negatives all laid out like that. Right. As a positive image.
Speaker 7:  And it's cute and it's fun And I get it. And you're using the thumb
Speaker 7:  winder in between every shot. It won't let you shoot unless you crank the
Speaker 7:  thumb winder in this second mode.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God.
Speaker 7:  But the thumb winder doesn't always register. If you go too fast
Speaker 7:  with that camera, you're, you're, do you have to like I started treating
Speaker 7:  it like an M three double wind. I'm like, I'm double winding this thing every
Speaker 7:  time just to make sure and like the novelty. I think
Speaker 7:  it's a super fun thing to do. And then after like, I don't know what your,
Speaker 7:  what your threshold will be, but after like three or four fake roles of film,
Speaker 7:  I'd just be like, forget it. I'm going back to the regular camera. 'cause
Speaker 7:  I wanna be able to have the option to just change things afterwards and not
Speaker 7:  have to, you know, go and go through 36 shots in black and white. When
Speaker 7:  I desperately see something I wanna shoot color. So I found myself just saying,
Speaker 7:  you know what? And the thumb winder was kind of silly and superfluous. So
Speaker 7:  after a while I was like, I just use this as a basic point and shoot camera.
Speaker 7:  But then why did I pay for that whole film and thumb wonder situation? I
Speaker 7:  mean, I don't know. That's, that's my feeling on it. I'm no fun. It's a gorgeous
Speaker 7:  camera. It's like gorgeously desired.
Speaker 2:  What is the price tag on it? We should say that out loud.
Speaker 7:  Like 800 bucks.
Speaker 8:  800
Speaker 6:  Us. Yeah. It's, I thought we were really surprised. The one thing
Speaker 6:  I will say about it is Chris may not have enjoyed doing like the
Speaker 6:  film mode thing, but as an outside spectator, 'cause I
Speaker 6:  didn't shoot photos on it. I had the terrible experience of shooting some
Speaker 6:  video on it, which I can briefly address. But,
Speaker 6:  but it looked like the whole time I'm like, that looks like fun. I wanna
Speaker 6:  do that. I wanna go take the half. Yeah. So there, there might be some appeal
Speaker 6:  there. I want to actually try it out, shoot some photos, see if I do enjoy
Speaker 6:  that. But like Chris mentioned, you know, the image quality's decent,
Speaker 6:  it's smartphone decent, you know. Yeah. It's, it's like a type one sense
Speaker 6:  or what the slow lens. So your smartphone will do the same quality. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But the video was hilarious because they have light leak effects, which,
Speaker 6:  you know, in photo just sit in one static place. But in
Speaker 6:  video, if you've got a leak it'll move based on where the light is coming
Speaker 6:  from. But this doesn't do this, so it looks like you just put like a piece
Speaker 6:  of glass in front of the lens and painted like an orange smear on it
Speaker 6:  and then it's just stuck in front as you wave the camera around. It looks
Speaker 6:  hilarious. Yeah. It's like early David Lynch when he was figuring out digital
Speaker 6:  cameras. But it's as weird as hell ruins
Speaker 2:  The, the illusion a little bit. Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  bien, you wrote the review for us and which seemed
Speaker 2:  very positive. Is this another like Sigma BF situation for
Speaker 2:  you where you're like, yes, it's limited, but I love what it
Speaker 7:  Is. I think he's a masochist. I I think that's what it's, I think you're
Speaker 7:  just a masochist. I
Speaker 8:  I'm, I'm just thinking optimist. No, I i i it was mostly
Speaker 8:  but so hard to justify. Right. We, we already talked about the price. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  The price is just ridiculous. If you look at the comments on any of the videos
Speaker 8:  or, or articles, everyone is like, thi this is insane.
Speaker 8:  What I did enjoy about it was actually using it
Speaker 8:  until you hit the, what was also mentioned. It feels slow.
Speaker 8:  You know when you take a photo and you crank it and it doesn't
Speaker 8:  register.
Speaker 7:  You found that too? Yeah. Oh
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It was very slow to like write onto the card And I had a fast card
Speaker 8:  in it. The processor in it is actually like really good. It shouldn't be
Speaker 8:  the case that it's so slow. Those are the things that like
Speaker 8:  bother me. What I did like about it's is that it felt like
Speaker 8:  some thought went into oh a hundred percent designing the hardware
Speaker 8:  and software int them for the experience of using it.
Speaker 8:  It didn't feel like, you know, hey here's a trend, we're gonna make
Speaker 8:  something really quickly. It like, you know, at these press events, they
Speaker 8:  give you the r and d story behind it And I was like, you know what, yeah
Speaker 8:  I can kind of buy it. I don't think it's quite just a cash grab, although
Speaker 8:  the price is ridiculous. So using it was fun. I did not try the video
Speaker 8:  with light leaks. Oh, you can if you got some time this
Speaker 8:  weekend. Enjoy. I'm good. No, no, no. This was, and
Speaker 8:  just for reference, like it wasn't a review, it was like a hands-on. I had
Speaker 8:  like a couple of hours with it. Oh yeah. So it was just like a pretty brief
Speaker 8:  experience with it and yeah, I think software hardware design
Speaker 8:  was interesting. Fun. It was fun to use, but it is
Speaker 8:  like, I would never buy because of the price. Even if I do buy it,
Speaker 8:  I am a little bit sucker for like high quality, beautiful, high megapixel,
Speaker 8:  everything. Sure. I don't think I would actually take it out as much. You
Speaker 8:  know, I, it would probably be the camera that I leave behind. I use
Speaker 8:  a lot more of like, you know, the pocket, the, the Osmo pockets and
Speaker 8:  one of these cameras. And I just want to cover every base.
Speaker 8:  The base that I don't want to cover is fun.
Speaker 8:  One inch sensor. Oh
Speaker 2:  Aura.
Speaker 8:  That's just extra.
Speaker 2:  You mentioned the Osmo And I have questions
Speaker 2:  actually I noticed this like I, this
Speaker 2:  was starting to ramp up when I was leaving deep review, but like
Speaker 2:  every camera company launching their like vlogger camera
Speaker 2:  and I got kind of a, a glimpse of, of
Speaker 2:  this I reported a little bit ago on, on the Cannon power shot
Speaker 2:  GX seven three. Right. The three. Oh
Speaker 7:  Lucky.
Speaker 2:  Have these like vlogging focused cameras panned out for the
Speaker 2:  manufacturers or did like the Osmo just win the
Speaker 8:  Osmo killed
Speaker 7:  Them all. That's funny. Yeah. The Osmo killed them all. I was thinking about
Speaker 7:  this though, just today. Like all these companies that we were going through
Speaker 7:  started making vlogging cameras. Right. Panasonic did. Nikon did. Sony of
Speaker 7:  course really came outta the gate first. Canon then started to, and it was
Speaker 7:  like no camera viewer that I really knew of. Super enjoyed these cameras,
Speaker 7:  right? We're all complaining about the same things. It's like, oh they're
Speaker 7:  expensive and like they're kind of silly And I don't know who wants these.
Speaker 7:  And I'm convinced it's 'cause there's so many people that do so many other
Speaker 7:  interests that we're just not interested in that are looking for a very basic
Speaker 7:  kit to get started. I guess if I was somebody starting out And I didn't know
Speaker 7:  what I was doing, I just wanted to like get something at Best Buy, put it
Speaker 7:  in front of me and make it work well then that might do it. Right. So
Speaker 7:  I I, I think that's why they were so popular. But I think now as more people
Speaker 7:  catch onto the Osmo, the beauty of a gimbal, the fact that again, it's very
Speaker 7:  simple. The fact that you can add microphones to it, like seamlessly,
Speaker 7:  that makes it even more convenient. And I think is more and more people figure
Speaker 7:  out what the pocket cameras do for them. We're gonna see even less and less
Speaker 7:  flog cameras.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. Have those been hard to get like the drones?
Speaker 8:  It's not hard to get except the price has gone up. Yes.
Speaker 8:  By 40%. I think it's about 900 bucks to like get the whole thing and it started
Speaker 8:  with 500.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean even at $900 it's still probably worth it.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, like when they were $500, what a steal. Yeah. What a great little
Speaker 7:  camera. And yeah, image quality as we've talked about is plateaued.
Speaker 7:  Nobody cares anymore. We want it to work and we want it to be easy and we
Speaker 7:  want to know that when we get home everything's okay and it's all set for
Speaker 7:  us. Like yeah, it's great.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well on the subject of making YouTube videos,
Speaker 2:  I have questions for the two of you, Chris and Jordan.
Speaker 2:  You guys have been at this for so long and
Speaker 2:  I'm curious on your perspective on how it's changed. You know, like
Speaker 2:  there's just a lot in that question. There's like the camera market has changed,
Speaker 2:  the technology has changed, like making the videos has changed but
Speaker 2:  I don't know how, how do you look at, at the change over the past
Speaker 2:  like decade that you've been doing this?
Speaker 7:  The style that younger creators make now is very different. We still stick
Speaker 7:  to our same style. We shoot a lot on location and as you can,
Speaker 7:  as you said Jordan with like nicer cameras, you know, Jordan's looking for
Speaker 7:  more cinematic results and control over depth of field. And so
Speaker 7:  whereas now I think a lot of young creators are looking more at presets and
Speaker 7:  more extreme color grades and faster cuts and stuff. But what do you think
Speaker 7:  Jordan?
Speaker 6:  And I think the big difference is when we started it just had to be passable.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And you could build a massive audience. Like basically our early stuff.
Speaker 6:  Is unwatchably bad?
Speaker 7:  No it's not.
Speaker 6:  But fairly quickly we got to a level where, yeah it was
Speaker 6:  better than, you know, something that someone with no background in video
Speaker 6:  production could put together. Where now you know, the bar is so
Speaker 6:  much higher if you're starting. But I think it almost puts us in an interesting
Speaker 6:  place 'cause it's not so much about like how is your production value, but
Speaker 6:  it's like what are you producing? And if that's compelling. Like I think
Speaker 6:  if you're like for us specifically, hey if you wanna review camera gear,
Speaker 6:  you know, you better back it up with some interesting photos or interesting
Speaker 6:  shoots or an interesting experience or something like that. Pure brute
Speaker 6:  technical knowhow is not gonna get you as far as it used to back in the
Speaker 6:  day. So, you know, we learned very quickly to just start injecting more
Speaker 6:  of our personalities into the video. And that's I think why we're still doing
Speaker 6:  this all that time later. Yeah, the tools have definitely, like editing is
Speaker 6:  faster now on location. They've given us a lot of stuff, you know, more dynamic
Speaker 6:  range in a camera means I can shoot in more locations without looking
Speaker 6:  for a place with easier light to work with. So all of that is just making
Speaker 6:  us more productive and that's what I, I love to see. Yeah. Is just like,
Speaker 6:  hey we can, we can actually do more now. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Does that resonate V
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But I actually wanted to ask a question. I feel like in the last couple
Speaker 8:  of years especially, you know, would, would the rise of short form video
Speaker 8:  content, especially when it comes to camera, every
Speaker 8:  release of a camera, everyone has a video about it. Everyone has
Speaker 8:  something ready to go on embargo. Right? It's more saturated than
Speaker 8:  ever honestly. And you know, we've seen reports of just like influencer marketing
Speaker 8:  budgets are like, you know, over roofing everything. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 8:  Is there anything else that you kind of do or think differently to stand
Speaker 8:  out to remain yourself?
Speaker 7:  We've always tried to do a lot of the videos that we reviews that we do with
Speaker 7:  the cameras that we have. Right. And we try to do them on location. So we're
Speaker 7:  not really in the office talking, we're out shooting on location because
Speaker 7:  we wanna give the viewers the idea like look this is how we're using the
Speaker 7:  camera. This is how you might use the camera Weather. Ceiling might be a
Speaker 7:  factor. You know, where you're actually gonna be out there and you know,
Speaker 7:  things like that. Auto focus, all these kind of things. And you see though,
Speaker 7:  I think a lot of creators are making really good stuff, but they're showing
Speaker 7:  a lot more of the end result of that video camera for example.
Speaker 7:  Or photographic camera, you know, after editing, after compiling it together.
Speaker 7:  And they're often shooting themselves speaking about it with different camera
Speaker 7:  gear. 'cause it's more convenient and it's quicker and it's easier if you're
Speaker 7:  just one person. Whereas we have the benefit of the, of the two of us.
Speaker 7:  So, but yeah, it's, it's just a different dynamic hence Jordan's shirt and,
Speaker 7:  and we've always tried to do that like beyond location using the cameras
Speaker 7:  as real world as we can. Not only for the photography but also for
Speaker 7:  the video. Yeah. Yeah. That one right there. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Film on location, you cowards. I love it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's where that comes from. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Alright, well thank you all three of you for joining me. And
Speaker 2:  I'm sure we're all gonna be together. IRL, you know. Yes. Soon enough
Speaker 2:  in the fall one way or another. So thank you.
Speaker 7:  That season's coming up. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Thanks guys. We've gotta take another break and After that
Speaker 2:  we're doing a mega hotline. Stay tuned.
Speaker 11:  I, you know, been doing a little work on my, my European phone market so
Speaker 11:  I can onto some of that side of things hopefully.
Speaker 2:  Yes please. Because the xmi
Speaker 2:  of the world are a mystery to me so
Speaker 2:  Great. Okay, so our first question
Speaker 2:  came from Brendan and he called
Speaker 2:  in so we can go ahead and listen to it.
Speaker 12:  Hi, this is Brendan from Rochester, New York. I have a pixel
Speaker 12:  six that is starting to get a little slow and nearing its end of you know,
Speaker 12:  guaranteed security updates next year. And so I was looking to buy a new
Speaker 12:  phone. I want something that's going to last for a while
Speaker 12:  and have OS updates and security updates, but I also want
Speaker 12:  something that's kind of on the smaller side. The pixel six is kind of heavy
Speaker 12:  and and big. So I was tempted by, you know, phones
Speaker 12:  like the asis Xfo nine.
Speaker 12:  I want something that's kind of around that size, which I know it's really
Speaker 12:  hard to find. So if you had any suggestions that would be great. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  I am so sorry Brendan, but we have nothing but
Speaker 2:  bad news for you.
Speaker 11:  My heart broke a little bit, especially that mention of the Zen phone nine
Speaker 11:  like I know I missed that one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I know. So the quick answer I think is
Speaker 2:  you're probably gonna want a Samsung Galaxy S 25 that is
Speaker 2:  the last smallish phone that is like,
Speaker 2:  you know, widely available in the US The Azu Zen phone kind
Speaker 2:  of went away. They like only make a big version now
Speaker 2:  And I don't think they even sell it in the us Are there options in the UK
Speaker 2:  that we just don't get here
Speaker 11:  Weirdly? No, this is one area we're still even the rest of Europe and
Speaker 11:  even if you look at China there's, there's not really a big difference other
Speaker 11:  than going into really tiny oddball things like the, the
Speaker 11:  Uni hertz Jelly Star, which is this minuscule phone with a minuscule screen
Speaker 11:  kind of that zen phone nine esque
Speaker 11:  form factor has pretty much gone. The S 25 is probably the best
Speaker 11:  bet. The, the kind of, the big one you might get in the rest of the world
Speaker 11:  is the Xmi 15. But that's basically the same size
Speaker 11:  as like a pixel nine, pixel 10. It's still a little bit bigger than an S
Speaker 11:  25. So if the main priority is size, the the S 25
Speaker 11:  is gonna be the best.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So we've failed Brendan, I'm sorry
Speaker 2:  but we yeah S 20 five's probably gonna be it
Speaker 2:  and our our hearts are with you.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. We have this perverse thing now where like even if you look at the
Speaker 11:  Chinese brands and what they're putting out even within China, not the stuff
Speaker 11:  that comes to Europe, we're seeing phones that are branded like mini or
Speaker 11:  compact and they're still 6.4 inch displays
Speaker 11:  and you know, they're bigger than an S 25, way bigger than an iPhone many
Speaker 11:  ever was. It's, it's kind of strange.
Speaker 2:  Yeah the phone beginning has happened and
Speaker 2:  it's, it's not gonna let up I think. So the next
Speaker 2:  question we have and we got this kind of a lot
Speaker 2:  is from Nate.
Speaker 13:  Hey there, this is Nate. I've been an apple like iPhone
Speaker 13:  user and Mac user forever. I'm definitely in
Speaker 13:  the the walled garden of Apple. Like I have the
Speaker 13:  AirPod Pro Apple watch and I'm just getting a little bored
Speaker 13:  and I'm curious what the other side is like And I
Speaker 13:  don't really know, you know with the Android phones
Speaker 13:  and even the watches and the headphones is there that
Speaker 13:  much of a difference? It'd be nice if they were similar but yeah, that's
Speaker 13:  my question. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  So this was kind of a theme, people being bored with their
Speaker 2:  phones And I don't know if I'm just being a bummer
Speaker 2:  but I kind of think that's 'cause phones are boring now.
Speaker 2:  What's your read on this Tom?
Speaker 11:  I think if boredom is the, the motivator, there are basically only two ways
Speaker 11:  you can go, which is buy a foldable which are maybe
Speaker 11:  a little bit more interesting if you are, if you're not already on one or
Speaker 11:  buy something from nothing, which is still ultimately just a phone
Speaker 11:  but at least it's gonna look kind of fun before you put your case on it
Speaker 2:  Before. Yeah, something from nothing Took me a second but yes,
Speaker 2:  yes. The, the phone brand, nothing. I'm kind of
Speaker 2:  thinking of your traditional like pixels and galaxies
Speaker 2:  and there are things here and there that are a little different. There's
Speaker 2:  definitely more AI features throughout
Speaker 2:  the os if that's something that interests you. I
Speaker 2:  don't think a lot of people are motivated by AI at this point.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I think a foldable is that's really the, the
Speaker 2:  best you can do as far as like it's going to feel different
Speaker 2:  and you're going to use it differently.
Speaker 11:  That changes your experience with the phone, whichever foldable form factor
Speaker 11:  you go for, whether you're talking like a flip phone which kind of can
Speaker 11:  reduce your screen time, you can leave the phone closed and engage with
Speaker 11:  it a bit less or obviously the book style gets you more of that, you know,
Speaker 11:  tablet that fits in your pocket kind of thing. Either way there Aren there
Speaker 11:  are different, different way of of having a phone. I mean the
Speaker 11:  other thing I'd say to that question with the kind of the broader, what
Speaker 11:  is there on the Android side side of that, that question from Nate.
Speaker 11:  One big difference that this is definitely a, a rest of the world thing
Speaker 11:  I'm afraid not the US thing but there is this whole kind of space where
Speaker 11:  cameras in the flagship Android devices
Speaker 11:  from the big Chinese OEMs like, like OMI and honor and Oppo
Speaker 11:  and Vivo, those cameras are and are really, really wild and
Speaker 11:  they are nothing like you're gonna find on any iPhone right now. Both in
Speaker 11:  terms of the design, these are like very big almost D-S-L-R-S camera rings
Speaker 11:  that dominate devices and make them very top heavy. But you know, amazing
Speaker 11:  telephoto lenses, really big sensors, really great depth of
Speaker 11:  field from shots and kind of a lot more processing options as well sometimes.
Speaker 11:  That's one thing I think that the Android side has that just there isn't
Speaker 11:  an option on the iPhone. The frustrating bit of that is then there's no
Speaker 11:  option for that in the US 'cause I think what Samsung and Google are doing
Speaker 11:  is much more in line with what Apple are doing, which is kind of, yeah more
Speaker 11:  modest camera bumps and very impressive cameras but not really
Speaker 11:  completely pushing the boat out there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah the, I feel like there's other companies in the world that have been
Speaker 2:  like what if hardware and yeah
Speaker 2:  the Samsung and Pixel phones are kind of like we've
Speaker 2:  locked in on the hardware and we're just optimizing the shit out of everything
Speaker 2:  with software. So that's kind of where we are.
Speaker 2:  I will say some of those, is it a phone? Is it a camera
Speaker 2:  Phones are so much fun to use and I'm extremely jealous
Speaker 2:  that you get to do that more than I do.
Speaker 11:  Oh they're great fun. But I mean I think there's definitely like there's
Speaker 11:  a big aesthetic trade off as well, which I think is part of the reason the
Speaker 11:  big US players haven't opted for it. 'cause you're already basically saying
Speaker 11:  I'm willing for my phone to look quite a lot uglier in the name
Speaker 11:  of having a way better camera experience. And I don't know that that's the
Speaker 11:  mainstream US or or European phone buyer, right. Most people
Speaker 11:  are not willing to make that swap. They want a really good camera but they
Speaker 11:  still want their phone to look like a normal attractive phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you gotta choose, you gotta make your choices and the
Speaker 2:  US manufacturers have made that choice for us. So our next
Speaker 2:  question is kind of relates because Brian wants to know about
Speaker 2:  Foldables so we can listen to that one.
Speaker 14:  Hi Allison. My name's Ryan. My thing that I
Speaker 14:  run into a lot with phones, at least for the last
Speaker 14:  year or so and what will be the next year is battery life.
Speaker 14:  And I am really contemplating some of the folding phones
Speaker 14:  that are out there on the market right now. Obviously
Speaker 14:  what will be the Pixel Pro 10
Speaker 14:  fold is really appealing. But I
Speaker 14:  don't know, just based on what I've seen, if battery life on any
Speaker 14:  foldable right now is that great. So
Speaker 14:  I guess like battery life inside of foldables or do I just
Speaker 14:  stick to my good old candy bar options and get the biggest
Speaker 14:  and baddest battery life. So that's kinda what I'm running into right now
Speaker 14:  and maybe others are too. Thank you so much and hopefully
Speaker 14:  talk to you, hear from you soon. Right.
Speaker 2:  So I'm curious your thoughts on this, but I think my general take
Speaker 2:  is the foldable, like the bigger book style
Speaker 2:  foldables have just kind of like the battery life was
Speaker 2:  not great and they've kind of gotten to a place where you have parody with
Speaker 2:  a decent slab style phone but not like you should not expect it
Speaker 2:  to exceed like your average slab phone
Speaker 2:  for battery life. What do you think Dom?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I broadly agree with that. I think one thing I'd say for the big
Speaker 11:  foldables is so much of it's gonna come down to how you expect to use it.
Speaker 11:  Which is what I mean by that is how much are you gonna open it up. I'm a
Speaker 11:  very boring foldable user when I'm reviewing them because I,
Speaker 11:  I actually don't find that many uses for the big screen personally. So I
Speaker 11:  use it 90% of the time as a regular phone closed
Speaker 11:  and the battery life then is pretty comparable. You're not really getting
Speaker 11:  a difference. Now obviously people listening will be, well why on earth
Speaker 11:  would I buy one of these if I'm not gonna open it up all the time? So that's
Speaker 11:  a very fair point. The battery life will go down when you open it up, but
Speaker 11:  you should think about like, do you want it to be something that you can
Speaker 11:  open up for half an hour on your commute in the morning
Speaker 11:  and occasionally when you are, you know, sitting on the couch and just wanna,
Speaker 11:  wanna read or is this something where you think all the time you're using
Speaker 11:  this, you're gonna open it up and use the big screen. 'cause the more you
Speaker 11:  use the big screen, the worst the battery's gonna be. So there's a bit of
Speaker 11:  a trade off there.
Speaker 2:  I have a similar experience where I'm just, I don't know if it's because
Speaker 2:  I just use a slab style phone all the time, but I, I sort of
Speaker 2:  have to remind myself like, oh no, this phone opens, I need to open it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And like try it that way. And I, I'll inevitably like
Speaker 2:  download Diablo Immortal or something to it to like really
Speaker 2:  play and test it out and I'm like, a, I think I would do this
Speaker 2:  more because it's so much nicer on a big screen and
Speaker 2:  b wow does that kill the battery life like So fast? Yeah. So yeah,
Speaker 2:  it is, it is so variable And I wouldn't
Speaker 2:  discount like your phone habits maybe changing once you
Speaker 2:  have the option of a, of a bigger tablet like
Speaker 2:  experience. But I don't know, I did read a lot of comments
Speaker 2:  recently on, on something I wrote about foldables where foldable owners
Speaker 2:  were saying that they rarely open their folding phone. And
Speaker 2:  I was like, oh,
Speaker 11:  Interesting. I've always thought that was a me problem. So it's, it's interesting
Speaker 11:  know people who actually own them kind of feel the same way sometimes. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  I guess there's two other things I'd say to Brian on that question
Speaker 11:  first, I think you are right that a flip phone is probably not for you
Speaker 11:  from the description of what you want. And especially if battery life is
Speaker 11:  the concern, I think the flip phones still struggle there. Like you said
Speaker 11:  Alison, you can kind of the, the book style give you parity with a decent
Speaker 11:  slab on battery life. The flips are definitely still behind and
Speaker 11:  they're good enough right now to run for a day. But you know, if you're
Speaker 11:  gonna use it for four years, I wouldn't trust it'll be good enough to last
Speaker 11:  a day in four years time on any of the flips really. And the other thing
Speaker 11:  I'll say is the little, the rest of the world perspective, because this
Speaker 11:  is a different story outside of the US though it's only beginning
Speaker 11:  to change this year. We've seen a lot of big foldables coming out with
Speaker 11:  silicon carbon batteries, which are meaning they're getting bigger capacities.
Speaker 11:  So I reviewed the Oppo Find N five, which was at the time the
Speaker 11:  thinnest around and that had a, I think a 5,600 million power
Speaker 11:  battery vivo just put out foldable And I think it's just in China and
Speaker 11:  India, the X fold five that's got a 6,000 million power battery though
Speaker 11:  I haven't tried that one. It's wild honor have announced the magic
Speaker 11:  V five in China, but they've also announced that it's getting a a, a European
Speaker 11:  release at least very soon. That one is I think
Speaker 11:  5,800 million powers. If all those numbers sound
Speaker 11:  like nonsense to you, all three of those battery capacities are bigger than
Speaker 11:  an S 25 ultra by some way. Yeah. So these are all big
Speaker 11:  foldables that could beat most slap phones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 11:  So this is happening. It's changing. Like I said, those aren't even all
Speaker 11:  out in Europe. I think the honor will be out in Europe, but the other two
Speaker 11:  aren't. But if you are in Europe, if you're in India, if you're elsewhere
Speaker 11:  in in Asia or somewhere, look at those brands because you might actually
Speaker 11:  find that there are some recent models from this year that, that really
Speaker 11:  are up there with not just an average slab phone for battery life, but up
Speaker 11:  there with the best slab phones for battery life.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's, there's been a real hesitation from,
Speaker 2:  at at least Google and Samsung from what I can tell about
Speaker 2:  adopting the silicon carbon batteries. So I wouldn't expect
Speaker 2:  that to change anytime like super soon, but you
Speaker 2:  never know. I don't know, maybe we can have nice things too.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I think this is a change that's gonna roll out faster and faster elsewhere,
Speaker 11:  but I, I don't expect either Samsung or Google to be jumping on this just
Speaker 11:  yet. But we'll see. It'd be nice if they did. Yeah, because it really is
Speaker 11:  gonna be, you know, both in Foldables And I regular phones, this is gonna
Speaker 11:  be a, a big driver of bigger batteries and smaller phones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Maybe we can have it all smaller phones.
Speaker 11:  Maybe we can have small phones again because we can have big batteries in
Speaker 11:  our small phones. Oh
Speaker 2:  My god, please. Okay, now I am rooting for silicon
Speaker 2:  carbon And I want it now. Next up we
Speaker 2:  have just a very Charming question from
Speaker 2:  Smiley.
Speaker 15:  Hey, my name is Smiley Roja Nunez. AKA Smiley, no
Speaker 15:  really singer songwriter. I'm calling in because I have a
Speaker 15:  Pixel four A 5G that I refuse to upgrade
Speaker 15:  from. Long story short, the pixel four A 5G has a headphone
Speaker 15:  jack And I like to go and perform music
Speaker 15:  in little clubs and open mics and it's so useful to have that headphone
Speaker 15:  jack. Also, it's one of the last pixels with the
Speaker 15:  unlimited photo storage. I don't feel like paying for a
Speaker 15:  plan first photo storage, so that's another reason why I haven't upgraded.
Speaker 15:  But now it does feel like it's getting in my way when it comes to using
Speaker 15:  Instagram, which unfortunately is a tool that I need to use to promote
Speaker 15:  myself and my artistry. So I'm thinking of upgrading.
Speaker 15:  I know that the one plus 13 is the best Android phone
Speaker 15:  available right now, but sadly it's huge. So
Speaker 15:  I'm like, what to do, what to do.
Speaker 15:  I don't know that I need this year's latest model, but yeah, appreciate
Speaker 15:  you listening to this message and help a brother out.
Speaker 15:  Peace. Peace.
Speaker 2:  I'm just very charmed, my smiley And I love
Speaker 2:  that he is held onto the pixel Forer 5G
Speaker 2:  like way to go, way to milk Google for the
Speaker 2:  unlimited photo storage and hold onto that headphone
Speaker 2:  jack. But I think this is another like
Speaker 2:  bad news kinda situation. I'm, I'm like
Speaker 2:  racking my brain for a, a like flagship
Speaker 2:  ish phone that has a headphone jack And I'm
Speaker 2:  try Jelly figure out if Motorola sells one.
Speaker 11:  No. Yeah, I feel like some of the cheaper models might still have
Speaker 11:  headphone jacks. Yeah, I don't think anything higher end
Speaker 11:  does even, you know, in, in Europe they have the whole Edge series, which
Speaker 11:  is kind of mid-range bordering on flagship and, and some of those come out
Speaker 11:  in the states under different names, but none of those have headphone jacks.
Speaker 11:  I think, I think you need to be looking at like the Moto G kind of
Speaker 11:  budget, couple hundred bucks models And I FI feel like some of those still
Speaker 11:  have a headphone jack kicking around, but yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's right.
Speaker 11:  I dunno how much of a performance bump that will feel like even coming from
Speaker 11:  a, I guess the foray is old so they, they will feel better than a foray
Speaker 11:  but not, not like a giant jump forward.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's what, okay. The Moto G stylist I
Speaker 2:  believe has a headphone jack and like a
Speaker 2:  very nice kind of vegan leather back
Speaker 2:  panel. The thing that I am
Speaker 2:  a little hesitant about is that it is just loaded with bloat wear,
Speaker 2:  a lot of which you can opt out of and uninstall.
Speaker 2:  So if you're willing to do that, it's a nice little phone.
Speaker 2:  I, I also worry a little bit about
Speaker 2:  longevity if you would. I feel like Smiley kind of wants
Speaker 2:  to hold onto a phone for a while given that he's still rocking the
Speaker 2:  four A 5G and Motorola, especially for the budget,
Speaker 2:  you get maybe two or three years of upgrades
Speaker 2:  and then you're, you're done. So you're shopping for a new phone again,
Speaker 2:  But that might be the only option with the headphone jack.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, my other hesitation on the Motorola would be the camera. 'cause Smiley
Speaker 11:  mentioned, you know, being interested by the opo, which the, the find
Speaker 11:  XASI think is the, the phone that the mini ended up being, you know,
Speaker 11:  call that out for being smallish with a camera but the Moto
Speaker 11:  is, is is not gonna have a great camera I if anything, that might be one
Speaker 11:  bit where it really does feel like a downgrade from a four A because it's,
Speaker 11:  I think any, yeah, pixel camera almost. It's gonna beat, beat sort of what
Speaker 11:  you find on a, on a cheap Motorola Motorola's cameras
Speaker 11:  are good on some of the higher end models but not on, I doubt the G stylus
Speaker 11:  is, is gonna be a real winner for that side.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah, that's a good call out.
Speaker 11:  There sort of is one phone that kind of exists that does this almost,
Speaker 11:  but I, I don't think, I don't think this might can buy it in the US And
Speaker 11:  I don't think he should, which is the Sony Xperia
Speaker 11:  one, Mach seven. Right. Which is kind of
Speaker 11:  compact ish. It's got a headphone jack, it's
Speaker 11:  got pretty good cameras. Not the best, But that they're not bad. I
Speaker 11:  dunno how great they are for longevity, but it's not out in the US
Speaker 11:  That particular model has had some issues. They've had to do a recall for
Speaker 11:  a lot of units across Europe. I certainly wouldn't trust Sony on
Speaker 11:  the longevity in terms of their commitment to the smartphone market. They
Speaker 11:  actually just said they like recent quarterly earnings that it's, you know,
Speaker 11:  The Xperia phone business is very important to them but I, I dunno how much
Speaker 11:  I believe that, but putting out one or two phones a year and and barely
Speaker 11:  releasing them at all, even if you could buy it, I think it would be about,
Speaker 11:  you know, one and a half grand is the, the price, right. So
Speaker 2:  It's, oh my God,
Speaker 11:  It's crazy expensive for what it is. Yeah, so that is the phone, but also
Speaker 11:  don't buy that phone.
Speaker 2:  It exists but also, yeah, don't, yeah, I,
Speaker 2:  you know, a couple years back I think I was still reviewing Xperia phones
Speaker 2:  and yeah it was that kind of like, this is
Speaker 2:  very pricey and I'm only hearing like two
Speaker 2:  years of software support promise. So just like the
Speaker 2:  math just just doesn't work for me there I think among other reasons.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I don't know. Let us know Smiley, I hope you find
Speaker 2:  something or maybe just gonna have to join the rest
Speaker 2:  of us in, in the world who lost the headphone jack
Speaker 2:  and we, we mourn it every day. So I've got
Speaker 2:  another one here. This is from TJ Huddleston.
Speaker 2:  He also messaged me on Threads or Blue Sky, one of those
Speaker 2:  And I kind of hinted at what I think he should get, but
Speaker 2:  here's TJ explaining it.
Speaker 16:  Hey, my name is TJ Huddleston. I am considering switching from iOS
Speaker 16:  to Android and I'm not really sure if that is the right move for me.
Speaker 16:  I, I used Android from its inception up until the iPhone 12
Speaker 16:  and one of the reasons I switched the iPhone 12 is I just wanted my phone
Speaker 16:  to work. I was, used my phone for work more often And I got tired
Speaker 16:  of all the slowness and and uncertainty when it came to Android
Speaker 16:  but now I'm just getting bored. But here's my, my issue is that
Speaker 16:  I work in a construction related field and so I always need access to
Speaker 16:  my phone. My phone is a tool and so I need really good battery life but
Speaker 16:  also I need a good warranty service. One of the things I really like about
Speaker 16:  having an iPhone or Apple device in general is that I can go to an
Speaker 16:  Apple store And I can have my phone fixed most of the time the same day.
Speaker 16:  And so I really want that capacity whenever I switch to an Android phone.
Speaker 16:  Part of me just wants to get a Samsung, maybe the S 25 Ultra because
Speaker 16:  it has that nice stylus And I can annotate on pictures and stuff like that.
Speaker 16:  So my question for Allison is if you were focused on
Speaker 16:  Repairability or maybe service when it came
Speaker 16:  to to maintenance and repairs, who would you choose? Thanks.
Speaker 16:  Love the show.
Speaker 2:  I love that TJ And I agree because he,
Speaker 2:  he names the phone I think he should get which is the,
Speaker 2:  the S 25 Ultra and there's a a few reasons
Speaker 2:  for that, some of which he mentions, but I'm curious if that was your instinct
Speaker 2:  too, Dom.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I mean definitely if we're talking about the US
Speaker 11:  and, and even really outside the US it's gotta be Samsung. If,
Speaker 11:  if your aim is serviceability and you want to be able to get
Speaker 11:  quick, easy, reliable repairs for a device and you don't want
Speaker 11:  it to be an Apple, then yeah Samsung is is absolutely gonna be the next
Speaker 11:  best thing And Google third best it it is one of those cases where the big
Speaker 11:  brands that play in the US are are absolutely the best options. And then
Speaker 11:  you know, the S 25 Ultra it sounds like he, you know, TJ likes the sound
Speaker 11:  of the stylus and the big display. He talked about wanting a foldable for
Speaker 11:  the big screen so going for the ultra makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, And I, I would steer him away from a
Speaker 2:  foldable in this case. Yes. Just for the, yeah, the repairability
Speaker 2:  things he mentions and like I can see how the, the big inner
Speaker 2:  screen would really come in handy. But I guess I think that's a, a
Speaker 2:  situation where you, you like also have a tablet if you
Speaker 2:  need that kind of thing. But the S 25 Ultra being a
Speaker 2:  gigantic phone is the closest you're gonna get on a slab
Speaker 2:  style phone. Something else going for the Ultra is that, and
Speaker 2:  it doesn't get talked about enough I think is the anti-glare
Speaker 2:  coating on the screen, which is really good
Speaker 2:  and especially if he is working outside with it a lot and if the,
Speaker 2:  you know, sun's shining we're sort of used to like casting a shadow
Speaker 2:  over your phone and like hunching over it and you then you can see it outside.
Speaker 2:  You have to see it to believe it but the ultra really is like
Speaker 2:  better to use outside I think.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, that's a great shout. Yeah, we've seen all, all the brands over the
Speaker 11:  last few years sort of competing on claims about how bright the displays
Speaker 11:  get with that focus on use set doors and it almost doesn't matter
Speaker 11:  because the ultra is there with the anti ggl coating that does a much better
Speaker 11:  job than just pumping up the brightness in the screen.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah it's, it's kinda wild. So I think it's a good
Speaker 2:  choice for that. And like you mentioned the,
Speaker 2:  just the availability of places you can walk into, you know Samsung
Speaker 2:  has an agreement I think with it's called like You break,
Speaker 2:  I fix it, not I fix
Speaker 11:  It. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think that's it. Something along those lines. But I see enough of those
Speaker 2:  around that I sort of file it away in the back of my head like
Speaker 2:  yeah I could bring a Samsung phone there if I needed to.
Speaker 11:  I say this with a little hesitation 'cause I'm not a hundred percent on
Speaker 11:  the US market side of this but I'm pretty sure Samsung has some sort of
Speaker 11:  subscription care service, a little like AppleCare plus, you know Yeah.
Speaker 11:  One of those sign up and pay them, pay 'em a certain amount per month and
Speaker 11:  it gets you a guarantee of a certain number of, of repairs or easier access
Speaker 11:  to repairs or something like that. So that would be something to look at
Speaker 11:  as well if you are, if you know that that worry that you are
Speaker 11:  regularly breaking your phone. Yeah. If you have that concern. The wild
Speaker 11:  card I'd say again with my little non-US hat on is a
Speaker 11:  Fairphone, which is a very different take on repairability and serviceability
Speaker 11:  'cause you fix it yourself but they are very easy to fix for the most part.
Speaker 11:  I would just be reviewing The Fairphone six, the latest model And I
Speaker 11:  am a complete idiot with this kinda stuff but I'm actually take the phone
Speaker 11:  completely apart to its parts and put it all the way back together and it
Speaker 11:  still worked at the other end of it all and they sell their own, you know,
Speaker 11:  replacement displays, USB ports, speakers, individual camera
Speaker 11:  modules, things like that. You can get The Fairphone in the US but
Speaker 11:  they're only sold through this company called Moreno that makes this privacy
Speaker 11:  de Googled os it makes 'em quite expensive and the OS is
Speaker 11:  a little specific and limiting I, I don't totally
Speaker 11:  dislike it but you've gotta want the D Googled side of it. Yeah. And if
Speaker 11:  that doesn't appeal, I think you'll find it quite frustrating. Especially
Speaker 11:  if, if TJ's hesitation was that he'd been in the Roy
Speaker 11:  early days of Android and and was hoping it was a lot better and more polished.
Speaker 11:  EOS is good but I don't think polished is like the word. It feels a bit
Speaker 11:  like going back to Android five years ago. Yeah. But if you are outside
Speaker 11:  the US or in the US and willing to import, you can get a Fairphone with
Speaker 11:  their own software, which is kind of closer to stock modern Google and
Speaker 11:  works pretty well and you know, they give you years of software updates.
Speaker 11:  You can fix the phone easily yourself, get spare pots. So that's a very
Speaker 11:  different take on on wanting a phone that's serviceable repairable, but
Speaker 11:  that's, that's an option elsewhere as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The DIY option, I took a
Speaker 2:  an HMD skyline apart and not, not like really
Speaker 2:  apart. It's a, it's one of those like ultra repairable phones. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  replaced the battery myself And I felt like I was
Speaker 2:  unstoppable. I, I was like I wanna take every phone apart.
Speaker 11:  I know. It was so much fun. Dissembling this Fairphone I surrounded by tiny
Speaker 11:  screws and, And I only got two bits wrong And I put it back together and
Speaker 11:  it still worked once I figured that out so. Oh nice. Anyone can do it if
Speaker 11:  I can.
Speaker 2:  TJ let me know what, what you bought, what you plan on buying
Speaker 2:  and good luck to you. So last
Speaker 2:  kind of call in here we have Sean with
Speaker 2:  I think a conundrum that I hear a lot from people. So
Speaker 2:  we'll listen to Sean.
Speaker 17:  Hey Allison, I am kind of torn. I
Speaker 17:  have been in the Android ecosystem for a very long time then
Speaker 17:  I switched to iPhones because my company switched to iPhones. Then
Speaker 17:  I ended up getting my own personal iPhone. So I've, you know, now I have
Speaker 17:  two phones and I'm kind of debating do I want to go back to
Speaker 17:  Android? You know, my whole family is now on iPhones and so it's
Speaker 17:  like that's really the struggle right, is they all have iPhones. So
Speaker 17:  now we've got, IM messaging now we've got shared calendars now we've got
Speaker 17:  all these different pieces that kind of integrate to each other. So when
Speaker 17:  I used to have an Android, it was a huge problem because we couldn't
Speaker 17:  have a shared family calendar. We had to try to make it work between Google
Speaker 17:  calendar and Apple Calendar and it just, just never great.
Speaker 17:  So could I just stick with Apple and it just keeps the
Speaker 17:  ecosystem harmonized together where the whole family's on the same thing
Speaker 17:  or if I do switch, what are some of the apps that maybe I could use or should
Speaker 17:  use to try to keep that same compatibility
Speaker 17:  going across all of the family's devices. Thanks a lot. Have a good
Speaker 17:  day.
Speaker 2:  A family divided,
Speaker 2:  this is always when I see a couple and one of them has an
Speaker 2:  Android, one of them has an iPhone. I am always asking them this question.
Speaker 2:  I'm like how's that going for you? I feel like my like
Speaker 2:  big answer is like how much do you wanna keep the piece?
Speaker 2:  And also generally it has gotten better
Speaker 2:  being a, a mixed OS family
Speaker 2:  these days than maybe it was you know, five years ago. But do you have a
Speaker 2:  go-to answer on this Dom when people are grappling with this?
Speaker 11:  I have no useful practical advice because when I first started
Speaker 11:  dating my current partner five years ago, she was using an iPhone And I
Speaker 11:  basically kind of forced her to switch to an Android 'cause she kept getting
Speaker 11:  jealous of like the cameras on my phones and eventually switched and it
Speaker 11:  was like, ah, that's better now we, we just sync up and everything's easier.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. So I haven't had to live that life of, of moving between them. At
Speaker 11:  least not in the last few years. I agree it's a lot better than it used
Speaker 11:  to be. If, if Sean's experiences from a few
Speaker 11:  years ago and kind of comparing five to 10 years ago that
Speaker 11:  that process to now it it will definitely be better. 80 to
Speaker 11:  90% of the time everything will just work and it'll be fine and it won't
Speaker 11:  matter that and you're on an Android phone and your partner
Speaker 11:  or your kids are on or on iPhones and there'll be that one time where
Speaker 11:  some calendar bit goes a bit screwy or you know, the messaging app
Speaker 11:  gets annoying or something like that and then you'll all be really irritated
Speaker 11:  by it. And how invested are you avoiding those
Speaker 11:  sort of sporadic irritations is the question. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it will be your fault. It doesn't matter if like if
Speaker 2:  the Apple products are not getting it right, it doesn't matter, it's your
Speaker 2:  fault. I have lived this in my own
Speaker 2:  household. Yeah And I will say like especially in the US we
Speaker 2:  don't tend to use the third party messaging apps like you all do.
Speaker 2:  So having RCS support on iOS now
Speaker 2:  has been huge. When I am on an Android phone now and I'm
Speaker 2:  on a flight, I can still message my husband on his
Speaker 2:  iPhone because we're just doing RCS over wifi and all that. So
Speaker 2:  that has been a really big like help I think to
Speaker 2:  the people in the, the mixed ecosystem situation.
Speaker 2:  Something I will add is that the very recent
Speaker 2:  Pixel 10 phones come with Q2, which
Speaker 2:  is a wireless charging standard but also has the magnets built
Speaker 2:  in and it's, it's basically MagSafe. So if your
Speaker 2:  family's using MagSafe accessories, they have things around the
Speaker 2:  house that you know, you would not normally be able to plug into like
Speaker 2:  a magnetic charger. You could look at the Pixel 10
Speaker 2:  and you'd be able to just like slide right into that
Speaker 2:  ecosystem there. But yeah, I think that your
Speaker 2:  point of like something is gonna go a little sideways, you can,
Speaker 2:  I, I certainly have been fine with
Speaker 2:  calendars, you know switching between iPhone and Android. I think I've gotten
Speaker 2:  it takes a little bit of futzing around but you can
Speaker 2:  get, you know all the Google calendars you're supposed to see on iPhone
Speaker 2:  and vice versa. Something goes weird sometimes
Speaker 2:  And I don't know, you just gotta own it. If you're cool with that then
Speaker 2:  the world is your oyster on Android. So we have a bunch
Speaker 2:  more questions. We'll get into some emails but we're gonna take a really
Speaker 2:  quick break.
Speaker 2:  different kinds of content to read. Reads two to three books
Speaker 2:  a week and also says she doesn't care about AI until it stops
Speaker 2:  hallucinating or has a killer app or something. Amen to that.
Speaker 2:  So the conundrum is because she
Speaker 2:  owns her phone, she's under no pressure to move but she wants
Speaker 2:  to make the reading experience better. Does she look at a
Speaker 2:  books device or a kind of premium
Speaker 2:  reader? She says swollen an e-reader is interesting.
Speaker 2:  She's more of a one device type of girl. So
Speaker 2:  yeah this one is interesting because I know more people
Speaker 2:  who definitely have a dedicated device for
Speaker 2:  reading on the go. Like a Kindle or or like our, our favorite
Speaker 2:  or books Palms. The really oddball one
Speaker 2:  I'll throw out there And I don't actually think Izzy should
Speaker 2:  buy it. I'm testing this TCL 60
Speaker 2:  XE that has an E in
Speaker 2:  ish mode where you, it just brings the screen to
Speaker 2:  monochrome. You can do it in two ways where it really
Speaker 2:  like is sort of a focus mode thing if you wanna like
Speaker 2:  pay attention to notifications less or you can just kind of
Speaker 2:  mimic an E Ink screen and just have access to like all the normal
Speaker 2:  stuff on your phone. I've been carrying it around as a kind
Speaker 2:  of second device in my, well I'm not doing anymore but I went
Speaker 2:  when I was try Jelly use a watch like an LTE watch as my phone.
Speaker 2:  I had this on me so I would have a screen to read
Speaker 2:  something and it was all right. It was like surprisingly
Speaker 2:  kind of pleasant for that. Not a great phone overall. So I don't think
Speaker 2:  that's the answer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you have any ideas here Dom?
Speaker 11:  I think Izzy should maybe look more closely at the, the book stall
Speaker 11:  foldable. It seems to sort of suggest this as an option and
Speaker 11:  then hesitate about the aspect ratio and the price, which is understandable.
Speaker 11:  I mean I would say, I said earlier I, when I have a book stall foldable,
Speaker 11:  I don't actually open them up that much except for reading. Reading is what
Speaker 11:  I find them really grateful. The aspect ratio when they're open it's kind
Speaker 11:  of squareish usually or like a a little bit portrait that
Speaker 11:  makes them odd for watching video or playing games and that
Speaker 11:  vision of open your phone up to watch a movie doesn't really work 'cause
Speaker 11:  you don't get a lot more space but open your phone up to read a book or
Speaker 11:  even just, you know, read an article on a website or something And I always
Speaker 11:  do that. That's when I wanna open them 'cause it just feels like suddenly
Speaker 11:  the screen is so much more spacious, so much more comfortable to read on
Speaker 11:  And I much prefer that. So I do think if reading is the use case that
Speaker 11:  maybe it sounds like an unnecessary expense to get this sort of one and
Speaker 11:  a half thousand dollars phone just to read eBooks on. But it is better And
Speaker 11:  I do think that would be a nice experience. I really think it will feel
Speaker 11:  like worlds better than reading on a slap phone and definitely better
Speaker 11:  than reading on on a flip phone, which is sort of the other option suggested
Speaker 11:  there, which I don't think getting a flip phone solves any of the problems
Speaker 11:  here other than the flip phones are fun And I love flip phones so I do often
Speaker 11:  recommend them But that doesn't necessarily seem like the right thing here.
Speaker 11:  So I, I would look at a, at a bookstore one they are expensive but you know
Speaker 11:  you can look at a last gen model or something, you know we've just had the
Speaker 11:  Pixel 10 pro fold. You can look at the nine pro fold and see if that means
Speaker 11:  you can get it at a better price and that kind of thing. I probably wouldn't
Speaker 11:  look at the last gen Samsung right now just 'cause they made such a big
Speaker 11:  jump with the, with the Z fold seven. And so the Z fold six is, is
Speaker 11:  maybe a bigger compromise compared to the pixels where I think the nine
Speaker 11:  is is really giving you a lot of what you get with the 10 i I like the look
Speaker 11:  of the 10 but I, I don't think you're losing too much with the nine unless
Speaker 11:  you really really want the Q2 charging. I read this question And I think
Speaker 11:  yeah buy a big foldable it sounds like that's gonna solve your problem.
Speaker 2:  Yeah the more I hear you argue for it, I'm like yeah, that does
Speaker 2:  make sense. And given that Izzy owns her S
Speaker 2:  24 plus when those trade-in deals come
Speaker 2:  around, yes Samsung will give you a lot of money
Speaker 2:  off a foldable for your S 24 plus.
Speaker 11:  Very good point, yeah, yeah,
Speaker 2:  Keep an eye on those that will really take the sting out of
Speaker 2:  the price because they are super expensive.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I think would be a lot of fun for that use case. And when you're
Speaker 2:  done reading you can just close it and that feels great.
Speaker 2:  So all right Izzy, I'm sorry we,
Speaker 2:  you're resigned to spending $1,500 but that's what we, that's what we
Speaker 2:  decided here in phone court
Speaker 2:  legally binding. Alright, so next
Speaker 2:  up we have a question from Sam and
Speaker 2:  also gonna kind of paraphrase this. So Sam
Speaker 2:  had an iPhone 13 pro, got sick of it and then
Speaker 2:  downgraded to the iPhone SE two to hang onto that
Speaker 2:  home button and, but is struggling
Speaker 2:  with the common complaints of
Speaker 2:  spending too much time on social media and wanting
Speaker 2:  access to like texting, email, calling podcasts, all that stuff,
Speaker 2:  but has a hard time kind of moderating the
Speaker 2:  social media and screen time. So Sam is looking
Speaker 2:  into dumb phones and thought about getting a flip phone
Speaker 2:  or the light phone but hesitated because they might not have
Speaker 2:  enough of the functionality. Spent some time with the Uni Hertz
Speaker 2:  Jelly Star, which we've kind of touched on ertz a couple times, but
Speaker 2:  android phones that really lean into the, the hardware of
Speaker 2:  like minimalism and it sounds like
Speaker 2:  it was too small and her eyes started hurting from reading the
Speaker 2:  small text on the small screen. She says I mostly use
Speaker 2:  text and email on it so it wasn't putting too much of a strain on my eyes,
Speaker 2:  but my one vice was reading the news on the tiny screen And I think
Speaker 2:  that's what strained my eyes the most. I am sorry to hear that.
Speaker 2:  So has switched back to the SE two but is missing a
Speaker 2:  tiny phone, so, oh my gosh Sam, you've been
Speaker 2:  on a journey, a journey that brought you to Uni Hertz and back.
Speaker 11:  I'm so sad that we finally have someone who like did go out and get the
Speaker 11:  small phone, the smallest small phone, the one everyone says they want
Speaker 11:  and it made her eyes hurt and now she's having to find a bigger phone. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I know. No, yeah, that's a
Speaker 2:  real bummer. Yeah, I own an iPhone 13 mini. I love it.
Speaker 2:  I'm not parting with it until it's a security risk. I don't think I'd recommend
Speaker 2:  someone go buy one secondhand at this point. Yeah, we're we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk a little bit more specifically about that, but there is the,
Speaker 2:  you know, the battery life is not gonna be super great at this point.
Speaker 2:  So the, the one suggestion I'll throw in here is that
Speaker 2:  maybe the answer is a cellular
Speaker 2:  watch because
Speaker 2:  this is an experiment I just ran, you know, try Jelly, see how much
Speaker 2:  I could get away with doing on the watch as kind of a minimalist
Speaker 2:  phone or like a, a phone replacement And I
Speaker 2:  had a little bit of trouble, you know, getting everything done with a watch,
Speaker 2:  but it gives you a surprising amount of functionality. You can
Speaker 2:  play your podcast, you can type messages to people and
Speaker 2:  it's a little fiddly but it's not the worst. So I would throw
Speaker 2:  that in as an option. It, it sounds counterintuitive, you're like
Speaker 2:  more screens and more notifications like
Speaker 2:  buzzing me, won't that be more distracting? But
Speaker 2:  I'm kind of a believer so that's the one I'll throw in there. D Dom, do you
Speaker 2:  have a, an idea here for Sam?
Speaker 11:  I have a different suggestion but it's kind of along the same spirit, which
Speaker 11:  would be looking at a, a foldable flip phone, which also is adding
Speaker 11:  an extra screen into the mix and adding a smaller screen into the mix. But
Speaker 11:  it sounds like the balance, I think Sam is try Jelly Strike here
Speaker 11:  is a small phone she won't use too much that will sort of stop her
Speaker 11:  from constant phone use. But one that when they do
Speaker 11:  use the phone won't hurt her eyes. And I
Speaker 11:  guess a flip phone for me like there, you know, so Samsung's Z Flip or Motor
Speaker 11:  Razor gives you a little of that because you can have it
Speaker 11:  shut and you can kind of control what notifications and what apps you
Speaker 11:  can have run on the outer screen and it can be this sort of minimalist phone
Speaker 11:  experience when it's closed and you just, I definitely found
Speaker 11:  my general screen time always goes down when I'm using a flip phone.
Speaker 11:  There's something about the psychological barrier
Speaker 11:  that the phone is closed that makes me much less likely to
Speaker 11:  open it while I'm watching TV and mindlessly scroll social media or
Speaker 11:  something. It doesn't matter that it only takes a second to open the phone.
Speaker 11:  It's not like it's a hardship, but there's some like imperceptible barrier
Speaker 11:  that makes me more likely just leave it be. And my screen time
Speaker 11:  overall definitely goes down. But when you do have that
Speaker 11:  moment where you give in, you have the device and you wanna scroll the news
Speaker 11:  for hours like, like Sam does, you have a normal sized phone that you can
Speaker 11:  open up and it's not gonna give eye strain from using it.
Speaker 11:  You know, there's enough screen space to bump the tech size off if that
Speaker 11:  would be helpful in this kind of case. Whereas the Jelly Star I think is
Speaker 11:  just too small to even make that really practical. So for me I
Speaker 11:  think those kind of, those kind of flip phones give you a bit of the best
Speaker 11:  of both worlds lowered screen time, but a real functional
Speaker 11:  useful phone screen when you wanna get to it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, totally. And I, that's what I love about a flip
Speaker 2:  phone is you can do so much and Motorola is
Speaker 2:  like slightly better about letting you just do whatever the hell you want
Speaker 2:  on the cover screen. You have to jump through a, a couple of hoops on a Samsung
Speaker 2:  phone but, and you can get there. But yeah, I run like
Speaker 2:  apps that are by no means meant to be run on a screen that
Speaker 2:  small and you can get away with stuff like checking like bus
Speaker 2:  arrival times or glancing at, you know, Google Maps and being
Speaker 2:  like, okay, that's, that's my next move. So that would be a, a super
Speaker 2:  fun option. I hate to be like, I don't know a mom,
Speaker 2:  but I think we probably all need to get better about
Speaker 2:  focus modes. Like yeah, you know, they're not
Speaker 2:  perfect but I think there's a lot I know I could
Speaker 2:  be doing to kind of like tailor what
Speaker 2:  notifications are allowed to bother me at what time and that would help
Speaker 2:  me kind of cut down on the, oh I was checking
Speaker 2:  my email and all of a sudden I've been on Instagram for an hour or whatever.
Speaker 2:  So that's like the less fun answer. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  buy a flip phone
Speaker 11:  That is part of it. Yeah. Yeah, I mean I think you And I both given kind
Speaker 11:  of the same answer in a way. It it's have a real phone
Speaker 11:  maybe but have some other smaller screen that you
Speaker 11:  can control and limit and make that the screen you use 80% of the time
Speaker 11:  while knowing, you know, there is a phone there when you really, really
Speaker 11:  need it and whether that smaller screen is on your wrist or on the outside
Speaker 11:  of the phone, it's kind of getting, getting to the same end result, right?
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Little screen on a big phone is the way
Speaker 2:  to go I think. All right, good luck with your flip phone Sam.
Speaker 2:  Next we have a message from Alina
Speaker 2:  and she says, currently I'm rocking a Pixel six a
Speaker 2:  running Graphene os, but it was already used when
Speaker 2:  I bought it. The screen glass is broken, it has 128 gigabytes of storage
Speaker 2:  and the touch gestures don't always work probably due to the broken glass.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I think it's time for a new phone a you know, is she's concerned
Speaker 2:  about a splash of water destroying the ole and is looking for
Speaker 2:  a relatively cheap phone that meets her
Speaker 2:  needs. She says she wants to keep it to $500 or
Speaker 2:  under, you know, it has some questions about the
Speaker 2:  Apple ecosystem. The iPhone Mini comes up again as, as
Speaker 2:  a a thought here she says I have all my music as
Speaker 2:  MP threes and use a music player that plays locally stored
Speaker 2:  music, which is 40 gigabytes of stuff, but like
Speaker 2:  way to Go is intrigued by folding phones and
Speaker 2:  a flip phone potentially. I think the boring
Speaker 2:  answer is a Pixel nine A And I do
Speaker 2:  think there's a fun answer here, but I mean the Pixel nine A fits
Speaker 2:  the price bracket. We'll get seven years of OS
Speaker 2:  updates so you don't have to worry about that. It does mean you are
Speaker 2:  embracing the Google apps and the Google experience. So
Speaker 2:  if you would like to get away from that, a pixel phone is not gonna be
Speaker 2:  the way to go. But I think really for it's,
Speaker 2:  it's just my go-to for, I want the
Speaker 2:  most durable, the most long lasting phone
Speaker 2:  I can get for the least amount of money. It's kind of that like
Speaker 2:  peace of mind phone to me. Like I make my parents buy
Speaker 2:  a a pixel a series when it's their time. Dom, do
Speaker 2:  you have any other ideas or something more fun than
Speaker 2:  my boring pixel suggestion?
Speaker 11:  I default to the exact same boring answer. Yeah, I think this is also
Speaker 11:  it a fits a lot of what Alina says she wants not everything but a lot
Speaker 11:  b for me, the moment anyone says around 500 bucks,
Speaker 11:  my brain just fills in pixel nine A. Yeah, it's a very
Speaker 11:  good default option to be looking at around that price. I might throw in
Speaker 11:  a a second shout out to The Fairphone, which I think is very
Speaker 11:  slightly outside of this budget. I I think it's 550 Euros
Speaker 11:  and Alina says she's in Germany so I hope that's a relevant number for her.
Speaker 11:  But she mentions not wanting kind of too much of the Google side. You, you
Speaker 11:  can get the version running EOS you can get that in Europe as well. So that's
Speaker 11:  completely degod as an option. She mentions a long,
Speaker 11:  long-term support and durability. I think it's eight years of
Speaker 11:  os updates Fair fund gives you, it's something definitely in that region.
Speaker 11:  So you're getting it for a long time. It's around the right price. She says
Speaker 11:  she doesn't doesn't seem to have sort of two super demanding kind of performance
Speaker 11:  requirements from it. So a Fairphone might be a nice option just for, for
Speaker 11:  meeting kind of that side of, of the demand and, and it really is gonna
Speaker 11:  give you that, that longevity and, and if you do break the screen again,
Speaker 11:  you can just replace it yourself.
Speaker 2:  Hey, it can be done. We know.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I've, I've, I've put that to the test.
Speaker 2:  All right, well I I love that she's in Germany and therefore has more than
Speaker 2:  like two options for phones. But yeah, there's your
Speaker 2:  safe answer and then the slightly more daring one,
Speaker 2:  but I think two good options there. So
Speaker 2:  the last question I wanna get to is the iPhone
Speaker 2:  mini question. And I wanna say this is a
Speaker 2:  representative question. I got so many iPhone
Speaker 2:  mini owners reaching out to me people at the iPhone mini 12 or 13.
Speaker 2:  I sort of brought this upon us because I prompted it
Speaker 2:  And I own an iPhone 13 mini, but I think a lot
Speaker 2:  of people are at that point with these phones where they're seeing
Speaker 2:  like the performance is slowing down, the battery
Speaker 2:  life wasn't ever great to begin with and is getting
Speaker 2:  steadily worse. So thi this is for everyone
Speaker 2:  who wrote in with the iPhone mini question and okay, get ready
Speaker 2:  for this question 'cause it goes on a journey. This is from
Speaker 2:  Zoe. She says, I am the iPhone 12 mini
Speaker 2:  owner. I absolutely love this phone and would take it to my grave if I could.
Speaker 2:  Same. It's the only phone since iPhone five five
Speaker 2:  s an original se. Oh my god, iPhone five is such a banger
Speaker 2:  that I can comfortably use one handed and the only one that fits
Speaker 2:  in the infuriatingly Tiny Pockets found in most women's clothing. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Oh my god, I so feel this. She says last year it
Speaker 2:  flew out of my pocket on a rollercoaster and was smashed to
Speaker 2:  oblivion. This is heartbreaking.
Speaker 2:  Unfortunately my replacement 12 mini is now showing its age.
Speaker 2:  So she's looking for the upgrade path
Speaker 2:  and it's considered a used iPhone 13 mini, but
Speaker 2:  thinks that'll probably put her back in the same position. The idea of something
Speaker 2:  that folds down to a pocket friendly size is very appealing.
Speaker 2:  But she says she's embedded in the Apple ecosystem, so
Speaker 2:  we'll ideally stick with iPhone unless there's
Speaker 2:  a super compelling Android alternative she ends this with
Speaker 2:  finally, if there's no obvious alternative, are my tiny hands doomed to
Speaker 2:  rely on pops sockets forever? Oh my gosh Zoe,
Speaker 2:  I, this is extremely relatable. This is
Speaker 2:  so tough. I just wanna say it's probably time to
Speaker 2:  embrace like the get the smallest iPhone that exists
Speaker 2:  now, which would be like just a regular iPhone
Speaker 2:  16. But I don't know, do you have any other ideas for
Speaker 2:  Zoe and all the other suffering iPhone mini owners?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I feel like we're sort of ending here with another of these sad questions
Speaker 11:  where we just can't give, give people the answer they want to hear. There
Speaker 11:  is no, yeah, there is no phone that solves this problem. There is no magical
Speaker 11:  Android alternative that fits the bill by the
Speaker 11:  iPhone 16 is, it's like you say, it's the smallest iPhone
Speaker 11:  you're gonna get. It's the closest you're gonna get to that experience.
Speaker 11:  The Android alternatives, like the S 25 or or the Pixel 10 are
Speaker 11:  basically the same size as an iPhone 16. So if you prefer iOS,
Speaker 11:  you should stick with that. You're not getting a big benefit by jumping
Speaker 11:  to Android. I think the only reason for someone in Zoe's position to jump
Speaker 11:  to Android is a flip phone if, if that's a temptation. I think,
Speaker 11:  you know, we've, we've kinda mentioned 'em a few times. I think they are
Speaker 11:  getting really good now. I, I'm a big fan of them. I think they don't have
Speaker 11:  to be that expensive. The, you look like the Motorola razor, the,
Speaker 11:  the base razor models, they're very affordable for what they are well below
Speaker 11:  a grand and still really solid phones. You do get
Speaker 11:  that compact size. They are big when they open up though I think
Speaker 11:  people don't always realize that, that they're small when they're shut,
Speaker 11:  they're small in your pocket, they're lightweight but they actually have
Speaker 11:  bigger screens than say an iPhone 16 to pick that as the point of
Speaker 11:  reference. So when it's fully open, it's not gonna feel like a small compact
Speaker 11:  phone. It might actually feel like a really big phone to you when you open
Speaker 11:  the flip phone up. And the last thing I'd just say is don't wait for the
Speaker 11:  foldable iPhone. We, we dunno what that will be. No, we dunno if it'll be
Speaker 11:  a flip or a book style. It's not gonna be this year. It might be
Speaker 11:  next year. It might not be next year. It's not worth waiting on for.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I would say hold out, I think if you can to the,
Speaker 2:  you know, we're so close to iPhone 17
Speaker 2:  season and there aren rumors of like
Speaker 2:  a slimmer iPhone. We're we're doing slim foams
Speaker 2:  this year.
Speaker 11:  The air, the air might help if that materializes the iPhone 17 air. I mean
Speaker 11:  it will be lighter if the weight is a big part of the concern.
Speaker 11:  Right. It doesn't sound like it's gonna be smaller in terms of screen size.
Speaker 11:  Like, like we've seen with the Samsung, you know that, that they're the
Speaker 11:  version of a thin phone. The edge is, yeah, it's not small, it's just
Speaker 11:  thinner and lighter. Yes. And I think that's the way Apple's going as well.
Speaker 11:  So if weight is your problem, I know some people love small phones and it's,
Speaker 11:  and it's a weight thing. I've spoken to people with wrist issues and a and
Speaker 11:  arthritis and for them it's not about screen size, it's about phone weight
Speaker 11:  and if that's you then, then hold out the iPhone 17 air or
Speaker 11:  whatever it is, might, might solve that problem. I don't know. But if it's,
Speaker 11:  if it's that little screen you like and the sort of easy one-handed use,
Speaker 11:  then wait for the iPhone 17 just 'cause it'll make the 16 cheaper.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. At this point this is sort of like a
Speaker 2:  moratorium on buying new iPhones sort of starts right now where it's like,
Speaker 2:  hey you, you might as well just wait and see, you know, they'll take a hundred
Speaker 2:  dollars off the price of iPhone 16. The, I
Speaker 2:  used the Galaxy Edge a bunch, which is, you know, In
Speaker 2:  theory could be like what a potential iPhone 17 air
Speaker 2:  would be. It being thinner and lighter is like,
Speaker 2:  makes it feel different. It was very nice. It did not
Speaker 2:  feel like a small phone. 'cause it has a big screen
Speaker 2:  in the pocket thing, especially like it's still a big phone.
Speaker 2:  It's still like at the capacity for my like little
Speaker 2:  pouch bags that I'm bringing to the playground. It
Speaker 2:  will fit into a, an evening clutch,
Speaker 2:  which I do not carry very often, But that was a data
Speaker 2:  point. But yeah, I think it is pops sockets forever. Zoe,
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry, our colleague Sean Hollister,
Speaker 2:  I think went through the exact same like path that
Speaker 2:  she's kind of mentioning. He had the iPhone mini
Speaker 2:  ditched it for the, I think he got a Samsung flip phone and had
Speaker 2:  that for about a year and was not happy with it. I, I think,
Speaker 2:  you know, the battery life was probably equivalent to the
Speaker 2:  mini Yeah. You know, all things considered and it, and it
Speaker 2:  doesn't like it folds down into a square, but it's a thick square
Speaker 2:  so it, it doesn't fit in a pocket the same way. Like I can get the
Speaker 2:  iPhone 13 mini into my front jeans pocket and it's not
Speaker 2:  ridiculous. Flip phones are, they're still a little bulkier and
Speaker 2:  like you mentioned, when you open it, it is a big phone and you are still
Speaker 2:  doing the big phone, you know, kind of juggle of
Speaker 2:  try Jelly, reach something in the corner of the screen. So yeah, I, I
Speaker 2:  think my general advice for the iPhone mini owners is like,
Speaker 2:  first of all, don't download beta software like I did because that
Speaker 2:  has been a journey. But you know, the things
Speaker 2:  you can try are like get the battery replaced. I don't
Speaker 2:  know if there's an, if this is a, a real thing, but a suggestion
Speaker 2:  I saw just for like older phones in general would be to back it up
Speaker 2:  and, and do a factory reset and that might
Speaker 2:  help performance a little bit. It's like
Speaker 2:  I haven't tried it myself it seems, you know, unplug it, plug it back in
Speaker 2:  kind of concept. Let's call
Speaker 11:  That energy to it. Yeah, I, yeah, I remember that working a lot on Windows
Speaker 11:  PCs back in the day. Yeah. I dunno how applicable it's to a phone these
Speaker 11:  days, but it might help. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Right. It's something to try. I it is like a, like a,
Speaker 2:  a ritual, you know, you can light some candles too.
Speaker 11:  It feels like you're cleansing the phone somehow getting rid of all that
Speaker 11:  junk you've built up. So give it a go.
Speaker 2:  It is like a juice cleanse for your phone. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  A detox. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I thought, I think about this a lot and it's sort
Speaker 2:  of just turns into a dance of like, when do you feel
Speaker 2:  like it's time to let go? When are you Yes. So
Speaker 2:  annoyed with the battery life, it's just not serving you anymore.
Speaker 2:  I don't use my mini that much because I'm bouncing around
Speaker 2:  from phone to phone. But I did have my sim in
Speaker 2:  it this past few weeks and it
Speaker 2:  is really slowing down and the battery life is, is
Speaker 2:  kind of crap. So yeah, it's
Speaker 2:  might be time. I don't know, I'm gonna hold on to mine, but I think
Speaker 2:  I give if, if you're looking for permission, like blanket
Speaker 2:  permission to let go of your iPhone mini I I will
Speaker 2:  offer that.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. But there's nothing to hold out for. There's nothing on the horizon
Speaker 11:  that will solve this problem. Don't, don't keep going. Thinking a
Speaker 11:  year from now the magical firm will arrive that fixes this. Like it's not
Speaker 11:  coming. So just make your peace with it and you know, enjoy the time you've
Speaker 11:  got left and yeah. Figure out what the next step is.
Speaker 2:  This is so sad. It's like,
Speaker 11:  Oh my gosh, grieve feel many, it's, it's okay.
Speaker 2:  You know? Yes, yes. Maybe we'll have a funeral. Maybe we can have
Speaker 2:  like sold some kind of service where people
Speaker 2:  can like bring their minis and we'll just, we'll just let them
Speaker 2:  rest. They've done a lot. They've, they've done probably more than
Speaker 2:  their little, little batteries and processors should have, so
Speaker 2:  we'll let them go. Well that's like a super downward
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And dawn, but that's what we have. Thank
Speaker 2:  you everyone who wrote in and called in. I listened
Speaker 2:  to all of your messages and read all of your messages and it was,
Speaker 2:  it was so fun. It is so nice to you know, no, you're not
Speaker 2:  alone and we're all going through this. Try Jelly to figure
Speaker 2:  out our next move and hopefully we, we help some
Speaker 2:  people and, and didn't depress too many
Speaker 2:  iPhone mini owners.
Speaker 1:  That's all we can ask
Speaker 2:  For. Yeah. But thank you for joining me Tom. No,
Speaker 21:  Of course. Thank you for having me.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. To read more about today's topics,
Speaker 2:  check out the show notes or go to The Verge dot com. As always,
Speaker 2:  if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, you can always email us at
Speaker 2:  vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline.
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE 11. We love hearing from you. Send us
Speaker 2:  all your thoughts and burning questions and ideas for what we should do on
Speaker 2:  the show. We do a hotline question every week, so keep them coming.
Speaker 2:  And if you like what we do here, consider buying a paid subscription.
Speaker 2:  The show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, Travis Eck and
Speaker 2:  Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the
Speaker 2:  Vox Media podcast network. Jake cast and the team will
Speaker 2:  be here Friday to talk about the news from the week. And I'll be back next
Speaker 2:  Tuesday. Thanks for listening