# Transcript
ID: d5259e23-04e2-4cd0-b48d-af57133087cd
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7620823104348372640/4497249682859341364/s93290-US-3997s-1745323561.mp3
Description: If you’re heading on vacation this summer, you’re going to want to listen to this. The Verge’s Gaby del Valle joins the show to explain how worried you need to be about your digital data when you cross borders, and what you can do to protect yourself. Even if you don’t think you have anything to hide, a little precaution goes a long way. After that, Puck’s Matt Belloni joins the show to explain why Apple, Amazon, Google, and other tech companies continue to pour money into the streaming business, when it seems so far removed from what those companies do well. (Spoiler alert: it’s fun to be friends with Ben Stiller.) Finally, we answer a hotline question about the Google Pixel’s ascent to “best Android phone for people who just want a phone.”
Oh, also: thanks to everyone who voted for us in the Webby Awards! We’ll know soon whether we won, but however it shakes out, we’re so grateful to everyone who voted for us.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of having really famous
Speaker 2:  friends. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and I am in my backyard
Speaker 2:  on my patio, putting together this little tykes house
Speaker 2:  that we got from my toddler. It was a gift from my parents. My
Speaker 2:  2-year-old I think is very much gonna like it, but also, if I'm being honest,
Speaker 2:  it was very fun and cathartic to put this thing together in the way that
Speaker 2:  it's fun to like do Ikea furniture. It's a little bit of work. It's just
Speaker 2:  enough to make you feel like you've really accomplished something. And I'm
Speaker 2:  like, yeah, I built a house today. Is it made of plastic? And will it blow
Speaker 2:  away next time there's wind? Yes, but that's not important. I built a house
Speaker 2:  today Anyway, this house is not what we are here to talk about today.
Speaker 2:  Today on the show, we're gonna do two things. First, I'm gonna talk to Gabby
Speaker 2:  del Va about a thing we've actually heard from you a lot about recently,
Speaker 2:  which is how to travel with your phone, especially across
Speaker 2:  borders right now. It's very complicated in the United States politically.
Speaker 2:  And so Gabby and I are gonna try to give you some tips on what to do to
Speaker 2:  secure your data before you travel. Then I'm gonna talk to Matt Bella From
Speaker 2:  Puck about what he's seeing in the big tech
Speaker 2:  streaming wars and why companies like Apple and Amazon and Google
Speaker 2:  want in on this in the first place. We also have a really fun hotline question
Speaker 2:  about Google. Lots to get to today, but first I have to figure out
Speaker 2:  how to get out of this house. I barely crammed myself in here and it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be very ugly getting out. So this is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, the house is finished. I get to get rid of this
Speaker 2:  giant box behind me. I made it out alive. Life is good. Let's get
Speaker 2:  into it. We've heard from a bunch of you over the last few months with
Speaker 2:  kind of a similar question, which is basically some version of, I'm about
Speaker 2:  to travel and I don't know what to do with my devices.
Speaker 2:  I think for a lot of political reasons, especially here in the United States,
Speaker 2:  there are new questions about how you should be securing your phone
Speaker 2:  and what data you should be traveling with across borders. It just feels
Speaker 2:  different now and I actually think this is the kind of thing that has been
Speaker 2:  interesting and important for a long time, but is really just coming to the
Speaker 2:  forefront now in a new way. So I grabbed Gabby DelVal who wrote a really
Speaker 2:  great story for us about this and we dug into it. Let's do it.
Speaker 2:  Gabby DelVal is here. Hi Gabby.
Speaker 6:  Hi. How's it going?
Speaker 2:  You're, you're here Out of the trenches of the insanity of our
Speaker 2:  world right now. I feel like every time you turn in a story, it's just like
Speaker 2:  the world is weirder than you even think or realize by Gabby. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's kind of my beat. It sucks. I,
Speaker 6:  I mean, I like it. I like doing it, but I'm like, what if things weren't
Speaker 6:  that way? That would be awesome.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, indeed. So I've, I've asked you to do this because you
Speaker 2:  wrote a story about basically traveling to the United States with
Speaker 2:  your phone in 2025 and we also got a hotline question
Speaker 2:  very specifically asking about the same thing. Your story did super well.
Speaker 2:  This is clearly a thing people are curious about and I just wanted to dig
Speaker 2:  into some of it. But let me, let me just play you the question that we got
Speaker 2:  on The Vergecast hotline as a way to just kind of set up the conversation
Speaker 2:  we're about to have. Does that sound good? Yeah. Alright. Lemme just play
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 7:  Hey David, I'm European and I'm about to travel to the us. I read about customs
Speaker 7:  and Border Patrol searching phones. What might happen if I refuse and if
Speaker 7:  I have to let them search my phone, how do I prepare? Do they delete chat
Speaker 7:  apps and password managers? Do I log out of my Google account and
Speaker 7:  delete my Google drive? Do I change my phone password? And what about my
Speaker 7:  laptop?
Speaker 2:  Okay, so there are a bunch of good practical questions in here, but be before
Speaker 2:  we get to all the good practical questions, I just wanna sort of lay the
Speaker 2:  land a little bit on this. And one thing I've been wondering a lot is how
Speaker 2:  widespread is this kind of border search right
Speaker 2:  now? The idea that like somebody will detain you and search through your
Speaker 2:  phone and look for anti-Trump text messages is like a thing we're hearing
Speaker 2:  about how big and widespread is this right now? Really,
Speaker 6:  I would say it's not super widespread, at least according to the most recent
Speaker 6:  data we have, which is from the 2024 fiscal year. So it's not current,
Speaker 6:  but that year less than 0.01%
Speaker 6:  of arriving international travelers had their devices searched by customs
Speaker 6:  and border protection. But at the same time, we are seeing, you know, a lot
Speaker 6:  of anecdotal reports of people having their phone searched, are people having
Speaker 6:  their laptop searched of being turned away because of what comes up in a
Speaker 6:  search. So I would say even though it's not
Speaker 6:  necessarily something that happens really frequently, like people's
Speaker 6:  anxieties are not entirely misplaced either because you don't know if it's
Speaker 6:  gonna happen to you ultimately.
Speaker 2:  Right. And it, it does seem like it'll probably be a minute before we get
Speaker 2:  real quantitative data about this stuff, but it certainly
Speaker 2:  seems like anecdotally the, the stories we're hearing about this seem
Speaker 2:  to have increased pretty dramatically.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I would say anecdotally they've increased. And I mean, you know, part
Speaker 6:  of that could be like whenever Trump is in office, like people care more
Speaker 6:  about what customs and border protection is doing, what ICE is doing. It's
Speaker 6:  just kind of a, like an attention effect. But at the same time, like the
Speaker 6:  reasons why people are being turned away are in some cases
Speaker 6:  unusual. Like a French scientist who sent like text messages saying that
Speaker 6:  Trump's research cuts were bad.
Speaker 6:  Like that's not a, a usual reason to turn someone away or
Speaker 6:  deny them entry.
Speaker 2:  So how did it come to pass that these are legal searches that
Speaker 2:  customs and border protection is actually doing? What is the legality of
Speaker 2:  these searches right now?
Speaker 6:  So in 2014 the Supreme Court ruled that law enforcement cannot
Speaker 6:  conduct warrantless searches of people's cell phones without their consent.
Speaker 6:  But there is what is called the border zone or border search
Speaker 6:  exemption, which is exactly what allows CBP to search your phone
Speaker 6:  at an airport or other port of entry. So in this instance, border doesn't
Speaker 6:  mean like the physical, like land borders of the us Like you're, if you're
Speaker 6:  flying into Chicago on an international flight, like that's a border
Speaker 6:  zone. If you're flying into like, I don't know Omaha, I'm just picking places
Speaker 6:  in the middle of the country, like you don't have to be physically at the
Speaker 6:  border for you to be in like a border zone.
Speaker 6:  So the border zone exemption basically means that there are just like
Speaker 6:  areas where the fourth Amendment, not that it doesn't exist, but
Speaker 6:  it's a little bit more flexible, a little bit less robust
Speaker 6:  because you're being inspected for entry into the country. So even though
Speaker 6:  you are physically present in the United States, you have not yet been legally
Speaker 6:  admitted. So it's, it's just like a kind of different,
Speaker 6:  different situation.
Speaker 2:  So, and and is the idea that just by virtue of the fact that
Speaker 2:  you are coming from not in the United States to in the United States, that
Speaker 2:  somehow there is, I don't know, like probable
Speaker 2:  cause or a reason to check or like I, I guess what is the reason behind that
Speaker 2:  exemption?
Speaker 6:  So I spoke to a lawyer at the Electronic Frontier Foundation who explained
Speaker 6:  it to me, basically is like, you know, there's always kind of been a border
Speaker 6:  exemption and it's, before there were phones it was, they would check your
Speaker 6:  luggage, they would check the things on your person, things that similarly
Speaker 6:  like what you would need, like reasonable, reasonable
Speaker 6:  suspicion or whatever for search and seizure. But because you are entering,
Speaker 6:  these things are considered like related to your travel, related to your
Speaker 6:  reason for being in the country. But your luggage, you know, they might be
Speaker 6:  looking for you smuggling something, trafficking something,
Speaker 6:  drugs, people contraband eggs.
Speaker 6:  Recently CBP has had an increase in people
Speaker 6:  smuggling eggs from Mexico, which is really funny. Oh boy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But your phone is not really
Speaker 6:  like just a thing that you're carrying with you or your laptop.
Speaker 6:  It like contains your entire life on it. Which is why like
Speaker 6:  domestically, the Supreme Court has held that, you know,
Speaker 6:  law enforcement can't just go through your phone without a warrant, but
Speaker 6:  it's because of this border search exemption. They can do it at ports of
Speaker 6:  entry.
Speaker 2:  Right. It's exactly the thing you just said about your phone is both the
Speaker 2:  reason it should be more protected and the reason customs
Speaker 2:  border protection would really, really, really like to look at like Exactly
Speaker 2:  those two things are exactly in like diametric opposition at all times.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So what do we know about how these searches actually work?
Speaker 2:  Like I'm, I'm imagining just like a, a dude
Speaker 2:  standing in the corner, just like flipping through the apps on your phone.
Speaker 2:  What, what actually happens in one of these searches?
Speaker 6:  So it depends. I would say, you know when you get to the airport and you
Speaker 6:  go through customs and they're like, where were you? What's the reason for
Speaker 6:  your travel? That's just like your standard run of the mill inspection.
Speaker 6:  You can get pulled into what's known as a secondary inspection, which is
Speaker 6:  when they take you into a back room and this is like they ask you more questions,
Speaker 6:  you're sitting in the room and so they can also look at your phone
Speaker 6:  If you say yes, there's two types of searches they can do. There's what's
Speaker 6:  known as a basic search. They have to put your phone on airplane mode and
Speaker 6:  they can look at whatever is on your phone on airplane mode. They can use
Speaker 6:  the search function on your phone. They can go through your pictures, they
Speaker 6:  can go through your texts, like any apps that you have open that like maybe
Speaker 6:  are still cache, like they can look through all of that with your phone on
Speaker 6:  airplane mode. Then there's what's known as advanced or forensic
Speaker 6:  search, which is when they hook your phone up to an external device and they
Speaker 6:  like grab everything that's on it and they keep it. Okay.
Speaker 6:  They keep it for as long as they want. And in
Speaker 6:  some jurisdictions, like they can only do warrantless
Speaker 6:  forensic searches that are pursuant to like border
Speaker 6:  crimes and some jurisdictions they can only do searches that are pursuant
Speaker 6:  to other types of crimes. It depends, but mostly they can
Speaker 6:  just look at your phone and take what's on it and they just store that information
Speaker 6:  forever. Or maybe not forever, but for a very long time. I need to check
Speaker 6:  the, the laws on that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But even in the basic search to your point, like I, I think it's, it
Speaker 2:  strikes me as I, I think one of the questions a lot of people are
Speaker 2:  going to have, like our, our caller here is like, okay, what, what information
Speaker 2:  are they looking for? And I think to the question of like, okay, you're gonna
Speaker 2:  dump everything on my device and take it. I think that's one
Speaker 2:  question, but like, okay, I'm sitting in the room and there's somebody flipping
Speaker 2:  through my phone. Are they just like doing a spotlight search for the word
Speaker 2:  Trump and seeing what happened? Like is that, is that a reasonable guess
Speaker 2:  as to what's going on here?
Speaker 6:  I dunno if I could speak to that just 'cause I, I don't know. Okay. Like
Speaker 6:  it'd be looking for anything like, it's kind of like the inverse
Speaker 6:  of well If you have nothing to hide, like what are you afraid of? It's like
Speaker 6:  you on there used against
Speaker 6:  texting his friend. Like it's so crazy that Trump
Speaker 6:  funding funding being a reason to deny them entry from the country is like
Speaker 6:  wild. Right. There is, there was a story of a
Speaker 6:  brown university doctor who had her visa rescinded and
Speaker 6:  got turned away. The CBP agents who were interrogating her say that she
Speaker 6:  had admitted to going to Lebanon where she is from to attend
Speaker 6:  the former leader of Hezbollah's funeral. Which
Speaker 6:  like in most instances that would, that would get you turned away.
Speaker 6:  But they apparently searched her phone and found
Speaker 6:  photos they called sympathetic photos and images of
Speaker 6:  the former leader of Hezbollah in her phone's recently deleted folder. So
Speaker 6:  not even like in her camera roll, but in the recently deleted folder.
Speaker 6:  And when they asked her like, why do you have these pictures on your phone
Speaker 6:  and why did you delete them? She was like, oh, my family sends them on WhatsApp
Speaker 6:  and I deleted them. 'cause like I, I don't know, like they're not me,
Speaker 6:  but like yeah I support some of his like religious tea. Like whatever she,
Speaker 6:  she said a lot of stuff. But the point being like If you read
Speaker 6:  between the lines there like WhatsApp defaults to downloading
Speaker 6:  whatever images people send you. Yeah. So yeah, like yeah, like my family
Speaker 6:  sends like a zillion like good morning everyone things and I have to delete
Speaker 6:  those on WhatsApp like every single day. Yep. All it was just
Speaker 6:  to say you don't know what they're gonna find in your phone and even like
Speaker 6:  trying to delete stuff might not necessarily help you
Speaker 6:  If you don't fully delete it and then they find it in your recently deleted
Speaker 6:  folder. Right.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Yeah, I was just thinking like we're, we're in the middle of,
Speaker 2:  you know, litigating like the, the signal group chat for attack planning
Speaker 2:  and all this stuff and it's like there's actually a lot of ways that things
Speaker 2:  can happen on your phone without you even necessarily
Speaker 2:  being actively engaged in it. Like I was actually thinking about the WhatsApp
Speaker 2:  one where like mine is all, all my friends are like degenerate sports gamblers.
Speaker 2:  So there's now my camera role looks like I'm a degenerate sports gambler
Speaker 2:  even though it's just all of my degenerate friends sending the bets that
Speaker 2:  they're losing that just dump into my camera roll now. And so I'm like, If
Speaker 2:  you just opened up my phone, you would actually make a bunch of assumptions
Speaker 2:  about me that are wrong. Totally. And that is just one specific tiny
Speaker 2:  way that that stuff can actually start to happen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Your friends are the ones whose parlays are hitting. It's not you,
Speaker 6:  It is your friends.
Speaker 2:  All my parlays hit Gabby. Yeah. Let's
Speaker 6:  Be clear. That's right, that's right. But yeah, like, I
Speaker 6:  dunno, like I have texts on my phone from like 12 years ago, I don't know
Speaker 6:  what I was saying 12 years ago. Totally. Like I just, I don't think about
Speaker 6:  it and you know, maybe, maybe we should be thinking about it,
Speaker 6:  which is, which is concerning. And it applies both to
Speaker 6:  like people traveling to the US from outside the country on visas. And to
Speaker 6:  us citizens, the difference is just like what your rights are, what your
Speaker 6:  abil, whether you have the ability to say no and what happens If you say
Speaker 6:  no.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, let's talk about that actually. 'cause I I was gonna ask you about
Speaker 2:  this 'cause you said If you say yes, these are the two kinds of searches
Speaker 2:  that they can do, can you say no? Who can say no?
Speaker 2:  What happens If you say no?
Speaker 6:  Technically anyone can say no, but different things will happen if you're
Speaker 6:  a US citizen and then you and you say no, they can't deny you entry into
Speaker 6:  the country because you are a US citizen. They might hold you in there for
Speaker 6:  a while. They might try to be like, why are you saying no?
Speaker 6:  But they can't not let you in. They can take your phone
Speaker 6:  and they can use forensics tools to get into
Speaker 6:  your phone if they really want to. This has happened before. There's case
Speaker 6:  law about it.
Speaker 6:  If you're a permanent resident so you have a green card, it's tricky. Like
Speaker 6:  you can say no and in some cases you can't be denied entry into the country.
Speaker 6:  But like If you've been outta the country for more than six months, then
Speaker 6:  you are basically like once again being inspected for entry.
Speaker 6:  And so saying no could like affect your inspection for entry If you have
Speaker 6:  like certain charges on your record. Like that could lead to you also
Speaker 6:  kind of being inspected again. So it's just a little bit
Speaker 6:  trickier than It is for you as citizens. If you have a visa and you say
Speaker 6:  no, they can just fully not let you in. They can send you back to
Speaker 6:  wherever you came from and they can deny you entry.
Speaker 6:  So the safer thing to do than saying no
Speaker 6:  is to, you know, travel with your devices really locked
Speaker 6:  down and really clean.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. So this, this is a good segue to like, let's get, let's get super
Speaker 2:  practical about this here. The, the sort of nuclear option here
Speaker 2:  is just like factory reset your phone before you get on the plane. Is that,
Speaker 2:  is that just the idea here? Is that what you should do?
Speaker 6:  I mean, it's not a bad idea. I would say it's not, it's not a bad idea back,
Speaker 6:  like upload whatever back at all up factory reset.
Speaker 6:  If you don't want a factory reset, there are like other things that you could
Speaker 6:  do. And I would say this advice applies most to us
Speaker 6:  citizens and permanent residents. If you have a visa, I'm, I'm not
Speaker 6:  really sure like whether, you know, just like targeted
Speaker 6:  deleting of stuff is gonna is gonna help you much. But
Speaker 6:  If you don't want a factory reset your phone,
Speaker 6:  you should, I mean actually everyone, everyone should turn off biometric,
Speaker 6:  fingerprint face. Id turn it off. Turn it off. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Wait, can you explain that to me actually? 'cause that was one thing in your
Speaker 2:  reporting that that I, I found sort of confusing and surprising that
Speaker 2:  there is a difference between what they can do with your face
Speaker 2:  ID or touch ID and what they can do with your like six digit passcode to
Speaker 2:  get into your phone. What is going on there?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so this is like a very interesting legal thing. It's the difference
Speaker 6:  between what's known as testimonial and non testimonial
Speaker 6:  testimonial and non testimonial evidence. I believe, and
Speaker 6:  this has mostly been litigated in like
Speaker 6:  local police departments unlocking people's phones with their fingerprint
Speaker 6:  or their face. But like some courts have ruled that a cop
Speaker 6:  cannot compel you to give them your phone password, like
Speaker 6:  one, two, three, four, they cannot ask you or whatever It is, but they
Speaker 6:  can use your finger or your face because
Speaker 6:  basically testimonial evidence is evidence that compels you to, to
Speaker 6:  disclose the, the contents of your mind or your thoughts. So you are by
Speaker 6:  telling them your password, you are disclosing something that you think you
Speaker 6:  are being compelled to tell 'em what you think. Interesting. But that doesn't
Speaker 6:  happen when they're just like putting your finger on the thing. This is also
Speaker 6:  like when people go to protest, they're advised to, you know, turn off like
Speaker 6:  biometrics because they can take your phone and just like kind of,
Speaker 2:  So just yeah, like the, the only analogy I can draw there is like, that's,
Speaker 2:  that's the law you make so that they can fingerprint you at the police
Speaker 2:  station and but you still don't have to talk. Like is that,
Speaker 2:  is there some similar there?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I don't know if like that's like the legal like reason
Speaker 6:  that is like a, like an analogy that like makes sense to me. Okay. There
Speaker 6:  is, so one federal appeals court ruled that
Speaker 6:  non testimonial evidence, so like a biometric login for your phone
Speaker 6:  requires no cognitive exertion placing it firmly in the same
Speaker 6:  category as a blood draw or fingerprint taken at booking. Yeah. So you're
Speaker 6:  totally right. Oh, there you go. Okay. Yeah. So because it doesn't require
Speaker 6:  you to think or express your thoughts against your will, then
Speaker 6:  they're allowed to do it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I'm not sure I buy that distinction, but It is, It is an interesting
Speaker 2:  distinction nonetheless. Okay. So the the practical advice there is turn
Speaker 2:  off everything but the passcode. Yeah, for sure. Turn off all biometric
Speaker 2:  authentication
Speaker 6:  And turn off your phone before you cross. Why? Because
Speaker 6:  the first time you turn your phone back on, you can't log in with biometrics.
Speaker 6:  So even If you forget to turn off biometrics, like the first time you need
Speaker 6:  to put in your passcode, there are, depending on like on your device,
Speaker 6:  you can maybe disable biometrics by like pressing the button on the side
Speaker 6:  a couple times. So like, yeah, the main thing is no
Speaker 6:  biometrics, passcode, login only turn your phone off
Speaker 6:  so you know, back up your device wipe whatever you wanna
Speaker 6:  wipe. And again, like people are gonna say like, why do I have to wipe my
Speaker 6:  device if I'm not doing anything wrong? It's like, because
Speaker 6:  the scope of what is wrong is expanding and expanding and expanding
Speaker 6:  even if the law hasn't changed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And, and truthfully like the, the way I would answer that question
Speaker 2:  is like maybe you don't, but is it worth the risk? Right? Like
Speaker 2:  Even if you don't think there is something in there, like I think about this,
Speaker 2:  like you were saying, your text messages from 12 years ago, like this is
Speaker 2:  the reason I, I like deleted all my tweets at one point I was just like,
Speaker 2:  I, I don't know what I was tweeting in 2010, but I absolutely do not wanna
Speaker 2:  be held responsible for it. Right? Like no one should be held responsible
Speaker 2:  for what they were saying on the internet or in text messages 15 years ago.
Speaker 2:  And in this particular case you are potentially signing yourself up for
Speaker 2:  if nothing else that and that Totally, that should scare
Speaker 2:  everyone. Like,
Speaker 6:  And if they do a forensic search of your phone, they keep, they keep the
Speaker 6:  data like they keep it, it's theirs. So
Speaker 6:  DHS is building out this massive surveillance database called heart, which
Speaker 6:  stands for the Homeland Advanced Recognition Technology.
Speaker 6:  And it's gonna basically replace their current massive database,
Speaker 6:  which is called the Automated Biometric Identification system
Speaker 6:  or I ident and heart is like their plan
Speaker 6:  is to be able to map people's like non-obvious relationships, like all of
Speaker 6:  these different things about a person's life that again, like go beyond like
Speaker 6:  who, like why are you traveling to the us where are you coming from? Like
Speaker 6:  what do you have on you? Like If you let them, you know,
Speaker 6:  take your phone and take all the contents on your own and back it up for
Speaker 6:  God knows how long, like that is data that that is being fed into this like
Speaker 6:  massive machine and you dunno how it's gonna be weaponized against you or
Speaker 6:  other people. It's kind of like the 23 and me thing, you know, like you get
Speaker 6:  a Christmas present, you spit into a vial and like suddenly like you're like
Speaker 6:  12th cousin is getting arrested for like murder maybe.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Just weird analogy I guess. But
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But It is true and I think that that question of
Speaker 2:  not only like how does this affect me, but how does this affect you? You
Speaker 2:  don't know the sort of second, third and fourth order effects that this data
Speaker 2:  being out there has. And this is the thing we've learned over and over, right,
Speaker 2:  that like the, the location data in your phone and the, the usage data on
Speaker 2:  social networks like this stuff actually affects a much broader circle
Speaker 2:  of people than just you as it gets out there. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 2:  It is, like that's a, that's a useful thing to hold onto, especially in this
Speaker 2:  particular case I think.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there was actually just a, an instance of a lawyer
Speaker 6:  who was coming back to the US with his family from spring break. US
Speaker 6:  citizen lawyer, the agents at
Speaker 6:  CBP at the airport, like tried to look through his phone. He got
Speaker 6:  away with like just a basic search, basically not a
Speaker 6:  forensic search. They didn't back up his information, but it's like his client's
Speaker 6:  information is on that phone. There was another instance where CBP
Speaker 6:  took an immigration lawyer's phone and you know, they did like
Speaker 6:  use the forensic search to like comb through what was on it. And a lot
Speaker 6:  of that of what was on it was like client information. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  And so, you know, a lot of us, myself included, use our phones for
Speaker 6:  work, for personal things and there's
Speaker 6:  not just information about me on my phone, there's information about my friends,
Speaker 6:  there's information about my family, there's information about like my sources.
Speaker 6:  And so I I would say like it's, it's really important for everyone
Speaker 6:  and it's like especially important for like journalists or lawyers or
Speaker 6:  people who have like sensitive information on their phones.
Speaker 2:  So given all of that, do you think that selective deletion strategy
Speaker 2:  even makes sense? Like is there a sort of half measure people can take
Speaker 2:  that will help them? Or is is are the possibilities here just so
Speaker 2:  huge and broad that you, you kind of might as well
Speaker 2:  just do the nuclear option because it's the safer way to go?
Speaker 6:  I mean, I would say like, you know, it's still a small,
Speaker 6:  very small percentage of people who are getting their devices searched. But
Speaker 6:  at the same time, like realistically, how long does it take to back up
Speaker 6:  your data and wipe your phone and then put everything back on?
Speaker 6:  But it's also annoying to sit in a weird interrogation room
Speaker 6:  for hours and have law enforcement looking through your phone.
Speaker 6:  So I would say I'm not gonna tell anybody what they should do,
Speaker 6:  but I think that the wise, this course of action
Speaker 6:  is to minimize your risk as much as possible. And maybe
Speaker 6:  that means wiping down your phone entirely. Maybe that means like typing
Speaker 6:  in keywords that you don't want people to see and then
Speaker 6:  deleting whatever fits into those keywords. I think just like the main thing
Speaker 6:  to do is assess your risk as much as possible and
Speaker 6:  try to protect yourself as much as possible. And then also,
Speaker 6:  especially If you are a US citizen, like assert your rights as much as possible
Speaker 6:  as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah, that's a good one. And If you delete things, you have to then
Speaker 2:  go to trash and delete them again. Delete permanently is the phrase you wanna
Speaker 2:  look for in almost every case because that's when they're actually deleted.
Speaker 2:  All right. Last thing and then we'll let you go. How do you think about this
Speaker 2:  stuff as it pertains to other devices? I think phones are unique in
Speaker 2:  that they have that sort of massive information that you're talking about,
Speaker 2:  but also like I travel with my laptop. Should people think about their laptops
Speaker 2:  the same way they think about their phones? Or are all devices kind of looped
Speaker 2:  into this?
Speaker 6:  I would say all devices are looped into this. I kind of
Speaker 6:  wanna do a separate piece on laptops because I also travel with my laptop.
Speaker 6:  I have so much stuff on my laptop, I do not want to put everything
Speaker 6:  like, I don't know, like on an external hard driver in the cloud and then
Speaker 6:  backed on my laptop. Like that frankly sounds like really annoying and time
Speaker 6:  consuming. Yeah. Resetting your
Speaker 2:  Laptop is way more annoying than resetting your phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I'm not sure about that to be honest. I will
Speaker 6:  say that my old MacBook does not have biometric
Speaker 6:  login, which is great for me in this particular
Speaker 6:  instance. And yeah, I, I don't know. That's a good
Speaker 6:  question and I think one I should probably call up some lawyers about
Speaker 6:  'cause I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But in principle, If you're, if you're traveling now, you should be
Speaker 2:  applying kind of the same thinking and rigor to all of your devices, not
Speaker 2:  just your smartphone.
Speaker 6:  Yes, yes, definitely. Okay. And like smartphones, you know, are
Speaker 6:  maybe easier to lock down, also easier to search,
Speaker 6:  but there's a lot of stuff on my laptop.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Lot of J store articles.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like think of the PDFs I have. We both have just like randomly kicking
Speaker 2:  around in our downloads folder. I'm confident some of those would get me
Speaker 2:  in trouble. I don't even know what they are, but I am confident they would
Speaker 2:  get me in trouble.
Speaker 6:  Oh, for sure. Same. I know, I know what mine are. And they're, they're weird.
Speaker 6:  They're weird. Even like when I'm showing something, like when I'm sharing
Speaker 6:  my screen, I'm always like, no, no, no guys. And you don't understand. It's
Speaker 6:  research. It's research, I swear. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. There is a part of the challenge here that there is so much kind
Speaker 2:  of mystery in it. And like you, you mentioned in the piece that you wrote
Speaker 2:  that even what airport you land in could change the way that you go through
Speaker 2:  some of this process because of the different ways that different districts
Speaker 2:  of federal courts have ruled about how these searches can work. So it's like,
Speaker 2:  I think my sense is It is in part designed to be
Speaker 2:  complex and hard to understand, which makes it all the more important that
Speaker 2:  like you as the person going through it understand what is in your rights
Speaker 2:  to do.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, totally. It's like it's, I mean, I just like having to read about
Speaker 6:  circuit splits to write this piece. I was like, I'm not a lawyer, I'm not
Speaker 6:  a lawyer, I'm not a lawyer. What's going on? And I was talking to lawyers
Speaker 6:  and lawyers are like, yeah, this is really complicated. It's really complicated.
Speaker 6:  It doesn't make any sense. We have begged the Supreme Court
Speaker 6:  to rule so that there's like a single national binding
Speaker 6:  policy and there isn't one. But at the same time, like I don't
Speaker 6:  want people to think too much about like the circuit splits and the
Speaker 6:  different jurisdictions because ultimately like the, the rulings and the
Speaker 6:  differences are mostly about forensic searches. The, the legal question
Speaker 6:  hasn't really been raised for basic searches, which means like they could
Speaker 6:  do basic searches basically anywhere.
Speaker 6:  And you know, once again, If you volunteer your phone,
Speaker 6:  you, If you say no, then there's like a whole situation with like legality
Speaker 2:  we're, we're sort of running at each other in the tech industry right now.
Speaker 2:  And that's, that's what I wanna talk about.
Speaker 11:  I was the last guy with a Blackberry. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I feel like everyone in LA was the last guy with a Blackberry.
Speaker 11:  They were very popular here. I don't know why. Maybe the, we were just kind
Speaker 11:  of afraid of losing the keyboard.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There was something too though. Like everybody in LA wrote really long
Speaker 2:  emails way after it was cool to write long emails is is a theory it
Speaker 2:  developed. So I think, I think I wanna start with Apple because I have, I
Speaker 2:  have like a big picture question I wanna talk about, but I think the easiest
Speaker 2:  way to talk about It is probably by talking about Apple tv,
Speaker 2:  which is on a run of like pretty good hits. Severance was huge.
Speaker 2:  Everybody's excited about severance. The studio seems to be very good. You're
Speaker 2:  in it. So you're hopelessly compromised. I
Speaker 11:  Am, yes. I'm not gonna trash my own show. The the
Speaker 11:  three scenes I'm in.
Speaker 2:  The good news is it seems to be very good. So I think you're, you're safe
Speaker 2:  on that front and yet the, there's been some reporting that
Speaker 2:  Apple is losing up to a billion dollars a year on this whole
Speaker 2:  project. So I guess maybe the easiest place to start is why is this not working
Speaker 2:  for Apple as a business?
Speaker 11:  Well do we know that it's not working? Just because they're losing money
Speaker 11:  doesn't mean that the entire endeavor is not working.
Speaker 11:  It's just not working on traditional metrics where you have
Speaker 11:  a p and l and you get into a business to make money in
Speaker 11:  that business. Apple seems from the very
Speaker 11:  beginning to approach Hollywood from two
Speaker 11:  perspectives. One, this would be a brand halo, this would be
Speaker 11:  something nice that they could do that would give them something cool to
Speaker 11:  talk about. And they would work with the kinds of stars that they as
Speaker 11:  Apple consider themselves worthy of working with. And
Speaker 11:  they would put out some shows and have a service that would be
Speaker 11:  additive to their services business, which they seem to care very much about
Speaker 11:  these days and would give them something cool to put in
Speaker 11:  commercials and to talk about in tweets and on earnings calls.
Speaker 11:  That was one reason. The second was to
Speaker 11:  essentially provide a
Speaker 11:  bundling opportunity with their other services if they could
Speaker 11:  keep you longer in the Apple ecosystem because they had
Speaker 11:  Apple One and they had news and games and
Speaker 11:  you know, television shows that you've heard of that that would be
Speaker 11:  additive to their other businesses. So I think
Speaker 11:  when we talk about the failure in Hollywood, there's
Speaker 11:  legitimate things they're not doing that they should be doing in my opinion.
Speaker 11:  But I don't know that we can say that they're not getting out of this what
Speaker 11:  they wanted to get out of it.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. I mean, and I think the, the question
Speaker 2:  of does it matter if Apple TV plus makes any money? Seems like it has
Speaker 2:  been sitting there for Apple since it started this project and I feel
Speaker 2:  like I, I'm curious how you see the brand halo piece of all of
Speaker 2:  this, because to me it's like, I, I remember back when they first launched
Speaker 2:  this thing and do you remember they had that event that they just like paraded
Speaker 2:  a bunch of a-list celebrities out on stage?
Speaker 11:  Oh yeah. It was the cattle call, right?
Speaker 2:  And so it's like, is is, is this entire endeavor worth it just
Speaker 2:  for that? Like, is that what Apple needs to get out of it and it can just
Speaker 2:  sell a bunch of iPhones and who cares about the money? Like is the brand
Speaker 2:  Halo real enough that it's actually worth it for this company?
Speaker 11:  Well, you'd have to ask them, but I think from my perspective, it was
Speaker 11:  meaningful for them to get all of these celebrities up to Cupertino. Remember
Speaker 11:  the famous Oprah line? Like they're in a billion pockets, y'all. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Like that was her reason for getting into business with Apple.
Speaker 11:  And If you look at the choices they are making on
Speaker 11:  the content side, one after another, It is
Speaker 11:  huge stars. If you, I mean the, it's a joke around town. Like
Speaker 11:  if you've got a big star filled package and you're selling
Speaker 11:  it around town, apple will bite. Like they just want to be in business
Speaker 11:  with big movie stars and big TV stars. And the
Speaker 11:  criticism of them is that they don't ultimately often enough
Speaker 11:  follow through on the promise of those stars. There's lots of projects
Speaker 11:  that are kind of littering Apple TV plus that have big names in them, but
Speaker 11:  don't ultimately turn into great shows. There are examples of course, of
Speaker 11:  shows that do turn into great shows with big stars,
Speaker 11:  but the, the, the evidence we have for whether
Speaker 11:  they're getting out of this, what they want is that they continue to sign
Speaker 11:  up big stars. And when it works there, you know, Eddie Q can go to
Speaker 11:  South by Southwest and have an hour long conversation with Ben Stiller
Speaker 11:  and he doesn't have to talk about all the other problems that are
Speaker 11:  circling Apple.
Speaker 2:  Is that something we see across Hollywood, this idea that like, it's
Speaker 2:  it's worth the cost to be able to sit next to Ben Stiller for an hour. Like
Speaker 2:  is this, is this sort of a long playbook run by companies in Hollywood? People
Speaker 11:  In Hollywood don't care, they just want them to keep doing it. The biggest
Speaker 11:  nightmare would be if Apple suddenly decided one day to get out and this
Speaker 11:  is not worth it to them. So they have people in town are like
Speaker 11:  terrified that Eddie Q's gonna wake up one morning and be like, wait, why
Speaker 11:  do I have that meeting in LA on my schedule? Like, why let's just not do
Speaker 11:  that anymore. Like, that is the fear because then it would suck
Speaker 11:  a few billion dollars out of the professionally produced content
Speaker 11:  industry. And Apple's a big buyer of that kind of content.
Speaker 11:  And does the average Apple customer
Speaker 11:  think more highly about Apple because they have a
Speaker 11:  John Ham show or they produce the studio? Like
Speaker 11:  I don't know the answer to that. I mean, that's a, a Harvard Business school
Speaker 11:  study waiting to happen. It probably doesn't hurt
Speaker 11:  and it's a rounding error for them to be in this business.
Speaker 11:  And it does let Tim Cook go to the Oscars and talk about it on the
Speaker 11:  earnings call and tweet about how much he loves Ted Lasso. So is that
Speaker 11:  worth it for them maybe?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the, the people will pay a lot of money to have famous friends
Speaker 2:  is a lesson I have learned over and over in, in covering this business.
Speaker 11:  Especially when you already have a lot of money. Right,
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. You already have the money. Get the famous friends.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, exactly. Like when you got everything in the world, what don't you
Speaker 11:  have exclusivity and famous friends are exclusive and to be able to say
Speaker 11:  that we are producing a Martin Scorsese movie with
Speaker 11:  Leonardo DiCaprio, not everyone can say that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So you've kind of run at the big picture question I wanted to ask you,
Speaker 2:  which is basically why do these big tech companies
Speaker 2:  want into Hollywood in the first place? And I think the, the way I
Speaker 2:  think about it like It is, it's a, it's a risky business at best and a
Speaker 2:  terrible business at worst, these companies don't
Speaker 2:  necessarily seem to have any particular aptitude for
Speaker 2:  it. And yet it seems like every tech company that
Speaker 2:  hits a certain kind of status is like, okay, our next big project is we're
Speaker 2:  gonna go just headlong into the streaming wars in some way.
Speaker 11:  Well, I think it's, it's specific to the companies. If you look at what
Speaker 11:  Amazon is doing, for instance, I actually do think that it makes sense
Speaker 11:  for Amazon to get into this business because look at what Amazon is,
Speaker 11:  It is a massive retailer and television
Speaker 11:  is a massive retail product. If they can be the
Speaker 11:  next generation gatekeeper of all television, that is a
Speaker 11:  good business for them to be in. And by the way, it would also help
Speaker 11:  keep people in the prime ecosystem and sell them more toilet paper.
Speaker 11:  So Amazon, I think is the poster
Speaker 11:  child for what a tech company can get out of Hollywood
Speaker 11:  if they do it right. And I think the jury's still out on whether they are
Speaker 11:  doing it right or whether they can turn this into a massive
Speaker 11:  business. They think at Amazon, they think that Prime video is gonna be
Speaker 11:  profitable in the next year or two. And if that's the case, then good for
Speaker 11:  them. They spend a lot of money and they are making headway there. And,
Speaker 11:  and in some ways they have a leg up on Apple because
Speaker 11:  what did Apple do this past year? They put Apple TV plus in the
Speaker 11:  Amazon Prime channels, right? Business. They essentially
Speaker 11:  bowed down to Amazon and said, okay, we need you to
Speaker 11:  sell our product. We Apple, the biggest company in the world,
Speaker 11:  need Amazon to get people to subscribe to Apple TV Plus.
Speaker 11:  And it's working, they are getting a lot of subscribers through the Amazon
Speaker 11:  channels program as are all the other services. And that is the end
Speaker 11:  game. Just like Amazon wants to sell you four different
Speaker 11:  varieties of recliner, they also want to sell you four
Speaker 11:  different varieties of programming.
Speaker 2:  But is is, is it definite? Are we sure that you then
Speaker 2:  need your own massive slate of content
Speaker 2:  and you need to spend eight and a half billion dollars on MGM in order to
Speaker 2:  do that? Like, I actually get the retail side of that for Amazon in particular.
Speaker 2:  That makes a lot of sense. But do you need your own
Speaker 2:  Hollywood universe in order to be that company?
Speaker 11:  It's a differentiator for sure. I mean, there's a lot of these companies
Speaker 11:  out there like Roku and DirecTV that don't produce their
Speaker 11:  own shows on that scale. And Amazon believes
Speaker 11:  that if it owns enough of this stuff and can use it as a lure to
Speaker 11:  bring people into the ecosystem, then that is a differentiator.
Speaker 11:  And I think I agree there. I think that the, the, the fact that
Speaker 11:  they have original programming that people do watch, I mean these shows
Speaker 11:  like Reacher and Cross and you know, the kind of guy with a gun
Speaker 11:  shows, people are watching that stuff on Amazon, obviously now they have
Speaker 11:  Thursday night football, which has been a big deal for them and it costs
Speaker 11:  nothing but money, which is what they have. And they are in business with
Speaker 11:  the NFL, which is the most premium video product there is.
Speaker 11:  So I, I do think it's a differentiator and it, and it sets them apart from
Speaker 11:  some of these just
Speaker 11:  platforms. It's, it's, it's a pro the programming does matter. Maybe not
Speaker 11:  on that scale, and maybe they won't do it forever, but I think it does matter.
Speaker 2:  I'm particularly Chris when companies like that come into Hollywood and they're
Speaker 2:  like, we, we are going to invest in streaming in some meaningful way, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna start making content. They all have essentially unlimited amounts of
Speaker 2:  money. What's what's, what happens in Hollywood when one of those
Speaker 2:  companies shows up? Is it just like, oh, thank God another money
Speaker 2:  fountain that they're just gonna have to come buy our stuff and everybody's
Speaker 2:  psyched about it?
Speaker 11:  Well, yes, I think that's certainly part of it,
Speaker 11:  but then it becomes what do they actually want and what are they
Speaker 11:  actually going to do for my creators? And that's the
Speaker 11:  representative community when they're looking at this. And I remember when
Speaker 11:  YouTube started doing professionally produced shows, it
Speaker 11:  wasn't just whether Google had the money to make them, obviously everybody
Speaker 11:  knows they do. It was, okay, how
Speaker 11:  is this gonna be produced? Are you, are you doing this via the unions?
Speaker 11:  You know, that's a big thing. Netflix, the first thing they did when they
Speaker 11:  got into original programming was, we are gonna play by the rules and we're
Speaker 11:  going to, we do union contracts with all of the different unions.
Speaker 11:  We're going to pay people differently. They're gonna give you more money
Speaker 11:  than your quote upfront, but they're not gonna pay back ends. And that
Speaker 11:  was a big shift for the industry and everybody went along with it because
Speaker 11:  they were making more money upfront. And when YouTube started doing this,
Speaker 11:  it was, how is this gonna be displayed? Is my show gonna be a
Speaker 11:  pop-up video next to a cat falling downstairs? Or
Speaker 11:  is this gonna be presented in a premium elevated
Speaker 11:  app format where you go to a separate area and then the premium
Speaker 11:  shows play? And I think those are all the questions that people get asked.
Speaker 11:  Still to this day, people complain about the Amazon interface
Speaker 11:  and it's hard to find stuff and it looks like a retail store and
Speaker 11:  that's a factor. The, the Apple interface is super elegant and
Speaker 11:  looks like an Apple product and people like that and their shows
Speaker 11:  look like they're expensive and they are it, how are you gonna market
Speaker 11:  this? That's the other thing is that Netflix doesn't
Speaker 11:  do very much marketing. They have an algorithm that does most of the marketing
Speaker 11:  for them. So outside of the awards context, you're not
Speaker 11:  gonna get much marketing for Netflix. And Apple and Amazon have said, okay,
Speaker 11:  we will actually market your shows. And I think it depends on who you are
Speaker 11:  as to whether you actually get that, but those are all the things that
Speaker 11:  you look at when, when the tech companies come to town.
Speaker 2:  And is that kind of the list that any new entrant in this
Speaker 2:  space would have to come up with? Like If you, if you're a
Speaker 2:  any studio or distributor, are you having to answer those same questions?
Speaker 2:  Like is there anything different when it's these tech companies that are
Speaker 2:  trying to do this?
Speaker 11:  The the thing that's different, I think is the, the
Speaker 11:  question of presentation. Because in the old
Speaker 11:  format, you kind of knew what a movie was, you knew what a show was. You
Speaker 11:  knew If you sold it to NBC it was gonna get a certain kind of treatment.
Speaker 11:  You could argue over the marketing and you could argue over the time slot
Speaker 11:  and all that stuff. And in movies, you, you argue over the release
Speaker 11:  commitment, whether you're getting a wide release, whether you're getting
Speaker 11:  a, a platform release, the marketing spend associated with it
Speaker 11:  on these platforms. There's a a fear of just being
Speaker 11:  churned up by the algorithm Hmm. And not being
Speaker 11:  presented in a way that your art is should be
Speaker 11:  presented. And when I talk to representatives, they really try to
Speaker 11:  think about that. And some places like Netflix say, you gotta, you know,
Speaker 11:  you gotta trust us. This is what we do. We will find the right
Speaker 11:  audience for your show. Others, you could have a little bit more of a
Speaker 11:  conversation. What's the marketing gonna be on this? Where, where
Speaker 11:  am what am I gonna get for a theatrical release for my
Speaker 11:  movie? And you know, the, the F1 movie that Apple is releasing
Speaker 11:  this summer, they guaranteed at least a 45 day window
Speaker 11:  in theaters. We'll see how long it ultimately ends up getting beyond that.
Speaker 11:  But that was the, a big reason why that F1 movie
Speaker 11:  went to Apple and not to Netflix or one of the others because
Speaker 11:  they got a guaranteed theatrical release. So those are, so those are some
Speaker 11:  of the considerations. There's
Speaker 2:  An interesting disconnect sort of inherent in all that, that you've written
Speaker 2:  about a bunch over the years. And like I, you always use the word content
Speaker 2:  as sort of a shorthand for the difference in how these people talk about
Speaker 2:  it, which I really like the C word. Yeah. We talk about it all the time too.
Speaker 2:  It's right. It's like what is, what is art and what is content? Yeah.
Speaker 11:  I mean that was the big problem at Amazon is the head of the studio referred
Speaker 11:  to a James Bond movie as content and the producer of the
Speaker 11:  James Bond movie did not like that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So that's actually the exact example I was about to ask you about.
Speaker 2:  Like, I think the, the whole saga with Bond and the broccoli and
Speaker 2:  the, that, the great quote where, you know, she hates everybody at Amazon.
Speaker 2:  Still not perfect relations everywhere. But I, I remember years ago there,
Speaker 2:  there was this feeling that like, the tech people don't get us Hollywood
Speaker 2:  people and the tech people were like, shut up. We have all the money. And
Speaker 2:  has that gotten better over time? Like, have these, have these groups of
Speaker 2:  people figured each other out a little more?
Speaker 11:  Well, the interesting thing is that slowly but surely these tech
Speaker 11:  companies have been populated by traditional studio people.
Speaker 11:  Hmm. If you look at the people that are running the content
Speaker 11:  operations at Apple, Amazon, and Netflix, they're all
Speaker 11:  traditional Hollywood people. Bella Baia ran the content
Speaker 11:  group at NBC and now she's the chief content officer at Netflix. Jen
Speaker 11:  Salki, who just ended up leaving, but she was also an NBC
Speaker 11:  executive before she went to Amazon. And over at
Speaker 11:  Apple, the top content executives ran Sony Pictures television and they
Speaker 11:  were big producers. So, you know, and, and on the movie side they pop so
Speaker 11:  slowly but surely, at least in the Hollywood groups, I'm not talking
Speaker 11:  about the people who work in Los Gatos for Netflix,
Speaker 11:  but the Hollywood people are Hollywood people. So there's a level of
Speaker 11:  comfort that the, the representation and talent
Speaker 11:  community has with those people because they're one of their own now
Speaker 11:  often that will butt up against the instincts of
Speaker 11:  the tech companies. And that's when you see conflicts
Speaker 11:  and it comes to a head all the time at Netflix where they absolutely do
Speaker 11:  not want to put movies in theaters. And obviously the artists all want their
Speaker 11:  movies in theaters and they lose projects Right. And left
Speaker 11:  over that. And they want traditional marketing. Netflix doesn't do that
Speaker 11:  because they have the algorithm and there's a, an interface where, you know,
Speaker 11:  the creatives would love for the credits of their shows and movies
Speaker 11:  to play after they air. But the Netflix model
Speaker 11:  is to push, push, push to the next piece of content. So it starts
Speaker 11:  autoplaying before you even see any credits. Correct. Like that's what you
Speaker 11:  have to live with if you're working with those services. But I guess in
Speaker 11:  the words of Don Draper, that's what the money's for.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I always get a kick out of, whenever you're watching something with
Speaker 2:  a post credit scene, you have to like work really hard to go find it because
Speaker 2:  Netflix is desperate to just get you off the credits and onto something else.
Speaker 2:  And I'm like, no, no, I'd actually, I'd actually like to watch this Netflix.
Speaker 2:  Thank
Speaker 11:  You. Yeah. It's annoying. I know. And, and like makes me feel a hundred
Speaker 11:  years old, but it's like, why, why are we already on the next show? And
Speaker 11:  I get it. Like it, you know, it used to be that those would count as views
Speaker 11:  when the autoplay started a new episode of a show.
Speaker 11:  All it would take is like 30 seconds or a minute and Netflix would count
Speaker 11:  it as a view. They don't do that anymore. Yeah. But yeah, it was kind of
Speaker 11:  a fraud. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Agreed. So I feel like there's that, that kind of
Speaker 2:  Hollywood people inside of these companies who then have to go like sit in
Speaker 2:  conference rooms with the business people and the tech people and the product
Speaker 2:  people, that tension, at least from where I sit, still seems
Speaker 2:  sort of alive and well. And I feel like, oh yeah, this is a thing that, that
Speaker 2:  we hear about and cover all the time. It's like if you're, you know, you're
Speaker 2:  Andy Jassy, you're the CEO of Amazon, and you look around and you're like,
Speaker 2:  okay, times are tough, tariffs are coming, things are complicated.
Speaker 2:  Where where can we pull back? And you, you look over at this thing where
Speaker 2:  you're like, well we just spent hundreds of millions of dollars on Citadel
Speaker 2:  this show that no one watched and was awful. That's a lot easier to
Speaker 2:  cut than a bunch of like AWS engineers. And, and so I wonder like, it, it
Speaker 2:  does seem like there's been a little bit of a cultural shift towards
Speaker 2:  sort of understanding how that world works and what the investments
Speaker 2:  look like in caring about, you know, the art. And those people seem to be
Speaker 2:  more powerful inside of those companies than they once were. But I do
Speaker 2:  still feel like if you're, if you're an executive at Amazon or Google
Speaker 2:  or Apple or any of these companies, I don't feel like the Hollywood people
Speaker 2:  are winning yet.
Speaker 11:  That's probably true. The, the ultimate deciders
Speaker 11:  still are in the headquarters and they're not in the LA operations.
Speaker 11:  Hmm. And I think that that is, you know, they are, they
Speaker 11:  operate on the whim of these, these overlords that determine
Speaker 11:  budgets. And there have been a couple come to Jesus moments, especially
Speaker 11:  at Apple, where they have said, listen, you know, we, we put these movies
Speaker 11:  in theaters and they flop and they give us
Speaker 11:  bad headlines. People write about, people write the words Apple and the
Speaker 11:  word flop in the same headline sentence. Like, that's not what we want.
Speaker 11:  We're Apple, we don't have flops. So, although I guess lately
Speaker 11:  they do, but
Speaker 2:  Yeah. More so recently. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  They, you know, so they're like, why are we doing this? So when they had
Speaker 11:  this movie Wolfs last summer, Clooney and Pitt, and they didn't think it
Speaker 11:  was great, they just said, we're not doing that. Well, you know, we're gonna
Speaker 11:  put it just on the service and there's a real question as to whether Apple's
Speaker 11:  gonna put more movies in theaters. I think F1 this summer is a big test
Speaker 11:  because they don't like the bad headlines. If they're not doing this for
Speaker 11:  money, essentially they're doing this for brand Halo and for services.
Speaker 11:  Then why endure bad headlines If you don't have to?
Speaker 2:  I feel like streaming hits are like the new cult classics where you say That
Speaker 2:  movie was a huge failure, and everybody's like, well, no, everybody saw it
Speaker 2:  later. They really liked it. It, it's like, sure. Well
Speaker 11:  That's been true forever. Yeah. I remember being in, in meetings with the
Speaker 11:  HBO people in the two thousands where they would talk about how
Speaker 11:  all the press attention is on their original series. But when you look at
Speaker 11:  the bread and butter of who was watching HBO, it was people watching those
Speaker 11:  movies that they didn't see in theaters but had their first
Speaker 11:  run on premium cable on HBO. Mm. And one of
Speaker 11:  the biggest movies for HBO of all time was the Flop
Speaker 11:  battleship. Remember that movie? Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I do
Speaker 11:  Huge flop in theaters, but it had a lot of stars that had Rihanna,
Speaker 11:  remember that it had all these like hot stars in it. And
Speaker 11:  like there is a train wreck element when you're watching on television
Speaker 11:  that works. The thinking in streaming is that
Speaker 11:  the originals bring people in and the license
Speaker 11:  content keeps them because you come in for the sexy
Speaker 11:  title. If it's Max, you're coming in for the HBO original series
Speaker 11:  and then you stay for the Warner Brothers library of movies and
Speaker 11:  all the other stuff that's on Max. The knock on Apple
Speaker 11:  is that for reasons beyond me, they have not invested in a library.
Speaker 11:  They could license a ton of movies. They could license kids
Speaker 11:  stuff, they could license shows from other networks. They don't
Speaker 11:  do that. It's really just a repository for their originals with
Speaker 11:  some, some other stuff that they put in there. And as a
Speaker 11:  result, the engagement numbers, the time spent on the
Speaker 11:  platform are tiny Nielsen releases a gauge metric
Speaker 11:  once a month where it tells you the percentage of
Speaker 11:  time for each service on connected TVs. And
Speaker 11:  obviously YouTube and Netflix are the top draws,
Speaker 11:  but Apple doesn't even rate Apple's not even on
Speaker 11:  the top 10 lists because the engagement numbers
Speaker 11:  are so low because people are coming in for those five shows that they've
Speaker 11:  heard of and that's it. They're not staying for anything else.
Speaker 2:  So as we look ahead, we're obviously, it's a, it's a weird moment in
Speaker 2:  the world and economy right now, but I feel like we've been,
Speaker 2:  for years every everybody has been asking like, okay, at
Speaker 2:  what point are some of these companies going to decide to
Speaker 2:  just go all in on this? Apple's gonna buy Disney or Netflix,
Speaker 2:  somebody's gonna go, Amazon's gonna go spend all the money in the known universe
Speaker 2:  and just eat the NFL entirely. Like someone is going to fully
Speaker 2:  like a hundred percent this strategy. And yet it hasn't happened yet.
Speaker 2:  Why? Why do you think not why haven't we seen the like full push into the
Speaker 2:  middle of the table from one of these companies?
Speaker 11:  I, I think there's a couple reasons. First, the antitrust concerns and the
Speaker 11:  Biden administration was so openly hostile to m and a activity
Speaker 11:  that I think there's, there was a real sense that any effort
Speaker 11:  on the tech company's part to buy a studio or pull off another
Speaker 11:  MGM or Fox, Disney would be met with pretty swift resistance.
Speaker 11:  And now under Trump, we're seeing a different kind of chaos
Speaker 11:  where the market is so volatile that you're afraid
Speaker 11:  to do anything in this kind of environment. So that's one
Speaker 11:  reason. Secondly, like other than the Beats acquisition,
Speaker 11:  we have not seen Apple do anything in the m and a
Speaker 11:  space in this arena. And all these people out there saying, well, oh,
Speaker 11:  it's only a matter of time before they buy Disney. Really? Like, are we
Speaker 11:  sure about that? Do you think Apple wants to be in the churro business and
Speaker 11:  the Turkey leg business in, you know, countries around the world
Speaker 11:  and have to deal with a kid getting eaten by an alligator, a Disney world
Speaker 11:  and things like that? Like that's, that's what they want to be in. I I just
Speaker 11:  don't, I just don't see that I could see them picking
Speaker 11:  off something like Warner Brothers, which would give them HBO,
Speaker 11:  which is what they wanted to buy a decade ago, and Time Warner
Speaker 11:  wouldn't sell it to them. That's right.
Speaker 2:  I forgot
Speaker 11:  About that. And I think that that makes a little bit more sense, but again,
Speaker 11:  that would come along with all of these dying television networks. And does
Speaker 11:  Apple wanna be in the business of managing the decline of television?
Speaker 11:  I mean, they could try to sell that stuff off, but that's a, that's a real
Speaker 11:  challenge there. So there's all of these different m and a scenarios
Speaker 11:  from the tech companies. They, they raise both
Speaker 11:  regulatory and logistical problems and I think that's why we
Speaker 11:  haven't seen them so far. Doesn't mean they won't happen. I'm just saying
Speaker 11:  that's why.
Speaker 2:  Last thing and then I'm gonna let you go. F1 you mentioned this earlier,
Speaker 2:  strikes me as kind of a big moment for
Speaker 2:  Apple TV plus specifically, but also this whole sort of
Speaker 2:  big tech streaming thing. This is certainly the biggest, most
Speaker 2:  expensive swing I can think of from one of
Speaker 2:  these sort of big tech companies trying to make this happen. It's doing the
Speaker 2:  theatrical thing. We've been seeing ads about it for like forever. Brad Pitt
Speaker 2:  was like, at F1 race, this is like, this feels like a moment to me. Does
Speaker 2:  it feel like a moment to you? Like are you, are you watching this carefully?
Speaker 11:  Certainly for Apple, it's definitely the biggest thing they've done and
Speaker 11:  they partner with Warner Brothers for the release. Apple doesn't release
Speaker 11:  their own movies in theaters. They partner with the traditional studios
Speaker 11:  for that. And I, I think it, it's a big moment for them because
Speaker 11:  it's kind of a make or break. I think if this is a total flop
Speaker 11:  and they put all this effort and money into a movie for theaters that didn't
Speaker 11:  really make a dent, I, I think they really question what
Speaker 11:  they are doing in the theatrical space and that has
Speaker 11:  repercussions all the way down the line. Having said that, Eddie Q was
Speaker 11:  at the CinemaCon movie theater convention last week and he was
Speaker 11:  doing meetings with the traditional theaters and he was at least saying,
Speaker 11:  we care about theaters and we're gonna do some movies in theaters.
Speaker 11:  So maybe they're committed to this, but I think if, if F1 flops,
Speaker 11:  they're gonna really question it. I don't think it will. I think the movie
Speaker 11:  looks good enough and I think that there will be an audience globally for
Speaker 11:  this movie. So it, it may not be a billion dollar grocer, but I think it
Speaker 11:  will do enough to, for them to feel like it was a success
Speaker 11:  and that it was worth, it's worth doing for the right movie in the future.
Speaker 2:  All right, Matt, thank you so much. This was really fun. Appreciate you doing
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, no problem.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  take a question from The Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 16:  The Vergecast. I have a couple thoughts after your last episode.
Speaker 16:  I wanted to ask about the Google Pixel. It seems like the Pixel has gone
Speaker 16:  from being a, what is this phone going to even do in the
Speaker 16:  future to a, this is what I recommend to my friends and family.
Speaker 16:  Can you walk us through how that happened? Thanks.
Speaker 2:  I really like this question because one of the reviews that I am frankly
Speaker 2:  most proud of in retrospect, but was very skeptical
Speaker 2:  of my own thoughts at the time were when I was at Wired and the very
Speaker 2:  first pixel came out, I said it was the best phone on the planet period.
Speaker 2:  Like not just best Android phone, best phone, because what we had been wanting
Speaker 2:  was a phone that ran Android that didn't come with all the limitations
Speaker 2:  of iOS and the iPhone and all of the closed wall
Speaker 2:  gardens of it, but was simple and easy to
Speaker 2:  use and just works and you didn't have to spend all your time like tweaking
Speaker 2:  settings and installing launches and thinking about it. Something that just
Speaker 2:  did all the things your phone was supposed to do. And the very first pixel
Speaker 2:  was very close to that. It wasn't perfect, but it was very close to that.
Speaker 2:  And I think to me, the most fascinating thing about the Pixel line ever since
Speaker 2:  then has been this weird
Speaker 2:  rollercoaster of progress that it has made, right? I think
Speaker 2:  Google has over the years gotten better at design. I think
Speaker 2:  you, you, you can quibble with that a little bit, but the sort of Cyclops
Speaker 2:  thing that happens on the pixels now I think looks nice. The cameras
Speaker 2:  have consistently been very good and yet every time you turn around there
Speaker 2:  is some weird thing going on with the pixels. This
Speaker 2:  is what I mean by the rollercoaster. It's like it's sort of two steps forward
Speaker 2:  and one step back with every one of these hardware iterations, there have
Speaker 2:  been these mysterious hardware issues with a lot of them. My wife actually
Speaker 2:  had one of these with a Pixel seven I believe it was, where
Speaker 2:  her screen just went green, like matrixy green all of a sudden out of nowhere.
Speaker 2:  And I looked it up online and tons of people were like, yeah, this happens.
Speaker 2:  Google says it happens, they'll replace it. This is the kind of thing that
Speaker 2:  is hard to engender real confidence. And
Speaker 2:  Google has had pretty rough customer support over the years. Its
Speaker 2:  interest in the pixel lineup has kind of waxed and waned. It has had some
Speaker 2:  issues with the tensor processors. There was one of the pixels where the
Speaker 2:  fingerprint reader didn't work very well. Some of the phones have been really
Speaker 2:  sort of big and clunky. Google has just never quite put all
Speaker 2:  the pieces together. But the thing it had going for it all this time
Speaker 2:  is that it was the simple one, right? I think Samsung for most
Speaker 2:  of its life in the Android world has been the default
Speaker 2:  Android choice and with good reason, right? Samsung makes really good phones,
Speaker 2:  it has really good interesting hardware, it has great cameras. It caught
Speaker 2:  up a long time ago in a lot of those things and consistently does a very
Speaker 2:  good job. But a Samsung phone is sort of by definition a power user
Speaker 2:  thing and Samsung has still not done enough
Speaker 2:  to pull back the operating system to make it so that you can
Speaker 2:  just get a phone and have it and use it and it can just be
Speaker 2:  your phone. I don't think most people wanna do work on their phones, right?
Speaker 2:  And so I think for me and for Allison Johnson
Speaker 2:  on our team and for a lot of our reviewers, the thing that we keep landing
Speaker 2:  on is that simplicity is really important, right? And when I say like a
Speaker 2:  Pixel nine A is a perfect phone for my parents, I mean that
Speaker 2:  literally, right? Like I, I think there are lots of people who want to do
Speaker 2:  stuff on their phone and they like mucking around in settings and I actually
Speaker 2:  think Samsung deserves enormous credit for how much it lets you
Speaker 2:  do on the phone. Samsung is just like a tinkerer's paradise
Speaker 2:  of an Android device and should get real credit for that. But
Speaker 2:  not everybody wants that. I think most people don't want that. And I think
Speaker 2:  frankly, the reason Google started making pixels in the first place is that
Speaker 2:  it understood that most people don't want that. Most people want a phone
Speaker 2:  that they turn on that works and, and that is
Speaker 2:  not a thing you get from most Android manufacturers. And so Google set out
Speaker 2:  to say, okay, we think Android is really great. We think everybody is kind
Speaker 2:  of bastardizing Android in the name of being interesting and
Speaker 2:  customizable and trying new things and adding their own apps on top of our
Speaker 2:  existing apps. And it was just too much. And so Google came in and said,
Speaker 2:  okay, we're gonna pair all of that all the way back and we are going to give
Speaker 2:  you the basic simple, straightforward,
Speaker 2:  pure version of Android. And I think that was the right idea.
Speaker 2:  And Android, you know, has also had its ups and downs. Android has had some
Speaker 2:  weird ideas about like where apps go and how widgets
Speaker 2:  work and all different kinds of settings, ideas. But I think at this point
Speaker 2:  Android has landed in a really stable, really mature,
Speaker 2:  really solid place and so has the pixel. I say this
Speaker 2:  with real trepidation because frankly at any moment Google could just
Speaker 2:  decide it doesn't care about this stuff anymore. And it has made grand
Speaker 2:  promises about supporting these things for a long time that it has walked
Speaker 2:  back in the past. Right now it's promises, seven years of security
Speaker 2:  updates for its devices. That's a big deal and a big win. Am I
Speaker 2:  confident that Google is gonna wanna make smartphones in seven years? No,
Speaker 2:  but if Google does wanna make smartphones in seven years, I think that's
Speaker 2:  great. And so at the least I think we've landed on a place
Speaker 2:  where you have two really great Android options and that's a
Speaker 2:  victory. You have Samsung, which is like the power
Speaker 2:  user lineup. It lets you do the most, It is the most capable, It is the most
Speaker 2:  phone like in every imaginable way. And on the other hand you
Speaker 2:  have the pixel, which is simple and straightforward. It is like the set it
Speaker 2:  and forget it smartphone. And I think that's also very powerful and I think
Speaker 2:  different phones will work for different people. I think frankly
Speaker 2:  I'm an iPhone user. I have been for a while. I'm terrified of leaving iMessage
Speaker 2:  just to be completely honest. But that dichotomy I think is
Speaker 2:  great. And I think the fact that the Apple lineup doesn't have that, where
Speaker 2:  you get to choose between the one that just sort of works and you don't really
Speaker 2:  have to think about and it's, it's simple and clean and nice
Speaker 2:  versus the one that will just let me go in and muck around and have some
Speaker 2:  fun. I love that about Android, I hate that about iOS.
Speaker 2:  But anyway, so that, that's where I've landed with the Pixel. I think the
Speaker 2:  the Pixel and really sort of solidifying with the nine lineup last
Speaker 2:  year and the nine A this year has landed at a point where like, I trust these
Speaker 2:  phones, right? They're good. They don't have obviously huge
Speaker 2:  glaring flaws. I don't have to tell you about the thing to watch out for.
Speaker 2:  It's just a good phone and It is a good phone that I'm not going to have
Speaker 2:  to spend hours teaching you how to use and that you're not gonna have to
Speaker 2:  spend hours figuring out how to use and that's a victory and
Speaker 2:  we need more of that in the tech industry. I say all this and
Speaker 2:  you know, give it three days and Google will cancel the next pixel
Speaker 2:  and everything will be set. But until then I'm gonna keep recommending the
Speaker 2:  Pixel to a lot of people because I continue to think it might just be the
Speaker 2:  best phone out there.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 2:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. Thank you. By the way,
Speaker 2:  to everybody who voted for us in the Webby Awards, we're gonna know on,
Speaker 2:  oh today, Tuesday the 22nd. Whether we won or not, we will tell
Speaker 2:  you on Friday, we're either gonna, you know, happy, celebrate, or
Speaker 2:  sadly yell at Brendan Carr one way or another. That's gonna be The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  As always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or other Android phones
Speaker 2:  you wanna sell me, you can always email Vergecast at The Verge dot com or
Speaker 2:  call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. Like I said, we're gonna do
Speaker 2:  a full hotline episode here in the very near future, so get your questions
Speaker 2:  in as soon as you can. We love hearing from you and they have set us up on
Speaker 2:  some truly wild reporting adventures, so thank you for that.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is produced by Eric Gomez, will pour Brandon Keefer.
Speaker 2:  Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of the Vox Media podcast network,
Speaker 2:  Nila, and I'll be back on Friday with Brendan Carr, open ai,
Speaker 2:  more signal shenanigans in the government and lots more.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll.