# Transcript
ID: 48ada51e-9d6b-4851-9a47-61ac9bd128f2
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1858112772837624997/-2128554668938846708/s93290-US-4869s-1743499051.mp3
Description: David has a Light Phone III, and it's making him wonder a lot of things about technology. So The Verge's Allison Johnson joins the show to talk about the whole trend of minimalist smartphones, and to figure out which features a smartphone absolutely needs, and which ones we could all probably do without. After that, The Verge's Andy Hawkins takes us through a big weekend in the Tesla Takedown movement, what's happening with Elon Musk's car company, how automakers are responding to impending tariffs, and whether we're wrong to be excited about the new Nissan Leaf. Finally, The Verge's Jen Tuohy answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11, or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about all-seeing cameras in our homes. Which mostly don't exist yet. Mostly.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of automotive
Speaker 1:  tariff coverage. Somehow. That's true. Didn't really
Speaker 1:  set out to do that here, and yet sometimes that's what we do.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here on a very
Speaker 1:  warm afternoon trying to decide how far into
Speaker 1:  the light phone three life I'm ready to go. So
Speaker 1:  I have the light phone three. If you don't know about the light phone, it's
Speaker 1:  basically this sort of decade old project from this company called
Speaker 1:  Light, trying to figure out like, what is the least amount of
Speaker 1:  phone irregular person need needs. So if you think about it, it's like,
Speaker 1:  okay, you need a phone that makes phone calls. You need a phone that sends
Speaker 1:  text messages. You probably need some kind of navigation. I think in 2025.
Speaker 1:  You need a camera. What else? What do you need? That isn't
Speaker 1:  social media. It isn't web browsing. It isn't all the distracting, problematic
Speaker 1:  stuff we're actually trying to get rid of on our phones and do less of.
Speaker 1:  What if you could just have a phone that did the essentials and nothing else?
Speaker 1:  I've been using this phone for a while, and it's not all the way there,
Speaker 1:  but it's pretty close, and I think it's close in some really interesting
Speaker 1:  ways. But the thing for me is like, I, I'm just not gonna stop using a
Speaker 1:  smartphone. Part of the thing is like, I do this for a living, right? Like,
Speaker 1:  I, I read a newsletter every week about apps. I'm not gonna stop using
Speaker 1:  a smartphone anytime soon, but I do like the idea of like a nights
Speaker 1:  and weekends phone or a way that I can just
Speaker 1:  disappear for a few hours, even if I'm like out walking the dog. Can I
Speaker 1:  take something with me that isn't my smartphone, but It is still a way for
Speaker 1:  me to be able to keep in touch with people who I need to be in touch with.
Speaker 1:  So what I'm trying to figure out is like, can I port my sim card? Does the
Speaker 1:  EIM swap stuff work? It turns out it's all very complicated, and I think
Speaker 1:  the real reason you can't do this stuff is because of carriers. But
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm pressing along. I'm going to try and figure this out. If you have
Speaker 1:  figured this out, how to have a smartphone and another phone, and
Speaker 1:  you figured that out in a way that actually like works for you, I am all
Speaker 1:  ears. I would very much like to hear from you. But anyway, that is not what
Speaker 1:  we're here to talk about on the show today, although it's a little bit what
Speaker 1:  we're here to talk about on the show today. First thing we're gonna do today
Speaker 1:  is I'm gonna talk with Allison Johnson about these minimalist smartphones,
Speaker 1:  and we're gonna try to figure out together what the right balance of
Speaker 1:  features and chaos and screen time is actually
Speaker 1:  the right set of things. I have a bunch of stuff we're gonna go through.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna try and figure it out. We're also gonna talk to Andy Hawkins
Speaker 1:  about the Tesla Takedown protest, which was having a big day this
Speaker 1:  weekend, plus what's going on with the automotive tariffs. This is a,
Speaker 1:  a sort of strange uncertain week for the auto industry, and
Speaker 1:  there's a lot to talk through. So we're gonna talk through it. Plus we have
Speaker 1:  a really fun question from the first cast hotline. Lots to do, lots to get
Speaker 1:  to, but It is like 70 degrees outside. And I still have
Speaker 1:  some testing to do on this thing. So I'm gonna go call my mom on the light
Speaker 1:  phone. It's gonna be great. This is the first cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Allison Johnson's here. Hi, Allison. Hello. I have
Speaker 1:  prepared a whole thing for us and I have prepared you. Not at all.
Speaker 6:  It's very exciting.
Speaker 1:  Are you, are you ready? Yes. So I've been using the light phone three
Speaker 1:  for the last week or so. I have it here. Ooh. I have a lot of feelings about
Speaker 1:  it. I find this phone deeply fascinating, and the thing that I
Speaker 1:  have been trying to figure out as I've been using this phone is basically
Speaker 1:  like, what is the least a phone
Speaker 1:  should be able to do in 2025? Like,
Speaker 1:  I, I, first, I want to get your sort of overall stance on
Speaker 1:  this kind of theory of a device that you can like, do some
Speaker 1:  smart things on a phone, but it doesn't run an app store, it doesn't give
Speaker 1:  you a web browser, it doesn't give you everything. It's like this sort of
Speaker 1:  minimum viable smartphone as a like either a nights
Speaker 1:  and weekend phone or like a thing for kids, which I know the light phone
Speaker 1:  has become very popular in. Or just like, I don't wanna spend so much time
Speaker 1:  looking at my phone, so I'm gonna buy a different phone. Do you buy this
Speaker 1:  premise at all? Oh,
Speaker 6:  Boy.
Speaker 6:  I, I want to, I want to believe in a minimalist
Speaker 6:  phone
Speaker 4:  For
Speaker 6:  Every time. I've kind of like gone two steps into
Speaker 6:  investigating it as an option. Like for me, because I don't want
Speaker 6:  10,000 notifications every day, I would like to exit
Speaker 6:  that existence. It just, it kind of falls
Speaker 6:  apart for me. Like, pretty quickly. I use the Barbie
Speaker 6:  phone for like a day and a half. Sure.
Speaker 6:  Like, had my phone number on it, and it
Speaker 6:  almost gave me a panic attack. Like trying to type text with T nine
Speaker 6:  is horrifying. Like, I know some people kind of think of the like, well,
Speaker 6:  you know, you put up some friction between you and
Speaker 6:  messaging, and maybe that's a way out of like constant communication
Speaker 6:  and stuff. For me, I hated it. And I, I look
Speaker 6:  at something like the light phone, like, especially that one, like, it's
Speaker 6:  a beautiful little device. I love the idea of like,
Speaker 6:  I'll just leave the apps behind and go into the world
Speaker 6:  unencumbered. But then I start thinking like, what if I need to
Speaker 6:  call an Uber and I get a panic attack again?
Speaker 1:  Okay. What a perfect unintentional segue to the game that I have devised
Speaker 1:  for us. So, no, I wrote down a list of, I think it's
Speaker 1:  35 things. Oh boy. And we are going to go through all
Speaker 1:  35 of these things, and we are going to decide, the gimmick here is you and
Speaker 1:  I are designing the perfect minimalist smartphone. Okay. That
Speaker 1:  does all the things it should do and nothing else. Right. And I, and we,
Speaker 1:  we have free rein. There are no rules. We're not worried about costs. The
Speaker 1:  question is just what should our phone do and not do? Okay.
Speaker 1:  And, and I'm just, we're gonna run through this list. Some of these I think
Speaker 1:  are really easy, some I think are really hard, and we're just gonna talk
Speaker 1:  through all of them. Yeah. Does it sound good? I love it. All right. I'm
Speaker 1:  just, it's, it's, I think it's 35 things, so we might be here a while. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Okay. These are in no particular order except the, the order
Speaker 1:  I thought of them first thing phone make phone calls. Yep. We're good at
Speaker 1:  this, right? We got, yeah. Okay. Easy one. Got it. Thing number two. Camera.
Speaker 1:  Should this phone have a camera?
Speaker 6:  I think it should, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Should it be a good camera one
Speaker 6:  Camera? And it can be okay, I think.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah. So we don't, we're not interested in, like, this is not the
Speaker 1:  camera. You like, spend your day taking pictures of your child. Yeah. This
Speaker 1:  is like a, it's a camera. If you like, need to take a picture of the poster
Speaker 1:  and remember it later. Yeah. That's what we're doing here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We'll be like, you can have a, a better camera separately.
Speaker 1:  Right? That's true. If you want a good camera, buy a good camera. Yeah. I
Speaker 1:  suppose as like part of the point of these phones.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You can buy a camera.
Speaker 1:  All right. But we're, we're allowing one pretty good camera.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm cool with this calculator.
Speaker 6:  Mm. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I was really hoping you were gonna be like, no, too addictive. I'm not a
Speaker 1:  calculator.
Speaker 6:  No. Does it run Tetris? Like my TI
Speaker 6:  83 did? That's an important question.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, do you remember all the games you could install in the TI 83?
Speaker 1:  Oh my God. Like a calculator's, a slippery slope. It
Speaker 6:  It is, it really is. It's a gateway
Speaker 1:  App. All right. But we're allowing a calculator. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Text messaging. Just like basic S-M-S-R-C-S text messaging.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  Okay. WhatsApp.
Speaker 6:  I like, I am just hearing Europe call
Speaker 6:  out like, yeah, they need WhatsApp. I feel like you should be able to
Speaker 6:  download a messaging app of your choice that feels
Speaker 6:  right.
Speaker 1:  All of them. One of them.
Speaker 6:  Oh my gosh. Well,
Speaker 1:  This is tricky, right? 'cause it's like, okay, if we're gonna allow you to
Speaker 1:  have WhatsApp, we should probably allow you to have Telegram. But then if
Speaker 1:  you have Telegram, we've just given you an entire social network and like
Speaker 1:  you can message in Instagram and that's gonna come up later. But I don't
Speaker 1:  think we wanna give people Instagram. Right? So it's like, this just gets
Speaker 1:  messy. But the reason I included WhatsApp is I think WhatsApp is, It is just
Speaker 1:  so thoroughly like the default messaging app for the world. Right. That we
Speaker 1:  kind of have to allow it,
Speaker 6:  It Okay. Yeah. I'll just have punt the question of other
Speaker 6:  apps. But WhatsApp we need, yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think I'm actually okay with no other messaging apps. Like, we're just
Speaker 1:  gonna let WhatsApp win the world. Yeah. Yeah. I don't feel great about it,
Speaker 1:  but it's, it's where we are. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I like it.
Speaker 1:  The next one is snapchat.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. Hmm.
Speaker 1:  I actually, I I will, I will foreshadow I struggled harder with Snapchat
Speaker 1:  than maybe any other one on this list. Really?
Speaker 6:  Oh.
Speaker 1:  'cause Snapchat to many people, including many young people who would really
Speaker 1:  benefit from a device like this one is their
Speaker 1:  communication system. It's like, it's, that's where they talk to all of their
Speaker 1:  friends. That's the, the like lifeline of their life. But then right next
Speaker 1:  to Snapchat, their Snapchat Discover, which has all the problems that we're
Speaker 1:  trying to avoid.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 1:  Messy.
Speaker 6:  It feels too close to the thing we're trying to Yeah. Get away from, which
Speaker 6:  is just the scrolling machine. I vote no Snapchat,
Speaker 6:  but maybe that's because I'm old and I am cranky
Speaker 6:  about Snapchat.
Speaker 1:  Well, I do think we just immediately lost the entire teen market with this,
Speaker 1:  with this plan, which is, it's not gonna be good for business, but sorry
Speaker 1:  teams, but, okay. I think we're, we're good. We're out on Snapchat. Go to
Speaker 1:  WhatsApp. I guess. You're welcome. We're just giving you, you go everything.
Speaker 1:  A web browser.
Speaker 6:  Ooh. That's tricky. I can, God,
Speaker 6:  that's so hard. Like, can you imagine walking around
Speaker 6:  and you think of a question, you can't look up the answer.
Speaker 1:  But also if we give you a web browser,
Speaker 1:  you kind of have access to everything else. Everything. We just made it very
Speaker 1:  slightly harder.
Speaker 6:  It's Pandora's box. Yeah. Yeah. I like, personally,
Speaker 6:  I would be fine with the web browser as the answer to like, do you in an
Speaker 6:  emergency need to call an Uber? Here's a crappy web browser. Type in
Speaker 6:  your, your, you know, credentials.
Speaker 6:  Can I vote for a web browser? But it's like kind of janky.
Speaker 1:  Oh, that's like a, like an e-reader style. Yeah. Web browser where like,
Speaker 1:  like you can use it if you need to. Yeah. But it's gonna suck. And you're
Speaker 1:  not gonna want to,
Speaker 6:  I did check emails on a, like first gen Kindle for
Speaker 6:  a while and it was the worst experience of my life. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  All right. I'm good with that. I was, I was also thinking maybe we do a web
Speaker 1:  browser, but we only white list like 10 domains.
Speaker 1:  Oh. So it's like, you can, you can use Wikipedia. You can do,
Speaker 1:  I don't know, you can do Google searches, but you can't
Speaker 1:  like go to most websites.
Speaker 6:  Mm.
Speaker 1:  This is probably a bad idea. But that was, that was my compromise. I know.
Speaker 1:  Theory.
Speaker 6:  I feel like I would just rely on like, the AI search results from Google
Speaker 6:  a lot and then I wouldn't like click through to the source
Speaker 6:  material. And that could be problematic.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's a dangerous game to force
Speaker 6:  On people. Yeah. I vote for full web browser, but it kind of sucks. So you
Speaker 6:  don't wanna use it
Speaker 1:  Like a, like a 2005 era web browser Yeah. Is what we're
Speaker 1:  offering you. Yeah. Alright. I'm good with that. It like, won't run any of
Speaker 1:  the web apps you want to do, but it will like show you text
Speaker 1:  on webpage, which is what we're after. Yes. Yeah. Okay. I'm good with that.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna call it Netscape Navigator. It's gonna be nuts. We
Speaker 6:  Love it.
Speaker 1:  Next one list is Spotify slash whatever music app you wanna pick.
Speaker 6:  Ooh. This is where the minimalist phones fall apart for me. 'cause
Speaker 6:  I'm like, I don't have physical media anymore.
Speaker 6:  Bless all of you. Who do? And you held onto that. That's incredible. I just
Speaker 6:  turned my soul over to Spotify, so I'm like, a phone that doesn't have Spotify
Speaker 6:  doesn't work for me. Really? So for me personally, I
Speaker 6:  vote yes for Spotify, but I don't know if that, does it
Speaker 6:  violate the, the minimalist phone ethos once you invite
Speaker 6:  Spotify in?
Speaker 1:  I don't think it does, honestly. This one's actually fairly easy for me,
Speaker 1:  for the same exact reason. Like Spotify music and
Speaker 1:  podcasts are probably the things I do most often. Like measured
Speaker 1:  by time on my phone. And there's a
Speaker 1:  thing, like in talking to the, the light phone folks, they've been thinking
Speaker 1:  like, okay, is there a way we can take, you know, part of the Spotify
Speaker 1:  experience and like, what if you could just sync a playlist and there was
Speaker 1:  like that mighty device that was the same kind of thing that it would keep
Speaker 1:  one of your playlists in sync. So I think there might be something Yeah.
Speaker 1:  There, like give me very simple
Speaker 1:  sort of old school iPod level access Yeah. To my Spotify library. But nothing
Speaker 1:  else like
Speaker 6:  A widget. Like just gimme a widget. Yeah. Where it kind of
Speaker 6:  sucks, like searching around for stuff, but you can find it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But I agree. I think if you want a phone like this to
Speaker 1:  actually work for people, it's gotta have a music app.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. It's kind of the WhatsApp of music apps.
Speaker 1:  I had a really funny experience with the light phone three 'cause they have
Speaker 1:  a music app, but you have to upload MP threes and
Speaker 1:  like you, I just don't have a local music collection anymore. Yeah. So I
Speaker 1:  literally was like digging around on my computer to find any MP three
Speaker 1:  file. Yeah. I could to upload to this thing just so I could test it out.
Speaker 1:  And I was like, my God, IIII have a hard drive full of
Speaker 1:  local music somewhere in this house. And I, for the life of me couldn't tell
Speaker 1:  you where It is or what's on it.
Speaker 6:  No. Did you have that U2 album that Apple
Speaker 6:  put on everyone's phone?
Speaker 1:  That, that lives on a phone that I will never touch again and refuse
Speaker 1:  to acknowledge.
Speaker 6:  Okay. That's fair.
Speaker 1:  Maybe that's what we do here. It is. Just once a month our minimalist phone
Speaker 1:  just gives you an album. Yeah. That's what, and you have listen that album
Speaker 1:  for the next,
Speaker 6:  You better like it.
Speaker 1:  Exactly. All right, next on my list is email. This one seems
Speaker 1:  easy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. You need, I need email.
Speaker 1:  Oh, interesting. I think it's easy. The other way really, I think if we're
Speaker 1:  trying to do a minimalist smartphone, the very first thing we should take
Speaker 1:  away from people is the hell of their email app. Oh
Speaker 6:  God. Yeah. I guess people who don't live
Speaker 6:  so online probably,
Speaker 1:  And let's be honest, we could both stand to be a little less online that
Speaker 6:  It would probably be Okay, this
Speaker 1:  Is what we're trying to do here.
Speaker 6:  I'm trying to think of an email that would like,
Speaker 6:  I would cause real problems for me if I didn't check it in real
Speaker 6:  time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I, okay. I vote no email. Email sucks. I
Speaker 6:  hate it.
Speaker 1:  I I do think the, the the thing you just did in your brain is
Speaker 1:  what I do with every one of these. Yeah. Where like, I'm like, oh my God,
Speaker 1:  what if something horrible happens and I have to know about it? Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  it's like, oh, that's almost certainly never gonna happen. And phone
Speaker 1:  calls exist. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, a useful societal thing is like, if, if something urgent is happening,
Speaker 1:  call me on the phone. Yeah. I'm good with that.
Speaker 6:  There was a time before email and no, nobody
Speaker 6:  died. Like from lack of email. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. I agree with that. All right, good. So no email, we're out on
Speaker 1:  email. Some kind of note taking app.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. We
Speaker 1:  Need that. Either one that we make or your favorite. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And that could be fun 'cause you know, it's not
Speaker 6:  distracting to take notes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I agree. Okay. Are we, are we like, are we building our own
Speaker 1:  like minimalist one or are we just like, listen up losers,
Speaker 1:  here's notion on our minimalist
Speaker 6:  Phone. Oh my gosh. A notion Phone is the whole thing. I'm
Speaker 6:  gonna have to contemplate Now.
Speaker 1:  People would, people would buy a notion phone. I'm, I would buy a
Speaker 6:  Notion phone. Okay. That's another podcast.
Speaker 6:  I think, you know, it could be basic. It could just be like text,
Speaker 6:  put the text in. Save it for later. Move on with your life.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  I, the only one I'll add to that is I also want voice notes. Yeah. So just
Speaker 1:  basic typing. Yeah. Let me, let me talk to my notes. Nothing else. We'll
Speaker 1:  worry about the rest of it when I get back to my computer. Right. But yeah,
Speaker 1:  I agree. You gotta have something, a re a dedicated
Speaker 1:  reading app, whether it's like a Kindle or like Pocket or whatever.
Speaker 1:  Just some place I have to read stuff. Should I be reading things on this,
Speaker 1:  this device?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I would like that. 'cause then if you, if this is kind of like a secondary
Speaker 6:  device, you could kind of sync that up and then it's there for you.
Speaker 6:  Is this, have we just invented the BS Palmer?
Speaker 1:  I mean, a little, but the, I, I'm actually, I struggled with this one more
Speaker 1:  than I expected to because on the one hand
Speaker 1:  I, I read a ton on my phone and that's like a thing I'd like to do. That
Speaker 1:  I think is mostly an additive activity. And I think that's fine. On the other
Speaker 1:  hand, part of what we're trying to do with this whole genre of phones
Speaker 1:  is get people looking at their screens less. Yeah. So I'm like, is the answer
Speaker 1:  go by physical books? 'cause I don't, I don't love that. But
Speaker 1:  I don't know, I'm so torn. Like, it's such a screen time debate
Speaker 1:  here. Right? Like, is our goal to get you to use your screen time better?
Speaker 1:  Or is our goal to get you to not look at your screen?
Speaker 6:  What if you can only sync up like, like
Speaker 6:  nutritious, meaty articles. Like you can't
Speaker 6:  be reading any crap on your phone or a book.
Speaker 6:  I don't
Speaker 1:  Know. That's, that's fun. I think we maybe do, it's a reading app, but
Speaker 1:  it's only books. And if you wanna read trashy books, that is up to you. But
Speaker 1:  I think like, I, I like the idea that we are going to like heavily incentivize
Speaker 1:  book reading. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Read books on your minimalist phone. I, I'm into it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right. Okay. But it will not be the Kindle app because the Kindle app sucks
Speaker 1:  and we will not put it on our phone. Yeah. Okay. I have four games for you
Speaker 1:  in a row and we are gonna litigate each one. Are you ready? Okay.
Speaker 1:  The first one is the New York Times Games app. So crossword. Absolutely.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I was just playing it
Speaker 6:  before we got on here, so Yeah. Gotta
Speaker 1:  Have it. Okay. Sold. I'm in too. Candy Crush?
Speaker 6:  No, no Candy Crush.
Speaker 1:  Why not?
Speaker 6:  I don't know. It feels wrong. It feels like the, can you
Speaker 6:  read a book versus can you just read any old thing on
Speaker 6:  the internet?
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna tell people what to do with their lives. This
Speaker 1:  Is the thing. Oh my gosh, I'm so glad you said that. I've gone back and forth
Speaker 1:  on this a thousand times because on the one hand I'm like, what I'm doing
Speaker 1:  is basically moralizing for you in the form of a smartphone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But then on the other hand, that is a little bit the job. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like,
Speaker 1:  I think part of third of the existence of these devices is Yeah. People like
Speaker 1:  you and me being like, I I am helpless in front of my
Speaker 1:  phone. Right. And I think, I think many of us are in like very real
Speaker 1:  scientifically provable ways. We are losing the battle to our
Speaker 1:  phones. And if, if somebody on the other side can like,
Speaker 1:  have my interest in mind in a realer way, maybe that's okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And so maybe our job is to tell people how to spend their time a little
Speaker 1:  bit here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You're kind of buying into like an ethos almost.
Speaker 6:  Or like, that's kind of the vibe I think. Like, you go to the light phone
Speaker 6:  website and it, it's all almost like, you know, the
Speaker 6:  humane shtick without, you know, lasers and AI
Speaker 6:  where it's sort, it's sort of beautiful and simple. You're like, I would
Speaker 6:  like that in the things that go along with it. Which maybe means I can't
Speaker 6:  play Candy Crush, but I can play Wordle. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I'm, I'm good with that. I do feel like I cannot prove this, but I feel
Speaker 1:  like Wordle is better for your soul and mind than Candy Crush.
Speaker 6:  I think so. I think so.
Speaker 1:  If, if anyone has done a study on that, please let me know. I would very
Speaker 1:  much like to hear it. Okay. Two more games. And I suspect
Speaker 1:  I will know the answer to both of these based on what you just said about
Speaker 1:  Candy Crush. TRO is next. Just because I love TRO and I wanna play
Speaker 1:  it all the time. Oh, but I don't think we should put it
Speaker 6:  On here. I say no. Okay. Having never played it for a second, I say no.
Speaker 1:  You both should because it's awesome and shouldn't because it will ruin
Speaker 1:  your life. It is, yeah. I'm, I'm, I'm not exaggerating. It
Speaker 1:  is the only thing I have ever done straight from the minute I sat down
Speaker 1:  on a plane to the minute I got off of the plane. Oh, wow. Just one.
Speaker 1:  It was like a four hour flight and I did it every single second of the flight
Speaker 1:  without putting my phone down. And literally we landed and I was like, well,
Speaker 1:  we're here already. And it was a real moment of like, oh, I can't play this
Speaker 1:  game anymore.
Speaker 6:  Okay. It is not, not, I'll save it for a flight. I'll try it out when I need
Speaker 6:  to fly cross country.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Sometime when you're like, I can't do anything for eight hours anyway.
Speaker 1:  Just play Bellara. Okay. And the last one is Fortnite, which I think is
Speaker 1:  Yeah. An obvious no for the same reasons.
Speaker 6:  Can't have it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Alright. Good. Moving on. A Maps app,
Speaker 1:  Google Maps, apple Maps, whichever one you want it to be. That feels like
Speaker 1:  we need that, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Okay. I would need navigation for sure.
Speaker 1:  All right. Good. Easy calendar. This one's a little email ish to me.
Speaker 1:  Right? I see pros and cons.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well, I do wanna know what day It is. So I vote for
Speaker 6:  a calendar that tells you what day It is. Should it
Speaker 6:  sync up to my work calendar is what
Speaker 6:  I would not want.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Maybe it's just like a, it's like a
Speaker 6:  paper calendar, but in app form where you
Speaker 6:  can like, oh, I like that. Maybe you add stuff to it.
Speaker 6:  But it does, it, it's just there, it just sits there. It doesn't just like
Speaker 6:  writing on a paper calendar,
Speaker 1:  You can't do anything with it. Yeah. It's just, it's just a calendar.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There was this thing we were chatting about for a minute
Speaker 6:  on Slack that was like, some company mate is called like paper
Speaker 6:  apps and it's like,
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  Everything has come back full circle where it, it's so cute. It's like they
Speaker 6:  have a golf game or something that you play, like you get the
Speaker 6:  little notebook and, but I'm like, oh, a notepad is
Speaker 6:  a paper app because that's, that's like how
Speaker 6:  it worked anyway. It gets so dumb so fast. But
Speaker 6:  it's cute. I like it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I'm into it. My pitch for this would be that we find some clever way to
Speaker 1:  combine it with the note taking app so that you can like, add
Speaker 1:  stuff to your calendar and know that it will go to your calendar, but
Speaker 1:  you can't actually look at your calendar.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Or at least you can't like, interact with your calendar in some way. Right.
Speaker 1:  Right. Because I think there's something to, like, knowing your next appointment
Speaker 1:  is fine, but I don't wanna be able to like open up and move
Speaker 1:  things around in my calendar on this device that feels, that feels wrong
Speaker 1:  for what we're trying to do here. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like read only.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And like pretty, and not Yeah. Gross.
Speaker 1:  Nice. And like maybe only shows me two events at a time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. You may only know two things at a time.
Speaker 1:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Next up some kind of video chat service,
Speaker 1:  FaceTime, zoom, meet all of them or one of them, whatever you want. But
Speaker 1:  something for video chat.
Speaker 6:  I vote No. Really? I think, yeah, I think you have to
Speaker 6:  talk on the phone or go to your computer.
Speaker 1:  Okay. My, my worry for this strategy would be, it's
Speaker 1:  possible that video chat has like crossed the line
Speaker 1:  into it's as important. Like, it might be as important as phone calls
Speaker 1:  and text messages.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I don't feel like it's all the way there, but It is. It is. It feels like
Speaker 1:  it's getting closer and closer every day. And so my worry is if we don't
Speaker 1:  allow this, there's just a bunch of people who are like, well then of course
Speaker 1:  I'm never buying this. Yeah. In the same way that if we don't have WhatsApp,
Speaker 1:  we've just instantly ruled out lots of people for whom this doesn't work
Speaker 1:  anymore. I don't know about video chat
Speaker 6:  Though. I know the other side of the coin is when you're like, I
Speaker 6:  can't, sorry, I can't video chat you, we can call on the phone.
Speaker 6:  That's kind of a relief. You're like, yeah, you get a little
Speaker 6:  vacation from like doing Zooms or Google meets or
Speaker 6:  whatever. So maybe it's a a little bit of like a
Speaker 6:  you're choosing this and it's
Speaker 6:  healthier for you. Question mark.
Speaker 1:  No, I I actually, I totally agree with that. You've, you've just swayed me.
Speaker 1:  'cause I think a again, we're talking about a phone you're not supposed to
Speaker 1:  stare at all day. Yeah. And b we do all
Speaker 1:  spend too much time looking at our own faces. Yeah. It's like not healthy.
Speaker 6:  We're all secretly like looking for a break from that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All right. I'm in no video chat, but maybe, maybe it has a thing where
Speaker 1:  people can, like, you can click on a Zoom link, but it'll just add you as
Speaker 1:  audio only. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I'm trying to, like, the big question with all of these is like, how do you
Speaker 1:  integrate with all the stuff people actually need to use, but in a less
Speaker 1:  gross way? Yeah. And I kind of like the idea of like, it has all the video
Speaker 1:  chat apps, but audio only.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I like that. That
Speaker 1:  Would work for me. Okay. I also, can I just tell you, this is just a random
Speaker 1:  thing. The this light phone beautiful little lovely device.
Speaker 1:  It's very sharp up here.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 1:  No. It's when I hold it against my face to make phone calls, it like kind
Speaker 1:  of hurts my ears after a while. I really like this phone, but I don't
Speaker 1:  love really long phone calls on it.
Speaker 6:  It hurts as a phone. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Not, not exactly what you're going for anyway. All right. We got a bunch
Speaker 1:  more. Let's keep going. A few of these I think are gonna be easy. So this
Speaker 1:  will be fun. A built-in AI chatbot of some kind.
Speaker 1:  Chatt, Claude Gemini. Pick your favorite. This goes back, I think to the
Speaker 1:  same thing as web browsers, which is like, what do you do if you have a question?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, I vote. No, I vote you
Speaker 6:  if you need your clot or whatever, put it in the web browser and go talk
Speaker 6:  to it there.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I I, I agree with you, but I just wanna play devil's advocate for one
Speaker 1:  second because I think there is a case to be made that
Speaker 1:  you could ditch half the other apps we've allowed and replace
Speaker 1:  them all with a pretty good chat bot. Like something that can,
Speaker 1:  can remember things for me that can take notes down for me, that can find
Speaker 1:  information for me is actually in a certain way, like what
Speaker 1:  we're going for here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's like we're, we've just like invented the whole premise of
Speaker 6:  AI on phones. Exactly. Where it's like, yeah. Ab abstract
Speaker 6:  all that away. The chat bot will just take care of it for you. But
Speaker 6:  the, the reality right now is you ask it to do a math equation instead of
Speaker 6:  having a calculator. Right. Rolling the dice. Whether that is
Speaker 1:  True,
Speaker 6:  You're gonna get the right answer or not.
Speaker 1:  That is true. Maybe when we do this exercise in like four or five years,
Speaker 1:  it'll be really different. Yeah. But right now the idea of replacing my calculator
Speaker 1:  app with Claude seems terrifying. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I know.
Speaker 1:  But I do think you're right. Like spiritually they're a perfect fit. This
Speaker 1:  idea of, of like, now I have a device that I don't have to look at all day.
Speaker 1:  And so it can actually like be redesigned around the fact that I don't have
Speaker 1:  to look at all that at all day and I can just talk to it and it does things
Speaker 1:  for me. Sounds awesome. Super duper doesn't work.
Speaker 6:  So somewhere the founders of Humane are just screaming
Speaker 6:  to void. They're like, you wanted this.
Speaker 1:  They're like, if it had worked, we'd still be here.
Speaker 6:  I know.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. Didn't work. Nope. All right. So we're not allowing that.
Speaker 1:  TikTok, I assume is just a No, we're out on TikTok.
Speaker 6:  No TikTok. No. Can't have it.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Cap cut for making videos?
Speaker 6:  Mm. No, I vote No, but I think like
Speaker 6:  maybe some kind of system where if you record a video with your
Speaker 6:  minimalist phone, it can go somewhere. So you could
Speaker 6:  make it, but I don't know, as soon as you have that knowledge of like, oh,
Speaker 6:  I should record this. It could be a TikTok. It changes your whole,
Speaker 6:  like mo when you're out and about. 'cause I'm
Speaker 6:  constantly like, I should take a picture of that. It'd be funny on Instagram
Speaker 6:  or whatever. Totally. And maybe we wanna get away with that away from it.
Speaker 6:  I vote no.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I think I'm out too. And I think there's definitely a,
Speaker 1:  a sort of line in the sand here somewhere where it's like, if this activity
Speaker 1:  on your phone is gonna take you longer than X amount of time, it's
Speaker 1:  a, it's a computer task. Yeah. Or an iPad task or like when you get home
Speaker 1:  task or whatever. And I think that is like, that's one of the things the
Speaker 1:  light folks have really tried to figure out is like, how long can we make
Speaker 1:  you use this device before? Actually we're just defeating the whole purpose.
Speaker 1:  And the answer is, go use the device that you bought to do things with. Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I think there's, there's something, there's something in there. And I
Speaker 1:  think cap cut. You're probably right. Like if you wanna spend an hour editing
Speaker 1:  a video, you shouldn't do that on our minimalist phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly. You
Speaker 1:  Should do it on an iPhone. iPhones will continue to exist until our company
Speaker 1:  takes over the world. Great. Of minimalist smartphones. Yeah. It's gonna
Speaker 1:  be great. Alright, I have a few more then. Then I'm gonna let you out of
Speaker 1:  this horrible exercise. Okay. Instagram I think is a, no, we Right. We're
Speaker 1:  out on Instagram. Instagram. The messaging thing is a little tough, but we'll
Speaker 1:  live. Yeah. Look, look at your memes somewhere else.
Speaker 1:  Duolingo.
Speaker 6:  Oh man. I do need my Duolingo.
Speaker 1:  Duolingo is both like incredibly problematic because it's all about streaks
Speaker 1:  and it pests you all the time. And It is like designed to be addictive, but
Speaker 1:  It is also in a certain way. Like, good for you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Oh man, that's a tough one. It's
Speaker 6:  another, yeah, because like
Speaker 6:  feasibly, I could go through a whole day with this phone. Like, it feels
Speaker 6:  like a phone I should be able to go through a whole day with. And if I
Speaker 6:  have to use a streak freeze because I was using my
Speaker 6:  minimalist and I'll be pissed.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I feel like there should be some access to Duolingo, but maybe
Speaker 6:  it can't bother me.
Speaker 1:  Oh, that's a, okay. That's a good one. Duolingo. But no, well, I think this
Speaker 1:  phone in general does not allow push notifications. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Except no, no push notifications. It can alert you when someone is calling
Speaker 1:  you on the phone. And I think that's the only notification allowed.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Agreed.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah. Duolingo I think might actually be like the
Speaker 1:  perfect summation of why this is such a hard problem to solve because It
Speaker 1:  is both like, It is so problematic in so many ways. But
Speaker 1:  like you just said, It is, it's, It is like a core part of many
Speaker 1:  people's day-to-day lives. Yeah. And not having it becomes a total non-starter.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Which again, a kudos to Duolingo for pulling that off with a language
Speaker 1:  learning app. Good god. But It is, It is a strange thing. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Alright. YouTube, I think we're, we're definitely not allowing YouTube.
Speaker 6:  No. YouTube.
Speaker 1:  I think we just don't want you watching videos on this phone. Like, I think
Speaker 1:  that's fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Read an article
Speaker 1:  Or just like, don't look at your phone.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 1:  That's fine too.
Speaker 6:  I am envisioning myself, like I'm trying to fix something in my house on
Speaker 6:  my own, which is a bad idea to start with. Oh, interesting. But then I'm
Speaker 6:  like, I need to find the YouTube video of however you do this. But
Speaker 6:  if I'm in my house, I can go on a computer. I'm not like out
Speaker 6:  in the world trying to fix, like put up a shelf on someone's wall.
Speaker 1:  Well, we're also allowing the terrible web browser so it'll play. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It'll play the YouTube video. It'll look bad. Yes. And maybe it only plays
Speaker 1:  at like eight frames per second. But it
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  In a pinch it works. So I think, I think that as a workaround I don't love,
Speaker 1:  but I can live with.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Yeah. Me too.
Speaker 1:  But I definitely don't think we have a YouTube app that's No. That violates
Speaker 1:  all of our rules. Yeah. Okay. And I think Netflix, same thing. No Netflix.
Speaker 1:  No Netflix. You have plenty of other places to watch Netflix. Don't do it
Speaker 1:  on your phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Watch a tv.
Speaker 1:  Right. Some kind of file storage app, Dropbox, Google Drive.
Speaker 1:  Pick your favorite.
Speaker 6:  Oh man. I'm just thinking about how annoying the iPhone
Speaker 6:  is to deal with as soon as you need to get a file off of it. It's true. And
Speaker 6:  it feels like we fought so hard just to have a files app on the
Speaker 6:  iPhone. I don't wanna not have it, but maybe you
Speaker 6:  can like sync stuff to Google Drive if you have to.
Speaker 6:  Does that make sense?
Speaker 1:  Okay. So you can't like access your Google Drive, but you can send something
Speaker 1:  to Google Drive.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I'm good with that. We can, we can do that with the API like a Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like a, it's you, you hit a backup button and it goes straight to Google
Speaker 1:  Drive, but you can't see all the files in your Google Drive. Yeah. All right.
Speaker 1:  I'm good with that. I can work with that.
Speaker 1:  Uber slash Lyft,
Speaker 6:  It could be the web browser thing, but
Speaker 1:  I actually think you need something with like real phone level
Speaker 1:  access. Yeah. That's like an app that is always on that can
Speaker 1:  do the, you know, really fine location stuff. This is one of those that
Speaker 1:  I'm like, I, I don't actually use Uber and Lyft all that
Speaker 1:  often in my day to day, but the idea of not having it as an option
Speaker 1:  feels like a problem. Yeah. So I think, I think I would need it.
Speaker 6:  I would too. Yeah. It's like a, a lifeline where I'm like,
Speaker 6:  well if everything goes south here calling Uber.
Speaker 1:  Right. And It is, It is a tool you expect to have available to you. And they
Speaker 1:  have a bunch of weird workarounds. Like I think you can call on the phone
Speaker 1:  and get an Uber. Oh, that's cute. And they have some of the like chat bot
Speaker 1:  integration stuff. But I think, I think we need the Uber app. I'm okay with
Speaker 1:  that. Yeah. And that's also not really an app you like hang out in anyway.
Speaker 1:  No. So I'm not, I'm not super bothered by it. If they
Speaker 6:  Like gamify the Uber app, I'll be so annoyed.
Speaker 1:  You know, they want, you know, they wanna Yeah. Somebody in there is like,
Speaker 1:  how do we Duolingo the Uber
Speaker 6:  App? Oh, I had to use a streak phrase on my Uber app.
Speaker 6:  God. Yeah. It's nightmare.
Speaker 1:  Dara, if you're listening, that's not a good idea. Don't do that. Please
Speaker 6:  Don't do it.
Speaker 1:  All right. I got two more
Speaker 1:  Slack slash Teams. Feels like if we're not allowing email, we cannot
Speaker 1:  allow Slack and Teams.
Speaker 6:  No. Get outta here. Slack and teams. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Okay, good. I'm, I'm glad we're on the same team. Last one.
Speaker 1:  Venmo slash cash app slash some way to send money. Does this
Speaker 1:  matter? Do we need this?
Speaker 6:  Can you can web browser that right? I'm trying to think of like, you can,
Speaker 6:  I went to a thing this weekend where we like
Speaker 6:  painted these little figurines. It was like called Art club and we
Speaker 6:  paid through Venmo. I'm like, I'd wanna be able to do that.
Speaker 6:  But Yeah, you have the camera, you scan the thing, you log in.
Speaker 6:  I say web browser for this one.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah. And that's one you can, you can kind of work around a crappy
Speaker 1:  experience.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Do we have tap to pay though?
Speaker 1:  Oh, because
Speaker 6:  I want that.
Speaker 1:  I didn't even have that on the list, but I think we need to.
Speaker 6:  But then you have a whole, do you have a wallet and then
Speaker 6:  do you have the Capital One app?
Speaker 6:  I don't know.
Speaker 1:  You just eventually end up recreating the pixel. Like there just is no way
Speaker 1:  to do this without accidentally making a pixel.
Speaker 6:  Yep. It's true. But
Speaker 1:  No, you need tap to pay.
Speaker 6:  I think you need tap to pay
Speaker 1:  Crap.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Here's our tap to pay rule one, no
Speaker 1:  one credit card.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You gotta pick, you pick one,
Speaker 1:  You can have a transit cards, whatever, but you get one credit card.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That feels, that feels necessary. 'cause otherwise, otherwise you end up
Speaker 1:  down too many weird rabbit holes.
Speaker 6:  Right. And you can like log onto our
Speaker 6:  like web portal on your computer to
Speaker 6:  upload your credit card credentials or something,
Speaker 6:  you know, encrypted, blah blah blah. It'll be
Speaker 1:  Great. Yeah. Our security is topnotch on this platform. It's so good. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Don't even, don't even worry about that. We've got it covered.
Speaker 1:  All right. Well, is there, that's my whole list. Is there anything else?
Speaker 1:  I forgot If we're building our, our perfect minimalist smartphone. Mm.
Speaker 1:  Anything else we desperately need that we don't have?
Speaker 6:  We're doing like alarms and stuff. Right? That's just like baked
Speaker 6:  into a Yeah,
Speaker 1:  That that like the thing shows the time, so it has to kind of
Speaker 1:  do alarms and timers. Like I, I feel good about that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Okay. I, I think I could live,
Speaker 6:  I could get through a day with this phone and it wouldn't give me a panic
Speaker 6:  attack too much.
Speaker 1:  Is it weird that, that that actually feels like the bar? Yeah. Right. Like
Speaker 1:  I'm good with that. I think it's, it's been a really interesting thing. 'cause
Speaker 1:  I think like talking to all the folks who make these minimalist phones, they're
Speaker 1:  basically trying to figure out how to make a phone that is
Speaker 1:  so different from all the other things that it doesn't just seem like a worse
Speaker 1:  version of your phone. But actually maybe what we need is just a worse version
Speaker 1:  of our phones.
Speaker 6:  I keep coming back to like a cellular
Speaker 6:  smartwatch is the minimalist phone in like,
Speaker 6:  you put in some earbuds, you've got your, your little
Speaker 6:  like crappy phone on your wrist, you're good to go. And then
Speaker 6:  when you, you know, you can just leave the house without the thing. The
Speaker 6:  only thing is you, you know, you don't have the camera, you know, it kind
Speaker 6:  of breaks down pretty quickly to wear like maybe there is room for
Speaker 6:  a thing that's like phone shaped. But yeah, I think
Speaker 6:  for me that's where I keep getting into this loop with
Speaker 6:  the minimalist phone is like, well it's gonna be missing this or that.
Speaker 6:  That's on the watch that I usually have on anyway.
Speaker 6:  Why wouldn't I just use the watch if I wanted
Speaker 6:  a break from my phone?
Speaker 1:  There have been all these rumors about an Apple watch with a camera
Speaker 1:  being kind of in the labs in Cupertino right now. And
Speaker 1:  I have gone from thinking that is an absurd, ridiculous idea to being like,
Speaker 1:  maybe that's actually the only thing between me and
Speaker 1:  being able to use just my watch for really long stretches of time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but how do you take a picture of, do you do
Speaker 6:  like, here we go. Yeah. No, they say geez.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Maybe this is just the, just have
Speaker 6:  a camera on you moment. Like
Speaker 1:  Maybe
Speaker 6:  We, we invented this thing actually it used to not be part of a, it's like
Speaker 6:  paper apps. Like Yeah. We do just have paper
Speaker 6:  that exists.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We're pretty, we're pretty good at paper now it turns out.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Alright, well Allison, thank you for doing this with me. If, if we missed
Speaker 1:  anything, if, if there's something on your list that you're screaming about
Speaker 1:  that you need in your mail, mil smartphone, tell us the hotline is 8 6 6.
Speaker 1:  First one one. The email is Vergecast at the v.com. Alison,
Speaker 1:  thank you very much. This is super fun.
Speaker 6:  Thank you. This is great.
Speaker 7:  Alright,
Speaker 1:  We gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk
Speaker 1:  Tesla. We're gonna talk tariffs and we're gonna talk about what in the world
Speaker 1:  is happening with cars. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Andy Hawkins is here. Hi Andy. Hi. How
Speaker 1:  are things?
Speaker 11:  Things are good. You know, it's, we're, we're out here, we're,
Speaker 11:  we're watching these protests, these Tesla protests. I assume
Speaker 11:  that's what I'm here to talk about now. It, I
Speaker 1:  In large part I think I, I have, I I just galaxy brand
Speaker 1:  myself into many corners with all this Tesla stuff. So we're gonna do a little
Speaker 1:  bit of that. But let's start with the protest this week because yes, this
Speaker 1:  weekend was, it was a big moment in the sort of
Speaker 1:  official Tesla Takedown universe of protests. Like what, just sort
Speaker 1:  of walk me through what happened this weekend.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, so these protests, they started, I, I guess you could say
Speaker 11:  two months ago, early February I think is when we started seeing some of
Speaker 11:  the first ones, people sort of sort of showing up outside of Tesla
Speaker 11:  showrooms and at charging stations and registering their
Speaker 11:  opposition to Elon Musk and to Doge and to the sort of
Speaker 11:  ransacking of the federal government. And they grew over
Speaker 11:  time and they, we started to see larger and larger crowds
Speaker 11:  and cities all across the country. And, and
Speaker 11:  then eventually they decided they needed to get organized. And that was,
Speaker 11:  I think that was sort of like the most interesting thing to me was this
Speaker 11:  was very much a, a bottom up grassroots effort.
Speaker 11:  Very much. There was not really sort of any like national leader to these
Speaker 11:  protests. And they, they sort of realized that that was not really sort
Speaker 11:  of a tenable situation. They needed to get organized. So they sort of got
Speaker 11:  together, there's been some various kind of, you know,
Speaker 11:  pro-democracy, left-leaning progressive groups that have been
Speaker 11:  sort of like involved on the margins, indivisible and a and a
Speaker 11:  few others. And so they decided to get together and sort of hold a
Speaker 11:  mobilizing effort and targeting this one date
Speaker 11:  March 29th, which was last Saturday as sort of their global day of action.
Speaker 11:  They were just like, everybody needs to come out. We need to hit every Tesla
Speaker 11:  location in the country. Let's hit some in Europe as well in Canada. And
Speaker 11:  really have like a show of force to let sort of like send the message that
Speaker 11:  this is like a, a sustained protest and effort to really, you know, send
Speaker 11:  the message that Elon Musk and and Doge are on their hit list, I guess you
Speaker 11:  could say. So Saturday was the day we sent reporters out
Speaker 11:  to as many of these protests as we possibly could. I think we hit almost
Speaker 11:  a dozen of them in London and in New York and
Speaker 11:  New Jersey, Washington dc Ohio,
Speaker 11:  Florida, Texas, California. Yeah. And
Speaker 11:  what we saw was sort of, you know, sort of like what we've been seeing for
Speaker 11:  the last few months now, which is a lot of clever
Speaker 11:  signs, a lot of illusions to fascism and to
Speaker 11:  Nazism and to, you know, photographs of Musk making his
Speaker 11:  fascist salute at the inauguration and, and a sustain,
Speaker 11:  you know, I think an effort largely the, the overall, the broader effort
Speaker 11:  was, you know, to to sort of toxify the the Tesla brand and to drive their
Speaker 11:  sales down, which was something that we heard from talking to these protestors.
Speaker 1:  Right. And it, it seems like, I think in,
Speaker 1:  in an effort to make this a moment, the the movement seems
Speaker 1:  to have succeeded, right? Like I, I feel like I saw coverage of this everywhere,
Speaker 1:  that if if the goal was to pick a moment to make this a big
Speaker 1:  story, this sort of loose collection of protests,
Speaker 1:  it seems to have worked.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I mean they've gotten the, the attention of the targets of the protest,
Speaker 11:  right? Like Elon Musk and Donald Trump have both
Speaker 11:  come out and made several statements
Speaker 11:  about not just the protest necessarily. They, they've been focusing more
Speaker 11:  on the, on the, the, the violent acts and the vandalism, which is
Speaker 11:  understandable from their position that that's what they would be focused
Speaker 11:  on. But what we definitely heard from the protesters was that this was a
Speaker 11:  peaceful movement. This was a non-violent movement. They do not
Speaker 11:  condone any of the, of the vandalism and the arson that's taken
Speaker 11:  place. They see that as something that's separate to their movement.
Speaker 11:  But obviously I, I would say on the Musk and the Trump side, there's an
Speaker 11:  effort to tie those things together. And so, you know,
Speaker 11:  that's where we got Trump talking about charges of domestic terrorism, although
Speaker 11:  we have yet to see anyone be charged with domestic terrorism, yet there
Speaker 11:  have been arrests of people who have been charged with setting fires and
Speaker 11:  defacing Tesla property, but none of these actual terrorism
Speaker 11:  charges quite yet. That may be difficult to actually accomplish. And then
Speaker 11:  maybe you had Musk on, on Fox last week talking about, you know, going
Speaker 11:  after people who are pushing Tesla propaganda. He, he said, right.
Speaker 11:  So I, it's clear that they have their attention and I think that that is,
Speaker 11:  it's been galvanizing for the protesters. I think that they feel that they're
Speaker 11:  succeeding because they have Musk's attention.
Speaker 1:  Well, and it's, it's been really interesting to watch the folks engaged
Speaker 1:  in these protests try to explain what It is that they're protesting.
Speaker 1:  Because on the one hand, this is all pointed at Tesla, right?
Speaker 1:  They're going to Tesla showrooms, they're going to Tesla buildings and protesting
Speaker 1:  Tesla. It's called Tesla Takedown. Like that is the thing that they're doing.
Speaker 1:  But it's not about Tesla. This is like very specifically pointed
Speaker 1:  at Elon Musk. And I think a to some extent that has
Speaker 1:  worked, right? Like you, you mentioned the Fox News interview he did, and
Speaker 1:  he basically goes on TV and is like sort of Weebly saying, my businesses
Speaker 1:  are struggling like that. I I assume that's what these protestors are after,
Speaker 1:  right? Like that that is the goal is you want, you want him to feel it at
Speaker 1:  the end of the process. But I, I do continue to wonder
Speaker 1:  is, is pointing all of this energy at Tesla the right way
Speaker 1:  to get to Elon Musk, does that seem like It is working for these protesters
Speaker 1:  because they're not mad at Tesla nearly in the same way that they're mad
Speaker 1:  at the guy who runs Tesla, right? Or am I, am I overstating the Elon Musk?
Speaker 1:  No,
Speaker 11:  No. I, I I don't, I no, I I think, I think you're right about that. They
Speaker 11:  are mad at Elon Musk. And I think the understanding is that Tesla is sort
Speaker 11:  of the unfortunate, you know, byproduct of the, what they have to do, right?
Speaker 11:  Because his wealth and his power are very much
Speaker 11:  linked to Tesla. His o ownership of, you know, around
Speaker 11:  13% of Tesla stock is sort of what comprises the
Speaker 11:  bulk of his net worth, right? And It is what, you know, he's had to sell
Speaker 11:  Tesla stock in order to fund the purchase of Twitter. You know, that's sort
Speaker 11:  of how he leverages his power is through his ownership stake in
Speaker 11:  Tesla. And so yes, Tesla is sort of just what they have to, they
Speaker 11:  have to focus on, right? This is a boycott, it's a, an effort to drive
Speaker 11:  sales down, to convince people to sell their Teslas,
Speaker 11:  to make the, the used market of Tesla, you know, sort of chaotic to,
Speaker 11:  and ultimately to affect his ownership and his net worth of
Speaker 11:  the company. I I don't think any of the folks that you would encounter out
Speaker 11:  there at these protests would say that they are opposed the idea of electric
Speaker 11:  cars or the furtherance of, of electric car sales. And you see some people
Speaker 11:  with signs that say, we don't, we like electric cars, we just don't like
Speaker 11:  Tesla. Right? And so that, that is sort of the, the, the, the
Speaker 11:  ultimate mission here. It's not to, to, I think to sink the
Speaker 11:  electric car market, but in some ways, obviously Tesla is a
Speaker 11:  huge chunk of the electric car market, but It is, It is
Speaker 11:  specifically about making the Tesla stock price go down
Speaker 11:  and making Elon Musk's net worth and thus his political power diminished.
Speaker 1:  I mean that's, that's the piece of the, the sort of cognitive dissonance
Speaker 1:  of all of this that just continues to blow my mind. Like my overarching
Speaker 1:  assumption would be that the people protesting outside of Tesla
Speaker 1:  showrooms this weekend were the exact same demographic of people who
Speaker 1:  may have been the optimal Tesla buyer 10 years ago.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like, and the, and the cars have not changed, right? Like it's,
Speaker 1:  it's just the, what they mean in the world has done a, like a full
Speaker 1:  180 to the point where like the people who used to walk in and spend money
Speaker 1:  are now protesting outside of the building. And It is like, if, if
Speaker 1:  you want a story of what has happened to American society in 10 years, like
Speaker 1:  there It is, man, it's just bizarre.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It, it's crazy. And they'll, they'll point to, they'll say, you know,
Speaker 11:  we, we would've been fully in support of Tesla's mission, right? Like Tesla's
Speaker 11:  mission for a long time was to, of further the, the mission of,
Speaker 11:  of new energy, clean energy, renewable energy, you know,
Speaker 11:  Musk for a long time talked about, you know, electric cars and battery storage
Speaker 11:  and all of these things as a way to save the world. And I think a lot of
Speaker 11:  those people would've ascribed to that mission. But, you know, their argument
Speaker 11:  would be, you know, he changed first, right? He was the one that got
Speaker 11:  red pilled and bought into all of these Twitter conspiracies and moved
Speaker 11:  to the right and ultimately endorsed Donald Trump and funded his campaign
Speaker 11:  and is now heading this effort to slash the federal government and
Speaker 11:  fire workers and cancel humanitarian aid. So I think a lot of these folks
Speaker 11:  would say, you know, it wasn't, wasn't us that changed. We liked Tesla,
Speaker 11:  we liked our cars, but you know, it's, it's him that changed and now
Speaker 11:  we have to sort of like respond to that. So yeah, It is, It is an incredibly
Speaker 11:  cognitively dissonant mo moment I think ultimately, and I think a lot of
Speaker 11:  these protesters would, would, would fully admit to that as well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's, it's just, it's just strange that it ended up like this.
Speaker 1:  So what, what is the sort of metric we're looking at to see if
Speaker 1:  this is working? Obviously you can look at Tesla stock price. I will
Speaker 1:  just say candidly, I, my, my increasing belief is that stock prices have
Speaker 1:  nothing to do with anything are completely divorced from reality. Especially
Speaker 1:  when it comes to things like Tesla, which have been about other things for
Speaker 1:  a long time,
Speaker 1:  but if, if you're looking at sort of what, what is, is this working or is
Speaker 1:  it not? Which direction is Tesla headed? What do we look at?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, so I think this week especially, we're gonna get some new data that's
Speaker 11:  gonna, I think, tell a lot about what's been going on in this sort of the
Speaker 11:  present moment. We've already seen signs of it. Right at the beginning of
Speaker 11:  the year, we saw Tesla report that, that it had flat sales
Speaker 11:  for the year and that it's, you know, its deliveries were actually going
Speaker 11:  down. And then in the last few months we started getting some regional data
Speaker 11:  from Europe and from China about how its sales had
Speaker 11:  dropped. I think in, in Europe over the last two months, sales were down
Speaker 11:  45% year over year in some markets, even more. I
Speaker 11:  think Germany was down to like over 70% year over year. And now
Speaker 11:  we're gonna see, wow, the, the, the first quarter sales data be reported
Speaker 11:  on Wednesday. Even a lot of the, the Tesla
Speaker 11:  optimists and the bulls out there are expecting it's gonna be a
Speaker 11:  rough number for Tesla. They're assuming that it, it could be down
Speaker 11:  by as much as nine to 10% year over year in terms of the number
Speaker 11:  of, of vehicles that it produced, but also the ones that it's delivered,
Speaker 11:  which is basically a proxy for, for sales. So
Speaker 11:  that's gonna be the thing that people are really gonna be zeroed in on.
Speaker 11:  I, it doesn't sound like even Tesla is really optimistic about this
Speaker 11:  delivery report this week. So that should be sort of a real clear
Speaker 11:  signal about how bad this brand image that Tesla has at the moment.
Speaker 1:  The, the like get rid of Elon Musk energy does seem
Speaker 1:  to be increasing. I don't think it's remotely realistic, correct me if
Speaker 1:  I'm wrong, but it it, the, the number of people with
Speaker 1:  some influence who are starting to say things like Tesla needs a CEO who
Speaker 1:  is not Elon Musk. That that noise seems to be getting louder. Is there any
Speaker 1:  substance behind any of that as far as you can tell? Yeah, it
Speaker 11:  Still seems to be pretty much on the fringe as far as I can tell. Like,
Speaker 11:  you've got like investors like Ross Gerber who, who have been saying, you
Speaker 11:  know, who have been sort of like Musk skeptics for a long time. Mm. Saying
Speaker 11:  that he thinks that there needs to be a change at the top. Obviously he,
Speaker 11:  he owns some, some Tesla stock, but it, I wouldn't say that it's anything
Speaker 11:  significant to, as a to point to I think larger problems within
Speaker 11:  the company. And certainly the board itself hasn't, hasn't said anything.
Speaker 11:  I think, you know, Robin Denholm, who was, who's the board chair was in
Speaker 11:  Australia like a week ago, and a lot of reporters tried to sort of, you
Speaker 11:  know, get her corner her and ask her about Tesla. She just refused to say
Speaker 11:  anything about it. So, you know, the board is still seen as being sort of
Speaker 11:  completely beholden to Musk. I mean, his brother's on the board, James
Speaker 11:  Murdock's on the board, you know, it's not it, I wouldn't say it's a Tesla
Speaker 11:  Takedown friendly situation, but, you know, and,
Speaker 11:  and there's still like a lot of people who are saying, you know, like if
Speaker 11:  you're, if you're someone who's optimistic about Tesla's future, don't worry
Speaker 11:  about the current moment. You know, we've got, there's lots of things to
Speaker 11:  look at at the horizon. There's a new refreshed model y that's gonna be
Speaker 11:  coming down the pipe that's Tesla's bestselling vehicle was the bestselling
Speaker 11:  vehicle in the world. And there, there, there's a refresh model
Speaker 11:  that's gonna be coming soon. And then obviously there's Tesla's claims about
Speaker 11:  AI and robotics and other things that have been sort of the bulk of what
Speaker 11:  people have been using as, as sort of justification for
Speaker 11:  the insane values that Tesla has been, has been enjoying over the years.
Speaker 11:  Right. So it does seem like there's, there, there needs to be more
Speaker 11:  pieces connected, more dots connected before we start to say that Musk is
Speaker 11:  truly in trouble, which I would say he's, he's not at the moment.
Speaker 1:  Okay. It makes me think of like the meta situation where at every shareholder
Speaker 1:  meeting somebody's like, fire Mark Zuckerberg and Mark says, no thank you,
Speaker 1:  and then everybody moves on. Exactly. That's essentially where we're Yes.
Speaker 1:  To your point on like the, the model y and the AI stuff and you know, must
Speaker 1:  talks about the cyber cab and like there is, there is a lot of stuff
Speaker 1:  in some version of the pipeline at Tesla, but I continue to find myself
Speaker 1:  wondering, like, has this company, and I'm purely just
Speaker 1:  talking like as a, as a financial animal for Elon Musk's net worth, because
Speaker 1:  I think we have to talk to them about them as two different things, right?
Speaker 1:  Like there's the, there's the car company and there's the stock price and
Speaker 1:  they are like totally different things.
Speaker 1:  Does any of that matter anymore? Like part of me wonders now if, if the
Speaker 1:  idea of Tesla is so politicized and so directly tied
Speaker 1:  to Elon Musk himself that nobody, nobody cares about the model y
Speaker 1:  anymore. I don't like if the model Y comes out and It is amazing,
Speaker 1:  is it gonna change one person's mind about whether or not they should buy
Speaker 1:  a Tesla right now? I just have a hard time seeing it.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, it's, it's a really good question. I think that, you know, there's
Speaker 11:  some arguments that can be made that Tesla's brand is pretty thoroughly
Speaker 11:  toxic at the, at the moment, but it's not clear as to how
Speaker 11:  many people take politics into account when they're out buying a vehicle.
Speaker 11:  And, and that's fair if Tesla is able to actually come out with a, with
Speaker 11:  a even lower cost model, which they've said that they plan on doing at some
Speaker 11:  point this year, we're not sure exactly how lower cost that's gonna be.
Speaker 11:  Is that gonna be like a, you know, the sort of the, the long rumor
Speaker 11:  $25,000 model two that's been talked about, although I think it's being
Speaker 11:  called the Model Q now, so I don't quote me on either of those things, but
Speaker 11:  you know, if, if they're able to actually achieve this, I think would be
Speaker 11:  a very significant achievement for, for the company, which is a lower a,
Speaker 11:  an actual lower cost electric vehicle, some sort of like
Speaker 11:  strip to the bones model three and beat all of the other legacy
Speaker 11:  OEMs that are out there. I think you could make the argument that Tesla
Speaker 11:  could see a significant bounce back. And then, you know, there's another
Speaker 11:  thing that I I I've sort of been thinking about in the back of my head,
Speaker 11:  which was do you remember the delete Uber movement?
Speaker 11:  Oh yeah. And during the, of course the first Trump administration when there
Speaker 11:  was a boycott at the JFK airport over like deportations,
Speaker 11:  and I don't even remember like the specifics, but like Uber wasn't boycotting
Speaker 11:  airport pickups in the same way that like taxi drivers were. And so
Speaker 11:  everybody got mad at Uber plus, like Travis Knick was gonna be on a bo
Speaker 11:  on some sort of CEO panel with Trump. Everyone got mad at Uber. And so there
Speaker 11:  was this hashtag delete Uber moment. Everyone's like, delete Uber, get rid
Speaker 11:  of Uber, you know, we don't need this company anymore. That petered out
Speaker 11:  after like a couple months. Yeah. And as far as I I I can tell Uber's
Speaker 11:  fine right now, it's profitable like it's doing well. Like these things
Speaker 11:  like tend to like happen in, you know, fits and starts. And
Speaker 11:  it's not clear to me, like I'm sure the Tesla Takedown people will say,
Speaker 11:  you know, this is, we're here to stay, we're here to, to make, you know,
Speaker 11:  Elon Musk's, you know, life of living hell. And they certainly, it's been
Speaker 11:  working and it's a very different situation than the delete Uber situation
Speaker 11:  in many ways. Like Musk is way more entrenched and embedded in,
Speaker 11:  in the Trump administration now than Uber ever was.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This will be an interesting test of, of like humanity's ability
Speaker 1:  to move through news cycles, right? Because It is, yes, It is generally true
Speaker 1:  in modern times that if you're in trouble all you have to do is wait and
Speaker 1:  eventually everyone will move on to something else. And, and the the lesson
Speaker 1:  learned is like, don't apologize, just, just wait and eventually
Speaker 1:  everyone's attention will disappear. This feels like maybe the most
Speaker 1:  extreme test we've ever had of that exact like,
Speaker 11:  I mean, I would argue that the Trump, there's the Trump example, right?
Speaker 11:  Like there was January 6th and an actual insurrection. Totally,
Speaker 11:  yeah. And like Trump was supposed to be like, you know, banished to the
Speaker 11:  wilderness after all that happened and, and yet here we are. So I mean if
Speaker 11:  Trump can make a comeback, Musk is, I think certainly looking at that
Speaker 11:  example, right? Yeah. Being sort of as close as he is to
Speaker 11:  him It is seen, you know, like maybe the same can be for me.
Speaker 11:  Why can't, if not him, why not me? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. Alright, so one other thing going on in the car industry this
Speaker 1:  week of the many, many, many things going on in the car industry this week,
Speaker 1:  big looming tariffs. I i, if I am an
Speaker 1:  automaker, am I just in full 10 out of 10 chaos
Speaker 1:  crisis mode right now? Is that where everybody is?
Speaker 11:  It's it's fully panic mode, I would say. Okay. For the, for the auto industry.
Speaker 11:  I've been talking with a lot of people at these companies and, and smart
Speaker 11:  people, analysts and others who, who sort of, whose job It is to watch this
Speaker 11:  stuff and, and they're saying that there's, there's just really no way
Speaker 11:  that you can avoid passing this cost on to customers. Like these
Speaker 11:  tariffs are gonna come down, every car in America can suddenly it could
Speaker 11:  be made in America, but that doesn't mean that the parts that go into the
Speaker 11:  car are necessarily originate in America. And so, you know,
Speaker 11:  you've got something along the lines of, you know, up to 50% of a,
Speaker 11:  of the, the parts that are inside a car come from sort of foreign countries.
Speaker 11:  Mexico and Canada especially are, are a huge hubs for
Speaker 11:  these parts. So with 40 to 50% of auto parts coming from abroad,
Speaker 11:  there's just really no way that these costs are, are, can be absorbed by
Speaker 11:  the companies that make the, make the vehicles. And so I think a lot of
Speaker 11:  smart people are predicting, you know, something around the lines of five
Speaker 11:  to $10,000 price increases just right out of the
Speaker 11:  gates. Wow. When these tariffs go into effect on April 2nd,
Speaker 11:  that is to say if they go into effect, right? We've been, we've been sort
Speaker 11:  of going back and forth and back and forth on whether Trump is actually
Speaker 11:  gonna do this, you know, what can be said to actually dissuade him from
Speaker 11:  putting these tariffs in place. It, it seems like these ones are actually
Speaker 11:  gonna come through, but you have to sort of allow for the fact that this
Speaker 11:  is a very unpredictable, unpredictable, fluid situation. Yeah. But you know,
Speaker 11:  I, I read today, I was reading a report today that the, some of, you know,
Speaker 11:  sort of assume that this is gonna add a hundred billion dollars
Speaker 11:  in costs annually to the auto industry.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 11:  I mean this is a incredibly tight margin industry. They cannot
Speaker 11:  absorb these costs. People are gonna be, be paying higher prices for cars
Speaker 11:  and there's really just no good reason for, there's no reason at all
Speaker 11:  why this is happening other than to satisfy Donald Trump's
Speaker 11:  bizarre theories about what tariffs are.
Speaker 1:  He does love a tariff, he loves a tariff. Just, it's just, it's, that's honestly,
Speaker 1:  it might be all there is to it. He, the man just loves a tariff. So if I'm,
Speaker 1:  if I'm an automaker, it seems like the, the short term thing that you
Speaker 1:  do is just immediately raise prices. Right? And I I I've, I've been reading
Speaker 1:  similar stuff, right? Like there and there was one thing that was like, I,
Speaker 1:  it was quoting somebody, some executive from one of these automakers who
Speaker 1:  was like, yeah, the prices are gonna go up and then prices don't go down.
Speaker 1:  So they're just, this all might go away, but the prices stay up because that's
Speaker 1:  what, that's what happens. So that's the like, immediate thing.
Speaker 1:  The the underneath thing seems to be potentially
Speaker 1:  the, the like long-term goal of the Trump administration is that all these
Speaker 1:  companies start making huge efforts to move stuff into the United States.
Speaker 1:  Are you, are you hearing rumblings of companies thinking about like, okay,
Speaker 1:  we have to retool everything in order to make this stuff work or prices
Speaker 1:  are just gonna go up, that's life moving on.
Speaker 11:  So there, there was already kind of like a bit of an onshoring movement
Speaker 11:  going on during the Biden administration where he was offering all of these
Speaker 11:  incentives and tax cuts and things like that for companies that
Speaker 11:  were bringing their manufacturing, especially EV and battery manufacturing
Speaker 11:  to the us. A lot of that is still happening as far as I can tell. I mean
Speaker 11:  these are huge projects, billion dollar projects that take
Speaker 11:  multiple years to line up all the investors and the partners and the, and
Speaker 11:  the land acquisitions and all of these things. So It is just gonna take
Speaker 11:  a long time for that to happen. Whether or not you start to see companies
Speaker 11:  try to start to, to do the same because of the tariffs. I think you're starting
Speaker 11:  to see some companies sort of repackage old announcements as,
Speaker 11:  as sort of responding to the present moment and presenting them as something
Speaker 11:  new. But that said, it's just not something that can be
Speaker 11:  flipped from week to week. You know, it's, this is something if you, if
Speaker 11:  you take into account just the complexity of supply chains, you know,
Speaker 11:  trying to create new factories, new hubs, this is a four to five to six
Speaker 11:  year timeframe that a lot of these happen happen. So it,
Speaker 11:  it would just be sort of a massive frustration for the industry, I think
Speaker 11:  to, to sort of bring all of these supply chains into the United States.
Speaker 11:  And, and from what I can tell the idea that you could have a, a vehicle
Speaker 11:  that is made with 100% US made parts
Speaker 11:  and labor and manufacturing and everything is basically a fantasy at
Speaker 11:  this point and is just not something that even if they undertook
Speaker 11:  this massive effort, which would cost them hundreds of billions of dollars
Speaker 11:  and take many, many years, even that is not necessarily going to result
Speaker 11:  in I think whatever the sort of fantasy that Trump has in in, in his mind
Speaker 11:  about this, you know, sort of domestic renaissance in
Speaker 11:  manufacturing.
Speaker 1:  Right. And I would assume that the, the uncertainty of it all is also part
Speaker 1:  of the challenge here. That if I'm, if I'm running a car company, like I
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm not actually sure it's smart or prudent right now to
Speaker 1:  say we're gonna make these giant sweeping changes because this is the new
Speaker 1:  normal. Like, God only knows what the new normal is.
Speaker 11:  And, and the thing that, that I thought was really interesting, there's
Speaker 11:  a lot of, there was a lot of stories in the last few weeks that are like,
Speaker 11:  oh, this is great for Tesla, right? Tesla is like one of the most domestic
Speaker 11:  manufacturers that we have. They make all their cars in Texas and California.
Speaker 11:  A lot of their parts are made here in the United States, including their
Speaker 11:  batteries. But even Tesla is exposed to this and they're gonna probably,
Speaker 11:  we're gonna see prices go up for them as well, which is, you know,
Speaker 11:  on top of already like declining EV incentives, you know, less
Speaker 11:  tax breaks, less, you know, less charging incentives. So, you know, I
Speaker 11:  think it's, it's safe to say that everyone is exposed on this, including
Speaker 11:  Tesla, which all, and I think Musk has himself has also said that, you know,
Speaker 11:  we're not gonna be unscathed through all this. So it's really just kind
Speaker 11:  of just a, it's a huge head scratcher I think for everybody.
Speaker 11:  'cause we were assuming that there was gonna be some, at least some carve
Speaker 11:  outs or maybe some exemptions, but it, it doesn't appear to be that the
Speaker 11:  case at, at this stage.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, well, like you said, we'll see a bunch of that is coming due this week.
Speaker 1:  So we, we will, we will see one way or another.
Speaker 11:  Exciting times, exciting times.
Speaker 1:  Let, let's, let's end on a more exciting note. Tell me I'm crazy
Speaker 1:  for being kind of into the new Nissan Leaf.
Speaker 11:  You're
Speaker 1:  Not, you wrote about this thing and, and I, I find the leaf fascinating.
Speaker 1:  Someday you're gonna come on the show and we're gonna do the whole story
Speaker 1:  of the Nissan Leaf, which I think is like the weirdest, most interesting
Speaker 1:  sort of footnote in the history of EVs, but there's a new
Speaker 1:  leaf and it's kind of hot and I'm kind of into it.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I know. It's the same, right? It was kind of like similar to me.
Speaker 11:  I got similar vibes from the, the new Toyota Prius a little bit. Like, I
Speaker 11:  was like, oh, they, they took something that was like a big old paperweight
Speaker 11:  that nobody really liked that much, but sold like incredible numbers. Like
Speaker 11:  it did really well, the new Nissan Leaf for a long time and they kind of
Speaker 11:  like sexed it up a little bit. Gave, you know, gave it a bit of a glow up
Speaker 11:  and it looked really good. We, we we're still kind of waiting for like the
Speaker 11:  full picture of like what it's gonna look like. We don't really have a,
Speaker 11:  like a, a lot of the specs, battery range, anything like that. The old leaf
Speaker 11:  had terrible range, but yeah, it was a pioneer, right? It was out there
Speaker 11:  first full like medium range ev to
Speaker 11:  go on sale even before the, the Tesla model s So it
Speaker 11:  was, it kind of like proved the market I think for a lot of OEMs
Speaker 11:  that this was something that people would actually be interested in buying
Speaker 11:  and the rumors that was gonna be that, that that Nissan was gonna get, get
Speaker 11:  rid of it for a long time. Nissan's going through a lot of problems right
Speaker 11:  now. Their sales have dropped just dramatically over the last
Speaker 11:  few years or so, especially in some key markets like the US and they tried
Speaker 11:  to merge with Honda late last year. That deal kind of fell apart,
Speaker 11:  although there's some rumblings that they might be trying to get back together
Speaker 11:  again. And then the, the, the leaf was supposed to be on the chopping block,
Speaker 11:  right? Like Nissan's got the aria, it's got some other EVs in the pipeline
Speaker 11:  that are a little bit more long range and a little bit more sort of like
Speaker 11:  in the form factor that consumers tend to like, which is more sort of like
Speaker 11:  in the SUV crossover air space. And now we're seeing the leaf is gonna become
Speaker 11:  a, a bit of a crossover as well. So yeah, I I would say let's,
Speaker 11:  let's do that Nissan Leaf. Let's do it from a Nissan inside a Nissan Leaf.
Speaker 11:  Let's record a whole podcast. I like that idea in a leaf and we can talk
Speaker 11:  about the whole history, which is, yeah, it's pretty fascinating. It's,
Speaker 11:  it's been a roller coaster ride for the leaf.
Speaker 1:  Indeed. Yeah. If you get a real picture of this thing from all angles, I'm
Speaker 1:  gonna need you to send it to me because I keep looking at this like, kinda
Speaker 1:  like Robin's egg blue thing and I'm like, yeah, I would buy this car. I'm
Speaker 1:  ready. Let's do this. I'm down. Nice.
Speaker 11:  They got one customer already lined up. Yeah, there
Speaker 1:  We go. All right, Andy, thank you as always. Oh, my
Speaker 11:  Pleasure. Thanks David.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 1:  take a question from The Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast hotline as
Speaker 1:  always. The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. You can email vergecast at The
Speaker 1:  Verge dot com. And by the way, It is always super delightful when you call
Speaker 1:  and have a question for a specific person because then I get to bother that
Speaker 1:  specific person and make them come do that with me, which is what happened.
Speaker 1:  Today's your question.
Speaker 18:  Hey, it's Peter from Brooklyn. This question's for Jen Tuy. Jen, I'm
Speaker 18:  wondering if there are any smart home companies that
Speaker 18:  are using AI with cameras to analyze what's going
Speaker 18:  on in your home. The example I keep thinking is if I could be
Speaker 18:  like, Alexa, where did I leave the scissors? And it shows me a
Speaker 18:  little video of, oh yeah, last Thursday you put them in this drawer.
Speaker 18:  Seems super creepy, but also super like something that
Speaker 18:  they would do. Just curious if anybody's doing it. Thanks.
Speaker 1:  You ask for Gen Tui, you get Gen Tui. Hi Gen Tui.
Speaker 17:  Hello. Happy to be here. Love to be summoned.
Speaker 1:  I just wanna say that super creepy and super useful should be the motto of
Speaker 1:  the smart home.
Speaker 17:  That is, that is true.
Speaker 1:  So I, I had a couple of sort of immediate thoughts that this sparked, but
Speaker 1:  I'm curious where your head went here in this question.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I guess the immediate answer is not yet.
Speaker 17:  This is definitely where you can see them going
Speaker 17:  to some extent. Especially say you specifically mentioned Alexa and Amazon
Speaker 17:  with its new Alexa Plus and it's new multimodal
Speaker 17:  generative AI capabilities, you could see this happening.
Speaker 17:  In fact, at the Amazon event that they had in February,
Speaker 17:  they specifically used cameras to say, you could
Speaker 17:  say to Alexa, when did my dog last go for a walk? And it, it
Speaker 17:  looked through the footage and replied and, and showed an
Speaker 17:  an image of, or a video of the last time someone had taken the dog out for
Speaker 17:  a walk. I think for this type of very fine grained
Speaker 17:  things like where did I leave the scissors? Mm, that's gonna
Speaker 17:  be a bit more of a challenge for Alexa in the current capabilities. Unless
Speaker 17:  you have ring cameras stationed everywhere around your house
Speaker 17:  capturing every movement, it definitely wouldn't have the capability yet.
Speaker 17:  Because another thing that a lot of these, so there are a number of security
Speaker 17:  cameras that are doing this AI search feature where
Speaker 17:  you can search through your camera history just with typing some phrases,
Speaker 17:  but they are very much trained on specific things that you might like to
Speaker 17:  look for. So I think, you know, scissors in a drawer might be the level
Speaker 17:  above what they're at now. It's more like cat on the porch or
Speaker 17:  delivery driver approaching door kind of things that they're doing now.
Speaker 17:  So Ring has that AI search feature. Google
Speaker 17:  Nest is launching it, it's currently in like a beta program.
Speaker 17:  Arlo actually has an interesting one where you can program your
Speaker 17:  own search query. So you could sort of say,
Speaker 17:  I guess you could set up a camera, an Arlo camera in your living room and,
Speaker 17:  and train it to watch your, where you put the scissors.
Speaker 17:  But again, it would have to be very specific. You'd have to know what you
Speaker 17:  would want it to look for. It's not gonna be able to sort of analyze everything
Speaker 17:  you've seen it's seen and look for it that
Speaker 17:  specific yet. But I can see it going there. I think, I'm guessing where
Speaker 17:  you are going David is would be where I would go with this, is it's more
Speaker 17:  likely to come from AI glasses. Yep.
Speaker 17:  Like we saw Google demo. This, this is,
Speaker 1:  So this is exactly where my head went is the, that it's called Project Astro,
Speaker 1:  that's it from Google and It is, it's the the demo.
Speaker 1:  Exactly. Was that right? Yeah, they, they were just walking around and they
Speaker 1:  had this sort of always on camera and they were like, oh, where did I leave
Speaker 1:  my glasses? And it, it directed them back there to where they left their
Speaker 1:  glasses. Notably not shipping, I could say that feature.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's starting to like percolate out in the world. It, it seems to
Speaker 1:  be a real thing, but It is not, It is not nearly yet what Google showed it
Speaker 1:  to be, but yeah, that, that is, like you said, that is the thing everybody
Speaker 1:  is working on. Yeah. This idea of like, how do I give
Speaker 1:  myself some sort of consistent awareness of my surroundings
Speaker 1:  and then use that to help me, which is a really
Speaker 1:  interesting problem, but a really hard one. And it does seem like
Speaker 1:  if your, if your bar is not scissors, but It is like, I
Speaker 1:  don't know on the level of like people and pets, right? I, I think about
Speaker 1:  the, the smart home stuff as like, it, it's comings and goings. I, I sort
Speaker 1:  of want to know when major events with people and pets are happening in
Speaker 1:  my house that it seems like these tools are actually getting pretty good
Speaker 1:  at pretty fast, right? Yeah. Like in, in theory the, the tech is there and
Speaker 1:  it seems like the distance between people and pets and scissors is just
Speaker 1:  like time and camera quality to some extent. Yeah.
Speaker 17:  Just training the machine learning models on what It is that you want
Speaker 17:  to be identified about or told about. And I think, yeah, right
Speaker 17:  now, because there is the creepy factor with cameras, a
Speaker 17:  lot of this is focused on what's happening outside your home. Not so much
Speaker 17:  inside but with, I mean if you have cameras inside your home
Speaker 17:  and you want to identify specific people or specific events,
Speaker 17:  you can do that right now. You, the ring video
Speaker 17:  AI search feature, which I wrote about, I used it to track, keep track of
Speaker 17:  my cat. Like I would keep losing my cat and I would just type in, you know,
Speaker 17:  cat gray today and it would show me all the videos
Speaker 17:  that it had captured of my cat walking around the various parts.
Speaker 1:  Your cat just slipping in and out of the wall. Yeah.
Speaker 17:  Although mainly outdoors. 'cause I, I don't really do cameras inside, but
Speaker 17:  echo devices have cameras on them. So like the show devices all have cameras
Speaker 17:  on them. So you could see this becoming part of
Speaker 17:  what they offer right now though it's just ring cameras, so those
Speaker 17:  aren't the cameras in the show. Devices nests,
Speaker 17:  same thing. They have indoor and outdoor cameras and also their Nest hubs.
Speaker 17:  A a few of them have cameras. So yes, I could definitely see this being
Speaker 17:  where they're going. And it's one of the really useful areas of AI that
Speaker 17:  I've, of generative ai I've seen in the smart home to date, getting that
Speaker 17:  kind of fine-grained detail about what's happened in your home without you
Speaker 17:  having to scroll through every video and look for Right. Or Yeah,
Speaker 17:  try and 'cause right to date you've had things like person, animal,
Speaker 17:  vehicle, so you can filter your video clips to just animal, but then
Speaker 17:  I'd be looking through, if I was looking for my cat, I'm looking through
Speaker 17:  videos of like squirrels and my dog going round in circles and not finding
Speaker 17:  the cat. Whereas now I can just ask it to find me cat and
Speaker 17:  it finds me cat sometimes
Speaker 1:  It finds me cat is pretty good. Yeah, I, I was thinking about this today
Speaker 1:  actually. I, my neighbor had to be out for the day,
Speaker 1:  but It is having luggage delivered like the, the airline lost her luggage
Speaker 1:  and so they're delivering it. And so she called me this morning, I was like,
Speaker 1:  Hey, can you be around in case they need to deliver the luggage? And
Speaker 1:  now I'm like glued to my house in case they come and knock on the door
Speaker 1:  and, and I had to leave for a few minutes and I was actually thinking like,
Speaker 1:  oh, being able to come back and be like, Hey, did, did the mailman come?
Speaker 1:  Like, did, did the Alaska Airlines people come is like genuinely,
Speaker 1:  sincerely useful. Yeah. In a way that I don't have that much smart
Speaker 1:  home stuff, but that was one of the moments where I was like, oh, I wish
Speaker 1:  I had that. I just rely on like my dog to bark and tell me that
Speaker 1:  there are people at the door and that's not, it turns out a, a perfect system.
Speaker 17:  Well the downsides of this type of feature is you are going to have to pay
Speaker 17:  for it. All of these services are included in like the ring
Speaker 17:  subscriptions, the Nest subscriptions. But interestingly enough, a couple
Speaker 17:  months ago a new company launched called Seymour ai,
Speaker 17:  which is S-E-E-M-O-U-R and It is able to
Speaker 17:  go through all my ring footage and let me search for it even if I'm not
Speaker 17:  paying for subscription. So, oh, interesting. If you wanna just try it out.
Speaker 17:  This is, that's a good way to to, to start at least
Speaker 17:  I don't know how they're doing it
Speaker 17:  and I'm sure ring's aware of it and I'm sure they'll probably charge at
Speaker 17:  some point, but right now you can download the app for free on iOS and if
Speaker 17:  you have ring cameras you can, it will search through your footage for you.
Speaker 17:  But again, it's very specific, like it tells me a lot that it's seen
Speaker 17:  destructive pet activity on my porch, which is normally just
Speaker 17:  my dog walking around. Sure. So like, again, they're trained to look for
Speaker 17:  specific things they think you might be interested in, but as you say, as
Speaker 17:  this advances, I think that gap between, you know, dog
Speaker 17:  cat destructive activity and this is where you left your
Speaker 17:  scissors may, may start to get a lot smaller and, and it could be very
Speaker 17:  useful if you don't mind having cameras in your house.
Speaker 1:  Well, so that's what I was gonna say is it seems like to me the two roadblocks
Speaker 1:  here are a, It is a huge technological leap, right? To
Speaker 1:  go from I know what a dog looks like to all
Speaker 1:  the things going on inside of your house Yeah. Is a huge
Speaker 1:  leap. Yeah. It's, and like we've seen how hard that is. But then the other
Speaker 1:  thing is, I, I just can't fathom the number of cameras you'd have to
Speaker 1:  have in your house in order to be able to pull that off. It seems like you
Speaker 1:  would need a camera or, or ideally a couple of
Speaker 1:  cameras essentially on every single square
Speaker 1:  inch of your entire house in order for this system to work. Because even
Speaker 1:  if you have a couple of blind spots, the whole thing kind of falls apart.
Speaker 1:  So I'm like, is this why everyone gets that ring drone camera that can
Speaker 1:  follow them around because it solves this problem? I
Speaker 17:  Don't know. I did think about that. Yeah. Okay. But that's only designed
Speaker 17:  to work when you're not in the house, so
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that'll
Speaker 17:  Change. And also never shipped. Yeah. Unlikely
Speaker 17:  to ship at any time in the future if you ask me. So yes,
Speaker 17:  the ring camera, the flying drone is, is designed to work
Speaker 17:  when you're not there. So it might not be as useful. I think Amazon would
Speaker 17:  like us to have screens with cameras in every corner of our room, but I
Speaker 17:  think sure would, yeah. Ultimately the idea of smart glasses
Speaker 17:  or I mean as as Apple recently, or it's leaked
Speaker 17:  recently that Apple might be putting cameras in your watch,
Speaker 17:  more cameras may be on you because again, that's less,
Speaker 17:  that's, there's still a bit of invasion of privacy. But something I talk
Speaker 17:  about a lot in the smart home is, it's one thing when you have the cost
Speaker 17:  convenience ratio that you are weighing when you are using technology, you
Speaker 17:  know, a smartphone or a smartwatch or using Gmail or, and you
Speaker 17:  are willing to give up some privacy for the features that you get, but it's
Speaker 17:  another when you're in your home and there are other people in the home
Speaker 17:  and you're giving up their privacy as well. So there's a lot more
Speaker 17:  cost of benefit ratio that has to be factored in there for everyone in the
Speaker 17:  home, not just yourself. So assuming everyone's on board with having cameras
Speaker 17:  in your home, you might be okay, but I think that's unlikely. So I
Speaker 17:  think personal devices are much more likely to get us to that
Speaker 17:  position that our callers interested in, especially if
Speaker 17:  it's you who's left the scissors somewhere. Although in my household, everyone
Speaker 17:  always steals my scissors, so I would need cameras on everyone. I got a
Speaker 17:  pack of five scissors for Christmas because I complain so often about how
Speaker 17:  many people, everyone's stealing my scissors. So I, I'm with him on
Speaker 17:  this. I would like to know where my scissors are.
Speaker 1:  How many of the five pairs do you still have? It's now the end of March.
Speaker 1:  Do we still have all five? No,
Speaker 17:  I have half of one.
Speaker 17:  I don't know where the rest are. All
Speaker 1:  Right. So we need somebody to invent this quickly. If you could get this
Speaker 1:  done for us and for Peter, this would be amazing. Yes. All right Jen, thank
Speaker 1:  you as always. You're
Speaker 17:  Very welcome.
Speaker 1:  All right, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 1:  came on the show and thank you as always for listening as ever. There is
Speaker 1:  lots more on everything we talked about from my review of the light phone
Speaker 1:  to Allison's coverage of AI and phones to all of Jens smart home
Speaker 1:  stuff to Andy and the team's latest on everything happening with Tesla
Speaker 1:  and the Tesla Takedown and tariffs, everything, all of it on The Verge dot
Speaker 1:  com. I'll put a bunch of links in the show notes, but so much of this stuff
Speaker 1:  is like actively unfolding. Keep it locked in the website and
Speaker 1:  if you have thoughts, feelings, questions, problems, other
Speaker 1:  weird car questions that you think maybe we can answer, please always get
Speaker 1:  in touch. You can email Vergecast at the burge.com. You can call the hotline
Speaker 1:  at eight six six BGE one one. We truly, truly, truly love hearing from
Speaker 1:  you. We've gotten a bunch of really fun questions about border security and
Speaker 1:  how to think about your devices as you move from one place to another,
Speaker 1:  particularly in and out of the US right now. We have some fun stuff coming
Speaker 1:  up on that over the next couple of weeks, so stay tuned. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer and Will Poor Vergecast is VERGE production
Speaker 1:  and part of the Fox Media podcast network. I'll be back on Friday with Neli
Speaker 1:  talking about all of the news happening this week, whatever weird stuff is
Speaker 1:  going on with images and chat, GBT, presumably some new gadgets.
Speaker 1:  I wanna see if he watches the studio on Apple tv, which everybody's into.
Speaker 1:  He was weird about severance, but I'm gonna get him into the studio. This
Speaker 1:  is my plan. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.