# Transcript
ID: 7235b9e8-b810-434b-9a9f-93ef90036f2b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5814059805072634243/-5967190069490634715/s93290-US-3661s-1760263798.mp3
Description: Back when text messages cost 10 cents each, BlackBerry came up with a better way: BlackBerry Messenger, commonly known as BBM. It was the first new idea about messaging in a long time, and it was a huge hit… for a while. Nilay Patel and Joanna Stern join David Pierce to talk about a messaging service that was years ahead of WhatsApp and iMessage, but ultimately fizzled.
If you like the show, ⁠subscribe to the Version History feed⁠ to make sure you get every new episode.
Let us know what you think: 866-VERGE-11 or vergecast@theverge.com.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (15 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  It's 2005. Your phone bill is out of control because
Speaker 1:  text messaging is taking off and you're paying 10 cents every single
Speaker 1:  time you send or receive a text message. 10 cents. It's
Speaker 1:  outrageous. But what if I told you there was a better way? What if there
Speaker 1:  was an app on your phone that you could use to send messages to all your
Speaker 1:  friends in real time for free and you could even see when they'd read your
Speaker 1:  messages? And did I mention it's on your phone? And that's never really happened
Speaker 1:  before. It all sounds too good to be true, but it's not. It's called
Speaker 1:  BBM or Blackberry Messenger, but everybody calls it BBM. And it's built right
Speaker 1:  into the phone that you either have or you wish that you had from the Virgin
Speaker 1:  Vox Media. This is version history, a show about the best and
Speaker 1:  worst and weirdest and most important gadgets and products in the history
Speaker 1:  of technology. I'm David Pierce, and today we have to talk about texting.
Speaker 1:  Stay tuned.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. It's version history. It's time to talk. BBM
Speaker 1:  my friends are here. Joanna Stern is here. Hi Joanna.
Speaker 6:  I'd like you to refer to me by my Blackberry pin number for
Speaker 1:  The, do you still know it? This is what I was gonna ask you. This is my first
Speaker 1:  question.
Speaker 6:  3 5 0 9 8 5 4.
Speaker 1:  The good thing is you could just make that up. I'll
Speaker 6:  I Yeah,
Speaker 1:  That's fine. Neil Absel is also here. Eli, do you remember your BBM pin?
Speaker 1:  No. My role on this episode is to be the person who grew up in the Midwest
Speaker 1:  away from these fancy east coasters and their Verizon network and blackberries
Speaker 1:  and provide the view of the common man. So, okay, this, this is another thing
Speaker 1:  I wonder, do you guys remember the story here Starts in 2005.
Speaker 1:  Did you have a Blackberry in 2005? No, I did not. Do you, what phone did
Speaker 1:  you have in 2005 do you think? I had almost certainly a Sony Erickson.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah, that was, this was, that was a Sony Erickson person. I like that
Speaker 1:  this was like the end, if memory serves of like the razor
Speaker 1:  was still the thing, but not for much longer. The LG chocolate
Speaker 1:  was huge in 2005. If I'm doing my time correctly here, it's a little bit
Speaker 1:  later. Was it a little later? A little later. Okay. Do you remember what
Speaker 1:  you had? I
Speaker 6:  Did. I had an LG flip phone. Nice. Yeah, a Verizon.
Speaker 1:  This was that era when the goal
Speaker 7:  Was to make the phone as small as possible, right?
Speaker 6:  Flip phones. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And they were like, that was like the Zoolander phone. And then the other
Speaker 7:  move was the Blackberry. And everyone I knew on the East coast had a Blackberry
Speaker 7:  and everyone in the Midwest had like an LG chocolate that was free with the
Speaker 7:  plan.
Speaker 6:  But to your point, I was in college and the fancy kids did have
Speaker 6:  BlackBerrys. Yep. I was not fancy.
Speaker 1:  Not yet Now.
Speaker 7:  Soon. It was coming for you soon. Joanna Stern would take her full bloom.
Speaker 7:  It
Speaker 6:  Was, it was fancy though at that point to have a color screen,
Speaker 6:  like
Speaker 1:  A Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  Like a color LCD either on the outside of the phone or the inside of the
Speaker 6:  phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I was, I was like, I had a, one of the like T nine candy
Speaker 1:  bar phones that again I got for free with my Verizon plan. My
Speaker 1:  family, we all got a family plan together in 2004 and it
Speaker 1:  was like a momentous occasion in my family and we all got the worst phone
Speaker 1:  they had available because it was free with the plan. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's good stuff. You get a lot of analog razors for free right before the
Speaker 7:  networks went digital and got better.
Speaker 1:  But Joanna, you are here because at some point between not having a
Speaker 1:  Blackberry in 2005 and way after everyone
Speaker 1:  stopped using PBM, you became like the world's foremost BBM user.
Speaker 1:  Is that Yes.
Speaker 6:  Fair. In fact, I know Neli never had BBM 'cause I
Speaker 6:  could never message him there.
Speaker 1:  I do remember you being like belligerent that everyone should be using
Speaker 6:  PBM. Yes. And when we started The Verge, it was even before then when we
Speaker 6:  were at Eng Gadget, a few people had BBMI can still
Speaker 6:  remember them.
Speaker 7:  And again, I'm just gonna point out this split was fancy East Coasters and
Speaker 7:  everyone else it
Speaker 6:  Was, it re it really
Speaker 7:  Was. It absolutely was. We, we ran Eng Gadget on AOL Instant Messenger, which
Speaker 7:  is a different episode of the show.
Speaker 6:  Oh, can I be invited back for that?
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah, that's, that may be the longest version history episode we ever
Speaker 6:  Do. Well we really ran it on ICQ. Yep. But we
Speaker 6:  must have just texted just text like I was not at my
Speaker 6:  huge laptop at the time. I must have just texted you. Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 6:  And then when you came into the picture
Speaker 1:  For 10 cents a message
Speaker 6:  When you were a little baby. I know that's true. And you came into the picture,
Speaker 1:  I think I had a, I think I showed up with a Trio six 50. Yeah. Which I was
Speaker 1:  very happy about that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. A close out Trio six 50.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All right. So let me just tell you the story of PBM
Speaker 1:  as I know it. You both lived it more than I did. You with a clear
Speaker 1:  sense of jealousy and sadness.
Speaker 7:  I was there for the ever man. I was like, I don't understand these phones
Speaker 7:  at all. Like here we go. So,
Speaker 1:  Okay. So the story here starts in early 2005
Speaker 1:  and the thing I learned is actually 2005 was the year instant messaging
Speaker 1:  as a whole became like a mainstream thing. There
Speaker 1:  was a study that year that found that it was instant messaging was as big
Speaker 1:  as email for the first time ever in 2005, which is actually later
Speaker 1:  than I would've guessed. And also like all the youngs
Speaker 1:  were IMing. That was like the big takeaway is like all the young people are
Speaker 1:  IMing and this is not like texting, this is IMing. They were like sitting
Speaker 1:  at the family computer on a OL into Messenger, which I did
Speaker 1:  all through high school. Yeah. That was my entire life. And
Speaker 6:  I was in again in college. 'cause you were a little baby, correct? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You were still drinking bottle and eating. That's right. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Instant me, like instant messenger defined college
Speaker 6:  at the that point. 'cause we couldn't communicate if we had left our computers.
Speaker 6:  Like you could do T nine texting on your little crappy phone. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Eli, the every man was even T nine texting in Minnesota or wherever you
Speaker 6:  were from. It was so,
Speaker 7:  So disrespectful. It was Wisconsin. I knew that. And
Speaker 7:  every, every commercial for texting
Speaker 7:  was like teens and they would all be sending some variation on the same
Speaker 7:  message, which was meet me at the spot. And it was just like,
Speaker 7:  it became, it was a running joke with my friends that we would only text
Speaker 7:  each other meet me at the spot because that was every single commercial
Speaker 7:  was like happy teens in a Jeep Wrangler being like, man hit the spot. And
Speaker 7:  like, this is all you ever text. I
Speaker 1:  Feel like it was usually surfing at the spot. Right? They like mostly surfed
Speaker 1:  at whenever, wherever the spot
Speaker 7:  Was. But 'cause you, because you, it was too expensive a whole conversation
Speaker 7:  just on like
Speaker 6:  Messaging
Speaker 7:  Phones. Right? You just did these like logistical conversations on text
Speaker 6:  And part of those like ads were, they were a bucket of text
Speaker 6:  messages that your family could get back to your family plan or you had to
Speaker 6:  kind of pay per text.
Speaker 1:  Right? Right. So that, that's the, the two things I feel like are really
Speaker 1:  important to remember about this period is like WeChat didn't exist.
Speaker 1:  WhatsApp didn't exist. Facebook hadn't done anything. Google Talk launched
Speaker 1:  in 2005, which thought was interesting, but it wasn't built into Gmail yet
Speaker 1:  and nobody was really using it. But it was like all this stuff was like starting
Speaker 1:  to happen. Yeah. But it was still you. You sent meet me at the
Speaker 1:  spot text messages and so I did And you did all of your actual conversation
Speaker 1:  stuff at
Speaker 7:  The spot. At
Speaker 6:  The spot.
Speaker 7:  You were like everything was about when and how or are we gonna get
Speaker 7:  to the spot? Right.
Speaker 6:  Or you would run back to the spot that was your desktop computer.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. To then once again say I'm going to the spot. Need the spot. Right.
Speaker 7:  What's really fascinating about this at that time is even back then,
Speaker 7:  everyone knew messaging platforms were so sticky that they could create like
Speaker 7:  powerful locked in competitors. So
Speaker 7:  during one of time Warner's many attempts to buy something, they
Speaker 7:  bought a OL, you might recall a doomed merger that was eventually
Speaker 7:  undone the Time Warner story. And during that
Speaker 7:  merger the government said, we're gonna let you buy a OL. But a OL and some
Speaker 7:  messenger is so powerful and so sticky that a condition of the merger
Speaker 7:  is you have to make it interoperable with other in instant messaging platforms.
Speaker 7:  Because E even back then, everyone knew this is lock-in. You can't get
Speaker 7:  all your friends to leave one platform and join another.
Speaker 6:  And in fact, I'm remembering some of those messaging phones did
Speaker 6:  at some point, I don't wanna say it was 2005, but maybe a little bit later,
Speaker 6:  like two years later had Aim Yep. Had
Speaker 6:  instant Messenger and maybe Google Talk. But it was the crappiest
Speaker 6:  experience. Yes. Because it was like some, I don't, what were they WAP apps?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They were all really bad. They ran in, they ran in like fake internet.
Speaker 7:  Right. You had to pay extra for fake internet
Speaker 6:  And you had gotten an error. It'd be like, you gotta pay at and t $700 to
Speaker 6:  get to this app. And so there was like, again, I just keep
Speaker 6:  highlighting this. There was the laptop computer world of
Speaker 6:  messaging and there was the mobile world of messaging.
Speaker 1:  Totally. And the, and the, the thing about the 10 cents thing is it like,
Speaker 1:  it was a absolute like money fountain for carriers
Speaker 1:  if I remember right. It was like the, the story is, it was basically like
Speaker 1:  a rounding error of bandwidth that they figured out how to put messaging
Speaker 1:  and that's why it's 160 characters and they just like 110 cents message.
Speaker 1:  Was
Speaker 7:  It 140? I
Speaker 1:  Think so. No, that was Twitter and they made it 140 so that you could also
Speaker 1:  put in the username and get to 160 character text message. Come on
Speaker 1:  school.
Speaker 7:  I said that as an avatar for the audience. But they, they which is also wondering,
Speaker 1:  They were making a ton of money off of this. Lemme just play this for you.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 7:  Hope they say meet me at the spot.
Speaker 8:  Be wau. Your cell phone bill is what's up?
Speaker 8:  All this texting O-M-G-I-N-B-D. It is a big deal. Who
Speaker 8:  are you texting 50 times a day? I'd Okay. My BFF Jill
Speaker 8:  tell your B fff Jill that I'm taking away your phone.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly what I'm talking about. Yeah. Yeah. Right. They were like
Speaker 6:  family messaging and it gonna, it's gonna cost you a fortune.
Speaker 1:  But so the the fascinating, like the right before BBM thing
Speaker 1:  that happened that I thought was super interesting and had completely forgotten
Speaker 1:  about is that Blackberry launched a new
Speaker 1:  app that was gonna integrate all this stuff. All the stuff that you're talking
Speaker 1:  about. Blackberry was like, we're gonna put, I think it was Yahoo Messenger,
Speaker 1:  AIM and ICQ. They were like, we're gonna do
Speaker 1:  IMing on your phone. Yeah. And it's, it's gonna be cool and it's gonna work.
Speaker 1:  And it was like a little wonky because doing that stuff on mobile is a little
Speaker 1:  bit harder because you have like the, the buddy system or the buddy list
Speaker 1:  stuff is fine. But then there's like the status stuff that's a little weirder
Speaker 1:  on phones. But they were gonna do it. Like they understood that internet
Speaker 1:  messaging to your point is gonna be the thing.
Speaker 7:  I think they also had a sense that people on Blackberries were essentially
Speaker 7:  emailing in real time. Yeah. 'cause the way the Blackberry network was
Speaker 7:  architected, and this is like the plot of the movie, which we both love.
Speaker 7:  Like that was Blackberry was they re-architected how to sell
Speaker 7:  networks worked and they had big Blackberry enterprise servers
Speaker 7:  all over the place be Yeah. That were actually doing the work.
Speaker 7:  Like your iPhone SB Yes. Blackberry Enterprise server. And that's like your
Speaker 7:  business would have one, but then Blackberry ran one for the big networks.
Speaker 7:  Yep. And the actual handsets were doing almost nothing on the network.
Speaker 7:  It was the servers that were handling all of the traffic and all the processing.
Speaker 7:  'cause the phones were bandwidth constrained, battery constrained, all that
Speaker 7:  stuff.
Speaker 1:  And that was as much the thing Blackberry did or that was their in motion
Speaker 1:  did then correctly that no one else was doing. Was they like made that stuff
Speaker 1:  work.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They centralized the hard part 'cause the network was crappy. Right.
Speaker 7:  And so they're like, okay, people are emailing in real time. We can just
Speaker 7:  extend that model to a oh one sent Messenger or Yahoo. Yahoo Messenger
Speaker 7:  and we'll bite off another little bit of the internet and make that on the
Speaker 7:  phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  That was a very linear progression from what they were doing with email.
Speaker 7:  Obviously this was not the right idea, but it was, you can see how they got
Speaker 7:  to it very
Speaker 1:  Quickly. Yeah. Well and so the, it it, it did sort of happen that
Speaker 1:  quickly as it seems it wasn't, there wasn't some like Grand Proclamation
Speaker 1:  about like, we need to embrace internet messaging. It was just like somebody
Speaker 1:  just like made the thing send text messages. And I have a whole story about
Speaker 1:  this, but there's also a clip from the Blackberry movie that you're talking
Speaker 1:  about that literally just explains the whole thing. This is, if I remember
Speaker 1:  correctly, it's like halfway into the movie and Jim Balsley, who's played
Speaker 1:  by Glenn Howerton, my boy Dennis Reynolds from It's always Sunny in Philadelphia,
Speaker 1:  shows up and his team pitches him on a messaging
Speaker 1:  app they've just created. Let's just play the clip.
Speaker 9:  Do you know how much it costs to send a text message? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  10 cents and the network gets every penny. We're never gonna see that money.
Speaker 9:  Right.
Speaker 10:  But these texts are sent via data
Speaker 10:  so behind the network's back, which means
Speaker 9:  Unlimited free texting only on Blackberry.
Speaker 9:  Fuck yes.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's exactly what
Speaker 6:  Happened. Yeah. It went down like
Speaker 1:  That. That's basically right. Dennis, from what I understand it from Always
Speaker 1:  Sunny was there and it was great. But like
Speaker 1:  IIII think you're right that it essentially was that simple. They were like,
Speaker 1:  oh well we can do this thing with email, we can just do it with text messaging.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I, to be honest, don't really like
Speaker 1:  remember the moment it came out, but from what I've read, it was like
Speaker 1:  a pheno, like the idea of you can send text messages to people and not pay
Speaker 1:  10 cents per text message was like immediately a big
Speaker 1:  deal. Do you guys remember this moment at all?
Speaker 6:  I was a little late to it. Okay. But I do remember that being
Speaker 6:  one of the reasons I wanted a Blackberry
Speaker 7:  Because your friends were on it and they
Speaker 6:  Had, 'cause my friends were on it and I knew I could be BM with them. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I had friends that had it and had talked about BBM to me. So
Speaker 6:  it was, as he said, this was the selling point. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It took off. So the, the app itself was created by
Speaker 1:  a bunch of people, but particularly this guy named Gary Klassen. Shout out
Speaker 1:  to Gary. He works at Google now. Which feels, of course the app I
Speaker 1:  learned very recently was originally called Quick Messenger. It was like
Speaker 1:  this close to being called Quick Messenger, all one word. And then
Speaker 1:  somebody called it BBM before they really called it Blackberry
Speaker 1:  Messenger. They were calling it BBM, which I found sort of fascinating. It's
Speaker 1:  like BBM is like almost a acronym out of just, we just
Speaker 1:  wanna call it the thing BBM. And it had this thing called
Speaker 1:  pin to pin messaging, which is where the, the PIN stuff was really important
Speaker 1:  because one of the things that let you do was read receipts,
Speaker 1:  which nothing had ever had before. But you could see if somebody had looked
Speaker 1:  at your message just because of the way that it was able to connect over
Speaker 1:  the, the Black Brain Network. And I have this quote from Gary K and that
Speaker 1:  I thought was really interesting. He said this in 2015 on the the 10 year
Speaker 1:  anniversary. He said BBM was the first form of text communication that was
Speaker 1:  instant cross carrier and mobile in a time when people were still attached
Speaker 1:  to their PCs.
Speaker 6:  Can we go back to the name for a second? Because when I was preparing for
Speaker 6:  this, I was, why wasn't it called bm? For obvious
Speaker 6:  reasons. I was gonna say you, they didn't call it that.
Speaker 1:  You got there very quickly. Right. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I got there very quickly. But like, I'm not sure, and I wonder
Speaker 6:  about listeners who are listening to this in this day and age, if they even
Speaker 6:  know that this related to Blackberry, like BBM
Speaker 6:  became this like thing that you needed to have a blackberry for
Speaker 6:  but the name wasn't in it. Like Blackberry Messenger was not what people
Speaker 6:  ended up saying. So it's, it ended up just Blackberry.
Speaker 1:  It was part of the platform. It's like MTV or the SATs. It's like it ultimately
Speaker 1:  doesn't stand for anything anymore. It's just
Speaker 6:  The name and it didn't like mean anything. Yeah. Like the branding wasn't
Speaker 6:  there for them. Right.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. 'cause even we're, we're gonna get to this, but like many years later,
Speaker 1:  BBM showed up on lots of other stuff and nobody ever called it, it wasn't
Speaker 1:  like Blackberry Messenger for iPhone, it was just BBM. Right. I was like
Speaker 1:  what does BBM stand for? Like, I don't know, like what does s ESPN stand
Speaker 1:  for? Like no one,
Speaker 6:  They should have called it BM and would've gone down better. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They would've at least gotten more coverage. Just
Speaker 1:  BM me later. Yeah, Fine. I think that's,
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna get HR calls by that back to serious conversation. So
Speaker 1:  anyway, so the app ends up launching August 1st, 2005. This all happens very
Speaker 1:  fast was what I learned. They like basically decided to do this
Speaker 1:  thing and shipped it in just a few months. And lemme just read you a list
Speaker 1:  of some of the things that it had, like in version one it
Speaker 1:  had group chat, it had online offline status you could send files,
Speaker 1:  it had read receipts, it had the mutual authentication, the like buddy list
Speaker 1:  stuff that it borrowed from Im and basically every other just sort of
Speaker 1:  straightforward messaging. Like it was a full on I am client
Speaker 1:  for mobile like from day one. But
Speaker 7:  I'm just saying nuts. They just were like, oh people are emailing in real
Speaker 7:  time now that now it's called BM. And so they just
Speaker 7:  inherited a bunch of like file transfers from their
Speaker 7:  existing email service. And then they added the buddy list and the pin and
Speaker 7:  on the reader receipts, right? It's
Speaker 1:  Like if you just smash Blackberry Enterprise Server into
Speaker 1:  aim, you get BBM in like a very straightforward way, which is kind of wild.
Speaker 6:  And going back to this idea of like what we used to do at our computers,
Speaker 6:  like I think this was fundamental to Blackberry and also fundamental to their
Speaker 6:  fall is they really just were like, what are people doing at their
Speaker 6:  computers and do they wanna do on the go? Because they were kind of the like
Speaker 6:  get shit done company. Right? We, we are gonna let you do your work on the
Speaker 6:  go. Ensure that ended up translating really well to consumers
Speaker 6:  and they saw, as you said at the beginning of this, that more people at this
Speaker 6:  time were starting to do instant messenger on their computers. And so they
Speaker 6:  were like, great. Put another thing into the, to the phone, which
Speaker 6:  obviously was the problem for them. They kept trying to shove things into
Speaker 6:  a phone without thinking about like taking like sort of the desktop model
Speaker 6:  and the computer model and just shoving it into mobile. Which,
Speaker 6:  you know, what happened.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's like Joanna was like, I got my first Blackberry in 2007. It's like,
Speaker 7:  do you know what else happened in 2007?
Speaker 6:  I wanna say it was the end of 2006. 'cause I'm all right thinking like I
Speaker 6:  graduated college in 2006 and got my first like phone. Like I was
Speaker 6:  like, I'm ready for the world. Right.
Speaker 1:  Blackberry? I definitely got my first Blackberry after the iPhone launched.
Speaker 1:  Now that I'm think about,
Speaker 7:  I wanna point out that David is also a fancy pan East coaster. Yeah, he is.
Speaker 7:  Oh sure. He was like, I, I grew up and I was in Connecticut and then I was
Speaker 7:  issued a Blackberry by the state
Speaker 6:  By my family. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  You're you're closer than you think.
Speaker 6:  David's family had a bad server.
Speaker 1:  I got it. I got it from the dad of a kid that I babysat. There you go. Go.
Speaker 1:  'cause he got a free one from work. That's a real thing that happened.
Speaker 7:  It's like if you entered Greenwich, Connecticut. Yes. In 2006 you were handed
Speaker 7:  a Blackberry.
Speaker 1:  Oh a hundred percent. It really, really was. You could tell who worked in
Speaker 1:  finance because, and I have these distinct memories of getting on the train
Speaker 1:  from Greenwich to New York and all like it felt like all
Speaker 1:  of a sudden one day everybody had a Blackberry. Yeah. And it was like, 'cause
Speaker 1:  that was the whole pitch, right? It's like you can do your emails while you're
Speaker 1:  on the train on the way to work. And that was like life-changing
Speaker 6:  From people and now
Speaker 1:  Instant message and me, I'm just sitting there like putting stuff in my calendar
Speaker 1:  as like senior in high school.
Speaker 7:  Oh there was nothing funnier when than when all the high schoolers s like
Speaker 7:  pom pilots and we're like, what's on your calendar? It's like nothing
Speaker 1:  To-do. List social studies. Like Yeah. Who is this for?
Speaker 1:  But yeah, so, okay. And you said this while we were watching the clip, but
Speaker 1:  one of their big things was this pin to pin technology was supposed to be
Speaker 1:  super secure. Turns out not so much.
Speaker 7:  Well, well it was just the, the target of the Blackberry
Speaker 7:  server was irresistible to governments around the world. So one
Speaker 7:  of the stories we were just endlessly covering in Eng Gadget would be India
Speaker 7:  has decided Blackberry needs to break encryption. Mm. And then they could
Speaker 7:  just turn off the Blackberry network 'cause they could just find the
Speaker 7:  BES and unplug it until Blackberry caved. And there was just this huge
Speaker 7:  back and forth fight in a way that, you know, now end-to-end encryption on
Speaker 7:  phones. It's, it's much harder to just go to Jim Balsley and be like,
Speaker 7:  fix it or I'm taking your business away. Right? Right. And at that time
Speaker 7:  there was just so much pressure on this company and eventually they'd, I
Speaker 7:  think they caved in a couple of countries around the world and that that,
Speaker 7:  that I think really that's when that you knew they no longer had
Speaker 7:  the power they once had. Hmm. Right. When the pressure on them was so
Speaker 7:  great and they couldn't just resist it 'cause they were Blackberry in the
Speaker 7:  way that, for example, apple and Google can just resist it because they're
Speaker 7:  Apple and Google. But yeah, eventually some of this stuff started breaking
Speaker 7:  down.
Speaker 1:  I also feel like it's just a thing you can unplug. It turned out to be a
Speaker 1:  bad security practice. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  In general. Like he, all the information is on that computer. I just give
Speaker 7:  me that computer is like a real thing cops can
Speaker 1:  Say. Right? Yeah, that's very true. All right, so BBM comes out big hit
Speaker 1:  immediately it takes off. It was really funny going back and reading a bunch
Speaker 1:  of stuff from like those first years. Nobody could really explain
Speaker 1:  like why they liked BBM so much except that it was cheaper and it
Speaker 1:  was really fast. That was the thing I'd forgotten about BBM, this thing where
Speaker 1:  you could like in literally instantly real time message each
Speaker 1:  other. I also forgotten how unreliable SMS was back in the day.
Speaker 1:  That like messages would just get lost, things would happen. You never
Speaker 1:  really, and BBM was like, it was a reliable fast way to get in touch with
Speaker 1:  people. And that was a bigger deal to folks even in that era than I had
Speaker 1:  remembered. Which is nuts.
Speaker 6:  And you didn't have, you didn't, you talked about the 160 character, you
Speaker 6:  didn't have that. Right? So it wasn't like splitting messages. Like when
Speaker 6:  we would text at that, you would get like an error, like can't send it anymore.
Speaker 6:  And you'd have to send that and then continue your message. Yeah. So that
Speaker 6:  it was just, again, all of those things that you had gotten used to messaging
Speaker 6:  at your computer and I can't remember like when did a, did aim have
Speaker 6:  receipts anyway, that was another huge thing about like you knew
Speaker 6:  somebody had gotten that message right? It had reli, it had gone through,
Speaker 6:  it was reliably delivered and they were not responding to you. Okay, wait,
Speaker 1:  Here's a fun question. Do you remember the letters? There were two letters
Speaker 1:  that it used to show you different status in in the read receipts. Do you
Speaker 1:  remember what they were?
Speaker 6:  DNR.
Speaker 1:  You're right. It was D for delivered and R for red. But at first,
Speaker 1:  a fun fact that I learned was that at the very beginning, instead of the
Speaker 1:  R, it was actually an A because a designer had read the thing wrong
Speaker 1:  and coded in an A instead of R. That's so for red it just showed up an A.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 7:  Perfect. That's great
Speaker 1:  Blackberry access.
Speaker 1:  But anyway, so we're fast forward through time here. BB m blows up.
Speaker 1:  BBM five comes out. Big deal. Very exciting. This was like peak
Speaker 1:  blackberry. It ended up getting like every feature you could
Speaker 1:  possibly imagine, which I'd forgotten. You could send money you could post
Speaker 1:  to. I didn't know that. Yeah, there was a, there was a money sending thing
Speaker 1:  eventually. This
Speaker 7:  The world's for
Speaker 1:  Super app. This came Really? Yeah, like this all, some of they came later,
Speaker 1:  but then you could eventually post a Facebook and Twitter. It had a, there
Speaker 1:  was BM music. Do you guys remember BM music? I don't know that I'm going
Speaker 1:  to do a good job of explaining. So lemme just play a clip from TechRadar
Speaker 1:  from I think 2011 where they actually got a hands-on with the thing
Speaker 11:  For a monthly fee of $4 99, which is around three pounds.
Speaker 11:  Blackberry users will have unlimited access to 50 personally selected songs.
Speaker 11:  And then once every four weeks you'll be able to change 25 on your
Speaker 11:  list. Now this doesn't sound like a great deal on its
Speaker 11:  own. It doesn't. What will pull in uses is the ability to access all 50
Speaker 11:  songs on each of your BB Empire.
Speaker 7:  Why are you trying to make it sound good?
Speaker 11:  But beware to choose your music carefully. The idea is that you create a
Speaker 11:  personal music profile with your chosen songs that other people can browse
Speaker 11:  through. So you might want to think
Speaker 7:  This is just hell
Speaker 6:  Look at this pan or no, it's not a pan. She's pushing the phone into the
Speaker 6:  shot. She's holding
Speaker 7:  The phones. Yeah. So thank
Speaker 1:  You Tech
Speaker 6:  Radar that
Speaker 7:  Don't off the camera. Yeah. That's an old tech radar video. Yeah. And I just
Speaker 7:  have to say that you can tell there is like a PR person standing over the
Speaker 7:  shoulder 'cause they had to make it sound somewhat reasonable. All of that
Speaker 7:  is hell on earth.
Speaker 6:  That's not an ad. No,
Speaker 1:  That's a decorat. Put her hands on was a review. Yeah. Oh you, it's, it's
Speaker 1:  completely true. She was definitely like at a launch event holding the phone
Speaker 1:  and there are three comms people standing behind. Yes. And we've all been
Speaker 1:  through this. This is
Speaker 7:  Awful. Yes. And eventually you become a sociopath and you're like, I don't
Speaker 7:  care what you think. Yeah. But early on you're like, yeah, I think they'll
Speaker 7:  sell it to some people who will think this is a good idea. And the camera
Speaker 6:  Guy or camera woman could not move. And so she had to pan the phone up
Speaker 6:  into the,
Speaker 7:  I just know I've made that video. I have a lot of sympathy for how that video
Speaker 7:  is produced. And you're just like, this is the stupidest idea in the world.
Speaker 7:  4 99 a month. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And you,
Speaker 7:  For 50 songs you have to
Speaker 1:  Pick, if I understand it correctly, you got to have 50 songs in your library
Speaker 1:  and then you could browse your friends' libraries and listen to their songs
Speaker 1:  too. So the only way to make your library bigger was
Speaker 1:  to access all of your friends' libraries. But then at the end, just like
Speaker 1:  random strays of Justin Bieber that it's like hide your Justin Bieber songs
Speaker 1:  so that your friends can't listen to them. Like I would like to listen to
Speaker 1:  Justin Bieber on my friend's playlist.
Speaker 7:  Okay. A lot of questions there. I I just want to once again
Speaker 7:  offer some context to the group. The iPod existed during this
Speaker 7:  time, super existed. This was their attempt not to compete with the future
Speaker 7:  iPhone or whatever. They were like
Speaker 7:  the, the way we're gonna get the iPod is by charging
Speaker 7:  $5 a month for you to have 50 songs that change
Speaker 7:  every month. And you have to make, you have to operate this database.
Speaker 7:  And meanwhile people are like, what I'm gonna do is open up Napster on my
Speaker 7:  desktop computer and put 5 billion songs in my, my
Speaker 7:  iPod for free.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I remember trying to make my Blackberry like
Speaker 6:  an iPhone and I would side load music onto my Blackberry
Speaker 6:  and it was a terrible experience. Yeah. So this was Blackberry being
Speaker 6:  like, you no longer have to put music on a micro SD
Speaker 6:  card or whatever card it was. Or use A-U-S-B-A micro
Speaker 6:  USB cord to side load from your BBM desktop app.
Speaker 6:  I did these things young Joanna did these things. Okay. This
Speaker 6:  was their solution to that. They're like, we will let you get the music through
Speaker 6:  our store. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Well and the reason I bring
Speaker 6:  This up, we were so far behind us Blackberry people, we were just trying
Speaker 6:  to keep up.
Speaker 7:  No, they just knew that you were Rich East coasters and they could milk you
Speaker 7:  for five extra dollars.
Speaker 1:  Had an iPad.
Speaker 6:  I didn't care point. It wasn't just Rich East Coasters. There were the Canadians.
Speaker 7:  The Canadians. That's
Speaker 6:  True. There were the rich Canadians. There were the rich people in Hollywood.
Speaker 6:  Those,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there were wealthy finance bros. All over the world.
Speaker 6:  All over the world. People are BB Ming and they don't wanna go to
Speaker 6:  the iPhone yet because it's not on Verizon. It's not on and or any other
Speaker 6:  carrier really. I mean they started launching internationally when,
Speaker 7:  Right at the beginning.
Speaker 6:  So yes,
Speaker 7:  It was first in at t and then they started adding markets. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  We are stuck. We are stuck with Blackberry. And so here comes
Speaker 6:  BM music 4 99 a month.
Speaker 1:  And by the way, it's a BBM thing, which I think is really interest. Right.
Speaker 1:  And so this is,
Speaker 6:  This is the thing. They knew they couldn't do anything. They had to put it
Speaker 6:  into BBM. Right.
Speaker 1:  BBM was Blackberry's last move. Which I thought was so interesting. It's
Speaker 1:  like the 'cause at this point you're, you're right. Like we're we're you're
Speaker 6:  It was the stickiness. Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Right. About the, you
Speaker 7:  Know what else would've been sticky? Taping an iPod nano to the back of your
Speaker 7:  Blackberry. A choice you could have made at any
Speaker 6:  Time. But I did that. I was that person. I had the Blackberry, like I said,
Speaker 6:  I'm side loading music to the Blackberry, but it's not working very
Speaker 7:  Well. Did you have the gadget pockets? Like you would like come home at the
Speaker 7:  end of the night Yeah. And you'd like take out your digital camera. Oh, absolutely.
Speaker 7:  And your phone and your iPod.
Speaker 6:  I was a woman so I had a bag. Sure. Yeah. Remember the HTC rhyme? They made
Speaker 6:  that song for me. They made phones for women back then. So, but like I,
Speaker 6:  this was me. Yeah. Like I, and so maybe I paid for BM
Speaker 6:  music. I'm not, I'm not ashamed to say I might have.
Speaker 1:  You probably did. But before, so this, this is
Speaker 1:  the turning point, right? 'cause this is where actually I think it was
Speaker 1:  2010, that for the first time in several years, Blackberry stopped
Speaker 1:  being the bestselling smartphone brand. That was the year that Android in
Speaker 1:  particular. Oh yeah. Like I really, really just left it behind. But real
Speaker 1:  quick, before we get away from peak Blackberry, let me just show you a
Speaker 1:  bunch of BBM ads from peak Blackberry.
Speaker 12:  BM feels like it's faster. He can set up these groups and everyone can have
Speaker 12:  input.
Speaker 13:  My friends were with a boy that I had a crush on. They made him leave
Speaker 13:  me a voice note on Blackberry Messenger. I meet up my ringtone,
Speaker 14:  Snap a picture of the lamp, send it on over to them. And then I sold a piece
Speaker 14:  with Blackberry Messenger. If you read
Speaker 15:  My BBM and you don't answer me, I know you read it. I love that.
Speaker 1:  I just wanna point out, this is 2010. All of that existed everywhere
Speaker 1:  else.
Speaker 6:  It's just like
Speaker 1:  Blackberry was just like pretending that it still had something to
Speaker 1:  hold onto, but it was the thing that kept people using blackberries. But
Speaker 1:  you
Speaker 7:  Could just run that ad about WhatsApp today.
Speaker 1:  Oh mean Hunter,
Speaker 7:  I message this is still how we communicate about everything, right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like I had a crush on a boy. So I texted a friend, I sent a picture of a
Speaker 7:  lamp to someone and they bought it. Yeah. Like what are we do? It's
Speaker 1:  All the same. It's, it's the playbook. It is wild. How much of this BM got
Speaker 1:  right? And then right
Speaker 7:  At the end you get the, the the, you know, the the dark haired girl with
Speaker 7:  the big sunglasses being like, I'm from New York. Can
Speaker 6:  I read something
Speaker 1:  Blackberry, please.
Speaker 6:  I wanna set fir first of all,
Speaker 7:  Oh, I've lived in New York for like 15 years. I I it's fine. Well
Speaker 6:  It's true. I wanna read this. This is an editorial I wrote for in
Speaker 6:  Gadget at the end of 2010. Okay. When I was
Speaker 6:  getting ready to get rid of my Blackberry. And I wrote,
Speaker 6:  I'm more than aware that many don't understand the appeal of BBM.
Speaker 6:  Notably nearly all my fellow gadget editors.
Speaker 1:  So you got bullied out of using was
Speaker 7:  Actual roasted on my own
Speaker 6:  Page, most of my closest friends and family have blackberries and the native
Speaker 6:  messaging client absolutely destroys text messaging in terms of
Speaker 6:  speed and capabilities.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. It was, it it probably, it was still true in 20 10, 2
Speaker 6:  Weeks later I got an Android phone. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Right. Because the reason that none of your fellow eng gadget editors would
Speaker 7:  use a Blackberry and use BM with you is because we all had smart, like
Speaker 7:  proper smartphones.
Speaker 6:  You edited this
Speaker 1:  Almost
Speaker 7:  Certainly. Yes. 'cause I had an iPhone and I was like, Joanna
Speaker 7:  needs to mourn before she joins the rest of us in the future. Well
Speaker 1:  But it but by that point, the only reason people stuck around was because
Speaker 1:  there were the people who were like, no, I need the keyboard. That was me.
Speaker 1:  Like that was still the time when
Speaker 6:  BBM keyboard people
Speaker 1:  Were absolutely convinced that the keyboard was better. And even if you sort
Speaker 1:  of understood the point of a touchscreen, you're like, no, I type a lot.
Speaker 1:  I need the keyboard. And we had not broken that by this period.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And in fact, the reason I got the droid too was 'cause it had a slide out
Speaker 6:  keyboard.
Speaker 1:  There you go. Yeah. So the infamous slide out keyboard that super lasted
Speaker 1:  a long time and all phones have them now. Right. I
Speaker 4:  Was very good typer on there.
Speaker 1:  The thing that I, Mike Lazarus would not have said at the time, but believed
Speaker 1:  at the time and is, is true, was that BBM was the only thing that
Speaker 1:  still mattered at Black Gray. And they knew it. This is the thing like even
Speaker 1:  going back, right? 'cause it was sticky Rim Rim knew it. And we need to take
Speaker 1:  a break, but then we're gonna come back and I'm gonna tell you how Blackberry
Speaker 1:  tried to get BBM to save the company. We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. So now let's go to like
Speaker 1:  2013. So there's actually some reporting
Speaker 1:  years ago that BBM had a working
Speaker 1:  cross platform and desktop version that would've worked everywhere as early
Speaker 1:  as 2010. But the executives chose not to release it
Speaker 1:  based on the, it's the same theory as iMessage, right? It's like if we make
Speaker 1:  it easy to use the best thing about our platform on someone else's platform,
Speaker 1:  people will leave our platform. Right? And this is happening in 2010 and
Speaker 1:  there's like one idea says BBM is our best asset. We need to put it everywhere
Speaker 1:  and get everybody using it. And it it becomes our thing. There's another
Speaker 1:  that is like, no, we have to sell blackberries and the only way we'll sell
Speaker 1:  blackberries is if people keep using BBM. So these two sides keep fighting.
Speaker 1:  This is like the oldest tech story effort. Yeah. Like every company does
Speaker 1:  this at some point and the executives end up choosing
Speaker 1:  to keep it all bundled together, which I think you could argue is ultimately
Speaker 1:  what killed the whole thing. But a thing that I learned is that Jim Balsley
Speaker 1:  played by our, our boy Glenn Howerton in the Blackberry movie.
Speaker 1:  His big idea for BBM at the time was to essentially turn it into a OL, right?
Speaker 1:  Like m music is actually a sort of a, a, a nod
Speaker 1:  at that idea. But it's like, what if we made this into a walled garden that
Speaker 1:  was like the whole internet, like truly embrace the super app idea. It's
Speaker 1:  like we're gonna go all in, it's gonna be amazing. People are gonna pay money.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be the thing that keeps you on blackberries, they'll buy the devices
Speaker 1:  just to use this thing. It's like we're we're gonna make it Facebook essentially.
Speaker 1:  And the goal was to like get past carriers, eat
Speaker 1:  competition. Like really sort of build everything into
Speaker 1:  BBM and charge money for people to use BBM. But at this point, Jim Bosley
Speaker 1:  is not the CEO of Blackberry anymore. Torsten Hinz is the ceo Blackberry,
Speaker 1:  he killed the whole thing because part of Jim's plan was to make
Speaker 1:  this platform more important than devices, which would've ultimately like
Speaker 1:  made them go across platform. So they get rid of that Jim quits
Speaker 1:  and then it all just continues to fall apart.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 1:  Like, so there's this idea, right? That like, okay, we can put these two
Speaker 1:  things together and there are lots of people who want it and it'll stay sticky.
Speaker 1:  And even if we don't keep growing and the market keeps growing, it'll still
Speaker 1:  work. Right?
Speaker 7:  And I just wanna come back to did not everyone knew from the very
Speaker 7:  beginning that messaging apps were sticky. Yeah. Right? All the way
Speaker 7:  at the beginning. Like the government is just rewind your brain to be like
Speaker 7:  the, the Federal Trade Commission and the F CCC understand that a OL
Speaker 7:  into messenger is so sticky that if you let Time Warner buy it, there'll
Speaker 7:  be an unstoppable behemoth. Again, this turned out not to be true,
Speaker 7:  but I think what people also didn't really understand is when that
Speaker 7:  stickiness goes, it goes all at once.
Speaker 1:  Right? Right.
Speaker 7:  And when people leave a messaging platform, they're all gone
Speaker 7:  immediately. Right. There's no whole, and
Speaker 1:  The, and the way it happens is when there is some sort of inflection point
Speaker 1:  event. Yeah. And that thing was the iPhone and,
Speaker 7:  And
Speaker 1:  Some combination of the iPhone and Android, which essentially happened at
Speaker 1:  the same time was like, it just, it it unstuck the whole thing.
Speaker 7:  Yep. And then, and then in particular 2011
Speaker 7:  iMessage it as Intru. Yeah. Right. So then this all goes to hell. But
Speaker 7:  the, I I think it's so interesting that people knew how sticky and
Speaker 7:  powerful a messaging platform was so early like so, so early
Speaker 7:  everybody knew and Blackberry was like, well we have this thing, we can just
Speaker 7:  bet on this thing to keep selling the phones. And what no one had quite figured
Speaker 7:  out is when they go, they just go, right, right.
Speaker 7:  There's no, there's no fading monopoly. It's just tomorrow it's gone.
Speaker 1:  I mean this is kind of the thing I was wondering, right? Is like the other
Speaker 1:  thing that happens right around now is WhatsApp becomes a thing and just
Speaker 1:  immediately takes over the world and like
Speaker 1:  it did the cross platform thing that like people inside of
Speaker 1:  research in Motion have been trying to do for years. And part of me wonders
Speaker 1:  like is there a world in which BBM got this right?
Speaker 1:  But then to your point, there's all this other stuff happening simultaneously
Speaker 1:  that it's like maybe even if they had played all of their cards correctly,
Speaker 1:  short of building better phones, like if they had done all the software things
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Short of building better phones, which is not,
Speaker 1:  Which is not nothing. Right? Yeah. Like if they had made every good BBM decision,
Speaker 1:  which they didn't, but if they had, could it have worked? I think it's it
Speaker 1:  there's a strong chance the answer is just no. 'cause there were too many
Speaker 1:  other things
Speaker 7:  Much coming forward all at once. Think how much revenue they would've Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Had to have given up. That's right. I mean it's just like straightforwardly.
Speaker 7:  They make money selling blackberries the hardware, the service
Speaker 7:  to the carrier and then BBM is just like riding along on top of it.
Speaker 7:  And then maybe you're buying $5 a month for BM Music, whatever.
Speaker 7:  Three people were nonsense. You're
Speaker 1:  Doing Jim B's plan was that you'd pay for it like a OL which
Speaker 7:  Right. So worked pretty well for a pretty long time. We're gonna take one
Speaker 7:  part of our whole business and we're gonna put it on Apple's platform, which
Speaker 7:  wants to kill us. Right. And we're gonna say somehow this costs
Speaker 7:  money and there's no in-app purchasing back, like none of this stuff
Speaker 7:  exists yet. Right. And we're just gonna give away free texting
Speaker 7:  and Apple's gonna take a 30% cut. Well none of that exists yet either, right?
Speaker 7:  Like I mean too far after these these these like Titanic fights don't exist.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And then even now you get to, I don't know, WhatsApp and it's not like
Speaker 7:  WhatsApp makes a bunch of money for meta. Like it's an advertising surface.
Speaker 7:  They charge businesses to text people. It's big around the world. But
Speaker 7:  they had to invent all of this new business model. Blackberry
Speaker 7:  could not be like, what we're gonna do is we're gonna destroy our
Speaker 7:  big rich business and then spend 20 years figuring out how to make
Speaker 7:  BBMA business and Apple's platform. Like I don't think, I don't think that
Speaker 7:  would've been a rational decision ever.
Speaker 6:  No. And what you saw happen was others just followed this playbook,
Speaker 6:  pun in pun intended,
Speaker 6:  which is Apple.
Speaker 1:  They didn't follow the playbook. They followed, they followed
Speaker 6:  A playbook. They A playbook. Well
Speaker 7:  Apple, well no, a lot of people made shitty seven inch tablets. Like that
Speaker 7:  playbook was deeply followed.
Speaker 6:  That's true. That's true. That's fair. But Apple tries to do it with iMessage.
Speaker 6:  Google does it in a more open way and makes 7,000 different messaging platforms
Speaker 6:  over the next seven years, 10 years. And
Speaker 7:  People's like, what if we don't run this company?
Speaker 6:  And that's what hardware manufacturers started to try to do.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. Alright, so we're, we're near the end of
Speaker 1:  the BBM story, but I just, I have two more moments I wanted to tell you guys
Speaker 1:  about. One does, do you remember in 2011 when the BBM network went down?
Speaker 6:  I do. Of
Speaker 7:  Course
Speaker 6:  You do. I covered it. Yeah. But I didn't have a Blackberry then.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This was like breaking news. This was
Speaker 6:  A big news. I
Speaker 1:  Remember covering it. Me, let me just play you some of the news coverage
Speaker 1:  from this outage.
Speaker 17:  Blackberry users are losing access to email, text messaging and
Speaker 17:  web browsing. Everything. You would own a Blackberry for
Speaker 18:  Exasperated Blackberry users gave vent their frustration with the slowed
Speaker 18:  down services over the last 36 hours.
Speaker 19:  I'm feeling quite depressed and lonely because no one's getting back to
Speaker 19:  me. My phone's not popping off like it used to pop off. So it's not, it's
Speaker 19:  not a good look at the moment. Blackberry,
Speaker 20:  I have had no communication or emails for two days and it's really annoying.
Speaker 6:  Amazing.
Speaker 7:  The guy's like, my phone's not popping off pop off my phone. That's, he's
Speaker 7:  my hero. Like that's the whole verge. Like that's what we do here.
Speaker 7:  We're like, the whole culture is like, is your phone popping off? Like his
Speaker 7:  phone was not, nations rise and fall on whether or not these phones pop off.
Speaker 6:  His phone was not popping off. So this is
Speaker 1:  What happens next in, in 2013 Blackberry, the
Speaker 1:  company is essentially like falling apart, right? Like it's, it's a mess
Speaker 1:  in so many ways. It's market share is shot. And I believe this was a
Speaker 1:  really great Wall Street Journal piece from many years ago that they understood
Speaker 1:  that BBM was like kind of the only remaining asset in the company. So they,
Speaker 1:  they actually think about spinning it out. They're gonna call it BBM Inc.
Speaker 1:  And the plan is to turn it into like WhatsApp or Skype. Do you remember this?
Speaker 1:  Yes. It was, this was such a fun, like weird alternative history
Speaker 1:  to go down where BBM Inc is a thing that exists. They were also gonna do
Speaker 1:  BBM channels, which was basically like a telegram clone. Again, like a lot
Speaker 1:  of correct ideas just at weird times and with really bizarre
Speaker 1:  execution at this point. This is 2013 BBM, how many
Speaker 1:  users do you think BBM still had in 2013?
Speaker 1:  Just guess within 10 million.
Speaker 7:  Within 10 million. Within
Speaker 1:  10 million. There's your hint.
Speaker 7:  Is it 10 million?
Speaker 1:  It's not 10, it's more than 10 million. Oh
Speaker 6:  6 million.
Speaker 7:  No,
Speaker 1:  She's just famously more than 10 million.
Speaker 7:  That's
Speaker 1:  Not 60. That's the
Speaker 7:  60 million
Speaker 1:  People still using PBM in 2013. Unclear how
Speaker 1:  share 50 songs at a time. I guess
Speaker 6:  Maybe it was just the install base had the, like everyone who had
Speaker 6:  a phone had
Speaker 7:  BBM. Was that BBM with with the app strategy or BBM on the phones? You
Speaker 7:  have no idea
Speaker 1:  This was, this was like the total BBM
Speaker 7:  Including the weird apps. They
Speaker 1:  Universe. I think so, yeah.
Speaker 6:  But they actually only had like a couple of million users
Speaker 1:  Probably. Yeah. That was like, this is how many people, it does not make
Speaker 1:  sense. Had access to it sense. Well
Speaker 7:  The iPhone wasn't out in all these markets yet. Right? I mean for a huge
Speaker 7:  number of years, Apple's entire growth strategy was like, yeah, we discovered
Speaker 7:  another country now ship a new country now. Now the iPhone has it. Right?
Speaker 7:  Right. Like are you,
Speaker 6:  We looked at a map.
Speaker 7:  Are you aware of China? Apple's twice as big as it was before. Like every
Speaker 7:  year they were doing this. But
Speaker 1:  Even just to give you another example, like in 2013, WhatsApp already had
Speaker 1:  300 million users. So it was like the BBM was still around, but it was,
Speaker 1:  it was already like completely left for dead. And like you said,
Speaker 1:  that was the year they shipped all the other apps. Finally they like, they,
Speaker 1:  they launched everywhere else. A thing that I learned was that the Android
Speaker 1:  a PK leaked before the official announcement and was
Speaker 1:  so popular and Blackberry was so unready for it that they had to pause the
Speaker 1:  rollout of BBM for a month. Wow. 'cause like a million people all tried to
Speaker 1:  download this leaked version of the app and it broke the whole system so
Speaker 1:  spectacularly that they had to delay the launch for a month.
Speaker 1:  They tried pre-install it on LG phones when it came out, which Sure.
Speaker 7:  Perfect. That's a thing you could do. That's a perfect, it's probably on
Speaker 7:  Sprint. You
Speaker 6:  Know what, this is also the era of
Speaker 7:  Like the pre-install app on the LG phone on Sprint. Yeah. Is how you know
Speaker 7:  you're dying.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Real quick though, let me just show you a chart that I found from a
Speaker 1:  company called Diso, which is, it's from November of 2013
Speaker 1:  and it shows the, the various messaging apps
Speaker 1:  share in a bunch of different countries around the world. And it's kind of
Speaker 1:  wild. And you have in places like India and Indonesia,
Speaker 1:  it's still like a third of the market. These are huge markets like the It
Speaker 1:  is, it is both very easy to lose this sort of momentum
Speaker 1:  and stickiness, but it's also very hard to kill a messaging app. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  in a lot of these places, especially before things like
Speaker 1:  Fast internet showed up a lot of places like it, it lingered so like it it
Speaker 1:  didn't, it was hard to kill BBM
Speaker 7:  Then we actually did do it. It just
Speaker 1:  Goes right.
Speaker 7:  And
Speaker 1:  I then it happened country by country in the same way that you're describing.
Speaker 7:  And I, you can see that even with like little social networks, like this
Speaker 7:  is an experience we now have fairly often where something like Be Real shows
Speaker 7:  up and it's like everyone's on Be Real and then like the next day it's like
Speaker 7:  Be Real has gone out of business. Right. Right. Because there's no business
Speaker 7:  model. It's for everyone's using your network unless you have like
Speaker 7:  sustained usage. And I, I don't think Blackberry, I don't think they could
Speaker 7:  have ever made that term with BBM. It was just fundamentally too hostile
Speaker 7:  to the actual fund platforms themselves.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. All right. Right. We need to take a break, but really quick before
Speaker 1:  we do, what year do you think BBM finally went away?
Speaker 7:  I mean Jan is still using it from what I, from what I gather,
Speaker 1:  2019 BM was eventually sold to somebody else.
Speaker 7:  Of course.
Speaker 1:  What year? What year do you think
Speaker 7:  It's the same private equity, right?
Speaker 1:  They wrote a sad blog post about how it was going away. What year do you
Speaker 1:  think it was?
Speaker 6:  2019.
Speaker 7:  1719
Speaker 1:  Is right. It's 2019.
Speaker 6:  I prepared for the show
Speaker 1:  And they claimed there were still people using PBM in
Speaker 7:  2019. I just came here with like class warfare. There's no other preparation.
Speaker 1:  You
Speaker 6:  Get the spot.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna go back and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna get to the version history questions. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. We have eight questions that we ask about every
Speaker 1:  single thing we do on version history. Question number one, what was the
Speaker 1:  best thing about BBM?
Speaker 7:  Oh, the absolute best thing about BBM is somebody who didn't use it and only
Speaker 7:  made fun of my elite Mid East Coast friends
Speaker 7:  was the number of celebrities who were addicted to their black. Remember
Speaker 7:  we called them crack berries and it wasn't 'cause they were emailing or using
Speaker 7:  the web browser. It's 'cause they were on BBM all day long. And there's just
Speaker 7:  video after video of like Drake and Marlon Waynes and Anna
Speaker 7:  Kendrick, like two thou. Stacey Keebler being like, I love my Blackberry.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, oh, this is hilarious. Like it is
Speaker 1:  Maybe the first example of like full on
Speaker 1:  smartphone addiction. Yeah. It was just like, 'cause there were, they like
Speaker 1:  the CrackBerry thing was real and
Speaker 7:  My phone stopped popping off like it used to.
Speaker 1:  There were like medical opinions about people who were addicted that are
Speaker 1:  BlackBerrys and, and it was, it was because of BBM. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And it was just 'cause they were talking to their friends all day. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And like you can see, you can take that right out and be like, well, democracy's
Speaker 7:  in danger. But like, we'll just rewind. The best thing about BBM was all
Speaker 7:  of these celebrities constantly at every event, just like
Speaker 7:  Bradley Cooper being like, I love it. I can't live without it. It's, it is,
Speaker 7:  we should run some of them. No, I'm,
Speaker 21:  I'm, I'm addicted to it. It's awful. I actually prefer it to talking.
Speaker 22:  I'm double fisted with blackberries. Hey.
Speaker 23:  Oh, I call it CrackBerry. I'm so addicted. Oh my gosh.
Speaker 24:  I email and I like pinning and I like Blackberry messenger.
Speaker 25:  Blackberry. I, I, I use this little thing for everything so my
Speaker 25:  life's in here. If I lose this, I don't know who I am, what I'm doing.
Speaker 1:  It's very good. Joanna, what do you think best thing about bb MI
Speaker 6:  Mean everything.
Speaker 7:  The spot. Say meeting
Speaker 6:  At it. I say the one thing that I, and David, I know you have opinions on
Speaker 6:  this, but you could do an away message.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Ooh,
Speaker 6:  I know, I know you have thoughts. I do. But you could tell people
Speaker 6:  your status in BBM.
Speaker 1:  That was my answer too. With a little
Speaker 6:  Emoji. Just
Speaker 1:  Like, and, and when that died, it never came back.
Speaker 1:  Never came. They all have it now. You can do status in like Instagram and
Speaker 1:  stuff. No one cares. Nobody looks at that stuff. It's irrelevant. You
Speaker 6:  Can do it in WhatsApp. Right?
Speaker 1:  I think it's, it's the same like cross meta
Speaker 6:  When it it comes to iMessage, I will use it.
Speaker 1:  I probably will too, but it's
Speaker 6:  Like, it's gotta come though. And why wouldn't
Speaker 1:  It? But it was, it was the right complicated and thing and it should come
Speaker 1:  back. I agree. It was, it was the away message. Yeah. Bring back the away
Speaker 1:  message. All
Speaker 7:  Flirting was conducted by away message.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. And especially,
Speaker 7:  Here's our fragment of the song lyric that is super about you. Totally
Speaker 1:  Right. And if the sound I'm talking about was the more I wanted you to reach
Speaker 1:  out to me about it. Right. Alright.
Speaker 6:  And you would leave it, you would put that up like you were going out for
Speaker 6:  the night and you put that up and then you'd come back and be like, what,
Speaker 6:  what was I thinking? Like that, that's how like far away
Speaker 6:  you would be from your computer for
Speaker 1:  All that time. Oh yeah. You couldn't just go back and turn it off. Right.
Speaker 1:  It was, it was that dashboard concessional song
Speaker 6:  All night. Exactly. You, you committed to that lyric for the night or
Speaker 6:  two days if you left your computer, if you were crazy like me in college
Speaker 6:  and just, what was the
Speaker 7:  Complain of an away message on a phone? This is by the one I just, what,
Speaker 7:  what were you setting away messages on bb m You,
Speaker 6:  You were Could stop
Speaker 1:  A meeting. Your phone meeting.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You were in in in college. Well,
Speaker 1:  But no, but again, it was it
Speaker 6:  Recording the vergecast
Speaker 1:  BBB M got so quickly to that thing of like, yes. It, it hit the you are
Speaker 1:  expected to respond quickly. I just
Speaker 7:  So fast. I just had this image of like, Joanna in college. No, I
Speaker 6:  Didn't have it in college.
Speaker 7:  Okay. When I were you in your first job and you're like, I'm going into a
Speaker 7:  meeting, I have to type a dashboard, confessional lyrics into my hardware
Speaker 6:  Keyboard. This was, that was aim. I was doing that in
Speaker 1:  Gotta
Speaker 6:  Go. No, no, that was in my dorm room. I was putting in the dashboard confessional.
Speaker 7:  I I'm with you on aim. I just didn't understand
Speaker 6:  Black friend had cheated on me or whatever it was. And then I've gotta go
Speaker 6:  out and then by the end of the night I'm back with my boyfriend and I'm like,
Speaker 6:  oh my gosh, I've revealed this. My aim message
Speaker 6:  is still that. Yeah, that's how long it would take to update this stuff.
Speaker 6:  And then you would get it on your, we would have this on B BM and we could
Speaker 6:  do it wherever we
Speaker 1:  Were. It could be. So
Speaker 7:  We, for the Youngs who are listening to this, I just want to, I just wanna
Speaker 7:  offer an example. Yes. How effective any of this ever actually was. I ended
Speaker 7:  up marrying the girl who lived in the dorm room next to mine.
Speaker 7:  You wouldn't She date me for eight years because the away message Eness
Speaker 7:  was so strong. She's like, you're a mess. Like, you just figure out how and
Speaker 7:  when to express yourself.
Speaker 1:  Like, no, I just love the cure. Leave me alone.
Speaker 7:  Like literally
Speaker 6:  Can I can't. And is why you don't want it on your phone.
Speaker 7:  I'm just trying to get, I'm trying to get to next door with this message
Speaker 7:  and it didn't work.
Speaker 1:  It's tough, man. I'm really sorry. Yeah. All right. What was the worst thing
Speaker 1:  about PBM? What do you got?
Speaker 6:  I think that it, that it stalled and they didn't, they didn't bring
Speaker 6:  it to other platforms.
Speaker 1:  I think. I agree. It's, it's, I mean,
Speaker 7:  Wait. No, no. It's the obvious insane
Speaker 7:  usability nightmare of the username is being random digits of numbers. Oh.
Speaker 7:  See
Speaker 1:  I'm actually pro
Speaker 6:  Pins. But you didn't have to do that.
Speaker 7:  Everyone did it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Everyone did it. Yeah. Because it was impossible to add another way. This
Speaker 6:  is
Speaker 1:  The worst. Yeah. They had like QR codes
Speaker 6:  At the end. Like it was, lemme reformulate my argument.
Speaker 6:  Yes. That was also on my list is one of the worst things. That's so fine.
Speaker 1:  I don't agree. I think like a, a number that is, it was a QR code that QR
Speaker 1:  codes your isn't your phone number is like a good and valuable thing. And
Speaker 1:  the fact that all of our usernames are just our phone numbers, which are
Speaker 1:  also like the most important piece of personal security. We have disaster.
Speaker 1:  Sure. Give me more random numbers that I can give to people. Like I'm fine
Speaker 1:  with it honestly. I
Speaker 7:  Just like, it's just like, this is so your ideas, you're gonna issue everybody
Speaker 7:  a a nine digit number again. Okay. Go nuts, Jim.
Speaker 1:  All right. Question number three. Would it have been a bigger hit if Apple
Speaker 1:  made it? Well,
Speaker 7:  It was.
Speaker 6:  Yes. It's called
Speaker 1:  Ess. Apple did do it and it wasn't much bigger hit
Speaker 7:  Wildly but more successful product. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, it, it is sort of funny actually because it's like it, you, apple
Speaker 1:  did just do all the things that,
Speaker 7:  Oh, message is lost. I like, literally like in the halls of the
Speaker 7:  theater, people are like, oh, Blackberry said now. Yeah. Like it's, it was
Speaker 7:  like that. We, today we have witnessed a murder. Like that was the vibe at
Speaker 7:  that event.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. I think they're gonna, this is, this is one of my favorite questions
Speaker 1:  there because there's some of times it's gonna be very complicated and sometimes
Speaker 1:  it's just, yes, apple did do it much better. Well,
Speaker 7:  You, it's Apple has all the same problems, right? iCloud is centralized in
Speaker 7:  countries like China. You can just unplug it. You can just go get the
Speaker 7:  data. The FBI if you have iCloud backups of your iMessage, it's not Incr.
Speaker 7:  Like all of the same stuff is in recapitulated now with iMessage and the
Speaker 7:  exact same way as Blackberry
Speaker 6:  And all of your arguments you've made about stickiness could be one of the
Speaker 6:  last things that holds people. But
Speaker 1:  I will say, like we, every time we talk about the stickiness of iMessage,
Speaker 1:  we get a bunch of use or a bunch of listeners from anywhere else in the
Speaker 6:  World in the country I know who
Speaker 1:  Are like, no one uses iMessage. It's just WhatsApp, WhatsApp one. And I think
Speaker 1:  that's largely true. And
Speaker 7:  All of those countries have higher Android market share.
Speaker 1:  Right? But there is clearly no question that it would've been a bigger hit
Speaker 1:  if Apple made it because it did work super well. Question number four, if
Speaker 1:  you could go back and do it yourself, what would you do differently? Joanna?
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm putting you in charge of BBM in 2008.
Speaker 1:  Peak of its powers. BBM, what are you doing differently?
Speaker 6:  Same thing we've been talking about making it available to more phones, more
Speaker 6:  cross platform. But to Eli's point, what about the rest of my hardware business?
Speaker 6:  And so, right. I
Speaker 1:  Mean this is,
Speaker 6:  Jim is crying.
Speaker 1:  That was my original answer. But then I'm looking at it, I'm like, okay,
Speaker 1:  actually the story of consumer messaging is that it's not a business at all.
Speaker 1:  There's no one has ever figured out how to rub two nickels together from
Speaker 1:  letting people text each other. That's why if you're WhatsApp, you end up
Speaker 1:  selling for a lot of money. It's what's killing Snapchat like over and over.
Speaker 1:  This is, there's just not a business here. And so that's, this is my
Speaker 1:  problem too. I'm like, that is, from a product perspective, clearly the right
Speaker 1:  answer. If you want, a lot of people use BBM, that's what you do. You put
Speaker 1:  it everywhere much faster. But there's sort
Speaker 1:  of no evidence to suggest that there was a company to support that.
Speaker 6:  Right. I think any of my ideas are not actually about BBM. It's like
Speaker 6:  ways to save Blackberry.
Speaker 7:  Yes. How would you have saved Blackberry
Speaker 6:  Beds?
Speaker 7:  The beds.
Speaker 7:  I mean that's, but
Speaker 6:  Maybe like, maybe I would've made a cloud business.
Speaker 7:  You, you can, you can't just say that no one, what's the, what is the cloud?
Speaker 6:  Well, this, this is before the cloud. Like this is, oh, you
Speaker 7:  Mean you would've done like a, a desktop messaging in the cloud
Speaker 6:  Situation or maybe,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, maybe it's better email or like the company was
Speaker 6:  an email company and like, this is around the time Gmail blows up. I mean,
Speaker 6:  there's a lot of cloud infrastructure that the company had
Speaker 6:  ideas about. And it could have made, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  You just said my answer, which is I would've fed it to Gmail. It's like,
Speaker 1:  love actually actually shoved the two company together. But like the
Speaker 1:  thing, part of the thing that Gmail did so successfully was they put Gchat
Speaker 1:  into Gmail. And that, that connection became a huge thing, became really,
Speaker 1:  really, really powerful. And if, if
Speaker 1:  Blackberry had built those two things together and then
Speaker 1:  put it everywhere, then it's a thing you can charge people money to use for
Speaker 1:  work. It becomes like, you, you put email back into it and there starts to
Speaker 1:  be more of a business case there that I would've been very into.
Speaker 6:  You love emails. My favorite, you have a t-shirt that says
Speaker 7:  Emails. It's my favorite. It's, they're the, they're the, again, nations
Speaker 7:  rise and fall. But I'm, I, what I would say, not to
Speaker 7:  be a downer, there was no saving this company at
Speaker 7:  its DNA level. This is a company that is built around constraints.
Speaker 7:  Slow processors, weak batteries, slow
Speaker 7:  networks constrained storage per email. And the reason
Speaker 7:  Gmail existed where they're like, well, storage is free, here's unlimited
Speaker 7:  storage, right? Like, here's a gigabyte of email storage. And everyone thought
Speaker 7:  that was fake. Apple is like, it's a huge touch screen that can
Speaker 7:  run apps in full color. And everyone was like, that battery will never last.
Speaker 7:  And Blackberry, at its core was optimized around limits
Speaker 7:  and scarcity of like resource, like literally the resources, network,
Speaker 7:  bandwidth, memory, whatever. It's, and I don't think they
Speaker 7:  could have fixed it. 'cause they needed to embrace the, the new era, which
Speaker 7:  was about, oh, everything has gotten much faster and more powerful. Even
Speaker 7:  like the first iPhone was not built for the network. It was on, remember
Speaker 7:  it was a two G phone. They didn't have 3G for another year. And they were
Speaker 7:  still like, screw it webpage. And like they, they were
Speaker 7:  betting on a curve that Blackberry was betting against. And I
Speaker 7:  don't know that they could have flipped it. Like, the thing I'm saying is
Speaker 7:  like, I would've fixed it by making it a totally different company with a
Speaker 7:  different attitude. And I don't know that, that, I think that sometimes companies
Speaker 7:  just missed the moment and like Blackberry is like the story
Speaker 7:  of that. Really.
Speaker 1:  So you would've sold
Speaker 7:  I would've, yeah. I would've gone to Apple and been like, your future is
Speaker 7:  the Fortune 500. Yeah. It very clearly was these BY
Speaker 7:  od policies bringing in advice. Policies are the future. Like here's our
Speaker 7:  infrastructure.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We've built a bunch of really interesting technology. You can have
Speaker 1:  it. I'm gonna go buy a boat.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You're in a, you're in a, you're about to be in a dog fight with Microsoft,
Speaker 7:  which they were Yeah. To, to a huge extent. Like here, just take that.
Speaker 1:  All right.
Speaker 7:  They would, by the way, Blackberry would've never done this. No.
Speaker 1:  Gosh, no. No. But maybe they should have. And then they could
Speaker 6:  Have walked and talk about the constraints. Like that's what they ended up
Speaker 6:  like the last five years is them being in
Speaker 6:  developing countries and developing world because they didn't have the network.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's where that
Speaker 7:  Exists in every car. Right. It's because every car maker under
Speaker 7:  specs, the processor and the memory and the, the compute of the car, and
Speaker 7:  they don't wanna pay for a lot of data. Makes sense. So they're like sense
Speaker 7:  What's the, what's the operating system we can run that's like for shitty
Speaker 7:  phones? Because basically there's a shitty phone behind the screen of your
Speaker 7:  car.
Speaker 1:  Right? Yeah. And if you put yourself in a position of always chasing the
Speaker 1:  worst chip Yep. That gets pretty ugly for you. Pretty fast. Yeah. All right.
Speaker 1:  Next question. What feature of BBM should every current
Speaker 1:  messaging app have? If you could just lift one and put it in
Speaker 6:  A messages
Speaker 7:  50 songs for $5 a month. It's, it's obviously way
Speaker 7:  messages.
Speaker 1:  I think that's right. There is some, I there is like a version of the like
Speaker 1:  music sharing thing that I can like almost see that would work. But you'd
Speaker 1:  have to change it completely. I think. I think we're, we're all in agreement
Speaker 1:  with the answer's. The way message is,
Speaker 6:  I think Apple does it, is it share play basically that you
Speaker 6:  don't pay for it. You have
Speaker 7:  No Apple try to share, use Ping and it Oh,
Speaker 6:  You have
Speaker 1:  A huge, that's right.
Speaker 6:  No, I don't use the social Yeah.
Speaker 1:  No. Apple Music nightmare stuff. I, I I learned a while ago that you can
Speaker 1:  use share play to have the same music on two headphones. It's a disaster.
Speaker 1:  No one should try it. Question number six, is there an alternate timeline
Speaker 1:  in which this thing was more or even more successful? And I think in
Speaker 1:  this case, it's what if the iPhone doesn't exist? If the
Speaker 1:  iPhone ships in 2012 and not 2007 is the
Speaker 1:  story of BM completely different.
Speaker 7:  There's an alternate world in which BBM is more successful if they didn't
Speaker 7:  fumble the bag and they just put it on smartphones,
Speaker 7:  like proper smartphones, right? That and then BM becomes this like messaging
Speaker 7:  layer. But everyone else made the same mistake. Like AOL Instant Messenger
Speaker 7:  did not have a proper app on these phones. Google, right? Was like, man,
Speaker 7:  everyone loves Gchat. It's not even called Gchat. Like it's,
Speaker 1:  It's called Google Talk.
Speaker 7:  What?
Speaker 6:  At some point it was called
Speaker 7:  Gchat. No, never was
Speaker 1:  Never. Gchat is like full on.
Speaker 6:  We made it. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That has been red. It
Speaker 7:  Bears messaging clients and they just never put the proper app on
Speaker 7:  a phone. Like everyone looked at these phones and thought, well we just won't
Speaker 7:  put an app there until some people were like, we are
Speaker 7:  billionaires. 'cause we put an
Speaker 1:  App there. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  WhatsApp.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. All right. Question number seven. Could you reboot it now?
Speaker 1:  And I think the simple messaging app question, the answer is no.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like, are we all in basic agreement on that?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think that's pretty tough now.
Speaker 6:  I mean, maybe for like me, just do it. Just give
Speaker 1:  Joanna her pin back and it'll be okay.
Speaker 6:  I did have a t-shirt and I tried to find it for this taping, but it said
Speaker 6:  bb m me and this was like a t-shirt. They like were giving out at
Speaker 6:  Sure. When those phones launched. 'cause they were still trying. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  B, BM and then E at the end.
Speaker 1:  I love it. What about the like biggest,
Speaker 1:  most ambitious like super appy version of the thing? No one has yet built
Speaker 1:  that thing
Speaker 7:  Because Apple won't let you in this country.
Speaker 1:  True.
Speaker 7:  Like just straightforwardly, you're, you're fighting against a set of
Speaker 7:  platform policies that prevent the thing from existing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And that's true everywhere at this point. There's no, you just can't
Speaker 1:  win that game.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You're not gonna roll into China and be like WeChat now,
Speaker 1:  Right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Try. Have you heard of WeChat? Have you tried this one? Do you,
Speaker 1:  Do you disagree? Could you reboot it now?
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think the everything app idea is harder in the US
Speaker 6:  because of the stickiness of all these other services that we're kind of
Speaker 6:  used to using. So maybe there's a way where they like,
Speaker 6:  like plug it. No, it's just like too complicated. The only, like, why would
Speaker 6:  we all go? The
Speaker 1:  Only case I've been able to make for it is maybe the, the
Speaker 1:  meta ness of WhatsApp is becoming a problem for
Speaker 1:  enough people that they would jump to something else. But I don't, I don't
Speaker 1:  know. There's too many options right now. It feels like that's, it just feels
Speaker 1:  like a losing battle to try to start a messaging app from nothing. I do think
Speaker 1:  we've come, even if, I do think people have a lot of nostalgia for BBM.
Speaker 6:  And I do think we've come a lot farther in our acceptance of using multiple
Speaker 6:  messaging apps, right? Like, we'll use Signal, we'll use WhatsApp, we'll
Speaker 6:  use iMessage. True. We'll use Gchat, whatever it's called these days.
Speaker 6:  But I feel like this idea of, at least in the US it's always been very
Speaker 6:  hard for people to grasp, I'm gonna need to do all these things in this app
Speaker 6:  because I like Venmo or I like the Cash app, or I like this music app. Or
Speaker 6:  at least, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 7:  I mean, the argument against interoperability for all those apps take it
Speaker 7:  for what it's worth is like, well, they're all on your phone, right? You
Speaker 7:  just close one and open the other. Like you there, there, there they are.
Speaker 7:  You don't have to worry about it. I think there's some downsides to that.
Speaker 7:  Like I don't think wanting one feature should make you leave the
Speaker 7:  entire platform and that your whole network of friends, like that's
Speaker 7:  basically how they compete now. But I I would say instead of trying to
Speaker 7:  make it bigger, you wanna make it smaller. Or if you were to try to relaunch
Speaker 7:  PBM, you, I don't know, you would be like, here's a messaging app that's
Speaker 7:  just for families and kids. Mm. And we're gonna make sure it's safe. Like
Speaker 7:  you, your kids want to text their friends like, we're gonna, this one will
Speaker 7:  be locked down. And there are some that compete like that. But you've got,
Speaker 7:  you don't have like the big Blackberry brand name and all this, the stuff.
Speaker 7:  And like that's, I I think this solution here is smaller, not bigger.
Speaker 1:  All right. I like it. All right. And then last question. Does BBM belong
Speaker 1:  in the version history Hall of Fame? I will not be telling you the rules
Speaker 1:  that or qualifications. What is, because there are none so far.
Speaker 6:  I left that blank. 'cause I What are, what is
Speaker 7:  No, the answer is no.
Speaker 1:  Does
Speaker 6:  It belong? How, how many slots are there?
Speaker 7:  Only so many people get in like the NFL Hall of Fame every year.
Speaker 1:  I don't think
Speaker 7:  There are like, and there's like a voting process. There is a voting process.
Speaker 7:  Some people don't make it every year after year. That's where the tension
Speaker 7:  comes from. The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame. Do you have a silent, the same
Speaker 6:  Judging process? Do we know?
Speaker 1:  I'm saying just vibes All Hall of Fame are just vibes. Okay. So that's what
Speaker 1:  we're doing here. Well you,
Speaker 6:  I think something Blackberry belongs in there don't know if,
Speaker 7:  And that is the argument you make for like, not including like a sports player.
Speaker 7:  Right? Right. You're like a picture. It's someone from we should get a your
Speaker 7:  teammate not that strong. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Understood. So I'm saying not knowing any of the qualifications except
Speaker 7:  the one thing I know of Hall of Fame is only you can't be every
Speaker 7:  episode is yes. Right. Agreed. We
Speaker 7:  can't decide this. The answer's a hard No.
Speaker 1:  Listen, you have to vote on its merits and I think on its merits, it doesn't
Speaker 1:  make it in. I agree. All right. That is it. That's the show we're done here.
Speaker 1:  Thank you both for being here. This was delightful. And thank you as always
Speaker 1:  for being here with us as well. You can watch this on YouTube. You can listen
Speaker 1:  to it everywhere you get podcasts. This show is a production of The Verge
Speaker 1:  and Vox Media. And as always, if you wanna support us, the best way to do
Speaker 1:  so is to subscribe to the verge.com. We'll see you next time.
Speaker 2:  Version
Speaker 1:  History is produced by Victoria Barrios, river Branson, Owen Grove, Brandon
Speaker 1:  Keefer, Travis Lar, Chuck Eric Gomez, Andrew Marino, and Alex Parkin.
Speaker 1:  Studio support from Chris Shirtliff. Our theme music is composed by
Speaker 1:  Brandon McFarland. Be sure to subscribe to the new version history podcast
Speaker 1:  feed to get all of our new episodes as soon as they arrive.