# Transcript
ID: 726210cd-7462-445b-b951-7718e69840f6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2952958397474485805/8884620625306920806/s93290-US-6933s-1740963673.mp3
Description: AI will fix everything, right? In this episode, friend of The Verge (and Waveform co-host) David Imel joins Nilay and David to talk all about Alexa Plus, and the AI-powered voice assistant Amazon thinks can do everything from turn on your lights to order your friend an Uber. The hosts also talk about the other gadgets of the week, from the wild new Sigma BF camera to the boring iPhone 16E. Finally, in the lightning round, they talk about TikTok becoming YouTube and YouTube becoming TikTok and Instagram becoming YouTube and TikTok, plus the latest in Brendan Carr being a dummy and what's coming next from Automattic, DOGE, and everything.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast with being free with
Speaker 4:  Prime.
Speaker 4:  Who knows? Maybe it's, maybe it's $20, maybe it's Prime is $15 and this
Speaker 4:  comes for the Ride.
Speaker 5:  That one feels slightly too plausible to me and I I don't like it.
Speaker 4:  That, that We're free with Prime.
Speaker 5:  We're free with Prime. Like we might be, I honestly
Speaker 4:  Don't know at, at the rate we're going What's,
Speaker 5:  What is free with Prime? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Bundle us in. Jeff. We support Free markets on the,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot to talk about this week. An awful lot to talk about. I'm your
Speaker 4:  friend Neil David Pierce is here. Hello. And I've got a guest in studio.
Speaker 4:  David Amel, the co-host of the Waveform podcast is joining me today.
Speaker 5:  How's it going? It's
Speaker 4:  Good here. It's good. I just like, I just want more human beings physically
Speaker 4:  present with me.
Speaker 5:  Understandable. And Pierce
Speaker 4:  Won't say yes to that idea.
Speaker 5:  We're, we're legally not allowed to be in the same
Speaker 4:  Room. He, you need to stay in your green screen basically.
Speaker 5:  No, it's like, you know how they like won't put the whole group
Speaker 5:  on a plane, like just in case something happens like you and I can't be in
Speaker 5:  the same room just in case we have to be several hundred miles away
Speaker 5:  because the end
Speaker 4:  This, this isn't the right time in America for plane jokes, David.
Speaker 4:  I was just on a flight and it landed and everybody burst into applause. And
Speaker 4:  that is a, you wanna, it's, it's a real thing. You wanna temp check on the
Speaker 4:  country. Yeah. It's the amount of clapping when planes land is, is going
Speaker 4:  up.
Speaker 5:  I got a new plane story in Slack every single time I arrived at the airport
Speaker 5:  and I had to remind everyone, I'm now at the airport,
Speaker 4:  So going on. All right. A lot happened this week.
Speaker 5:  Wait, first Neli, you have to tell us where you went on vacation because
Speaker 5:  as always happens when you go on vacation,
Speaker 5:  some single digit but not insignificant percentage of The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast audience believes that you have quit your job and we'll never ever
Speaker 5:  come back. So can we just, can we just tell the people
Speaker 5:  about your vacation and that you have triumphantly returned?
Speaker 4:  No.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  That's the answer
Speaker 5:  Is neli back. Who knows?
Speaker 4:  I think it's, you want to be at a place in your life where people are like,
Speaker 4:  there's a secret furious plot to defend Aate you every time you take a a
Speaker 4:  break.
Speaker 5:  I, I literally got an email last week that was like, well, NELI seems like
Speaker 5:  he's about to retire. And then they just sort of went on with the rest of
Speaker 5:  their question. I was like, hold on,
Speaker 4:  I might be, you never know. No, we went to Turks and Caicos. It was,
Speaker 4:  it's like Max's winter break. So we went to the beach and we sat on island
Speaker 4:  and then everyone else on that island at that beach was also from
Speaker 4:  New York, which is the whole state is on winter break. So all
Speaker 4:  of the children of New York were on this one small British island.
Speaker 4:  It was great. We caught a, we, we dove for a cog shell, but we did the whole
Speaker 4:  thing. It was just
Speaker 5:  A lot of like little kids going, I'm walking here
Speaker 4:  Basically
Speaker 6:  On the beach. Love
Speaker 4:  That. Basically Max made a bunch of friends. It was delight. My phone service
Speaker 4:  was bad, which was important. Perfect. This is a thing I look for Yeah. In
Speaker 4:  destinations now is it was at t's roaming agreement. Not quite as
Speaker 4:  rock solid as it should be. Yeah, that's where we're going.
Speaker 6:  I use the satellite texting feature on the iPhone quite a bit in the
Speaker 6:  last few months. That's
Speaker 4:  Not great, man.
Speaker 6:  Well, yeah, it's, it's great to not have the service. It is
Speaker 6:  surprising that it works at all. Yeah, but you know, I, it, I'm probably
Speaker 6:  Apple's like perfect boy for that because no one has ever used
Speaker 6:  it except for me. So
Speaker 4:  Have you seen the conspiracy theories? They, they launched the trial of
Speaker 4:  letting T-Mobile iPhones connect to starlink. So now there are
Speaker 4:  conspiracy theories online that Elon Musk is spying on you on your iPhone.
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I don't, I don't have Google Fi, you know, so I'm just using the baseline
Speaker 6:  Apple free feature probably has nothing to do with Elon, but
Speaker 4:  That's very good. Yeah. Does
Speaker 6:  It work well? Oh, it well.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. Is it RCS? Is it SMS? Is it I what? What's the story?
Speaker 6:  Well, it only works with iMessage. Okay. Of course. Which is very dumb.
Speaker 6:  Extremely dumb. But it works fine. They have,
Speaker 4:  Wait, so if you're like in an emergency and you need to text somebody with
Speaker 4:  an Android phone, it's like, sorry, you're a green bubble, you're gonna die.
Speaker 6:  That's a great question. I think in the emergency SOS
Speaker 6:  like version of it, it will send an SMS and it will ping off of that satellite.
Speaker 6:  I got you. But there are much, there are not that many satellites, right.
Speaker 6:  That they're actually using because they just go over pretty quickly. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So you have to wait a few minutes every time, like every five minutes it
Speaker 6:  just goes over the hill and you have to wait another five minutes and then
Speaker 6:  you can connect to it again. Yeah. And then if you're in a car, even ha it
Speaker 6:  has like a glass roof or something. Or if there is one single tree, you cannot,
Speaker 6:  you cannot text via satellite. So it, it works. And
Speaker 6:  I did need to use it in a semi-emergency where someone at home was having
Speaker 6:  a problem and it was really great for me. Hey, that's great. Hashtag not
Speaker 6:  sponsored. So Yeah,
Speaker 4:  See it's spicy here on the, there you go. That's very cool.
Speaker 4:  I just sign up for horrible roaming agreements and be like, my phone isn't
Speaker 4:  working and then I'd stop thinking about the news for
Speaker 6:  A week. Yeah. Roaming your arenas sound terrible. I've had Google Fi since
Speaker 6:  like 2017 and it is overpriced when you live in
Speaker 6:  the United States. But it is great when you have to think about nothing ever
Speaker 6:  at all. Yeah. In other countries. But then Google
Speaker 5:  Periodically forgets that you exist for several years at a
Speaker 6:  Time. That's true. And you're like, can
Speaker 5:  I have new features? Google
Speaker 6:  And Google says, no, no. Yeah, we can have nothing. And then they just rebrand
Speaker 6:  the name of the service and move on. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  Pretty, don't give you any new features.
Speaker 4:  That seems about right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Lots talk about this week there was an Amazon Alexa event.
Speaker 4:  They announced Alexa plus we should talk all about that
Speaker 4:  Panas pane. Literally in the middle of the event while he was announcing
Speaker 4:  Alexa Plus looked at me in the eye and said, Hey, how you doing? It's one
Speaker 4:  of the weirdest and funniest moments at any event I've ever had in my entire
Speaker 4:  life. Very good. Very panus. Only me by the way. That only
Speaker 4:  happened once. And it was to me, he looked at me dead in the eye, said, Hey,
Speaker 4:  how you doing? And I was like, Hey. And then he went on, he continued announcing
Speaker 4:  Alexa plus go watch the video. He d you can see him do
Speaker 6:  It. Did they put it up?
Speaker 4:  It wasn't livestream. There's no videos. There wasn't a live
Speaker 6:  Stream. Yeah. It was really painful for us when we were trying to cover this.
Speaker 4:  I didn't realize, I just said go watch video. 'cause I just assume everything
Speaker 4:  is available. But I don't think they, oh
Speaker 5:  No. Well and I think Panos at one point at the beginning of the event said
Speaker 5:  like, welcome to everybody watching from home. And I was like, well
Speaker 5:  my guy You are used to Microsoft events. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  We just let read your live blog and I,
Speaker 4:  All right, well I might be lying about Panos Fane looking me dead in the
Speaker 4:  eye in the middle of his presentation and saying, Hey, how are you doing?
Speaker 4:  But I promise you it happened.
Speaker 6:  There are like 20 people that can confirm that. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Apple announced a very boring iPhone, which we will talk about for a very
Speaker 4:  boring amount of time. A very appropriate amount time. But it'll be exciting.
Speaker 4:  That's what I meant to say. I don't know about that. There's a Sigma camera
Speaker 4:  that David, I need to yell about at length. There's some framework stuff.
Speaker 4:  We got a lightning round. Brendan Carr. I'm back from vacation buddy.
Speaker 4:  I didn't forget about you. It's got it's packed show. Let's start with Alexa.
Speaker 4:  The, it's what we expected. I will tell you Ponos is on
Speaker 4:  decoder on Monday. So I've talked to him at length about this. And what I
Speaker 4:  mean by what we expected is everybody saw chat, GBT
Speaker 4:  or LLMs in general and they thought, boy, this is how the, these
Speaker 4:  voice assistants should have worked this whole time. And now they announced
Speaker 4:  a version Alexa that approximates that. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well notably none of the assistants for the home have had it yet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it's actually a big deal that they're finally bringing it to something.
Speaker 4:  It is a big deal.
Speaker 4:  I think the most important thing to note here is
Speaker 4:  outside of phones, Alexa has the biggest user
Speaker 4:  base installed base of devices that have AI now,
Speaker 4:  which is just nothing else has gotten there. Yeah. Like Google
Speaker 4:  has sort of rolled out some stuff to some bits and bobs of phone
Speaker 4:  apps. Yeah. But like Google home devices do not have Gemini.
Speaker 6:  True
Speaker 4:  Apple Home pods. They have Siri, which, which
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 4:  Not a thing. Yeah. There is the humane pin.
Speaker 4:  Dear sweet humane pin
Speaker 6:  Humane. Yeah. HP stands for humane pin. By the way,
Speaker 5:  My, my close personal friend, my dead humane pin
Speaker 4:  Pice did not know that the humane pin had been canceled. When I said, I was
Speaker 4:  like, you got the big installed base and you know, it's not like you were
Speaker 4:  sweating the humane pin. He is like, well they're part of HP now. And I was
Speaker 4:  like, no, they're not. And that was the end of that.
Speaker 4:  But like that the, the idea was that voice
Speaker 4:  assistance would be this big platform shift. We'd create a new generation
Speaker 4:  devices that would take over the phone that has absolutely not played out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But there's a lot of echo devices out there.
Speaker 4:  And so this is kind of a big deal. Like just from that standpoint, I
Speaker 5:  Think it hasn't played out, actually doesn't give these things
Speaker 5:  quite enough. Credit people use Alexa a
Speaker 5:  lot. Like, like a lot. It's, it's a running joke that
Speaker 5:  people use it for, you know, music and timers and their lights.
Speaker 5:  And it's largely true, but like the, the idea that
Speaker 5:  people would interact with technology in a different and
Speaker 5:  voice first way like happened it, it came to pass. It is a
Speaker 5:  fully mainstream device and interaction method now.
Speaker 5:  And that's some combination of I think what Apple
Speaker 5:  did with Siri early on and then Google Assistant and Alexa.
Speaker 5:  But I think especially as you talk about like standalone, I talk
Speaker 5:  to my house, things like that happened. It worked. We, we can, we can
Speaker 5:  argue for days about how useful it is and I think the answer is it's not
Speaker 5:  that useful. But like it, it worked at like Amazon did the thing
Speaker 5:  and now the question is like, can we take this behavior
Speaker 5:  that we've trained people and point it at something? Yeah. And I think
Speaker 5:  that is the open question and that is what Alexa Plus is trying to be. It's
Speaker 5:  like, okay, we've now taught you that it's possible to talk to your technology.
Speaker 5:  Now we have to give you things to do with it. And that was always gonna be
Speaker 5:  the hard part and remains the hard part. And I have 1000 questions about
Speaker 5:  what Amazon is trying to do here. But like I, I think it did come to pass
Speaker 5:  in a real way, and this is like the opportunity that Amazon has where they're
Speaker 5:  like, there are a lot of people who are used to talking to their devices
Speaker 5:  now we have to give them something to do with it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that's what I mean by it's, well I don't mean to diminish it by
Speaker 4:  saying it's as expected. What I mean to say is they put out
Speaker 4:  commercials at the Super Bowl with celebrities in them talking to their Alexas.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then people tried to do that and it didn't work because the classic
Speaker 4:  because, and I think at the event a bunch of Amazon executives
Speaker 4:  called it Alexa speak, where you trained yourself to talk to the
Speaker 4:  Alexa or the Google Home or whatever it was in like Robot voice. Yep.
Speaker 4:  And like give it ordered commands. Yeah. Because it's just a computer at
Speaker 4:  the end of the day and it needs like structured commands. And now it's like,
Speaker 4:  oh because there's an LOM, because there's some AI
Speaker 4:  natural language input, you can just talk to it and then also
Speaker 4:  it can figure out what you want and talk back to you naturally. And now you're
Speaker 4:  in this conversation with this thing that can like maybe do stuff. And so
Speaker 4:  that's like the big idea of Alexa plus is like total reboot
Speaker 4:  of Alexa
Speaker 4:  with not one, but like multiple AI models underneath it.
Speaker 4:  The hard part as I understand it, was building the system
Speaker 4:  that figures out what AI model to use when, because you don't wanna
Speaker 4:  light up like all of anthropic to turn off your lights. Right.
Speaker 4:  So like that, that was very much the hard part. That's what everyone is telling
Speaker 4:  me is like they have all these different models they can use all these different
Speaker 4:  ways they can do this stuff and they, they call it orchestration.
Speaker 4:  So you issue it a command and then it figures out how to do it. And then
Speaker 4:  they don't wanna call them apps. So they keep using this term experts.
Speaker 4:  So it's like the photos expert will show you your photos and it's like what
Speaker 4:  is what? And that is just an Amazon language.
Speaker 5:  It's like an actual term of art in the AI community. Yeah. Like one of the
Speaker 5:  things they call this problem is the mixture of experts problem. Yeah. Where
Speaker 5:  it's like if we, if we turn on the whole system every time you have to do
Speaker 5:  anything that's way too much work. No,
Speaker 4:  No. That's the a this is what No, no, no, no, no. That's the AI community
Speaker 4:  is using experts as a term of art in that way. Amazon
Speaker 4:  is like when you ask it for photos, the photos expert
Speaker 4:  shows you
Speaker 5:  Photos. Oh right. No,
Speaker 4:  I agree. It's like, and what they mean there is like, there's an app.
Speaker 5:  It is absurd. Like don't get me wrong, it's like, it's like
Speaker 4:  Everyone's just using words however they want.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Amazon tried to make skills happen and that didn't work and now they're
Speaker 5:  trying to make
Speaker 4:  Experts happen. I think. I think they wanted to not use skills again.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because that went so poorly.
Speaker 4:  So anyway, it's the
Speaker 5:  Whole system. Although ironically skills is actually a better explanation
Speaker 5:  of what Amazon is trying to do this time. Yeah. Last time it was just apps.
Speaker 5:  Now it's actual skills.
Speaker 6:  They can just keep calling it that because no one knew they were called that
Speaker 6:  before. No. So it's fine, they
Speaker 4:  Wanna make this break, but it's all, this is like very clever, right? You
Speaker 4:  can just naturally speak to Alexa.
Speaker 4:  Panos gave a bunch of demos on stage. Other people from Amazon gave a bunch
Speaker 4:  of demos on stage at this event. They were all live. Importantly,
Speaker 4:  he was only talking to echo show devices. So the
Speaker 4:  8, 10, 15, 21 are getting this first, his point
Speaker 4:  of view is that screens are important and you want a screen, he wants to
Speaker 4:  put a screen in your house. And the big change
Speaker 4:  for Amazon is Alexa used to be on everything. Like you buy
Speaker 4:  a smoke detector with Alexa in it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I remember that event.
Speaker 4:  It was crazy. And now they're like, they're cutting down the product line.
Speaker 4:  There is gonna be some new hardware eventually we are told.
Speaker 4:  But they're cutting down the product line. They wanna put a screen in your
Speaker 4:  house that's in the center of your living room or wherever your kitchen,
Speaker 4:  you talk to it, it shows you stuff. You, you, you have a device
Speaker 4:  and that is the centerpiece of their strategy. And then it, it is smart and
Speaker 4:  it can do things, everything from tell your kids a story to, I think this
Speaker 4:  is really fascinating. Like
Speaker 4:  automatically great smart home routines for you. So you're like around
Speaker 4:  bedtime, do bedtime stuff and it's like, okay, I'm gonna din the lights and
Speaker 4:  play some music and turn on your security system and we'll just like come
Speaker 4:  up with some ideas
Speaker 6:  That will go right every time.
Speaker 4:  I have a lot of questions about how that's gonna work. And then it has some,
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna say age agentic 'cause there's a lot of ways for this to work,
Speaker 4:  but it has some cap, it has some ability to do stuff out in the world.
Speaker 4:  So you can have it book an Uber for your friend, which is a we
Speaker 4:  can, we can pull apart that demo piece by piece. I would like. 'cause it
Speaker 4:  was very complicated.
Speaker 6:  Hello to Rabbit
Speaker 4:  Out there. Yeah, exactly. So that was APIs. So with Uber and DoorDash and
Speaker 4:  a handful of others, they're just using the boring old APIs,
Speaker 4:  which is how most computers work.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. I thought the age agentic stuff was going to be a big part of
Speaker 6:  this. And
Speaker 4:  Then the age stuff is, they called for like a dish dishwasher
Speaker 4:  repair. Right. So if, If you like run some service
Speaker 4:  like Thumbtack was the one they, and you don't want to build a bunch of APIs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You can just say to Amazon, it's okay for Alexa to click around on
Speaker 4:  our website and the agent can do that. And then there's like a middle
Speaker 4:  ground where you're like, you can like
Speaker 4:  Suno the music service.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Creating songs out of nothing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Where it's like it's still, it's gotta do some API stuff but it can
Speaker 4:  still click around on the website. Weird. Like weird, weird stuff.
Speaker 4:  And a lot of the demos of that capability,
Speaker 4:  I I were less believable in the moment. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Just like Rabbit.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 6:  I know that they're partners but my question with any of the agentic stuff
Speaker 6:  is what happens. Like are they actually just targeting certain
Speaker 6:  areas of the site or are they doing recognition of the buttons? Like Rabbit
Speaker 6:  always says it was recognition. As soon as one of these websites changes
Speaker 6:  their website, everything breaks. Yep. That happened before. Could see it
Speaker 6:  happening again.
Speaker 4:  Well, so Rabbit's pitch was it could go to any website. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  really they had just like card coded itself to like Uber and Spotify. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Amazon's pitch is a little different, which is that people will come to
Speaker 4:  Amazon right. And they will say, we would like our
Speaker 4:  website to be part of your agentic system. So presumably there's
Speaker 4:  not like the incentives are aligned more so to make sure the
Speaker 4:  agent can use the website consistently or like you'll maybe you'll build
Speaker 4:  a special or website and Yeah. That's even less of a lift than building an
Speaker 4:  API but you can still do it. Yeah. I dunno. But I do know that the
Speaker 4:  straight up book, my friend in Uber at JFK made
Speaker 4:  no sense. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like no sense how do I
Speaker 6:  Know what pickup zone to go to? Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean there are a hundred things about that demo that don't make any
Speaker 5:  sense. Like, and and and the way I've come to think about all the age agentic
Speaker 5:  stuff is there's like, well
Speaker 4:  Tell people what the demo is. 'cause apparently there's no livestream change.
Speaker 5:  Well I'll, I'll I'll get there. But the, the, I think the way to think about
Speaker 5:  the age agentic stuff in general is like there's a set of things that are
Speaker 5:  just like knobs that some app can expose in an API
Speaker 5:  and rather than try to fake your website, you should just use their API and
Speaker 5:  Amazon has the business deals to do that, right? So like if
Speaker 5:  I don't have to use ticketmaster.com and I can just access the Ticketmaster
Speaker 5:  database victory, right? Like that is, that's still agentic and that's still
Speaker 5:  good. That is the correct answer. In the middle there's the stuff that is
Speaker 5:  like solvable internet problems, right? That it's like go to Bing
Speaker 5:  and click on the first result is like a, a thing chat GPT does all the time
Speaker 5:  when you're an operator. Right. That or like scan down this page for things
Speaker 5:  with five star results. These are like tractable problems for ai. And
Speaker 5:  then there's the thing that's just like, ah, we'll figure it out. Like AI
Speaker 5:  is smart, it'll figure it out and we will see what happens. The problem with
Speaker 5:  all of those is there are a billion edge cases to every single one. Right.
Speaker 5:  And lemme see if I remember the demo correctly. For Uber it was, it
Speaker 5:  started with booking a restaurant reservation. Yep. Successfully booked
Speaker 5:  the restaurant reservation through OpenTable, which is presumably just an
Speaker 5:  API that Alexa has access to, again, fairly tractable problem,
Speaker 5:  right? Like there are times there is a restaurant, I notice how many people
Speaker 5:  like it can click the dropdowns for you in the API. Fine. The next thing
Speaker 5:  was my friend is coming from JFK, can you book
Speaker 5:  an Uber to pick them up and I guess bring them to the restaurant.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Right there. I just wanna say right there a fully
Speaker 4:  insane thing to say to any, any another
Speaker 4:  human being to your friend who's landing at JFK I've booked you
Speaker 4:  an Uber. Uber, why?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Right?
Speaker 4:  Yes. You know who can book an Uber, use your phone. Anyone with a phone,
Speaker 4:  like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I will say I have a, a friend who is an, an assistant for
Speaker 6:  a hedge fund manager and this is stuff that she does
Speaker 6:  all the time. And so I see an end case
Speaker 6:  where way in the future the, the idea of a lot of
Speaker 6:  these AI platforms is like, what if we could take this job that people do
Speaker 6:  and get rid of it? Yeah. Yeah. And so in this universe
Speaker 6:  it's sort of like, just automate this job away. Right.
Speaker 6:  But
Speaker 4:  Right. But I but I'm saying the command, I need an Uber or I would like to
Speaker 4:  have a car pick me up. Yeah. Your hedge fund manager friend. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  boss. Your hedge fund manager. In this example, the hedge fund manager just
Speaker 4:  says out loud, I need a car. And then a person uses the Uber app. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  In this case they would just, they would still just tell their own
Speaker 4:  AI Yeah. To book them a car.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's, it, I, that was the part that got me like right there in that demo
Speaker 4:  was like, I'm gonna send my friend a car at JFK is in, in like,
Speaker 4:  in a very abstract sense. Makes a lot of sense and then keep
Speaker 4:  going. Right.
Speaker 5:  Well, but there
Speaker 4:  Are, but just that instinct was like very confusing to me.
Speaker 5:  Also, David, to your point, like in, in that system where I'm the assistant
Speaker 5:  working with somebody, odds are overwhelmingly good that we share an Uber
Speaker 5:  account that your picture is going to be there somewhere that you're an authorized
Speaker 5:  user that it's gonna pop up on your phone to tell you where to go. So like
Speaker 5:  these, these systems exist that I know what terminal you're at
Speaker 5:  and have a way to tell people what terminal,
Speaker 6:  Like Right.
Speaker 5:  There's a, there's a shared universe of information that exists in that world
Speaker 5:  that does not exist in my friend Molly is flying into JFK.
Speaker 6:  Right? Right. And so,
Speaker 5:  So, but in all of this, okay, now I have a, a series of this
Speaker 4:  Super sounds like you're about to do a drug deal. By the way, every time
Speaker 4:  you say my friend Molly is the JF k my,
Speaker 5:  That was, I forget who it was and I'm sorry, but somebody in our slack was
Speaker 5:  like, this definitely ends with just a bag of drugs being delivered to your
Speaker 4:  Restaurants. This is starting to come into focus. Alright.
Speaker 5:  But so it raises all these questions, right? Like, okay, where at J-F-K-J-F-K
Speaker 5:  is an enormous airport with lots of terminals and lots of different pickup
Speaker 5:  points at each of those terminals. How is it going to figure that
Speaker 5:  out? How is it going to tell the Uber driver? And then how is it gonna communicate
Speaker 5:  that information to Molly who is completely looped out of this whole set
Speaker 5:  of information We
Speaker 6:  Need to normalize just doing really basic tasks yourself. This takes
Speaker 5:  Click the button
Speaker 4:  Three seconds in the demo. It was like, I've booked a car
Speaker 4:  to pick up your friend Molly at JFK and at no point. And then I think
Speaker 4:  the next command was like, text Molly this information. Right. But like I
Speaker 4:  I, I'm assuming some of our listeners have never landed at JFK.
Speaker 4:  It is a huge sprawling, ridiculous
Speaker 4:  airport and it's uber pickup situation is
Speaker 4:  among the worst I believe in the world. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's very bad. Yeah. Second to LA Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like LA is like you're going to a different city Yeah. To get on this Uber.
Speaker 4:  Like have you, have you thought about standing in a parking lot six miles
Speaker 4:  away from the airport? Yeah. Like that's LA Yep. JFK is almost as bad.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I just landed back at JFK and I had to get on a train to another
Speaker 4:  terminal to walk up a flight of stairs to go to another weird parking lot.
Speaker 4:  And no one is, was happy about that. The Uber driver was like, I went to
Speaker 4:  the first terminal and I was like, the app is, it's all bad. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And the idea that Alexa collapsed that to JFK Right. Pano said all of the
Speaker 4:  demos are real, I'm I'm sure in some universe
Speaker 4:  it just picked the first result for JFK in the Uber app and it was like at
Speaker 4:  the cargo terminal or something. The
Speaker 5:  Way that that ends is there is an Uber circling JFK
Speaker 5:  endlessly looking for your friend Mike
Speaker 4:  Powering down the runways who
Speaker 5:  I would point out does not have access to your Uber account because you
Speaker 5:  don't share an Uber account with your friend Molly. Because why would you
Speaker 5:  do that? And so your friend Molly actually has no way to contact this Uber
Speaker 5:  driver. So actually what you've done is you've invented a more complicated
Speaker 5:  situation to solve than If you had just done it yourself.
Speaker 4:  And I just wanna point out, by the way, this is the simplest case of the
Speaker 4:  integration where everything happened with APIs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like Uber has APIs that are exposed to Amazon in this way.
Speaker 4:  The OpenTable has APIs that are exposed to Amazon this way. The next
Speaker 4:  one where it was slightly more agentic
Speaker 4:  was I to me is like where it all starts to fall apart.
Speaker 4:  Right. Because the Uber case you can solve you, you can solve
Speaker 4:  it, right. You, Molly can send you some Uber access code or give you
Speaker 4:  access to her account.
Speaker 5:  It's also the kind of thing you're never gonna do. And in the ca in the real
Speaker 5:  case where it's like, book me an Uber to go to the airport, perfectly
Speaker 5:  solvable problem. Like that is, that is a thing that will work. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Again, normalize doing basic things yourself. Yeah. No, that's what I mean.
Speaker 5:  It's like if Molly were just to get off and be like, Alexa, I'm, I'm at
Speaker 5:  terminal five. Can you get me an Uber to this restaurant? Like that is, that
Speaker 5:  is actually a thing that every step of the way is a solvable problem for
Speaker 5:  ai.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Especially If you have access to Uber. The problem the,
Speaker 4:  I'll talk about the age agentic one 'cause I'm more curious about how they
Speaker 4:  will solve some of those problems. The problem is that, you know, who would
Speaker 4:  also love that deal is Lyft. Right? And so you're saying book
Speaker 4:  me an Uber and that means one thing. But If you say, book me a car, now Amazon
Speaker 4:  gets to pick what service or it gets to, and this is what they really
Speaker 4:  don't want to have happen. It gets to go look at both services and say the
Speaker 4:  Lyft is $5 cheaper than the Uber. Do you want me to book you the Lyft? And
Speaker 4:  like I do that on my phone right now and the apps can't stop me. But
Speaker 4:  there's nothing stopping Uber from saying Amazon, we wanna be
Speaker 4:  exclusive here. Right. And I I I always call this the DoorDash problem. Like,
Speaker 4:  these service providers get commodified in these interfaces and there's no
Speaker 4:  incentive for them to participate unless Amazon pays them money. And
Speaker 4:  then now we start making deals that prevent you from competing. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  you can just see this, it's really fascinating. It's really interesting.
Speaker 4:  It's what everybody wants to have like a butler to booking cars for them
Speaker 4:  left and right and then actually making it work requires a bunch
Speaker 4:  of companies to basically take themselves out of the loop.
Speaker 4:  And it's unclear right now as to why, If you like order me a
Speaker 4:  sandwich and DoorDash never gets to show you an ad or upsell you on
Speaker 4:  fries or get you to sign up for DoorDash plus or whatever they call it,
Speaker 4:  why would they
Speaker 5:  Pay part of
Speaker 4:  It? Why would they do it? Yeah. Right. Because they all, their margins are
Speaker 4:  just crushed and now they're just a commodity provider of sandwiches. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Next to whoever else. And like I don't, I just dunno why they'll do it. We'll
Speaker 5:  See, I don't know. But If you, If you then get to be the exclusive commodity
Speaker 5:  provider of sandwiches, that's a pretty good business
Speaker 5:  for one company. It's a pretty good
Speaker 4:  Business. It's a great business for one company that has no growth potential,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. Like, like you will be forever as only
Speaker 4:  as big as the sandwich market inside of the Amazon Alexa
Speaker 5:  App. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Maybe that's all you aspire to. And that's fine. David, listen
Speaker 5:  Me, I have gold.
Speaker 4:  The harder one was when they were like, my dishwasher and my stove is
Speaker 4:  broken. Find me or repair person for my Meade appliance meal
Speaker 4:  appliance is by the way, very expensive, very expensive to fix. So this is
Speaker 4:  a perfect, only Amazon executives have this specific problem kind of demo.
Speaker 4:  And it went onto a website called Thumbtack, which like has a list
Speaker 4:  of repair people just like Angie's List or any of
Speaker 4:  these other billion websites that are like this. And I'm sitting there watching
Speaker 4:  that demo and it did it, right? It clicked around the website, it found a
Speaker 4:  service provider with some reviews and said they're gonna come at eight in
Speaker 4:  the morning at the end. And I was like, that's great. 'cause now they don't
Speaker 4:  have to use those websites. And then the reality of all of those websites
Speaker 4:  is you go on there to find a plumber or a repair person for your
Speaker 4:  dishwasher or whoever, and they don't give a shit about those websites. And
Speaker 4:  they have not actually handed their business over to Thumbtack and
Speaker 4:  let Thumbtack run their schedule or their billing or their customer relationships.
Speaker 4:  They've just listed themselves there. 'cause they wanna be in some SEO
Speaker 4:  result for people searching for repairmen. And then you call and then they
Speaker 4:  run their own business and it's like, oh, Amazon depends on that
Speaker 4:  whole ecosystem actually working. Right? And like there's
Speaker 4:  nothing Alexa can do about the fact that it mostly doesn't work.
Speaker 4:  Like If you, If you go on some of these websites, like sometimes yes the
Speaker 4:  house painter comes and they actually let their, those kinds of middlemen
Speaker 4:  services run their business. But for the most part they're like, I
Speaker 4:  don't want anything to do. It's like, I want you to pay me in cash Under
Speaker 4:  the table is like the end result of most
Speaker 5:  Of those interactions. Well, and it's specifically because all of those businesses
Speaker 5:  have been chopped off at the knees by middleman after middleman, after
Speaker 5:  middleman after middleman. And so I mean you're, you're starting to
Speaker 5:  see this with restaurants and stuff in the DoorDash universe where they're
Speaker 5:  just like, no, like I, I will deliver my own food by paying
Speaker 5:  a high teenager to drive it to your house because that is actually a business
Speaker 5:  I can afford. And so like all this stuff has been so
Speaker 5:  centralized that it's actually broken for the
Speaker 5:  businesses themselves and they're starting to run away from it. But because
Speaker 5:  it has been so centralized and this is the bet that Amazon and everybody
Speaker 5:  else is making, it's really hard to decentralize it because
Speaker 5:  now everybody is used to being on those platforms. And so, like if you're
Speaker 5:  Uber Eats or DoorDash, if you're a restaurant now you have to make the
Speaker 5:  bet that people will go find my restaurant rather than just pick the next
Speaker 5:  best thing on the platform. And I think how that shakes out remains to
Speaker 5:  be seen. But like it's pretty clear which one of those things Alexa is betting
Speaker 5:  on, which is that platform convenience, which you can make it even more convenient
Speaker 5:  by abstracting it all the way to order me a pizza or find me a repairman
Speaker 5:  will outweigh actually having successful businesses on the other
Speaker 5:  side.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I I think this is just like, this is the problem. Like
Speaker 4:  I should just write a piece called the DoorDash problem. Like why would you
Speaker 4:  wanna run the pipes between you and the sandwich in a world
Speaker 4:  where that is becoming the most, the least
Speaker 4:  differentiated part of the entire experience. Yeah. Right. If you run
Speaker 4:  Thumbtack, and I'm sorry if there's like a, we have a bunch of listeners
Speaker 4:  who work at Thumbtack. I mean, I'm, I'm proud of you and
Speaker 4:  you're doing a good job every day, another victory.
Speaker 4:  But like what, what about Thumbtack is
Speaker 4:  making it better on both sides of that equation that isn't gonna just get
Speaker 4:  completely erased by the fact that Alexa's just clicking on your website
Speaker 4:  for you. Great. Like someone will figure that out.
Speaker 4:  And that's like, so that's the hardest stuff that they demoed. It's not rolling
Speaker 4:  out at first.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna roll that over time. What is rolling out first on the Echo
Speaker 4:  show devices is like an even harder problem, which is we're gonna automate
Speaker 4:  your smartphone.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, oh, like no part of this is easy. Is that a harder
Speaker 5:  Problem?
Speaker 4:  So PATOS told me and someone De Dakota on Monday, he's like,
Speaker 4:  the Alexa smart home ecosystem was already so good
Speaker 4:  that everything we demoed required no new code. Right? Alexa Plus could
Speaker 4:  just like push all the buttons and twist all the knobs any way it wanted
Speaker 4:  to and make its own routines because that stuff has just been ready to go
Speaker 4:  for so long. So they yes, I think they think it's good.
Speaker 4:  What I mean by it's harder is you buy this new device,
Speaker 4:  you plop it down in your kitchen and then now you have a smart home.
Speaker 4:  That's the promise. But the reality is you've gotta
Speaker 4:  add everything to your Alexa smart home system. Yes. All those cloud
Speaker 4:  accounts have to sync every, some stuff you're
Speaker 4:  controlling in an app on your iPhone. Another thing, you're right, like you
Speaker 4:  actually have to still do the setup to make the magic happen and
Speaker 4:  nothing about the setup has gotten particularly easier here. And you need
Speaker 4:  to decide where you
Speaker 5:  Wanna set it
Speaker 4:  Up on and and then you need to decide where your automations and routines
Speaker 4:  live. Right. And if that's gonna be Amazon forever.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Are they Amazon or are they on Google Home? Are they on the manufacturer's
Speaker 6:  website? Yeah, there's like five different places that you could potentially
Speaker 6:  set up all of these devices.
Speaker 5:  David, are you a smart home guy?
Speaker 6:  Minimally. I live in a Brooklyn basement. What
Speaker 5:  Do you have?
Speaker 6:  I pretty much completely put everything on
Speaker 6:  HomeKit I guess. I guess it's called HomeKit. Yeah. Because I have Eve stuff.
Speaker 6:  Mm. So, but it is only Eve smart plugs and smart
Speaker 6:  blinds. I got them because of Matter
Speaker 6:  famously does not really work, which is cool, but
Speaker 6:  it at least it's all in the same thing. But I also do have a
Speaker 6:  singular Google Home Hub mini that I was
Speaker 6:  dreaming of being able to tell to make my blinds go up and down
Speaker 6:  famously still does not work.
Speaker 5:  This is the Yeah, this is the like what a perfect smart home scenario. We're
Speaker 5:  like, okay, I bought all the pieces. Yeah. And each of the things does the
Speaker 5:  things that are required for this puzzle to fit together and yet it
Speaker 5:  doesn't for some unknowable technical reason. Yeah. That will never, ever
Speaker 5:  get solved.
Speaker 6:  I set up a routine that automates my blinds, that's all that I really care
Speaker 6:  about. And then I have a widget on my phone that turns my lights on and off.
Speaker 6:  And I really don't care to make it more automated than that.
Speaker 5:  I think that's good. And truthfully, I think like a, I think that is
Speaker 5:  most people's smart home desire, right? Yeah. Like I want one thing to
Speaker 5:  happen when I do another thing is I genuinely believe the extent of most
Speaker 5:  people's smart home wishes. Yeah. And that's also a thing that something
Speaker 5:  like Alexa Plus is well positioned to do pretty well because
Speaker 5:  what, what these routines and things have is a like massive
Speaker 5:  user interface problem. It's the same thing like a rail on apple shortcuts
Speaker 5:  all the time. And it's like, it's this massively powerful thing buried
Speaker 5:  behind what amounts to like a scripting language. And you need to go through
Speaker 5:  a series of really complicated like if then statements. Yep. So to be able
Speaker 5:  to just say to this system, Hey, every time I turn off my alarm clock,
Speaker 5:  turn the lights on in the bathroom is like that's actually a thing that a
Speaker 5:  system like an LLM is well positioned to understand what
Speaker 5:  that means. And then if Amazon has done a as good a job as
Speaker 5:  P is saying, which I think reasonably probably has of
Speaker 5:  understanding all of those endpoints, it can actually put all
Speaker 5:  of that together in a way that strikes me as like it would work. Right. And
Speaker 5:  then I'm just at a point where all I have to do is learn how to explain what
Speaker 5:  I want rather than like program it in detail in the Alexa app. But
Speaker 4:  So that even that explain what I want the, you know, their examples were
Speaker 4:  come up with a bedtime routine and it was like
Speaker 4:  Alexa just was like, I don't know, I'm gonna play some music. I'm gonna turn
Speaker 4:  off these lights, I'm gonna dim these other lights. Call it a bedtime routine.
Speaker 5:  I really don't think that's a real use case. This is one of the things that
Speaker 5:  drives me the craziest about all of these things is it's like what? Like
Speaker 5:  it's, I, I still have this picture on my desktop for some
Speaker 5:  reason from, for like years of this Apple event from
Speaker 5:  years ago, I think it was an iPad launch where they had this picture they
Speaker 5:  were showing like the lifestyle photos they always show and it was a, it
Speaker 5:  was a guy sitting in like the crook of two beams on the Brooklyn
Speaker 5:  Bridge sketching on his iPad. And I was just like, no one does this
Speaker 5:  like talk about your
Speaker 4:  Products. You didn't do that when you lived in New York.
Speaker 5:  I did it the once and they took my picture and they paid me for it and then
Speaker 5:  I went home. It's fine. But it's just like all of these things is Jake,
Speaker 5:  I, I spend a lot of time wondering if part of the problem
Speaker 5:  here is that no one actually understands what any regular human would ever
Speaker 5:  want to do with these products. Because the idea that I'm gonna come home
Speaker 5:  one day and be like, Alexa, make up a bed bedtime routine. I'm so sorry to
Speaker 5:  everybody who's hearing a say Alexa over and over by the way. Wait, you
Speaker 4:  Never, you never just ask a computer to make it nice when you're sleepy.
Speaker 4:  No.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Never. And no one is going to and the idea that I'm gonna ask it to and then
Speaker 5:  I'm going to live with what it creates for me for the rest of my life is
Speaker 5:  just preposterous. And so I hate this stuff now. Yeah. 'cause it's like show
Speaker 5:  me this product as it's going to actually work for people instead of like
Speaker 5:  a fake thing that seems vaguely impressive until you poke at it at all.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It seems to me that most of these companies extrapolate this stuff
Speaker 6:  to the furthest degree where they're like, how can we reduce as much friction
Speaker 6:  as possible between the user and doing what they want to do And they just
Speaker 6:  forget that people don't wanna just give up complete control to these systems.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The famous book me a travel itinerary
Speaker 6:  and book my plane and book my hotel, nobody wants to do that. And
Speaker 6:  yet every company uses it as their example. Luckily
Speaker 6:  Amazon did not actually have them book the itinerary. They just
Speaker 6:  made the itinerary. Which is better. That is better. I
Speaker 5:  Agree. I like that.
Speaker 6:  But still that is like the extrapolated version of that, right? Like nobody
Speaker 6:  even in the home, nobody wants you to bedtime routine.
Speaker 6:  I don't know what it's gonna be. Let's just find out if that's gonna be the
Speaker 6:  case, let me like test five of them out and then I will pick. People don't
Speaker 6:  actually wanna just give up complete control to a system like this. Especially
Speaker 6:  when it's completely random, you don't know what it's gonna be. Totally.
Speaker 6:  Well,
Speaker 4:  So I have many things to say.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry. I'm sorry to everyone.
Speaker 4:  One, I think the hard part here is not the reduction of friction. It's letting
Speaker 4:  people know they can do this stuff at all. And that I think requires,
Speaker 4:  but does
Speaker 6:  Anyone want to
Speaker 4:  Yes. To some, to some broad approximation
Speaker 4:  just have stuff happen is a thing people want, like
Speaker 4:  when I get home, turn on the lights is nice. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just nice. Right. And I am convinced that like my family does not
Speaker 4:  know how lights turn on or off anymore because many lights in our
Speaker 4:  house just turn on or off throughout the day. Interesting. Like we have,
Speaker 4:  we have Hugh Lights in our kitchen and they're in adaptive mode. So they
Speaker 4:  just go from cool in the morning to warm at night.
Speaker 4:  I think this is the coolest shit in the world. No,
Speaker 6:  That's great. Someday Max
Speaker 5:  Is gonna go to college and like call you from her dorm room being like, why
Speaker 5:  is it dark?
Speaker 4:  So Jen Tey told us that her kids, her teenage children don't know how
Speaker 4:  to use house keys. Oh
Speaker 6:  My God.
Speaker 4:  Which is incredible. We're
Speaker 5:  Ruining future generations. Neli.
Speaker 4:  But, so I got a text from Becky and she was like, the
Speaker 4:  light, the kitchen is the wrong color. And I was like, this is victory. I'm
Speaker 4:  getting divorced now, but this is victory. The kitchen is the wrong color.
Speaker 4:  Like the, the lights are warm in the morning. And she's like, why is it so
Speaker 4:  orange in here? And I was like, I've won and I've also lost in like equal
Speaker 4:  measure. Yep. So it's true that people like it when things just sort
Speaker 4:  of like happen the right way at the right time. Sure. And I think most people
Speaker 4:  cannot express that in structured if then statements.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like if I come home between these times,
Speaker 4:  turn on lights when garage opens is people
Speaker 4:  do not speak that way.
Speaker 5:  And going through every single little thing in your home and having to create
Speaker 5:  an, if that statement is just really tedious.
Speaker 4:  But you can say, when I get home, turn the lights on and Alexa figures out
Speaker 4:  how to script that for you. That I think is very powerful. Yes. The, the
Speaker 4:  jump is getting people to even understand that this is now
Speaker 4:  a thing you can ask for. And then delivering it in a way
Speaker 4:  that is consistently good enough that they, they tell their friends about
Speaker 4:  it and then their friends buy Alexa and a bunch of smart lights and like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know about any of that. Right. Like the comparison that I have to,
Speaker 4:  that is like, I keep talking, I always talk about the local news test. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Like what piece of technology will like break through on the local news
Speaker 4:  And like the first iPhone was like, look at this, you could pinch to Zoom
Speaker 4:  and like that was all you needed. And then they sold all the iPhones. This
Speaker 4:  one's like, here's what you do, you buy this weird screen, it can talk to
Speaker 4:  you like a person and tell you stories. Also you need to change all of the
Speaker 4:  light bulbs in your ass. And it's like, well this is just, what are we doing?
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 5:  To your point, you know what that thing was the first time around with Alexa
Speaker 5:  was music. Yeah, yeah. Was you can have it play music just by asking for
Speaker 5:  It was like, oh that's crazy. That was, that was the breakthrough thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. And I, I think everybody has wanted the smart home to be that
Speaker 5:  next thing and it hasn't been. But but so
Speaker 5:  now the question is like, if you've made it easier to the point where you
Speaker 5:  can just do this as quickly as asking for it,
Speaker 5:  like maybe it becomes that thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I do think there are an awful lot of people out there who have
Speaker 4:  bought gov, light strips or weird smart bulbs.
Speaker 4:  There's an awful lot of smart locks out there. Like some of this
Speaker 4:  stuff is ready to go. Yeah. And to be linked together in automations like
Speaker 4:  this. And I like, you know, AI is good at coding
Speaker 4:  and like really what we're talking about is like write a little script for
Speaker 4:  me. Okay. Like there some of this all
Speaker 4:  clicks together but I'm still just at like, you have to get people to even
Speaker 4:  want it.
Speaker 5:  I also, I cannot stop thinking about how important cameras are to all
Speaker 5:  of this and how many feelings this is going to make people feel about cameras.
Speaker 5:  Like one of the demos was being able to ask
Speaker 5:  if somebody had walked the dog recently I think. And it'll actually like
Speaker 5:  comb back through your security camera data to see, oh no
Speaker 4:  Actually I know how that one works. There's another demo that was scarier
Speaker 4:  from the camera sense.
Speaker 5:  Oh okay. Tell me more. You were there. I wasn't there. Let
Speaker 4:  Me know. Someone has walked the dog recently is
Speaker 4:  that's just Amazon owns a bunch of stuff including Ring. Yeah. So If you
Speaker 4:  have ring cameras today without any of this Alexa stuff, it will detect
Speaker 4:  pets, it will detect people, it will detect packages. That's a service that
Speaker 4:  you have to get from Ring as part of the Ring service. But that's just a
Speaker 4:  ring video search product that Alexa as an API can just
Speaker 4:  call. So that wasn't Alexa doing any of that. That was just
Speaker 4:  ring. Okay. And it was just being expressed through the Echo show.
Speaker 5:  Still a little creepy how accessible you've made the archive
Speaker 5:  of that recording. But, but sure. Fair enough. What was the other demo?
Speaker 4:  It's the same accessible ness as it is in the Ring app today.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Right. Like if especially 'cause they they already owned it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, that's, that's
Speaker 4:  Fair. Like, like the problems with ring accessibility are like, and then
Speaker 4:  they send it to the cops. Like that's a different Right there is that but
Speaker 4:  like inside of your ring archive, like it gets indexed and
Speaker 4:  searchable. The one you're thinking about I believe
Speaker 4:  is when you see my daughter play this music
Speaker 4:  and that one is very creepy to me.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that is creepy. I don't like that at all. Yep. And that thing is
Speaker 5:  like, again, so much of what we're describing works
Speaker 5:  way better If you have cameras, If you have lots of cameras
Speaker 5:  that do lots of things really convincingly like the
Speaker 5:  play music or turn on the lights when I get home thing. Like
Speaker 5:  you can do that a bunch of ways, but the actual cleanest and most reliable
Speaker 5:  way to do that, to know that it's you coming home is cameras
Speaker 5:  and this, this, this system in general a requires a
Speaker 5:  vast amount of data to really work. And one of the things that Panos talked
Speaker 5:  about a bunch and that Amazon is making very clear is like it's going to
Speaker 5:  ask and remember a lot of information about you. You can forward
Speaker 5:  emails, you can send, IM like, Alexa would like to know every single thing
Speaker 5:  that happens to you all the time. Always everywhere. All the time. And like
Speaker 5:  on the one hand, fine, Google has that data anyway just by virtue of like
Speaker 5:  we are all alive. But Amazon wants it too.
Speaker 5:  And it wants your camera data and the more data you give it, the better this
Speaker 5:  system will be. And that, that linear scale
Speaker 5:  is going to be deeply fascinating to see people try to walk through.
Speaker 4:  It's just so funny because I can tell that you have not tried to set up any
Speaker 4:  smart home automations. Do you know what the best way to know that your home
Speaker 4:  is? Amazon has no access to it. It's when your fucking phone
Speaker 4:  connects to your wifi network.
Speaker 5:  Amazon owns Euro so Sure they do.
Speaker 4:  Oh that's interesting. But that's like too creepy. That's like one
Speaker 4:  step too creepy. But like that is how a bunch of home kit automation.
Speaker 4:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  No, you're right. That's
Speaker 4:  Good point. Right. So like when you do, if you've ever set up a home kit
Speaker 4:  automation. Yeah. Right. There's run this when no one's home or just I'm
Speaker 4:  home or anyone is home and all it's looking for is whether various
Speaker 4:  devices signed in I iCloud or on your network. Hmm. You can do, I think there's
Speaker 4:  a little bit of geofencing in there, but it's, it's the network connection
Speaker 4:  that like tells you you're home. And
Speaker 4:  it's funny 'cause the other day my wife and I were both
Speaker 4:  not home and Max came home and none of the lights turned on
Speaker 4:  because she doesn't have an iCloud device. Ooh.
Speaker 6:  She doesn't know how to turn the lights on.
Speaker 4:  So she No, she turned on the lights, but they were on, I would say wrong.
Speaker 4:  Go. Well Max is
Speaker 5:  Just sitting in the dark.
Speaker 4:  I was like, why are the lights wrong? Is actually what I
Speaker 5:  Said. She's like, now I need an iPhone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Basically. But it's really interesting to think, oh
Speaker 4:  they'll, they'll link Arrow into this and know like network states of devices.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot they can do. Did was this compelling to you?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, in some ways. I mean the fact that the Echoes
Speaker 6:  were sort of the first ways that people interacted with any form of
Speaker 6:  voice-based ai Yeah. I think was interesting to me because Amazon was so
Speaker 6:  early to that and then they were so late to everything else. And so
Speaker 6:  this like dream of my mother can set up something and come home and start
Speaker 6:  talking to her smart speaker and it actually does things instead of
Speaker 6:  me having to teach her voice lessons or like Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Specific lessons on how to talk to the AI is a big thing.
Speaker 6:  The automations I if they work is going to be the giant
Speaker 6:  question. Yeah. I would love it If you could ask it to have an,
Speaker 6:  an automation and then it just randomly it creates a bunch that you
Speaker 6:  can pick from. Yeah. Because I just, I don't know. I understand some
Speaker 6:  people probably just want things to be made for them and just be developed,
Speaker 6:  but having no, no say in any of the development of these things and just
Speaker 6:  letting it do things for you just feels very sketch almost as sketch
Speaker 6:  as the pickup my friend from JFK, you know what I mean? I don't know if it
Speaker 6:  will work. This is the thing. That's
Speaker 5:  One reason that I think pushing really hard towards screen
Speaker 5:  devices is really smart for Amazon. Yes. Because it just lets it do that
Speaker 5:  kind of stuff where it's gonna be able to be like, Hey, here's the thing
Speaker 5:  I was gonna do. Make sure this is make sure we're cool. Like
Speaker 5:  is this, is this what you want? Is this your grocery order? Like do you want
Speaker 5:  this or this? Like, it's the kind of sort of quick back and forth.
Speaker 6:  Did they show any of that?
Speaker 4:  Yes, they did. The grocery demo in particular, one
Speaker 4:  was like so far from what anyone would ever do, but also the coolest one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So they were like, go to Amazon Fresh, I wanna do this
Speaker 4:  recipe, here's ingest. Like I wanna make these cookies and start filling
Speaker 4:  it out. And then he was talking to it
Speaker 4:  while he was like clicking quantities on the screen. Yeah. And so he was
Speaker 4:  adjusting one row of data while it was like adding this. That's kind of so,
Speaker 4:  and it was just like very cool, like multimodal.
Speaker 6:  Are people gonna do that?
Speaker 4:  I I don't, I have no idea. It's a
Speaker 6:  Big question. Gen
Speaker 5:  Tuy will and no one else. Yeah. But that is the kind of interaction
Speaker 5:  that If you can get it makes all of this stuff work better. Right. Right.
Speaker 5:  'cause it's like the, the first time you ask a question and you get like
Speaker 5:  a 600 word long spoken answer, you're like, this is nothing.
Speaker 5:  I hate this.
Speaker 6:  That's the part that it needs to fix. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But then it's, and and this is the thing, I, I've always gotten a kick outta
Speaker 5:  this in, in like sci-fi and stuff. Like, they always just gravitate towards,
Speaker 5:  let me show you. Right. And then it's like a put it put, put it on a screen
Speaker 5:  and I can look at it, which is like better movie making than listening to
Speaker 5:  something talk for four minutes. But it's also just better user experience.
Speaker 5:  It's like, do you want this or this? And I don't have to show them or I don't
Speaker 5:  have to read them to you. I can show them
Speaker 6:  To you. Right. Famously, the Google Home Minis that every carrier on the
Speaker 6:  planet throws 15 of you at at Christmas. Every single time you
Speaker 6:  ask it, what's the weather? Or turn the light on it goes. Just so you know,
Speaker 6:  in the morning we can also do this. Just ask me what to do every single time.
Speaker 6:  Every time. And I just want, okay, bing, you know, that's it.
Speaker 5:  Or just turn the light on. What If you didn't talk? And then I knew it worked
Speaker 5:  because the light was on. What
Speaker 6:  If you didn't talk? Yeah. That's a visual cue. I, I think as long as you
Speaker 6:  have some sort of cue, which is like why the screen is important, especially
Speaker 6:  when you're having it do these tasks that you cannot see because they're
Speaker 6:  APIs or because they're like age agentic or whatever.
Speaker 4:  Oh. This is one of the coolest parts of the whole thing. They call them lexicons.
Speaker 6:  I do like that.
Speaker 4:  So the little blue bar on the bottom of the screen turns into like, line
Speaker 4:  animations told me that he wants sort to be like 200, but now they're 33
Speaker 4:  because he's approving all of them individually. Okay. Which is
Speaker 4:  great. That's cool. I love it. That's good. They're very cute. And then Alexa
Speaker 4:  just sort of picks whatever kind it wants. Mm. Like it turns into like a
Speaker 4:  little line drawing of music notes or like a picture of Oh, if it thinks
Speaker 4:  it's arguing with you, it shows you a ping pong paddle going back and forth.
Speaker 4:  'cause you're, you know, I
Speaker 6:  Don't wanna argue with
Speaker 4:  Some fear. It's all this is great. Like,
Speaker 5:  I hate that. I really like that. But I really like that
Speaker 4:  It's, it was like easily the cutest part of the whole thing. It, and
Speaker 4:  so they're, they're trying to show these interactions. Look, we gotta
Speaker 4:  get the stuff, like I said, but it, you'll listen to this on what Friday
Speaker 4:  or sometime after that On Tuesday. POTUS will be on the Coter Monday.
Speaker 4:  Even more about the Neo Alexa and how it works. There's a bunch of
Speaker 4:  questions about what models it's using when, how they're managing all that
Speaker 4:  cost. Andro is involved. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which they're a major investor in, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're a major investor and they built their own model called Novo, which
Speaker 4:  they're using. Does
Speaker 6:  Anyone know anything about the Novo model? The
Speaker 4:  Rumor is that they were trying to build this for a long time and it was delayed.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I remember that.
Speaker 4:  And then they had Philanthropics swoop in to help them.
Speaker 5:  Hmm. And we should say we should take a break. We've been talking about this
Speaker 5:  for way too long, but
Speaker 5:  all evidence and reporting so far suggests that
Speaker 5:  Alexa plus is super late and sucks. And so
Speaker 5:  this thing is not shipping until at least several weeks from
Speaker 5:  now. We've seen a few demos that Amazon did as
Speaker 5:  I wasn't at the event, but everything I understand is it was all super on
Speaker 5:  rails. It's all canned. So like, I actually think the big picture ideas
Speaker 5:  here from Amazon are both really ambitious and pretty close to
Speaker 5:  Right. And If you made me bet right now, I would say I bet
Speaker 5:  it's not any good. Yeah. Yeah. But I sincerely hope I'm wrong and we will
Speaker 5:  see. I'll be better.
Speaker 4:  I'm very curious, again, to underline what David is saying,
Speaker 4:  all of the demos were canned. Yeah. We were not allowed to just like freely
Speaker 4:  talk to this thing. Mm. So, who knows?
Speaker 5:  And for months, like I, I would, I would also remind you that this thing
Speaker 5:  launched the first time 18 months ago, and Dave
Speaker 5:  Limp, we've had a whole regime change on this team
Speaker 5:  since this thing launched. The first, first time. Amazon has been talking
Speaker 5:  about this for a long time. And for, I mean, a year, the, the
Speaker 5:  reporting and everything we've been hearing has been that this thing is not
Speaker 5:  very good and it has been massively delayed. And I think
Speaker 5:  there is a, there is an argument to be made that Amazon is launching this
Speaker 5:  now because it had to, not because it's ready. And I hope
Speaker 5:  I'm wrong and I'm very curious to try this thing. But like, what
Speaker 6:  Is the primary pressure, do you think? Like who, who are they worried about
Speaker 6:  coming after them? Because Google's not doing anything age agentic right
Speaker 6:  now. Google's smart Home is still Google Assistant, which is Yeah. The artist
Speaker 6:  formerly known as, you know. And it's not really doing anything.
Speaker 4:  I think, I think everybody's still worried about ti If you find yourself
Speaker 4:  talking to advanced voice mode instead of Alexa. Yeah. You're not switching
Speaker 4:  back. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And operator is out there. Google is doing stuff like Project Mariner
Speaker 5:  is real
Speaker 4:  Operator is not out there. Yeah. Operator's out there in the way that like,
Speaker 4:  like a, like a baby goat is out there just like stumbling over shit. Like
Speaker 4:  it doesn't matter.
Speaker 5:  I used Operator today. You know what, what, what I can't use today is Alexa.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. What did you use
Speaker 5:  It for? I used it as a test to see if it could
Speaker 5:  buy me something on Amazon and it could not.
Speaker 4:  Baby goat baby. I'm saying Yes, it is good. There's a toddler out
Speaker 4:  in the world who's just falling over itself all the time.
Speaker 4:  I think they're a little, probably a little worried about Apple. Right. That's
Speaker 4:  the larger context to this is Apple's way of doing Agentic stuff
Speaker 4:  is gonna be app intense with Siri on the phone. It has perfect access to
Speaker 4:  all those apps. Those developers can get strong armed into playing ball.
Speaker 4:  Apple's very good at that. And particular Apple's gonna do
Speaker 4:  some iPad on a robot arm in their ass.
Speaker 6:  Right. Like, that is true.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot there that is gonna be difficult. Can Apple actually pull any
Speaker 4:  of that off? We don't know. Siri is getting worse by the day. Somehow.
Speaker 4:  I think they, they just like needed to put it, put the
Speaker 4:  stake in the ground. Yeah. And say, actually we put l like AI
Speaker 4:  capabilities into Alexa in the way that everybody wanted us to. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And Panas has said this to us before, Eli, but I think I I suspect probably
Speaker 5:  said it to you on the decoder too, is like, they see this as like a
Speaker 5:  full on platform shift. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He, yeah. He very much said that in like the most intense panas
Speaker 4:  way.
Speaker 5:  There is a sense now that missing, missing this would be like missing mobile
Speaker 5:  15 years ago. Yeah. Right. In the sense that it, like, it, it crowned a
Speaker 5:  generation of trillion dollar companies and killed everybody else. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there, there is right or wrong real belief in the industry that this
Speaker 5:  is that moment again. And there is a sense that you cannot afford to be
Speaker 5:  late at all because
Speaker 6:  They've got 200 worldwide, 200 million. They just need to keep
Speaker 6:  growing that number because it accelerated very fast at first. Yeah. It's
Speaker 6:  starting to peter off, even though it's still one of the most popular service
Speaker 6:  in the world.
Speaker 6:  I, I don't know who the user is that is like, I don't
Speaker 6:  have Prime, but I want Alexa, LLM
Speaker 6:  who is, who are you? I don't know who you
Speaker 4:  Are. You know us. Let us know. Maybe
Speaker 6:  The like really hardcore AI heads that just want to try everything.
Speaker 6:  But I also don't know I they wouldn't have Prime. We'll find out, I
Speaker 6:  guess, eventually. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But it, they, if anyone can do it, it's Amazon. 'cause they have
Speaker 4:  scale, if anyone can make the platform shift happen. Yeah. Because they already
Speaker 4:  have the microphones in everybody's house. Yeah. They've already like, and
Speaker 4:  they own that whole platform tip to tail.
Speaker 6:  It was probably a way for them to say it's $20 because everyone else is $20.
Speaker 6:  And in that way they're, they're kind of saying we're just as good in
Speaker 6:  every way. But you can get it If you have Prime for cheaper. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, I'm, I'm excited to see just how chaotic it is.
Speaker 4:  We'll see again. And next week on Decoder Panos answers a bunch more questions
Speaker 4:  in like, classically intense Panos in that way. It was, it was a fun conversation.
Speaker 6:  Also, we finally get to do the assistant like battles between
Speaker 6:  all of the major assistants. Well, once Siri is actually like,
Speaker 6:  out out.
Speaker 4:  So never, never.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  just us listing things we asked Siri to do that they cannot do. It'd
Speaker 5:  Be the longest VERGE cast episode in history
Speaker 6:  That used to be able to do and to no longer do.
Speaker 4:  I asked it how many days until something the other day and it a, it was like,
Speaker 4:  do you want me to ask Chad gt? It's rough.
Speaker 6:  And Chad GT famously is not good at math. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was like, this is the most powerful phone in history.
Speaker 6:  Nice. Like
Speaker 4:  Speaking of iPhones, we should probably talk about the iPhone 16 E at some
Speaker 4:  point. But actually I want to talk about the Sigma bf this camera.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna say it's very telling that the iPhone 16 E is handily
Speaker 5:  the second most interesting gadget that came out this week. Which in part
Speaker 5:  says something about, I would
Speaker 4:  Say third, I just think we're like legally obligated to be like there was
Speaker 4:  a new wifi iPhone.
Speaker 5:  You're right. It is. It is at least third. It might be, it might be fourth
Speaker 5:  given some of the framework stuff, but it's certainly not first. And I think
Speaker 5:  Sigma is clearly, first
Speaker 4:  My proposed headline for Allison's review was no one should care about this
Speaker 4:  phone. They didn't, they didn't go with it. She did go with it's fine and
Speaker 4:  give it a seven, which is the most seven headline in the
Speaker 4:  history of headlines. Yep.
Speaker 6:  I still dunno who's gonna buy this thing.
Speaker 4:  So what, what's going on here
Speaker 6:  With the, the camera or the phone?
Speaker 4:  Oh well I still dunno who's gonna buy this thing. Yeah. Actually applies
Speaker 4:  to both. Let's start That's extreme. That is true. Let's start that.
Speaker 6:  That's true.
Speaker 4:  Let's start with the camera. 'cause it's vastly more interesting than the
Speaker 4:  iPhone. Okay. Then we can come back to the iPhone Sigma BF is, it's just
Speaker 4:  a beautiful camera. Right? And it seems like no one should buy it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's a new camera from Sigma. It is a Japanese camera brand that
Speaker 6:  has made famously extremely weird cameras. Yeah. They have done very weird
Speaker 6:  things with sensors. They made something called a phon sensor, which has
Speaker 6:  different pixels on the color filter array all on the same pixel. You get
Speaker 6:  better quality. They did not do that with this camera because they got rid
Speaker 6:  of it a while ago. And everyone is sad about that.
Speaker 5:  Sigma stuff is generally pretty good, right? Like it's a, it's yes, they're
Speaker 5:  weird but they make good cameras. Right. Is my impression.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Okay. They're weird. They're good. They're part of the LM Mount Alliance,
Speaker 6:  which Panasonic and Leica are also part of. So that's nice. Weirdly enough,
Speaker 6:  you don't really see them on the street almost ever. Yeah. Mostly because
Speaker 6:  they're so weird. And I think that people just go, when you're going hiking
Speaker 6:  in Utah, you see a hundred million of the cheapest canon camera and
Speaker 6:  the cheapest Nikon camera sounds right. Sigma always does weird stuff. That's
Speaker 6:  kind of their angle. They released a camera this week called the BF does
Speaker 6:  not stand for boyfriend or best friend. It stands for
Speaker 6:  beautiful foolishness. Really? Really, really. I love this. So
Speaker 6:  this is kind of like when someone says, I know that this is stupid,
Speaker 6:  but, and in that way it's very difficult to critique.
Speaker 6:  You know what I mean? It's like, there are many things about this camera
Speaker 6:  that I'm like, but they're like, we know that
Speaker 6:  it's dumb. Yeah. But here it is. Anyway. And you have to respect that in
Speaker 6:  a way. Right. So this is a full frame, 24 megapixel camera.
Speaker 6:  They tried to remove as many buttons as physically possible.
Speaker 6:  It is machined out of a block of aluminum they can make nine per day.
Speaker 6:  So it's not a high yield kit, which not that many people are gonna buy it
Speaker 6:  anyway, so that's probably fine. Famously Fujifilm can
Speaker 6:  only make 15,000 x 100 sixes per week. And that still was not enough
Speaker 6:  because they had over a million oders in China alone on the first day.
Speaker 6:  Wow. So this camera, I don't, I don't even know to say what it
Speaker 6:  looks like. It is just a small block of aluminum in a, in a weird way.
Speaker 6:  It has a LCD screen on the back that does not tilt.
Speaker 4:  This is my o This is actually my only complaint about this camera.
Speaker 6:  That it has no EVF?
Speaker 4:  No, the, the screen doesn't tilt.
Speaker 6:  Oh. Oh, okay. Well I don't,
Speaker 4:  And I have a very specific reason why, but that Okay. Im like, I love you.
Speaker 4:  I'm buying this camera. I'm mad that the screen doesn't tilt. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  a very, very minor complaint in, in the scheme of things. It's, I
Speaker 6:  Don't think it's that minor. Yeah. I think screens should tilt even though
Speaker 6:  they break easier. Yeah. It has no viewfinder. That is also
Speaker 6:  horrible in my opinion.
Speaker 4:  I feel nothing about that.
Speaker 5:  Especially for a $2,000 camera. Like the, the, the number of people
Speaker 5:  who would, can afford that camera want to buy that camera
Speaker 5:  and have strong, like, visceral feelings about
Speaker 5:  how far away from your eye you should hold your camera. Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's just one group of people.
Speaker 6:  It's just that that makes it with, with no articulating, articulating
Speaker 6:  viewfinder and no like EVF or OVF. You
Speaker 6:  can only do this. Yep.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's, and this is why I think the screen should tilt.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's it.
Speaker 6:  Any other angle than right in front of you. Yeah. You know what I mean? It
Speaker 6:  has this neural kind of jog wheel on the back that you're supposed to do
Speaker 6:  most of the stuff through. It has a play button. It has a
Speaker 6:  menu button for go into the menus. The menu looks not
Speaker 6:  great. Not great. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You see Seb from Allied was like, yeah, looking at this interface is why
Speaker 4:  I make camera apps. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  It's not great.
Speaker 6:  Has an extra little screen that tells you like the aperture and things like
Speaker 6:  that. Even though I just, I hate when you hide the aperture behind
Speaker 6:  a sub menu. It's horrible for cameras. I don't know. I
Speaker 6:  think that the, the biggest reason that people really like this camera is
Speaker 6:  because it is super basic. It is just a square
Speaker 6:  of aluminum with no, no, no. A couple little neural parts.
Speaker 5:  No. Let me tell you why people like this camera
Speaker 6:  Because aluminum people like
Speaker 5:  This camera. 'cause it is sexy as hell and I want it. So
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is like, yeah, this
Speaker 5:  To me is like, imagine like a cave painting of a camera where it's like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, you go back like 8,000 years and it's like, oh, someone in,
Speaker 5:  you know, someone just drew a camera and it, this is the first camera that
Speaker 5:  anyone ever imagined that's this camera. And I love it for that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I will say the fact that it doesn't have s a memory card slot. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  it has a built in SSD is like, oh, this thing has a,
Speaker 4:  has a shelf life.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. You're either gonna have to get it serviced, which I'm not really
Speaker 6:  sure how they're gonna get inside of it when it's a solid block of aluminum
Speaker 6:  without taking a lot of stuff off of it. Or you're just gonna have
Speaker 6:  to get a new one. But hopefully it doesn't die before. You know, memory
Speaker 6:  cards famously die a lot. Yeah. But at least you can put a new memory
Speaker 6:  card in.
Speaker 4:  So here's my argument in favor of this except for the tilting screen, which
Speaker 4:  I agree is a huge problem. Okay. I again, 'cause I mostly take pictures of
Speaker 4:  a 6-year-old who is notably down here. Right. So I'm always shooting
Speaker 4:  at like hip height, which means I wanna tilt the screen up. Yeah. That's
Speaker 4:  it. That's like I, I need to solve that problem. This camera doesn't solve
Speaker 4:  that problem. It is sex as hell And I do want it,
Speaker 4:  I think it is like well beyond time for a cam
Speaker 4:  camera manufacturer to get rid of like
Speaker 4:  camera controls as we know them. Like as a person who mostly shoots
Speaker 4:  an ancient Nikon D 7,500, still the greatest hands on
Speaker 4:  camera ever made.
Speaker 4:  It's like fine. And there's just a million buttons on it. And I know what
Speaker 4:  they all do. And the reason I've never upgraded that camera is 'cause I know
Speaker 4:  where all those buttons are and I know what they all do. Right. And that's,
Speaker 4:  it's cool. Like I like having that relationship with that camera and I've
Speaker 4:  got most of them set so I never have to touch them again.
Speaker 4:  I just know where they are. And the reality is, if I could just set them
Speaker 4:  and then set this one dial to mostly ever control shutter speed, I'd be
Speaker 4:  fine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right, right. Or like exposure compensation. The
Speaker 5:  Only problem with that approach is you, you want that camera, but to be
Speaker 5:  like the size and quality of like a
Speaker 5:  Sony RX 100. Yeah. Right. Like give me all of what you just described a
Speaker 5:  basically designed to shoot in auto super simple all in one
Speaker 5:  piece. More or less unbreakable thing. That, that is like a really
Speaker 5:  fun, cool point and shoot. And I think it'd be gangbusters. I'd be all over
Speaker 5:  that thing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You're kind of describing X 100 in a, in a few ways. That's
Speaker 4:  What I mean. That's why people love them. But this one, to me, I just like,
Speaker 4:  I just like the idea that Sigma's, like we have no history of
Speaker 4:  Nikon F Series S SLRs to honor. That's fair. Like screw it.
Speaker 4:  We're just changing how the controls work.
Speaker 6:  Have you seen the old Sigma cameras? 'cause they're much weirder
Speaker 6:  than this. Yes. They're really, really weird.
Speaker 4:  Like, it's funny 'cause Sigma started out as like a, like a lens brand. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And they were like, screw it, we can do whatever we want. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It would be a lot more compelling in that way. You just described Neli if
Speaker 5:  the menu was better. Yeah. It's like here's a really usable thing unless
Speaker 5:  you have to do anything.
Speaker 6:  Have you guys driven the EQS? The, the new one? The electric one? Yes.
Speaker 6:  You've
Speaker 4:  Used, it's like being in a Korean nightclub on wheels. Yeah. I dunno how
Speaker 4:  else to describe it.
Speaker 6:  But you've used the infotainment system, right? Yeah. Yeah. It's like Windows
Speaker 6:  95. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's ev No one has good ideas about software design. No. And like the fact
Speaker 4:  that most products are now our software means that we live in a, like
Speaker 4:  a world of crime. Yeah. But yeah, I I see what you're saying that yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's pretty and I just want it on the shelf.
Speaker 6:  Right. I understand. I understand.
Speaker 4:  I want, I want to put a $2,000 knick-knack on my shelf. Also, the fact that
Speaker 4:  you, it is removable lenses means that it will never actually be as small
Speaker 4:  as it looks.
Speaker 6:  That's true.
Speaker 5:  But this is also like David, I feel like we are, we're in such an era where
Speaker 5:  like the camera is both a tool and an accessory, right? Yeah. And this is
Speaker 5:  like, this is the X 100 story, right? Where like a lot of people who bought
Speaker 5:  X one hundreds bought them not to shoot with them, but to be shot shooting
Speaker 5:  with them
Speaker 6:  Like a Leica. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like it's a creator camera because I want you to see me using it. And
Speaker 5:  I, it's like a, it's a fashion accessory as much as anything. And I feel
Speaker 5:  like this is Sigma just kind of acknowledging the same thing and they're
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, you'll take some pictures with this, but it's also gonna look
Speaker 5:  cool as hell. And that's like 60% of the
Speaker 6:  People. I was thinking about that in a lot of ways because the M 11 is over
Speaker 6:  $9,000 for the body. This is 2000. So
Speaker 6:  there you go. Think of the savings much more affordable. Looks very
Speaker 6:  beautiful. People will ask you, what is that? It shoots about two and a half
Speaker 6:  hours of video If you wanna do the highest quality video and then you have
Speaker 6:  to offload it. I do like this idea of offloading everything onto
Speaker 6:  your computer from the USBC port and not having to worry
Speaker 6:  about an SD card at all. Because SD cards are sort of
Speaker 6:  like, I don't know, Bluetooth standards or wifi standards where you gotta
Speaker 6:  read the little three or the nine on it and there's no five for some reason.
Speaker 6:  And you just have to decide what is the speed and the fact that you can just
Speaker 6:  plug it into USBC port and then into your computer. Very nice.
Speaker 6:  But you know, that comes with its trade offs.
Speaker 4:  It's not great that this conversation has inspired me to start searching
Speaker 4:  for an X 100.
Speaker 6:  Good luck.
Speaker 4:  I mean, they're very
Speaker 6:  Hard to find.
Speaker 4:  I can pay a $700 premium for one right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Or you could get the five, which is not that different. But,
Speaker 4:  You know, let's just wrap up the show. I've got
Speaker 6:  That's busy.
Speaker 4:  Alright, let's talk about the iPhone briefly.
Speaker 6:  Can I say one more thing? Yeah, of
Speaker 4:  Course.
Speaker 6:  The LCD has a, has a sub, like a, a sub bezel. And I just
Speaker 6:  want to acknowledge that
Speaker 4:  None of the press photos show the LTD on it. Does it? Well
Speaker 6:  It doesn't show it on, but it shows it, it shows the sub bezel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I see it. Which is not something Apple would've done. I just want to acknowledge
Speaker 6:  that
Speaker 4:  I'm buying all the cake. Oh
Speaker 5:  No, it's bad. You're right. I just looked and it, you're right. How
Speaker 6:  Does that make you feel? Do you not want it anymore?
Speaker 4:  Have you bought an RX 100? Take pictures of a kid yet? No. This is the single
Speaker 4:  greatest purchase you can make If you parent. Yes. It's the right choice.
Speaker 4:  Buy one of those. Like everyone's always happy with the photos. No one's
Speaker 4:  ever sad. Yeah. The screen tilts.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're, they're, I would, I would not say they're indestructible. Like they're
Speaker 4:  very destructible, but like they're tough enough, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You don't have to worry about interchangeable lenses. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're, they're great, but like they are in fact destructible. Like you
Speaker 4:  get some dust near that lens mechanism. Yeah. You don't have an S 100 anymore.
Speaker 4:  It's all, it's all over. Okay. But they're, I think all these
Speaker 4:  cameras are ultimately David's point kind of competing with the concept of
Speaker 6:  The R accessory kind of.
Speaker 4:  Well no, it's the RX 100. It solves the most problems
Speaker 4:  in that zone. Yeah. And it's, it's very hard to solve the pro
Speaker 4:  like all the problems better than that camera does.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I also wanna acknowledge that they made an RX one a long time
Speaker 6:  ago, which was full frame and they just never updated it. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 6:  been around for a long time and they could be dominating this space, but
Speaker 6:  they decide not to for
Speaker 5:  Some reason. I've loved that camera. Yeah, it's great. Holy crap. I loved
Speaker 5:  the RX one.
Speaker 6:  It was great. It was fantastic. And it hasn't been updated in like over five
Speaker 6:  years, so I don't really know what they're doing. No. Leica is
Speaker 6:  like the only one right now that makes a full frame fixed lens camera. Weird.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it costs $6,000 and no one can afford it. See the
Speaker 5:  Sigma's cheap man. What are we doing here? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You're getting one. It's an impulse purchase. We did call one in for a review,
Speaker 4:  so we did not go on the influencer trip to Japan that everyone
Speaker 4:  else wanted because we had this annoying ethics policy. But we did ask for
Speaker 4:  a review unit. I think someone's getting it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, well they can make nine a day. So presumably we'll get it in
Speaker 5:  2034. We'll get one. It'll be awesome. Someone
Speaker 4:  On our team is, is getting one. And, and then I'm gonna, I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna look at it with a love in my eyes. My, you know, like cartoons with
Speaker 4:  my eyes in
Speaker 5:  My hearts.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we should talk about this iPhone. It's a, it's like amazing how
Speaker 4:  much we want to avoid talking about the iPhone 16 E
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Know we have some virtual listeners who just totally tune out when we talk
Speaker 4:  about cameras. I was much happier talking about the camera than I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  be talking about the iPhone 16 E
Speaker 5:  Never has a phone been so thoroughly exactly
Speaker 5:  what we expected it to be. Oh,
Speaker 4:  That's, I was gonna say, never has a phone been so thoroughly. Exactly. Not
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. It's funny because on social media, usually the few
Speaker 6:  days after a new iPhone comes out, people are trying to justify the reasons
Speaker 6:  why they want to upgrade. I've not seen one thing about
Speaker 6:  this from anybody saying why you should get this necessarily
Speaker 6:  except for people that are insane. No. And
Speaker 5:  On the one hand, look, I like this phone is so clearly not meant for those
Speaker 5:  people. Yeah. And that's
Speaker 6:  Fine. That's fair enough. Right? Like,
Speaker 5:  It it's good point. It just, it's, this is a, a, a thing that Apple I
Speaker 5:  think struggles with is that it operates at such scale and with so much attention
Speaker 5:  that everything it launches is ostensibly geared
Speaker 5:  towards everyone everywhere. And this is just so
Speaker 5:  not that. Right. Like, I, I don't think anyone who is considering a
Speaker 5:  pro phone will ever look twice at this. Right. Like, Mila, you're, you're
Speaker 5:  proposed headline. No one should ever have to care about this. I actually
Speaker 5:  think it's like very descriptive because this is for people who don't care
Speaker 5:  about their phone. This is like, I, I want, I want to have a phone,
Speaker 5:  but it's
Speaker 4:  Five ninety nine nine. If you're that person, you
Speaker 4:  should buy a used iPhone 15
Speaker 5:  Or a new iPhone 15.
Speaker 4:  Oh. If you
Speaker 6:  Buy used 15 Pro for like the same amount.
Speaker 4:  Right. And you'll get Mag safe and you'll get way better cameras and like,
Speaker 4:  you'll, you'll just pick a half.
Speaker 5:  No Apple Intelligence neli.
Speaker 6:  That's a plus. I can,
Speaker 4:  I I cannot be bothered to what end.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I I think Apple really thought Apple Intelligence was gonna drive a, a huge
Speaker 4:  cycle. And
Speaker 5:  It was the Supercycle, this was the que this was the thing last year. Do
Speaker 5:  you remember this? They were talking about the supercycle of smartphone upgrades
Speaker 5:  because of Apple intelligence. Yeah. And Old Boy is that not the thing?
Speaker 6:  Well, have you noticed that the billboards have changed? They used to be
Speaker 6:  Hello Apple Intelligence? I don't see those anymore at all. Now it's
Speaker 6:  all Gen Moji billboards because they know that's what people actually care
Speaker 6:  about. Do they though? It's all I care about.
Speaker 4:  Do you, so is this just a phone that can get Gen Moji? Is that
Speaker 4:  this is
Speaker 5:  Your cheapest gen Moji access pretty
Speaker 6:  Wait, okay.
Speaker 5:  Hold on. I no longer care about the 16 e David. I need to know everything
Speaker 5:  about your Gen Moji life.
Speaker 6:  Oh God.
Speaker 5:  What are your use cases for Gen Moji? How
Speaker 6:  Long do you have?
Speaker 6:  I'm frustrated by Gen Moji and the same reason that I'm delighted by Gen
Speaker 6:  Moji. Okay. In that it's just like they,
Speaker 6:  they tried to make Gen Moji exactly like emoji in every possible way.
Speaker 6:  And in that way it's very useful for regular people as
Speaker 6:  long as they know where the button is, which it's glowing. So I hope that
Speaker 6:  they know where it is. But they look like Apple emoji 'cause they're trained
Speaker 6:  on that apple emoji character set and there just aren't emojis for
Speaker 6:  everything. Like Unicode, they add three or four a year, everyone has to
Speaker 6:  vote on them. That's great. But when you wanna make very specific
Speaker 6:  things, you know, like stickers, I think were one of the biggest
Speaker 6:  upgrades to the iPhone in a very long time. Or at least to iMessage. Because
Speaker 6:  when you can press and hold on something, make a custom sticker, everyone
Speaker 6:  uses that. People love it. That is cool. Gen Moji is like that, but
Speaker 6:  it's more, it's like, it, it, it abstracts it away a little bit so that
Speaker 6:  it's more usable with people that you do not have that specific
Speaker 6:  relationship with.
Speaker 5:  What was the last Gen Moji you made? We're doing this now.
Speaker 6:  Oh gosh. All right. I'm gonna look right now. I I
Speaker 4:  I've never made a gen emoji. Maybe I should buy an iPhone 16.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like is this in your day to day? Like you're just, you're just out
Speaker 5:  here. Gen moji up a storm.
Speaker 6:  I, I
Speaker 5:  Don't like do you wanna get dinner and you're like, Jen Moji make me a person
Speaker 5:  eating
Speaker 4:  Spaghetti. But is that how you invoke a Gen moji? You have to say Jen Moji.
Speaker 6:  Jen
Speaker 4:  Moji, Jen Moji, gen Moji.
Speaker 6:  I'm not sure if we can put this in the show, but If you just say, If you
Speaker 6:  just Gen Moji gun, it will make you a gun.
Speaker 6:  Cool. I just wanted to test that. Very strange. So
Speaker 4:  You're just sending cartoons of guns to you?
Speaker 6:  Oh, laughing, crying, throwing up. Very good one.
Speaker 4:  Oh, this is your Gen Moji. These
Speaker 6:  Are, these are Gen moji. This is, this is one I'm saying they mix stickers,
Speaker 6:  gen moji and emoji in the same area of the keyboard because
Speaker 6:  they want people to think of them as the exact same thing. I will
Speaker 5:  Say I like laughing, crying, throwing up as a gen moji. That's pretty
Speaker 6:  Good. It's quite good. I I will send it to you because it is very good.
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna send you some guns. Just,
Speaker 5:  I wanted just
Speaker 4:  In the middle of the night, David, get ready.
Speaker 6:  I just wanted to test how many different types of guns I would make. And
Speaker 6:  it's a lot. You could do a pipe.
Speaker 4:  Wait, so,
Speaker 6:  Oh, this one is good. This is the, the pumpkin and the devil
Speaker 6:  emoji mixed and I use them for Halloween. That's very good.
Speaker 4:  I do like that you're just spamming David with like the worst emoji I've
Speaker 4:  ever.
Speaker 5:  This is fantastic.
Speaker 4:  That's very good. So again, to just bring this all
Speaker 4:  the way around, our thesis is that people will buy a $600, no not
Speaker 4:  good iPhone to send cartoons of guns.
Speaker 6:  No, but, but I have noticed all of the billboards have changed
Speaker 6:  to Gen Moji billboards. Yeah. And I think that they looked at Apple Intelligence
Speaker 6:  and before it was just so abstract. Before it was just, hello Apple Intelligence
Speaker 6:  iPhone 16. Now it's Gen Moji it, that's their
Speaker 6:  whole thing. Yeah. It has lasted longer than the, than the Apple Intelligence
Speaker 6:  ads. Like there are more Gen Moji ads. They have lasted a longer period of
Speaker 6:  time.
Speaker 4:  It's funny 'cause they, they started all those ads before you could get Apple
Speaker 4:  Intelligence and then people got Apple Intelligence and and they stopped
Speaker 4:  advertising it. Yeah. And yeah, I see, I see what you're
Speaker 6:  Saying. My experience with Apple Intelligence outside of Gen Moji was that
Speaker 6:  I took a script that I had in Apple Notes
Speaker 6:  and I did the rewrite feature intending to revert back to the
Speaker 6:  old script because, you know, I was just testing it and then it
Speaker 6:  crashed Apple Notes and then I could not revert it to my
Speaker 6:  actual script. And that was my only copy of the script.
Speaker 6:  Woof. And that was my mistake. So I just, I don't think people really
Speaker 6:  care about this. Can
Speaker 4:  I? But the only true feeling I have about the 16 e
Speaker 4:  is that not having Mag safe on it is criminal.
Speaker 6:  It is
Speaker 4:  Like almost all of the phone mounts in my house.
Speaker 4:  All of the batteries that I use now, like it's all MagSafe all the
Speaker 4:  way down the line in the car. I have one next to the mirror in
Speaker 4:  my bathroom and I just like put the phone on the next to that in the morning.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Have it played YouTube TV at me. That's amazing. It's
Speaker 4:  like all of that is super fun and interesting. And that is the only like
Speaker 4:  really great accessory ecosystem that Apple's ever created. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And they're just like the cheap phone, the $600 phone can't have it.
Speaker 6:  Why are people are now going to go into the Apple store, they're gonna buy
Speaker 6:  an iPhone 16 e they're gonna go over and they're gonna look at the mag safe
Speaker 6:  charger because everyone wants that MagSafe wireless
Speaker 6:  charger that is $50. And the Apple employer's
Speaker 6:  employees either gonna say, oh, that doesn't work with your phone, even though
Speaker 6:  it's new or they're not gonna know that. And then they're
Speaker 6:  gonna be like, I don't get this. Like, I have to hold it against my phone
Speaker 6:  and it charges at 7.5 watts. Like how does this work?
Speaker 6:  It just seems like a hor like why would you take this out? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is the, the one completely perplexing thing about this phone is MagSafe.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I I actually think you can make a pretty strong case for every
Speaker 5:  other one of the trade-offs. I think it, it lands a hundred dollars too expensive.
Speaker 5:  Like I really agree with Allison's takeaway, which is like the,
Speaker 5:  the idea of we need a cheaper iPhone and we're going
Speaker 5:  to make some sacrifices to get there. I think other than MagSafe, apple got
Speaker 5:  almost right, there are like a couple of little things about it, but whatever,
Speaker 5:  like it's, it got it mostly right. But I agree that the MagSafe thing just
Speaker 5:  sucks. And we, we talked a little bit about this last week and heard from
Speaker 5:  a bunch of people who were like, whatever, just buy a MagSafe case for your
Speaker 5:  phone and would I bet that Apple
Speaker 5:  is gonna sell you some of those? Sure. But like
Speaker 5:  that's not a solution to the
Speaker 6:  Problem. They just get rid of Max safe altogether and everything's Q2 and
Speaker 6:  Q2 ready.
Speaker 4:  That sounds like Apple. Yeah. I dunno it's a phone. Let us know if you're,
Speaker 4:  if you're the target market for this phone, who is the, but this is like
Speaker 4:  the weirdest iPhone launch. Yeah. I can remember
Speaker 4:  like never has an iPhone come out with such a Okay.
Speaker 6:  Come out out.
Speaker 5:  Do you think if this thing were $450 we'd be having a totally different conversation
Speaker 5:  about it?
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  If it was 350.
Speaker 6:  Well,
Speaker 5:  I think that's unreal. That's like unrealistic for what phones cost right
Speaker 5:  now. Like Yeah. I don't know If you've heard of that. Tariffs Tar Neli Tariff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And tariffs. Like is
Speaker 6:  This the first tariff phone? That's the other question
Speaker 4:  I read. Ben Thompson makes the argument that this is the first tarone,
Speaker 4:  but we'll see. I mean like Tim Cook is, you know, we we're, we're gonna get
Speaker 4:  to it in the next segment. Yeah. And it's, it's part of the light your end.
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook is just throwing fake numbers at Donald Trump to get out of the
Speaker 4:  tariffs. So smart move. We'll see. We'll see if, and also every
Speaker 4:  realistically, no one ever buys this phone. Like, you go
Speaker 4:  to your Verizon store and Verizon's like this one. Yeah. And you just leave
Speaker 4:  and that's the end of that.
Speaker 6:  So did you, did you watch Marquez's review of it by the way? No. That he
Speaker 6:  has a ski at the beginning. It's like 90 seconds long and there's, he, one
Speaker 6:  of him plays the employee and one of an employees a customer.
Speaker 6:  And the customer's just asking, I want a phone that does exactly this. Exactly
Speaker 6:  this an employee just gives him everything but the 16 e because it just makes
Speaker 6:  no sense. And I just, again,
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Who is this? I'll,
Speaker 4:  I'll go watch it. Apologies that it's like one of the few I haven't watched,
Speaker 4:  but it's like I don't wanna care about the 60. I just didn't give it the
Speaker 4:  time.
Speaker 5:  It's a way in the door. And then Apple can sell you more expensive things.
Speaker 4:  I do love the,
Speaker 6:  Except for Max Save accessories.
Speaker 4:  This is my favorite, my favorite ongoing like thesis about Apple
Speaker 4:  is that they have some products that don't exist. Like they just have
Speaker 4:  like this, the 16 e only exists on the website.
Speaker 5:  It's like the lobster at a diner. Like it's it's not there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like they're not manufacturing it, it's not real. It's like the
Speaker 4:  illusion of a phone, right. To get you to buy a more expensive phone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like, no, I think they're manufacturing the phone. We'll see. Alright,
Speaker 4:  we gotta take a break. We were supposed to talk about the framework laptop,
Speaker 4:  which looks really cool. But David tells me that framework, CEO Nro Patel
Speaker 4:  is coming on the show next week.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he's coming. Sean and I are gonna hang out with NRO actually later
Speaker 5:  this afternoon and we're gonna have a lot to say, but like if I'll, I'll
Speaker 5:  put all the framework stuff in the show notes. I think that company is fascinating.
Speaker 5:  The desktop looks really cool. I'm especially excited about the framework
Speaker 5:  Laptop 12, which is their like lower end touchscreen
Speaker 5:  flippy one that I think is gonna be maybe the most kind of main streamy thing
Speaker 5:  framework has made yet This company's very exciting and I think up to
Speaker 5:  some really cool stuff. But yeah, we're gonna have lots more to talk about
Speaker 5:  on that one on Tuesday. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Cool.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're gonna take a break. We're gonna come back with lightning
Speaker 4:  round. We're right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Lightning round unsponsored for flavor.
Speaker 4:  The people have started saying it to us, so we're gonna start saying it back
Speaker 4:  to you. It
Speaker 5:  Is marching up the charts of the most demanded merch in the history of The
Speaker 5:  Verge is an unsponsored for flavor
Speaker 4:  T-shirt. It doesn't mean anything,
Speaker 5:  It doesn't mean anything, but we're gonna
Speaker 4:  Make it. When people spon, we, you can't tell us what to do.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's their defining principle here at The Verge.
Speaker 5:  For some reason to me that that belongs on the bottom of a skateboard that
Speaker 5:  just says unsponsored for flavor. That's, that's where that goes.
Speaker 4:  I say you could throw away the entire, it's a long ethics policy on the
Speaker 4:  website. It's very complicated. You can throw it out and you can replace
Speaker 4:  it with, you can't tell us what to do. And that would pretty much get you
Speaker 4:  there
Speaker 4:  anyway. If you'd like to sponsor the lightning round, you can call someone
Speaker 4:  at Box Media and pay them money and then we will still do this. But today
Speaker 4:  we're unsponsored, which means there's not even a hint of corporate control
Speaker 4:  because you, again, to repeat myself, you, you can't
Speaker 4:  tell us what to do. Unsponsored for flavor. Okay, David,
Speaker 4:  take it away.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So the, the first thing here is that YouTube announced
Speaker 5:  this week that More than a billion people now watch podcasts
Speaker 5:  on YouTube. Which is a kind of a number we knew,
Speaker 5:  right? Like YouTube has been creeping up as the most important
Speaker 5:  podcast platform for some time. YouTube music exists,
Speaker 5:  but this is not YouTube music. This is YouTube. YouTube, YouTube, Maine
Speaker 5:  as they call it, which I forever think is very funny. And
Speaker 5:  basically YouTube is very proud of this fact. They're like,
Speaker 5:  we are, we are, we are a massively important podcast platform.
Speaker 5:  I think there are several dozen issues with the fact that YouTube is
Speaker 5:  this powerful a podcast platform in part because it's not a podcast
Speaker 5:  platform. Like there's a non-zero chance you're watching this on YouTube
Speaker 5:  right now. YouTube is not a podcast app for a bunch of reasons. You
Speaker 5:  can't get background audio playback unless you have YouTube premium.
Speaker 5:  You can't sort out shows correctly. The, the audio
Speaker 5:  versus video playback just sucks on YouTube. And YouTube's answer to this
Speaker 5:  is YouTube music. But again, no. And so
Speaker 5:  I just think we're, we're at this really interesting moment where YouTube
Speaker 5:  is both becoming the most popular podcast platform and is kind of changing
Speaker 5:  what podcasts are. Yeah. And it has changed it so much to the point where
Speaker 5:  now like Spotify is racing to do video
Speaker 5:  and it is because it's trying to catch up to YouTube in part because video
Speaker 5:  is very popular in part because video is very shareable and in part because
Speaker 5:  video is really discoverable in a way that audio is not. So
Speaker 5:  everybody now is turning to video. You
Speaker 6:  Didn't like the TikTok, Spotify thing for music where you heard a
Speaker 6:  clip of a song you've never heard before and decided you wanted to listen
Speaker 6:  to the whole thing.
Speaker 5:  What could possibly go wrong? No, it's a terrible user interface.
Speaker 5:  And I, I did this whole thing in the
Speaker 5:  installer or the newsletter I write last week where I basically was like,
Speaker 5:  tell me your music setup. And the overwhelming piece of feedback from people
Speaker 5:  was, I use Spotify, I hate Spotify. Yes. Which is like
Speaker 5:  precisely how I feel about Spotify. Like Perfect. No notes. And it's because
Speaker 5:  all of this stuff is trying desperately to chase YouTube.
Speaker 5:  And YouTube meanwhile is just out here flexing. It's like, yeah, If you want
Speaker 5:  to be relevant on the internet, you have to be on YouTube. And that is
Speaker 5:  increasingly true for people who make podcasts. And I think like Spotify's
Speaker 5:  number I think was that it had a hundred million podcast listeners and
Speaker 5:  Spotify is like what everybody thinks is either the most important or second
Speaker 5:  most important podcast platform next to Apple podcasts. And YouTube is just
Speaker 5:  out crushing everybody. It's nuts.
Speaker 4:  Lemme ask a foundational question.
Speaker 4:  What is a podcast?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I was gonna, I was gonna ask that too
Speaker 4:  Because
Speaker 6:  I,
Speaker 4:  Are we just talking about YouTube videos that say their podcasts?
Speaker 6:  Well what is that then?
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean, we have been making this show for a long time and it is true.
Speaker 4:  Some people
Speaker 4:  watch it on YouTube, lots of people actually watch it YouTube. But I, I don't
Speaker 4:  know like what is the difference between waveform
Speaker 4:  and a regular Marquez video?
Speaker 4:  It's is it, is it just the microphones,
Speaker 6:  The editing, the microphones? I
Speaker 4:  Dunno.
Speaker 5:  But do you know who broke that distinction?
Speaker 4:  YouTube.
Speaker 5:  YouTube, yeah. This is, this is the point, right? Like what, what, what has
Speaker 5:  happened, and I think YouTube has actually done this to a lot of different
Speaker 5:  forms of art, is YouTube has just collapsed everything into YouTube and
Speaker 5:  now everything looks like YouTube and works like YouTube and follows YouTube's
Speaker 5:  particular like trends and systems and norms.
Speaker 5:  Because it's YouTube. Because YouTube is the only platform that matters and
Speaker 5:  thus everything has to be YouTube.
Speaker 6:  How do you categorize a late night show? Because that's a podcast
Speaker 6:  in the way that a YouTube show is a podcast.
Speaker 5:  It's a podcast but it's also just a bunch of YouTube clips in a row.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, no, cable news has just been podcasts for a long time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  If you ever just like watch whatever cable news channel you wanna watch,
Speaker 4:  but you just like watch CNBC or CNN or M-S-N-B-C or Fox News or whatever,
Speaker 4:  you know. Oh, this is just the most chaotic podcast industry. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Very unstructured
Speaker 4:  At all. It's just happening all at once all the time. A lot of
Speaker 5:  Them actually run podcasts that are just the full audio feed of the show.
Speaker 5:  It works horrible Six, I don't dunno if 60 Minutes still does it, but they
Speaker 5:  did for a long time and like it
Speaker 6:  Works well. 60 Minutes makes sense. Yeah. People can visualize things in
Speaker 6:  their heads. Is that different from an audio book? I don't know.
Speaker 4:  So we, I'm trying to remember the headline. The, the narrative
Speaker 4:  podcasts are running into audio book story was a big story. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then narrative PO podcast, like serial, like fell out of favor in
Speaker 4:  like a real way. Yeah. 'cause the, I I hear you on YouTube and
Speaker 4:  I'm, I I do love to criticize YouTube at basically any turn. But like really
Speaker 4:  what you're seeing here is platforms pushing everyone to lower
Speaker 4:  the cost of content. Yeah. Because they don't pay enough money.
Speaker 4:  And so like YouTube as if you're on like a YouTuber,
Speaker 4:  the amount of money you get from YouTube, from AdSense and the partner program
Speaker 4:  is just going down over time. The amount of views everybody's getting
Speaker 4:  is just going down over time. 'cause there's so many more YouTubers,
Speaker 4:  right? So everyone's just trying to make cheaper stuff and we've been
Speaker 4:  making the show for a long time. So I will just tell you like
Speaker 4:  hanging around talking is a very cheap way to make content. Like
Speaker 4:  we try hard, you know, we got like graphics, there's frame TVs everywhere.
Speaker 4:  Those weren't cheap. Lemme tell you,
Speaker 4:  Samsung's making a pretty penny off all the podcasters in this world with
Speaker 4:  the Frame TV graphics that are everywhere. But like, that's what's happening
Speaker 4:  is like we're just pushing the cost of content down. So we, YouTube was able
Speaker 4:  to take podcasts and say, really, we're gonna film your podcast
Speaker 4:  and now we're just gonna ingest hours more video from every
Speaker 4:  creator who's doing podcasts. They don't have to be scripted, they don't
Speaker 4:  have to be structured. We don't take cameras on location here. Here you go.
Speaker 4:  Here's hours and hours of more video. Yeah. What I don't
Speaker 4:  know is whether that's actually taking share away from Apple Podcasts.
Speaker 4:  I know why Spotify's scared, right? This is Spotify's big bet. And
Speaker 4:  they're losing to YouTube in one very specific way. Right. But
Speaker 4:  I don't know if like the, the Apple Podcast listener was
Speaker 4:  always an audio listener is like, screw it, I'm gonna watch this on YouTube
Speaker 4:  instead.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't know. I, I have a lot of, I mean, we get a lot of anecdotal
Speaker 5:  information and feedback from people that I would say
Speaker 5:  by and large what we've heard from people who are like watching and listening
Speaker 5:  to this right now is that it is more sort of additive
Speaker 5:  than cannibalizing. Like there are definitely people who have found
Speaker 5:  the show on YouTube and only consume it on YouTube,
Speaker 5:  but we also get a lot of people who are like, oh, I listen to it while I'm
Speaker 5:  on a walk. And then it's like fun to watch clips. Or I watch the show later,
Speaker 5:  I put it on the TV while I'm in the, or like whatever. So I think it's,
Speaker 5:  from what we've heard so far and what we've seen in our data, they're not
Speaker 5:  kind of killing each other. But also right
Speaker 5:  now, if you're launching a new show, I absolutely guarantee you're spending
Speaker 5:  more of your time thinking about YouTube than you are thinking about Apple
Speaker 5:  Podcasts. And that to me is the real shift over time.
Speaker 6:  I think that people there, the shift towards passive consumption, like
Speaker 6:  needing just things to be playing at all periods of time that they can check
Speaker 6:  in on kind of passively and when they want to. We have a lot of people that
Speaker 6:  tell us, oh, I do the dishes while I have waveform on the tv. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I look over every now and then and I think some form of like
Speaker 6:  ingestion through their eyes while it's also being ingested through their
Speaker 6:  ears every now and then is like what people want. They just want things playing
Speaker 6:  all the time. There's a reason people leave their apartments, they go to
Speaker 6:  the subway, they realize they don't have their headphones with them and they
Speaker 6:  have a panic attack and people just need more longer things.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And the fact that they, the audio medium of podcasts has
Speaker 6:  companies that are like, don't worry, we made sure this is less than 10 minutes.
Speaker 6:  No one wants a less than 10 minutes po. Is anyone asking for that? Because
Speaker 6:  you can just pick it back up like nobody is asking for that. If anything,
Speaker 6:  people love the length of, you know, this show, people
Speaker 4:  Want a two hour Vergecast statement. That's what I'm telling you. That's
Speaker 6:  Exactly
Speaker 4:  Right. And we are very close to delivering it here.
Speaker 6:  I've never heard
Speaker 4:  In the lightning round that is already on 10 minutes on a single item. No
Speaker 6:  One's told me that they want a shorter one. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 4:  All right David, we're changing your job. You're just doing Twitch streams
Speaker 4:  24 7 from now
Speaker 6:  On. Justin TV's back baby
Speaker 4:  From your green screen basement. I'm leaning into that conspiracy theory.
Speaker 4:  This David's basement's a green screen. I,
Speaker 5:  I have begun occasionally subtly moving things around in
Speaker 5:  my background and if anyone would like to tell me what those things are,
Speaker 5:  I welcome it. Alright.
Speaker 4:  Let me add up these next two lightning round items for you.
Speaker 6:  I forgot this was the lightning round.
Speaker 4:  We, so apparently, yeah, that's what I was told. Instagram reels may get
Speaker 4:  its own app. Makes sense. Presumably to compete more directly with TikTok.
Speaker 4:  And then TikTok is upgrading its desktop website
Speaker 6:  To compete with YouTube. They say to compete
Speaker 4:  With YouTube. What do you got
Speaker 6:  First one. Yep. Makes sense. I mean, I think
Speaker 6:  people go to Instagram for reels at this point. So
Speaker 4:  I think all of this is based about the TikTok band.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I think if, because remember TikTok is technically banned in
Speaker 4:  this country. Yeah. Like the law passed, the Supreme Court upheld it
Speaker 4:  and then Donald Trump was like, no, we're not doing that. Yeah. And the app
Speaker 4:  stores, apple and Google were like, that's too much risk. And then Pam Bondi,
Speaker 4:  the new attorney general, sent them a letter, which we have still not seen
Speaker 4:  that made them feel comfortable to put TikTok back. So now we're in this
Speaker 4:  weird period where this app that is banned,
Speaker 4:  they got a 75 day reprieve from the Trump administration of enforcement of
Speaker 4:  the law that's coming up in what, April. Right David? So
Speaker 4:  in April this app might go away again or it sold to,
Speaker 4:  I don't know, Don Jr. Limited whatever's gonna happen. Like I don't know
Speaker 4:  what's gonna happen. Yeah. And if that, what that moment,
Speaker 4:  whatever that moment is, will be a change. And so If you Instagram,
Speaker 4:  you have to be ready for it. Right. So here's reels like not Instagram
Speaker 4:  re like this much more direct competitor to TikTok. And if you're TikTok,
Speaker 4:  I think you have to be like, well you can't ban a website.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Realistically, Instagram is just reels. I think
Speaker 6:  it's, it's almost just like a rebranding thing. And I wonder if it sticks
Speaker 6:  around because Instagram has tested having dedicated apps for things that
Speaker 6:  Instagram already does quite a few times and they've shut them down quite
Speaker 6:  a few times. Remember
Speaker 5:  IGTV, that was
Speaker 6:  Fun. That was a period of time
Speaker 4:  Someone very senior in Instagram told me recently that IGTV was
Speaker 4:  exactly the right idea. And the only thing that got wrong was the videos
Speaker 4:  were too long.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's interesting.
Speaker 4:  He is like, we had TikTok, it was just long videos and what people wanted
Speaker 4:  was short videos.
Speaker 5:  I mean that's kind of true. They tried to do the like Hollywood thing and
Speaker 5:  it's actually like, no, just let people film videos of themselves. People
Speaker 4:  Want garbage. Yeah, right. Just set up some microphones and start a podcast
Speaker 4:  about Yeah. Gadgets and Brendan Carr and you're gonna be fine.
Speaker 6:  Famously why Quibi worked for sure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Dude, I think I disagree with you saying that Instagram is just reels.
Speaker 5:  And I actually think my theory about why this is happening, and I'm just
Speaker 5:  gonna throw this at you both and I'm curious what you think is I, so I watch
Speaker 5:  these Adam er, like a MA videos every week where they talk
Speaker 5:  about, he talks about like what's going on. And that man cannot
Speaker 5:  figure out what is the most important thing on Instagram, right? Like
Speaker 5:  there are stories which a lot of people watch and care very much about that
Speaker 5:  they are forever, like making more important in the product and then denigrating
Speaker 5:  in the product, there's the feed, which is like a dying thing, but is also
Speaker 5:  like the central pillar of Instagram. So they're trying to make the feed
Speaker 5:  a thing again and they're like, we, we wanna let it, we wanna let you post
Speaker 5:  to your feed without it being such a big deal to post to your feed. Right?
Speaker 5:  And I think Instagram has just producted itself into
Speaker 5:  total chaos. And I think a
Speaker 5:  knows that clearly the easiest thing to spin out and make its own is reels.
Speaker 5:  Because then you have an app that opens to video that is playing with the
Speaker 5:  volume on, which is really important. Yeah. And is a really important part
Speaker 5:  of why TikTok has been so successful, right? 'cause you open it up and it
Speaker 5:  is playing with the volume on. And that is not an that, you can't just turn
Speaker 5:  that on on Instagram, but you could, if it's just an app called Reels, right?
Speaker 5:  And then it also says, okay, now we understand what Instagram is. Again,
Speaker 5:  because no one knows what Instagram is anymore. You just post things,
Speaker 5:  places and hope that people see them, which is not a recipe for success.
Speaker 5:  And so now everybody's like, what happened to my reach? Where do I post if
Speaker 5:  I wanna reach people? And this like, this might actually help Instagram tell
Speaker 5:  a story about itself That makes sense for the first time in a long time.
Speaker 6:  Do you think they know what that will be? If a reels app launches though?
Speaker 6:  Because they fame meta famously just takes the best part of
Speaker 6:  every app from their competitors and then puts it in Instagram specifically.
Speaker 6:  Right? So now you know, they've got the Snapchat in Instagram, which is stories,
Speaker 6:  and they've got the reels in Instagram, which is TikTok, and then they've
Speaker 6:  got the Instagram and Instagram, which they have long forgotten about.
Speaker 5:  Right? Well, but I think that goes back to your point about it. It reels
Speaker 5:  is the most important part of Instagram. Like I think a, I would
Speaker 5:  bet that if this app still exists, reels will still be in Instagram and they'll
Speaker 5:  still be in Facebook. And then what Meta gets to say is actually
Speaker 5:  we have this video app, but we also have this gigantic distribution across
Speaker 5:  everywhere. Yeah. So it's like we have TikTok, but we also have TikTok
Speaker 5:  attached to Instagram. It's
Speaker 6:  Like the Fedi verse. But for one platform,
Speaker 5:  For one company.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, which is, which I would just point out is what we call a monopoly
Speaker 4:  Boosted TikTok videos everywhere you look on meta platforms. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm telling you, I I think it's just so that when people lose access to TikTok,
Speaker 4:  again Meta can say, download a new app.
Speaker 5:  It's just TikTok. Yeah. No, I think that's right.
Speaker 4:  I think there's probably some conniving clever motivation, but then there's
Speaker 4:  also a very dumb thing, which is like, are you mad? Push this button. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that solves a lot of
Speaker 5:  Problems. Yeah, I totally agree.
Speaker 6:  I mean, wasn't Instagram notes supposed to be their Twitter competitor? Oh
Speaker 6:  yeah. Yeah. And then they just like, shut that down. Or
Speaker 4:  That became Threads.
Speaker 6:  Became threads. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or are you mad at Twitter? Download this app and it worked for five minutes
Speaker 4:  until they're like, what if this algorithm was the worst? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We'll see. End of that. Okay. We gotta do Po It's a lightning ran. So
Speaker 4:  we're gonna move through politics very quickly.
Speaker 4:  David, I'm assigning you to this job. 'cause I can't, you know.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I'm just gonna, I'm just gonna say a bunch of things in a row and
Speaker 5:  you can stop me whenever you feel like it. Does that sound good? Yeah. DOGE
Speaker 5:  remains insane. The, the big news of this past
Speaker 5:  week was that Elon Musk, a lot
Speaker 5:  of federal employees got an email telling them to respond with five bullets
Speaker 5:  about what they did. And then Elon Musk posted on X that if they didn't respond
Speaker 5:  to that email, they would take that as resignation. That's nothing
Speaker 5:  and is nothing. So a bunch of departments said, don't answer this
Speaker 5:  email. A bunch of departments said, answer this email. Everybody's up in
Speaker 5:  arms about it, nobody knows what to make of it.
Speaker 5:  Musk and then Donald Trump continue to kind of say it's a real
Speaker 5:  thing and people should do it, but it, it appears to be nothing except just
Speaker 5:  more abject chaos. DOGE
Speaker 5:  God only knows what it is or who works there. But the, the new thing that
Speaker 5:  happened this week was that Amy Gleason, who is formerly an employee at the
Speaker 5:  US Digital Service was I like
Speaker 5:  named Scapegoated. Like I don't, I don't know what word you want to use
Speaker 4:  In the executive order that creates DOGE. It says there will be a DOGE
Speaker 4:  administrator
Speaker 4:  that no one knew who that person was. Right. Like judges were asking United States
Speaker 4:  Attorneys General, who is the administrator of DOGE, and they'd
Speaker 4:  be like, I don't know that at this time. Right.
Speaker 5:  Because I think literally they didn't, and, and a lot of reporting from,
Speaker 5:  from us and Wired and others suggest that even the people who work there
Speaker 5:  didn't know who they were reporting to. Elon Musk is in every meaningful
Speaker 5:  way in charge, but he is not a government employee. So that's not how
Speaker 5:  that works.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He's a special government employee. Sure. What is a photo, David? That's
Speaker 4:  where we are.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, knock yourself out. Yeah. Yeah. You can have whatever you want.
Speaker 5:  He was in a cabinet members meeting. Like, none of this is real anymore.
Speaker 6:  I don't know. I think the, the thing that makes all of this just break
Speaker 6:  and not, and weird and all the reporting kind of be weird, is that all of
Speaker 6:  this assumes that there are processes and things that you can and cannot
Speaker 6:  do when you're in certain positions. And they are just saying, none of that
Speaker 6:  matters. Correct. And we're gonna do what we want anyway. Yeah. And in certain
Speaker 6:  ways they're subverting these things and saying, okay, here's the administrator
Speaker 6:  because you asked so many times, but none of them matters for them. They
Speaker 6:  just do not care. So it's important that re the
Speaker 6:  reporting is happening, but also what do these facts mean?
Speaker 5:  Right? There's that paragraph in all of these stories that is like, this
Speaker 5:  breaks with longstanding norms and understanding of how these things, and
Speaker 5:  it's like, yeah, dude. Like every single other thing. Yeah. We've been here
Speaker 4:  For a while. No other president has had a full cabinet meeting where just
Speaker 4:  some guy wearing a shirt that reads tech support and wearing a baseball cap
Speaker 4:  with his fingers talked the most. Yeah. That was Elon in the cabinet meeting.
Speaker 4:  That's,
Speaker 5:  That's just so, okay. So then I say all of this, which led
Speaker 5:  to, I would say the funniest thing that happened this week,
Speaker 5:  which is in, in the Housing and Urban Development Department, somebody
Speaker 5:  put on TVs all around the department, an AI
Speaker 5:  generated video of President Trump
Speaker 5:  sucking on Elon Musk's feet. Like I don't know how else to say it other than
Speaker 5:  that. And it became, it became a whole thing. It
Speaker 5:  got shared a bunch of places
Speaker 5:  and it is, it is, it is hysterical. If you have not watched it. Don't,
Speaker 5:  but also I will put the link in the show.
Speaker 4:  Actually, the funniest part of this is it is an AI deep fake. And so
Speaker 4:  like Blue Sky had a content moderation controversy about it. 'cause
Speaker 4:  you're not supposed to share AI deep fakes. But then it was a newsworthy
Speaker 4:  video of a TV in a government agency being hacked.
Speaker 4:  So then they undid it and they're like, we're very sorry. We, we we've rethought
Speaker 4:  our moderation decision here. Just weird. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But if there's anything that's gonna get us to an antide fake law, it's deep
Speaker 4:  fakes. That's true. This caliber. That's true. It's real weird.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. So that's like DOGE and everyone's reporting on DOGE and like
Speaker 4:  the Times say as a whole list of all the people who work there, it's long
Speaker 4:  and extensive. It's definitely a coup. I just wanna be as clear as I can
Speaker 4:  be. There's a weird coup happening in our government. Yep. And it's by weird
Speaker 4:  nerds. Okay. We're gonna keep, we're gonna keep reporting on it.
Speaker 4:  Then there's like the regular Trump stuff that also happened this week,
Speaker 4:  which I find very funny because it, it just rhymes with the Trump won.
Speaker 4:  So like Tim Cook had a meeting with, with Donald Trump
Speaker 4:  and promised him $500 billion of US investment. They put
Speaker 4:  out a press release about it. They said they're gonna build a school in Michigan
Speaker 4:  for manufacturing. They're gonna do, they're gonna build servers
Speaker 4:  for Apple Intelligence. I guess they're all just gonna do Gen Moji all
Speaker 4:  day long. They're gonna build those in Houston.
Speaker 5:  Yet those guns don't generate themselves.
Speaker 4:  Right. So Trump is happy. 'cause he got, you know, I think whenever Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  promises him American manufacturing, he's like, screw it. They're making
Speaker 4:  iPhones in Kansas. Like he doesn't know he's not paying attention. And Trump
Speaker 4:  won. Famously Tim Cook opened a factory that was already open
Speaker 4:  and invited Trump to the grand opening of the already open
Speaker 4:  factory where they were gonna start making the M Pro that they
Speaker 4:  had already been making at the factory. Yeah. Fantastic. It's f you can,
Speaker 4:  you can, it's, it's, you can go look at it. It's a very confusing
Speaker 5:  Situation. I'm glad that Tim Cook knows that he can do this. At least
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook is trapped on a treadmill of his own making. Yeah. Like he can never
Speaker 4:  retire. His job is to manage Donald Trump. Yeah. Forever.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, so they announced this 500 bill investment, which is great. I, I
Speaker 4:  want Apple to invest in the United States. I think we should manufacture
Speaker 4:  more things here. All this is good, great for the economy. We should build
Speaker 4:  manufacturing centers of excellence in Detroit all day long. I have no
Speaker 4:  qualms with any of the things that they're doing, the substantive things
Speaker 4:  that they're doing. What I will point out is that the Wall Street Journal,
Speaker 4:  Rupert Murdoch's, wall Street Journal looked at the numbers
Speaker 4:  and they're like, these numbers are fake.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Love that. So I'm just gonna read you this paragraph in the Wall Street Journal.
Speaker 4:  Apple's $500 billion is mostly already on the books, is the headline.
Speaker 4:  Apple spent about $1.1 trillion in the past four fiscal years on total
Speaker 4:  operating expenses and capital expenditures. Wall Street expects
Speaker 4:  nearly 1.3 trillion in total expending over the next four years according
Speaker 4:  to consensus estimates. While Apple doesn't break out expenses per
Speaker 4:  geography, about 43% of its revenue comes from America. Assuming the
Speaker 4:  US constitutes the bulk of that number. If spending is in line with revenue,
Speaker 4:  then a rough figure of 40% of projected global spending through 2028
Speaker 4:  equates to about $505 billion. So If you just
Speaker 4:  math out how Apple spends money,
Speaker 4:  there you go. They
Speaker 5:  Used Apple Intelligence to rewrite their expenses and show Donald Trump the
Speaker 5:  expense.
Speaker 4:  This is just the money they were gonna spend. They
Speaker 5:  Took an Excel spreadsheet or I said numbers, spreadsheet and, and said
Speaker 5:  Apple Intelligence make this a press release. Yeah. And that's what it was.
Speaker 4:  You can argue with this, right? You can say Apple almost certainly does not
Speaker 4:  spend, does not invest in line with where revenue comes from. Right. They
Speaker 4:  do most of the manufacturing in China and, and other places overseas. Like
Speaker 4:  you can see all the stuff. But what you're, the, the, the
Speaker 4:  plan from Apple is always the same is they manage Trump
Speaker 4:  in particular because they cannot accept tariffs. So they manage
Speaker 4:  Trump in particular by, by making him promises that they have already
Speaker 4:  made to themselves and they just reannounce things and somehow Tim Cook has
Speaker 4:  just made an art of this. It is wild.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean it's the show is the thing. Right. And there's a, there's a
Speaker 5:  bunch of really fun details in all of it though. Like, I think Apple's plan
Speaker 5:  that they said was to hire 20,000 people over the next four years, which
Speaker 5:  is roughly in line with Apple's ongoing hiring plans. They hire
Speaker 5:  about 5,000 people a year. Incredible. They were gonna, there was like a
Speaker 5:  big thing. They were gonna spend a bunch of money with TSMC in Arizona, apple
Speaker 5:  is already the largest customer of TSMC in Arizona. It's like
Speaker 5:  all you have to do is look at it, but you get to write the thing that's like,
Speaker 5:  thank you Donald Trump. We're spending $500 billion and like e everybody
Speaker 5:  wins. Right? Like is it, is it ruthless in calculating and not really true?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it's, it's, I feel the same way about it that I do about the, everybody
Speaker 5:  sending a million dollars to go to the inauguration. It's like
Speaker 5:  I get it. Like it is obviously straightforwardly good business and also
Speaker 5:  you should feel bad about yourself.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just weird. 'cause there's this big split between, you know,
Speaker 4:  like classic Trump corruption, you know, like
Speaker 4:  these, he's a real estate developer so you gotta spend money on his party,
Speaker 4:  you know, and it's like, oh, he is a club promoter. You gotta do some like
Speaker 4:  club promoting stuff. Like great, you know, like Trump won, like we,
Speaker 4:  we lived it and this is substantially better than, for example, Foxcon
Speaker 4:  announcing LCD factory in Wisconsin that they never built. Right.
Speaker 4:  Apple announced some stuff, it's already doing great. That's right next to
Speaker 4:  the DOGE corruption, which is like weird secrets
Speaker 4:  and like straightforwardly illegal and unconstitutional power grabs by
Speaker 4:  Elon Musk that everyone's just like, oh that's new.
Speaker 5:  There's a good one of those this week
Speaker 4:  In fact. Yeah, this FAA thing. Yeah. What's going on there?
Speaker 5:  So basically the, the short version of it is it looks like the
Speaker 5:  FAA which has been kind of infiltrated with
Speaker 5:  SpaceX employees who have showed up to, you know, quote unquote fix the FAA
Speaker 5:  may take a $2.4 billion contract that it
Speaker 5:  had given to Verizon in order to do, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  FAA things, I don't pretend to know what the FAA does, but there was
Speaker 5:  $2.4 billion that now they would like to give to starlink
Speaker 5:  instead. And there's been a big focus
Speaker 5:  of a lot of very good reporting over the last couple of weeks about the very
Speaker 5:  straightforward ways in which DOGE is going into departments
Speaker 5:  that either regulate Elon Musk's companies and destroying them or
Speaker 5:  give money to Elon Musk's companies and taking more money from them.
Speaker 5:  And this is just, this is just that again, and like this is
Speaker 5:  money that was give was awarded to
Speaker 5:  Verizon that is now being reconsidered. And a bunch of people who work for
Speaker 5:  SpaceX are now at the FAA saying, oh actually this money should go to
Speaker 5:  SpaceX. And everybody's like, isn't that corruption? And it's like, yes
Speaker 5:  and no one, and who cares?
Speaker 4:  So here's how Elon is justifying this, which is a delight.
Speaker 4:  So I dunno if you've been noticing this, like it's not been great for air
Speaker 4:  travel in the United States lately. So Elon has decided to blame this not
Speaker 4:  on firing a bunch of FAA employees, which is a thing that he did
Speaker 4:  Weird,
Speaker 5:  Including the head of the FAA
Speaker 4:  What If you traumatize everybody who works at the FAA
Speaker 4:  and then you're like, but we made your internet connectivity a little bit
Speaker 4:  better. Do you think that will fix it? You know, I run a podcast
Speaker 4:  that's largely about management that has never come up as an idea.
Speaker 4:  So he's traumatized this workforce, he's stressed them, he's
Speaker 4:  cut them, they're, they're mad and then he's blaming all the
Speaker 4:  air traffic problems on a
Speaker 4:  communication system that is quote, breaking down very rapidly.
Speaker 4:  And also quote from Elon, not back up by the FAA itself,
Speaker 4:  FAA assessment is single digit months to catastrophic failure.
Speaker 4:  Putting air traveler safety at serious risk.
Speaker 4:  That's a big claim. Like you, you gotta back that one. Someone at the
Speaker 4:  FAA should be like, here's the report that says we are nine months
Speaker 4:  away from catastrophic air control failure.
Speaker 4:  That hasn't happened. Just putting that out there hasn't happened.
Speaker 5:  Also, you know, who didn't make that system is Verizon. Right?
Speaker 4:  They haven't started yet. Right. This is the new system. So it's
Speaker 4:  unclear what he thinks is breaking, he's saying
Speaker 4:  he's providing starlink terminals at no cost to taxpayer on an emergency
Speaker 4:  basis to restore air traffic control connectivity,
Speaker 6:  No cost to taxpayer. Right?
Speaker 4:  Well there's that, but it's also like, so wait, is it just internet access?
Speaker 4:  'cause that's what starlink is.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Are is it, are you saying that's
Speaker 6:  Not the system? That's just the internet?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Are you saying Verizon can't put some Fios in at the
Speaker 4:  airport?
Speaker 4:  What are you, like, what are we talking about here? Like I know I have, I
Speaker 4:  have, I have many problems with our nation's ISPs.
Speaker 4:  I I think most of them are bad. I think if any is PCEO wants to come on
Speaker 4:  the show, I will look them in the eye and say, I think you did a bad job.
Speaker 4:  You're charging people too much money. Great.
Speaker 4:  Provisioning internet access at the airport is like actually not a problem
Speaker 4:  that they have.
Speaker 6:  I was gonna say, I don't think I've ever said poor Verizon before. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  In this, and we'll see, I still, you know, but in this case it's
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 4:  But he's taking a $2.4 billion contract for
Speaker 5:  Himself. There's just a lot of that going on right now. And there's like,
Speaker 5:  there was some really fun follow up on the
Speaker 5:  $400 million State Department planned to buy cyber trucks
Speaker 5:  that they originally tried to blame on the Biden administration, but it turns
Speaker 5:  out when it was the Biden administration it was $400,000 and then they made
Speaker 5:  it $400 million on the Trump administration and then they canceled the whole
Speaker 5:  thing. It's like, it's just, it's just
Speaker 5:  nakedly obvious what everyone is doing here. And the question is just,
Speaker 5:  is anyone going to stop them at this point? Yeah. And that to me feels like
Speaker 5:  a very open question.
Speaker 4:  I think Elon's drug use will stop it before
Speaker 4:  a person. Hmm. That's my, my current going theory.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  A period of time. Could be Yeah. A period of time.
Speaker 4:  My man's obviously like living hard right now. Yeah, yeah. I've seen
Speaker 4:  him on many stages talking.
Speaker 5:  All right, NELI, it's time for America's favorite segment. The podcast within
Speaker 5:  a podcast. We took a break last week and the people, the people demand it.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's wrap it up. It's
Speaker 5:  Time for Brendan Carr is a dummy,
Speaker 4:  A new segment here on America's favorite podcast about the FCC. Brendan Carr's
Speaker 4:  a dummy. So let me just say, I'm just gonna say
Speaker 4:  this sentence to you this week, Brendan Carr,
Speaker 4:  the chairman of the FCC has decided the best use
Speaker 4:  of his authority is an unelected
Speaker 4:  censorship cop is to attack a
Speaker 4:  country music festival.
Speaker 5:  That's not where I thought that sentence was go. That's the
Speaker 4:  Opposite. That what's doing thought that was gonna go. That's, that's what
Speaker 4:  our man is doing this week. I, I wanna be a hundred percent clear, this is
Speaker 4:  a real thing that the notable idiot Brendan Carr has decided to
Speaker 4:  do this week. So the I the iHeart Media runs the
Speaker 4:  iHeart Country Festival and he sent a letter
Speaker 4:  to Bob Pittman, the CEO of iHeart
Speaker 4:  saying, Hey, are you doing some Paola?
Speaker 4:  Are you saying if people take cheaper rates to play the iHeart Country
Speaker 4:  Festival, that you'll give them more airtime and iHeart radio stations
Speaker 4:  in a vacuum? This should be a great story in
Speaker 4:  1954,
Speaker 4:  in reality, I don't know if anyone has heard of this company called Spotify,
Speaker 4:  which just does naked payola all the time,
Speaker 4:  but because iHeart runs radio stations
Speaker 4:  and Brendan has regulatory control over the airwaves, he
Speaker 4:  gets to make political hay with a certain constituency by saying, I'm attacking
Speaker 4:  Country Music Festival to make sure there's no liberal corruption
Speaker 4:  in country music. No problem. That has played
Speaker 4:  country music for years now.
Speaker 4:  Just stupid. Like it's you iHeart's
Speaker 4:  a monopoly. Like Yeah dude, there's weird corruption in
Speaker 4:  iHeart media and Clear iHeart used to be Clear channel. If
Speaker 4:  you're like a nineties kid like me, clear Channel is like one of the most
Speaker 4:  nakedly corrupt media enterprises like in this country's history.
Speaker 4:  Yeah dude, they're, they're doing some payola at the Country Music festival.
Speaker 4:  Good job. Yeah, good job Brendan. He followed up, by the way, he had a closed
Speaker 4:  door meeting with Republican members of Congress to talk
Speaker 4:  about George Soros owning radio stations and what he can do about that.
Speaker 4:  I would just point out Rupert Murdoch also owns a bunch of radio
Speaker 4:  stations, TV stations in this country. He doesn't seem to be a problem. It's
Speaker 4:  definitely George Soros. So we're just doing partisan censorship
Speaker 4:  by Brennan Carter. None of this makes any sense because none of it
Speaker 4:  stands up to even the slightest bit of like intellectual scrutiny.
Speaker 4:  He just likes having the power of being an unelected censor.
Speaker 4:  And that brings us all the way to the stupidest thing that he's doing, which
Speaker 4:  he's making these noises about reinterpreting
Speaker 4:  Section two 30
Speaker 4:  to, I dunno, make it easier for him to put Mark Zuckerberg in jail or something.
Speaker 4:  Right. Section two 30 is a law that says the big companies are not liable
Speaker 4:  for what the users post on their platforms. So if I put something Instagram,
Speaker 4:  you can't sue Mark Zuckerberg over what is on my Instagram account. The whole
Speaker 4:  internet relies on this lawsuit. The our comment section relies on the S
Speaker 4:  law, existing Reddit, you name it next door. But he's like, we
Speaker 4:  got a reign in big tech and I will
Speaker 4:  reinterpret section two 30, unelected
Speaker 4:  deeply unstylish Brendan Carr will reinterpret
Speaker 4:  this law, which was written by the way, by people who are still alive.
Speaker 4:  Like Ron Wyden wrote section two 30. He was on decoder two weeks
Speaker 4:  ago. You could just ask him what he thinks it means, but Brendan Carr is
Speaker 4:  going just reinterpret it somehow he
Speaker 4:  released this in a story in the New York Post that I swear to you is written
Speaker 4:  like the worst LinkedIn poetry I've ever seen in my entire life.
Speaker 4:  Like just one sentence long paragraph in the story just says social media
Speaker 4:  has replaced chat rooms. End of sentence, end of paragraph.
Speaker 4:  Why
Speaker 4:  it's very confusing. We'll link to it. Just I want you to know this is some,
Speaker 4:  this is like the VO on poetry of policy writing in the New York Post. Like
Speaker 4:  it's so bad. And the idea is that he will somehow
Speaker 4:  reinterpret section two 30 to make Facebook a publisher and then everyone
Speaker 4:  can sue Facebook defamation. This is absolutely not how that law is supposed
Speaker 4:  to work. This is the height of stupidity from Brendan Carr. And I know this
Speaker 4:  because again, the guy who wrote the law talks to us all the time. He was
Speaker 4:  just on our shows like two weeks ago and this is not what he meant when he
Speaker 4:  wrote the law.
Speaker 5:  I do feel like it's dangerous for you to say at any time that this is the
Speaker 5:  height of Brendan Carr's stupidity because like it's still
Speaker 5:  early. My dude, we're only like six weeks into this.
Speaker 4:  That's true. Well look, he's gonna take down a country music festival first.
Speaker 4:  There's one thing you want the FCC of this country doing. It's attacking
Speaker 4:  the country music industry. What are you doing Anyway, Brendan, as always,
Speaker 4:  I know you listen, I I know your staff gives you readouts. I, I I I,
Speaker 4:  I've known it for years buddy, If you wanna come onto coder or, or come on
Speaker 4:  this show, you can tell us about your smart home setup. I bet it sucks. You're
Speaker 4:  welcome to, you're just not very smart Brendan. You're welcome to come on
Speaker 4:  the show and face an actual hostile interviewer who questions your use
Speaker 4:  of the governance's power to shut down speech that you don't like. 'cause
Speaker 4:  that's what you're doing every single time and we're just not gonna let you
Speaker 4:  off the hook. All right, that was our weekly segment. Brenda
Speaker 4:  Carr's dummy,
Speaker 5:  We need theme music. Brandon Keefer on our team, I will tell you has been
Speaker 5:  quietly creating theme music for Brenda Carr as a dummy. And
Speaker 5:  there is a chance we are going to roll that out at some point in the day
Speaker 5:  in your future. So get
Speaker 4:  Ready. Can you just imagine waking up and being like, huh, I should control
Speaker 4:  speech in this country. What I will do with that power that I've given myself
Speaker 4:  for no reason is attack a country music festival. Yeah. Run
Speaker 4:  by iHeart Media.
Speaker 5:  That's the consequential stuff right there. When
Speaker 4:  I think of complete corrupt
Speaker 4:  iHeart,
Speaker 5:  Go after Coachella first and then we'll talk, you know what I mean?
Speaker 4:  David, I'm gonna read you this sentence and you gotta tell me it's a pallet
Speaker 4:  cleanser for a two hour birch house. Okay. Automatic combines, beeper
Speaker 4:  and text.com messaging services. What does that
Speaker 5:  Mean? So this is two hours easily.
Speaker 5:  So we talked a lot on the show about beeper
Speaker 5:  the messaging app that ran afoul of Apple in some really interesting
Speaker 5:  and complicated ways. Beeper eventually sold to Automatic. The
Speaker 5:  company that owns wordpress.com, they'll email
Speaker 5:  me if I'm not stat specific about which part of WordPress automatic overseas
Speaker 5:  automatic kind of a mess because Matt Mullenweg is having a weird
Speaker 5:  time on the internet right now. They're in lawsuits. But anyway,
Speaker 5:  they made this big bet on messaging. They bought both beeper and this company
Speaker 5:  text.com, which is doing the same kind of thing that Beeper was doing.
Speaker 5:  Basically trying to like unify all of your messaging apps into one messaging
Speaker 5:  app.
Speaker 5:  Eric Midkowski, who was the head of beeper, at least as I
Speaker 5:  understood it, was going to run this whole new thing. The combination of
Speaker 5:  the text.com team and the beeper team at Automatic Eric Micki
Speaker 5:  since left and is now doing Pebble again. And so
Speaker 5:  Kean Aria who was running text.com is now in charge of this whole team
Speaker 5:  and they just put out betas of the first new apps, which
Speaker 5:  are essentially just reskinned text.com apps into
Speaker 5:  a thing that is now called Beeper. So Beeper is the new name, but text.com
Speaker 5:  appears to be the actual technology. They redid an
Speaker 5:  iPhone app, but they're still at this like unified messaging everywhere thing.
Speaker 5:  I downloaded the betas, they're as interesting and messy
Speaker 5:  as ever, but they appear to be still
Speaker 5:  for real at this game. I had a, I wondered if after all
Speaker 5:  of the Apple kerfuffle, if they would just spin out a different direction
Speaker 5:  and try to do something else in messaging. But Automatic appears to be
Speaker 5:  actually pushing towards this.
Speaker 4:  Huh? That all made sense. I think Brendan cars should arrest them.
Speaker 5:  There you go. I'm here to help. Also, before we go, I have some breaking
Speaker 5:  news. Yeah. Oh, Andy Jassy, the CEO of Amazon
Speaker 5:  said this afternoon on Bloomberg
Speaker 5:  television that Amazon is going to be releasing
Speaker 5:  some new Alexa devices this fall.
Speaker 5:  And he said the sentence, I think there's a sustainable business model,
Speaker 5:  which is always what you wanna hear.
Speaker 4:  That's good. That makes sense. That tracks what basically what pun us was
Speaker 4:  saying.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so it's, it's, this is 2025,
Speaker 5:  I think in two runs just became the year. Alexa is either going to work
Speaker 5:  or collapse in a really fascinating way. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's definitely gonna turn on all the lights in your house full booking you
Speaker 4:  a ticket to Japan. It's you can get outta here
Speaker 5:  And then an Uber will show up and bring you to JFK. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or drugs. It's one or the other. Or drugs. All right. David, thank you so
Speaker 4:  much for being here. Thank you. That was incredible my man. Appreciate it.
Speaker 4:  We'll have you back soon. Other David, you're fun. Take it. That was it.
Speaker 4:  That was for chest rock and roll.
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 9:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 9:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 9:  Our show's produced by Will Pour Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 9:  that's it. We'll see you next week.