# Transcript
ID: 6ffd12f5-b7ef-4b67-95e4-328e63ffe7ab
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5118939435036343506/5951356495111222957/s93290-US-4599s-1752571987.mp3
Description: On this episode of The Vergecast, we’re going to dive deep into why accessible design is universal design. First, guest host Victoria Song will chat with Jason Valley, a visually impaired Verge reader. Jason initially reached out to Victoria after her Live AI hands-on, challenging the notion that the feature was a “solution looking for a problem to solve.” Jason shares how the tech has helped him live a more independent life, what he’s hoping to see improve, and how the blind and low-vision community has enthusiastically embraced the technology.
After that, Victoria sits down with Be My Eyes CEO Mike Buckley. Be My Eyes is an app that pairs blind and low-vision users with sighted volunteers to help them go about their day. Buckley gives his thoughts about how accessible tech design benefits everyone, why smart glasses and AI are a natural combo, and what challenges and opportunities in this space remain.
And finally, we have features reporter Mia Sato on to answer a spicy question about smart glasses from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com). Specifically, do smart glasses belong in the bedroom?
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of what AI smart glasses
Speaker 2:  are actually good for. I'm your friend v and we are in week
Speaker 2:  two of Hot Girl Vergecast Summer, eh. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  today's show is really exciting and quite personal for me.
Speaker 2:  Actually, a few months ago I was reviewing the Meta Smart Glasses
Speaker 2:  And I kind of flippantly commented that I didn't understand why anyone would
Speaker 2:  need AI to give a really obvious description of
Speaker 2:  something that they're looking at. Well, a bunch of visually
Speaker 2:  impaired VERGE cast listeners and VERGE readers wrote in and said,
Speaker 2:  actually, me, me. I am the person that this helps. And so
Speaker 2:  a few of them actually challenged me to rethink my framing. And I said, you
Speaker 2:  know what? You're right because here at The Verge we do love good feedback.
Speaker 2:  So today we are talking about smart glasses and
Speaker 2:  accessibility. And first we'll hear from one of the listeners who
Speaker 2:  wrote into me and he's going to tell us how the Meta glasses has changed
Speaker 2:  his life for the better. And then I'll talk to the CEO of Be My
Speaker 2:  Eyes. That's a company that provides AI and live
Speaker 2:  volunteer services for people with visual impairments. They're integrated
Speaker 2:  into those smart glasses and we'll hear about how they're thinking about
Speaker 2:  how this technology can help the visually impaired going forward. And finally,
Speaker 2:  my colleague Mia Sato will be joining me to answer a very spicy,
Speaker 2:  potentially not safe for work. Question about smart glasses, all
Speaker 2:  that coming up right after the break. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Our first guest is Jason Vallie. He is one of
Speaker 2:  the listeners who wrote into me about how AI smart glasses changed his
Speaker 2:  life. He also sent me a picture of his guide dog Noelle, who is cute
Speaker 2:  as a button and we'll put a picture of her into the show notes. Let's
Speaker 2:  get into it. So Jason, this is kind of a really
Speaker 2:  special for me interview because I do read
Speaker 2:  all the reader feedback we get, maybe not the comments sometimes, but usually
Speaker 2:  if it comes into my email I I definitely try and take time to read it.
Speaker 2:  So when you reached out to me it was because I had done
Speaker 2:  a hands-on of the Meta AI live AI feature
Speaker 2:  And I, I sort of just kind of posed it in the framing as
Speaker 2:  a, a solution in search of a problem. I was kind of
Speaker 2:  asking like, who, who is asking for this? And you sent such a thoughtful
Speaker 2:  email about like, Hey, I use this
Speaker 2:  tech, this tech actually dramatically impacts my life.
Speaker 2:  So I guess what I wanted to ask you is like what
Speaker 2:  drew you to the Meta ray bands in the first place and like can
Speaker 2:  you explain the appeal of live AI for
Speaker 2:  your life?
Speaker 6:  Live AI is a visual interpreter for me in my
Speaker 6:  life. If it's not something that I can perceive with my remaining vision,
Speaker 6:  clearly I need to ask somebody, Hey, do you mind telling me what this
Speaker 6:  is? Sometimes that can be a challenge. Not everybody
Speaker 6:  is capable of saying, Hey, you know, this is such and such,
Speaker 6:  this is a widget, it's blue, it's round, it's this or
Speaker 6:  it's that. Having the live ai, I can go into
Speaker 6:  environments where I would need a chaperone. That could
Speaker 6:  be a Dollar Tree, it could be going to a restaurant And I can
Speaker 6:  engage live AI and ask it to read the menu or tell me
Speaker 6:  what's in front of me so that I'm not inconveniencing my
Speaker 6:  companions and I'm getting on in a normal life. I'm enjoying my
Speaker 6:  lunch, I have a menu that's in front of me that I can actually do something
Speaker 6:  with. It's not just a, I guess a fan in front of
Speaker 6:  me while everybody else is picking out their stuff. I know what I want. I
Speaker 6:  can decide for myself and that's kind of a powerful thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, you know, that's definitely not something that I as
Speaker 2:  a sighted person would think about because me using that
Speaker 2:  feature, it was very much like a, well, yeah, I, I can read
Speaker 2:  the thing in front of me, but I think when we talk about blind and low
Speaker 2:  vision people, that is a wide spectrum of
Speaker 2:  you know, the ability to see. So could you maybe describe
Speaker 2:  what your condition is most like so that our listeners understand?
Speaker 2:  'cause I think when us cited people hear blind and low
Speaker 2:  vision, we just think of the main image that most people think
Speaker 2:  of, which is someone who can't see it all.
Speaker 6:  Correct. Vision loss in general affects a
Speaker 6:  wide variety of people from no light perception at all
Speaker 6:  to somebody who has low vision, which I
Speaker 6:  believe is defined as 2060. And that's
Speaker 6:  at a point where a person can no longer drive. In my particular
Speaker 6:  case, I contracted a staph infection in 2015
Speaker 6:  and it affected my blood pressure. I had two emergency surgeries
Speaker 6:  to correct it and it essentially damaged
Speaker 6:  the retina in the back of my eyes and three separate
Speaker 6:  injuries that occurred over the course of a year. And the official
Speaker 6:  diagnosis that I got was N na ION, which stands for
Speaker 6:  non alytic ischemic optic neuropathy.
Speaker 6:  What that means to the average person is an optic nerve
Speaker 6:  stroke and my retinas, which
Speaker 6:  would normally be in the shape of a volcano, where
Speaker 6:  your central vision is a very tightly compacted group of nerve
Speaker 6:  cells in the middle, mine are entirely flat. So what that
Speaker 6:  translates for me is in my left eye I have no light
Speaker 6:  perception from about 11 o'clock to about four o'clock. And then
Speaker 6:  from four o'clock to seven o'clock in my left eye
Speaker 6:  I can look at things. If I look at it directly, it disappears. If I look
Speaker 6:  past it with my eccentric vision, I can still perceive it, I can still
Speaker 6:  read things if the text is large enough, if I have it
Speaker 6:  white text on black, it makes it easier to see in my
Speaker 6:  right eye. I have no central vision. I have just the
Speaker 6:  periphery and again, when I look at something it disappears. But if I look
Speaker 6:  past it with my eccentric vision, eccentric vision,
Speaker 6:  I can see something there. And then everything else,
Speaker 6:  for lack of a better term, is looking through a plastic
Speaker 6:  baggy. Everybody agrees that it's clear, but if you fold it, you really
Speaker 6:  can't see through it at any distance. So for me, I have
Speaker 6:  to be about eight to 10 inches from a screen with large text for
Speaker 6:  it to be useful to me in the wild.
Speaker 6:  If I go to a restaurant, let's say a buffet, I really
Speaker 6:  don't wanna get my face eight to 10 inches from the food to see what's there,
Speaker 6:  right? I think that's kind of disgusting. And there's a reason the
Speaker 6:  sneeze hoods are there to keep human contact from your food.
Speaker 6:  So having the glasses, if I go into this buffet, I
Speaker 6:  can ask it what's in front of me? Can you read the sign? And it'll tell me,
Speaker 6:  okay, well you have this option in front of you.
Speaker 6:  So I don't have to rely on people with my
Speaker 6:  residual vision in the wild I can do things for myself. I
Speaker 6:  travel independently with a guide dog, we have a walking lifestyle in
Speaker 6:  my neighborhood and I have some great friends which will take me out to do
Speaker 6:  my shopping. That could be at Lowe's to get supplies
Speaker 6:  that I use for my crafting. It could be a trip to Dollar
Speaker 6:  Tree to get some things that I need. It could be to
Speaker 6:  Aldi's. That place is easy to shop for. Everything is insane
Speaker 6:  in all the stores. So getting
Speaker 6:  back to the vision part, these places are a challenge for anybody
Speaker 6:  with any level of vision loss. So having
Speaker 6:  these glasses, having a visual interpreter quietly telling me the
Speaker 6:  things that I need is absolutely a game changer
Speaker 6:  for independence. What brought me to them is
Speaker 6:  some years ago, I'm on my, I guess 10th year vision loss
Speaker 6:  is there's a device out there called OrCam. That device
Speaker 6:  starts about $3,500. That's rather
Speaker 6:  expensive for a blind person who's on disability
Speaker 6:  looking at the price tag for the Meta. When they came out last
Speaker 6:  July, I was able to snag a pair of refurbed ones with a double
Speaker 6:  warranty for $200. I was able to slip in
Speaker 6:  some custom lenses for 65. And I have myself a great working
Speaker 6:  pair of Meta glasses.
Speaker 2:  So that's a huge example of cost And
Speaker 2:  something that I think we don't necessarily think of because you're right,
Speaker 2:  $3,500, that's a, that's an Apple vision pro
Speaker 2:  level area of price. So you know
Speaker 2:  something like the Orbi versus the Metas, like
Speaker 2:  was this something that to you was immediately obvious like yes, I
Speaker 2:  need to try this. Yes, this is absolutely worth the investment
Speaker 2:  no matter, you know, it, it can be kind of tough with
Speaker 2:  emerging technology where you haven't tried it yourself. You're kind of relying
Speaker 2:  on, for the large part, cited reviewers impressions of
Speaker 2:  this technology. And I think one thing that as tech reviewers
Speaker 2:  could do better is to think of accessibility needs
Speaker 2:  to the ability that we are able to, when we are reviewing these products.
Speaker 2:  And I, I'll admit that was something that I was not
Speaker 2:  necessarily aware of or thinking of when I first
Speaker 2:  reviewed the Meadow Ray band. So I think if blind or low vision person
Speaker 2:  was reading my review, they wouldn't get a sense of how this could help them.
Speaker 2:  So I, I'm curious in your process of knowing
Speaker 2:  what was available to you before and then reading about this
Speaker 2:  new technology that was coming out, was it immediately apparent to you that
Speaker 2:  this could be a game changer?
Speaker 6:  The packaging I guess you could say on what was being
Speaker 6:  pitched offered a lot of wonderful,
Speaker 6:  I started doing some research looking online, looking at the different
Speaker 6:  options that were there And I realized, realized that this was the first
Speaker 6:  option that actually had the AI enabled on it.
Speaker 6:  And I started before a lot of the current options became
Speaker 6:  available. There's been a lot of updates over the last year that have, that
Speaker 6:  have been amazing And I part of the early access program on that.
Speaker 6:  Part of my research involves social media. I'm part of
Speaker 6:  several blind visually impaired groups and these
Speaker 6:  started to show up on the radar and people started talking about 'em
Speaker 6:  and what it can do and what it can offer. And I've always been
Speaker 6:  an early adopter of technology and it's like, okay, this is looking like
Speaker 6:  it really wants to fit what I would like it to do.
Speaker 6:  So I started making a plan to get it into my budget and got it into
Speaker 6:  my hands in July of last year and it's
Speaker 6:  been a game changer since then.
Speaker 2:  Right. So you know, you mentioned that it
Speaker 2:  has enabled you to live and work more
Speaker 2:  independently. I'm curious if you were ever a user of
Speaker 2:  something like Be My Eyes, that's kind of another example that's come
Speaker 2:  up primarily through smartphones and it does have an integration with the
Speaker 2:  Meta Ray bands as a type of technology that also
Speaker 2:  helps other people live and work more
Speaker 2:  independently. So I'm curious like how does this experience compare to you?
Speaker 2:  Is it complimentary? Do you use Be My Eyes on on the
Speaker 2:  glasses itself,
Speaker 6:  I use Be My Eyes on my phone a an iOS
Speaker 6:  user. My primary use of Be My Eyes is
Speaker 6:  to describe images that I can't pick out the details on.
Speaker 6:  So I can see a rough image of something. If you look at it,
Speaker 6:  it's very blurry. So I can run it through the AI and tell me
Speaker 6:  in detail what it is that I'm looking at and pick up the nuances that
Speaker 6:  are there. I haven't really used the volunteer
Speaker 6:  aspect of things to reach out. I'm a little less comfortable talking
Speaker 6:  with somebody about my medications or some of my day-to-day
Speaker 6:  stuff. Having the AI gives me that privacy. So
Speaker 6:  I'm a, I guess you could say a hybrid user of Be My
Speaker 6:  Eyes, but I do have it enabled that if I need to contact a volunteer I
Speaker 6:  can enable it with a voice command.
Speaker 2:  That's like a really interesting example 'cause I think
Speaker 2:  when people talk about AI from skeptics, at least
Speaker 2:  a common refrain I hear is like who is this for? Why would you
Speaker 2:  want this? And this idea that maybe the AI
Speaker 2:  can afford you at least a sense. 'cause we don't know what all these companies
Speaker 2:  do with their data per se, but like it can at least afford you a sense in
Speaker 2:  your daily life a feeling of like, oh I don't have to have another person
Speaker 2:  see my medication. Is that kind of the main
Speaker 2:  appeal for you for AI versus
Speaker 2:  a volunteer? Are there certain situations where you might wanna talk to
Speaker 2:  a volunteer more than a ai and how have
Speaker 2:  you found the AI in general when you are in those situations?
Speaker 6:  AI is a bit more concise with the information that I'd
Speaker 6:  like to get with the Meta ai,
Speaker 6:  I'm not able to do some things because of their safety guardrails that
Speaker 6:  they've put on. So I can't discuss
Speaker 6:  a lot of my medications up close with it. I can simply get information
Speaker 6:  off the bottle of the name and that's about it and then it'll tell me I can't
Speaker 6:  proceed with the rest of the information. I can't describe it. So
Speaker 6:  that is a frustrating point. But in other things,
Speaker 6:  if I need to get instructions for something
Speaker 6:  I guess less dangerous if you will, something that doesn't have a
Speaker 6:  life and safety, it really streamlines my day to get
Speaker 6:  through it. So instead of waiting for somebody else to
Speaker 6:  become available to me that can say, Hey Jason, you know this is
Speaker 6:  your electric bill and it says that you owe X amount,
Speaker 6:  I can ask Meta to, Hey look at this and
Speaker 6:  describe it. And it'll go through and give me the juicy bits, it'll tell
Speaker 6:  me how much I owe who it's for and when it's due,
Speaker 6:  rather than giving me a complete spit out of everything top to bottom
Speaker 6:  and all the information that I don't need with a human
Speaker 6:  being. I can get that personal touch, but not
Speaker 6:  everybody is capable of describing something
Speaker 6:  in the way that's useful for me. People can
Speaker 6:  do it in a general sense, but if I really need information,
Speaker 6:  some people will say, well it's over there to
Speaker 6:  a blind person over there is a really open concept,
Speaker 6:  especially when somebody's pointing and making use of those hand
Speaker 6:  gestures. So I'll ask somebody, you know,
Speaker 6:  Hey could you be a little more specific? Oh yeah, it's
Speaker 6:  over to your left over there and you know, sometimes I'm
Speaker 6:  slapping my forehead, you know, and frustration and having
Speaker 6:  an ai I can kind of drill down on the
Speaker 6:  information that I need so I can ask it,
Speaker 6:  please look and describe and it'll tell me, okay, it is
Speaker 6:  such and such. Okay, well I'd like to know a little bit more. What is the
Speaker 6:  information on it, what text is off there? And it'll get into more
Speaker 6:  detail. And if it's still not enough, I can ask it and it's
Speaker 6:  significantly more concise. So I'm
Speaker 6:  getting the information that I need. If I'm in a place I'm not
Speaker 6:  familiar with, I can ask it to read the sign on a bathroom and tell
Speaker 6:  me if it's for male or female. That avoids a little bit of
Speaker 6:  embarrassment. If I'm looking at an elevator pad, I can tell
Speaker 6:  which way the buttons are supposed to be going. If I need to go
Speaker 6:  to my doctor's office, I can look at the directory and find out what suite
Speaker 6:  number it is.
Speaker 6:  So having the AI on demand
Speaker 6:  saves me a lot of time and not having to wait. It gives me precise
Speaker 6:  and concise information to get through my day so
Speaker 6:  that I'm not inconveniencing somebody else. And when you're visually
Speaker 6:  impaired it really feels like you're inconveniencing others to
Speaker 6:  ask.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you know that. Thank you so much because
Speaker 2:  this is kind of a thing that I don't necessarily always think about,
Speaker 2:  but I, you know, it hurts my heart a little bit to hear that you, you feel
Speaker 2:  like you're inconveniencing other people to be quite honest.
Speaker 2:  But I appreciate that AI is at least giving you a greater
Speaker 2:  sense of independence. You know, when my mom was sick, the, the thing that
Speaker 2:  she told me all the time was that she just wanted to feel independent and
Speaker 2:  to not have to ask me. Even though, you know, for me I was like, I, I would
Speaker 2:  love to help you. I would love to do anything for you. So, you know,
Speaker 2:  it does hurt my heart a little bit to hear that, but I am kind of
Speaker 2:  sitting with the thought and absorbing the idea that, you know,
Speaker 2:  maybe one really beautiful takeaway is helping
Speaker 2:  people feel independent in this. I'm curious what hopes you
Speaker 2:  have for this technology going forward. And you know, we do have
Speaker 2:  some Meta people listening to this podcast, so you know,
Speaker 2:  if you could speak to them directly and you know, some improvements
Speaker 2:  that you'd like to see in this text and pain points that you've had, like
Speaker 2:  would love to hear them.
Speaker 6:  Some of the pain points that I've experienced with a live AI
Speaker 6:  is it's a battery drain. I get about
Speaker 6:  four hours of average use before I have to recharge my battery.
Speaker 6:  If I'm not using the live ai, as soon as I kick that in, I could
Speaker 6:  get about 20 minutes to a half hour on a full charge
Speaker 6:  and then I have to recharge my glasses, then I have to go analog and
Speaker 6:  that's kind of an inconvenience. So having a more
Speaker 6:  efficient battery would be nice. I
Speaker 6:  also notice that unless I'm on a really fast data
Speaker 6:  connection, that sometimes a live AI isn't as
Speaker 6:  fast and responsive. So I don't know if there's a way
Speaker 6:  to kind of tweak that for the information that it's getting from the user.
Speaker 6:  But definitely the battery would be helpful
Speaker 6:  to have something along the, the live ai. Something
Speaker 6:  that I've noticed and I've compared notes with some other friends
Speaker 6:  is I'll ask the live AI to please let me know when it
Speaker 6:  notices something that I'm looking for. And in
Speaker 6:  my case, let's say I go to Dollar Tree and I'm looking for a
Speaker 6:  specific item And I know that I'm in the area, I
Speaker 6:  ask Meta to find it and it says, okay, I'll locate that for you.
Speaker 6:  We go past it and I'll say, did you find it? Oh yes, I found it.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, why didn't you tell me? Wow. I asked a friend of mine
Speaker 6:  who's also visually impaired and in his case
Speaker 6:  he asked it to tell him, okay, let me know when I'm at my greenhouse.
Speaker 6:  And he knows he is getting close and he asks
Speaker 6:  again and Oh yeah, we're we're there. And it's like, well you said you were
Speaker 6:  gonna tell me. Okay, I'll remember that for next time. And it doesn't seem
Speaker 6:  to remember that going forward. So I'm not
Speaker 6:  sure if that's necessarily a, a pain point or growing
Speaker 6:  pain of training in AI model.
Speaker 6:  You know, it's not necessarily a a blind thing, but it would be incredibly
Speaker 6:  helpful for that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I would agree with you. I also would like something like that
Speaker 2:  because I am super A DHD And I constantly
Speaker 2:  forget the things that I'm looking for all the time and then start looking
Speaker 2:  for other stuff. So I think that would help everybody, not just people who
Speaker 2:  are visually impaired. You mentioned that you are
Speaker 2:  part of a bunch of communities and that part of
Speaker 2:  you finding out about this tech was hearing about it from word of mouth.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious, have you seen the metas getting adopted by
Speaker 2:  your community in ways that maybe were unexpected
Speaker 2:  or, you know, are are, is the community kind of
Speaker 2:  adapting to the fact that this tech is largely accessible, widely available?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I think you mentioned something in an email about your guide dog
Speaker 2:  and maybe thinking about ways the glasses
Speaker 2:  can interact with guide dogs
Speaker 6:  In my community, these are spreading like wildfire.
Speaker 6:  One Facebook community that I'm part of is Blind Buddies and
Speaker 6:  it's like every third post somebody is asking for the
Speaker 6:  impression of getting the Met Raybans and
Speaker 6:  you read the posts of people coming down and how they use it
Speaker 6:  for sorting their mail, sorting the medication, getting through their
Speaker 6:  daily life. It's accessible. People are being
Speaker 6:  gifted pairs, people are saving up to get a pair. These are
Speaker 6:  becoming a must have in the blank community when,
Speaker 6:  when people are responding back, there is so much
Speaker 6:  positive for the visually impaired.
Speaker 6:  It's a wonderful example of how mainstream technology
Speaker 6:  benefits everybody. Rather than just being a niche group,
Speaker 6:  which is very expensive to develop and work in.
Speaker 6:  We have access to something
Speaker 6:  that is just phenomenal at a very economical price.
Speaker 6:  And something that also is beneficial to our
Speaker 6:  families is the visual interpreter fatigue. When
Speaker 6:  you're constantly asking somebody to describe something for you,
Speaker 6:  that creates a lot of stress on family members, whether it's your spouse
Speaker 6:  or your kids or whoever is helping you on your day-to-day.
Speaker 6:  So that's a, that's a lot of value that gets put into the day-to-day
Speaker 6:  within our community as well. Increasing our
Speaker 6:  cont contentment and happiness in the family by not being so reliant.
Speaker 2:  So tell me about how your AI glasses kind
Speaker 2:  of integrate with your Guide dog school that you're in.
Speaker 6:  I'm a student at the Seeing Eye in Northtown, New Jersey
Speaker 6:  And I lost my guide dog link back in December And
Speaker 6:  I was paired with a new guide dog Noel. And this
Speaker 6:  guide dog school is a hundred percent donation based
Speaker 6:  and they've been considering adding a small module
Speaker 6:  to guide dog training in how guide dog handlers
Speaker 6:  integrate their ai. And something that
Speaker 6:  came up was introducing it at the right time.
Speaker 6:  AI for every visually impaired person is not
Speaker 6:  appropriate at every level. It's a great augmentation
Speaker 6:  to get through your day, but it's also important to have the basic
Speaker 6:  skills so that if this technology isn't available to
Speaker 6:  you, you still have your basic skills and then from there you can only do
Speaker 6:  better when you have it.
Speaker 2:  That's a really beautiful point.
Speaker 6:  One instance we had talked about in the
Speaker 6:  email how it benefited me getting to and from Guide Dog School,
Speaker 6:  I use an app called Soundscape on my phone. I
Speaker 6:  use that when I travel in unknown locations and it gives me an
Speaker 6:  audible description of what's around me as far as a
Speaker 6:  GPS and having the wonderful audio
Speaker 6:  coming above my ear. It's subtle,
Speaker 6:  it doesn't take away from my awareness around me.
Speaker 6:  So I can use that to get into the airport. I can interface
Speaker 6:  with an escort to get me to the ticketing counter. When I
Speaker 6:  landed in Newark, I didn't know who was picking me up
Speaker 6:  and it was easy just to tap on my glasses and answer the call coming
Speaker 6:  in rather than put all of my luggage down and answer.
Speaker 6:  I could just accept the call and connect
Speaker 6:  with the people. And when I got on campus, we have the
Speaker 6:  legendary coffee machine, it's in Braille
Speaker 6:  and it's also in text And I can't really read either. So using
Speaker 6:  the glasses to find out which brand of
Speaker 6:  caffeine I wanted for the morning made guide dog school a lot easier.
Speaker 6:  'cause we're 18 days of up at 5:00 AM
Speaker 6:  and going to bed at 10:00 PM and we're walking five, six miles
Speaker 6:  a day. Kind of need that energy and need the right energy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. You know, caffeine should be
Speaker 2:  accessible to everybody who needs it regardless.
Speaker 2:  So what would you like for those of us who are
Speaker 2:  cited or perhaps skeptical of AI to better understand
Speaker 2:  about the experience that you've had? Like what is something that
Speaker 2:  everyone listening to this show should walk away and maybe
Speaker 2:  file away in their brains to, to think about?
Speaker 6:  I think with ai, people are looking for the negatives
Speaker 6:  right now. And I think we need to be open-minded to the
Speaker 6:  amazing things that it can offer us to improve
Speaker 6:  the human condition. I mean, if you look at what
Speaker 6:  Blind Life was like a hundred years ago or 150 years ago
Speaker 6:  before braille really became a thing,
Speaker 6:  being visually impaired meant a life of isolation and
Speaker 6:  loneliness.
Speaker 6:  I mean, having access to this evolving technology
Speaker 6:  allows us to be normal, to
Speaker 6:  live a life like everybody else, having access to
Speaker 6:  the same tech that everybody else has without it being special
Speaker 6:  or being something that sticks out like a sore
Speaker 6:  thumb. These are amazing things for us. I mean, to have
Speaker 6:  a visual interpreter that sits above my ears,
Speaker 6:  that's kind of a game changer. I mean, to
Speaker 6:  dismiss that as as a bad thing,
Speaker 6:  I, I'd really have to rethink that. I mean, there's so much wonderful that
Speaker 6:  can be harnessed from ai for those of us that don't have all
Speaker 6:  of our senses. I mean, you take the hearing
Speaker 6:  impaired community, having
Speaker 6:  somebody or having an AI interpret visually what somebody
Speaker 6:  is saying without sign language, that's also another
Speaker 6:  opportunity for AI to advance. So there's a lot of things
Speaker 6:  for the human condition to improve with AI rather than it being the
Speaker 6:  doomsday device.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, you know, I can also fall a little guilty
Speaker 2:  into the AI doism. I think it's good to hear about
Speaker 2:  the positive use cases because one thing that we're all having
Speaker 2:  trouble with is parsing what the AI tech
Speaker 2:  people or the, you know, Andy Jassy out here
Speaker 2:  with Amazon saying like, oh, you know, we're gonna reduce the workforce.
Speaker 2:  I mean that's, that's not a great thing for the CEO of Amazon to come out
Speaker 2:  and say, but I think sometimes it's hard to imagine how it fits
Speaker 2:  into our daily life. So I really wanna thank you for taking the time
Speaker 2:  not only to like call me out to think in a different way. I deeply
Speaker 2:  appreciated that, but also just to like challenge us all to think
Speaker 2:  about how it can fit into to daily life. And
Speaker 2:  I am so deeply thankful that, you know, you were able to share
Speaker 2:  your slice of, of this experience with us and so that we can maybe
Speaker 2:  think more creatively because it is very popular
Speaker 2:  and sometimes very funny to make jokes about how AI is going to
Speaker 2:  kill us all or steal up our job. So, you know, I think this is an important
Speaker 2:  conversation to have too.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  Also funny to joke around with the ai, we have two dogs in
Speaker 6:  our home. One is a nine pound black and white chihuahua.
Speaker 6:  And I asked my AI to describe it and it described him as a cat.
Speaker 6:  And I tried to describe to my AI that in fact the
Speaker 6:  dog and my AI was arguing with me that says, it's obviously a cat,
Speaker 6:  you can tell by its ears.
Speaker 2:  We're back with Mike Buckley. He's the CEO of Be My Eyes. It's a service
Speaker 2:  that uses AI and live volunteers along with smart glasses and phones
Speaker 2:  to provide assistance to users who are blind or visually impaired.
Speaker 2:  Thank you so much for joining us here on The Vergecast. And
Speaker 2:  one of the reasons why I wanted to talk to you was smart glasses are a
Speaker 2:  huge rising trend in tech, wearable tech especially, And I
Speaker 2:  cover wearable tech, but one of the things we don't talk all
Speaker 2:  that much about is how it could be an assistive technology
Speaker 2:  as well. So was wondering if you could give our listeners kind
Speaker 2:  of a brief introduction into what Be My Eyes is and
Speaker 2:  how you found yourself with the company.
Speaker 7:  Awesome. Thanks for having me. So Be My Eyes was started by a
Speaker 7:  Danish furniture craftsman who was losing his eyesight and he was
Speaker 7:  pissed off because there were times when his family and
Speaker 7:  friends weren't around to kind of help him with sight needs as his
Speaker 7:  eyesight was deteriorating. So he invented this app
Speaker 7:  whereby through one touch of a button, someone who's blind or low
Speaker 7:  vision can be seamlessly connected to a sighted
Speaker 7:  volunteer on a one-way video, two-way audio call,
Speaker 7:  right? So the sighted volunteer can see outside the back of
Speaker 7:  your smartphone and that volunteer can help with anything like,
Speaker 7:  is this the tomato soup? Does this shirt match my pants? Am I at the
Speaker 7:  right airport gate? And after the first week of the apps launch, there were
Speaker 7:  10,000 people on it. And if you fast forward to today,
Speaker 7:  there are about 900,000 blind and low vision users
Speaker 7:  and astonishing 8.8 million volunteers, which
Speaker 7:  I think is the largest online volunteer army in the world and the second
Speaker 7:  largest volunteer army period after the Red Cross.
Speaker 7:  And we operate in 150 countries in 180 languages.
Speaker 7:  And what I like to say about this is hands our founder,
Speaker 7:  he successfully merged technology with human kindness
Speaker 7:  right to solve a societal need. And if you
Speaker 7:  fast forward from the inception in 2015 to about
Speaker 7:  2022, we started talking a lot about artificial
Speaker 7:  intelligence under a belief that AI could have very
Speaker 7:  serious benefit for people who are blind or have low vision in
Speaker 7:  terms of visual interpretation. And so we were an alpha launch
Speaker 7:  partner of Open AI way back in, in the
Speaker 7:  spring of 2023, which seems like 10 years ago at this point, given
Speaker 7:  all the AI developments.
Speaker 2:  Oh it really does.
Speaker 7:  But now we do more than 3 million AI sessions a month
Speaker 7:  of visual interpretation where the blind or low vision consumer
Speaker 7:  can literally take a picture of just about anything and get very fast
Speaker 7:  interpretation. Fascinatingly, even though
Speaker 7:  the AI sessions have gone through the roof, we've also seen that
Speaker 7:  the calls to human volunteers have also gone up. And So
Speaker 7:  there is this thirst, I think still for human connection
Speaker 7:  as well as a thirst for consumption under an AI model. And, and as
Speaker 7:  long as the user kind of has a choice of either, either kind, we like that.
Speaker 7:  But that's what be My Eyes is, and all of that is free for the blind
Speaker 7:  or low vision consumer. And we pay the bills by using this product
Speaker 7:  and selling it to enterprises for great customer service, for blind and low
Speaker 7:  vision consumers and for workplace accessibility. So people can use Be My
Speaker 7:  Eyes at work or people through our app can call a bunch of
Speaker 7:  our customers through one touch of a button and get seamlessly connected
Speaker 7:  to customer service, but with the benefits of AI or enhanced
Speaker 7:  video. So that's how we pay the bills.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty fascinating that users can choose between whether they wanna
Speaker 2:  interact with an AI in a particular circumstances or with humans.
Speaker 2:  Have you gotten any feedback about like what scenarios
Speaker 2:  they might prefer? One or the other?
Speaker 7:  You know, it's, it, it varies. It's very individual based, but there are
Speaker 7:  a couple of common themes. Like I talked to a woman who
Speaker 7:  said she's using the AI in our house more often
Speaker 7:  when she hasn't cleaned up, right? Because she doesn't want someone to see
Speaker 7:  like that her kitchen's messy. You know, I think that there's also
Speaker 7:  a repo, you know, a group of people who are blind and low vision who just
Speaker 7:  appreciate the human interaction. One of the unfortunate realities of people
Speaker 7:  with sight loss is that there are higher rates of loneliness and
Speaker 7:  higher rates of depression and higher rates of mental health. And so having
Speaker 7:  that human connection can be quite meaningful for people sometimes.
Speaker 7:  I think there is also, like sometimes people can be better than ai and
Speaker 7:  other times AI can be better than people, right? Like if you call me up
Speaker 7:  and ask me about, you know, something super technical,
Speaker 7:  you know, a router's broken, I'm probably not gonna be very effective.
Speaker 7:  But the AI will probably have an answer really quickly. And so I think that
Speaker 7:  there's a lot of trial and error going on and most consumers
Speaker 7:  are using both.
Speaker 2:  It's very nice to hear actually that the volunteers are still
Speaker 2:  requested and wanted because the narrative with AI
Speaker 2:  often is that it's one scary two, that it's going to take jobs
Speaker 2:  away. And I mean, these are volunteers, but it's still people who
Speaker 2:  meaningfully are giving up their time to do something nice. So
Speaker 2:  it's very kind of reassuring to hear that this isn't maybe
Speaker 2:  a case where it's either or, it's either and is that
Speaker 2:  the right way to say it? Like it's, it's an and situation, not an OR situation
Speaker 7:  As of right now, yes. I mean, who knows really what the future
Speaker 7:  holds for us, right? As these systems become more sophisticated. And
Speaker 7:  I think it's just about every day now where we hear about someone
Speaker 7:  interacting with AI as though it was human. And that's, you know, good or
Speaker 7:  bad, I'm, I'm gonna weave the value judgments to somebody else at the moment.
Speaker 7:  But we did, like I remember telling our board of directors that
Speaker 7:  we may put the kind of volunteer product out of business through the adoption
Speaker 7:  of AI hasn't happened. But as of right now, it is an and
Speaker 7:  rather than an or.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean, to be fair, if I wanted to ask someone if something matches,
Speaker 2:  like if my shirt matches my pants, I think I would trust a human a
Speaker 2:  little bit more than an ai, but, well, I guess we'll see how that
Speaker 2:  evolves. But, so one thing I've, I I
Speaker 7:  Just, as long as you're not asking me me about fashion, because I, I'll,
Speaker 2:  You know what, fair, but let's say, you know, this really
Speaker 2:  kind of depends on a camera, right? So I'm just curious, you mentioned
Speaker 2:  that obviously this works with a smartphone, that's a pretty mobile
Speaker 2:  device that's easy for people to carry around. It's super ubiquitous. Are
Speaker 2:  there any other types of gadgets that this works on?
Speaker 7:  Look, of course, you know, smart glasses, right? Right, right.
Speaker 7:  It's a huge and growing market for us. And think about this
Speaker 7:  from the perspective of the blind or low vision consumer.
Speaker 7:  If I have to interact with my world just to get basic visual
Speaker 7:  information that's very different than using glasses. What are the glasses?
Speaker 7:  It's hands free, right? That's power,
Speaker 7:  right? That's power for the blinder low vision consumer. Imagine
Speaker 7:  if you're going to an airport and you have a piece of luggage in one hand
Speaker 7:  and a guide dog or a cane in the other hand as a blinder low vision,
Speaker 7:  what the hell do you do with your phone? Right? That's not a good
Speaker 7:  experience. So using glasses or a wearable of any
Speaker 7:  kind, but obviously The Ray Band Meta glasses have been a, a, a complete
Speaker 7:  game changer for so many members of the blind and low vision community. Those
Speaker 7:  glasses are power and freedom, independence,
Speaker 7:  speed, right? For a large section of humanity. And by the way,
Speaker 7:  the second you think about, you know, oh, you hear blind and low vision,
Speaker 7:  it's not about you, it's about all of us, right? There are over
Speaker 7:  300 million people globally who are blind or have low vision. And the World
Speaker 7:  Health Organization indicates that this number may double by 2050 because
Speaker 7:  of macular degeneration, increased rates of diabetes,
Speaker 7:  aging population, growing populations generally. And so the fact that you
Speaker 7:  can have a wearable that frees up your hands is a, a
Speaker 7:  true game changing step function, right? So we have
Speaker 7:  a very strong belief that smart glasses
Speaker 7:  and, and working with Meta will not only help for sort of personal and
Speaker 7:  human use cases, but also for employment use cases. And
Speaker 7:  we're about to start a pilot with a Fortune 20 company on this front very
Speaker 7:  soon. I cannot use their name yet though.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Well, you know, thank you for the hint. We'll keep an eye out for
Speaker 2:  that. But you know, I actually am someone with very
Speaker 2:  poor eyesight like thanks parents and genetics, but like
Speaker 2:  I have extreme astigmatism and even I am at the point where I'm starting
Speaker 2:  to use accessibility settings on my phone just so I can read things
Speaker 2:  easier. So I don't, I don't remember a life without glasses. To me
Speaker 2:  having smart glasses seems like a very natural
Speaker 2:  evolution about it. So I guess one question I have was, was it
Speaker 2:  always obvious to you that Smart Glasses was kind of the next
Speaker 2:  kind of frontier for your product and your service? Because,
Speaker 2:  you know, we, we tried Smart Glasses 10, 12 years ago with Google Glass
Speaker 2:  and that was, that was a big no-no for a lot of people. So just curious,
Speaker 2:  with the Meta Ray bands, was that a really obvious partnership to you where
Speaker 2:  you guys like, Hey, we heard you're making this, why, why haven't you
Speaker 2:  contacted us?
Speaker 7:  I can't say it was obvious because you And I lived through
Speaker 7:  glass holes, right? We, we, we remember that like
Speaker 7:  at a certain point though, we kind of saw people in our
Speaker 7:  community starting to use these things before we even
Speaker 7:  had an integration and there was some Hope Express. So
Speaker 7:  no, it wasn't obvious, but it became apparent over time.
Speaker 7:  And how the partnership came about was is, you know, I contacted Meta
Speaker 7:  And I was not really having success. And then, but then finally I
Speaker 7:  got through to Andrew Bosworth, the Meta CTO,
Speaker 7:  and he got it immediately and he helped make it happen. And so
Speaker 7:  we contacted them, but to his credit, Andrew Boz
Speaker 7:  said, yeah, we have to do this. And it's, it's been a great partnership ever
Speaker 7:  since.
Speaker 2:  So how does the integration work?
Speaker 7:  So we basically have built things on the backend
Speaker 7:  engineer to engineer at both companies where you can actually call
Speaker 7:  a human volunteer through the Meta glasses. And we're talking about more
Speaker 7:  advanced integration now of AI functionality, customer service
Speaker 7:  group calling a whole bunch of other things. Again, under that belief that
Speaker 7:  this is power for the community, number one, right? And independence.
Speaker 7:  And second, that the consumer needs to be given a choice as to
Speaker 7:  how they want to access visual information. That may be AI sometimes,
Speaker 7:  or it may be a human sometimes. So we're, we're looking at enabling both.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty cool. So fun factor, it wasn't necessarily
Speaker 2:  an obvious use case for me either. I was actually testing
Speaker 2:  the live AI and the multimodal AI beta when it came
Speaker 2:  out earlier this year. And I was kind of, I have to admit I was a little
Speaker 2:  flippant. I, I said something along the lines in my writeup
Speaker 2:  about how like, okay, who, who needs this caption obvious
Speaker 2:  description? 'cause even though my eyes are bad, I can still see
Speaker 2:  with corrective very strong corrective lenses. And I actually heard
Speaker 2:  a lot from our readers and people in the blind and
Speaker 2:  low vision community, which is one reason why I'm reaching out now to be
Speaker 2:  like, actually this is life changing for us. This is game changing for us.
Speaker 2:  Don't discount us here. So this is my penance talking to you guys.
Speaker 2:  I'm just curious like how you view something like
Speaker 2:  multimodal AI from the sense of like, it creates
Speaker 2:  its own challenges, right? It's very power intensive, it's
Speaker 2:  very draining on the battery. Have you guys put
Speaker 2:  any thought as to how you're gonna adapt your particular services to
Speaker 2:  accommodate something that's so new and so power hungry and
Speaker 2:  you know, is possibly prone to hallucinating things? Like
Speaker 2:  how, how do you approach that challenge as well?
Speaker 7:  I look full speed ahead and you have to give the consumer the choice, right?
Speaker 7:  Like there's no doubt that live interpretation
Speaker 7:  of one's environment is powerful, important and
Speaker 7:  necessary. That doesn't mean it's perfect, right? And whether
Speaker 7:  it's a hallucination or whether it's my favorite test to do with
Speaker 7:  live AI is if you hold your hand out and then count your fingers down and
Speaker 7:  ask it to tell you what's going on, it doesn't tell you it's counting. So
Speaker 7:  there's still latency, right? There's a, there's a lag between what the camera
Speaker 7:  is able to interpret and what the AI is able to interpret in, in terms
Speaker 7:  of what's going on. But the future is really, really
Speaker 7:  bright here, right? Real time will eventually become
Speaker 7:  actually real time, which will have transformative power
Speaker 7:  in terms of use cases. Like think about navigation, right? Think about
Speaker 7:  getting around an airport, think about obstacles right as you walk
Speaker 7:  along in the street, all of that is coming. I mean, Meta is already
Speaker 7:  demoed. Orion glasses, which is a whole separate and wild
Speaker 7:  capability, but combining that with kind of live AI
Speaker 7:  I think is again, potentially transformative. I would also say that
Speaker 7:  as a a, a sighted person, I had the same initial reaction
Speaker 7:  you did about, oh, what do I need? Kind of the live interpretation. And then
Speaker 7:  I was wearing my Meta glasses when I was walking around to city
Speaker 7:  with a bunch of historical landmarks And I just kept saying, Hey Meta,
Speaker 7:  what is this? You know? And it told me what it was And I said, what's the
Speaker 7:  historical significance? Tell me more about the year or the, the architect
Speaker 7:  or the artist. And it was, it was like lovely, right? And it
Speaker 7:  was lovely to have my phone in my pocket and not be searching
Speaker 7:  around for information that way. And so I do think that we're
Speaker 7:  literally at the cusp the very early stages of
Speaker 7:  exploring the utility of this technology.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, for sure. Sure. And like, it seems like there's a lot of different
Speaker 2:  takes on smart glasses, obviously. I think for
Speaker 2:  your service to work it requires a camera. But
Speaker 2:  I guess, yes. Do you think that the smart glasses
Speaker 2:  in general, provided they have a camera in there that could be the
Speaker 2:  kind of ideal form factor for
Speaker 2:  your tech? And are there other companies you're kind of
Speaker 2:  thinking about working with that you can talk about? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Look, yeah, it, it, it's certainly plausible that this will be the
Speaker 7:  form factor of wearable that wins, right? Who knows.
Speaker 7:  But like, you know, what if I have a necklace
Speaker 7:  that can do the same thing And I don't wanna wear glasses all the time, like
Speaker 7:  maybe that's gonna win. Like, you know, you know, there were all these rumors
Speaker 7:  about wood, apple or somebody else put a camera in the
Speaker 7:  earbuds. I don't think that's happening anytime soon, but it's kind of
Speaker 7:  interesting conceptually, right? But then I have to have something in my
Speaker 7:  ears all day. Is that what I wanna do? So I I don't think we really know,
Speaker 7:  you know, the form factor that's gonna win out at the end. I will say that
Speaker 7:  in the current market, glasses are the best, right? And,
Speaker 7:  and Meta has the best product. Now is Google gonna come?
Speaker 7:  Is Apple gonna come? Are there like eight startups that are
Speaker 7:  working on this too? Sure. And who knows what, like Joni, ive
Speaker 7:  and Sam are gonna build over at OpenAI, right? Although people are
Speaker 7:  suggesting they don't think it's glasses, but who knows? I do think that
Speaker 7:  in the near term, the market for the people in, in
Speaker 7:  the community that we represent the blind and low vision, it's certainly
Speaker 7:  the best form factor and, and has a incredible potential.
Speaker 7:  And, and of course, you know, we're willing to work with just about anybody
Speaker 7:  and everybody, but I, I will always have a soft spot for Meta because
Speaker 7:  Meta said yes to us and, and they worked with us. And,
Speaker 7:  and by the way they did that, you know, without asking for a lot of credit
Speaker 7:  and without like trumpeting it in, in a, in a way that was kind of
Speaker 7:  artificial or let, let's just say Meta put in a lot of human hours
Speaker 7:  in doing this while no one was looking.
Speaker 2:  I feel like you are right that it was pretty a low key in
Speaker 2:  terms of the overall overarching messaging
Speaker 2:  because for better or worse we are always kind of
Speaker 2:  catering to the mass market. And this kind of feels a little bit
Speaker 2:  like an oversight. But I do think,
Speaker 2:  you know, this was kind of a use case that I saw mentioned for Android
Speaker 2:  XR in the Google IO keynote. Was that something that you
Speaker 2:  gued to, have you seen like other
Speaker 2:  companies talking about this to you guys? Have you seen like any increase
Speaker 2:  in outreach from people interested in this technology? Or is it just
Speaker 2:  mostly been this one main partnership so far?
Speaker 7:  No, I mean it's a growing market and we've been contacted by everybody
Speaker 7:  on some level, you know, and so of course we've talked with Google and
Speaker 7:  we've talked with Apple for years about a whole host of things and there
Speaker 7:  are some integrations that we have on the, you know, apple Vision Pro.
Speaker 7:  And it suffice it to say like, we're getting more calls than ever,
Speaker 7:  which is great. I think it's gonna be interesting to see if what company
Speaker 7:  or group of companies solve some of the problems that you're talking about,
Speaker 7:  right? Whether it's battery life, right? Whether it's, you know,
Speaker 7:  small form factor getting the cost down to a point like, like where
Speaker 7:  it's really great, like part of the, the remarkable thing
Speaker 7:  about the Met Raybans is that the price point is not
Speaker 7:  absurd, right? Right. Relative to a phone. And if you
Speaker 7:  look at like other assistive technology, you know, even the Google
Speaker 7:  glasses back in the day, there were thou they're often thousands of dollars.
Speaker 7:  And here's the reality, 70% of people who are blind or have low vision
Speaker 7:  are either unemployed or underemployed. So when you start talking
Speaker 7:  about $2,000 or $2,500 for a device, it's over,
Speaker 7:  right? It's not gonna work. But if you have a $300 device
Speaker 7:  or a $330 device that also doesn't charge you
Speaker 7:  monthly for kind of AI costs, that's a big
Speaker 7:  deal, right? And I can foresee a future in a not too distant
Speaker 7:  future where a government or a social service will
Speaker 7:  subsidize the cost of that hardware because they know it provides
Speaker 7:  substantive value to its citizens or to help facilitate
Speaker 7:  employment and power and independence that we've talked about before. And
Speaker 7:  so I think it's coming.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean that would be wonderful if that that's the case. Like even I
Speaker 2:  know in a bunch of wearable tech, sometimes they are HSA or
Speaker 2:  FSA eligible and that really just helps with the accessibility and
Speaker 2:  for people who might need it. But along that thought process, you know, I
Speaker 2:  always say that accessible design is universal design because like, it's
Speaker 2:  a really important thing. I think we as tech reviewers could be a lot more
Speaker 2:  thoughtful about that when we evaluate products. But from
Speaker 2:  someone who is deeply in that space of, of kind
Speaker 2:  of developing accessible tech, thinking about how accessible tech needs to
Speaker 2:  go into the future as well. I'm wondering like what would you like
Speaker 2:  to see improved? We do, we do happen to have a lot of people who
Speaker 2:  are in the right rooms and the right spaces to make those improvements. Listening
Speaker 2:  to this podcast, I should think. So like what, what do you think
Speaker 2:  would be like massive areas of improvement that could
Speaker 2:  really make a huge benefit? Like whether it be design
Speaker 2:  engineering, just like how we're thinking about developing like smart glasses
Speaker 2:  or any other type of wearable device with a camera for this particular type
Speaker 2:  of technology.
Speaker 7:  I think it's, the thing that you alluded to is that like it
Speaker 7:  has to happen at the design stage. Like I'll give you
Speaker 7:  a perfect example of this. Years ago, whether it was
Speaker 7:  malls or banks or airports, everybody rolled out
Speaker 7:  some like touchscreen kiosk, right? Whether it, it was
Speaker 7:  an ATM or a hotel thing. Do you know who that sucks for
Speaker 7:  someone who's blind or low vision, it's completely useless.
Speaker 2:  Ah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  To do that. And now we're gonna solve a lot of these challenges in the near
Speaker 7:  term through voice interaction, right? Which has huge power and
Speaker 7:  potential, but like the design stage is really important. And
Speaker 7:  making that very small, modest investment in the design stage
Speaker 7:  to make sure your product is accessible and adaptable to broader
Speaker 7:  communities, not only pays dividends in capturing the market
Speaker 7:  of disabled consumers, but it also makes your product better for
Speaker 7:  everyone. And I'll give you an example of this. When we were an early partner
Speaker 7:  with OpenAI on the first GPT models, we
Speaker 7:  brought 19,000 blind and low vision beta testers
Speaker 7:  to that effort who gave constant feedback and
Speaker 7:  iteration on the descriptions that they were getting
Speaker 7:  from the models, which helped the open AI
Speaker 7:  scientists and engineers further refine how those models
Speaker 7:  work, making them better for everybody. So I think those investments pay
Speaker 7:  off not only in trying to capture the market of the disabled consumers, but
Speaker 7:  also making the product better holistically for a broader segment of society.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think I was talking with my Meta contact recently and they mentioned
Speaker 2:  that one of the options now that's possible, I, I still have to test it
Speaker 2:  with the Meta glasses, is that you can now opt into much more
Speaker 2:  descriptive descriptions from the ai. So like, maybe me as a sighted person,
Speaker 2:  I don't need super detailed descriptions, but
Speaker 2:  if I am part of the blind or low vision community, I can opt
Speaker 2:  for really detailed descriptions of that. And I think that,
Speaker 2:  you know, that's like a, a really small tweak that
Speaker 2:  I know I wouldn't have thought of if I didn't invite
Speaker 2:  underserved communities into the room while talking about design.
Speaker 7:  But to think about what you just said, like that could be really useful for
Speaker 7:  a sighted consumer as well, like having a toggle switch that
Speaker 7:  controls the depth of information that I get. Like how much, like
Speaker 7:  if, if I'm out and about, I might want like a three second answer to questions,
Speaker 7:  but if I'm on vacation or I'm touring a museum or whatever else, I might
Speaker 7:  want to switch all the way on the other side 'cause I want robust information.
Speaker 7:  And so that's a really great example of how thinking about
Speaker 7:  the design elements of the robustness of description and
Speaker 7:  characterization can benefit not only the blind or low vision consumer, but
Speaker 7:  anybody.
Speaker 2:  I guess I'm curious if there's any parting thoughts from
Speaker 2:  your experience or stories that have been shared with you from
Speaker 2:  actual people using this technology that, you know, I think the vast
Speaker 2:  majority of our listeners, myself included, are sighted people. So like what
Speaker 2:  are some things that we should be thinking about when we are
Speaker 2:  thinking about how we evaluate this tech in our daily
Speaker 2:  lives?
Speaker 7:  You know, everybody comes at a consumer product or anything from their own
Speaker 7:  lens, but I mean, in terms of the, the people you know that, that you reach
Speaker 7:  every day, like I think it's good for everybody to think about, you know,
Speaker 7:  the fact that the world and the people within it and the, and their
Speaker 7:  needs are pretty diverse, right? And so it's sometimes hard to think
Speaker 7:  outside of our own little bubbles. I know I'm guilty of it, but I can tell
Speaker 7:  you that from the perspective of the community that we work with,
Speaker 7:  the blind and low vision consumer, I try to avoid hyperbole
Speaker 7:  because there's plenty of that in the AI world going around right now, right?
Speaker 7:  Without me adding to it. But I get two
Speaker 7:  emails a day anytime I run into someone at a
Speaker 7:  conference talking about the fact that, that the
Speaker 7:  glasses and the experience of be my eyes and AI
Speaker 7:  combined with those Meta glasses is literally life changing.
Speaker 7:  Don't take my word for that, talk to the blind or low vision consumer, but
Speaker 7:  I have stories about like, people taking the train for the first time on
Speaker 7:  their own or getting, you know, getting around an airport. There was
Speaker 7:  a story, actually, there's a guy named Robbie and he posted about it
Speaker 7:  publicly, so I don't feel like I'm outing him. Who, who, right? He works
Speaker 7:  for the BBC and he read a book to his
Speaker 7:  2-year-old daughter for the first time using those glasses and
Speaker 7:  be my eyes, like, how cool is that? So
Speaker 7:  think about the things that we all take for granted and then think about
Speaker 7:  Robbie for the first time as a dad, as a blind father
Speaker 7:  reading to his daughter. I, I, I just, I don't,
Speaker 7:  it doesn't get any better than that when you think about like kind of
Speaker 7:  human impact, right? And the benefits of this technology, like
Speaker 7:  there's a million reasons to be wary of ai right? And be fearful
Speaker 7:  of it, but like I'm pretty sure that there are a bunch of reasons
Speaker 7:  also to embrace it and champion it. And that, that
Speaker 7:  story of Robbie reading to his daughter is probably my favorite.
Speaker 2:  I, that's a really lovely story and honestly I
Speaker 2:  test a lot of AI stuff and some of it can feel very
Speaker 2:  dystopian, so thank you. Yeah. Honestly for the reminder that,
Speaker 2:  you know, there are creative uses that can help people
Speaker 2:  genuinely lead better lives. That maybe to your point, are
Speaker 2:  not steeped in the hyperbole of this is going to change
Speaker 2:  everything but not give concrete examples of
Speaker 2:  Alright, we are back. Let's get to the hotline as
Speaker 2:  always. The number is 8 6 6 VERGE 11 and the email is
Speaker 2:  vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all your questions and we try to
Speaker 2:  answer at least one on the show every week. So let's get into this week's
Speaker 2:  and for this week I have my lovely colleague Mia Sato on, and
Speaker 2:  we are going to answer a little bit of a spicy question about
Speaker 2:  smart glasses roll clip.
Speaker 13:  Hey David, I've got a question about smart glasses. I
Speaker 13:  haven't heard y'all talk about this yet in this way. I know that
Speaker 13:  with like the wristband or like the necklace that like listens to you,
Speaker 13:  there's ways to be like, oh no, I'm gonna mute it so don't hear
Speaker 13:  this private conversation,
Speaker 13:  but like the glasses seating, but also I need the
Speaker 13:  glasses to see. So I don't know,
Speaker 13:  maybe this is too sensitive for The Verge cap,
Speaker 13:  but I have a wife and sometimes she And I
Speaker 13:  like doing things And I like being able to see her when I do
Speaker 13:  those things. But if
Speaker 13:  she wanna have sex with me, if I've got my camera glasses on,
Speaker 13:  but if I take 'em off then I can't see her. Huh?
Speaker 13:  So like, are we gonna live in a world where if
Speaker 13:  you have smart glasses you have to have a pair of
Speaker 13:  normal glasses or your wife won't have sex with you?
Speaker 13:  Like I don't know what that world looks like and at that point, why have
Speaker 13:  the glasses in the first place anyway? I cannot
Speaker 13:  be the only person I have thought about this. But also like
Speaker 13:  when I go to the bathroom is Meta, it's gonna have like a
Speaker 13:  bunch of pictures of like me going to the bathroom.
Speaker 13:  I don't like that. And if Neli Patel hears this, he's gonna say, well you
Speaker 13:  do take four cameras into the bathroom with you every time. And I say, yeah,
Speaker 13:  that's true. Like an AI is training on it, right?
Speaker 13:  Like
Speaker 13:  my phone camera's not on all the time, right?
Speaker 13:  Anyway, please help me. I wanna get smart glasses, but I
Speaker 13:  also like having sex
Speaker 13:  rock and roll.
Speaker 14:  Amazing. It's an incredible question.
Speaker 2:  An amazing question. Anyway, I asked you to be my, my, my
Speaker 2:  partner answering this question because you've write so many
Speaker 2:  smart things about how technology shapes culture And I feel like
Speaker 2:  this is directly on that intersection and you know, this is my
Speaker 2:  beat and I've written some stuff about wear wearable etiquette as well. So
Speaker 2:  yeah, I, I feel like we are the most equipped people at The Verge to answer
Speaker 2:  this question with loving, kind empathy.
Speaker 2:  Yes. So yeah,
Speaker 14:  Yeah, yeah. So listener, I, I dunno your name,
Speaker 14:  maybe that's better for the best, but I guess I'm curious,
Speaker 14:  first of all, what your wife thinks. Like is this a conversation that
Speaker 14:  y'all have had about where in the house is
Speaker 14:  appropriate to wear the glasses versus where isn't? That would be
Speaker 14:  my first thing is just like, get a temperature check.
Speaker 14:  Because I do think that there are some things that are intimate
Speaker 14:  enough that like you might want a disconnected life
Speaker 14:  there, right? Like, like you said, going to the bathroom
Speaker 14:  maybe when you have sex with your wife
Speaker 14:  other times. Yeah. Because
Speaker 14:  like, I think like the reality is that even when
Speaker 14:  companies say like, we have these great security protocols, your
Speaker 14:  data is safe. There have been instances where
Speaker 14:  moments that you wouldn't want a stranger to see are
Speaker 14:  leaked or revealed in some ways. And we can get into that and talk about
Speaker 14:  those examples. Yeah. But to me, one is like, ask your wife
Speaker 14:  what she thinks. But also I feel like smart classes are not for the bedroom.
Speaker 2:  I think
Speaker 14:  That's just point blank period. That's super
Speaker 2:  Fair. So like last year when the smart classes and the Vision Pro
Speaker 2:  were, were getting kind of some buzz. I wrote a piece about like
Speaker 2:  a wearables primer etiquette And I interviewed Emily
Speaker 2:  post's grandson about it. And one of the things that he mentioned is
Speaker 2:  exactly what you're touching on, which is like having these conversations,
Speaker 2:  like this is definitely a conversation you need to broach with the wife and
Speaker 2:  like talk about what boundaries they're comfortable with
Speaker 2:  from like a gadget perspective. I can tell you there's an off button
Speaker 2:  on the Meta ray bands specifically, so you can just turn it
Speaker 2:  off. But like the, the interesting thing about these
Speaker 2:  glasses and how they signal privacy when there's video
Speaker 2:  recording or
Speaker 2:  photo taking is that there's a little LED light,
Speaker 2:  so you'll see the LED light when that's happening. So that is a visual cue
Speaker 2:  and a signal. But maybe I, you know, I, I
Speaker 2:  don't wanna kink shame people do
Speaker 14:  True
Speaker 2:  A, a number of acrobatics in the, in the, in the bedroom. I don't know
Speaker 2:  where hands are being put. There could be ostensibly
Speaker 2:  a situation if they're on that they could accidentally take a picture
Speaker 2:  or start video. You know, there's, or like you
Speaker 14:  Forget to turn
Speaker 2:  Them off or forget or you forget to turn them off before it's happening.
Speaker 2:  There's Meta AI in there. If you say anything that sounds
Speaker 2:  like, hey Meta, I don't know what your wife's name is, but what if it's Greta
Speaker 2:  and you trigger the AI and the AI just starts doing something like,
Speaker 2:  you know, one, you need to have the conversation. And two, I also agree
Speaker 2:  that there are just certain spaces, public versus
Speaker 2:  private where maybe you, you wanna like consciously draw
Speaker 2:  a line between the technology and, and your life.
Speaker 2:  Like I just think that's healthy digital hygiene in general and
Speaker 2:  you know, you don't have to throw away your old glasses. Yeah. When you get
Speaker 2:  the smart glasses. Yeah. You could just keep them. Well
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Another part of this question that I wanted to pick up on was like
Speaker 14:  the idea that you shouldn't have two pairs of glasses, which I completely
Speaker 14:  disagree with. Like, you actually actively should have multiple pairs of
Speaker 14:  glasses because like what if you break some, what if you just want to switch
Speaker 14:  up your look Like I am a recent glasses wearer. I'm not wearing glasses
Speaker 14:  right now, but like I have like four pairs of glasses because
Speaker 14:  sometimes one pair looks better with what I'm wearing or like
Speaker 14:  some like fit on my head differently And I need something different,
Speaker 14:  you know, depending on the day or depending on the activity. So I would
Speaker 14:  say like, it's totally fine to have two pairs of glasses. I get that it
Speaker 14:  might be annoying to switch back and forth, but like maybe you just leave
Speaker 14:  a pair of normal glasses on your nightstand or you know, in the drawer or
Speaker 14:  whatever.
Speaker 14:  I think it's fine to have two pairs of
Speaker 2:  Glasses. Glasses. It's totally, I am a lifelong glasses wear. I got my first,
Speaker 2:  again, I'm also wearing contacts right now, but I got my first pair when
Speaker 2:  I was four and the first thing that I real, I, I learned was you must
Speaker 2:  always have a backup pair of glasses. Yeah. Because you don't know when when's
Speaker 2:  gonna break. And the thing about these Meta glasses is that they, you do
Speaker 2:  have to put them in a case to charge. So it's not like you can wear them
Speaker 2:  24 7 anyway. Not that you would want to. So
Speaker 2:  also if it's just gonna affect your performance 'cause you got them on, they're
Speaker 2:  heavier than normal glasses as well. So
Speaker 14:  I not as aerodynamic.
Speaker 2:  They're not as aerodynamic. And again, no king shaming. I don't know what
Speaker 2:  you're doing in, in there. I don't know what acrobatics are required
Speaker 2:  or whatnot. So have a second pair of glasses. Always
Speaker 2:  let Yeah. And I, you know, I would actually say that to anyone who's thinking
Speaker 2:  about smart glasses have a pair of dumb glasses on hand. Like you don't Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You don't always want to have an ai Yeah. Coming with you
Speaker 2:  everywhere for everything. Right.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And I feel like this example in this question is like,
Speaker 14:  in my opinion, too intimate to even like risk. It,
Speaker 14:  there have been cases where like Roombas have recorded people in their homes
Speaker 14:  without them realizing like on the toilet. Like that's like a real thing
Speaker 14:  that has happened. And then I don't think that in that case it was like
Speaker 14:  publicly released, but people working for Roomba or working, you know,
Speaker 14:  contractors or whatever did have access to those images. Like this is a
Speaker 14:  thing that happens and in my opinion, like there are places
Speaker 14:  that are just a little too intimate for tech
Speaker 14:  companies to have a seat at the table. Like, you know, for example, like
Speaker 14:  for me, I don't do any digital journaling
Speaker 14:  that is like pen
Speaker 2:  Hundred percent. I'm with you on that. Right? Like, I also don't do any digital
Speaker 2:  journaling
Speaker 14:  At all. Yeah. I'm not doing the Apple Journal thing. I don't want them to
Speaker 14:  know my thoughts. I want there to be one copy of it and if I want to destroy
Speaker 14:  it, I can burn it in the backyard.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Not that 100%. I am, I'm on, I used to do digital
Speaker 2:  journaling and those have all since been deleted. Yeah. And my pen and paper,
Speaker 2:  like, it's just nice. Yeah. Sometimes to do things analog. Yeah. Not everything
Speaker 2:  has to be this way, but you know, why
Speaker 14:  Take the risk?
Speaker 2:  Why take the risk? And also to, to your point, even if
Speaker 2:  there's an off switch and even if you're really diligent about the off switch,
Speaker 2:  you are human, you are going to forget. I was testing the Bee, which was
Speaker 2:  a wearable AI thing that listened to everything you did.
Speaker 2:  I went to the bathroom,
Speaker 2:  it heard everything including me.
Speaker 2:  Exclaiming. Oh shit. That was a shit.
Speaker 2:  And then the AI recommended that I get back on lactate because it was like,
Speaker 2:  girl, ooh,
Speaker 14:  Don't like that.
Speaker 2:  I don't like that. That was the, the most humiliating thing of my life. And
Speaker 2:  it was, it was literally I went, oh shit, that was a shit. Oh shit, this
Speaker 2:  thing is listening to me. Shit. A lot of shit's in
Speaker 14:  A row. A lot of shits.
Speaker 2:  And it recorded all of that. And you know, that company, it was like, everything
Speaker 2:  is private. We don't record the audio recordings, but there's a transcript.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There's, there's like a, there's a trail of a thing that was said.
Speaker 2:  So
Speaker 14:  Yeah, also like terms and conditions are subject to change at any time.
Speaker 14:  Absolutely. Right. Are I feel like we have all learned that lesson many
Speaker 14:  times over to the point where like, I'm not wearing the
Speaker 14:  smart glasses to have sex. I think that's, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Bedrooms,
Speaker 14:  No
Speaker 2:  Bathrooms. I'm sure there's another thing that starts with ep
Speaker 14:  Even just, even just like being around your house sometimes, like
Speaker 14:  that is a private space. And
Speaker 14:  I don't know, I feel like most people, like you walk around in your underwear,
Speaker 14:  you, you do forget your bathrobe in the bedroom, so you need to like
Speaker 14:  do the naked dash through the house. Like there are lots of
Speaker 14:  instances where it's not just relegated to like only in the bedroom, only
Speaker 14:  in the bathroom, only in the closet. So yeah. I, I feel also,
Speaker 14:  like, I will say I'm, there's probably like zero
Speaker 14:  instances where I could be convinced to get smart glasses for all the
Speaker 14:  reasons that we've talked about. Like, I'm very forgetful. I kind of just
Speaker 14:  like do what I need to do when I need to do it. So it's a no for me.
Speaker 14:  But maybe you're, you, you have a happy balance.
Speaker 2:  I am, I'm more of a, of a kind of a middle ground where
Speaker 2:  obviously I'm testing these things. Obviously I'm a gadget girly. But I do
Speaker 2:  think you have to be really thoughtful and intentional about when you're
Speaker 2:  using this tech before this tech like rules you. So
Speaker 2:  I think have this conversation with your wife and she gets final say. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Because the, the thing about this new technology is that we are navigating
Speaker 2:  new privacy, like comfort zones and
Speaker 2:  levels with it. And you know, with the new, the new
Speaker 2:  era of smart glasses, privacy hasn't come up quite as much. 'cause I think
Speaker 2:  we're a lot more comfortable just everyone doing like a, oh my God, this
Speaker 2:  is my TikTok in public. Wow. So we're much more comfortable
Speaker 2:  theoretically with cameras being around all the time, but this is a
Speaker 2:  very private, intimate space. This is a very private, intimate act.
Speaker 2:  You gotta have the conversation first and it has to be something that you
Speaker 2:  both agree on and that you both consent to it because oh, you,
Speaker 2:  she's not gonna, I, I can tell you she's not gonna be happy if you just buy
Speaker 2:  them and wear that. Don't
Speaker 14:  Explain it.
Speaker 2:  Don't explain it.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. That's not good. As
Speaker 2:  There will be no sex having if that happens. So
Speaker 14:  Yes. Yeah. Yeah. Just think of it as an opportunity to kind of like expand
Speaker 14:  your glasses. Look. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Have more than Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Take away. Have a couple. Have a couple pair.
Speaker 2:  The the takeaway is have more than one pair of glasses. You can have more
Speaker 2:  than one pair. Treat yourself. Treat
Speaker 14:  Yourself.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I think, I think hopefully
Speaker 14:  This is helpful and have your wife call in too, if she has additional
Speaker 2:  Thoughts. Yes. I would love to hear from her if she has her thoughts, like
Speaker 2:  I would love to hear it. Yeah, we could do a follow up.
Speaker 15:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So that's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks Mia. Thanks
Speaker 2:  anonymous listener. Thanks for everyone on the show today and thank you for
Speaker 2:  listening. So there's a whole lot more from this conversation at The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. We'll put links in the show notes, but also read The Verge dot com,
Speaker 2:  find our bylines. You guys are internet savvy. I know you know how to do
Speaker 2:  it. As always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, you can always
Speaker 2:  email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep
Speaker 2:  calling the hotline. 8 6 6 VERGE 11. We love hearing from you.
Speaker 2:  Send us all your thoughts and we do mean all your thoughts and questions
Speaker 2:  and ideas for what we should do on the show. We do a hotline question every
Speaker 2:  week, so keep them coming. This show is produced by Eric Gomez,
Speaker 2:  Brandon Kiefer, Travis Uck and Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Jake will be
Speaker 2:  back on Friday to discuss all the news from this week and goodbye.