# Transcript
ID: 01897e1b-f19c-472e-884d-a3b40f269640
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5160715714893428604/5127460524943486535/s93290-US-5897s-1756690257.mp3
Description: The Pixel 10 is in the house, and we’ve been testing them for over a week now. Allison and Vee sit down with Jake to discuss their tests — the good, the bad, and the poorly translated. They demo the Pixel 10's live phone call translations and dive into Pro Res Zoom, which uses AI to enhance photos zoomed in up to 100x. Then, it’s time to talk Dish, Intel, and Elon. Dish is giving up on being a major mobile carrier, Intel is now partially owned by the US government, and Elon has filed a questionable lawsuit against Apple. Finally, we wrap up with a Thunder Round to discuss K-Pop Demon Hunters, YouTube Shorts’ secret “AI,” Android’s registration requirement for developers, Taco Bell’s drive through AI attempt, and a delivery locker on wheels.
Speaker 5:  Hello and Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of suing Your Way
Speaker 5:  to the top. I'm Jay Kanakas, executive editor of The Verge.
Speaker 5:  David and Neli will be back leader this year. We've got a lot to
Speaker 5:  talk about today and a really good crew, senior reviewer, the
Speaker 5:  songs with me. Hello and senior reviewer, Alison Johnson.
Speaker 5:  Hello. Lots of talk about Dish continues to be a complete
Speaker 5:  disaster. The US now owns part of Intel, which is a questionable
Speaker 5:  investment. Elon actually sued Apple and
Speaker 5:  OpenAI. I thought that was just a random tweet that was
Speaker 5:  gonna go nowhere. Senior news editor, Richard Lawler is gonna join us
Speaker 5:  later to talk about all that. But first, let's talk phones. A lot of phone
Speaker 5:  news this week, And I think most importantly, the two of you have been testing
Speaker 5:  the Google Pixel. 10 lots of new stuff there. It's got
Speaker 5:  magnets in it, tons of ai. There's Magic Q, which runs
Speaker 5:  on device, makes suggestions about what you're doing. ProRes Zoom,
Speaker 5:  which uses AI to reach a hundred x. Both of you have been testing these.
Speaker 5:  Alison, your review just published yesterday. How is it, how's the,
Speaker 5:  how's The Pixel 10 Pro?
Speaker 6:  Basically good, like I would, I would say
Speaker 6:  you look at all that together, it's pretty good. Like Google's been
Speaker 6:  on a good trajectory with The Pixel phones. I think like
Speaker 6:  they're feeling more and more flagship. You know, they got more expensive,
Speaker 6:  but it feels like the price is justified. So the
Speaker 6:  10 Pro, just to review, you know, we
Speaker 6:  get Tensor G five, Q2 is built in with
Speaker 6:  Magnus. Thank you. V She's doing a little QVC segment over there.
Speaker 5:  Excuse me. You're taking Jimmy's money? I am.
Speaker 7:  I'm showing Jimmy how it's done. See, I'm holding the phone right side up.
Speaker 7:  It's not upside down. Yeah, this is for the YouTube
Speaker 7:  viewers, but good
Speaker 6:  Call. Yeah, yeah, my, my TLDR is
Speaker 6:  the AI is starting to actually make sense,
Speaker 6:  starting to be a little more helpful than just a random smattering of like,
Speaker 6:  it's over in this app, it's in the screenshots. Gemini's gonna bother you
Speaker 6:  every time you open a Google Doc and
Speaker 6:  don't run out and buy it for any of that. But the it, it's a very good
Speaker 6:  phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You said some of that in your review. You were like, it's actually
Speaker 5:  getting helpful this year. And then I was like, well, what It didn't, they
Speaker 5:  have some helpful stuff like in the past And I was like, oh, right. Like
Speaker 5:  it's, it really was like a lot of like weird like gimmicks grab baggy stuff
Speaker 5:  and it's like some of it makes sense and a lot of it, like there's the, the
Speaker 5:  Add Me feature for photos where you can like hand your phone to
Speaker 5:  somebody else and then it'll put you into, And I am like, this is a really
Speaker 5:  lovely demo. And I would love to know if they have
Speaker 5:  data on how many people actually use that.
Speaker 7:  It's like not a situation that happens that often. It's, it's like it happens
Speaker 7:  when you're on vacation, but like,
Speaker 5:  Are you gonna really like take time and be like, Hey, good friend of
Speaker 5:  mine, I know we could just hold our arm out,
Speaker 5:  take a selfie, but there is this specific feature on my phone that you
Speaker 5:  don't know how to use it. I need to learn how to use, but in this moment
Speaker 5:  we can. And like there were, there were demos there. It
Speaker 5:  felt like there were demos And I think like you're kind of right. It seems
Speaker 5:  like this year, maybe Magic Q in particular,
Speaker 5:  there's actually the start of something that you actually would
Speaker 6:  Use. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Kinda. I think Magic Q worked a little bit better for Allison than it
Speaker 7:  did for me because we would be talking on Slack and they're like, can you
Speaker 7:  send me this message? So it was like faking it a little bit because you just
Speaker 7:  wanna see if it's gonna, because it, it like, I think you have to
Speaker 7:  prompt it in such a way that it will be like Aha information
Speaker 7:  is being asked for, but that's not necessarily how people
Speaker 7:  convey it to you. So like Alison, in your
Speaker 7:  review, and this was real, she slacked me and she's like, can you ask me
Speaker 7:  when my Japanese breakfast concert is? And I did and it worked
Speaker 7:  for her. And then I was like, oh, can you ask me when I'm seeing Heather's?
Speaker 7:  And she did. And it didn't work for me.
Speaker 5:  Aw.
Speaker 7:  So I was like, but it's in my calendar.
Speaker 5:  The thing that I, I think feels limiting right now. And
Speaker 5:  I, And I am curious if they'll ever be, be able to expand. This
Speaker 5:  is, I think Allison, you said it only works in Google's own apps.
Speaker 5:  Like it only has access to Google data.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And kind of small list of them, like calendar Gmail
Speaker 6:  messages, like messages is kind of the most frequent place I saw
Speaker 6:  it. It can suggest things in Gboard. So you can see
Speaker 6:  one I had just now as I opened Spotify and
Speaker 6:  it came up with a suggestion from The Pixel screenshots
Speaker 6:  app of like some band names I might have been searching for. I was like,
Speaker 6:  that's actually helpful 'cause I'll screenshot something as playing on
Speaker 6:  KXP. And I'm like, I should listen to that later. And I never do anything
Speaker 6:  with it.
Speaker 6:  So that kind of thing. There are, there is a way for them to kind of like
Speaker 6:  creep into other apps, but it's mainly in the main Google apps right
Speaker 6:  now.
Speaker 5:  Which like in fairness, you know, they do contain a lot of your life,
Speaker 5:  But that is, it's still like pretty limiting if it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, it's calendar events.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I,
Speaker 7:  It's like I, I think the one that they, they message they mentioned was
Speaker 7:  like, oh, and you can get reminders for your Google Keep app. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  the
Speaker 6:  I don't use Oh, I know. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Google keep for reminders, but okay, I'll try it.
Speaker 7:  So I was on Tuesday, I was at Shakespeare in the park, which if you're not
Speaker 7:  a native New Yorker, you wait in a really fricking long line at Central
Speaker 7:  Park at, and this year it's a stacked cast. So I had to get to Central Park
Speaker 7:  at 4 45 in the morning. This
Speaker 5:  Is ludicrous. It's ludicrous. You messaged me at like some ungodly hour
Speaker 5:  of the morning And I'm like, what? Sorry, why are you awake this
Speaker 7:  Early? Oh yeah. And I was doing an edit because I was sitting in
Speaker 7:  line at like 4 45 in the morning And I was like, I'll just do a little work
Speaker 7:  now because I'm gonna be here for the next seven hours trying to get a ticket
Speaker 7:  to this, this free ticket to this show. But the whole point was I was there
Speaker 7:  with a couple of friends and one of my friends turns to me and she's like,
Speaker 7:  remind me that I need a sweatshirt tonight because it's gonna be
Speaker 7:  the same temperature and when we're in this outdoor theater, I need a sweatshirt.
Speaker 7:  And I was like, how about I remind you by you telling
Speaker 7:  me
Speaker 7:  in a text message to remind you to bring
Speaker 7:  the sweatshirt and, 'cause I need to test this Magic Q thing. And
Speaker 7:  she gave me this look like, are you fucking for real? And
Speaker 7:  I said, yes, please, please. I, I I just wanna see if this works. And it
Speaker 7:  did. And I got a little Google keep reminder that
Speaker 7:  said, at eight o'clock remind friend to bring a
Speaker 7:  sweatshirt. And I was like, oh, there go. And then at eight o'clock it did
Speaker 7:  not pop up to say no,
Speaker 5:  No. So close.
Speaker 7:  It was so close, but, or at least I didn't notice it. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  The way it feels to me, me is a little bit like,
Speaker 6:  you know, when auto, like one time passwords
Speaker 6:  started auto filling from text messages. It was huge.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was great. I was like, this is awesome. I don't have to do anything.
Speaker 6:  And then you, you just kind of forget about it. And that's just how phones
Speaker 6:  work now. It sort of feels like it's gonna be that.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I did have more success with it having
Speaker 6:  stuff popping up,
Speaker 6:  but then I don't, I don't think that's something I was like, well thank God
Speaker 6:  for this. You know, I was just kinda like, oh, this is super nice
Speaker 6:  And I will just get used to this and take it for granted. Probably.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I it whenever like a password doesn't autofill for me. I'm like,
Speaker 5:  this is the end of the world. Yeah. Like, I can't go on like this.
Speaker 6:  You have to throw your phone into the C
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Something has gone horribly awry. I, I like that as
Speaker 5:  sort of like a, a framework for where useful AI
Speaker 5:  is. Like that's not doing something
Speaker 5:  ostentatious, it's not doing, it's not not changing the world.
Speaker 5:  It is just being like legit. It's helpful in small, very like, precise
Speaker 5:  ways that like require a little bit more contextual awareness. And
Speaker 5:  I think like perhaps traditional programming could have gotten you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like we've had ways to put things on calendars before that
Speaker 6:  didn't involve generative ai. You know, we've been trying
Speaker 6:  to do that in emails and everything like that. This just feels the extra
Speaker 6:  a little bit smarter where it can connect dots a little bit
Speaker 6:  better.
Speaker 7:  I did remember one time Magic Q came up with a conversation with my
Speaker 7:  friend And I was like, oh, and she was mentioning things that we could do
Speaker 7:  for day trips and she mentioned some festival and Rhinebeck And
Speaker 7:  I was like, I don't know where Rhinebeck is. And then it popped up like a
Speaker 7:  Maps magic Q thingy and it's like, Rhinebeck. And I was like, oh,
Speaker 7:  I can see how far Reinbeck is. And I was like, oh, I'm not driving two and
Speaker 7:  a half hours. So,
Speaker 6:  And now that's
Speaker 7:  Out, you know? Yeah. So now I know, but I was like, that was one time where
Speaker 7:  the magic cue, I was like, oh, okay,
Speaker 5:  That's not so bad. YouTube tested a bunch of these sort of
Speaker 5:  AI applied features. Right? What, what were the other interesting ones?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so ve helped me out on the day that she was
Speaker 6:  technically not working, but it sounds like doing kind of a lot of work.
Speaker 7:  Listen, it's a long seven hour wait. Like you gotta figure out stuff
Speaker 7:  to make and make the time pass.
Speaker 6:  I, I was like, can I call you and
Speaker 6:  you can speak in a different language to, to this phone. And
Speaker 6:  she had the, The Pixel 10 as well.
Speaker 6:  So we tried out the voice translate and that one is
Speaker 6:  like, we've seen this from Samsung previously.
Speaker 6:  It's, it just kind of chimes in and speaks
Speaker 6:  the translation live on the phone while you're talking back and forth.
Speaker 6:  So you can make a dinner reservation or, or whatever. This one mimics the
Speaker 6:  speaker's voice both ways, which
Speaker 6:  is a little wild.
Speaker 6:  And we had like a weird time with it.
Speaker 7:  My friend was also there off the side and my friend was just like, her eyes
Speaker 7:  were just like,
Speaker 6:  Yo, what?
Speaker 7:  Because at one point Robot Allison, who
Speaker 7:  was speaking in Japanese to me was just went like, she
Speaker 7:  glitched, she went, eh,
Speaker 6:  It was wild.
Speaker 7:  And we were screaming like it was just like going, what happened? And then,
Speaker 7:  you know, we kept like talking through it and so then we were
Speaker 7:  confusing the robot at one point. And then on her end, robot V
Speaker 7:  went, ah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it started like screaming back at me.
Speaker 6:  This doesn't sound very successful. It seems like worse
Speaker 6:  than it was
Speaker 7:  Before. It was kind of half successful. I think like Allison coming through
Speaker 7:  in Japanese was actually pretty good. I was, it was one of the
Speaker 7:  times until the screaming until the screaming, the screaming until we broke
Speaker 7:  it. But I, I actually think I was the one that like broke things because
Speaker 7:  Allison was talking like a normal person and fluent English because that's
Speaker 7:  her native language. And unless, unless you're hiding something from me,
Speaker 7:  Allison, but she's talking in her natural language, she's
Speaker 7:  talking in full sentences that make sense. Me in my Japanese, which is
Speaker 7:  a little rusty, my sentences were a little bit broken. They
Speaker 7:  weren't fully textbook appropriate like, you know, like textbook grammar.
Speaker 7:  'cause when you talk in Japanese it can be very, you can just
Speaker 7:  start leaving out pronouns and people will understand it 'cause it's
Speaker 7:  contextual. And
Speaker 7:  the only way I could explain it was that I was glitching in real time because
Speaker 7:  I'm code switching between languages. So part of me would forget a word And
Speaker 7:  I'd be like, ah, what would I call that? And it's, and it's
Speaker 7:  translating all those little like, oh, what, how do I say that again? And
Speaker 7:  me talking to myself a little bit while I'm talking to Allison and that's
Speaker 7:  what I think caused it to go. That's fascinating. Absolutely not. I broke
Speaker 7:  the machine it and you know, she's asking me about Shakespeare. I'm like,
Speaker 7:  oh, I don't know the Japanese title for 12th night, so
Speaker 7:  I'm just gonna ize it and go 12 night. And it was just
Speaker 7:  like, nope. Not translating that you hoe this is what I imagine
Speaker 7:  Gemini is thinking in its head. But it was very much
Speaker 7:  like, oh that kind of informs when you would use this, right?
Speaker 7:  Because if you're making the reservation, like Allison saying,
Speaker 7:  you're talking in a measured tone,
Speaker 7:  you're talking in full sentences probably. And the person is also doing
Speaker 7:  that and you're talking in your own native languages. But if, you know, I
Speaker 7:  think one of the demos they were saying you could talk to family members
Speaker 7:  who you maybe don't necessarily speak the same language as, and
Speaker 7:  that's a situation in my actual family. And I was like, listen,
Speaker 7:  we speak konglish in my family, in which people are non
Speaker 7:  sequitur, just mashing grammar of two different
Speaker 7:  languages together in a pigeon. And I think that would just confuse
Speaker 7:  just trip up the, the robot. And so the solution
Speaker 7:  would to just speak, be speaking in your native language. But
Speaker 7:  after years and years of just talking to each other in this pigeon, I
Speaker 7:  don't like, that would be really hard to, to just do. 'cause
Speaker 7:  my aunt will be like, ah, did you get
Speaker 7:  call? And it is just like those going back and forth in between the English
Speaker 7:  and plugging vocabulary in different ways. And I was like, oh, that would
Speaker 7:  not work.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's fascinating though. Like, it, it hasn't adapted to the way
Speaker 5:  that a lot of people actually speak
Speaker 7:  Yet. And that's my like, commentary on most translation tech. It's getting
Speaker 7:  a lot better with ai. That's very exciting to me. But just the way that
Speaker 7:  we actually speak is so varied and changes
Speaker 7:  minute to minute. And I mean, you see the creative linguistics the kids are
Speaker 7:  doing with Gibby toilet and all of that. So, you know, we should
Speaker 7:  test that. If it can un if it can translate gibby toilet,
Speaker 6:  Oh, I'm calling you right now. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's, it's gonna scream again. It's
Speaker 7:  Gonna go like scream
Speaker 6:  What? And the, I mean it it, it did sound like
Speaker 6:  V at times it was just so weird to hear like an,
Speaker 6:  an imitation of your voice coming through the phone. There were, there were
Speaker 6:  times it sounded like, kind of like you and there were times it would just
Speaker 6:  go in a different direction. I'm like, that that is a different person. That's
Speaker 6:  a different voice. But it it, it tried. The little robot tried.
Speaker 7:  So Allison speaking in Japanese is very deep voiced.
Speaker 6:  She's
Speaker 7:  Just very deep voiced, which is like an interesting choice
Speaker 7:  because like Japanese and Korean and especially those are languages
Speaker 7:  where you tend to speak higher. So like when I speak in those languages,
Speaker 7:  my voice pitch goes up. 'cause that's just like naturally a feature of the
Speaker 7:  language. Everyone's pitch goes up.
Speaker 5:  It still sounded like Allison to you
Speaker 7:  Sometimes. It's like in the beginning. Yes. And
Speaker 7:  then it would just turn into a robot, Japanese lady.
Speaker 5:  The other question for me on these is like, what is the latency? Because
Speaker 5:  it's like, it has to, number one, do the translation. It then has to make
Speaker 5:  it sound like the other person's voice. And if there's any latency, like
Speaker 5:  this just breaks, nobody's gonna sit around for that. It's
Speaker 6:  Sort of intentionally like, let's you talk for a minute and then there's
Speaker 6:  a little like, woo. Like it's, it makes a little noise, like something is
Speaker 6:  happening and then the translator starts talking. Okay. So
Speaker 6:  it, it's kind of nice 'cause you, it gives you a minute to be like, okay,
Speaker 6:  they're talking, you hear them talk for a second. It doesn't, it doesn't
Speaker 6:  feel like a delay. I am annoyed about it's, it just sort of,
Speaker 6:  and and from there it flows pretty well. I didn't think it was
Speaker 6:  like, like super slow or anything.
Speaker 7:  Just like that conversational rhythm that Allison was going into where she's
Speaker 7:  pausing, stopping to think, switching gears mid-sentence
Speaker 7:  that trips it up. It absolutely trips it up because like in the demos when
Speaker 7:  you get that, you're just speaking in full formed thoughts and that's just
Speaker 7:  not how conversation is. Yeah. So I like, this is not necessarily
Speaker 7:  a Google AI problem. This is a, all AI translators in my experience problem
Speaker 7:  where you just be like, oh, you know, I'm talking and then, oh wait
Speaker 7:  a second, I have a different thought. And actually mm, yeah. You know, like,
Speaker 7:  mm. So anyway, and you do that very natural. You understand
Speaker 7:  in, in person the robot just goes, ah,
Speaker 7:  starts, that's actually what the robot did starts screaming on both
Speaker 7:  of our ends. And I was like, oh, okay. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You both have the, the phones in front of you, right? Yeah. Let's, I, I need
Speaker 5:  to hear this. I need to, let's like, let's give this a try.
Speaker 6:  All right. I'm calling you V
Speaker 7:  Okay, yeah, yeah. The
Speaker 5:  Rest of The Vergecast will be conducted this way. Oh
Speaker 7:  God. This is gonna be
Speaker 5:  Okay. Do you need to like activate a certain mode or just like starts?
Speaker 7:  I, you do need to activate like a certain thing. Okay, here we go.
Speaker 7:  Answer call assist voice translate.
Speaker 6:  V what did you have for breakfast today? What did you have today? Breakfast
Speaker 6:  today?
Speaker 8:  Any do
Speaker 9:  Some mandarin oranges too? I ate it.
Speaker 7:  Japanese people are saying
Speaker 9:  My lines. I'll definitely know. Maybe
Speaker 5:  V whose fault do we think this translation is?
Speaker 7:  Okay. Okay, I'm stopping this
Speaker 5:  No more.
Speaker 7:  Like, so, you know, my Japanese is not perfect, but
Speaker 7:  an actual, what I, what I said basically was I think a Japanese person
Speaker 7:  who was listening to me, even if I'm not using the right exact
Speaker 7:  word, that a native speaker would, they would understand the meaning of what
Speaker 7:  I was saying. They would probably be like, oh, you know, she's, it is like
Speaker 7:  when you talk to a non-native English speaker and they use a funny word,
Speaker 7:  but you get the gist across and you don't really think about it because it's
Speaker 7:  normal. You, you understand it. The AI
Speaker 7:  translated it in a funny little way. It's not wrong.
Speaker 7:  The translation's not wrong. But because Allison is speaking in, in a native
Speaker 7:  way, the Japanese that's coming across is more correct in a certain thing.
Speaker 7:  And so that was something I noticed and was like, oh, it reminded me of this
Speaker 7:  time when I was in college And I went to college in Tokyo and
Speaker 7:  one of the classes that they made us take, if you didn't like test
Speaker 7:  out of it was conversational Japanese. And so the assignment was
Speaker 7:  that you had to actually call Pizza Hut,
Speaker 7:  the Japanese Pizza Hut version and order a pizza.
Speaker 7:  And
Speaker 7:  'cause they were like, you're gonna live here for so many months, so you
Speaker 7:  need to know how to be a functional human. And these are not necessarily
Speaker 7:  things that you learn in a high school Japanese class. So
Speaker 7:  we were doing this and my friend had a meltdown
Speaker 7:  because she didn't realize that how to read a Japanese
Speaker 7:  address and how to give a Japanese address. Oh. So the person on the phone
Speaker 7:  was just like, she was just reading out numbers as you would in
Speaker 7:  a like, you know, like something, something
Speaker 7:  something in Tokyo. And it's like you have to actually say no in between
Speaker 7:  instead of dash. That's how you would say it. And so she lost her mind. They
Speaker 7:  lost their mind. And I, you know, I was thinking back to that And I was like,
Speaker 7:  this would super have like coming
Speaker 7:  crutch at that time she could have just talked to them, ordered a pizza,
Speaker 7:  given them the address, and that would've been written, that would've been
Speaker 7:  like translated in a way that's super helpful but not helpful in the sense
Speaker 7:  that she wouldn't have learned how to actually say it properly in Japanese.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So in that sense I was like, oh, it's actually also not great
Speaker 7:  if you're trying to get better at the language, but might come in
Speaker 7:  like handy in a pinch when you're just like, I I don't have the brain cells
Speaker 7:  to, to attempt this today. Yeah. And I just want a pizza like
Speaker 7:  fair. So it's interesting.
Speaker 6:  I don't like ordering a pizza on the phone in English. It makes me
Speaker 6:  nervous.
Speaker 7:  It was, it was a, I watch several,
Speaker 5:  They also have AI for that Allison, they, they like,
Speaker 5:  this is all use pointless. Oh no, they're just going to AI everything
Speaker 5:  eventually.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's true.
Speaker 5:  The, okay. There is another big AI feature that I really wanna make sure
Speaker 5:  we talk about, which is the ProRes zoom, which
Speaker 5:  on the camera there's a five x telephoto optically and you
Speaker 5:  can zoom in and after 30 x it starts using AI built
Speaker 5:  into the camera app to enhance the photos. And
Speaker 5:  last week I was like, I was like, this looks
Speaker 5:  incredible. This looks, this is like blowing my mind because I'd
Speaker 5:  just seen a few sample images out of the early hands ons
Speaker 5:  and some more stuff has come out since then. You, you've had a chance to
Speaker 5:  test it. And I'm,
Speaker 7:  There's, I would say some,
Speaker 5:  Some flaws are showing in places. I'm curious, Alison, like you actually,
Speaker 5:  you towed it around another giant camera. So like test this
Speaker 5:  against like an actual a hundred x zoom. How, how is it,
Speaker 5:  how do you feel now that you've tried it about having AI in
Speaker 5:  your camera, changing your photos?
Speaker 6:  I feel weird about it.
Speaker 6:  My big picture take is like, it is pretty good if you
Speaker 6:  stay in the 30 to maybe like 50
Speaker 6:  x range. It can, you know, I'll, I'll take a picture of
Speaker 6:  a container ship from a bridge and it knows what to do
Speaker 6:  with the, you know, you get kind of those jagged lines and digital
Speaker 6:  zoom and things just look weird and crunchy. It will clean
Speaker 6:  that up and it looks totally passable.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, all right, this, it doesn't look amazing. It's not like a
Speaker 6:  National Geographic photo of a container ship. Like, it, it looks like a,
Speaker 6:  a decent phone picture of a container ship. But I
Speaker 6:  did carry around at Jake's urging,
Speaker 6:  so this was his fault.
Speaker 5:  I, I'm sorry, I didn't know how much of a burden this would be. I
Speaker 5:  was like, we should get a real hundred X zoom. And turns out that's
Speaker 5:  heavy and large.
Speaker 6:  I know I, I should have known too, but I did the
Speaker 6:  math And I was like, there is exactly one camera that can do this. It
Speaker 6:  is a Nikon cool picks P 1100. It is a
Speaker 6:  gigantic beast.
Speaker 5:  This thing is hilarious there. I like the photos of it that they
Speaker 5:  advertise like, it's like the size of somebody's face.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it is. And there there's just no like camera
Speaker 6:  bag. I have to put it in. That makes sense. I just had to like
Speaker 6:  lu it around. The first time I, I went out, I was like, I'm gonna take side
Speaker 6:  by side photos. I've got this phone, this camera was trying,
Speaker 6:  I was trying to handhold the camera at 2,400 millimeters.
Speaker 6:  That doesn't work. You don't, like I failed deep review
Speaker 6:  college or whatever. So I went out again with the
Speaker 6:  tripod. My tripod is flimsy and crappy
Speaker 6:  and it, the, the camera, once you get zoomed out far enough,
Speaker 6:  it starts sagging a little bit even though I've got it locked in.
Speaker 6:  So I did not end up with amazing
Speaker 6:  side-by-side photos. I have a side-by-side
Speaker 6:  photo in the review, which is basically a boulder with some
Speaker 6:  trash next to it
Speaker 5:  Because that wasn't a most scenic photo. No,
Speaker 5:  you've like everything else in your review. Lovely. It's like a boulder and
Speaker 5:  like a stick.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. There's like some garbage just sort of laying around And I was
Speaker 6:  like, well this is what we've got. 'cause it was the only thing I could get
Speaker 6:  framed up reliably
Speaker 6:  and very humbling experience the, the
Speaker 6:  Nikon. And I put the, The Pixel on the tripod too to give it
Speaker 6:  a fair shot. Yeah. The, as you would expect,
Speaker 6:  the optical zoom does better. I was sort of surprised. I thought
Speaker 6:  the The Pixel did okay, like considering everything
Speaker 6:  it was doing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The a hundred x like that one clearly looks optical and it's not, it's
Speaker 5:  not a great photo, but it's significantly clearer. The Pixel photo
Speaker 5:  is not bad though, particularly when you compare it to the like pre AI
Speaker 5:  version. And this is the thing that's been fascinating is like,
Speaker 5:  I think there are cer there seems to be certain subjects where this
Speaker 5:  AI enhancement is great And I think if you didn't tell me it was ai,
Speaker 5:  I would be like cool. They're just doing some fancy upscale and looks great.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, you know, particularly for photographs of
Speaker 5:  buildings, architecture in general,
Speaker 5:  it seems to look great. It just like, you can't tell that
Speaker 5:  this has been upscaled in any way. I've done, like I've looked really closely
Speaker 5:  side by side and I'm not seeing any weird AI wackiness. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The thing that trips it up, as soon as there is a
Speaker 5:  single letter of text, it goes uhoh,
Speaker 5:  I'm ai I have no freaking idea what I'm doing. Yeah. And so
Speaker 5:  there'll be this image that like, so you you, the thing that's
Speaker 5:  wonderful is like The Pixel gives you the before image and the after image
Speaker 5:  so you can see what's happening. And so you'll have this, this image
Speaker 5:  that by, by all account everything else, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's just like perfectly cleaned up, crisper, sharper
Speaker 5:  looks clearer. And then there'll just be these letters that are just like,
Speaker 5:  I don't know what language is. It is just like, it's just total
Speaker 5:  garbage. And I'm like, what happened here? Like
Speaker 7:  It's just weird 'cause it's like, when are you gonna do this? Right? Like,
Speaker 7:  when are you gonna zoom in a hundred times? For what purpose are you zooming
Speaker 7:  in a hundred times on a thing? If it's, I mean I know I did it on the Shakespeare
Speaker 7:  line to beat for chits and giggles 'cause I was just bored. And so I
Speaker 7:  went a hundred, a hundred times zoom on my friend's eye and that was a
Speaker 7:  nightmare.
Speaker 5:  I hope was a scary hope that didn't as that's, I saw her eye, that is a nightmare.
Speaker 7:  That is her eye before the AI got involved. Okay. That's the
Speaker 7:  AI after.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 7:  That's, And I think that's just actually a really fun art project
Speaker 7:  because what is this, this is a nightmare. It's
Speaker 5:  Beautiful. This is like a black pit of despair with some like streaks
Speaker 5:  of, of
Speaker 7:  That's I'm
Speaker 5:  Like color around that side. That's
Speaker 7:  Like an eyelash maybe that's, that's something and you know,
Speaker 7:  sure. Like what, what are you trying to do? Are you trying to find some
Speaker 7:  interlopers license plate number? Is that why you're doing a hundred Zoom?
Speaker 6:  I mean the idea is landscape kind of stuff.
Speaker 6:  Landmarks, you're on vacation, you're taking a picture of Statue of Liberty.
Speaker 6:  It's kind of far away. So I, I get that
Speaker 6:  it, there are all kinds of implications of what is a
Speaker 6:  photo. Did you really take a photo of the statue? Liberty if AI just kind
Speaker 6:  of filled in the gaps for you? The the writing thing is
Speaker 6:  funny because it does get really nervous and doesn't know what to do. I
Speaker 6:  found that like really big lettering it could do okay.
Speaker 6:  But as soon as it was a little smaller in the image,
Speaker 6:  it just kinda like, I don't know what that is. I,
Speaker 5:  That, that's what kind of breaks my mind about it. Because like, again, if
Speaker 5:  I, I think if I took a, a Statue of Liberty photo with this, like,
Speaker 5:  it, it, it would, it would appear to be my photo by all accounts.
Speaker 5:  But as soon as there is text in it, I'm like, no,
Speaker 5:  there's literally an AI rewriting this image.
Speaker 5:  And that's very trippy. And I think last week I was like, man,
Speaker 5:  maybe this is some new era of photography. Everything is getting upscaled,
Speaker 5:  but it seems like they've actually been pretty precise here
Speaker 5:  in and pretty limiting in what it's applied to. It feels like it probably
Speaker 5:  shouldn't be applied to text at this point in time, even though it'd be cool
Speaker 5:  to be able to zoom in and read some signs from far away, but it doesn't know
Speaker 5:  what language is, so it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I didn't see anything too wacky
Speaker 6:  or unexpected outside of this. The letters and
Speaker 6:  signs, it gets a little confused by, I think specular
Speaker 6:  highlights if there is, you know, like bright sunlight on the
Speaker 6:  surface of a pond and there were, there's a bunch of garbage and
Speaker 6:  like duck feathers floating around in the pond. It didn't know what to do
Speaker 6:  with those because they just look like points of white stuff and
Speaker 6:  you magnify that a hundred times, it just looks weirder and
Speaker 6:  weirder. So it could kind of, it sort of took those things
Speaker 6:  and went in a different direction. You're like, no, this, this isn't it.
Speaker 6:  But for the most part it was, it was pretty impressive.
Speaker 6:  Closer to 30 times. And as long as you're not asking it to,
Speaker 6:  to read English,
Speaker 5:  This is like gonna give us, i I think material to debate
Speaker 5:  the, what is a photo question for, for years to come. I suspect this is
Speaker 5:  also not going to be the end of AI and camera apps.
Speaker 5:  Very interesting year for The Pixel. Not a lot of like huge hardware
Speaker 5:  changes, but the AI stuff is, is I think particularly interesting this year.
Speaker 5:  Other big thing in phones happening this week. Apple announced the
Speaker 5:  iPhone 17 event. It's happening September 9th. I think we're expecting
Speaker 5:  that to be a pretty interesting one. But now that we've seen what Samsung
Speaker 5:  has to offer this year, now the pixels are out. What do we need to see from
Speaker 5:  Apple to kind of keep up the momentum?
Speaker 6:  I think it's gonna be another situation where they kind of
Speaker 6:  tap dance around the ai, you know, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Thing that's not happening or happening. It seems
Speaker 6:  like we're gonna get some, some different hardware, camera
Speaker 6:  bump goes sideways or something like that. But I think that
Speaker 6:  the elephant in the room is gonna be AI again.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I don't know. It's in, in a weird way, it feels like these phones are
Speaker 7:  merging into each other in a, 'cause if the camera bump goes sideways, like
Speaker 7:  some of the leaked renders I've seen, I'm like, it just kind of looks like
Speaker 7:  this.
Speaker 5:  It's not, it's not a bad look. I've like, it's not, I've looked at these
Speaker 5:  mockups And I'm like, it's a little funky, but
Speaker 7:  It's not a bad look. But then I'm just like, they're, they're, they're merging
Speaker 7:  into each other in, in a way that's like, you know, Pixel comes out with
Speaker 7:  a journal app, this comes out with a sideways sidebar.
Speaker 7:  MagSafe is on both of them, which, you know, honestly, that was great having
Speaker 7:  MagSafe fond. This was like really great. But
Speaker 7:  I don't know. It's, it's weird, it's bizarre. And Google
Speaker 7:  coming out with such a strong opinion on AI and where
Speaker 7:  it belongs in our devices and, and our lives.
Speaker 7:  I'm just sort of like, ooh, what are they? They threw down the gauntlet
Speaker 7:  a big, what's Apple gonna do?
Speaker 5:  Big a big design refresh is always a good way to, I would say
Speaker 5:  distract from, from any other things. Like you can, you can do nothing else
Speaker 5:  and you're like completely brand new design. Like I, I say, you know what,
Speaker 5:  I'll, I'll take it. I take it. I feel like there's such liquid ass right
Speaker 5:  there. Oh yeah. This is the thing. You've gotta, you've gotta find something
Speaker 5:  to pair with the lovely liquid glass designed, you
Speaker 5:  know, the, the, I think different years are for different things, but also
Speaker 5:  like, it's been a minute since the iPhone has changed in a pretty significant
Speaker 5:  way. The current design is getting a little stale. So like, I I don't hate
Speaker 5:  it. I do, the AI thing is really interesting because it's true.
Speaker 5:  Apple sat down like a year and a half ago. They're like, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna be a major player in this year and a half later. And we kind of know
Speaker 5:  that they're skirting around it, skirting around it still.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. They could, they could have some surprises in store. I don't
Speaker 5:  know that it's gonna happen. I think there's been like ongoing rumors that
Speaker 5:  they're gonna get a Gemini partnership to go alongside the chat GBT
Speaker 5:  thing. It's not clear if that's actually gonna happen in time, but
Speaker 7:  We'll see. Yeah, we'll see what the one more thing is if there is one. And
Speaker 5:  It's not gonna be Google.
Speaker 7:  I mean honestly, honestly, I was just like orange,
Speaker 7:  orange phone. Orange, orange maybe. Yeah. Orange. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  orange. Because orange is not my color, but I have, I have
Speaker 7:  yelled for years that I would like an iPhone pro model
Speaker 7:  to actually have a color and not like a hint of a color.
Speaker 7:  So I saw the, the renders And I was like, listen, that color's not for me.
Speaker 7:  I'm not an orange person, but I appreciate it. Cool.
Speaker 5:  This is what Apple needs to do this year. Make colors happen. Make colors,
Speaker 5:  real colors. Sat
Speaker 5:  like sad dark place that Neli isn't here to
Speaker 5:  commiserate with us about this one.
Speaker 5:  I think as you all know,
Speaker 5:  NELI for a period of time this year has run a, a very
Speaker 5:  famous, well-respected, well-received segment,
Speaker 5:  internationally known as Brendan Carr as a dummy. This
Speaker 5:  segment highlighted the, you know, ups and
Speaker 5:  downs and mostly the downs of FCC chairman Brendan Carr.
Speaker 5:  Now this segment will not be returning today because it
Speaker 5:  is copyright trademark All rights Reserve Neli Patel Enterprises. And, And
Speaker 5:  I, I just couldn't get a license to it. But it is here in spirit
Speaker 5:  because I cannot emphasize
Speaker 5:  the disaster, the absolute disaster of what
Speaker 5:  has happened with Dish, like Dish was already a disaster.
Speaker 5:  And, And I I do not know how it could get worse. And now it
Speaker 5:  it it did, it got worse. It's just, it's just a complete fa like there's
Speaker 5:  been nothing redeemable about Dish's
Speaker 5:  5G Network. Is that correct?
Speaker 11:  I'm sorry. I was, I'm thinking, I'm trying to think of something And I'm
Speaker 11:  just, I'm coming up with nothing. I I got nothing. I think Mitchell, this,
Speaker 11:  this piece that Mitchell Clark wrote three, nearly three years
Speaker 11:  ago now, I went to the Genesis point of Dish 5G Network and all I got
Speaker 11:  was disappointment just captures the entire experience, I think.
Speaker 11:  Oh
Speaker 5:  My God. And not only that, that was the high point of Dish Network.
Speaker 5:  So, okay, what happened this week is that they no longer
Speaker 5:  have a network. They just sold it. So here is
Speaker 5:  what happened in April,
Speaker 5:  SpaceX, Elon Musk guns complains to the
Speaker 5:  FCC. That dish isn't making use of some of their spectrum.
Speaker 5:  Now, in fairness to SpaceX, they're
Speaker 5:  right. Dish isn't doing anything. They should have, they should
Speaker 5:  be doing something. They're on the hook to launch a
Speaker 5:  nationwide wireless carrier. They didn't do it. So a few
Speaker 5:  weeks After that, FC chairman Brendan Carr opened the investigation
Speaker 5:  into Dish's 5G Network.
Speaker 5:  This causes huge problems for Dish because Dish is a disaster dish,
Speaker 5:  by the way, I don't even know how to get into this dish. Sold
Speaker 5:  itself back to EchoStar, which was originally what Dish was called and then
Speaker 5:  spun out Dish. It, it doesn't matter. The point is they have,
Speaker 5:  they're not in a great financial place. So the Wall Street Journal reports
Speaker 5:  in June that EchoStar considering filing for
Speaker 5:  bankruptcy because Brendan Carr's crusade
Speaker 5:  against them is making it impossible for them to do anything. They
Speaker 5:  said that they, that Carr's threats have quote, effectively frozen our
Speaker 5:  ability to make decisions, which in fairness, it was frozen
Speaker 5:  anyway. They weren't doing anything, but it would've been nice if they had
Speaker 5:  done it. Let's go back to 2019. Donald Trump was president.
Speaker 5:  This is important because Donald Trump was president again and in
Speaker 5:  2019, T-Mobile wanted to buy Sprint.
Speaker 5:  And at the time the Department of Justice, again, under Trump,
Speaker 5:  Trump was like, Hey, it's a bad idea
Speaker 5:  to reduce the number of major wireless carriers in this country.
Speaker 5:  We had four that would make three. And so they cut this deal, they
Speaker 5:  cut a deal where T-Mobile says, fine,
Speaker 5:  we will sell off Boost Mobile, Virgin
Speaker 5:  Mobile, sprint Prepaid and some spectrum
Speaker 5:  to Dish in order to buy Sprint
Speaker 5:  and Dish will agree to actually launch a
Speaker 5:  mobile network. They'll agree to become a 5G carrier. And Dish
Speaker 5:  even agrees to a timeline. They work with the FCC. And
Speaker 5:  by June, 2022, they had to cover 20% of the US population with this 5G network.
Speaker 5:  By June, 2023, they had to cover 70% of the population. They do it,
Speaker 5:  they meet these, these requirements in some,
Speaker 5:  you know, alleged capacity and then they never
Speaker 5:  actually launch a service. This is Neli has been on about project Gen five
Speaker 5:  sis, AKA project, Genesis. I don't know what this thing is.
Speaker 5:  This website hasn't been touched in years. They haven't made a social media
Speaker 5:  post since 2022.
Speaker 5:  It's now the second Trump term. Okay?
Speaker 5:  The first Trump term. They were like, dish, you have to be a wireless carrier.
Speaker 5:  It's important that there are four wireless carriers. Okay, that's a big
Speaker 5:  gamble because who's gonna trust Dish to do this?
Speaker 5:  But, but they have a point. That would be good. It would be good if Dish
Speaker 5:  launched a wireless network. Now it is 2025
Speaker 5:  Trump is president again. I know I keep reiterating that, but it's important
Speaker 5:  because this is the same administration. And
Speaker 5:  now Brendan Carr, the FCC chairman is
Speaker 5:  out here saying stuff like, there isn't a quote magic number
Speaker 5:  of carriers that the US needs. He doesn't care. He's like four carriers,
Speaker 5:  whatever. This all leads to this week. When Dish just comes out and
Speaker 5:  they're like, okay, okay, we just sold all our spectrum to at t
Speaker 5:  like basically all of it. They, they sold all the good 5G Spectrum to at
Speaker 5:  t and Dish is like, yeah, we're, we're like kind of a carrier, but not really.
Speaker 5:  It's three carriers. Again, we're just back to three carriers. Not only are
Speaker 5:  we back to three carriers, but at t got this huge chunk of really good spectrum
Speaker 5:  that's gonna make them an even better carrier. We're just gonna make it even
Speaker 5:  harder for other people to compete with them. Dish, everybody,
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr, everyone the Trump administer This is, this is how that has
Speaker 5:  gone. Did did I miss anything?
Speaker 7:  My brain hurts.
Speaker 11:  I I think you covered everything in, in the middle of that, I went back
Speaker 11:  and pulled up our visual history of the whole timeline from that
Speaker 11:  got to DirecTV and Dish coming together
Speaker 11:  there there's even more mess when you consider the media side
Speaker 11:  another neli favorite. But yeah, that, that, that is about
Speaker 11:  it. I think.
Speaker 5:  Has Dish done literally anything other than like
Speaker 5:  split apart and reassemble its assets over and over again
Speaker 5:  for like 20 years?
Speaker 11:  No, that's
Speaker 5:  What that timeline shows, right? Like that's what it is. I don't, I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't understand what Dish is now. I don't know, understand what it ever
Speaker 5:  was.
Speaker 11:  They did some innovative DVR stuff for a while there in
Speaker 5:  The middle. Yeah, honestly, I,
Speaker 7:  You know, I, I'm realizing that I've heard of Dish, but I don't think
Speaker 7:  I've ever known truly what Dish is
Speaker 5:  One. If you're still rocking a dish, DVR Vergecast to The Verge dot com,
Speaker 5:  we wanna hear from you. How's that going for you? If you ever use
Speaker 5:  Pro Gen five sis please it. I
Speaker 5:  don't, I do not know what's happening. Brendan Carr's argument
Speaker 5:  here is he's like, oh, the MVNOs are really big
Speaker 5:  now. And so we don't need more major carriers that have their own
Speaker 5:  networks because there's competition. This does not seem like a
Speaker 5:  good argument to me, right? The MVNOs, they
Speaker 5:  operate on the carriers. The carriers can do whatever they want with them.
Speaker 11:  Competition that is the same, that is someone in, in the
Speaker 11:  same outfit wearing a different shirt is not really competition.
Speaker 5:  That is like precisely it. This is such a disaster and
Speaker 5:  no one cares. And I think for the FCC
Speaker 5:  in particular, it's just a complete abdication of their
Speaker 5:  role. And I, I think particularly like this is
Speaker 5:  cars doing. He was just like, Hey, we gave him
Speaker 5:  a deadline. They didn't really exactly
Speaker 5:  follow through on it, so just, just quit, right? Instead of
Speaker 5:  being like, Hey, you're on the hook for being a major wireless carrier, a
Speaker 5:  thing that we regulate. Why don't you go do that? He was like, Hey, get outta
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 7:  He just wanted to wash himself of the dishes, wash
Speaker 7:  the dishes. Listen, I've been, I've been, I've been trying to think of that
Speaker 7:  one for a solid two minutes.
Speaker 5:  We listen, nobody wants to spend time with Dish. That's,
Speaker 5:  that's the lesson we've all learned.
Speaker 7:  There are EchoStar now
Speaker 5:  There they are Echo star. Now
Speaker 5:  a fact that confuses me every time I see it.
Speaker 5:  And you know what a fact, that won't matter 'cause it will never show up
Speaker 5:  on our cell phones.
Speaker 11:  But I mean, as as you mentioned, that really is the problem. Because if,
Speaker 11:  if, if you live in an area that isn't well covered by the cell towers, if
Speaker 11:  the prices are too high for the kind of service that you want, if you have
Speaker 11:  fewer real options, there's no one who has a reason to try and get your
Speaker 11:  business. And oh, and, and NVO we've seen the NV Os, we, we have
Speaker 11:  any number of them. Maybe some of you have signed up for Trump Mobile or
Speaker 11:  tried to let us know if you get those phones. But I
Speaker 11:  don't look at any of those. I I've tried some of them. I don't look at any
Speaker 11:  of them as competitors for the major carriers. They just aren't. They aren't
Speaker 11:  on the same level.
Speaker 5:  The thing that gets me is like what say one of them became like
Speaker 5:  a, you know, a, a major player. What leverage do they have? Right?
Speaker 5:  Like what's going to stop the major carriers from being like, Hey, pay
Speaker 5:  us more money. Okay, now they have to raise their prices. Like now this all
Speaker 5:  goes away. They're only working because it wasn't necessarily
Speaker 5:  a huge thing. The carriers are giving them discounts. The carriers can make
Speaker 5:  their service worse anytime they want. The carriers can charge them more
Speaker 5:  anytime they want. And
Speaker 11:  When you're on one of these more budget services, oftentimes you're dealing
Speaker 11:  with things like the kind of prioritization or these caps or
Speaker 11:  you know, kind of fine details. And I think there should be more options
Speaker 11:  and plans, but there needs to be more competition and you just don't have
Speaker 11:  that if you don't have carriers with their own towers.
Speaker 5:  I think you can look back like the decade leading up to T-Mobile buying
Speaker 5:  Sprint. I think because of T-Mobile in particular, there was actually
Speaker 5:  a lot of competition in the mobile carrier space. They
Speaker 5:  were, they were making noise. They, they had to get scrappy, they had to
Speaker 5:  fight pretty hard to be on par with at and t and
Speaker 5:  Verizon. I mean
Speaker 7:  That's why I got on T-Mobile because you know, like they had that guy, I
Speaker 7:  forget his name, but John
Speaker 5:  Ledger J Yes.
Speaker 7:  Him. Yeah, yeah. He was in the pitch CEO and he was like acting
Speaker 7:  up, but at the same time he was acting up all the time. But at the same
Speaker 7:  time I was like, oh, you know, that's more affordable. I'm poor. I can do
Speaker 7:  t T-Mobile and the service is actually pretty good. But I went
Speaker 7:  down to my spouse's ancestral Homeland of T and
Speaker 7:  Maryland recently,
Speaker 7:  you know, and everyone there has Verizon 'cause it's the only network
Speaker 7:  that works. And we're gonna put works in Square Co in
Speaker 7:  scare coat quotes because on his pop hop's farm,
Speaker 7:  there's only one tree where you can get one bar of service. Oh gosh. So to
Speaker 7:  make a phone call before wifi, you always
Speaker 7:  had to go to the one tree on the nut farm to, to make a phone call.
Speaker 7:  So to your point, maybe Dish could have helped him out there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. If he had lived up to the promises. 'cause that tree
Speaker 7:  is not close to the farmhouse. It's quite far to have to get the one bar
Speaker 7:  of Verizon. But
Speaker 11:  Maybe now the government has more reason to give SpaceX a lot of money for
Speaker 11:  starlink. This
Speaker 5:  Is the weirdest part. They didn't, the, the thing that instigated all
Speaker 5:  of this SpaceX complaining Echo Star slash
Speaker 5:  Dish slash whatever it's called now, still owns the spectrum that
Speaker 5:  SpaceX wants. They're not, they're not using it, they're not doing anything
Speaker 5:  with it as far as I know or as far as Face X claims.
Speaker 5:  So in the end everybody loses,
Speaker 7:  Yay. That's just the story of America in
Speaker 7:  2025.
Speaker 5:  Okay, it's now time to talk about a slightly more successful
Speaker 5:  company at times. And that is Intel,
Speaker 5:  which
Speaker 11:  May, if you average it out over the years,
Speaker 7:  If you, you know, it think slightly is a little harsh. You know, people know
Speaker 7:  what Intel is and what Intel does.
Speaker 5:  Those stickers went a really long way. They
Speaker 7:  Really d you know, bu bubu bu like I
Speaker 5:  That's true. What is
Speaker 11:  The current name of Intel's processor series Core what?
Speaker 5:  Pente
Speaker 7:  10, lake Moon something.
Speaker 7:  I don't do laptops no more.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. No. If you average it out is right. Intel hu has been a
Speaker 5:  bit of a rough streak, which has led up to,
Speaker 5:  this happened on last Friday, so it was after we recorded the last
Speaker 5:  vergecast,
Speaker 5:  Intel gave a 10% stake of the company to the
Speaker 5:  US government in exchange for
Speaker 5:  $8.9 billion. This is weird for a lot of reasons,
Speaker 5:  including that the US government does not typically take ownership stakes
Speaker 5:  in private companies.
Speaker 5:  But I, I wanna talk about why this is a just bizarre and question we'll deal
Speaker 5:  for Intel for a minute. The first being that
Speaker 5:  they were already getting this money. This, this money was
Speaker 5:  already awarded to them, primarily from the CHIPS Act.
Speaker 5:  What happened is that Trump was like, eh, what if we just don't give it to
Speaker 5:  them? Now, I don't know if that's legal, might not be
Speaker 5:  the CHIPS act. I will, you know, remind everyone passed the
Speaker 5:  Senate and the House on a bipartisan basis. Everybody was like, Hey, it would
Speaker 5:  be a good idea to prop up the US semiconductor industry.
Speaker 5:  That's an important industry. We realized that during COVID, it has a lot
Speaker 5:  of national security implications. Let's make sure that's doing well. Intel,
Speaker 5:  they're not doing great. Let's give them some cash.
Speaker 5:  Trump didn't like it because it was associated with Biden. And so he is like,
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna, I'm not gonna give him the cash. And so he, so thi
Speaker 5:  this is the timeline of what happens early August. Trump
Speaker 5:  demands that Intel's new CEO the Bhutan resign. He's just
Speaker 5:  like, I don't like this guy. He has, he has some ties to China, get him outta
Speaker 5:  here. Tan goes and visits the White House
Speaker 5:  as CEOs do these days and suddenly they're good
Speaker 5:  pals. And I assume that has to do something with
Speaker 5:  the fact that,
Speaker 5:  you know, a week or so later, he gives 10% of the company to the
Speaker 5:  United States in exchange for this money that the United States was already
Speaker 5:  paying them.
Speaker 5:  This is what a deal. It
Speaker 7:  What a deal. Art of the deal.
Speaker 5:  This is, I mean I I this is very, this is bizarre on,
Speaker 5:  on all counts. Number one, tan is in some ways
Speaker 5:  gave away 10% of Intel to protect his job, which I think is
Speaker 5:  questionable precision.
Speaker 5:  Number two, the what is really happening here
Speaker 5:  is that Intel is his foundry business. Foundry business is not doing great,
Speaker 5:  right? Is not making the best ships.
Speaker 5:  Companies don't wanna make a deal with Intel's foundry business 'cause they
Speaker 5:  don't even know if the Intel's Foundry foundry business is gonna be there
Speaker 5:  long enough to keep making the chips. And so the US
Speaker 5:  government is now getting involved And I think the reason that Intel wants
Speaker 5:  to do this is that they're like, Hey Trump,
Speaker 5:  maybe he will just pressure Apple to make some chips with us. Everyone's
Speaker 5:  leaving Intel and, and they're, they're, they're looking to Trump
Speaker 5:  to put some pressure on them to get
Speaker 5:  customers for Intel.
Speaker 7:  There's some real galaxy brain math happening here. Like I feel like my
Speaker 7:  brain is leaving my skull ying itself to Jupiter and
Speaker 7:  doing some mental gymnastics to try and see the logic behind this. And I,
Speaker 7:  it's finding none. It's finding none.
Speaker 5:  The, the, the logic as far as I can tell is, is
Speaker 5:  like crony capitalism, right? It is. The logic here is
Speaker 5:  the US government will get involved on
Speaker 5:  Intel's behalf and Trump is gonna put
Speaker 5:  pressure on people and
Speaker 5:  the folks he likes are gonna win. The folks he doesn't like are gonna lose.
Speaker 5:  And right now, at this moment, he likes Intel and he's gonna
Speaker 5:  try to get some people to be Intel's customers and hopefully
Speaker 5:  Intel can make some good chips for them. But we don't know if they can, which
Speaker 11:  Has been basically Intel's whole problem for years now that they've been
Speaker 11:  supposed to be making better chips and sort of haven't. And I,
Speaker 11:  I guess we'll see what happens with these next generation of chips that
Speaker 11:  they're building. But they've missed out on really the AI boom. They
Speaker 11:  had.
Speaker 11:  TSMC has become massive on, on their watch. They've missed out on this
Speaker 11:  technology that they developed. Is that just
Speaker 11:  Pure, from a tech perspective? I don't see how this solves the problem of
Speaker 11:  Intel messing up, which has been the story of their last decade or so
Speaker 11:  from a business perspective, I don't know what's going on. And from a political
Speaker 11:  perspective, it's scary.
Speaker 11:  Is there, is there another part that I forgot?
Speaker 7:  They also missed out on the mobile boom, which is like, if you talk to
Speaker 7:  Qualcomm for any like second 'cause Qualcomm has always had a
Speaker 7:  chip on their shoulder about how everyone knows about Intel
Speaker 7:  and not them. Even though they're in every like Android phone and they're
Speaker 7:  all over the place. 'cause you know, you literally talk to Qualcomm for five
Speaker 7:  seconds and they're like, where we're in mobile, we're in everything where
Speaker 7:  Qualcomm Snapdragon, yay. And nobody knows,
Speaker 7:  like outside of tech nerd Damm, no one knows what Qualcomm is, but everyone
Speaker 7:  knows Intel and, but yeah, they miss the
Speaker 7:  mobile train, they miss the AI boom and now they're like
Speaker 7:  the, I don't know, Intel's just sad, man.
Speaker 5:  Well, and and to Richard's point, like this doesn't solve Intel's
Speaker 5:  the, you know, recent inability to make the correct business
Speaker 5:  decisions. Yeah. Like the tech isn't there. The business digits have been
Speaker 5:  off,
Speaker 5:  right? Like forcing people to be Intel's customers, it keeps them
Speaker 5:  afloat, which, you know, I, I would like Intel to survive.
Speaker 5:  I would like its Foundry business to succeed. I think that that is a, a good
Speaker 5:  thing for the industry, but they need to make good products,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 7:  Fundamental rule of business is make a good product. So
Speaker 7:  yeah, they, they kind of need to do that. But
Speaker 7:  I don't know, man, their marketing team is still great, But that might be
Speaker 7:  the only team at Intel that's still good. I
Speaker 11:  Dunno. But they've been losing ground to A and B and now Windows on Arm
Speaker 11:  is really good. Suddenly, apparently Qualcomm and ev, everyone is coming
Speaker 11:  for them. Their Nvidia is reportedly making a chip. There's
Speaker 11:  a lot of crossover and a lot of,
Speaker 11:  a lot of overlap, I think in, in these companies and what they're doing.
Speaker 11:  And I just, I still don't see the, the position for Intel to get themselves
Speaker 11:  into, to make things better.
Speaker 5:  There's also a bizarre national security component to this. Part of this
Speaker 5:  is great. We wanna make sure, you know, the United States wants to make sure
Speaker 5:  that there are foundries in the US that can make good chips
Speaker 5:  that the supply chain is here. This makes sense. On the other hand,
Speaker 5:  TSMC was a really valuable national, national security
Speaker 5:  contribution to Taiwan, right? And if
Speaker 5:  the US is removing, trying to remove reliance on
Speaker 5:  TSMC, then that's bad news for tsmc. It's bad news for Taiwan,
Speaker 5:  which is bad news for the tech industry in general because
Speaker 5:  most of the chips are coming from TSMC, tt, SMC has
Speaker 5:  the best stuff. And so this just
Speaker 5:  gets messy on basically every level.
Speaker 5:  I, I Trump sees what he's doing as just getting
Speaker 5:  10% of this company. But if you continue to follow out the
Speaker 5:  next steps of this, what has to happen in order for this to make any
Speaker 5:  sense? It it does, it is not good for anybody in the
Speaker 5:  industry except perhaps Intel
Speaker 11:  And maybe not even Intel. I, I guess right,
Speaker 11:  the, I don't specifically know what the counterargument is, but I guess
Speaker 11:  if you, if you take a look, how different is this from something like the
Speaker 11:  auto bailout, like in the treasury, like
Speaker 11:  kind of taking over GM in these bankruptcies? I feel like that was an
Speaker 11:  emergency from outside. This is an emergency that Trump created and so it's
Speaker 11:  not the same.
Speaker 5:  No, I think that makes sense. And then I, correct me if I'm wrong, I don't,
Speaker 5:  the, the US didn't take a stake in those companies, right? Like that that
Speaker 5:  was it. It they were giving them money, right.
Speaker 11:  For a time, I believe the treasury owned gm.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting. Okay. Yeah. But
Speaker 7:  Like, part of that was just that, you know, the, the US bailed out the auto
Speaker 7:  industry just because of, you know, the, the jobs and like the, the
Speaker 7:  industry, the local, how much it would devastate the local economy that this
Speaker 7:  kind of just devastates Intel. And yes, there are like jobs that are
Speaker 7:  associated with Intel and whatnot. It's just, I
Speaker 7:  feel like there were bigger implications with, I don't know, the entire US
Speaker 7:  auto industry going versus one
Speaker 7:  semiconductor company that happens to be American.
Speaker 11:  If their problem had started with the president of the United States claiming
Speaker 11:  that their CEO might be an agent for a foreign government, we would be
Speaker 11:  discussing it very differently.
Speaker 7:  That too.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, And I think the, the auto bailout also goes to show the, the government
Speaker 5:  has a lot of levers it can pull from the outside
Speaker 5:  without going so far as taking an ownership stake in a company
Speaker 5:  indefinitely. And I think that is where it gets concerning,
Speaker 5:  right? Intel has the backing of the US government that just
Speaker 5:  necessarily gives Intel a very fascinating position
Speaker 5:  and advantage over everyone else in the industry. And
Speaker 5:  it puts pressures on everybody else in the industry, whether they like it
Speaker 5:  or not. Okay. One more thing we have to talk about today. A few weeks ago
Speaker 5:  we maybe may made fun of Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  a little bit. Did, did
Speaker 7:  We call it a she again?
Speaker 5:  I we did, I think we, we said, is this was a Elon threatened
Speaker 5:  to sue Apple over not featuring Grok in the
Speaker 5:  app store. And I, I think we all thought it was a joke, right? Because
Speaker 5:  Elon, Elon threatens the lawsuits a lot, does not always file them. He did
Speaker 5:  In fact file a lawsuit. He,
Speaker 7:  I don't know whether to say yay, you know, like, oh, you, you finally
Speaker 7:  followed through on a, on a thing, yay for you. Or to be like, oh my
Speaker 7:  God, you followed through on this thing. Not yay for me.
Speaker 5:  It's not a great lawsuit, but he did do it. So
Speaker 5:  XAI suing OpenAI and Apple and they're
Speaker 5:  alleging anti-competitive conduct over a bunch of different issues. They,
Speaker 5:  they have, they, they have beef with OpenAI getting
Speaker 5:  an exclusive deal to put Jet g BT into Siri.
Speaker 5:  They claim that Apple is quote manipulating app store rankings.
Speaker 5:  And they say that Apple is delaying app store reviews for
Speaker 5:  Grok. Now, I think we can just say off the bat,
Speaker 5:  famously all the apps store reviews take forever. So that's, that's
Speaker 5:  not unique. But the, the premise here is basically
Speaker 5:  this deal is unfair because it's not open to everybody and we're getting
Speaker 5:  screwed in the app store. And I, they, they
Speaker 5:  undercut that argument right away because in this
Speaker 5:  lawsuit, they highlight the fact that X
Speaker 5:  is ranked number one as the free app for news. And
Speaker 5:  GR has ranked number two on the, as the free apps for productivity.
Speaker 5:  So they're in this lawsuit, they're like, Hey, we have these great apps.
Speaker 5:  They're at the top of the app store, but they're also getting screwed by
Speaker 5:  the app store algorithm. And it's like, what is this case?
Speaker 5:  What case are you making here? They're just mad that it's not in the
Speaker 5:  must have apps section. Don't, don't
Speaker 5:  argue against yourself. You're doing great. You just said you're doing great.
Speaker 5:  Your argument is we're doing great. And so we should also get featured in
Speaker 5:  this other area.
Speaker 7:  Having tested Annie Gru's not a must
Speaker 7:  have app, I must say.
Speaker 11:  And Elon has been obsessed with app store rankings as someone who has
Speaker 11:  notifications on for his tweets. He was always tweeting about
Speaker 11:  X or X AI or grok or whatever, being number one in the app store in
Speaker 11:  some country that you forgot existed.
Speaker 11:  He gets his feet of data and must share the news with everyone all the time.
Speaker 5:  Richard, that is extremely unhealthy. I have to tell you,
Speaker 11:  It's the healthiest.
Speaker 11:  I, I know that I have not gone into active psychosis because I still can't
Speaker 11:  understand what Elon is saying and, And I get a, And I get a reminder of
Speaker 11:  this every 10 minutes or so. It's great. That's,
Speaker 5:  It really is. It is really that often it's horrible. You are right though.
Speaker 5:  Like just the other day he like retweeted somebody who's like, which again
Speaker 5:  cuts against their argument. He's like, we're featured in the must-haves
Speaker 5:  with one of those editorial sections. They said they were featured in the
Speaker 5:  United Arab Emirates in one of those editorial sections. And it's like, okay,
Speaker 5:  so they are getting featured.
Speaker 5:  I I do not know that they have much of a case here. This is
Speaker 5:  just like not a good thing to argue when at the same time
Speaker 5:  you're saying that actually we're doing quite well. The, the other part of
Speaker 5:  this case I think is actually very interesting. And
Speaker 5:  I, they're saying, Hey, we, we actually can't
Speaker 5:  compete with chat GBT because they're getting so much
Speaker 5:  data and so many queries via Siri, which
Speaker 5:  is this really interesting thing where they're kind of acknowledging, oh,
Speaker 5:  we have to farm how everyone uses this thing or
Speaker 5:  we can't improve it. Which is one of those things I think we all know, but
Speaker 5:  it's like another thing to see it written down.
Speaker 7:  I mean, if you want grok baked into Siri, maybe
Speaker 7:  don't make sex bots. Like, I, I don't, I don't know how
Speaker 7:  else to say that part, but yeah, I don't want to talk
Speaker 7:  to Siri and have bad Rudy, the little angry panda
Speaker 7:  say that I'm lame because he's, if you insult
Speaker 7:  that panda, all he says is like, I'm not lame. You are lame.
Speaker 7:  And that's just, I, I don't know what he expects
Speaker 7:  when he acts out the way that he does. And Apple,
Speaker 7:  apple has not been like hiding how they are this entire
Speaker 7:  time and what they want out of the apps in their app store.
Speaker 7:  They, they haven't hidden that
Speaker 5:  Well. And, and it's like, right, you have the chat bot that number one
Speaker 5:  recently went on a tear and called itself Mega Hitler
Speaker 5:  for, for no clear reason that you have now baked several,
Speaker 5:  like pre-made boss into it. They've updated Annie, the, the,
Speaker 5:  you know, physical digital person
Speaker 5:  incarnation of grok with some new outfits
Speaker 5:  so she can so much like strip down into like a bathing suit or something
Speaker 5:  now, which is just very embarrassing. But again, it, it's like
Speaker 5:  Apple is like pretty, you know, for better or worse, they're fairly like
Speaker 5:  prudish with the app store, right? They could do that thing. They're,
Speaker 7:  They always say that they're family friendly that Yeah, Annie is not family
Speaker 7:  friendly. Like, sh it's just not
Speaker 5:  Right. It, it's, I think there's, like, again, this is another world where
Speaker 5:  I, I think if this was a random small company, like they're,
Speaker 5:  they're getting kicked outta the app store. Like I, I think Apple
Speaker 5:  has plenty of reasons to not feature this app
Speaker 5:  and Elon is still asking for more And I, I get it. Like, I understand
Speaker 5:  why you would be pissed about not getting a, a special deal. But actually
Speaker 5:  one thing that's really interesting, Tom Warren on our team, he writes
Speaker 5:  the Notepad newsletter reports on Microsoft. He reported, I I think it was
Speaker 5:  this month that Microsoft has been testing,
Speaker 5:  you know, the latest version of Grok and they don't wanna deploy it
Speaker 5:  to, to Azure because they're worried about the safety of it,
Speaker 5:  right? Like this is not just an Apple thing. Like
Speaker 5:  this is, this is Elon's product. It is not ready for this,
Speaker 5:  it is not a thing other companies want to be associated with.
Speaker 7:  And you know, I don't think any of us are surprised when Elon has a tantrum,
Speaker 7:  but this is the equivalent of him having a tantrum orally. Like, I'm not
Speaker 7:  the best in every single thing, so I'm gonna sue you for not
Speaker 7:  letting me be the best in every single thing. And it's not my fault. I
Speaker 7:  have not done anything in this product that makes it not the best.
Speaker 7:  You clearly, you know, it's just like very juvenile behavior
Speaker 7:  and external blaming of, of, I
Speaker 7:  think if he were to listen, he would hear some very fair feedback and
Speaker 7:  criticism for all of his products. And despite that, it's still,
Speaker 7:  like you said, it's still ranked very highly in various sections, just not
Speaker 7:  the section he wants to be the highest in. And that's just
Speaker 5:  Richard, have you spent any quality time with chatting with Grock?
Speaker 11:  I have not.
Speaker 5:  This, that's where you draw the line. You'll get a constant feed of
Speaker 5:  Elon. Yeah, but you won't talk.
Speaker 11:  We've got rock at home. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 7:  He's already getting the Elon feed, you know, he don't need the rock feed
Speaker 7:  on top of that.
Speaker 5:  That's real.
Speaker 11:  But I, I think the thing about this lawsuit that destructs me is that
Speaker 11:  we're about as receptive as of an audience as there is, I think to criticisms
Speaker 11:  of the App store and the way Apple maintains it. We've been talking about
Speaker 11:  this for years, anti-competitive monopolistic practices,
Speaker 11:  the decisions that they make, the way that they do that. Other companies
Speaker 11:  have made these arguments before,
Speaker 11:  but as, as v put it, there are reasons why gr might
Speaker 11:  not be.
Speaker 11:  They're, they're really good reasons and, And I think that they can make
Speaker 11:  those arguments, but it's pretty consistent with Elon's overall
Speaker 11:  approach. That if he's not, if he's not very visibly winning and
Speaker 11:  celebrated for winning, then it's someone else's fault that he's
Speaker 11:  losing and he's going to make it everyone's problem.
Speaker 5:  That's really true. And I do, I do think there is some degree to which like,
Speaker 5:  okay, apple didn't pander to him and so,
Speaker 5:  okay, he's just gonna try to fight them a little bit. I naturally, the lawsuit
Speaker 5:  is filed in Texas where he can potentially find a friendlier
Speaker 5:  judge. So we'll see what happens. Maybe he can, you know,
Speaker 5:  cause some problems for a little bit. I'm
Speaker 5:  not convinced this is a good case. Oh, one one last very quick
Speaker 5:  thing. You, Elon is also suing
Speaker 5:  open AI over the fact that they're, you know, trying to become a public company
Speaker 5:  where they say, were in the meantime, X AI
Speaker 5:  drops its status as a public benefit corporation. Thi
Speaker 5:  this is, I don't know, I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't know what's happening over there. Other than that Elon is
Speaker 5:  obviously
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back time for the Thunder on Richard. I, you don't know
Speaker 5:  this yet. Neli obviously is not around and so I
Speaker 5:  have gone on a power trip. He's, you know how Neli feels with the
Speaker 5:  lightning round. So he, he thinks this is a, a fantastic part of the show.
Speaker 5:  I have beef with it because there's a bunch of stories we wanna get to and
Speaker 5:  we never get to all the stories. And so I have destroyed the lightning round.
Speaker 5:  It's gone. It's done. It's never coming back until maybe Neela gets
Speaker 5:  back. We'll find out in place. We have declared
Speaker 5:  this the thunder round. This is the thunder round
Speaker 5:  instead of the lightning round, we're gonna do five stories, five minutes
Speaker 5:  each. I've given Eric Gomez our producer, the Power of Thunder. If we
Speaker 5:  go too long, we're gonna hear a little rolling thunder playing us off. And
Speaker 5:  if we need to move on, thunder will crash. Strike
Speaker 5:  smack will, there will be thunder, there will be a loud noise
Speaker 5:  telling us it is time to move on. Alright, let's get into it.
Speaker 5:  V what have you got for us?
Speaker 7:  So my new title at The Verge dot com is Senior
Speaker 7:  K-Pop Demon Hunters Reporter.
Speaker 5:  Congratulations in
Speaker 7:  The promotion. You, this is, this is, you know
Speaker 5:  This a long time coming. I
Speaker 7:  Was a senior reviewer then I was a senior curse tech reviewer, and now I
Speaker 7:  am senior K-Pop Demon Hunters reporter. And that's because
Speaker 7:  K-Pop Demon Hunters is officially the most ever
Speaker 7:  watched movie on Netflix most popular movie
Speaker 7:  of all time.
Speaker 5:  And people actually like it. It's a
Speaker 7:  Great movie. This is, this
Speaker 5:  Is the crazy, I cannot think of that for it Sold out real theaters.
Speaker 7:  Real theaters.
Speaker 5:  This is,
Speaker 7:  This is going, this is going to the Oscars. Like mark my words.
Speaker 7:  I think I I read that they are actually going to be nominating
Speaker 7:  the soundtrack for the Oscars. And
Speaker 7:  as they should, it is a banger of a soundtrack. And I'm not
Speaker 7:  at all biased as a K-pop stand, but it is a banger of a
Speaker 7:  soundtrack. And like the movie is actually, it's a reezy
Speaker 7:  90 minutes. It's, it's very good.
Speaker 5:  This is legitimately the first Netflix movie
Speaker 5:  that I've heard people talk about after the movie came out
Speaker 7:  And continue to talk about it. Yes,
Speaker 5:  It's always right, the they'll create buzz in the lead up to a movie. The
Speaker 5:  movie comes out, you don't hear a thing, you don't hear a, this is the only
Speaker 5:  one that, I didn't hear anything about this before it came out and
Speaker 5:  nonstop for the past like two months,
Speaker 7:  There was like almost no promotion there. I think there was one trailer
Speaker 7:  for it. They did not promote it at all. It came out all of a
Speaker 7:  sudden all my TikTok things were, And I actually didn't wanna watch it at
Speaker 7:  first because I like K-pop and because I'm Korean, I was like, oh, K-pop
Speaker 7:  demon hunters. Are you kidding?
Speaker 5:  Pandering. Kidding me.
Speaker 7:  Pandering. Yeah. And then just the, the, the feed was way too
Speaker 7:  much. And then all of the people were like, oh my God, it's based on this
Speaker 7:  panel. And I was like, all right, all right, let me go watch this movie.
Speaker 7:  And then I watched it three times.
Speaker 11:  That's one of my least favorite things when everybody's right. Like
Speaker 7:  It's just, it's just a good time.
Speaker 5:  The the singers in the who voice the, the characters,
Speaker 5:  they're actual K-pop
Speaker 7:  Performers. So ej, they're, they're not one of 'em.
Speaker 7:  One of them is Audrey Nuna and she's kind of a, a rapper. And
Speaker 7:  then the other one is Ray Ami, but the main one, ej,
Speaker 7:  she is a bonafide, she's what
Speaker 7:  you could call her the Benny Blanco of Korea because you know Benny
Speaker 7:  Blanco has written all
Speaker 5:  Of these. How is she on a podcast?
Speaker 7:  She speaks English, so she's probably very good. That's okay. But
Speaker 7:  basically she's written all of these major bangers
Speaker 7:  for these
Speaker 5:  These Oh, wild, okay. Huge bang. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. These huge, that's hence the Benny Blanco thing. Like I found out that
Speaker 7:  she wrote this song Psycho by Red Velvet And I went, what? That's on all
Speaker 7:  my playlists. Holy crap girl. And she was a trainee
Speaker 7:  at one of the major K-pop studios. Sm
Speaker 7:  known for putting out a lot of
Speaker 7:  insanely talented vocalists, which she obviously is, but she
Speaker 7:  wrote all of the songs for the movie and performed in them. And so it
Speaker 7:  has that very authentic, genuine thing. But one of the most
Speaker 7:  insane parts of k-pop demon hunter's insane success to me
Speaker 7:  is that Sony, which made the, the, the, the thing, they basically
Speaker 7:  gave it to Netflix. 'cause they didn't think it was gonna do
Speaker 5:  Numbers. That's, they just had no idea what they had on their hands. They
Speaker 5:  had
Speaker 7:  No, this movie took nine years to make is the other thing. Oh my, it's like
Speaker 7:  a passion
Speaker 5:  Project. Gosh.
Speaker 7:  They put their whole heart and soul into like, representing Korea,
Speaker 7:  representing like this whole culture. Which is why I think it's
Speaker 7:  resonated a lot with K-Pop fans because there's just so much love put
Speaker 7:  into every single part of it and it's authentic and, but
Speaker 7:  it's still just like a good story. And like the visuals are
Speaker 7:  very like unique and fun and kind of not,
Speaker 7:  it's not Pixar, right? It, it kind of has the same vibe as the
Speaker 7:  Spider-Man animated movies. So there's
Speaker 5:  The animation looks beautiful, it's
Speaker 7:  Really fun and it's like got a di di distinctive style. And
Speaker 7:  one of the things I see people saying online that I agree with is that for
Speaker 7:  once it's original, yes. It's like an original story. It's
Speaker 7:  original characters. It's not a remake of a remake of a remake, it's just
Speaker 7:  something new that's out there and it's gonna be done to death in the same
Speaker 7:  view as squid games. But yeah, just the
Speaker 7:  fact that Sony needs a hit and they're like, I don't know what to do with
Speaker 7:  this here. Netflix, you take it and then Netflix is like,
Speaker 5:  This explains a lot. I wanna ask something really quick of both of you.
Speaker 5:  Can you both try to name one other movie in Netflix's
Speaker 5:  top 10 of their original films? One other movie
Speaker 5:  that Netflix has made that was was Successful
Speaker 7:  Bird Box.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Okay. That's one of them. That's one of them. That's number six. Richard,
Speaker 5:  have you, do you have ever any Netflix original movies?
Speaker 11:  Oh, only because I saw the list. Do I know read notice. The, the movie
Speaker 11:  that made no one admits to of having watched I
Speaker 5:  I've
Speaker 7:  Never heard of it.
Speaker 5:  I constantly am like, I'm like, it's like gray
Speaker 5:  notice 'cause they have, they have Gray Man and red notice And I can't remember.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, that's all I can re remember remember as far as Netflix originals
Speaker 5:  go, but this is it. This is like,
Speaker 5:  nobody talks about 'em. The only thing that matters is K-pop demon
Speaker 5:  unders. But at least they've got a hit. Alright, Richard, what have you got
Speaker 5:  for us?
Speaker 11:  Pretty big controversy going on in the YouTube world. Surprisingly never
Speaker 11:  happens. Several creators are upset because they, they noticed
Speaker 11:  and they've started talking about how some of their YouTube Shorts videos
Speaker 11:  look different. Brett Shaw I think had made a video about this.
Speaker 11:  It was reported on the BBC and, and in other places. And YouTube
Speaker 11:  responded. Basically what what they noticed, particularly comparing
Speaker 11:  the YouTube Shorts version, I think to Instagram reels, is that the
Speaker 11:  versions of their videos that were on YouTube had
Speaker 11:  these extra details and looked really absurdly sharp and
Speaker 11:  they, they felt like, it looked like, it looked like an AI deep fake is,
Speaker 11:  is how they kind of felt like their videos looked. And YouTube's Renee
Speaker 11:  Ritchie, he responded, he said that it was an experiment that YouTube was
Speaker 11:  running as far as I can tell, they hadn't told anyone about this beforehand.
Speaker 11:  And that they are using the kind of machine learning you experience with
Speaker 11:  computational photography on smartphones, not generative ai. This is
Speaker 11:  kind of the push and pull that is going back and forth between people saying
Speaker 11:  it's AI or not ai. So if you've, if you've taken a look at the evidence,
Speaker 11:  what do you guys think? AI or just upscaling?
Speaker 7:  Hmm.
Speaker 5:  It, it looks like nasty upscaling to me. Like
Speaker 5:  this is just a failure on YouTube's part in general. It looks they,
Speaker 5:  you know what they look like. They looked like ripped videos
Speaker 5:  on TikTok that somebody has like put an ad on top of
Speaker 5:  like, I've seen this look. And it is when somebody is boosting your
Speaker 5:  video and trying to hide that they have like downloaded off something else.
Speaker 5:  Know
Speaker 7:  What that's, I had to go onto a Zoom call earlier today on the
Speaker 7:  AI phone And I don't know if it was Zoom or something else, but I
Speaker 7:  looked at what I looked like in the camera. I'm like, oh no,
Speaker 7:  that's too much like me. Like it just, you know, it was
Speaker 7:  just sharpened to the point where I was like, it's uncanny, it doesn't look
Speaker 7:  right. And so I turned my camera off.
Speaker 5:  I Do you think there's this like very funny, weird thing happening where
Speaker 5:  people are like, I don't like it. It must be ai and and
Speaker 5:  the thing is this is actually just bad. It doesn't matter what it is, it
Speaker 5:  is just bad. Like they just shouldn't do this.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It, it didn't look good. They didn't tell people that this was happening
Speaker 11:  to their videos. The select number of videos they use this on.
Speaker 11:  But yeah, I've been sitting in demos at trade shows with
Speaker 11:  companies showing off their HD upscaling that would make your four a DP
Speaker 11:  into 10 80 p for years. And this is what it looks like. Yes. If someone
Speaker 11:  did that and turned the dial up and they all, they all claim every TV claim
Speaker 11:  that it had an AI processor in it for the last 10 years. So is
Speaker 11:  it ai, is it machine learning? What is the difference? I do not know,
Speaker 11:  but it's, it just, it looks way over sharpened. They, they turned it up
Speaker 11:  too much. And I think that the other part is how all of the
Speaker 11:  tests and all of the features that YouTube is adding, we, we saw some backlash.
Speaker 11:  We saw the thing pop up. There's a woman who was kind of upset because she
Speaker 11:  noticed on Instagram reels that her voice translation, it translates
Speaker 11:  it into another language, but also simulates your voice, which I
Speaker 11:  think people were not ready for. So whenever you see
Speaker 11:  something and it's altered, of course for many people, the first question's
Speaker 11:  gonna be, oh, it's ai it's just where we are now.
Speaker 5:  No, that's a good point though. And like that, that did happen and Instagram
Speaker 5:  really was doing that and like, it was kind of impressive.
Speaker 5:  But like you, it was probably good. Good to know that that's gonna happen
Speaker 5:  before you see yourself talking in another language. I was like
Speaker 5:  watching those and like, is it even sinking the lips? Like I Yep.
Speaker 5:  It's trippy. It's really trippy and, and super
Speaker 5:  impressive. I'm sure if you're a creator, like seems good if you want more
Speaker 5:  reach, but like, you wanna know what's happening with your videos.
Speaker 5:  And there's this other element here where like YouTube is
Speaker 5:  acknowledging that it's machine learning and it's like, oh God, where is
Speaker 5:  the difference between machine learning and ai and which is the one that
Speaker 5:  we're mad at and which is the one that we, and like my whole thing is like,
Speaker 5:  what is the outcome here? And the outcome here is they made
Speaker 5:  weird crunchy videos and didn't tell anybody that they were gonna make 'em
Speaker 5:  weird and crunchy and everybody was just mad that they looked ugly.
Speaker 7:  I mean that's the, the real crux of it is just like, if you're gonna do this,
Speaker 7:  don't make me look ugly. Right? That's vain creatures.
Speaker 7:  If I looked better, I'd be like, oh, thank you ai. Right? I look
Speaker 7:  crunchy.
Speaker 11:  You have these creators who worked really hard to make their videos look
Speaker 11:  the way that they look. They, they have expectations. They know how YouTube
Speaker 11:  works, they know how they'll be delivered on different platforms and they've
Speaker 11:  gone to a great degree to get it to look this way. And then suddenly
Speaker 11:  you change it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  At first when I heard they were secretly AIing videos, I'm like, oh my God,
Speaker 5:  did they face tune people? 'cause that's creepy. That's messed up. No,
Speaker 5:  they, they took the clarity slider and dragged it all the way to the top.
Speaker 5:  Don't do that. Okay, next story. Google
Speaker 5:  announced this week that they're gonna start requiring
Speaker 5:  verification for developers who want to publish
Speaker 5:  apps on Android that live outside the play store.
Speaker 5:  This I think doesn't sound monumental, but it
Speaker 5:  kind of is, kind of is, right? This is essentially how Apple
Speaker 5:  operates the Mac, right? Anybody can publish a Mac app,
Speaker 5:  but it's a pretty, it it's secretly a lockdown platform, which is, it makes
Speaker 5:  sense, it's sort, that's how Apple has always kind of kept its
Speaker 5:  gates tight. But if you wanna publish outside of the app store in the
Speaker 5:  Mac, as people traditionally have, you still have to have a Dev Apple developer
Speaker 5:  count. Apple's always require these developer counts. And So
Speaker 5:  if you, you know, go awry and do something
Speaker 5:  illegitimate, they can just shut down your app.
Speaker 5:  This makes a little bit of sense to me on the Mac where Apple has always
Speaker 5:  had this level of control. Android on the other hand, is ostensibly
Speaker 5:  this open platform is ostensibly a platform that is open source
Speaker 5:  that nobody controls. Now Google is saying
Speaker 5:  it is an open source platform, however, we would like every developer to
Speaker 5:  register with us and we will therefore be able to shut off your app if
Speaker 5:  it's a problem. Now, on one hand that, okay, great, that's a good security
Speaker 5:  feature, right? I see the reason for it. I see how
Speaker 5:  that makes sense. But to me, the other thing I see here
Speaker 5:  is Google continuing to tighten its grip on Android and make it feel
Speaker 5:  even more and more like a product that belongs solely to Google.
Speaker 5:  And that's sort of been the entire trajectory of Android. I feel like
Speaker 5:  over the past, you know, decade plus.
Speaker 7:  I think that's only gonna get more true the more that they try and
Speaker 7:  tie Android to Gemini. You know, like I think as that
Speaker 7:  happens, as Gemini becomes another like vector in
Speaker 7:  which Google tries to assert itself into products, I think
Speaker 7:  I think you're gonna see more of this going forward. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  And, And I don't think this is the reason why everyone who uses Android
Speaker 11:  uses Android, but there was in the past a reason to use Android because
Speaker 11:  you could have more control of your device. You could install apps from
Speaker 11:  anywhere you could, you know, do do what you wanted. And that is just,
Speaker 11:  it's a bit, it's becoming a bit less true. And we saw kind of an example
Speaker 11:  of what this could become. Just, I think in the last
Speaker 11:  day Apple pulled a a, a Torrent app for the iPhone that was
Speaker 11:  published in the alt store in Europe. But they can do that
Speaker 5:  And, and it's like, it's not clear why. And you know, like we, we can ask
Speaker 5:  them, but they don't have to answer. They're like, you know, they can still
Speaker 5:  just enforce their arbitrary rules and look like,
Speaker 5:  is that app being used for piracy? A hundred percent. A hundred percent.
Speaker 5:  Should Apple be in charge of deciding whether you can
Speaker 5:  pirate stuff or not? Like I, I don't think that's the right
Speaker 5:  move here. And like, this is sort of the direction this takes where
Speaker 5:  Google now is going to have that authority.
Speaker 7:  And it's also different if you, from the get go, like Apple from the get
Speaker 7:  go is like, no, we, we have the control. But Google has historically
Speaker 7:  been like, we're, we love open source. We like being that
Speaker 7:  kind of more interoperable company. And to
Speaker 7:  Richard's point, like who among us doesn't know the, the Android stand?
Speaker 7:  And I say this lovingly who's just like, oh, I just sideloaded onto this.
Speaker 7:  Like I can just do whatever I want with this versus you
Speaker 7:  iPhone people enjoy your prison in the walled garden or whatnot.
Speaker 7:  And so I think that when you position yourself
Speaker 7:  one way and then you pivot and people
Speaker 7:  start noticing that pivot, that's when people get mad. It's like when
Speaker 7:  you're a free app and then all of a sudden you're like, hey guys,
Speaker 7:  subscription. Even if it's a baby step, even if it's like a small thing
Speaker 7:  in a direction, you just get a lot of outlash be a
Speaker 7:  backlash rather because people are like, that's not what you said you were,
Speaker 7:  that's not what you said. That's not what we signed up for and now you're
Speaker 7:  going the other way. So it's slippery slope. Very
Speaker 5:  Slippery. I I think you're completely right and I've talked about this before,
Speaker 5:  but it's fascinating. If you look at Google's contracts with other,
Speaker 5:  you know, smartphone makers, they do everything to lock down
Speaker 5:  Android to make sure it's a Google product. Even though it's open source.
Speaker 5:  They say, if you want the play store, if you want our best apps, you
Speaker 5:  gotta put them in this folder on this screen in this spot. They're super
Speaker 5:  specific about all of this. And so, you know, I think we don't quite see
Speaker 5:  it all the time, but there are just a lot of different ways that app
Speaker 5:  that Google very clearly keeps its hands around Android
Speaker 5:  to make sure that it is a Google product, even though it remains
Speaker 5:  technically open source. So you'll still be able to side load this is still
Speaker 5:  gonna be an option. I do think like, yes, this is a good security feature,
Speaker 5:  but it it, it has some very, I think, strange
Speaker 5:  implications for the future of Android as an open platform.
Speaker 5:  Alright, the what's next?
Speaker 7:  So I, I really love this one, but Taco Bell, an
Speaker 7:  executive there is just like, hmm. So, you know, our plan to put AI in the
Speaker 7:  drive-throughs.
Speaker 7:  Maybe I have second thoughts about doing that because
Speaker 7:  there's a lot of people complaining on social media and a lot of people
Speaker 7:  trying to troll the AI on social media by asking for,
Speaker 7:  I believe 18,000 cups of water.
Speaker 7:  And so he, he tells the wa the Wall Street Journal, we're learning a lot.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna be honest with you. I think like everybody, sometimes
Speaker 7:  it lets me down, but sometimes it really surprises me, which
Speaker 7:  is, you know, I don't wanna go to a drive-through and talk to an AI and get
Speaker 7:  a surprise. So I just,
Speaker 7:  this tickles me because it's just, the other thing he says is that
Speaker 7:  he's discovered that using AI exclusively in certain situations, like a drive-through
Speaker 7:  for quote super busy restaurants with long lines might
Speaker 7:  not be such a good idea after all. Which
Speaker 7:  I don't know, you think?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Richard Drive through ai thumbs up, thumbs down
Speaker 11:  Co. Could we just have buttons?
Speaker 11:  Like
Speaker 11:  you, you have, you offer like 10 things. Just let me press the button and
Speaker 11:  then we we can do it. Yeah. But yeah,
Speaker 11:  I think it's not that hard to imagine that a bored teenager
Speaker 11:  in many cases or basically anyone just ha
Speaker 11:  happening to do this job is better equipped to deal with someone
Speaker 11:  walking up to the, you know, driving up to the window and saying, yeah,
Speaker 11:  I want 18,000 cups of water than an AI is.
Speaker 11:  It's just not, it's just not going to work. Like also they might fight you
Speaker 11:  underwriting waffle, waffle of having waffle human employed Waffle House.
Speaker 11:  Could you,
Speaker 7:  Would you imagine you're
Speaker 11:  Not, you're not going to do that at Waffle House.
Speaker 7:  You're not doing that at Waffle House, waffle House. They, have you ever
Speaker 7:  seen that video of the lady at the Waffle House and they throw the chair
Speaker 7:  at her and she's like, not on my watch and she just pulls the chair out
Speaker 7:  of the air. Yes. Yeah, you're not gonna do that at Waffle House.
Speaker 5:  I, this is such a fascinating use case. 'cause like I, on one hand,
Speaker 5:  you know, could, could an AI handle a drive-through order? Like probably
Speaker 5:  with, with some frequency it could, it could do that correctly.
Speaker 5:  But this is like a business that serves customers and needs to do things
Speaker 5:  correctly, like all the time quickly
Speaker 7:  Too.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And it's one of those things where like, okay, great, if AI
Speaker 5:  screws up a response to me one in 10
Speaker 5:  times, like it's not, it's not, it's annoying, it's not great, but it's not
Speaker 5:  a big deal. It's just talking to me. I see that it's messed up. I can deal
Speaker 5:  with it if it's in a drive through d dealing
Speaker 5:  with th thousands of customers a day, like you can't
Speaker 5:  have that error rate. Like AI's error rate is not ready for this.
Speaker 5:  This is like precisely one of those situations where a company is like
Speaker 5:  automate, we can make a ton of money. CEO I'm gonna sound cool, my earnings
Speaker 5:  call saying ai, ai, ai. And then you put it into use and it's
Speaker 5:  like, oh, like even if this works most of the time, like it needs
Speaker 5:  to work all of it.
Speaker 7:  Well, you like, I sometimes when, when Big Tech talks about things that way,
Speaker 7:  I'm just like, did they seem so pure? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Inside. Because I was like, did you give it to a troll?
Speaker 7:  Right. Did you troll test this for 'cause
Speaker 7:  there it only takes one jerk to break the whole thing. And they're like,
Speaker 7:  it'll be great. It'll do this. The ideal situation will happen and we're
Speaker 7:  helping everyone. And it's like, did you give it to a 13-year-old
Speaker 7:  who, who really lives for the shits and giggles? Because
Speaker 7:  if it can't survive that it's, it's just not gonna survive the
Speaker 7:  real world. And if you're taco be the only people I know
Speaker 7:  who go to Taco Bell are probably having the munchies and or really
Speaker 7:  hungry. And so if your AI is not working, they have the
Speaker 7:  munchies, they're in a drive through line, they have road rage and they're
Speaker 7:  hangry. This is not the ideal Yeah. Situation for,
Speaker 7:  for an ai. And I, I kind of feel bad for the, not that AI has
Speaker 7:  feelings, but I kind of feel bad for it in, in, in one sense. And then my
Speaker 7:  other spiel is that, you know, whenever I call an insurance
Speaker 7:  company and they put me in the AI like robot tree And I have to listen
Speaker 7:  to the dumb thing And I'm just going, let me talk to a human,
Speaker 7:  you know, how is that not the same thing? It be the
Speaker 5:  Drive through, you just yell zero at the ai.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, And I would just be like, human, human just, I want a
Speaker 7:  taco mild sauce please. Chalupa.
Speaker 7:  Like, it's, it's, it's, it's not, it's not. I just want
Speaker 7:  a chalupa.
Speaker 5:  I i it makes a lot of sense that Taco Bell's customer
Speaker 5:  base immediately made them regret this, right? Yeah. And I appreciate they
Speaker 5:  did good work here. Live
Speaker 7:  Moss, you know, live,
Speaker 5:  Unless you're the AI at Taco Bell, in which case
Speaker 5:  Liv Mayos I think, and that is
Speaker 5:  the limit of my Spanish. Richard, wrap us up. What have you got?
Speaker 11:  This one came from Andrew Hawkins. We have Robo Mart.
Speaker 11:  They have introduced a new delivery robot that aims to shake up
Speaker 11:  autonomous delivery. It, it is essentially, remember when
Speaker 11:  Amazon introduced those lockers where you could get something delivered?
Speaker 11:  Like if you didn't want to it to be delivered to your house and sit outside
Speaker 11:  all day, you can maybe have it delivered to the locker, get a code or something
Speaker 11:  and you just go pick it up. So what if the locker drove to your house?
Speaker 7:  No,
Speaker 5:  I, I can't tell if this is brilliant or the dumbest thing I've ever heard
Speaker 5:  of.
Speaker 11:  It's both. That is exactly what I said. I I, it's, it's one of those two
Speaker 11:  things And I dunno know, it might be both of them all at once.
Speaker 5:  It's both. I think the future is just lockers
Speaker 5:  everywhere for everything. People love the lockers. I love the lockers.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, Ooh, a locker, I could pick something. I don't have anything to
Speaker 5:  pick up. It could have something
Speaker 11:  The size of a shuttle bus and can carry up to 500 pounds. What? You've gotta
Speaker 5:  Look at this nature. What? No, no. Oh my God. It's, I thought, sorry,
Speaker 5:  I thought this was a small robot, not a
Speaker 5:  full bus sized vehicle. Oh my god. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  It's like a sprinter van, you know, just rolling around full of it's
Speaker 11:  whatever.
Speaker 5:  Does this make any sense? No, I don't. But the problem is,
Speaker 5:  this requires what happens if the person is the, the thing with the
Speaker 5:  locker. The locker sits there, it waits for you.
Speaker 5:  If I'm not at home and the locker shows up, is this,
Speaker 5:  well, the locker
Speaker 11:  Could come to your office,
Speaker 5:  But is it gonna, like,
Speaker 7:  It's not useful for, for my groceries
Speaker 5:  Parallel park and try to like, wait for me, like
Speaker 5:  what happens to the person who is like 10 lockers in? What,
Speaker 11:  What I loved was one of the quotes on their website from the mar from Mars
Speaker 11:  unattended retail. This partnership helps solve the industry's biggest issue.
Speaker 11:  Ice cream melting before reaching the home when purchased in store or through
Speaker 11:  other delivery methods.
Speaker 5:  What? Just get a cooler Wait because it's refrigerated. How
Speaker 5:  is it? Oh, it's refrigerated. I mean, just get a cooler.
Speaker 5:  This is a really expensive locker. This is, this
Speaker 5:  is the least efficient way to ship ice cream.
Speaker 5:  I what, how is this an issue? I don't understand this.
Speaker 5:  I like, I've tried, I've tried grocery delivery before.
Speaker 5:  I would say it has mostly been a bad experience. I've,
Speaker 7:  I've not had that bad of an experience with grocery delivery, even with ice
Speaker 7:  cream.
Speaker 5:  Have you, have you tried Amazon Whole Foods, like grocery delivery.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I don't use, I, my they they were not
Speaker 5:  Great. They, this is so I tr I tried this because I, I got
Speaker 5:  mad at my local grocery stores. You know what they should, they should carry
Speaker 5:  better produce. All right. It is. You cut open too many
Speaker 5:  peppers that are bad inside. You get pissed.
Speaker 5:  The problem I kept running into with, with Amazon is I'd be like, all right,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna order some food and then they would just be out of stock of like
Speaker 5:  everything. Like there is there some weird online thing, but
Speaker 5:  just it's not, I was never upset. Like, I'm not gonna order ice cream.
Speaker 5:  It's fine. I don't need to order ice cream for delivery. Like I can manage
Speaker 11:  You dream. You're sitting at home wanting an ice cream sandwich and having
Speaker 11:  a bus, okay, rolled up to deliver you one ice cream sandwich. This is that.
Speaker 11:  That's not, can I
Speaker 7:  Tell that's
Speaker 5:  An abuse power. Richard, you have invented a business known as an
Speaker 5:  ice cream truck. This exists, this is famously
Speaker 5:  a very successful industry.
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 15:  In New York, those things are like rolling around at all
Speaker 15:  hours of the night. I can walk outside at any time and get
Speaker 5:  An ice cream sandwich. I don't need a giant truck
Speaker 15:  With a personalized
Speaker 5:  Locker
Speaker 15:  To gimme eight of them at once.
Speaker 15:  They're solving an already solved problem. We have
Speaker 15:  delivery, we have refrigerated trucks. Oh,
Speaker 15:  I don't know what this is for. I
Speaker 15:  I'm saying
Speaker 15:  they,
Speaker 5:  They saw that they,
Speaker 15:  You know, when
Speaker 11:  You put it that way?
Speaker 15:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know, IIII understand why a business
Speaker 5:  person, I understand why like an Amazon would look at us and go,
Speaker 5:  this is genius. This is going, this is on the level of ai. It will
Speaker 5:  revolutionize our business. And then as soon as you figure out, think about
Speaker 5:  like, how am I actually gonna put this to use? I just
Speaker 5:  have literally no idea.
Speaker 7:  I'm also afraid of this on the road. I already have seen a TikTok of someone
Speaker 7:  just like filming one of those say like the, like the small ones that
Speaker 7:  deliver drinks around and they're just like, don't hit him.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God.
Speaker 15:  It's like Frogger, is it gonna get across
Speaker 7:  The street and we gonna do this? I'm afraid of this.
Speaker 5:  It's got a bit of a tank vibe. It's got a, it's like, yeah, this thing is
Speaker 5:  hefty. It's hefty. Depends how much ice cream is carrying.
Speaker 7:  But it can you just imagine it getting into a collision and then just the
Speaker 7:  ice cream exploding out of the lockers and then it melts that way.
Speaker 5:  You know what, that's the dream.
Speaker 11:  Yes, I can that, that is going immediately to the top of The Verge dot com.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast. Stay tuned. Allison will be hosting
Speaker 5:  on Tuesday. If you like. What we do here, the best way to support us is to
Speaker 5:  get a subscription to The Verge at The Verge dot com. We publish a lot of
Speaker 5:  great stuff every single day. We'd love to hear your questions and
Speaker 5:  feedback. Let us know what you want us to talk about in the show. Email us
Speaker 5:  vergecast at The Verge dot com or give us a call. 8 6 6 VERGE 11.
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 5:  A show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer, Travis Uck, and Andrew
Speaker 5:  Marino. See you next week.