# Transcript
ID: dc1fa3ea-9733-4266-a5d9-14a2544d5e19
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/518335110444909177/-300297330910862603/s93290-US-5083s-1745918249.mp3
Description: Sometimes you want more tech in your life — and sometimes you want a lot less. This episode is all about less. First, Tim Stevens joins the show to talk about his story about the Slate Truck, an ultra-minimal electric vehicle that has almost no features to speak of and yet still promises to reinvent the way we think about cars. After that, Casey Johnston tells us about her journey in managing her screen time. She has tips for how to get the most problematic apps of your phone, is a big proponent of a factory reset, and has seen first-hand what happens when you look at your devices just a little less. Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about whether there's a MacBook Air equivalent in the Windows world. The answer surprised us, and it might surprise you too.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of trucks that have no
Speaker 2:  stereos and no paint and like no features of any kind.
Speaker 2:  And I still want it very, very, very badly. I'm your friend David Pierce,
Speaker 2:  and right now I'm doing some headphone testing. So I have a blue set of AirPods
Speaker 2:  Max that frankly, I just hadn't used AirPods Max in a while, so I picked
Speaker 2:  up a pair, don't tell anybody, but I have every intention of turning these
Speaker 2:  to the Apple Store, but just wanted to try 'em out for a while. And then
Speaker 2:  I got these, they're called the Picken F fives, and
Speaker 2:  they are just the most incredible blatant AirPods
Speaker 2:  Max knockoff you've ever seen in your entire life.
Speaker 2:  I am fascinated by these things. The AirPods Max are $500.
Speaker 2:  These are like $50 and I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna have a lot more to say about these 'cause I actually think there's
Speaker 2:  a really interesting story behind these headphones and the TikTok shop and
Speaker 2:  the way that we buy and find electronics now. But I will tell you
Speaker 2:  these sound a lot better than a 10th, as good as the AirPods Max.
Speaker 2:  More on that to come. Anyway, on this show, we're gonna do two things today.
Speaker 2:  First, we are going to talk about the Slate Truck, which launched last week.
Speaker 2:  It is one of the most interesting new vehicles we've seen in a very
Speaker 2:  long time. Tim Stevens wrote about it for us. He's gonna come on the show,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about it After that. I'm gonna talk to Casey Johnston, who
Speaker 2:  writes a newsletter called She's a Beast, about how to use my phone less.
Speaker 2:  I have been on this slow journey to try and
Speaker 2:  downgrade my screen time a little bit, not because I think phones are inherently
Speaker 2:  bad and that looking at screens is inherently bad. But just because I find
Speaker 2:  myself like picking up my phone to look at TikTok while I walk to the
Speaker 2:  bathroom six feet away, and that just doesn't seem quite right. So
Speaker 2:  Casey has some really interesting ideas. We're gonna talk about all of that.
Speaker 2:  We also really fun hotline question about laptops that caused a sort of
Speaker 2:  small existential crisis among a bunch of us. Lots to get to.
Speaker 2:  This is a really fun show. This is like extremely up my
Speaker 2:  alley. All of this stuff, it's been very fun. All of that is coming up in
Speaker 2:  just a second, but I just realized I have like six pairs of
Speaker 2:  headphones connected to my phone now, and I have to walk the dog, which means
Speaker 2:  I have to go solve a bunch of Bluetooth problems in order to listen to
Speaker 2:  podcasts while I walk. I'm gonna figure that out. We'll be right back. This
Speaker 2:  is The Vergecast. I'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Tim Stevens is here. Tim, welcome to The Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Hey David, thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  Tim, you are a freelance tech and auto writer. You and I
Speaker 2:  have been tech blogger enemies for many years.
Speaker 6:  Frenemies, I'd like to say
Speaker 2:  A frenemies is good. I'm, I'm good with frenemies. You also write a newsletter
Speaker 2:  called Around The Next Bend, but last week you
Speaker 2:  wrote a story for us about I I honestly
Speaker 2:  think I have been thinking about this a lot and I think I can say this without
Speaker 2:  hyperbole the most interesting car I have seen in years.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I would totally agree. And I think what makes it interesting is how
Speaker 6:  bare bones, how basic It is. And, and what's also interesting is how well
Speaker 6:  it's resonating, given how little it actually has and, and does if, if that's
Speaker 6:  not saying too much.
Speaker 2:  Totally. So yeah, I wanna talk about, there's kind of the, the car, the company
Speaker 2:  and, and why everyone is into this. But let, let's just talk about the car
Speaker 2:  first. Yeah. So describe the Slate Truck to me.
Speaker 6:  So the Slate Truck is basically an attempt to kind of reboot what a
Speaker 6:  car could be. It is a very, very basic machine on, on many levels, starting
Speaker 6:  with the paint, for example, there is no paint, it's basically made of molded
Speaker 6:  plastic. All the body work is, which has a lot of benefits. If
Speaker 6:  it's scratches, it doesn't matter because there's no paint layer to scratch
Speaker 6:  off, so it's just gonna stay the same color. But it was designed,
Speaker 6:  interestingly, to be a great surface for receiving vinyl
Speaker 6:  wraps, which is a very common thing that people are doing these days. So
Speaker 6:  you can get it in any color you want to, you just gotta kind of DIY it. It
Speaker 6:  is an electric truck seats too. It is not like a
Speaker 6:  king cab kind of thing where you can have comfortable seating in the back.
Speaker 6:  But interestingly, if you do need seating for more people, you can buy an
Speaker 6:  upgrade kit, which basically bolts a couple of seats in the bed and turns
Speaker 6:  it into an SUV. You can probably catch the, the theme here is
Speaker 6:  customization. That's, that's a big thing for sure. It's fully electric rear
Speaker 6:  drive, relatively small battery between 150 and 230 miles of range.
Speaker 6:  Depending upon which configuration that you go with fairly low power.
Speaker 6:  You're not looking at, you know, a crazy sort of 60 times or anything like
Speaker 6:  that. It doesn't have a lot of towing capacity. About a thousand pounds there.
Speaker 6:  Payload, I think is about 1500 pounds, which is comparable to something like
Speaker 6:  a, a Ford Maverick. So, you know, you're looking at a kind
Speaker 6:  of bare bones ev but the, the really interesting things, I think is what
Speaker 6:  it doesn't have, again, doesn't have paint, doesn't not have a touchscreen,
Speaker 6:  doesn't even have a car stereo of any kind. It doesn't have power
Speaker 6:  windows. You've gotta crank the windows down in, in a very old school kind
Speaker 6:  of way. And so it, it, It is again, a very bare bones
Speaker 6:  machine, which I, I think makes it very compelling because the biggest story,
Speaker 6:  of course is that they want this thing to cost less than $20,000 after federal
Speaker 6:  incentives, which means the full price of the things probably on the order
Speaker 6:  of 25 to $2,700.
Speaker 2:  How much do you think the story here starts with price? Like, can you work
Speaker 2:  backwards from, we wanted to get this thing to be $19,999
Speaker 2:  and sort of tell the rest of the story?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah, for sure. I think that the price is definitely something that
Speaker 6:  they had in mind when they were beginning this company about three years
Speaker 6:  ago, and they started in the, the initial designs. And to get such a
Speaker 6:  radically low price on an ev in, you know, the current state of
Speaker 6:  the world, the current state of the economy requires, you know, you make
Speaker 6:  some drastic cuts like power windows for example, or touchscreens or
Speaker 6:  radios. But it also really require the team, the
Speaker 6:  designers at Slate Auto to come up with a way of not only cutting back
Speaker 6:  on features in the vehicle, but also cutting back on the production and the
Speaker 6:  development and the design costs of the things. So for example, you know,
Speaker 6:  we talking about the lack of, of paint being an advantage potentially if
Speaker 6:  you have something that gets scratched, that kinda thing. There's also a
Speaker 6:  huge advantage from a production standpoint because if you are creating
Speaker 6:  aluminum body panels or steel body panels that requires these massive
Speaker 6:  stamping machines that are like three stories tall, that cost millions of
Speaker 6:  dollars. But if you're injecting molding plastic, you can basically do that
Speaker 6:  in any kind of building. You can do that in your apartment if you want to.
Speaker 6:  And the fact that it's not painted means that they don't need a paint shop.
Speaker 6:  And paint shops are incredibly expensive too. So those two things right there
Speaker 6:  make this company, you know, makes them getting off the ground much
Speaker 6:  easier and it again, takes huge amounts of costs outta the design and development
Speaker 6:  of a vehicle like this. So when you look at a lot of the changes, a lot of
Speaker 6:  the things that are missing, they have obviously an impact in terms of the
Speaker 6:  cost of the vehicle itself, but they also have a huge impact on the ability
Speaker 6:  for the company to get to production quickly and cheaply, which again, then
Speaker 6:  just factors into keeping the cost of the vehicle low.
Speaker 2:  So does that feel disingenuous to you at all? Like, I,
Speaker 2:  I look at this thing and it's like, okay, it's, it's, it's $20,000, great.
Speaker 2:  I would like my car to have a stereo. That, that seems like a reasonable
Speaker 2:  thing to ask for in a car. Yeah, you have to, you have to pay more money
Speaker 2:  f to put your kids in the backseat, right? So I think is this,
Speaker 2:  is this sort of a, a bit that this company is doing to be able to say
Speaker 2:  we're selling a truck under $20,000, which I think for a lot of reasons we
Speaker 2:  should talk about, is a meaningful thing to be able to say. Yeah, for
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 2:  Or is this a real sort of honest to god, just different and
Speaker 2:  interesting approach to how you even think about making a car?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you, you can definitely take a look at this from the cynical or the
Speaker 6:  optimistic approach from the cynical approach. You know, this is the low
Speaker 6:  cost airline approach of EVs or even yes, if you want a sandwich, yes, then
Speaker 6:  you gotta pay extra for that kind of seats. It's
Speaker 2:  10 for a tray table, is
Speaker 6:  It? Right? If you wanna be able to put both of your feet on the seat in front
Speaker 6:  of you, you gotta pay extra for that kind thing. You can definitely look
Speaker 6:  at it in that way. And I think that there is some truth to that as well.
Speaker 6:  But, but you know, and the Tom and I spent speaking with the executives and
Speaker 6:  the designers and everything else, they do genuinely feel kind of emotionally
Speaker 6:  attached to this idea of, of rebooting motoring and, and creating something
Speaker 6:  that is attainable by everybody. So I I I think you can come
Speaker 6:  at it from two different ways, but I, I think the, what I, I like the idea
Speaker 6:  here is that you've got one truck in one spec. This
Speaker 6:  isn't an upsell kind of thing. You can get a story if you want to, they'll
Speaker 6:  sell you an upgrade kit for that. They'll sell you upgrade kits for all sorts
Speaker 6:  of things on the thing if you want to. But unlike a lot of EV startups like
Speaker 6:  El Lucid or even Tesla in the early days where you had to buy their new EV
Speaker 6:  in like this super souped up package with all the options and it cost twice
Speaker 6:  as much as it was supposed to. This is just gonna be a bare bones thing to
Speaker 6:  begin with. And then you just add on the things that you want to. And I think
Speaker 6:  the other interesting thing is that a lot of this is really, I don't wanna
Speaker 6:  say open source, but it's gonna be pretty easy for a lot of people to do
Speaker 6:  this on their own. You'll be able to 3D print components if you wanna put
Speaker 6:  that in there, you can mount your own Bluetooth speaker if you don't wanna
Speaker 6:  use theirs. It's not the kind of thing where you're gonna be forced down
Speaker 6:  an upgrade path with huge high premiums on, on, on there. You can kind of
Speaker 6:  do this stuff as you want to and you can do it as you can afford to as well.
Speaker 6:  So if you can only afford the truck up front, but you want to add that serious
Speaker 6:  system down the road 12 months later after you save up some money, you can
Speaker 6:  do that. And, and I like that approach.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think it's a pickup truck? I think a lot of this sort of sensibility
Speaker 2:  you described strikes me as making a lot more sense if you
Speaker 2:  were making something that looked like a Nissan Leaf or like a, or
Speaker 2:  like a really cool scooter, right? Sure. Like we've seen all these things
Speaker 2:  where people are basically like, what if I just built a thing with two wheels
Speaker 2:  and some wild ideas around it? And maybe that's the future. Like so much
Speaker 2:  of what you're talking about feels like it suits that better than like what
Speaker 2:  people have in their mind when they think of pickup truck.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's a good question, David. I think for one thing It is cheaper.
Speaker 6:  You know, you've only got half the interior to worry about. That saves some
Speaker 6:  money there too, I think from a pure, you know, if you go to that concept
Speaker 6:  again of something that is, that you can wear into part of the idea
Speaker 6:  here is something that evolves with you and then it gets better with age.
Speaker 6:  You know, I, I looked into one of their design boards at one point and had
Speaker 6:  this picture of a shark on there that was covered in scars and the shark
Speaker 6:  was old and beat up, but it looked cool as hell and that was part of what
Speaker 6:  they wanted the aesthetic of this vehicle to be. That it, it gets better
Speaker 6:  looking with time like an old pair of blue jeans, like a leather wallet,
Speaker 6:  that kind of thing. And I think that that concept works
Speaker 6:  better with a truck than, than with a car, simply because we're used to trucks
Speaker 6:  being at job sites, you know, hauling mulch and lumber and that kind of thing.
Speaker 6:  But whether, again, that could be an optimistic or pessimistic thing. Did,
Speaker 6:  did that concept come about because they decided to have a truck and they
Speaker 6:  wanted to come up with a good way to spin it? Or is that really part of the
Speaker 6:  concept of, of the vehicle to begin with? And that you could go either way.
Speaker 6:  But the other thing is, I think that this functionally makes a lot of sense
Speaker 6:  for a lot of people. The idea of, I think a lot of people would love to have
Speaker 6:  a small truck that they can go get some, some mulch, they can go get some
Speaker 6:  lumber or they can even put their muddy dog in the back if they want to without
Speaker 6:  getting it all over the interior. And I think that that makes sense too.
Speaker 6:  But also the idea that you can then convert it into an SUV, which is the
Speaker 6:  most popular category of vehicles right now without too much effort means
Speaker 6:  that this could have enough flexibility to work even if you don't want a
Speaker 6:  truck. But, but I'm curious to see what uptick is and how many people actually
Speaker 6:  decide to get the SUV kit for.
Speaker 2:  Okay. How much are you a truck guy in general? I know you, you wrote in the
Speaker 2:  story that you, like many people find ridiculous how
Speaker 2:  enormous and tall trucks have become. Yeah. But are you like on the
Speaker 2:  slide just driving around in your F1 yelling at people
Speaker 2:  out the window? Like are you, you're not a truck guy Generally,
Speaker 6:  I've owned trucks. I've spent years living wi with trucks. I think trucks
Speaker 6:  are great. I would love to actually have a truck, but I have too many vehicles
Speaker 6:  as It is right now, and a truck doesn't quite fit in there. But I think one
Speaker 6:  of the main things that stopped me from getting a truck is that there aren't
Speaker 6:  many small cheap options like this anymore.
Speaker 6:  You know, it used to be that you could go buy a really basic Toyota T 100
Speaker 6:  or a Nissan Frontier for, you know, under $20,000 and
Speaker 6:  have a basic truck that sat to people had a manual transmission and crank
Speaker 6:  windows. And I can't tell you the number of people who have been asking
Speaker 6:  me when is Ford gonna bring back something like the old ranger
Speaker 6:  in the nineties, which a lot of people loved, which was very much that kind
Speaker 6:  of truck. But it was still cool because it had like flare sides and cool
Speaker 6:  graphics and stuff like that. And so what I, I would love to have would
Speaker 6:  be something like a K truck, which is the small Japanese trucks that, that
Speaker 6:  a lot of folks are importing, which are unfortunately basically not legal
Speaker 6:  here in New York state right now, which is preventing me from getting one,
Speaker 6:  something super basic that I could beat the hell out of, that I could take
Speaker 6:  to Home Depot and, and put a bunch of pavers in the back and not care if
Speaker 6:  it scratches up the paint. If I could buy something like that for cheap,
Speaker 6:  I, I probably would have one. So that's why I'm personally excited about
Speaker 6:  a slate. But yeah, I, I spent a lot of time in trucks. I've done a lot of
Speaker 6:  towing and hauling and, and that kind of thing, and so I respect them, but
Speaker 6:  I think the big problem right now with the consumer truck industry in the
Speaker 6:  United States is that these trucks are just gotten simply too big. If you
Speaker 6:  look at something like a Silverado 2,500, a Ram 3,500,
Speaker 6:  you could literally put a sixth grader standing in front of that truck and
Speaker 6:  the person in the driver's seat could not see that child just because
Speaker 6:  of the height of the hood. These things are unnecessarily large and
Speaker 6:  they're hugely expensive with the average price of $60,000 in the us
Speaker 6:  and that I think is too much. And so I hope that slate is a huge success
Speaker 6:  and that makes these other truck companies think, well, maybe it's time for
Speaker 6:  us to deliver something small and cheap as well. So the
Speaker 2:  Analogy that that makes me think of, and you are a, a perfect
Speaker 2:  person to litigate this analogy with me,
Speaker 2:  is the people who want small smartphones. Yep. And I think we, we've been
Speaker 2:  on this inexorable march to bigger, more expensive
Speaker 2:  smartphones Yeah. For a decade. And there has always been this group of people
Speaker 2:  who is like, no, I want the iPhone four, I want something that
Speaker 2:  fits in my hand. Yeah. These things are preposterous and yet
Speaker 2:  I, every bit of available evidence suggests that what people actually want
Speaker 2:  when they vote with their dollars is the big smartphones. And, and I, I have
Speaker 2:  to assume that the same is true in the trucking industry, which is why they
Speaker 2:  keep making bigger, taller trucks. So is is slate like the,
Speaker 2:  the iPhone SE and that It is like sort of adorable but not
Speaker 2:  real for most people? Or is is there something different going on here? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's a great analogy. Obviously consumer demand is what has pushed the truck
Speaker 6:  industry to where It is today. It's not like, you know, Ram and Chevy and
Speaker 6:  Ford are forcing these giant trucks down the throats of anybody. People aspire
Speaker 6:  to own a bigger, better, faster, more powerful truck, and so people go out
Speaker 6:  and buy them. I think that's happening on the smartphone world as well. But
Speaker 6:  I I I am sure you as well know, a lot of folks are still hanging onto their
Speaker 6:  older iPhones because they don't want something that's too big. And I think
Speaker 6:  the problem in the smartphone industry is that, you know, nobody else can
Speaker 6:  release an iPhone, only a can. So if Apple decides that big phones are,
Speaker 6:  what's it, and they're not gonna make smart phones anymore, nobody else can
Speaker 6:  do that. On the Android side, obviously it's different, but a lot of folks
Speaker 6:  are very tied into the Apple ecosystem and they're not gonna go anywhere
Speaker 6:  on the auto side, it's a very different story. There are really, there are
Speaker 6:  ecosystems as such, but they're not nearly as powerful as, as you know, as
Speaker 6:  Apple or Android or something like that. So for someone to switch brands,
Speaker 6:  for someone to have a conquest and, and go from one brand to another, it's
Speaker 6:  not that big of a deal. And especially it's easy with a slate because, you
Speaker 6:  know, there's no software really to worry about anyway. So it's, it'd be,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of a new it, it's greenfield territory. And that I think
Speaker 6:  is the biggest question for me is are people really gonna put
Speaker 6:  their money where their mouth is? You know, like I said, people have been
Speaker 6:  asking me when is Ford gonna make a a small ranger again? When is someone
Speaker 6:  a good ring out a cheap frontier or a cheap Tacoma and
Speaker 6:  this is their time to put their money forward and say, this is what I actually
Speaker 6:  want. The interest in the article has been huge and that's encouraging,
Speaker 6:  but we also saw huge interest around the cyber truck when that was unveiled
Speaker 6:  and that obviously has not landed quite so well. So I'm curious to see how,
Speaker 6:  how this lands when it does ship, hopefully toward the end of next year.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah, we're, we're gonna come back to that because I've, I've heard,
Speaker 2:  I've heard that phrase so many times that I've come to not believe it, but
Speaker 2:  we're gonna come back to that. The last thing I'm trying to figure out about
Speaker 2:  the truck is Slate seems to imagine kind of the
Speaker 2:  ecosystem of a car very differently from
Speaker 2:  your average company. Like what was your sense of how they're thinking about
Speaker 2:  it in terms of like, okay, I I do want to add a stereo. Is that
Speaker 2:  something slate is going to make? Is that something that they're
Speaker 2:  imagining I can just like walk to Best Buy and buy? Am I gonna, am I gonna
Speaker 2:  do the repairs on the car myself? Which is a thing I think an an executive
Speaker 2:  hinted to you as part of their plan. Like the sort of car
Speaker 2:  world is enormous and much bigger than just the car that you own. Right?
Speaker 2:  I is slate trying to fit into that or sort of reimagine that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, slate I is really rapidly or, or radically I should say,
Speaker 6:  embracing the DIY mentality, both in terms of right to repair and also in
Speaker 6:  terms of customization. So, you know, again, it starts on the outside with
Speaker 6:  these vinyl wrap kits that Slate will offer, but they'll also make it pretty
Speaker 6:  easy to do your own wood templates, that kind of thing. So customizing the
Speaker 6:  look should be more easy than any other vehicle out there. But yeah, when
Speaker 6:  it comes to customize the interior, there are provisions in there for
Speaker 6:  connecting USB devices, power for speakers, that kind of thing. So you can
Speaker 6:  pretty easily bring your own devices there or they have said that they will
Speaker 6:  offer some upgrade kits as well to bring speakers into the vehicle. But I
Speaker 6:  think the idea by and large is for you to be doing
Speaker 6:  this work yourself or to work with some kind of aftermarket installer if
Speaker 6:  you want to, but they're gonna be creating something that they call Slate
Speaker 6:  University, which is basically like a, like a big online
Speaker 6:  fact, a knowledge base kind of thing where you can look up information on
Speaker 6:  how to install speakers into your vehicle, how to do a vinyl wrap and even
Speaker 6:  how to do some repair. So for example, if your mirror
Speaker 6:  breaks and that's covered by warranty, instead of you having to go to a shop
Speaker 6:  to replace that mirror, they want to basically send you a new mirror and
Speaker 6:  tell you how to install it. Interesting. Which on one hand it feels kind
Speaker 6:  of basic to some degree, like, shouldn't someone do that for me? But also
Speaker 6:  on the other hand, it sounds a lot nicer for me to just go out in my driveway
Speaker 6:  and take off the old mirror and pop on a new one rather than driving it down
Speaker 6:  to the dealership, dropping it off in the morning, maybe getting a courtesy
Speaker 6:  car or maybe just spending four hours sitting in the waiting room reading
Speaker 6:  Golf Digest for four hours, waiting for this thing to get done, that I could
Speaker 6:  have done myself into five minutes. So I think again, there's an optimistic
Speaker 6:  and a pessimistic way of looking at this. I, I personally am someone who
Speaker 6:  likes to work on my cars and to have a company that is going to be
Speaker 6:  actively supporting me doing that is, is quite novel. Most companies don't
Speaker 6:  want you to do that because their dealers make so much money on aftermarket
Speaker 6:  service and sales support that, that they don't really want to cut that off.
Speaker 2:  It's funny, part of the reason I ask is I had this, I had the experience
Speaker 2:  you described literally on Friday, like just a few days ago,
Speaker 2:  I had to drop my car off and they were like, oh, it's a pretty simple thing
Speaker 2:  to fix. The problem is we don't have this one gasket that we need.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, well can can I just go to like AutoZone and buy the gasket
Speaker 2:  and bring it to you? And he was like, no, if it doesn't come from this specific
Speaker 2:  place, it's not covered in your warranty. And then it's technically an out
Speaker 2:  of warranty repair. So they sent me home and now I have to go back and do
Speaker 2:  this whole process again later this week. That course, just so they can put
Speaker 2:  a gasket that looks like every other gasket on my car. And so there is,
Speaker 2:  there is something about that that I would love to break apart,
Speaker 2:  even though the idea of sort of
Speaker 2:  encouraging everyone to try and fix their own car has some pretty obvious
Speaker 2:  scary downsides.
Speaker 6:  Right. And, and they've said very clearly to me that anything that is dangerous
Speaker 6:  will not be allowed to be done yourself. So anything involving the high voltage
Speaker 6:  system, for example, if you want to get the larger battery pack, it's actually
Speaker 6:  going to be a second battery pack you'll install in the vehicle, but you
Speaker 6:  won't be doing that yourself because A, it's gonna be incredibly heavy, but
Speaker 6:  B at that point you'll be interfacing with the vehicle's high voltage system.
Speaker 6:  So that kind of thing you'll have to take it to somewhere else to have done.
Speaker 6:  But upgrades and minor repairs, things like that, they want you to do, do
Speaker 6:  yourself. And I think that that, again, a lot of folks will find very empowering
Speaker 6:  and to have the support to do so. And I can only imagine what the, you know,
Speaker 6:  the user groups are gonna be like, I'm big in the 3D printing community as
Speaker 6:  well, or I should say I'm, I'm quite actively involved in it. And it's really
Speaker 6:  interesting to see the kind of support and, and help that you see when people
Speaker 6:  are trying to figure out how to get a new film and to print on their new
Speaker 6:  printer and the kind of advice that they get. And I'm really looking forward
Speaker 6:  to seeing that kind of approach brought to a car because it's not the kind
Speaker 6:  of thing that you typically see.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. What's your sense of how mainstream an idea
Speaker 2:  like that really is? Because I actually think that the 3D printing community
Speaker 2:  is kind of a good way to look at this, right? Where Yeah, lots of people
Speaker 2:  have 3D printing, It is more accessible than ever. It's more useful than
Speaker 2:  ever, but it's not, there was a time many years ago when, when you and I
Speaker 2:  were covering tech and everything Yeah. It was like we're all gonna have
Speaker 2:  3D printers in our house and that didn't pan out. And there's something
Speaker 2:  about this idea that seems like it, it's obviously going to appeal
Speaker 2:  to a specific kind of, you know, raspberry pie owning
Speaker 2:  tinkerer who Yeah. Who sort of enjoys the process of all of this stuff and
Speaker 2:  thinks that putting the mirror on their car is fun and doing the vinyl wraps
Speaker 2:  is fun and interesting and there are a lot of those people, but there's a
Speaker 2:  much bigger group of people that has traditionally not wanted to do those
Speaker 2:  things. It's slate after those people.
Speaker 6:  I think so for sure. Okay. Yeah, as you said, I think the maker community
Speaker 6:  is really gonna resonate with this vehicle and I think that's some of the
Speaker 6:  biggest excitement I've seen online so far for the vehicle. It is in that
Speaker 6:  community, but for sure Slate wants to deliver a fully functional vehicle.
Speaker 6:  It may be limited in function in terms of many other vehicles, but it, it's
Speaker 6:  the kind of thing that you'll be able to drive and use without having to
Speaker 6:  do anything to it if you don't want to. And then it's just gonna be up to
Speaker 6:  you if you wanna learn how to do these other things or pay someone else to
Speaker 6:  do these things for you to do the upgrades and that kind of thing. So for
Speaker 6:  sure it'll be a fully functional vehicle and slate for sure definitely wants
Speaker 6:  to be targeting, you know, they want anybody who's right now stuck in a six
Speaker 6:  or seven year car payment cycle on a vehicle that is gonna be,
Speaker 6:  you know, maybe not even drivable by the time their loan is up. They want
Speaker 6:  someone to have a a a, an affordable practical option that's,
Speaker 6:  that's far better for them on the daily, even if they're not, you know, a
Speaker 6:  3D print enthusiast, that kind of thing. So for sure they wanna target that
Speaker 6:  audience, but whether or not this car resonates with that audience, that
Speaker 6:  I think is a big question. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I it's the, the like pickup truck,
Speaker 2:  DIY sort of enthusiast world Yeah. Is,
Speaker 2:  is just fascinating and we've just never seen somebody try to kind of do
Speaker 2:  all of that at once. And I think part of the reason I I am so interested
Speaker 2:  in this truck is it It is, It is like speaking my language
Speaker 2:  in so many specific ways.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. Mine
Speaker 2:  Too. And yet I'm just, it's, it's just hard to see who is really gonna resonate
Speaker 2:  with it. Let's talk about the company a little bit because I think it's,
Speaker 2:  it's timing is fascinating, but obviously
Speaker 2:  this, this truck has been in the process longer than Trump's tariff
Speaker 2:  regulations have been happening. Yes. So the idea of like we spun up an American
Speaker 2:  manufacturer to make cars is, is like true but not sufficient. Right?
Speaker 2:  So tell me a little bit about this company. Where did Slate Auto come from?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it, it, this is part of what I have to be a little bit
Speaker 6:  cagey on because I don't know all the details yet in terms I've asked a lot
Speaker 6:  of questions in terms of funding and that kind of thing. And certainly, you
Speaker 6:  know, there's been a lot of reports out there that have some interesting
Speaker 6:  information out there. But from what I can say, you know, the company's been
Speaker 6:  in, in development for about three years now. CEO is Chris Barman
Speaker 6:  who's a former executive at Fiat Chrysler. And so she was there for a
Speaker 6:  long time and now she is taking over things. Lead designer is Tisha
Speaker 6:  Johnson who was at Volvo. She headed up Volvo's interior design for a long
Speaker 6:  time. So they've got some very talented people who are behind this and, and
Speaker 6:  this, you know, the idea was definitely fundamentally to create this low-cost
Speaker 6:  vehicle from the beginning. So this is something that they kind of stumbled
Speaker 6:  into the impression that I've gotten and said this was really the idea from
Speaker 6:  the beginning. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So they started with not like we wanna build a new company, but they started
Speaker 2:  with like, we wanna build this car.
Speaker 6:  Th that, that's my impression. Yeah. And then, so the company I believe is
Speaker 6:  actually headquartered in Michigan, but they have a design studio in the
Speaker 6:  LA area. So I think the majority of the work is happening in Michigan in
Speaker 6:  terms of production. The in indications are that
Speaker 6:  they'll be producing the vehicle in Indiana. The exact details of that have
Speaker 6:  not been disclosed yet. But again, the advantages of, of
Speaker 6:  the production we were talking about earlier of injection molding versus
Speaker 6:  stamping, that kind thing means that they can have a, a relatively small
Speaker 6:  footprint and basic factory compared to what, you know, if you look at the
Speaker 6:  Tesla Fremont facility for example, that thing is a massive sprawling thing.
Speaker 6:  Slates beginning investment should be a lot lower and their factor should
Speaker 6:  be a lot simpler and smaller than that. And then when it comes to funding,
Speaker 6:  obviously, you know, there's a lot of talk about Jeff Bezos being involved.
Speaker 6:  I asked rather pointedly, you know, is this a facet of Amazon
Speaker 6:  is a spinoff of Amazon, are we gonna see these with Amazon stick stickers
Speaker 6:  on 'em doing deliveries? Will you be able to go on amazon.com and and buy
Speaker 6:  them? And they downplayed that quite a bit. This is definitely
Speaker 6:  not officially part of Amazon, but when I asked them, will you be able to
Speaker 6:  buy the these on Amazon, they kind of shrugged their shoulders and said,
Speaker 6:  who knows maybe so, you know, don't think of this as an
Speaker 6:  Amazon subsidiary Right. But there may be some family ties in there due to
Speaker 6:  Jeff Bezos's involvement, if that makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah, our, our old friend Sean O. Kane has done some very good reporting
Speaker 2:  on this at TechCrunch. Excellent. To willing link to all that in the show.
Speaker 2:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  In fact, he had a new report that just dropped us think two days ago on that
Speaker 6:  factory. So he's got some more details there as well, which given the strength
Speaker 6:  of the reporting so far, I, I think, I think sounds legit to me.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah. We'll we'll put that in the show notes for sure. What do you
Speaker 2:  make of the timing the, this company's been, I would say, in, in sort of
Speaker 2:  remarkable secret for three years as you described. Why, why do you think
Speaker 2:  it's, it's coming out now, especially with a car, it's not planning to ship
Speaker 2:  for, you know, a year and change.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's impressive how quiet they've been. When I learned
Speaker 6:  about Slate, I had, I was invited to go see this thing and I had no idea
Speaker 6:  what it was. So I kind of went on faith of some of the people who I knew
Speaker 6:  were at this company, but I knew nothing about it. And to be able to keep,
Speaker 6:  you know, it's hard enough for a car company to keep a new model secret for
Speaker 6:  that long, but to keep an entire company secret for that long, It is quite
Speaker 6:  impressive.
Speaker 2:  And this is a pretty unusual looking vehicle, right? It like in in person
Speaker 2:  it's not, you're not gonna mistake it for something else pretty quickly.
Speaker 2:  Right, right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I talked to 'em about that and they actually have not done any open
Speaker 6:  road testing on the vehicle at all, which is part of how they did that. Because
Speaker 6:  otherwise yeah, we would've seen, I think people would've speculated that
Speaker 6:  it was a new, you know, 40 V or something like that if it had come out. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But anyhow, so that was part of how they, they managed to do that. But I
Speaker 6:  think the timing now makes sense because, you know, it takes 4, 5, 6
Speaker 6:  years to develop a, a new vehicle. You wanna get some interest in it, in
Speaker 6:  in time to get some ERs going to, for them to get an idea of what the demand's
Speaker 6:  gonna be like and where the demand is going to be. You know, they need to
Speaker 6:  come up with fulfillment centers, delivery centers and, and service centers
Speaker 6:  for these vehicles. And so they need to know where to, you know,
Speaker 6:  centralize those things. So I think that gives them enough runway to figure
Speaker 6:  out what they need to do from a logistics standpoint, which is another huge
Speaker 6:  part of this. You know, launching a new car company that can be very complicated.
Speaker 2:  Well, and just on the, on the logistics piece, it seems like the logistics
Speaker 2:  piece is where a lot of these sort of would be car startups get
Speaker 2:  screwed up. Exactly Right. And I think, do you have a sense
Speaker 2:  of what Slate maybe has learned or is trying to do differently?
Speaker 2:  I mean it seems like, again, to your point about the manufacturing, just
Speaker 2:  yeah, making the thing easier to make goes a really long way because if there's
Speaker 2:  one thing we've learned over the last 20 years of EVs, it's that
Speaker 2:  they're hard and expensive to make and that that is the thing that will kill
Speaker 2:  you. Is it as simple as that, that that's their move to try and do better
Speaker 2:  here?
Speaker 6:  No, there's a whole lot of interesting stuff going on on the delivery fulfillment
Speaker 6:  dens and service and support side as well. So direct sales for one thing,
Speaker 6:  which is probably not a surprise at this point, but that does add a lot of
Speaker 6:  complication. There are different rules in different states in terms of what
Speaker 6:  you can and cannot do for delivery centers. It's pretty restrictive in,
Speaker 6:  in many states in the US So there's a very good chance that you won't be
Speaker 6:  able to go around the corner to a slate store as such and pick up your
Speaker 6:  vehicle. Chances are you're probably gonna be driving a fair distance or
Speaker 6:  slate has said that they will deliver them to you. But interestingly, from
Speaker 6:  a service standpoint, they're actually partnering with some nationwide service
Speaker 6:  center or service centers to do all the warranty work on
Speaker 6:  their vehicles. They haven't said exactly which one It is, but I'll think
Speaker 6:  of something like a Meineke, you know, your local muffler shop, that kind
Speaker 6:  of thing. It'll be something like that where you'll be able to take your
Speaker 6:  vehicle to get a service and they said that they've got basically the entire
Speaker 6:  country covered or they will have the entire country covered on day one,
Speaker 6:  which is interesting and very different again than what we've seen before.
Speaker 6:  And, and then, you know, from a a logistics standpoint, not having dealerships
Speaker 6:  means that they get the full cost of the vehicle. There's no dealership taking
Speaker 6:  a cut. Same thing with accessory sales. You'll be getting those directly
Speaker 6:  from the company. Typically a dealership would take a cut of that as well
Speaker 6:  if you're buying accessories, options, that kind of thing. So again, that
Speaker 6:  just helps their margins, which helps 'em get to that, that low price point.
Speaker 2:  Okay. What, what, how would you handicap the odds of this thing actually
Speaker 2:  hitting the road in late 2026? I think we, we've been burned by this many
Speaker 2:  times. Yeah. And even I think there, there's even a question of like, is
Speaker 2:  any of this real Right? I think, I think I, I'm actually pretty
Speaker 2:  willing to give this the benefit of it out in part Yeah. Because I want to,
Speaker 2:  and in part because it actually, a thing that they've done is make it,
Speaker 2:  make a car that's easy to make, which I find very compelling. And also like
Speaker 2:  I'm more willing to bet on the existence of this thing than your average
Speaker 2:  $120,000 new, you know, Roadster competitor.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, for sure. Yeah. I, I'm quite bullish, but I was, if
Speaker 6:  I were in a position where I had not seen the thing, if I had not talked
Speaker 6:  to the executives, if I had not been to some of the facilities to see these
Speaker 6:  things, I, I would probably be extremely, extremely skeptical myself. 'cause
Speaker 6:  we've been burned by, you know, your aptera, your canoes, that, that kind
Speaker 6:  of thing over the years. Yeah. Kers even. And so
Speaker 6:  there's a lot of reason for skepticism here and I think that that's fair.
Speaker 6:  Especially, you know, we're talking about even if It is a relatively affordable
Speaker 6:  car, it's still gonna be a big investment for people. And so it makes sense
Speaker 6:  to be skeptical about where you put your money. And so for that reason, I,
Speaker 6:  I think that's fair. But having, having seen the vehicle, having sat in the
Speaker 6:  vehicle, having talked to these executives and having really looked
Speaker 6:  deeply at how they've engineered not just the vehicle but the company to
Speaker 6:  support this short runway, quick path to
Speaker 6:  profitability, I think that they are in a much better shape when it comes
Speaker 6:  to launching a new EV brand then just about anybody out there. And they
Speaker 6:  haven't had to go to extremely questionable lengths to get funding to continue
Speaker 6:  to give them the money that they need to. So the only question mark in my
Speaker 6:  eye is what is the consumer reaction going to be? Obviously it's been very
Speaker 6:  positive so far, but again, we've seen that with other EVs in the past.
Speaker 6:  It haven't gone very far. So if the demand is there, i I give the
Speaker 6:  company a, a good chance of success. But as you alluded to
Speaker 6:  before, Trump tariffs and everything else going on right now, ev
Speaker 6:  subsidies are very much a question mark hanging over the current state of
Speaker 6:  the industry. There are definitely some roadblocks to
Speaker 6:  to, to overcome, but I would say we're probably looking at
Speaker 6:  80 to 90% success chance of them actually getting a vehicle to
Speaker 6:  production, I would say. Which, which to me is, is quite high given
Speaker 6:  the I'll
Speaker 2:  I'll take that. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But in terms of the long-term success of, of the company at that point, I,
Speaker 6:  I think it's anybody's guess After that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. Yeah. I mean is there a 90% chance we're all gonna be
Speaker 2:  here in 18 months? Who knows? So I'll take it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, me too.
Speaker 2:  Last thing and then I'm gonna let you go. I is the car nice. Like you've,
Speaker 2:  you've, you've touched it, you've sat in it. I'm so there, there's so
Speaker 2:  much about this that is designed to be, you know, minimalist and cheap and
Speaker 2:  straightforward, but it also, like the whole thing falls apart if it's not
Speaker 2:  like fun to sit inside and drive. Right, right. Is it fun to sit inside?
Speaker 6:  I have not driven the car yet. Yeah. And, and I think that, that, that's
Speaker 6:  the big caveat. But in terms of actually getting in the vehicle, It is actually
Speaker 6:  quite nice. Yeah. The interior is extremely basic as you can imagine. But
Speaker 6:  it's comfortable. I am fairly tall at six feet, but I have short legs,
Speaker 6:  which means I sit very tall, which means I often have a hard time fitting
Speaker 6:  into a lot of cars in terms of headroom, I had no issue at all. You know,
Speaker 6:  there, there's no sunroof here, so that helps. But I had plenty of headroom
Speaker 6:  in there and even I, I got got to sit in one of the SUV configurations of
Speaker 6:  the vehicle and I was shocked that I was actually okay getting in the second
Speaker 6:  row as well. It was a little bit clumsy to get in there, but once I was in
Speaker 6:  there I was pretty comfortable, which was quite surprising to me. So from
Speaker 6:  an overall room comfort standpoint, that that was
Speaker 6:  fine. And even things like the bed, for example, the truck bed is extremely
Speaker 6:  low, which modern trucks F-150 Silverados, the bed height is
Speaker 6:  kind of at chest level almost. Right. If you're loading hay bales in there,
Speaker 6:  that kind of thing, that's very awkward. But yeah, I'm quite comfortable
Speaker 6:  in, in the truck. But the big question is driving that changes everything
Speaker 6:  and I have no idea what it's like to drive yet. In fact, most people at Slate
Speaker 6:  don't either because they haven't done any open road testing. So.
Speaker 2:  Right. And presumably now that it's out there, part
Speaker 2:  of the point of getting it out there, I would assume is to be able to start
Speaker 2:  putting this thing on the road. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They've got a lot of miles ahead of them in cold weather testing, hot weather
Speaker 6:  testing, all sorts of towing conditions, you know, to publish a towing rating
Speaker 6:  in the US requires a lot of regimented testing at, at grade, at
Speaker 6:  high temperatures, that kind of thing. So they've got a lot of work ahead
Speaker 6:  of them over this next 18 months or so. But, but yeah, I think
Speaker 6:  from where they're at right now, things are, things are looking quite good.
Speaker 2:  I'm excited. I, I confess, I am in absolutely no
Speaker 2:  way a truck guy. Like I, I live in, I live in a town home
Speaker 2:  in, in the suburbs of dc Like no one needs a pickup truck less than I do.
Speaker 2:  But I have spent a lot of time looking at this thing over the last few days
Speaker 2:  being like, I, I, I could buy this car.
Speaker 6:  It seems cool. I, I think it solves a lot of problems or it, it offers
Speaker 6:  a lot of aspirational hope for a lot of people who don't want the burden
Speaker 6:  of a giant truck sitting around. But who would like the ability to go, you
Speaker 6:  know, to go to yard sale, to go to an antique shop, to right. To get that
Speaker 6:  kinda stuff, not have to worry about the logistics of a renting a truck or
Speaker 6:  borrowing a truck. And I, I think it'll, it'll find a home for a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  I hope it does. And
Speaker 2:  There does seem to be a thing where people, people want a car to believe
Speaker 2:  in, in a, in a, in a sort of real like human moral way. And this
Speaker 2:  seems to have hit that note pretty well for a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  Right? I think most people right now, if you're car shopping, you kind of
Speaker 6:  pick a car that matches your personality and as we're seeing certain brands
Speaker 6:  are, are changing their personality rather Dr. Dramatically. And so I think
Speaker 6:  people are seeing that that can have a negative impact if you've already
Speaker 6:  owned the car that no longer suits your personality. The idea with Slate
Speaker 6:  is that you can change the car's personality to match yours. You can even
Speaker 6:  go so far as to change the lighting patterns on the nose, which is really
Speaker 6:  kind of like the identification mark of the vehicle is really that nose
Speaker 6:  and slate will let you change anything on there that you want to. So I think
Speaker 6:  this will be something that people can really find personal ownership and
Speaker 6:  commitment too.
Speaker 2:  I love it. Alright, well when you drive it, you're coming back. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about it Sounds
Speaker 6:  Very good. I look
Speaker 2:  Forward to it. Tim Stevens, thank you so much.
Speaker 6:  Thanks David.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a quick break and then we're gonna come back and talk
Speaker 2:  about how to use your phone a little less because I think we could all stand
Speaker 2:  to use our phone a little less. We'll be right back.
Speaker 12:  Yes. I'm Casey Johnston and I'm a writer and editor and
Speaker 12:  author. I have written about tech and health and science
Speaker 12:  my whole career. Started out as a tech blogger, which is how I know David
Speaker 12:  and I have a book coming out next month called A Physical
Speaker 12:  Education that is about my experience getting into lifting weights, the
Speaker 12:  science and psychology thereof. And I
Speaker 12:  write a newsletter called She's a Beast that's about health,
Speaker 12:  strength, body stuff, food stuff, all that good stuff.
Speaker 2:  See that's, I started describing She's a Beast and basically did
Speaker 2:  the same thing. I just started saying words. I was like, so I'm glad to know
Speaker 2:  that that is the official explanation for what she's abuse is.
Speaker 12:  It's, it's difficult to sum up something I, I cover a lot of ground,
Speaker 12:  but it's just like, I promise it's good. So just, you know,
Speaker 12:  see it for yourself if you like it, don't rely on my description, just,
Speaker 12:  just check it out. I like it. And then if it's for you, you'll know when
Speaker 12:  you see it. So I, I trust you.
Speaker 2:  All right. So the reason I have brought you here today is 'cause I think
Speaker 2:  you have done as like thoughtful and complete a
Speaker 2:  sort of excision of your smartphone from your life as anyone I've seen. And
Speaker 2:  I just wanna talk through a bunch of the like process and what has actually
Speaker 2:  worked for you and all of this. But I just, let's, let's rewind a little.
Speaker 2:  You've been writing about this for months now, but
Speaker 2:  like was there an impetus where you were like, I am looking at my phone too
Speaker 2:  much, I need to, I need to quit it with the screen time? Was there like a
Speaker 2:  thing that happened? I
Speaker 12:  Don't know if there was a particular event, but I was getting to
Speaker 12:  a point in the fall of 2023,
Speaker 12:  early 2024, where I just felt like I have no
Speaker 12:  control over how much time goes into this thing.
Speaker 12:  Like it's just disappearing down the hole of my phone
Speaker 12:  screen. And I actually started pulling out old
Speaker 12:  phones like, do you save phones ever?
Speaker 2:  Oh sure. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  I know some people just like get they, they do like the swap program. But
Speaker 12:  I like every once in a while in a cycle I
Speaker 12:  will keep one and not resell it because I break my phones
Speaker 12:  often also like, sure, break, crack the screen and then, and then you're
Speaker 12:  out a phone. So started pulling out my old phones being like,
Speaker 12:  is there some sort of like solution and going backwards
Speaker 12:  somehow? And I was of course reading every, every article that ever
Speaker 12:  came out that was like, I went back to a flip phone and like here's how
Speaker 12:  it went. 'cause I was just like dreaming of having a
Speaker 12:  more, a better handle on this situation. And at
Speaker 12:  one point I popped my sim card into a iPhone four
Speaker 12:  s and it was just like, this is so small and so cute and it like,
Speaker 12:  it's so much, it's like the screen, they're like, the phones are
Speaker 12:  unmanageable large now. And when I put this,
Speaker 12:  the sim card in, it was like, there's something that didn't work. I think
Speaker 12:  phone calls didn't work but it could message and it could do maps and
Speaker 12:  I had no apps installed on it and I was like, this is sort of
Speaker 12:  ideal. Like the key seems to be stepping back. And I noticed that in
Speaker 12:  every flip phone article where people
Speaker 12:  go back to like T nine texting, like they go all the way back, the main
Speaker 12:  things that they miss are group messaging and like the sort of
Speaker 12:  convenience of messages that sync across your devices and the mapping,
Speaker 12:  you know, there's no substitute for Google maps. Totally. You have to like
Speaker 12:  draw yourself a map. Yeah. So I was like, what if I made a
Speaker 12:  version of sort of like make my phone as dumb as I can
Speaker 12:  retain those two important things. 'cause it's like the thing that prevents
Speaker 12:  us from going all the way back to flip phones is basically like those two
Speaker 12:  things occasionally like Uber, stuff like that.
Speaker 2:  Right. It does strike me. It's such a slippery slope though. And I like,
Speaker 2:  'cause I think I, I've been through this too where it's like, okay, the first
Speaker 2:  thing I'm gonna do is just delete all of my apps, right? And it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  well then I'm gonna, I need, I need a couple. And then it's like, oh crap,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna travel. So I, I'll put Uber back and then it's like, oh well I
Speaker 2:  ha I should probably put Ticketmaster back 'cause I'm gonna a concert in
Speaker 2:  a couple weeks and then all of a sudden like 10 days later, all I've done
Speaker 2:  is like a bunch more work to reinstall most of the apps that I already had.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like the, the thing that is like alluring about going back to
Speaker 2:  a piece of junk phone is that it prevents you from doing that. There is this
Speaker 2:  idea that like if you don't wanna use your phone so much, just don't use
Speaker 2:  your phone so much. Just like be disciplined, you jackass. Right? Like be
Speaker 2:  a better person and it'll all be fine. And I feel like this is a thing you
Speaker 2:  think about in, in another part of your life a lot. And I feel like you seem
Speaker 2:  to have brought some of that to your phone where it's like you just, you
Speaker 2:  have a phone that could be more and you just sort of stared at it one day
Speaker 2:  and you were like, I will not let you do it.
Speaker 12:  Right. I mean it's difficult because the
Speaker 12:  technology has insinuated itself
Speaker 12:  in so many ways. Even to the point of,
Speaker 12:  you know, in this article that I wrote, it's like, it's our clock.
Speaker 12:  Like how many times, like we have these stats about like people pick up
Speaker 12:  their phones a hundred times a day, 200 times a day, whatever. But how many
Speaker 12:  of those times am I just trying to see what time It is? Like Hmm. I'm not
Speaker 12:  even necessarily always going
Speaker 12:  to the, well wanting to go on the social media apps.
Speaker 12:  I just wanna find out what time It is. But it's like I go to look at the
Speaker 12:  time and then I have a notification for Instagram. So I check that out and
Speaker 12:  then I'm scrolling the feed and then I'm liking things and
Speaker 12:  then I switch to another app and I'm scrolling that feed and it just sort
Speaker 12:  of like becomes this waterfall situation. And it
Speaker 12:  all got started because I just wanted to know what time it was. Right. So
Speaker 12:  I think I realized the questions that I wanted to ask are like,
Speaker 12:  what are the essential functions? What am I trying to do with this thing?
Speaker 12:  Which of the things are unique offerings to the smartphone
Speaker 12:  is another important question. Mapping technology that is in your pocket.
Speaker 12:  That is a thing that I think that it would be difficult to
Speaker 12:  excise from our lives at this point. But like the clock is not in there,
Speaker 12:  the clock doesn't have to be in there. The clock could be a watch. You know,
Speaker 12:  so there's a sort of like trying to back up
Speaker 12:  and figure out what is truly additive about
Speaker 12:  the smartphone versus where has it inserted itself that
Speaker 12:  it doesn't need to be, was a crucial question for me in this.
Speaker 2:  Was that line pretty obvious for you as you went through it?
Speaker 12:  I think so. I, I think honestly the browser app
Speaker 12:  is on the line where it's like probably 80%
Speaker 12:  of the time I'm in the phones browser. I don't need to be. And
Speaker 12:  I'm just sort of like indulging a curiosity or like
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 12:  Logging into my email, but sometimes I do need it because it's like, oh,
Speaker 12:  I'm at a concert and I was emailed the tickets and I didn't print them
Speaker 12:  out and now I need to go into my email and get the tickets. So
Speaker 12:  I have to kind of hold the line at that point and be like, oh, I could
Speaker 12:  reinstall like an email app and have the whole thing on there. But
Speaker 12:  I try to keep a lot of my activity that used to be
Speaker 12:  through apps in the browser. And then at least you are not
Speaker 12:  setting yourself up for notifications in any way.
Speaker 12:  Hmm.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. Yeah, I mean the, the browser is an interesting one to
Speaker 2:  me. 'cause I think the argument for it in a lot of cases
Speaker 2:  is just, it's just a little more friction. Like, it's a little more annoying
Speaker 2:  to look at social media in a browser than It is in an app.
Speaker 2:  And that that's probably a good thing. Yes. And I think I buy that, but I
Speaker 2:  also, at least in my own life, have discovered that I'm
Speaker 2:  perfectly willing to put up with that friction in order to stare at Twitter
Speaker 2:  on my phone. Like I, I was like, oh, I could use the app or I could use the
Speaker 2:  web app and then once I'm logged into the web app, it's not so much more
Speaker 2:  work that I can just, I'm just gonna go do it. And so I've struggled with
Speaker 2:  the same thing of like, the browser is, it does make my phone worse,
Speaker 2:  but I'm not convinced it makes me use my phone any less. But then
Speaker 2:  without it I'm like, I, I feel lost. Whether that's real or not, I don't
Speaker 2:  know. But I feel, yeah, I feel bad about it.
Speaker 12:  I still try what I used to do pre-phone wipe, which is
Speaker 12:  what I did delete. I just did a factory reset on my
Speaker 12:  phone and then tried to be like super, super, super discerning
Speaker 12:  about what I reinstalled and even like deleted everything that came on.
Speaker 12:  'cause it now comes with a ton of stuff. Yeah. And just tried to move it
Speaker 12:  all away or, or delete the apps or whatever. What I used to do was
Speaker 12:  I try and hide the apps in the other apps. Oh sure. Like
Speaker 12:  if I used an app too much, I would just like hold it down, drag it like
Speaker 12:  10 screens away and plop it there and be like, okay, now I can't find it.
Speaker 2:  And then at least you have to make yourself do like a hilarious amount of
Speaker 2:  work to go open the app. Yes. That comes for something. I, I like that. Or
Speaker 12:  You search, but like that's cheating.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, I I think you should turn all that stuff off. Tell me about
Speaker 2:  the factory reset thing. 'cause that's one thing you recommend that I have
Speaker 2:  not seen other people who have done this experience recommend.
Speaker 2:  So why, why wipe the thing and start over?
Speaker 12:  Yes. So another problem I had was, I would be like, I'm
Speaker 12:  too involved with apps. There are too many apps. They're doing notifications.
Speaker 12:  I can't turn them all off 'cause I don't even, it's like you don't even
Speaker 12:  realize you're getting the notifications and they pop up and they go away
Speaker 12:  and you're like, who bothered me? I can't even remember. So I would try
Speaker 12:  and delete apps one by one, but I had
Speaker 12:  so many apps and then deleting them one by one did not work
Speaker 12:  because every time I would be going through and be like,
Speaker 12:  oh, do I really need to get rid of this? Like, it's not doing
Speaker 12:  anything. It's not hurting me. And then it would, you know, that would repeat
Speaker 12:  for most of the apps and I would only delete like five of them. And it just
Speaker 12:  took so long. So I was like, I just need to start
Speaker 12:  over and let go of all of my
Speaker 12:  archaic apps that don't work anymore as well as the ones that are bothering
Speaker 12:  me. But I'm having trouble articulating like I
Speaker 12:  needed to, I needed tabular Raza, just like go back
Speaker 12:  to zero and let things come back into my life as
Speaker 12:  needed. And being careful about what I let back in.
Speaker 12:  That's scary because also there will be apps
Speaker 12:  that have like data in them and you're not sure if
Speaker 12:  you like got everything out. So I did you
Speaker 12:  wanna do an number urgency backup
Speaker 12:  just in case you do realize, oh shoot, I do have that app that I
Speaker 12:  need things from and I didn't get everything out a bit. The one
Speaker 12:  that you really need to be careful about with this is if you have an authenticator
Speaker 12:  app.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 12:  Make sure you figure out how you're gonna set it up on your new phone
Speaker 12:  because it can, you can just get stuck I think with all of your
Speaker 12:  accounts. So that's a big one. But everything else,
Speaker 12:  most things now are through the cloud. Like you have an account through
Speaker 12:  the app and you just like log back into your account with whatever the app
Speaker 12:  is and then everything you have is there.
Speaker 2:  One of the things you wrote that has stuck with me the most
Speaker 2:  is you like went out of your way to make your phone
Speaker 2:  worse. Which I think is really interesting. 'cause like for me, the thing
Speaker 2:  I've always tried to do is like I put a picture of my kid on my home screen
Speaker 2:  as like a reminder that I should be looking at my kid and it's like,
Speaker 2:  this is, this is more important than my phone. And you're like, no, no, screw
Speaker 2:  that. Make it like black and stupid so that you don't wanna look at it at
Speaker 2:  all. You, you made this switch from like, my phone is this sort of like charming
Speaker 2:  companion that I have that reminds me of things to like, this thing is stupid
Speaker 2:  and boring and I hate it. Yes. And that, that shifting that mindset actually
Speaker 2:  ends up being really useful. Which I had never thought about. But now,
Speaker 2:  and people say this with like making your phone gray scale so that you don't
Speaker 2:  wanna look at it and stuff. And like I have sort of mixed feelings about
Speaker 2:  that. It like kind of works, but it also just makes everything kind of more
Speaker 2:  annoying without much upside in a lot of ways. But the idea
Speaker 2:  of like, what if I just made my phone worse actually strikes me as really
Speaker 2:  compelling.
Speaker 12:  Okay. Yeah. I, yeah, the grayscale thing never really connected for me
Speaker 12:  either. I definitely tried it at some point, but when people first discovered
Speaker 12:  it, when it was like a assistive technology thing
Speaker 12:  maybe. So I remember that and it never, it was like, this doesn't really
Speaker 12:  do anything. But yeah, some of these things come to me like as I'm
Speaker 12:  writing or just like in the middle of doing this. I think when I set up
Speaker 12:  this phone again, I was just like, sure, whatever, default home screen,
Speaker 12:  whatever you do. And then I realized, oh, the phone is
Speaker 12:  really trying to endear itself to you with these like serving you
Speaker 12:  memories through the photos app. And like the, you know, my
Speaker 12:  husband has a, his home screen rotates through photos
Speaker 12:  that are I think are maybe curated by the photos app. And they're always
Speaker 12:  so cute. It's like our baby, our cat, our dog, the two of us.
Speaker 12:  Like, and it's, the way I put it in my article
Speaker 12:  was don't let it wear the skins of your loved ones. 'cause it's like,
Speaker 12:  It is trying to manipulate you. They know what they're doing when
Speaker 12:  they, when they make the phone screen able to be all of your most cherished
Speaker 12:  memories, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Put those somewhere else. Yes. I think is a, is a, is a useful place
Speaker 2:  to be. And speaking of you, another thing you advocated for, and this is
Speaker 2:  a thing I want to talk through a little bit, 'cause this is something I've
Speaker 2:  been sort of intermittently trying, is like, you set yourself up a second
Speaker 2:  device or like a, and, and I think, I think if I have this right, you set
Speaker 2:  up a device that is like always plugged in or like has a, has a
Speaker 2:  place that it lives. And if you want to do some of this other stuff,
Speaker 2:  you have to go to that place to do those things. Is that, am I characterizing
Speaker 2:  that right?
Speaker 12:  Yes, that's correct. I mean, I, so the ideal second device I
Speaker 12:  think is a, is an old former phone.
Speaker 12:  Ideally one that has like no battery life left anymore so that you
Speaker 12:  have to keep it plugged in. See, mine is actually, I keep it at
Speaker 12:  my desk, which you would think is bad, but it really, the phone is so
Speaker 12:  useless. See now it's dead 'cause it wasn't plugged in.
Speaker 12:  But you have a, a second device. This is a iPhone
Speaker 12:  11. Okay. Maybe. And you put all of your
Speaker 12:  problematic apps on there. So for me, one of my big
Speaker 12:  hesitations in going off social media was
Speaker 12:  this is part of my job. Like I work in media, I post on
Speaker 12:  Twitter. I post on Instagram, I have a lot of followers. How will, how will
Speaker 12:  anyone know about what I do if I don't post? So
Speaker 12:  it was very scary to let go of both my
Speaker 12:  ability to post when I felt like I needed to, and also to be able to
Speaker 12:  scroll the feeds in order to see what other people are
Speaker 12:  doing and like how I gotta be on the trends and all these things. So
Speaker 12:  what would happen when I would try and delete, say Instagram from my regular
Speaker 12:  phone is that eventually I would be like, oh,
Speaker 12:  well I gotta redownload it 'cause I have to like message this person. And
Speaker 12:  Right. I'll just, you know, I'll just put it back on my phone and
Speaker 12:  log back in and then, and then you don't wanna delete it again. So what
Speaker 12:  I did was put all of the problem apps on a different
Speaker 12:  phone and that made it, so if I had some
Speaker 12:  sort of Instagram task that I thought I had to do,
Speaker 12:  I would have to sit down in the
Speaker 12:  phone spot with my phone. That only works.
Speaker 12:  I mean this because it has no sim card, it only works on wifi and
Speaker 12:  it would be a sort of discreet task in a location on a specific device.
Speaker 12:  And what ended up happening was that I
Speaker 12:  just sort of stopped posting. Like I, I, it
Speaker 12:  completely did away for me the temptation because most of the scrolling
Speaker 12:  I did, I think honestly was not, I do a lot of scrolling at home,
Speaker 12:  but removing it from the couch where I usually do it or
Speaker 12:  like in in bed before I go to bed, or when I wake up in the morning
Speaker 12:  and having it be in a specific, somewhat uncomfortable location
Speaker 12:  or a location where, like at my desk I'm usually kind of busy doing other
Speaker 12:  stuff that broke the pattern for me at
Speaker 12:  least. And I was never really tempted to reinstall
Speaker 12:  Instagram when I knew it was already installed and logged in and everything
Speaker 12:  on this phone that's like usually only 10 to 40 feet
Speaker 12:  away from wherever I am in my house. 'cause my house isn't that big. So
Speaker 12:  I was able to just offload that little piece of
Speaker 12:  like, mental weight onto this other device. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  That's really smart. And now the result has been that I barely use this
Speaker 12:  phone Yeah. At all. So,
Speaker 2:  Which is, I would argue the correct outcome. I've, I've tried offloading
Speaker 2:  all that stuff to an iPad at, at various
Speaker 2:  points, which works.
Speaker 12:  I've heard of people doing the tablet. Yeah. It
Speaker 2:  Works for everything except social media apps because social media, like
Speaker 2:  those apps are trash on iPads, which is a problem. I've also tried to do
Speaker 2:  it on my computer, which kind of works and sort of applies to that same like,
Speaker 2:  it's in a place thing. But I really like the idea of just having a, having
Speaker 2:  a problem phone that like lives far away from where I normally am.
Speaker 2:  Yes. When I, or and, and that's, I, I like this a lot. But the, the social
Speaker 2:  media thing is one of the things I wanted to ask you about because I feel
Speaker 2:  like the, the through line of a lot of the stuff you've written about this
Speaker 2:  is that kind of quitting your phone and quitting social media,
Speaker 2:  I think are ki like, were like kind of the same thing in your experience
Speaker 2:  or at least like fed each other in a really interesting way. Like if you
Speaker 2:  quit social media, have you effectively quit your phone?
Speaker 12:  Well, it's like what do you do on your phone that is
Speaker 12:  problematic and addictive? That's not social media.
Speaker 12:  You could one, one could do, you know, I don't know, you could be
Speaker 12:  really invested in like Clash of Clans or something. Sure, yeah. If
Speaker 12:  you're like spending a lot of money and like a lot of hours and
Speaker 12:  trying to accumulate resources on there. But that's not the problem
Speaker 12:  I have. I think for me they're pretty one to one. What
Speaker 12:  draws you in is on your phone is the question. For me, it was a lot of
Speaker 12:  social media, but it wasn't always, sometimes what draws me in is like a
Speaker 12:  New York Times push alert, which they treat very
Speaker 12:  irresponsibly sometimes it's really breaking news. Every
Speaker 2:  C list actor who dies. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Sometimes it's breaking news and sometimes it's like a recipe and it's like,
Speaker 12:  okay, come on. And I, I'm susceptible to the recipe,
Speaker 12:  you know, so this is like how they get you
Speaker 12:  is that you turn on the push alerts because what if
Speaker 12:  I miss something? What if breaking news happens
Speaker 12:  and I am not aware of it? And then you have to leave them on and then you're
Speaker 12:  getting the recipes and you're getting the breaking news. So it's like,
Speaker 12:  I think part of the what had to be let go
Speaker 12:  was the notion of like, if there's breaking news, if
Speaker 12:  I will find out in a way that's not like gonna
Speaker 12:  ultimately
Speaker 12:  hamper me in my life, like what could I find out from my phone
Speaker 12:  that I need to know right this second that I won't find out eventually.
Speaker 12:  And that was difficult for me coming from a news background as I'm sure
Speaker 12:  you also feel where it's like, you feel like you gotta
Speaker 12:  know everything as soon as possible because you gotta like come up with
Speaker 12:  your takes or whatever. And not everyone's in that position and I'm not
Speaker 12:  in that position anymore. I think we've gotten to the point where we feel
Speaker 12:  like, well if we can know as soon as possible we should. And that is not
Speaker 12:  true at all. And I think, no, I've tried to encourage more people lately
Speaker 12:  to at least consider trying, seeing
Speaker 12:  what it's like if you don't find out about
Speaker 12:  everything right away. It feels problematic to
Speaker 12:  encourage people to know less in our world right now.
Speaker 12:  And I understand the objections to that, but I think
Speaker 12:  you should feel encouraged to control that
Speaker 12:  flow a little bit more. And you might not realize
Speaker 12:  how much, you still know how much you'll still be apprised of what's going
Speaker 12:  on without feeling like you need to be like an open,
Speaker 12:  just like lying back and letting everything like wash over
Speaker 12:  you constantly. Right.
Speaker 2:  Which I think is pretty clearly a and not necessary for
Speaker 2:  most people. And b, not healthy. Like, it just
Speaker 2:  overwhelmingly the feeling I get is that like the, the thing where we all
Speaker 2:  feel like we need to know everything immediately all the time. It is just,
Speaker 2:  it's just bad. Yes. Like it's just unhealthy in ways that I think we're only
Speaker 2:  beginning to fully understand.
Speaker 12:  Right. Right. It's like you can take seriously all
Speaker 12:  of the data that's come out on this and the research, it's like,
Speaker 12:  and there have not been a lot of redeeming studies
Speaker 12:  science about screens and like social media.
Speaker 12:  And I think we can, you know, even what I'm describing is not like
Speaker 12:  throwing the entire thing in the trash and like living in the woods. Like
Speaker 12:  you're still in the, in the world and you're still gonna get information,
Speaker 12:  but you're allowed to control that relationship.
Speaker 12:  You should feel empowered to control it a little bit more.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think that's, I think that's exactly right. How long did that adjustment
Speaker 2:  take for you? Because I think the, the struggle I've had candidly
Speaker 2:  is like, I will, I will try these things. I'll run the experiment and it
Speaker 2:  feels really bad for three days and like weird.
Speaker 2:  And I'm like, okay, I'm not actually solving any problems here, am I? Maybe
Speaker 2:  this is just, maybe I'm not doing anything better here. I'll just go back
Speaker 2:  to installing all my apps. It'll be fine. And like somehow I end up on Reddit
Speaker 2:  again. You know what I mean? So I'm like, what, what did it
Speaker 2:  take for you to kind of get through that first hurdle? Was there even that
Speaker 2:  first hurdle?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, there definitely was a hurdle. I
Speaker 12:  remember in the first few days, like so many moments of
Speaker 12:  experiencing some like mild discomfort of
Speaker 12:  I'm not being entertained right now. I'm like in the line at the grocery
Speaker 12:  store or I'm like, you know, I was, I think I was at a basketball game
Speaker 12:  and nothing was happening in the basketball game. And I was like, well,
Speaker 12:  I'm gonna pull up my phone and scroll Instagram. Oh wait, it's not there.
Speaker 2:  Did you do a lot of picking up your phone and realizing you had picked it
Speaker 2:  up for absolutely no reason? Yes.
Speaker 12:  Oh yeah. Yeah. Oh yeah. I was pulling it out and looking at it and opening
Speaker 12:  it and being like, there's nothing here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Those are the moments I feel like a true lunatic where I'm like, I,
Speaker 2:  this is for nothing. I just, this is a pure like addictive response that
Speaker 2:  I just had. Yes. To grab my phone that didn't make a noise and has nothing
Speaker 2:  for me. No, but I'm just looking at it now.
Speaker 12:  Yep. Oh yeah. It feels bad. And it's also like,
Speaker 12:  there's the, there's the pit of like, oh, well what am I gonna do now?
Speaker 12:  I have nothing to do. Which is like, we used to
Speaker 12:  live, like you and I are old enough to remember, you
Speaker 12:  know, there are people who have not lived in a world, this makes me
Speaker 12:  feel so sad and crazy. There are people who are like adults,
Speaker 12:  full adults now who have never lived in a world without smartphones.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. We're both in our nineties now. Yes. Just so everyone
Speaker 12:  Know, we're a hundred years old and we remember the Telegraph. So It is
Speaker 12:  like, you know, this has been a lot of change for us, but seriously, we
Speaker 12:  remember being, you know, if you were, if you had nothing to do, you just
Speaker 12:  sat there, you know, which feels silly to say or you just sort of
Speaker 12:  watched what was going on around you. So that was part of my, like
Speaker 12:  rehabilitation too was like, I mean, especially for me, I
Speaker 12:  work from home, so I have a lot of control over my schedule
Speaker 12:  and like where I go in a way. But that also means that
Speaker 12:  I'm not even like in the world that much. So when I get to be out in the
Speaker 12:  world, I try to be like, you know what? I'm out in the world. Be in the
Speaker 12:  world. Don't be on your phone.
Speaker 2:  What do you do when you're waiting in line at the grocery store? Now?
Speaker 12:  I look around, I watch people, you know, see,
Speaker 2:  This is the problem. I honestly, this is, this is gonna really make me sound
Speaker 2:  like a terrible person. But I hate that answer. Like, there's just something
Speaker 2:  about that that is like, there's so many things where I'm like, okay. I'm
Speaker 2:  like, I should be hanging out with my family instead of
Speaker 2:  looking at my phone. Fully agree. I should be driving instead of looking
Speaker 2:  at my phone. Fully agree. Right. Like there's a million things where I think
Speaker 2:  It is like an unequivocally good thing, but then I'm like, is It, is it okay
Speaker 2:  to look at my phone while I'm standing in line at Starbucks? Like
Speaker 2:  intellectually no. But like also, yes, I don't know.
Speaker 2:  And, and this is, this is where I'm like, okay, well I'll just keep this
Speaker 2:  one app on my phone just to look at while I'm in line at the grocery store.
Speaker 2:  And then the whole thing falls apart. So it's like, maybe you do just have
Speaker 2:  to draw the line somewhere past in line at the grocery store.
Speaker 2:  But I don't know, like it's, it's so boring waiting in line.
Speaker 12:  Well,
Speaker 2:  I mean, we solved that problem.
Speaker 12:  I think that's great. Yes. So part of the problem is like, you're just like,
Speaker 12:  I'm bored, I'm bored, I'm bored. What do I do if I'm bored? I need, I need,
Speaker 12:  I, I can't be bored. And, but I think you do need to
Speaker 12:  be bored. I think I found like
Speaker 12:  even just doing a couple sessions of pre deleting everything
Speaker 12:  from my phone where I would be like, I'm gonna just like hard
Speaker 12:  line, put my phone down, go outside without my phone
Speaker 12:  and just sit there and just sit there and
Speaker 12:  just like, try and be without my phone for like 30 minutes and be without
Speaker 12:  anything. Be don't, don't be entertained. You know? And I would do
Speaker 12:  that and at first it would be like, you know, something could be happening
Speaker 12:  on my phone right now and I don't know about it. Yeah. And this is very
Speaker 12:  uncomfortable. But then after I sat there for 10,
Speaker 12:  15 minutes and it would get to like 45 minutes, it'd be like, okay, I'm
Speaker 12:  having like literally so many thoughts.
Speaker 2:  You kind of forget what it's like. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  I'm thinking of so many things. Having, I, for me, having
Speaker 12:  ideas is huge. I need idea. My, my business thrives on
Speaker 12:  ideas, you know, having so many ideas and it
Speaker 12:  sounds stupid, but like that's sort of the point is that it's not
Speaker 12:  supposed to either sound awesome or
Speaker 12:  like legible even to anyone but me. I'm just
Speaker 12:  like having an experience. I'm in my own head
Speaker 12:  thinking about stuff. Like, I think we need that time to sort of like,
Speaker 12:  it's almost like what sleep does for us, where it's like we need time to
Speaker 12:  sort of like, let the thoughts tumble. It's like a, what are those things?
Speaker 12:  Like a rock, like a rock Tumblr. Sure. It's, it's sort of, we're putting
Speaker 12:  the, the raw craggy rocks in and smoothing 'em out just by
Speaker 12:  giving them time to roll around in there. And I think we
Speaker 12:  need that some time to just sort of let our eyes go out of
Speaker 12:  focus and just have that time. So that, that
Speaker 12:  was like a useful experiment. I think at one point was to
Speaker 12:  allow myself in a comfortable place. Like I was in my own home,
Speaker 12:  not in a grocery line. I
Speaker 2:  Feel like you're describing like your first acid trip where you're like,
Speaker 2:  I had, I had a, I had a spiritual guy.
Speaker 12:  It's like, honestly not that different from, from that where it's like,
Speaker 12:  oh, there are you, your brain. There's so much going on in there
Speaker 12:  and you don't realize. 'cause you're always trying to like push it down
Speaker 12:  with everything that's going on in your phone. That,
Speaker 12:  I don't know, there were just, it was like I had a backlog of stuff to sort
Speaker 12:  of percolate. That's how it felt. I was like, oh, I've so much to think
Speaker 12:  about that I haven't gotten a chance to think about. And like, how am I
Speaker 12:  gonna, I don't know, do this thing or what should
Speaker 12:  I, how should I approach this like, topic or,
Speaker 12:  oh, I forgot this person said this thing to me that was crazy. What do,
Speaker 12:  what really did I think about that? 'cause it happened sort of in passing
Speaker 12:  and I didn't have time to sort of process it.
Speaker 12:  So I recall that feeling pretty, pretty vividly. So I think if
Speaker 12:  you like, are interested in experimenting with this, that might be a good
Speaker 12:  thing to try is like, put your phone away, separate
Speaker 12:  yourself from it for, you don't have to do a really length, big
Speaker 12:  length of time. You could do like 15 minutes or something and just sort
Speaker 12:  of give yourself a little space and see what happens. See what
Speaker 12:  comes from that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's a good one. How long did it take before you stopped checking
Speaker 2:  your phone? When nothing was going on?
Speaker 12:  Okay, good question. I think it was three days. Sounds
Speaker 12:  kind of like, okay, a good, that, that feels
Speaker 12:  about right in terms of like how long it took to stop, like
Speaker 12:  pulling it out of my pocket as a reflex. But I think
Speaker 12:  I can like, just, just because it makes you feel so dumb to do so.
Speaker 12:  But I think I still felt that discomfort and urge of like, I'm,
Speaker 12:  I am like bored and I wish I had something
Speaker 12:  to do and I have nothing to do. Hmm.
Speaker 12:  And that took a little longer. I don't know.
Speaker 12:  I think I still feel that way sometimes. So It is like a kind of
Speaker 12:  boundary you have to have with yourself in a way. Like when we
Speaker 12:  have, there's just always, we're so used to having a lever to pull,
Speaker 12:  to entertain us and take us out of ourselves. So it's kind of
Speaker 12:  like an active ongoing negotiation.
Speaker 12:  I can tell you from my life experience that I've
Speaker 12:  gotten a lot out of trying to
Speaker 12:  be more deliberate about those types of patterns. Hmm. It is a
Speaker 12:  pattern that is deserving of your like attention and
Speaker 12:  energy. I think, I think if you do give yourself the space
Speaker 12:  to stay with yourself in those moments, you will find
Speaker 12:  it pays off. You know, if you love using your phone and you don't have
Speaker 12:  a held healthy relationship with it, then it's like, fine, go be yourself.
Speaker 12:  This is for me who has an unhealthy relationship
Speaker 12:  with it. Right. And for anyone else who does, who wants it to be different,
Speaker 12:  you know? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which is, that's, I'm, I am also very much one of those people. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think for me it's, it's, I, the factory reset thing is very compelling
Speaker 2:  that I'm like, maybe it's just I'm just gonna do a full start over
Speaker 2:  and just see how far I could get. And that feels like, because the, the
Speaker 2:  next phase in my own journey, I've like, I've hit the point now where I,
Speaker 2:  I charge my phone in a room that isn't my bedroom, which is itself a victory.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Good, good, good first step. Very much enjoying that. Very good. And
Speaker 2:  the next step was like, what if I just delete all of my apps? And now I'm
Speaker 2:  like, nevermind, I'm just gonna factory reset my phone and start from there.
Speaker 2:  Because actually it'll, it'll feel better that way.
Speaker 12:  What else have you tried? I think I saw you tried the light phone. Maybe
Speaker 2:  I've tried the light phone. That, that one's tricky because for like a bunch
Speaker 2:  of wireless carrier reasons, I can't just like put my number on the phone
Speaker 2:  and then iMessage a break and it would be a whole thing. Yeah. So I can't
Speaker 2:  fully commit to the light phone life, even though I think it's actually,
Speaker 2:  it's like very close to being,
Speaker 12:  Yeah. See, this is the problem is that they're all just like a little bit
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Off in significant ways.
Speaker 2:  It's like two apps away from being the right thing for me. But those two
Speaker 2:  apps turn out to be very important.
Speaker 2:  I think that for me, it's actually very funny. So I, I am perpetually like
Speaker 2:  needing to test new phones and as you were talking about the second phone
Speaker 2:  idea, I'm like, oh, I'm gonna keep the iPhone as my like normal phone. And
Speaker 2:  then I'm gonna just like cycle in Android phones as my like problem apps
Speaker 2:  phone. Okay. And this actually solves a bunch of like, work problems for
Speaker 2:  me. Okay, good. While also meaning I just like take
Speaker 2:  Instagram off of my phone and put it somewhere else. There you go. The thing
Speaker 2:  I, I just like an hour before we got on here, bought the
Speaker 2:  brick. I don't know if you've seen this, the, the thing. So it's like a little
Speaker 2:  NFC device and you tap your phone on it and it locks you out of everything.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God. Except the apps that you've decided are allowed and you have to
Speaker 2:  go back to it to unlock it. Okay. And I think there's like, there's something
Speaker 2:  very powerful in that to me that it's like, have you ever been to the concert
Speaker 2:  where you get like the, the yonder case that they put your phone in?
Speaker 12:  I've heard of this. Or they have them for like schools now I think too.
Speaker 12:  Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I got, I, the only time I've had it happen was at a John Mullaney
Speaker 2:  show. For some reason John Mullaney, like didn't want us to record him doing
Speaker 2:  his. Oh, right,
Speaker 12:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  And so they put it in the bag and I was sitting there holding the bag and
Speaker 2:  at first I was like mad at the bag, but by the end of the concert I was like,
Speaker 2:  this is great. Like, I have the thing that actively prevents me, like a person
Speaker 2:  has to allow me to use my phone again. And there was something wonderful
Speaker 2:  about that. So I'm like, how can I outsource this
Speaker 2:  challenge a little bit? Yeah. And that's, that's the next thing on my list.
Speaker 2:  So we'll, we'll see how that one goes for me.
Speaker 12:  Okay. The brick. I'm gonna have to look into this. Yeah. I've like opened
Speaker 12:  the page for the light phone and like the books, various
Speaker 12:  books, devices so many times being like, is this the answer?
Speaker 12:  And I think ultimately I was like, it just isn't. Or I think
Speaker 12:  it will have issues along the lines of like, maps, maps don't work
Speaker 12:  or you can't transfer your phone number or something. And then that's always,
Speaker 12:  that's such a killer. It's, or or like with a flip phone too, it's like,
Speaker 12:  I would love to just have a flip phone again. But then it breaks too
Speaker 12:  many things about how we live our lives now I feel like. All right.
Speaker 2:  I gotta let you go here, but plug your book and then we're gonna go.
Speaker 12:  Oh yes. Okay. So I have a book coming out next month. It's called A Physical
Speaker 12:  Education. Please Buy It. It's really good. If you've ever thought about
Speaker 12:  like, if you've, if you've ever hated your relationship with
Speaker 12:  exercise or food or your body, this book is for you. I promise.
Speaker 12:  It will, it will be very, it'll be satisfying to read I
Speaker 12:  think in a lot of ways for somebody like that, which
Speaker 12:  might be a lot of your listeners or, so I hope
Speaker 2:  It, it's, I I suspect so. Yeah, we'll put the link in the show notes.
Speaker 2:  Casey, thank you. This is so much fun.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  take a question from The Vergecast hotline. It's about laptops and It
Speaker 2:  is causing me a lot of feelings. We'll get into it. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, let's get to a question from The Vergecast hotline
Speaker 2:  as always. The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. You can email Vergecast at
Speaker 2:  The Verge dot com. We love all of your questions. Antonio de Benedetto is
Speaker 2:  here to help me with this one. Hi Antonio.
Speaker 17:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  I I have a question for you that I think seems easy but is
Speaker 2:  going to be sneakily complicated and may take us a very long time to come
Speaker 2:  to an answer. It's from our email. Lemme just read it. It comes from
Speaker 2:  rab. It says, I'm usually the gadget recommendation guy amongst my friends
Speaker 2:  and family. And I'm also a Mac user. The MacBook Air has been my go-to laptop
Speaker 2:  recommendation for years, but some of my friends insist on having Windows.
Speaker 2:  I was wondering if there's any consensus at The Verge about what the go-to
Speaker 2:  rock solid Windows laptop recommendation is. Is it surface? Is it whatever
Speaker 2:  Dell is calling their XPS line Now? Is it an HP Envy? Is it semi
Speaker 2:  seus? I have no idea. Antonio. I also have no idea.
Speaker 2:  I realize this reading, this email, I literally don't know even where to
Speaker 2:  start with this question. So let's, you're you're here to help. Let's, let's
Speaker 2:  help sir here.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I'm happy to help. It's unfortunately a more complicated
Speaker 17:  answer than it should be. But the good news is there are a lot of
Speaker 17:  good answers. Okay. It's just that there's no good answer for like everyone
Speaker 17:  like there is with the MacBook gar.
Speaker 2:  No, I reject this premise. We're not doing this. No, no, no, no, no. You
Speaker 2:  can't, you can't do the thing where you're like, okay, I'm gonna ask you
Speaker 2:  a thousand follow up questions. We, we have to arrive at, at an answer at
Speaker 2:  the end of this. And I think this is a useful exercise, honestly, because
Speaker 2:  for a long time it was just the XPS 13, right? Like it's would you agree
Speaker 2:  with that? That for a bunch of years it was like, if you just want a very
Speaker 2:  good Windows laptop, and I don't have to ask you any follow up questions,
Speaker 2:  it's probably the XPS 13,
Speaker 17:  I think for a while it was, and then they ruined the keyboard. And I think
Speaker 17:  a keyboard is kind of important for a laptop. 'cause it's kind of like one
Speaker 17:  of the main ways you use it. What is
Speaker 2:  Dell doing? Yeah, when you say ruin the keyboard, what, what
Speaker 2:  do you mean?
Speaker 17:  All right, so it's, it, it may come down to taste, I know some people may
Speaker 17:  be fine with it, but they use what they call like a lattice list keyboard.
Speaker 17:  It's basically a keyboard that's like gapless right between the keys
Speaker 17:  and it looks very nice and then you touch it and it feels
Speaker 17:  awful. And I make so many more typos. I use the XV 13
Speaker 17:  a ton and I, I, I was not happy to give it such a
Speaker 17:  bad review, but I just found that it, the, the keyboard was just a nightmare.
Speaker 17:  But that's, that, that used to be a really good go-to option. Now at maybe,
Speaker 17:  maybe Dell will recover itself once it, you know, starts releasing them
Speaker 17:  under like Dell Pro Premium plus max whatever,
Speaker 17:  if we can, I'll ignore the names when the laptops deliver, you know, what
Speaker 17:  they used to deliver.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's you, you can get away with having stupid names when you have
Speaker 2:  good laptops. So the answer right now I think is not the XPS 13, I will say
Speaker 2:  a a useful thing to do is probably go see if you can like type on one in
Speaker 2:  a store.
Speaker 2:  And It is, 'cause there are probably people who will not hate this keyboard.
Speaker 2:  I agree with you. I think the gapless keyboards in general I find unusable,
Speaker 2:  but it's like, if it works for you, fine. Knock yourself out. What
Speaker 2:  else even might go on the list of like just sort of
Speaker 2:  default recommendation laptops right now.
Speaker 17:  Okay, so I know you're not gonna like this, but I I, I come up with three.
Speaker 17:  Okay. And the reason there are three is because see in the Mac world it's
Speaker 17:  obviously easy. It's m chipps all around, right? And
Speaker 17:  as like David, you always say like, buy the, the best thing you can afford
Speaker 17:  and it'll last you how however long. So I think a lot of Windows
Speaker 17:  laptops are competitive and good in that
Speaker 17:  thousand to $1,300 range. And I think it really comes down to your
Speaker 17:  use case based on the chips that are in there. For example, the
Speaker 17:  Microsoft Surface Laptop seventh Edition or just Surface laptop seven, if
Speaker 17:  you wanna just call it that for shorthand. That's Microsoft's answer
Speaker 17:  to the MacBook Air. It is a very MacBook Air, like Windows laptop
Speaker 17:  comes in some nice colors even it's very thin and light. It's got a
Speaker 17:  Snapdragon X processor. That's a blessing and a curse because
Speaker 17:  the blessing is that you get MacBook air levels of battery life
Speaker 17:  standby time and that's one of like the MacBook Air's like
Speaker 17:  strongest points. But with the Snapdragon X, you're also,
Speaker 17:  you're running Windows on arm, which is so much more fine than it used to
Speaker 17:  be. But it's not like you can just give this to
Speaker 17:  anyone and it's gonna use work for every use case. There are some apps that
Speaker 17:  may not be compatible. There are of course games that are not compatible.
Speaker 17:  I know if anyone's hearing this like, oh, like who's gaming on a thin light
Speaker 17:  laptop? But you know what? Thin light laptops can do a little light gaming
Speaker 17:  just like a MacBook Air can do a little very, very light gaming and
Speaker 2:  There is something to the, like it will just run all the things that
Speaker 2:  I need it to run. Right? Like, and I, I think exactly to some extent, the
Speaker 2:  thing for me with the Surface laptop is I think if it's not the right thing
Speaker 2:  for you, you probably already know if that makes sense. Like there there
Speaker 2:  is this gigantically long, long tail of software that will
Speaker 2:  not work well on that computer. But like if you just, if if you just wanna
Speaker 2:  like run a browser most of the time, which I think is frankly what most people
Speaker 2:  do on most of their computers, it's gonna be fine. So I think that
Speaker 2:  one is an interesting one for me where I think most people will sort of
Speaker 2:  self-select in or out of that. But it also kills me that Windows on
Speaker 2:  arm is like, it's, it's so close, but it's not there yet. It's so close.
Speaker 17:  But yeah. Then, okay, so another option with an A
Speaker 17:  MD chip. I just reviewed this, the new Framework, Laptop 13,
Speaker 17:  the new model with the Ryzen AI 300 series chips.
Speaker 17:  This is, I'd say the most charming laptop around.
Speaker 17:  It's also a very, very good laptop. And it may seem
Speaker 17:  daunting to recommend this to someone because it's a, it's repairable,
Speaker 17:  it's modular, it, it, you know, it it, you can get it as a DIY addition,
Speaker 17:  which I do recommend to people if you, you know, feel comfortable
Speaker 17:  like putting it together, but you're not, I mean you're just plugging in
Speaker 17:  the ram and like putting in the SSD and that's been like
Speaker 17:  attaching a couple things. It's really, really simple. I had it, I I took
Speaker 17:  like 20 minutes to do that or less. It took longer to install windows, but
Speaker 17:  you can get it as a prebuilt for a little more money and it comes ready
Speaker 17:  to go. There's no window. The windows is already installed and yeah, it's
Speaker 17:  a no nonsense laptop. It's very good. It's very MacBook Air like. But the
Speaker 17:  coolest thing, this is so cool. You pick the ports, right?
Speaker 17:  You get four ports and you pick the expansion cards that you want for it.
Speaker 17:  You can do all four USBC, you can do two
Speaker 17:  USBC an HDMI and A-U-S-B-A. You can do a micro
Speaker 17:  SD if you want. You can do an ethernet jack. Like that's so cool. And you
Speaker 17:  don't get that. I mean, ethernet port kind of sticks out 'cause it's, you
Speaker 17:  know, it's a thin, it's this thin and light laptop, but you don't normally
Speaker 17:  get that on a thin light laptop. You normally need like a beefy gaming laptop
Speaker 17:  to get an ethernet jack. And that could be kind of helpful. Battery life
Speaker 17:  is like, not the best, but it's pretty good. I think you can get through
Speaker 17:  a day of work and maybe if you work it blow too hard, you might have to,
Speaker 17:  you know, keep it juiced up. But I, I know a lot of people do work plugged
Speaker 17:  in anyway and yeah, it's just, it's a very good laptop.
Speaker 17:  It's also just so freaking cool to pick your ports. You can even do some
Speaker 17:  customizations, like have a translucent bezel that you can install and it's
Speaker 17:  like it's magnetic. It just like drops in and out. Very cool. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So I did not expect to find that a compelling possibility
Speaker 2:  here, but I like that a lot. So what's what's your third one?
Speaker 17:  Okay, so my third one is the ACE or Swift 14 ai.
Speaker 17:  It's not the prettiest laptop, it's not the, the quality
Speaker 17:  overall is quite fine. It's nothing that's really gonna blow you away like
Speaker 17:  a MacBook Air or even like the Surface, but it's a very
Speaker 17:  function over form laptop. The screen is just, okay, it's a, it's a
Speaker 17:  1920 by 1200 P screen. Nothing special there. But what It is nice
Speaker 17:  about this is the, the balance of performance and the ports. You get two
Speaker 17:  USBC and two USBA and an HDMI out on
Speaker 17:  a 14 inch laptop that's pretty small, pretty compact. Again, not as
Speaker 17:  compact as a MacBook Air, but it's a thin and light and the
Speaker 17:  lunar like chip gets the job done. You can, you know, do pretty much everything
Speaker 17:  you need with it. It's a good performer. It doesn't benchmark as high
Speaker 17:  as a MD stuff, but it doesn't last quite as long. Battery lifewise as
Speaker 17:  as Snapdragon, but it's kind of a Goldilocks, it's kind of, well that's
Speaker 17:  just, just the right balance. And actually Lunar light can do some
Speaker 17:  decent gaming for integrated graphics. Not counting like
Speaker 17:  strict halo, which is like a different beast Sure. For integrated
Speaker 17:  graphics. But yeah, that's a, that's a solid all arounder
Speaker 17:  happy medium and a, a decent laptop.
Speaker 2:  I just Googled this by the way, and It is the most boring laptop I've ever
Speaker 2:  seen in my life. And I kind of mean that as a compliment, right? Like I,
Speaker 2:  I've,
Speaker 17:  Yeah, it's not compelling. I've
Speaker 2:  Come around to like, I don't actually need my laptop to be like thrilling
Speaker 2:  and have new ideas about how things should look like. Just give me
Speaker 2:  a decent looking set of ports and a body that
Speaker 2:  doesn't feel like it's about to fall apart and, and we're cool. And I think
Speaker 2:  for a long time, Acer failed the make it not feel like it's about
Speaker 2:  to fall apart test, but it sounds like this one's a little better. They,
Speaker 2:  they've like, they've learned how to make a solid thing even if
Speaker 2:  they don't know how to design anything. Yeah,
Speaker 17:  Yeah. It's, again, it's not attractive, but it's, it's kind of just fine
Speaker 17:  all around decent keyboard, decent track pad, you know, and those things
Speaker 17:  are important of course. And then if you can spend a little more
Speaker 17:  check out the Asus Aser, but Asus Zen book S
Speaker 17:  14, we've reviewed the 16 inch version, which had the rise
Speaker 17:  in AI chip, which is an awesome machine, but much pricier.
Speaker 17:  But the Zen Book S 14 comes the lunar lake chip from Intel.
Speaker 17:  And it's much more felt and very nice looking,
Speaker 17:  a lot more of a design object than especially the Acer.
Speaker 17:  And you get an old lid screen, that's a really nice panel to look at. So
Speaker 17:  if you can spend a little more and you still want that happy medium with
Speaker 17:  a lunar lake chip, then yeah, send bug S 14.
Speaker 17:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  This is a good
Speaker 17:  List. I snuck in a fourth. Sorry. No,
Speaker 2:  This, this is a really good list and I think both speaks
Speaker 2:  to how sort of interesting the Windows landscape is right now, but also how
Speaker 2:  very confusing the Windows landscape is right now. Because it, it's, you're
Speaker 2:  probably right that there are a bunch of like chip reasons actually that
Speaker 2:  it's really hard to have one single pat answer to this question.
Speaker 2:  There's just so much up in the air about sort of which of these
Speaker 2:  configurations is the correct Windows path forward. And my
Speaker 2:  guess is we'll have a much clearer sense of that in like 18 months than
Speaker 2:  we do right now. But especially with Qualcomm and the co-pilot plus PC
Speaker 2:  universe, that all just feels very new and interesting. But not,
Speaker 2:  not quite finished yet, but we asked for one
Speaker 2:  answer. I think I know which of the four I if like, if I'm standing in a
Speaker 2:  store and I'm like, just buy this one and, and leave me alone. To me, I think,
Speaker 2:  I think the answer is actually the Framework Laptop. It is the easiest to
Speaker 2:  like undo the decision. If you've made it, you can just like put in new ports,
Speaker 2:  it'll upgrade over time. It'll last a long time. People really love it.
Speaker 2:  I haven't used the, the keyboard on the new ones in, in a while, but I keep
Speaker 2:  hearing good things. Like this is a terrific computer. Would we be crazy
Speaker 2:  to just call that the, the sort of MacBook Air of the Windows ecosystem for
Speaker 2:  very different reasons. But it does feel like if I'm just gonna give you
Speaker 2:  a computer, I'm pretty confident you're gonna like, that feels like a good
Speaker 2:  place to start.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I think, I think it's, I'm fine with saying that it's, the framework
Speaker 17:  is a great laptop and yeah, it's just the, the keyboard is good.
Speaker 17:  It's a little, the, the it key feel is a littles fungi than I like, but
Speaker 17:  it's great to type on Trackpad is, I think
Speaker 17:  good, but you know, it, it feels a little cheaper than some other trackpads.
Speaker 17:  It's not, it's not the fanciness that, you know, apple has to, in my opinion,
Speaker 17:  apple has the best track pads, the haptic track pads from Apple are
Speaker 17:  really still the best. Right? As long as you don't mind that it
Speaker 17:  doesn't physically click. I've gotten used to it over the years, I'm fine
Speaker 17:  with it. Yeah, the Framework Laptop is a, is a good all arounder.
Speaker 17:  And again, just picking the ports is so cool. And having something that
Speaker 17:  you can feasibly get repaired or repair yourself
Speaker 17:  more easily and replace, I mean, you can upgrade the ram, you can upgrade
Speaker 17:  your SSD later. You can yeah, change your mind on the ports. You can, you
Speaker 17:  can bring an extra port with you. That's just kind of weird, you know, like
Speaker 17:  it's, you can't do that anywhere else. So yeah, I, I don't mind it being
Speaker 17:  the, the recommendation even if it's got a little asterisk of like, you
Speaker 17:  may have to do some my tea or maybe, maybe some little bit of a weird pick.
Speaker 17:  But it's, it's a cool ass laptop.
Speaker 2:  All right, Antonio, thank you. Appreciate it. So Rob, I hope that helped.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for the first cast today. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  came on the show and thank you as always for listening. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  questions, feelings, other features on the Slate Truck that you would like
Speaker 2:  to see, please tell us about everything. I, I truly, there has not been
Speaker 2:  a thing I have been as fascinated by as the Slate Truck in particular in
Speaker 2:  a long time. Email Vergecast at the first.com call the hotline.
Speaker 2:  Eight six six VERGE one one. Also, I'm running a bunch of experiments on
Speaker 2:  myself about how to use my phone less. So if you have a tip or
Speaker 2:  a trick or a gadget or an app that has really worked for you in managing
Speaker 2:  your screen time, I wanna hear all about it. Send us an email, call the hotline,
Speaker 2:  hit us up. This show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon
Speaker 2:  Kiefer. The Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. Neli. And I'll be back on Friday to talk about open AI
Speaker 2:  and the trials going on. I'm gonna be in court a bit this week for the Google
Speaker 2:  trial. Lauren fines in court for the meta trial. We have lots to talk about.
Speaker 2:  Lots going on. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.