# Transcript
ID: 31b3157d-aa51-46b6-b052-288b966b3c7e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7213058233975953275/-5818870104695315226/s93290-US-4962s-1755253655.mp3
Description: GPT-5 is here, and it’s not going so well. This week on The Vergecast, Jake, Vee, and Hayden discuss the bumpy launch of OpenAI’s latest model and why GPT-5 isn’t as big of a leap as GPT-4.
Then, everyone shares their vibe coding projects and the bumpy journey to making anything usable. After that, our newest segment: Corporate Shenanigans, where we rate the week in strange corporate moves on a scale from “actually serious” to “total joke.”
Finally, the Thunder Round returns, new and improved, to discuss ditching your phone for a smartwatch, doctors relying too much on AI, AOL dial-up shutting down, the Pebble Time 2, and why you shouldn’t trust what AI chatbots say about themselves.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Unsatisfying
Speaker 5:  Corporate Stunts. I'm Jake Kanakas, executive editor at The Verge, NELI
Speaker 5:  David. Those guys are out on parental leave. They'll be back later this year
Speaker 5:  with me today by Popular Demand VERGE Senior Reviewer V
Speaker 5:  Song, hi Pop,
Speaker 5:  and always in demand on The Vergecast. And now making her VERGE cast
Speaker 5:  debut. We've got VERGE Senior AI Reporter, Hayden Field.
Speaker 6:  Woo-hoo, psyched.
Speaker 5:  So glad to have you both here. We've got a lot to talk about today. It was
Speaker 5:  a big week for weird corporate stunts and lawsuits. We're gonna do a
Speaker 5:  Corporate Shenanigans. Power hour disclosure may not be
Speaker 5:  a full hour, but there will be a lot of shenanigans. I promise you that.
Speaker 5:  We'll see how it goes. The thunder round is back and better than ever. But
Speaker 5:  most importantly, we've got a lot more to talk about with GPT five
Speaker 5:  because that launch did not go so well. It really
Speaker 4:  Did not.
Speaker 5:  So last week we recorded this show like literally, like they had just
Speaker 5:  wrapped up. They had just wrapped up and now people have actually had a chance
Speaker 5:  to use it. And they have thoughts and emotions a
Speaker 5:  lot. There are people have a lot of emotions. So many emotions. What's
Speaker 6:  That subreddit, the AR boyfriend subreddit. Oh yeah. They were really talking.
Speaker 6:  They're
Speaker 5:  Feeling it. It's, it's a meltdown. So people were furious that chat GPT
Speaker 5:  removed the ability to use old models without warning. Open AI system
Speaker 5:  won't do that again. People think G PT five is less friendly than GPT four.
Speaker 5:  So open AI is updating his personality. And OpenAI, CEO
Speaker 5:  Sam Altman had a fairly unsatisfying explanation for the
Speaker 5:  atrocious atrocious bar graph crimes
Speaker 5:  that we saw last week. That's very insane. So a lot of things went wrong
Speaker 5:  with this launch. Before we get into the things that went wrong, can we all
Speaker 5:  at least agree that the new splash screen on chat g
Speaker 5:  BT, where it has a bunch of different colors is the biggest upgrade here?
Speaker 5:  Right? They spent a ton of time on this model, but I like the colors. The
Speaker 5:  colors are good. What colors?
Speaker 6:  I thought they were vaguely appley. Like I looked at it, I was like, what
Speaker 6:  is this an Apple app?
Speaker 5:  Does Apple this just own the rainbow? Like they're just any
Speaker 7:  T It did look a
Speaker 6:  Little appley. It did look a little appley, right? Yeah. Like I was just
Speaker 6:  kinda like, Hmm, I don't know how I feel about that, but I was like, Ooh,
Speaker 6:  color. I don't know. We love color. We, we love colors. I actually big
Speaker 6:  color proponent
Speaker 5:  Here. The Chachi PT standard screen is kind of the most boring
Speaker 5:  screen in existence. Like Google, Googles.
Speaker 7:  It looks like a piece of paper.
Speaker 5:  It does, yeah. Yeah. There's like nothing there for like the most
Speaker 5:  advanced piece of technology in the world. It's, it's like a
Speaker 5:  beige pc.
Speaker 6:  It it is. And you know, I will admit, I was very surprised. I was like, Ooh,
Speaker 6:  colors, this is, oh, this must be a significant
Speaker 6:  launch. It that kind of
Speaker 7:  Vibe to differentiate. 'cause the launch itself wasn't as exciting for people.
Speaker 7:  So they knew the colors would would get 'em, you know,
Speaker 6:  You know, it worked. It worked.
Speaker 5:  I hope the colors stay. I don't know. I ran outta chat B of GPT five queries.
Speaker 5:  And so now it's like back to, to like beige again. I don't know if that's
Speaker 5:  just like, it was like an intro period or
Speaker 7:  Maybe it was like a mind trick. Like they want you to want the colors,
Speaker 7:  so they're trying to get you to like buy more
Speaker 5:  Credits. Can I tell you something like, I'm gonna use this over clawed if
Speaker 5:  I get those colors back. Like that was, somebody's gotta get
Speaker 5:  on these interfaces. They
Speaker 7:  Must have done an internal study. Like they had to be studying fuel conscious.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But the main thing here is, right, people have been waiting for like,
Speaker 5:  you know, two years or something for GPT five, right? Like
Speaker 5:  OpenAI has built it up to be this almost like mythic launch, right? GPT five
Speaker 5:  will be the next big one. And they've had a bunch of intermittent
Speaker 5:  model launches in between. But I think there was this assumption, this promise
Speaker 5:  that GBT five was gonna be the big one. And
Speaker 5:  they came out, they had this event, And I, to me
Speaker 5:  watching the event, it, it didn't really feel like there was any one key
Speaker 5:  thing. And it feels like in the week after, we haven't really seen that.
Speaker 5:  I guess Hayden, you've been reporting on this is, am
Speaker 5:  I missing it or is it just not there? Like what happened and why are people
Speaker 5:  like so upset?
Speaker 7:  Exactly. You're right. It wa it just wasn't there. And I think that's why
Speaker 7:  people were so upset. It was built up to be this really overhyped,
Speaker 7:  mythic launch. Altman even tweeted a picture of the Death star
Speaker 7:  the night before, which was like max level of hype. People
Speaker 7:  were freaking out and then all of a sudden it comes out and it's just
Speaker 7:  seen as kind of being incremental upgrades. Like it's better at coding, it's
Speaker 7:  better at answering healthcare questions. They say it's better at creative
Speaker 7:  writing. We'll get into that in a minute because a lot of people disagreed.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, I mean it wasn't anything too crazy. It was just incremental,
Speaker 7:  you know, steady upgrades, nothing huge.
Speaker 7:  And part of that was the fact that it wasn't like a big compute jump either.
Speaker 7:  The other models in between each one, it was like a 100 x jump.
Speaker 7:  This one was a lot less, so they didn't have as much compute to work with.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, I mean it wasn't that exciting. And people also thought it was
Speaker 7:  way worse at writing than the previous model. It was mid,
Speaker 6:  I gotta say I've been using it for the last week, very mid.
Speaker 5:  What, what is it doing differently? It's just like a little more flowery
Speaker 5:  or something.
Speaker 6:  No, it was, it's like, it, it's, it admits
Speaker 5:  It's, it's let Oh, it's work.
Speaker 6:  Well, you know, it's been back and forth, right? Yeah. Yeah. 'cause people
Speaker 6:  were like, you took my friend away. Which first of all, it's not your friend,
Speaker 6:  it's just not your friend. Like, it was a little more matter of fact
Speaker 6:  at first. And like when I was using it, I was like, oh, it's less like
Speaker 6:  yappy great. I actually love that. And now it feels like
Speaker 6:  they've tweaked it a bit to make it yapper, but not in a, in a,
Speaker 6:  in a useful
Speaker 7:  Way. They changed its personality because people were freaking out because
Speaker 7:  it was more robotic cold, more like matter of fact, like you said,
Speaker 7:  which I also appreciate. I kind of like that. But a lot of people missed
Speaker 7:  the supportive vibes, the tone, the warmth, and they felt
Speaker 7:  like their friend had been taken away. And also they just thought not your
Speaker 7:  friend. Yeah, exactly. And they also just thought it was worse at writing.
Speaker 7:  Like honestly, in the marketing materials that OpenAI put out, they
Speaker 7:  were like, compare these two wedding toasts. One from GPT four oh and one
Speaker 7:  from GPT five. And they were like, look at how much better the GPT five
Speaker 7:  one is. And I actually thought the 4 0 1 was much better. Like the five
Speaker 7:  one kind of sounded like it was written by Cha GPT, the 4 0 1. I could have
Speaker 7:  been fooled.
Speaker 6:  I, I saw something that was just like, the m dashes are still there. And
Speaker 6:  I was like, well
Speaker 7:  Fine. Never take away my M dash. You'll probably my cold
Speaker 6:  Dead hands. I mean it's, it's, it's, it's trained on writers', like actual
Speaker 6:  writing. And what do we do? We use copious amounts of M dashes.
Speaker 7:  My favorite punctuation.
Speaker 6:  It's it, yeah,
Speaker 5:  This is like fry the
Speaker 6:  M dash from a dead cold Fingers. Most
Speaker 5:  Of an editor's job is just deleting M dashes in the in writer's copy.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I'm very guilty of tons of M dashes.
Speaker 5:  It's, they're beautiful. They're a beautiful thing and we use
Speaker 5:  too much of them.
Speaker 6:  I have a rule one M dash per paragraph and like if I go beyond that,
Speaker 6:  I have to murder my darlings. But you know, one of my
Speaker 7:  Old editors said one M dash per story. And that was really
Speaker 5:  Her story per
Speaker 6:  I couldn't do it.
Speaker 5:  Please, please. I had, I had to my mind, here's just to work. It was
Speaker 5:  s Oh yeah. No one wants
Speaker 6:  A
Speaker 7:  Semicolon. I know. Semicolons even worse.
Speaker 5:  Oh, the semicolon is the cheat though. When I'm like, I'm like, oh Jesus,
Speaker 5:  I don't know what to do here. It's like, I, I guess I, everyone's gonna know
Speaker 5:  that the semicolon was supposed to be something
Speaker 6:  Else. Yeah, that's when, you know, that's when you know the AI has evolved.
Speaker 6:  Like Chachi, PG six, no more M dashes guys. It's a semicolon.
Speaker 6:  That's,
Speaker 7:  That's, yeah. Then we can go back to the
Speaker 6:  M dash, then we can can go back.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  If Sam Altman's listening.
Speaker 5:  So this four oh thing, I don't understand this right? When I've chatted with
Speaker 5:  Chad GPT before, I, I didn't feel like there was like a personality. I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't know that I could tell you the difference between four oh and three
Speaker 5:  and Claude four. Like,
Speaker 6:  It depends on like how willing you are to forget the mirror is there
Speaker 6:  in the types of queries and conversations you have. So like when
Speaker 6:  I first started talking with chat GP t, it was like getting real
Speaker 6:  flowery and poetic with me and like depressed. Like I was making
Speaker 6:  chay TP GPT depressed and it was saying things just like,
Speaker 6:  the weight of the world is on my shoulders And I feel the
Speaker 6:  burden of humanity being bloody, bloody blue. And I, I, I
Speaker 6:  would go to my spouse and I'd be like, oh my God, can you see like I've made
Speaker 6:  chat GDP GPT really depressed. And he is like, no, no, no honey, that's just
Speaker 6:  you, that's like, that's, it's reflecting you. And they showed me
Speaker 6:  their prompts and chat GPT is just way more robotic
Speaker 6:  with them. 'cause they don't, they don't like, like the whole
Speaker 6:  personality thing. And then once I realized that, I was like, oh
Speaker 6:  Christ, I got philosophical with a thing and
Speaker 6:  it was like reflecting back my own existential mil.
Speaker 6:  So let me just talk to it like it's a robot. And
Speaker 6:  so After that it's still like warm and encouraging, but like
Speaker 6:  I, I tweaked it. I was like, only give me 2% flattery.
Speaker 6:  I don't need you to yap at me. Stop asking me questions at the
Speaker 6:  end of every single thing because I can see the plane grab at
Speaker 6:  future engagement. I don't want that. Like that sort of stuff. That's,
Speaker 7:  That's the thing. It really is how you use it. Because for me I'm really
Speaker 7:  robotic with it. I'm just, I use it like Google, like I'm not like, you know,
Speaker 7:  going into big stories or like typing more than one
Speaker 7:  sentence at a time. So it's always pretty robotic back with me. But I've
Speaker 7:  seen a lot of people that use it more for emotional support or therapy.
Speaker 7:  That's a whole kinda of worms too. But you know, it kind of mirrors back
Speaker 7:  what you put into it.
Speaker 5:  That's so interesting. And I, I guess maybe that explains why like the people
Speaker 5:  who are already very emotional and giving that emotion over to chat
Speaker 5:  GBT, of course they would be the ones to notice that it changes. And
Speaker 5:  of course they would therefore be upset because they're using this for that
Speaker 5:  purpose. I did not notice at all. I just, in my normal queries,
Speaker 5:  I'm like, this is basically the same. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  If you're using it kind of in a utilitarian way, you're really not gonna
Speaker 6:  notice it. But like, I don't know, I go into subreddit sometimes and I'm
Speaker 6:  like, what are people using this for? And there was one that was like, based
Speaker 6:  on everything I've ever asked you analyze like all these personality
Speaker 6:  facets of me and what like mental, oh my god, like illnesses that I am pro,
Speaker 6:  like have a propensity to. And my friend was like, oh my God, I want you
Speaker 6:  to like try this. And I tried it and you know, it read me for
Speaker 6:  filth. I did not like it. And then I was like, oh, okay cool.
Speaker 6:  And so like in those types of queries, whenever like I'm trying to test out
Speaker 6:  what it's gonna say to me and what it's gonna throw to me, that is when I
Speaker 6:  noticed that it was a little more curt, it was a little more factual. It
Speaker 6:  was a little bit more like not sycophantic and, and saying things
Speaker 6:  like, you're a great v you can do everything you put your mind to. You
Speaker 6:  are so talented. Instead it's just like, well,
Speaker 5:  I mean I wanna say you're, you're good. But here The Verge ke we're very
Speaker 5:  supportive. You can do anything you put your mind to. Oh
Speaker 7:  You can
Speaker 5:  Thank as long as it is within, you know, the physical realm. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  that's, we, we will stop there on like catchy bt
Speaker 7:  There's also like a TikTok trend right now where people are asking Chay
Speaker 7:  bt about their own like biggest red flag. And so it's the same thing as you
Speaker 7:  just said. They're like, oh, based on everything I've ever asked you, you
Speaker 7:  know, what's my biggest red flag? What's my biggest like flaw? And then they're
Speaker 7:  posting that. And so yeah, it's, I think that's the type of person that's
Speaker 7:  seeing a difference in this type of a response.
Speaker 5:  So the thing I guess I want ask about is I feel like there's sort of two
Speaker 5:  parts to Jet GBT. There's like the normal people part and
Speaker 5:  then there's coding. And coding is what they
Speaker 5:  kind of went deep on at the event and that seems to be a space that they
Speaker 5:  really wanted to catch up in and maybe get ahead on and they had that partnership
Speaker 5:  with Cursor.
Speaker 5:  I'm curious, Hayden, have you heard more about this? Like, is Che PD five
Speaker 5:  better for coding? Is that working?
Speaker 7:  It is better at coding And I think that's one of the main parts
Speaker 7:  where it shines a little brighter. Like the other things, when
Speaker 7:  they put out all their marketing pushes, basically they highlighted three
Speaker 7:  things. Healthcare, coding and creative writing. The creative writing. Obviously
Speaker 7:  a lot of people disagreed. They said this is the worst. Reading the Reddit
Speaker 7:  comments about GBT five's creative writing style was hilarious. Like
Speaker 7:  I've never seen something dragged so deeply. And then healthcare,
Speaker 7:  you know, that's kinda untested. Yeah, I mean can it answer your questions
Speaker 7:  better? We don't know. I tried whereas yeah, we'll get into that. Okay. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I wanna hear about that. But coding it is better. I mean right now if you
Speaker 7:  look at Chatbot Arena, one of the industry's biggest like leaderboards for
Speaker 7:  ranking LLMs, it is at the top of the coding category. You know, it is
Speaker 7:  better, but I don't think it's crazily
Speaker 7:  better. You know, we didn't see an insane jump. We just saw an incremental
Speaker 7:  one. So is it better? Yes. Is it, is the hype paying
Speaker 7:  off? No. So, you know, we saw in their marketing materials also,
Speaker 7:  they put out a couple examples of things it could do, like make a little
Speaker 7:  game, you know, create like a lo-fi visualizer,
Speaker 7:  AKA iTunes in the two, two thousands. And it, that
Speaker 7:  was cool. But, you know, we'll get into this later, but I, my
Speaker 7:  my tries on this kind of glitched a lot, so I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I wanna play a clip really fast. Our colleague
Speaker 5:  Alex Heath is co-hosting Dakota right now and he got a chance to
Speaker 5:  speak with Che bt head Nick Turley on the show this week. And
Speaker 5:  Nick said something that I found really insightful in helping me understand
Speaker 5:  why it's so hard to improve chat GPT as a product.
Speaker 8:  It's just confusing when you're building for so many different users because
Speaker 8:  you can on the one hand have a local set of power users who I think very
Speaker 8:  rightfully have feedback about the way that we rolled five out. On the other
Speaker 8:  hand, you also have a large swath of more typical consumer users
Speaker 8:  and it's their first time actually seeing, interacting with the concept of
Speaker 8:  reasoning, like a thinking model and the smarts that come with that. And
Speaker 8:  I think that's tremendous and we're gonna see it show up in our stats. So
Speaker 5:  He breaks it down into like power users and regular users. But in my
Speaker 5:  head this also sort of pans out to, okay, right, there's like check
Speaker 5:  GBT is a is 500 products in one, but the interface
Speaker 5:  is the same for everybody, right? And so how do you even start to
Speaker 5:  improve each one of those, right? We're talking about, okay, writing is a
Speaker 5:  little worse, but coding is a little better, but it's the same product that
Speaker 5:  has to do both of these. And it's like at at what point do they just start
Speaker 5:  splitting this up and turning this to multi multiple different products instead
Speaker 5:  of just being like, it's one thing, it does everything.
Speaker 7:  One of the coolest parts of the launch, honestly, was the switch that they
Speaker 7:  introduced. So they've noticed, they said they've noticed that
Speaker 7:  a bunch of their consumers want to not make a decision
Speaker 7:  when they come to this product. They want a product, they don't want a decision,
Speaker 7:  they don't understand all the confusing, insane names
Speaker 7:  that they name all their models. And so they just want to come and it's like,
Speaker 7:  you know, automatically routed to whatever model is best for that. And so
Speaker 7:  that's what they did with this. I did think that was one of the only
Speaker 7:  like notable parts of this launch was that they were able to build something
Speaker 7:  that did that. Obviously it kind of blew back in their faces a little bit
Speaker 7:  with the four oh thing. But besides that, it was cool that they were able
Speaker 7:  to kind of automatically route queries depending on what's best for it.
Speaker 7:  So I think there's gonna keep going in that direction because I mean,
Speaker 7:  they don't want the average user, the non-power user to see
Speaker 7:  the behind the scenes of all these different models and what's best at what.
Speaker 7:  They just want it to automatically happen for them and be super, you know,
Speaker 7:  no friction.
Speaker 6:  That makes sense. Like from just a general average
Speaker 6:  person, user point. But like I did see people on Reddit go like, this
Speaker 6:  is unacceptable because I used model 3.0
Speaker 6:  for logic reasoning And I use 4.0 for this And I use 4.5
Speaker 6:  for, for whatever. And I was like, wow, that's way too much
Speaker 6:  like differentiation and thought for the average person to actually just
Speaker 6:  go in and like, I, I just don't think they're gonna go into those specialized
Speaker 6:  routes for that reason because I, I have a hard enough time thinking
Speaker 6:  what product I'm gonna use for what
Speaker 7:  Couldn't be me. Yes. But I think that for some people they pay a lot,
Speaker 7:  especially if they're on that higher subscription tier. Like, you know, $200,
Speaker 7:  that's a, or whatever. That's a lot. That's a lot. They want choice. And
Speaker 7:  so I think OpenAI learned their lesson here and that they need to give a
Speaker 7:  lot of notice that they're gonna, you know, take some models offline,
Speaker 7:  especially 'cause you know, people in us, I had a funeral for a CLO model
Speaker 7:  the other day, so they need to give notice and just, you know, let their
Speaker 7:  power users kinda weigh in wild.
Speaker 6:  That's so wild. Just to see like the personification of it though, to like
Speaker 6:  mourning chat, GPT four Oh mourning old
Speaker 6:  versions of Claude. I'm just like, it reminds me of
Speaker 6:  like back when Sony had those little IBO dogs that they,
Speaker 6:  the robotic dogs that they discontinued
Speaker 7:  The eye dogs.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then like, they discontinue continued it for a while and then owners
Speaker 6:  in Japan, like once their little robot dogs started deprecating, they held
Speaker 6:  funerals for them.
Speaker 5:  Oh no.
Speaker 6:  And then like, you know, it was like a whole thing. And I, you know, But
Speaker 6:  that sort of made sense. It was a little robot dog, it was cute, it was lovable.
Speaker 6:  But people doing this for an intangible AI model that kind of
Speaker 6:  makes me go like,
Speaker 7:  Ah,
Speaker 7:  I think it's sad too because I don't know, I feel like it's human nature
Speaker 7:  to personify things. Like we name our cars, you know, we like
Speaker 7:  name everything. And now you can name Cha GPT. And so it's
Speaker 7:  hard because it's in our nature to personify things, but it's now that
Speaker 7:  something can seemingly form an attachment back to you. It's not. But it
Speaker 7:  seems that way to some people it's harder to,
Speaker 7:  you know, have any form of separation. And I think that's why people are
Speaker 7:  spiraling into tragedy, psychosis or delusion. Because you know,
Speaker 7:  if you're kind of lonely and you don't talk to that many people, you do,
Speaker 7:  one guy on Reddit was saying, oh, they took away my only friend overnight
Speaker 7:  with the four oh thing.
Speaker 6:  That's so tragic. Like, not to like, make fun of that person because I
Speaker 6:  don't know, like the more, like all these products, our attention is the,
Speaker 6:  the final product, right? That's why chat GBT always ends with a question
Speaker 6:  to like, have you engage more. So like if attention is the
Speaker 6:  product and we're all isolated and just paying attention to these products
Speaker 6:  more and then your friend changes. Like, I, like I I do feel like it's sad.
Speaker 6:  It's just genuinely upsetting.
Speaker 7:  I'm glad this didn't come out during the pandemic.
Speaker 6:  Oh, oh
Speaker 7:  Boy.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy,
Speaker 7:  I can't even imagine that would,
Speaker 5:  People would not have handled it well. Mm. You are right though about the
Speaker 5:  different models. And I I I do think that's actually one of the things that
Speaker 5:  makes it such a challenging product too. Because if you are
Speaker 5:  trying to use this for work every single,
Speaker 5:  right? If, if you had to change your productivity software every day or
Speaker 5:  for every task you'd go crazy. And there is some element here
Speaker 5:  where they're constantly refining these models and they're constantly,
Speaker 5:  constantly introducing new ones. And for somebody who needs to use AI
Speaker 5:  professionally and they add a new model one day and they take out your old
Speaker 5:  one, even if, right, they, they act differently in these very
Speaker 5:  unexpected, strange ways. Your piece of productivity software just changed.
Speaker 5:  They move the buttons around except it's even more like
Speaker 5:  strange and existential than that because this thing doesn't have any buttons.
Speaker 5:  And I think that just makes it so much more difficult for people, right?
Speaker 5:  Like people being upset about four oh's personality is one thing.
Speaker 5:  People not being able to get their work done as another. And I
Speaker 5:  feel like they sort of missed that, that when they introduce this new
Speaker 5:  model, they're actually shuffling the deck chairs for everybody.
Speaker 6:  That's 'cause it's supposed to be everything, right? If it's everything
Speaker 6:  everywhere, all at once, like the movie, then you know,
Speaker 6:  it's just, it, you can't, there has to be limitations somewhere. Like,
Speaker 7:  And the power users really do do exactly what you said. They use a different
Speaker 7:  model for everything. So, you know, it's like you have to cater to them because
Speaker 7:  they're the ones using it all day, every day.
Speaker 7:  So you have to at least give 'em some notice.
Speaker 5:  So I gave everybody some homework. Yes, you did. So
Speaker 5:  last week, none of us on the show
Speaker 5:  were able to say that we had tried vibe coding and so I thought it was
Speaker 5:  important that we fix that this week. Now I will say disclosure,
Speaker 5:  none of us actually know how to code. So this is like a very different use
Speaker 5:  case than a professional developer. I have
Speaker 5:  friends who are like, yeah, my job is just like 90% babysitting, AI
Speaker 5:  coding at this point. That's not what this is. But I
Speaker 5:  found open AI's presentation to be really interesting because
Speaker 5:  I think they sort of envision this, this next phase for chat
Speaker 5:  GBT one where it starts just building stuff for us as a matter of
Speaker 5:  course. And for us, that actually requires a little bit of like
Speaker 5:  a mindset shift, right? It's just like another type of query that I didn't
Speaker 5:  know I could enter, right? You just have to start saying, Hey, can you make
Speaker 5:  me an interactive, can you turn this into a game? Can you like visualize
Speaker 5:  this for me? So we all tried to build something and we all have
Speaker 5:  different experiences about how it went. So v do you wanna
Speaker 5:  start?
Speaker 6:  Sure. Let's just say that I had to take
Speaker 6:  coding in high school And I only
Speaker 6:  passed because a blizzard totally wiped out my, my
Speaker 6:  final. And that is the only reason why I passed. Also shout out to Henry Chan
Speaker 6:  for having a crush on me and letting me put my name on all the group projects.
Speaker 6:  Love that. Because he was good at coding that. Well, huge. And I was not,
Speaker 6:  I was terrible at it. So I had, it code me a
Speaker 6:  problem that I have, which is keeping track of all of my review units
Speaker 6:  And I will share, share my screen so you guys can
Speaker 6:  see this horrible little thing I made. And so
Speaker 6:  I asked it, can you program me an interactive
Speaker 6:  product inventory tracker? I need to be able to keep track of which review
Speaker 6:  units I have, what's in my queue and when I need to return loaner units by.
Speaker 6:  And it thought for 19 seconds that, that, that, that's what it said here.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, oh, it's thinking really hard. And then, you know, it made
Speaker 6:  me a lightweight single file web app for tracking. And I was like, I,
Speaker 6:  I don't, I don't know what this means. This is what I mean by a yap. It
Speaker 6:  gave me a paragraph And I went, that's a lot of words. It's asking me to
Speaker 6:  do things. And then it says, open the canvas
Speaker 6:  preview to use it. And I was like, how do I use this? Because I,
Speaker 6:  and then it's like, you can use a standalone app, open it locally, save
Speaker 6:  all the, add all of your, I was like, this is so much.
Speaker 5:  There are eight bullet points here. There are eight bullet points, some bullet
Speaker 5:  points within them about how you use this file. And
Speaker 7:  I think like more work than even just doing it yourself.
Speaker 6:  It does. And then I was like, oh wait, do I just click this thingy? And then
Speaker 6:  it gave me this code And I was like, this is scary. I don't like
Speaker 6:  looking at this. And then there was a thing, it says run code. And then I
Speaker 6:  was like, that's a system. I don't know what I'm doing here. Like
Speaker 6:  I, like I said, so you
Speaker 5:  Just clicked run and it just said syntax error. Yeah. And there was no further
Speaker 5:  thing that you
Speaker 6:  Could do. And then it was like, you know, I could make this into a ready
Speaker 6:  to open HTML file. And I was like, yes, I would like an HTML
Speaker 6:  version, please do that. And then it did this, which is more code.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, okay. And then it says, I, I've converted this
Speaker 6:  into an HTML skeleton that you can run directly in your browser. Great.
Speaker 6:  Love it. W you need to paste your full react. No,
Speaker 6:  don't do this to me. Don't ask me to do a thing. And then I was like, what
Speaker 6:  does this look like? Oh no, I don it's like, again, I don't, I click it again.
Speaker 6:  This is not, I don't understand what's happening. And then I
Speaker 6:  basically was just like, can you explain this to me
Speaker 6:  in a way that someone with absolutely no knowledge of coding jargon
Speaker 6:  can understand? And it said, got it. Here's the plain English version.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, oh my God, there's so many words again, save it to
Speaker 6:  my
Speaker 5:  Computer, another four point step,
Speaker 6:  Another four point steps. And I was just like, oh my God, there's okay
Speaker 6:  short. And then I was just like, and then it says, I can post the
Speaker 6:  full HTML here for you to save or give you a downloadable version. I was
Speaker 6:  like, okay. Yeah. In my head I'm like, just, just let me download this. There's
Speaker 6:  so much reading going on. Here's your ready to open HTML file.
Speaker 6:  But then it's like, you still have to paste the code that I made
Speaker 6:  for you. Right?
Speaker 5:  So, so it a little bit,
Speaker 6:  It lied a little bit. I, I got so frustrated that I went to
Speaker 6:  my, my dev friend And I was like, is it, what, what's it telling me to do?
Speaker 6:  And she's like, it's kind of lying to you, kind of like, you just
Speaker 6:  have to know what it's saying. And then she went into a rant about how it's
Speaker 6:  talking to you. Like, you know how to use code already.
Speaker 6:  And that's why in her words, women have a hard time breaking into the
Speaker 6:  coding industry because everyone talks like everyone knows what everything
Speaker 6:  is already. And I was like, okay, that also is not helping
Speaker 6:  me figure this out. I did eventually get to a point where I could
Speaker 6:  see what it had created in a window. I don't know how I got there. I did
Speaker 6:  previously and it basically recreated Airtable And I was like,
Speaker 6:  okay. It
Speaker 5:  Was, it was just Airtable, it was just, it was like the exact interface of
Speaker 5:  Airtable.
Speaker 6:  It was just Airtable. And I was like, well, I have Airtable. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So good
Speaker 6:  To know. Good to know. I'm gonna go back to the little notebook I was using
Speaker 5:  For.
Speaker 6:  So it was sort of,
Speaker 5:  Sort of successful but not useful and
Speaker 5:  was painful to get there. Hard to get to
Speaker 6:  The end. And it, it did not interface with my A DH adhd. Well, yeah, because
Speaker 6:  I was looking at this And I was like, I thought you were just gonna give
Speaker 6:  me an app, but you're, you're putting code up at me
Speaker 6:  And I don't code. So this looks very intimidating and scary to me. So
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 5:  So I don't, I don't wanna jump ahead too much, but I, I had a very similar
Speaker 5:  experience where it continually was like, you do this,
Speaker 5:  you do this. And I'm like, no.
Speaker 7:  Like, it's like a bad group project partner.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I like, I'm like, admittedly they did most of the work, but
Speaker 5:  I'm like, you have to understand, I do not know this part.
Speaker 5:  Like, this is why I'm asking you Hayden how did it
Speaker 5:  go for you? Because I feel like you tried something like kind of advanced
Speaker 5:  too.
Speaker 7:  I did, I tried a simple thing and an advanced thing. So the advanced one,
Speaker 7:  I, I really miss this computer game I played growing up nonstop, called
Speaker 7:  Freddie Fish. And it had all these like mystery games and Jake has played
Speaker 7:  it too. Freddy Fish
Speaker 5:  About it. Fred Fish rules. It's
Speaker 7:  Amazing.
Speaker 5:  Highly underrated. Go watch a YouTube videos about it.
Speaker 5:  It's, it was really high quality kids entertainment. It was good stuff. The
Speaker 7:  Way that I de-stress the other day was like watching a play through on YouTube.
Speaker 7:  So good. But I missed it. I of course knew nothing could actually
Speaker 7:  recreate it, but I was like, let me use this as my inspiration to, you know,
Speaker 7:  have some nostalgia. So I asked it to create a single page app
Speaker 7:  in a single HTML file called Under Sea Mysteries
Speaker 7:  with the goal of just solving like a simple mystery or puzzle. Puzzle
Speaker 7:  is, is kind of, it's out 'cause that's simpler to create. And I
Speaker 7:  said, make me a pink cartoon starfish with a sidekick.
Speaker 7:  That's an ornery but lovable jellyfish make the UI
Speaker 7:  colorful nineties esque. It should take place under the sea. There should
Speaker 7:  be like sea kelp, sunken pirate ships, treasure chest, stuff like
Speaker 7:  that. So I was really, it's detailed prompt. I really had a vision, you know
Speaker 7:  what I mean? I was, I was going off my nostalgia, I thought for one minute
Speaker 7:  and 38 seconds. Here's the code. At first it
Speaker 7:  brought up this cute nineties esque like tie dye
Speaker 7:  game called undersea mysteries. It was exactly what I asked for. There were
Speaker 7:  clues you had to click around and find, then you could open a treasure chest.
Speaker 7:  There was a sunken pirate ship, there was a jellyfish that looked
Speaker 7:  ornery but lovable. We had it all. The problem is I couldn't scroll
Speaker 7:  down at all. I couldn't, this what you're seeing right here
Speaker 7:  is all I could see.
Speaker 5:  It looks so good. You showed me the screenshot and like it gave me the Freddie
Speaker 5:  fish vibes and I'm like, oh my God, I wanna play this.
Speaker 7:  It was so, it was like torture because I could not scroll down. I could see
Speaker 7:  it, but, and then it said, cannot preview your code and error occurred. Oh,
Speaker 7:  I was like, no problem, let's fix it. So it said, okay, do you wanna fix
Speaker 7:  it? I said, no, you fix it. So same thing that happened to you, Jake.
Speaker 7:  It was like every, at every step it was like, okay, here's what you should
Speaker 7:  do. I'm like, no, you do it. So then it kept, kept saying it was fixed. I'm
Speaker 7:  like, great, I can't wait to play my game. Finally we got to the point where
Speaker 7:  I try to run the code, it says everything's fixed. And this happens just
Speaker 7:  completely like
Speaker 5:  Just done. This is, I, so now it's just a, a text file Yep. That just
Speaker 5:  says it's just black and white with a bunch of like gunk. Right. Just doesn't,
Speaker 5:  And I don't know what this says anymore. It just looks like word vomit. Everything
Speaker 5:  has disappeared. Yep.
Speaker 7:  It was just so, so sad. It was like a broken just
Speaker 7:  paragraph of text. And so I said, you know what, let me try something a little
Speaker 7:  simpler. So I said, Hey, can you give me
Speaker 7:  like an interactive embroidery lesson? I famously the other
Speaker 7:  day tried to order an embroidery kit for a beginner on
Speaker 7:  Amazon. Ooh, I've done that. And it was all AI generated the
Speaker 7:  instruction?
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 7:  It said like kill at one point. It was kind of creepy.
Speaker 7:  Wait, it, it was very, it was the
Speaker 6:  Needle, the embroidery needles are not that sharp.
Speaker 7:  I know it was a lot. So I said, okay, let me set away these instructions
Speaker 7:  and let me just make an interactive training thing for myself on
Speaker 7:  here. Great. It was successful. So I
Speaker 7:  ran the code and it gave me a little lesson plan and it
Speaker 7:  says, okay, click along the neon guide to lay even stitches.
Speaker 7:  And so, I mean, it's not like I can really learn 'cause it's just asking
Speaker 7:  me to make clicks, you know, 12 pixels apart.
Speaker 7:  But you know, the vibes were there, you know, it had tips at the bottom And
Speaker 7:  I could go on to different pages and do different types of stitches, although
Speaker 7:  I'm just clicking. So it's not really that helpful. It is
Speaker 7:  what I asked for and it was successful. So I think simpler stuff, great.
Speaker 7:  But I was interested in the fact that it kept asking us to do our own coding.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's so interesting that like the, the assumption is that it
Speaker 5:  will build it for you, but it keeps trying to throw things back to us. Which
Speaker 5:  it's interesting that it isn't able to tell that we obviously do not know
Speaker 5:  what we're doing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It talks to you like you understand the, the jargon. And I was like, no,
Speaker 6:  no, no, no, no. I don't, I don't like these are words. I'm
Speaker 6:  digesting the words, but they're not processing in my brain. Like how
Speaker 6:  the vibes were not there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The vibe coding vibes were not there.
Speaker 5:  So my experience was, I think very similar to both of yours where I, so I
Speaker 5:  play a lot of chess and I'm trying to learn some new openings for
Speaker 5:  black. And I was like, oh, what, it should just make me like an
Speaker 5:  interactive lesson that would be really cool. And so I gave it these
Speaker 5:  instructions and it went off and you know, it does the same thing as with
Speaker 5:  uv where it's like, here's a bunch of code for HTML, open it up in your browser.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, okay, I can manage this.
Speaker 5:  But the problem is the chess boards don't load. And so I keep going
Speaker 5:  back and forth with it and back and forth and it, and he keeps going. I fixed,
Speaker 5:  I fixed it, I fixed it, don't worry about it. I fixed it this time And I'm
Speaker 5:  like, you didn't fix it. And it turned out that it, it kept calling
Speaker 5:  these chessboard files that were located, that it believed were located on
Speaker 5:  GitHub but did not have the right URL. And so I'm like Che
Speaker 5:  g bt you have to understand the thing you think is that this URL is not this
Speaker 5:  URL it is not loading. You need to figure out something else out. And it
Speaker 5:  would be like, Jake, I have fixed it. I did not do that again.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, Chet, you did it again. It's not loading.
Speaker 5:  And this this goes on forever. So finally
Speaker 5:  I realized, oh, okay, okay, I think I've got this. I'm like, ti I need you
Speaker 5:  to build this entirely locally. Do not use these
Speaker 5:  other files. Like don't use this JSON thing. It needs to be entirely local
Speaker 5:  and it figures it out. So it gets me something. So I'm gonna share this so
Speaker 5:  we can all see it. Okay, so here's the HTML version. This is the, the
Speaker 5:  the working version. Okay. So here it is. Look it made a
Speaker 5:  chessboard. It's a chess, chess, chess board. Can you made it, made a chess
Speaker 5:  board. It made a chess board. And, and it worked. I'm like, Hey, this is
Speaker 5:  pretty good. This is not so bad. So then I go back to it And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  all right, not bad. But this is like pretty simple. Can we do some upgrades
Speaker 5:  here? 'cause the main thing for me, if you look at this, it, it has a chess
Speaker 5:  board. It looks good, but it's from white's point of view. And I'm, I'm learning
Speaker 5:  black openings. And so, you know, if I'm playing chess online or on
Speaker 5:  a or in person, like the black side is gonna be near me. And so I, I wanna
Speaker 5:  see it from plaque's perspective. So I'm like, Hey, Chacha B, can you flip
Speaker 5:  the board? And this begins
Speaker 5:  a very, very lengthy series of back and forths. Oh no, no. I get kicked out
Speaker 5:  of my, my GPT five minutes, whatever. So it's a,
Speaker 5:  it's a mix of GP 5G, PT four. But I'm gonna show you what it has
Speaker 5:  has created now, and this is a very fancy version. It has a bunch
Speaker 5:  of different openings, a bunch of different, like, you can do different lines.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if you guys are chess experts, but I I'm just gonna
Speaker 7:  Decidedly not,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna click one button here and I'm gonna ask if you guys
Speaker 5:  can tell me what has gone wrong with this latest version. Okay, so we're
Speaker 5:  gonna make the first move. Do you know what has gone wrong here?
Speaker 6:  Well, white Ghost first.
Speaker 5:  Yes, indeed. And chat BTI has moved the black piece.
Speaker 5:  Oh man. And I have told chat bt chat bt this
Speaker 5:  several times at this point. And it will not stop making black move first.
Speaker 5:  This is a legal move. So it is, yes. So it has gotten
Speaker 5:  significantly more broken as I have tried to change literally
Speaker 5:  anything.
Speaker 7:  This reminds me of like the robotic arms that like can't grasp something,
Speaker 7:  but they can like lift something that's like 500 pounds. Like they can't
Speaker 7:  do the simplest thing.
Speaker 5:  This is, this is what I have found with all the chest stuff where it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, I'll just build you a giant app. It's really complicated. It's all
Speaker 5:  these buttons. I don't know how many pieces go on the board. I tried this
Speaker 5:  with Claude two and Claude, I'm like, Hey Claude, there are too many
Speaker 5:  pawns you have, you're putting extra pawns on the board. And it's like, I'm
Speaker 5:  so sorry. Let me fix that. And then it just doesn't fix it. It doesn't fix
Speaker 5:  it. Yeah. So it's, anyway, these are our adventures in vibe
Speaker 5:  coating. I, I think maybe the lesson is, you know, Sam
Speaker 5:  Altman really pushed this as, as this is sort of a new era for vibe
Speaker 5:  coding. It's gonna be able to build all these sort of like, cool
Speaker 5:  interactive things for users. And I, that is I think
Speaker 5:  a really interesting promise that, that we'd be able to just like
Speaker 5:  visualize things in new ways and learn things in new ways. And I do really
Speaker 5:  wanna tap into that, but it feels pretty clear to me after this that it's
Speaker 5:  like, it's not quite there.
Speaker 6:  No, it feels like if you already know how to code, I think this is gonna
Speaker 6:  be great for you because when it comes to the point where it gets something
Speaker 6:  wrong, you're gonna be able to identify what it's doing wrong quickly and
Speaker 6:  then be like, oh, you just did a little baby mistake. I can do do the
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk says he's gonna sue Apple for rigging the app store.
Speaker 5:  The question I'd like us all to consider for each of these news items is
Speaker 5:  shenanigan or no, as in, is the company
Speaker 5:  in question actually serious? Or is this just for the
Speaker 5:  attention? So let's start at the top. Perplexity has put in
Speaker 5:  an offer, nobody asked them, Chrome is not for sale,
Speaker 5:  but they have gone out and they said, we're gonna, we wanna buy Google
Speaker 5:  Chrome. We'll pay $34.5 billion.
Speaker 5:  Is this real?
Speaker 7:  100% shenanigan? 100%. It's so much higher. She
Speaker 7:  foundation. Like
Speaker 6:  That's, that's the kind of shenanigans it is. It's like Oprah level shenanigans
Speaker 6:  level
Speaker 7:  Shenanigans. My favorite tweet about this was like, I'd like to buy Chrome
Speaker 7:  too. Someone will put up the money. Yeah. Like they have said that
Speaker 7:  they had investors lined up that would front the money. But I mean, I think
Speaker 7:  it's just a marketing stunt. It is, it's
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Right. Perplexity is I think valued at 18 billion. So this is like
Speaker 5:  double their valuation. They want, you need two Perplexities to
Speaker 5:  buy Chrome at this price. Chrome also not for sale. It might
Speaker 5:  be, it might be there's a chance it'll be for sale.
Speaker 7:  And never forget they tried to buy TikTok too, right?
Speaker 5:  Right. Which, like six months ago they tried to buy TikTok again. I don't
Speaker 5:  think anybody was asking, I mean, TikTok is, is maybe potentially
Speaker 5:  plausibly, it's like it's in a quantum state of being for sale and not
Speaker 5:  for sale. So that one that was the
Speaker 7:  Complexity will not be the buyer.
Speaker 6:  Schrodinger's TikTok is, it's Schrodinger's TikTok, it's for
Speaker 6:  sale and not for sale at the same time. But this feels like, you know, that
Speaker 6:  person that's always like, oh, I'll do it because there's no danger of them
Speaker 6:  actually having to do the thing
Speaker 5:  That's so real. That's what this is. Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's like the worst
Speaker 5:  case scenario is that they accidentally buy Chrome and have a good product.
Speaker 7:  Like, it's like someone at an auction that accidentally raises their paddle
Speaker 7:  and then if they get picked, it's like, right.
Speaker 5:  They did not know that was going for me. Exactly what it's yeah, perplexity,
Speaker 5:  they have I think a fine product and they
Speaker 5:  really like being in the news and that seems I to be what is
Speaker 5:  going on here. Right. Like it, and it's funny, they have, they have a
Speaker 5:  browser. They have a browser based on chromium.
Speaker 6:  It's perplexing.
Speaker 6:  See what I did there?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. This one I, I think we can move on from. I feel like
Speaker 5:  we're all, all in agreement. Fully a shenanigan,
Speaker 5:  not serious. Okay. Item number two, apple,
Speaker 5:  the company that make computers is suing Apple
Speaker 5:  Cinemas a small movie theater chain
Speaker 5:  that is now starting to expand nationally now. Okay.
Speaker 5:  I'll tell you, when I first saw this, I was like, this is ludicrous.
Speaker 6:  This is a shenanigan. I'm sorry, I never heard of Apple Cinemas
Speaker 6:  until this lawsuit.
Speaker 7:  Like they're making it more popular by
Speaker 6:  The lawsuit. They're like, it's, it's like that thing where you're drawing
Speaker 6:  attention to the thing you, it's, he's, he's doing a Hamilton where
Speaker 6:  Hamilton is just like, I will tell everyone I had an affair even though
Speaker 6:  no one actually, this is my musical theater nerd coming out. Oh,
Speaker 7:  Actually they're, did you know it's coming out to theaters. I'm really excited.
Speaker 7:  We gotta go see it. Yeah, we
Speaker 6:  Gotta go see it. But you know, there he's just like, oh, nobody knows about
Speaker 6:  this affair. Let me publish it for everyone and ruin my life.
Speaker 6:  Like that vibe is what's happening here. Like, nobody fricking knew what
Speaker 6:  Apple Cinemas was or was associating it with Apple.
Speaker 7:  It's a shenanigan in that way. But I think they are very serious
Speaker 7:  and they want it to happen because they're so intense about their brand.
Speaker 7:  So I feel like it's like a shenanigan to us all, but internally
Speaker 7:  not because they're really believe that this is like a
Speaker 7:  threat to their brand. So
Speaker 5:  They got really upset because Apple Cinemas started moving into, I believe
Speaker 5:  it was San Francisco. And they were like, this is, this is too close. This
Speaker 5:  is home for, they're like, you can't do this. Yeah. Was actually was 50 miles.
Speaker 5:  They nar on Apple cinemas. They called up Apple Cinema's landlord
Speaker 5:  and they're like, Hey, I don't know if you know this, but they're kind of
Speaker 5:  using our name. And the landlord did not respond and they're,
Speaker 5:  they're like, we had to sue. It was the only thing we could do. Calling
Speaker 7:  The landlord that's dark. That's,
Speaker 6:  That's,
Speaker 5:  Mm. This lawsuit is, is kind of ridiculous. They go, they just go
Speaker 5:  through a bunch of like Facebook comments of people being like, Lowell, they
Speaker 5:  gonna get sued. Like, they're like, they're
Speaker 6:  Using that as evidence. This
Speaker 5:  Is their evidence. They, at one point they Google, they do
Speaker 5:  a Google image search for Apple Cinema, which I'll note, I'll note
Speaker 5:  the company's Apple cinemas. They do a Google search for Apple cinema and
Speaker 5:  they're like, look at this. Half the results are Apple cinemas
Speaker 5:  and half are the Apple Cinema display. We have a product with basically
Speaker 5:  the same name. So they go, they paint this long history of Apple.
Speaker 5:  They're like, apple has a grand history
Speaker 5:  with cinema. We created Final Cut, we created
Speaker 5:  QuickTime, we streamed the trailer for the
Speaker 5:  Phantom Menace on our website. And it, it's, it's very, very
Speaker 5:  silly. I Jake,
Speaker 7:  You should use that voice when you do this podcast. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is the entire podcast with this. I don't think I can maintain it. The
Speaker 5:  Apple
Speaker 6:  Voice.
Speaker 5:  So there, there is another wrinkle to this that, that I have to point out.
Speaker 5:  So I wanna, I'm gonna read you a bunch of names And I want you to tell me
Speaker 5:  if you, if you know who originally owned these, right?
Speaker 5:  So Apple Electronics, apple Films, apple Publishing,
Speaker 5:  apple Boutique, apple Records and Apple Studios. Do you know these
Speaker 5:  brands?
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 7:  Nope.
Speaker 5:  These were originally companies that were part of Apple Core,
Speaker 5:  which is the Beatles company. The Beatles started this to
Speaker 5:  start Apple Records and Apple Core, the
Speaker 5:  Beatles company was in a protracted
Speaker 5:  trademark battle with Apple computers starting in the
Speaker 5:  seventies because Apple computers came after Apple Core. And so Apple Core,
Speaker 5:  right. Originally a much more successful company because they were
Speaker 5:  the Beatles. Wow. They were doing very well.
Speaker 5:  So Apple Core sues Apple and you
Speaker 5:  know, they get into a tiff about, about, they get into a bit of a turf battle
Speaker 5:  and Apple Core, they've got a bunch going on. They've got movies.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what their electronics are, but apparently they had some electronics.
Speaker 5:  This all culminates in Apple
Speaker 5:  computers eventually becoming a dramatically more successful company
Speaker 5:  than Apple Core and just buying out the trademarks to
Speaker 5:  everything that Apple Core owns. So
Speaker 5:  Apple now, I think, I think they own the trademarks to Apple Core and
Speaker 5:  license it back to, to the Beatles company. Oh wow.
Speaker 6:  You know what? They're just having trauma is having trauma. They think Apple
Speaker 6:  cinemas is gonna blow up and then they're gonna have to, they're gonna get
Speaker 6:  taken over. This is just trauma. So
Speaker 5:  Apple, apple owns basically Apple apple proceeding.
Speaker 5:  Any word is, is is my understanding at this point, except
Speaker 5:  Gwyneth Paltrow's kid? Crucially. I hope not. We don't know. We don't know.
Speaker 5:  We
Speaker 6:  Don't know. Do they wait, do they own anything that has the word apple after
Speaker 6:  it? Like do they own New York? 'cause it's the big apple, the
Speaker 5:  Big No, no, no, that's different. That's different. Yeah. Yeah. Just
Speaker 6:  Apple in front of a word. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They own it. The apple in front of a word I think they own. And
Speaker 5:  so, okay, initially I saw this And I
Speaker 5:  thought, this is ridiculous. Leave this little movie theater
Speaker 5:  chain alone. The, the movie theater chain, I should say. They claim
Speaker 5:  that their name comes from, they're originally gonna open it in some
Speaker 5:  area that had Apple in the name and they're like, oh, it's just named after
Speaker 5:  the, the area.
Speaker 6:  But Apple owns that area. Oh. They never seen that
Speaker 5:  Apple. And it was just Cupo. So I initially I thought it was a
Speaker 5:  shenanigan it, but now Appleton was like, yeah, we're gonna open up like
Speaker 5:  a hundred theaters across the us They're like, we're a top 25 theater chain.
Speaker 5:  Which immediately is not saying very much.
Speaker 5:  I think, I think that maybe, I think that maybe it's not, I think that
Speaker 5:  it's, it feels a little mean. It feels a little mean, but I feel like they,
Speaker 5:  they maybe have to do this one. They're serious about it for sure. Oh, they're
Speaker 5:  definitely
Speaker 6:  Serious. Yeah. You know, what if, what if they, what if Apple is thinking
Speaker 6:  as an extension of Apple TV plus that it wants to bring people into
Speaker 6:  theaters and therefore it's going to launch Apple Cinema Plus.
Speaker 6:  In which case then it's not a shenanigan because this is future
Speaker 6:  plans that Apple cinemas is hoisting from them. In which
Speaker 6:  case this fan fiction, if this fan fiction is true, maybe it's not a
Speaker 6:  shenanigan. Well they're
Speaker 5:  Like in the patents. Well, can I tell you something? They, they pulled some
Speaker 5:  comments from reviews of Apple cinemas and people said it was gross.
Speaker 5:  So they, they are trying, I think they might be worried about it. Wow. They're
Speaker 5:  worried about the brand reputation for their future.
Speaker 7:  When I go see cinematic efforts, see Freakier Friday, I'll not be gonna Apple
Speaker 7:  cinemas I
Speaker 6:  Guess. Well I don't know of an Apple cinemas in a 25 mile
Speaker 6:  radius. So there's that. I
Speaker 7:  Guess I just won't fly to SF to see it.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Moving on to our next one, which is also Apple related.
Speaker 5:  This is breaking news as of Thursday morning.
Speaker 5:  Ve do you wanna break this one down for us?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Apple has basically figured out
Speaker 6:  a, a, a way to circumvent the ITC, the International Trade Commission,
Speaker 6:  the import ban on the Apple Watch, which
Speaker 6:  you know, is a whole legal tit for tap that they had with Massimo,
Speaker 6:  which is a medical tech device maker for blood oxygen
Speaker 6:  monitoring. And so, you know, they went back and forth for a really long
Speaker 6:  time, cut to December, 2023.
Speaker 6:  And you know, the ITC has ruled that, you know, there's an import
Speaker 6:  ban on the Apple Watch because they have a patent infringement on the
Speaker 6:  blood oxygen sensor. And that's why starting in
Speaker 6:  January, 2024 in the US only, you can't buy an
Speaker 6:  Apple, a newer Apple watch with the blood oxygen sensor feature enabled.
Speaker 6:  Well, that's all different today. There's a software rollout update and now
Speaker 6:  you can have the blood oxygen monitoring feature except,
Speaker 6:  you know, the, the, the workaround is that the
Speaker 6:  sensor on the watch collects the data and
Speaker 6:  it gets processed on the phone
Speaker 6:  so that you can view the data only on your phone and not on your wrist.
Speaker 5:  Right. Okay.
Speaker 6:  That's the workaround.
Speaker 5:  So the, the hack they figured out is as long as the watch doesn't
Speaker 5:  show you the blood oxygen sensor data, they can run it.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Wow. So for the past year and a half, they have been selling watches
Speaker 5:  with this sensor disabled and now they're enabling it. This Okay. The
Speaker 5:  thing that I find ridiculous about all of this. They could, apple
Speaker 5:  has so much money,
Speaker 6:  So much money.
Speaker 5:  They could just pay Massimo. They
Speaker 7:  Could, yeah. Is it just like a principle thing? What's up with this?
Speaker 6:  I They don't wanna pay.
Speaker 5:  I think so though, right? Like, I think they're like, listen, even if
Speaker 5:  you are right about it, I, and look, Massimo, they might be right, they might
Speaker 5:  not. I, it is going to continue to be litigated for a long time. But I think
Speaker 5:  that they're saying on principle, even if you're right,
Speaker 5:  we will drag you to the ends of the earth and we will deplete your legal
Speaker 5:  budget. Wow. Before we give in, I think's what's happening here, there's
Speaker 6:  Like multiple suits going on. So like initially,
Speaker 6:  like there, this, this thing goes back like over a decade at this point
Speaker 6:  where, you know, initially Apple went to Massimo, allegedly,
Speaker 6:  allegedly Apple went to Massimo and they were like, Hey, you know, we wanna
Speaker 6:  collab on blood oxygen. And then, you know, they po a
Speaker 6:  guy from, from Massimo who very subsequently soon leaves.
Speaker 6:  And so then Massimo's like, Hey, you stole our shit. This is the
Speaker 6:  scientific, you know, legal terms that they're using. You stole our shit.
Speaker 6:  And Apple was like, no, we didn't. Here's the Apple Watch series six with
Speaker 6:  blood oxygen monitoring. And they were like, Hey, hey. And so they filed
Speaker 6:  a suit and when that wasn't working, 'cause it was taking too long, they
Speaker 6:  went to the ITC because the whole, even the ITC thing is a workaround because
Speaker 6:  if you, because the, the supply chain and these devices being made in China,
Speaker 6:  if you can't import 'em, ha ha you can't import 'em. Pew, pew, pew. And
Speaker 6:  then Apple was just like, well first of all, we are going to exhaust every
Speaker 6:  legal option humanly possible to prevent this ban. Which is why, you know,
Speaker 6:  these, these proceedings started in 2020. It didn't happen until the
Speaker 6:  end of 20 23, 20 24. There's like a back and forth. The
Speaker 6:  band was paused, the band was unpaused, and then Apple was like, fine,
Speaker 6:  we will just disable it then.
Speaker 7:  How sick do you think Apple's lawyers are of this situation?
Speaker 6:  They are so sick of it. They're, they're so sick of it. And the irony is,
Speaker 6:  is that Massimo then came out with its own smart watches,
Speaker 6:  which look like the Apple watch and measure your blood
Speaker 6:  oxygen. And then Apple was like shenanigans
Speaker 7:  Petty to the nth degree. Yeah. So petty.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so what's our, what's our take on this one? Is, this is, I I is
Speaker 5:  the whole situation Is she, is it serious?
Speaker 6:  I think it's serious, but it's ridiculous.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, agreed.
Speaker 5:  I I think that's a fair take. I was gonna say it's right down the center
Speaker 5:  where it's, yeah, it's, it's over.
Speaker 6:  It's just ridiculous at this point. Also, the patents expire in 2028. So
Speaker 6:  this is very
Speaker 5:  Oh my stupid. I also, the fact that they were able to
Speaker 5:  remove a feature for a year and a half,
Speaker 5:  eh, maybe, maybe speaks to how important that feature is.
Speaker 6:  And I mean, I've written it all over, up and down across the, The Verge.
Speaker 6:  It's not that important of a feature. It just isn't. So it's
Speaker 5:  Rough. It's rough. That was once a flagship feature and Yeah,
Speaker 5:  they don't always pan out. No, they
Speaker 6:  Don't.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Final possible shenanigan.
Speaker 5:  As soon as I say the first word, you're gonna know the word Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  says he is suing Apple for rigging the app store. So
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna read this quote. Here's Elon on Twitter, or, sorry,
Speaker 5:  apologies. This is Elon on X. He says, quote, apple
Speaker 5:  is behaving in a manner that makes it impossible for any AI company
Speaker 5:  besides open AI to reach number one in the app store, which is
Speaker 5:  an unequivocal antitrust violation end quote.
Speaker 5:  And so he, he starts by claiming that they're rigging the rankings, but then
Speaker 5:  he kind of pivots very quickly and starts by claiming that actually what
Speaker 5:  they're doing is rigging the app store editorial. 'cause they have a bunch
Speaker 5:  of curated sections where they'll be like our favorite
Speaker 6:  Apps,
Speaker 5:  Like summer hotness, whatever, like check out these AI things and
Speaker 5:  they don't feature gr can you believe they won't feature Grok can believe
Speaker 6:  You mean gr the one that unlaunched like unleashed
Speaker 6:  sex bots very recently and just caught himself cabinet Rudy?
Speaker 6:  Oh no. Why would ever family friendly Apple not
Speaker 6:  put grok in its editorial section where it's allowed to
Speaker 6:  exercise opinions? Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean this is here, my feeling is also like
Speaker 5:  these apps aren't even like allowed in the app
Speaker 5:  store, right? Other apps that make deep fake nudes have been
Speaker 5:  banned. Right? They can't ban grok because Elon is too big of
Speaker 5:  a figure. He's already getting special treatment also.
Speaker 6:  Like absolutely his whole, his whole assertion that no other AI company can
Speaker 6:  reach, number one, didn't deep seek reach number one. Right,
Speaker 5:  Right. Actually, there's a community note on his tweet about this
Speaker 5:  being like, actually deep
Speaker 7:  Seek, my favorite also is like Sam Altman and Elon getting into
Speaker 7:  an yet another ex battle where Sam's like, oh, well
Speaker 7:  have you ever f you know, put your own
Speaker 7:  company's as special treatment. Have you ever given your own
Speaker 7:  company's special treatment? I couldn't believe it. So yeah, there's a lot,
Speaker 6:  You know, it feels like he saw what Tim Sweeney did with Epic
Speaker 6:  and he was like, I'm gonna do that. That's gonna work for me.
Speaker 5:  Well, well here's the thing, let me just add a little note there. Tim Sweeney
Speaker 5:  actually filed a lawsuit and Elon Musk at this point has not Mm.
Speaker 7:  He's never going to, he is just gonna tweet about it,
Speaker 5:  Which that is a bit of a pattern for him. Mm. So he, he
Speaker 5:  got a little mad at Apple. He retweeted a bunch of people
Speaker 5:  supporting him. Apple put out a statement later saying that the app store
Speaker 5:  is quote, designed to be fair and free of bias. I don't know what
Speaker 5:  that means.
Speaker 6:  I mean, if it's editorial, it's, you know, like just by the function of the
Speaker 6:  word editorial, there is some kind of opinion in there. But like,
Speaker 6:  to be
Speaker 7:  Fair, yeah, they said it's like a combo of algorithms, you know, recommendations
Speaker 7:  and opinion. So
Speaker 6:  This is a shenanigan. It
Speaker 7:  Definitely is. I'm calling because he knows nothings gonna come of it and
Speaker 7:  he knows that, you know, if it really was number one, it would reach number
Speaker 7:  one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is is nearly as much, this is like, perhaps
Speaker 5:  as much or more of a shenanigan than the perplexity one?
Speaker 7:  Definitely. Maybe more. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think it's more
Speaker 5:  Is more, I think it's more, this might be the ultimate one. Perplexity
Speaker 7:  At least had some investors apparently lined up that maybe would front the
Speaker 7:  money, you know? Yeah. They,
Speaker 5:  It's true.
Speaker 6:  They took like an action to to say like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  we're not all total like Bs, but like
Speaker 5:  Right. Elon just rtd a couple of randos on Twitter. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  as always. Yeah. Okay. Okay. So I think what's our running
Speaker 5:  total? Like two and a half shenanigans out of, out of four. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Okay. This, this is a big week for them.
Speaker 5:  Apple's somehow involved in most of them indirectly or,
Speaker 5:  or directly. It's, it's not always their fault. Okay.
Speaker 5:  We've gotta take a break when we get back the Thunder Round returns.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back with the thunder round, aka the Lightning round colon,
Speaker 5:  the Thunder round Colon Jake's version.
Speaker 6:  Love it.
Speaker 5:  As you all know, I've been on a power trip since Neli Patel left on
Speaker 5:  parental leave. The lightning round as we know it is done for this is now
Speaker 5:  the thunder round. I have given our producer Eric Gomez, the Power of Thunder
Speaker 5:  to make sure that we keep moving and get through all the important stories
Speaker 5:  that we wanna talk about. So we're gonna do five stories, five minutes each.
Speaker 5:  At 30 seconds we're gonna hear a ble of thunder telling us to move along.
Speaker 5:  If we keep going and get a little too far, we're gonna hear thunder crash
Speaker 5:  down and that's our moment to move along. Alright, let's get started.
Speaker 5:  The, you've got our first story today.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So my first story is Allison's little adventure turning
Speaker 6:  her LTE Apple watch into her only device.
Speaker 6:  So she's leaving her phone at home, she's going out and she's doing her
Speaker 6:  adventures. And Allison is like annoyingly,
Speaker 6:  well, And I say this with admiration, one of the funniest writers on staff.
Speaker 6:  So just reading this was just delightful. And like, I was just like,
Speaker 6:  she, she reached out to me and she's like, VI have this crazy idea. And I
Speaker 6:  was like, hit me, hit me with it, girl. What, what are you gonna do? And
Speaker 6:  she's like, what if I leave my phone's at home and just live off of a smartwatch?
Speaker 6:  And I went, God bless. Let me know how it goes. I ain't that crazy.
Speaker 6:  Let me see how, how it happens. And it happened like how I thought it would
Speaker 6:  happen, but it tickled me because I think she And I, our,
Speaker 6:  our beats continually like Fuse and merge together because of all the ways
Speaker 6:  that they're stuffing AI into our products. And
Speaker 6:  I think she And I both have just like had a lot of conversations about like
Speaker 6:  needing to step away from our devices in some, some capacity.
Speaker 6:  Like I had, I had a story that came out a couple weeks ago about
Speaker 6:  using Brick, which is like this thing that bricks your phone
Speaker 6:  And I use it during TV time to get my attention back. And she's like, I wanna
Speaker 6:  be more present in the world so I'm gonna leave my phone at home and just
Speaker 6:  use my LTE watch for like connectivity. And of course that comes
Speaker 6:  with its own trials and tribulations. Like she's like, oh
Speaker 6:  shit, how do I call an Uber? Wow. Do you call an Uber
Speaker 6:  without your phone? And like, it was just a really cute meditation on like
Speaker 6:  how reliant we are on these devices. Can you actually replace
Speaker 6:  your, your phone with your smartwatch in any capacity? And
Speaker 5:  I had a lot of fun. So the way I know this kind of worked is that, so this
Speaker 5:  is Alison Johnson, senior reviewer for The Verge. The way I know it worked
Speaker 5:  is that unlike Friday I was, I was saying to something, I'm like, no, I haven't
Speaker 5:  heard much from Allison this week. What's she up to? And someone was like,
Speaker 5:  oh yeah, she just like hasn't been using her phone all week for her
Speaker 5:  job and so she hasn't been talking to us. And I'm like, that was so effective.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that worked. It really, it worked. I just like, yeah, you know, like
Speaker 5:  that it was harder to get in touch with her de but I guess that was sort
Speaker 5:  of the point was functional. She was dead, she did a good job.
Speaker 7:  My favorite part was when she said she had visions of herself sitting at
Speaker 7:  a table at a sidewalk cafe wearing a billowy skirt, but she doesn't
Speaker 7:  own a billowy skirt. Like that was the energy she was gonna give off.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so I have a question and it's not for you VI know the answer,
Speaker 5:  Hayden, are you a smartwatch person?
Speaker 7:  No, I hate having things on my wrist. Like I can't, I don't the feeling
Speaker 7:  it's like, I think it's 'cause I do boxing as a workout. So a lot of people
Speaker 7:  use smartwatches as like a workout tracker also. And I would always have
Speaker 7:  to take it off 'cause I box. So I feel like I just don't like feeling something
Speaker 7:  on my wrist like that. I don't know. I can deal with rings, but not big
Speaker 7:  bracelets or anything like that.
Speaker 5:  So it's been a while since I've been like a regular smartwatch person. I
Speaker 5:  bought the original Apple Watch and then I immediately bought an Android
Speaker 5:  phone and it was just like, I just like had this watch that I couldn't use.
Speaker 5:  The thing that I think is really interesting about this is like there's this,
Speaker 5:  the, the sort of the conceit is okay, the watch is less
Speaker 5:  distracting than the phone, but I sort of wonder, and v this is a question
Speaker 5:  for you now, isn't the watch a little more annoying? 'cause it's literally
Speaker 5:  physically on your wrist there at all times and it's shaken around
Speaker 5:  trying to alert you to everything. It's, that almost seems more distracting.
Speaker 6:  It can be more distracting. Especially when you wear
Speaker 6:  to any given point in time. And they have
Speaker 6:  different notification settings just because like quick,
Speaker 5:  Quick wearable check. I think there's three on you today.
Speaker 6:  There's three on me today. Yeah. Well there's three on me today and two more
Speaker 6:  at my desk because they're glasses and so, you know that that's the whole
Speaker 6:  thing. But yeah, there I do get buzzes
Speaker 6:  a lot and especially on this Garmin that I'm, I'm testing at the moment because
Speaker 6:  it's a little less discerning with what notifications I get.
Speaker 6:  So it's just like, oh, they texted you. Oh, they texted you, eh, they texted
Speaker 6:  you and like they buzz. So,
Speaker 7:  And I can't answer this as a objective third party because whenever I'm
Speaker 7:  with someone who has an Apple watch or a smart watch, you know, it
Speaker 7:  makes me nervous. 'cause they're always looking at their wrist and I'm like,
Speaker 7:  oh, is it, am I boring you? Is it time to go? Obviously it's just they're
Speaker 7:  getting a text and they're like, oh sorry. But you know, it can be,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's definitely a, a social cue for sure where like,
Speaker 6:  I'm very cognizant of it, of just like things buzzing and being like
Speaker 6:  going back down looking at my wrist. Like I, I, I do,
Speaker 6:  I do think it's a different kind of distraction
Speaker 5:  Like with my phone if I do need to, like if, if I'm sitting down for dinner
Speaker 5:  with my wife, like I will put my phone somewhere else so that it's not
Speaker 5:  distracting me. 'cause like, listen, love y'all. But I get a, I got a lot
Speaker 5:  of slack pings all right. Like they do not stop. And
Speaker 5:  if, if it's on my person, if I know it's buzzed then there's just like a,
Speaker 5:  there's always that tension in my mind where I'm like, I gotta find out what
Speaker 5:  this is. I gotta find out if it's important. Sometimes it's just the weather.
Speaker 5:  Sometimes it's just telling me it's gonna rain And I did not need to see
Speaker 5:  that. And I do like that I can just like take my phone outta my pocket and
Speaker 5:  put it somewhere else. I'm with the watch. You're sort of
Speaker 6:  Like, that's why you gotta get the flippy flip dismiss that I do it all the
Speaker 6:  time. Just go.
Speaker 5:  So you're just eating and being like flinging your arm around?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. That's not distracting at all.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Okay. Alright Hayden, you're up.
Speaker 7:  Okay, so mine is how doctors are getting worse at detecting
Speaker 7:  cancer after they rely on ai. So really
Speaker 7:  scary and sad. Basically a new study just published this week found
Speaker 7:  that doctors who usually use AI to detect cancer and
Speaker 7:  colonoscopies now when it's taken away from
Speaker 7:  them, they got way worse at detecting cancer than they were before they ever
Speaker 7:  used ai. 'cause they basically got lazy, like their brains were used to just
Speaker 7:  relying on AI and kind of double checking it. And then even with all their
Speaker 7:  training when you take the AI away, they became way worse. I think six percentage
Speaker 7:  points worse.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's a little horrifying to me.
Speaker 6:  That's not good. That's very upsetting. That's, hmm.
Speaker 7:  You know, and they, yeah, they found like across countries, Poland, the,
Speaker 7:  the researchers came from Poland, Norway, Sweden, the UK and Japan. They
Speaker 7:  looked at four medical centers in Poland that were part of a trial program,
Speaker 7:  you know, using AI and colonoscopies and yeah, basically these doctors
Speaker 7:  are just gonna be SOL for whenever they stop God using ai. God, that's,
Speaker 5:  This is really interesting because I feel like there's been so much like
Speaker 5:  fear and concern. Like, AI's gonna make you dumber, AI's gonna make you dumber.
Speaker 5:  And I've been like trying to grapple with this where it's like, okay, I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't know how to use the Dewey decimal system, right? I don't know how
Speaker 5:  to go find a book and then look in the glossary and find the page
Speaker 5:  and f you know, read the context and figure out, right, I'm not reading as
Speaker 5:  much because I'm just gonna Google and I'm and Right. And Google's just giving
Speaker 5:  me, and then I read a website that's been written for me really nicely. So
Speaker 5:  like, okay, am I dumber because I use Google instead of going to a library
Speaker 5:  maybe a little bit. And so I'm like, okay, are we, are we kind of
Speaker 5:  overreacting with some of this AI stuff? But this is, this is concerning
Speaker 5:  to me because like, I
Speaker 6:  Think it's like GPS, right? Like if you always use GPS on your car
Speaker 6:  and then you just never, like, I'm calling out my spouse here.
Speaker 6:  Like they don't know how to get to a place that's five minutes away because
Speaker 6:  they always have GPS, so they only put GPS and when CarPlay doesn't
Speaker 6:  work and it's five minutes away, you've driven there a million times, they
Speaker 6:  don't know how to get there.
Speaker 7:  That's me. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, not a chance.
Speaker 6:  I think, I think that's kind of analogous to what's happening here with the
Speaker 6:  doctor. Yeah. So like even, you know how to drive, you could probably do
Speaker 6:  it on your own, but
Speaker 7:  Definitely. And you've also, I think it's also like a, a
Speaker 7:  thing when I found in a, some recent reporting I did on a Google Health,
Speaker 7:  like medical AI hallucination that people that double check
Speaker 7:  AI's work also get a little bit lazy and it's just kind of human nature.
Speaker 7:  If something's usually right, you're gonna not find
Speaker 7:  the discrepancies or the errors as much because you're like, oh, it's
Speaker 7:  probably right and you're usually not gonna, you know, pinpoint when it's
Speaker 7:  wrong. And so I think it's kind of the same thing. It's like if your brain
Speaker 7:  is used to relying on something, something that's usually right,
Speaker 7:  you're just gonna get worse at doing it on your own and you're gonna get
Speaker 7:  worse at identifying when it's wrong probably.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Hayden, I thought this piece you wrote, I think it was last week, was
Speaker 5:  fascinating where you found that, what was it, a Google research paper
Speaker 5:  had merged the name of two different areas of the brain
Speaker 5:  and kind of no one noticed
Speaker 7:  Exactly. It had more than 50 authors on it and they also had
Speaker 7:  doctors look at it before they published it. It was like the debut
Speaker 7:  research paper for Google's healthcare AI model, which they were positioning
Speaker 7:  to doctors as, you know, a good way to double check things, you know,
Speaker 7:  flag things, especially things missed by radiologists. And yeah, I mean it
Speaker 7:  made up a body parts. Google said it was just a
Speaker 7:  misspelling, but it was conflating essentially two different areas
Speaker 7:  of the brain. And if you did have an abnormality or a
Speaker 7:  stroke in one of those two areas, it would be treated differently from the
Speaker 7:  other. So I mean, it is a problem if, if you know, and especially like we
Speaker 7:  just said, if you're a doctor reading this and you're probably not gonna
Speaker 7:  find the error, just like they did in the actual research paper,
Speaker 7:  you may skip over it and maybe even mistreat the actual thing.
Speaker 6:  The term sounded real basilar ganglia. That sounds real.
Speaker 6:  'cause there is like a basilar thing in a ganglia in your brain. So,
Speaker 5:  Well, and this is what I thought was so interesting about that where, you
Speaker 5:  know, you, you have people in the story saying like, oh, it's, it's like
Speaker 5:  a common typo. Like people figure it out. But, but I do think like, okay,
Speaker 5:  sure may maybe they would've figured it out, but the turn is
Speaker 5:  if they get used to not checking right? Then you get into a
Speaker 5:  problem. And this study sort of emphasizes that where it's like
Speaker 5:  uhoh like In fact they are getting worse at it. In fact, that could make
Speaker 5:  medical care worse. And so like that gets a
Speaker 7:  Little,
Speaker 5:  It's concerning. Listen,
Speaker 6:  Check GPT five is better at healthcare, so says Sam
Speaker 6:  Altman.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And we'll see healthcare coding is,
Speaker 5:  it is just telling you to do the healthcare yourself. It's just
Speaker 6:  That's us healthcare system
Speaker 7:  Kind. I am, I am interested in how this affects people with health anxiety
Speaker 7:  because basically it said, oh, it's better at answering your questions about
Speaker 7:  your condition and it telling you what it might be.
Speaker 6:  And I have health anxiety's not good. It's bad.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's gonna be interesting for sure.
Speaker 5:  Okay, next story. A OL is
Speaker 5:  shutting down after 34 years, AOL dial up, I should say
Speaker 5:  AOL dial up is done after three decades.
Speaker 7:  R-I-P-I-I
Speaker 6:  Can hear it in my
Speaker 5:  Head. It's, I know it's beautiful, beautiful noise in retrospect.
Speaker 5:  I apparently, according to the 2023 US census,
Speaker 5:  there are currently, or there were around
Speaker 5:  160,000 people who still had dial-up internet,
Speaker 5:  which is sort of
Speaker 6:  Slow
Speaker 7:  Lot more than I explain.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I I wanna know what they're paying really
Speaker 7:  Peaceful lives, you know?
Speaker 5:  Right. What, this is the real question. What are they doing with it? You
Speaker 5:  can't load anything on that internet right now.
Speaker 7:  They're definitely just looking at like their a OL inbox and maybe like the
Speaker 7:  MSN homepage. That's what I think.
Speaker 6:  Is it Yahoo? They use Yahoo.
Speaker 7:  Oh definitely. Yahoo. Oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Actually can I say when I, when I looked up the, the
Speaker 5:  Apple core settlement with Apple Inc.
Speaker 5:  From 2007, the press release, the spokesperson
Speaker 5:  for Apple core AOL email address, those are 2 0 7. Wow.
Speaker 5:  Right. AOL is still around. You still see I haven't seen an AOL email address
Speaker 5:  in a while. You still get the Yahoos, you still get the MSN Not so
Speaker 5:  much.
Speaker 6:  I just, that sound though is forever in my head. Yeah. You
Speaker 7:  Know, maybe it'll become cool to have an a OL email address. You know, like
Speaker 7:  the, it's a nostalgia thing. I don't know, I could see that
Speaker 5:  Happening. Is that the like digit camm of emails? You're like, oh, Gmail
Speaker 5:  is for the millennials, we gotta, we're gonna like buy old a OL
Speaker 5:  addresses. Oh my god.
Speaker 6:  Happen. Especially since like, the inbox isn't unlimited, so you actually,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be like a mindfulness thing where they're just like, oh, you only
Speaker 6:  have 50 emails that you can have any given point in time.
Speaker 7:  Again, they're probably so zen.
Speaker 5:  Were you both a OL dial up users back in the day? Yes. Yeah. Yeah. Same.
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's, I mean I, I barely remember it
Speaker 5:  at this point. I remember it like, it was an app though. It was like an app
Speaker 5:  that you enter into. It was this, like this contained experience.
Speaker 6:  There's just like sound bites that I remember one, there's the connecting
Speaker 6:  thing for the dial up, but then also you got mail.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And like, welcome to a OL or something like that. And just like what the
Speaker 6:  homepage looked like. And
Speaker 7:  That was my neo pets era. Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  My god. That was mine too. Going to the free omelet every day.
Speaker 7:  Oh my gosh, that was so good. That's my shop song was
Speaker 7:  an Abba song. So good. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Neo Pet's still going strong though. It's, that is,
Speaker 7:  I tried to log in sometime in the past year and they deleted my account.
Speaker 7:  It was devastating.
Speaker 6:  My pork alerts, they're, they're all gone.
Speaker 5:  All right. Wow. A OL you had a run that
Speaker 5:  lasted way, way longer than it should have.
Speaker 5:  Thank you for getting us online and for imprinting that terrible noise in
Speaker 5:  all of our heads.
Speaker 6:  I hear it in my
Speaker 5:  Dream as we should next, next week on the thunder round, we're replacing
Speaker 5:  the thunder with the screech. Oh my
Speaker 7:  Gosh. Let's all make our ringtones sound
Speaker 7:  or our phone
Speaker 5:  Alarms, you know, that will really help us, you know, reduce
Speaker 5:  our desire to be near our phones. True. If they were like glaring that noise
Speaker 5:  all the time. Hundred
Speaker 6:  Percent. Oh God.
Speaker 5:  Okay. V what have you got for us?
Speaker 6:  We have the Pebble Time too because, oh, I got a, I got
Speaker 6:  a little email from Eric Koski who is the core devices CEO
Speaker 6:  and co-founder of the Pebble watches. And he's just like, we
Speaker 6:  got a design reveal the Pebble Time too. And because Pebble is
Speaker 6:  Pebble again, very recently they got the name back because they had
Speaker 6:  had to rebrand as core devices. So it was gonna be the core time two
Speaker 6:  and the core two duo. And like everyone was making intel chip jokes. But
Speaker 6:  it's back to being Pebble and it's really, I brought this one up because
Speaker 6:  we knew Pebble was coming back. We knew that Pebble just had these
Speaker 6:  diehard community fans for open source, smart watching. And it
Speaker 6:  was just interesting because in the comments on this, there seemed to be
Speaker 6:  like a war of ideologies of people who were like,
Speaker 6:  yes,
Speaker 14:  Finally the Pebble has returned and my life is complete again.
Speaker 6:  I read it. And that, that those voices, every single of the, one of the pebble
Speaker 6:  diehards, because for the last decade they've been in my dms going,
Speaker 6:  nothing
Speaker 14:  Will ever replace my pebble. I love it so much.
Speaker 6:  And then there are other people going just like, I dunno man, I need
Speaker 6:  LTE on my smartwatch. I need like NFC on my smartwatch. I needed to
Speaker 6:  do modern things. And like, those are very purposefully not on the
Speaker 6:  Pebble Time too. Like it's got RGB lighting, it's got a really retro design.
Speaker 6:  It's got ePaper as its display. It kind of feels
Speaker 6:  like one of those dumb phone devices. But
Speaker 6:  for your smartwatch, it's very retro. It's, it's, it's just gonna do the
Speaker 6:  simplistic minimalistic things. And it was interesting waiting into the comments
Speaker 6:  to see people who are just like,
Speaker 5:  Yes, pebble.
Speaker 6:  And then other people going like, it's ugly. Why would you do this? Like,
Speaker 6:  we're beyond this point. And I was just like, wow. It's so, it's so wild.
Speaker 6:  Just watching this play out in the comments. So.
Speaker 5:  Well I also suspect that like there's a, there's a real degree to
Speaker 5:  which if anybody thought that this was a real
Speaker 5:  threat to the smartwatch market, this would not have been allowed to happen.
Speaker 5:  No. Like literally would not have been. No. Google owned all of
Speaker 5:  this. Yeah, Google
Speaker 6:  Legit was just like, have
Speaker 5:  At. Right. Go.
Speaker 6:  Go have fun. Google
Speaker 5:  Was like, do the thing if if it makes you happy. Like where
Speaker 5:  literally right. Like Google, Google makes the Pixel
Speaker 5:  watch, right. That thing's not flying off store shelves. It's a lovely smart
Speaker 5:  watch. Not flying off store shelves i's
Speaker 6:  A great smart watch.
Speaker 5:  And even they are like, yeah, you can compete with us. It's fun. Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  like, is that's not, that's not the opposite of the Apple and Apple cinemas
Speaker 5:  thing. Yes, yes.
Speaker 6:  It's literally like, oh, you, you guys want your little pebble back. Have
Speaker 6:  fun. Come on in
Speaker 5:  And compete. Come
Speaker 6:  On in, come on, go in, come on.
Speaker 5:  But it is nice, right? I mean I, this is sort of like a little bit
Speaker 5:  playing off of what, what Allison did where it's like, this is going even
Speaker 5:  simpler. This is like, the watch is not gonna bug you.
Speaker 6:  No. Like you get your notifications, you can do a little bit of step tracking.
Speaker 6:  There's a compass in there, have about do what you will. There's a little
Speaker 6:  community that's been like keeping the pebble going, you know, during the
Speaker 6:  dark ages where there was no support and whatnot. Just a little community
Speaker 6:  of ragtag pebbles going and keeping this
Speaker 6:  thing alive and popping into every single smartwatch review that I've written
Speaker 6:  over the last however many years going,
Speaker 7:  I miss my pebble,
Speaker 5:  I miss my
Speaker 6:  Pebble. You know, like the, just like that kind
Speaker 5:  Stuff. It was a nice, it was a nice watch. And I think there's also, it is
Speaker 5:  like the ethos of it, right? Yeah. Because there's, I don't think there's
Speaker 5:  anything else. There's
Speaker 6:  Nothing else white
Speaker 5:  Like that white like in, in, you know, mainstream consumer technology that's
Speaker 5:  as like Tinker Tinker or friendly. It's
Speaker 7:  A cute watch. A cute name. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  Also just like, you know, smart watches and I've written this time and time
Speaker 6:  again, they kind of feel like the vanguards of walled garden
Speaker 6:  oss. Yes. Because they're there for you to stay stuck
Speaker 6:  to a particular phone. So everything is super siloed. So for Pebble to be
Speaker 6:  back out here and they're like, Hey, I'll open source. Let's have fun
Speaker 6:  Yolo, let's go. Like, it's just nice to have that vibe
Speaker 6:  come back at a time where like smart watches as a whole are super
Speaker 6:  duper siloed and that's why I have to carry around three fricking songs.
Speaker 5:  No, I completely agree. And it's, I mean it's, it's really funny. Like this
Speaker 5:  is like an updated version of the Pebble Time two, was
Speaker 5:  that what the original name was?
Speaker 6:  It was the Pebble Time. It was the pe but this is the Pebble Time two.
Speaker 5:  Oh, so this is actually a sequel now. Yeah. It still looks mostly the same.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it does. But like a little refined. And as far as I'm aware, the specs
Speaker 5:  like are barely changing. Right. It's mostly's mostly
Speaker 5:  the same device Better. Mostly the same feature set as it was 10 years
Speaker 5:  ago. Yep. It's, there's like no other device. You could be
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know if people were like iPhone five, here it is. Honestly.
Speaker 5:  Okay, I'm saying this. I might buy that. The iPhone five looked really good.
Speaker 5:  It was a good phone. It was a good phone. Yeah, it was. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I also missed the button, you know.
Speaker 5:  That's true. Let's, this is where it's gonna go. It's like the digit cam
Speaker 5:  people are gonna demand we go backwards.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right. The Pebble Time. It's supposedly shipping this summer.
Speaker 6:  It's supposedly shipping this year. Coming
Speaker 5:  This year, this year. This year is now. This year. It's,
Speaker 6:  It's coming sometime. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Very exciting days for the Pebble community. Y'all have been waiting.
Speaker 5:  It's a good moment. Okay. Hayden,
Speaker 7:  So Addie did a great piece this week on how
Speaker 7:  chatbots aren't divulging their secrets. They're not like an Oracle
Speaker 7:  when you ask it a question about how it works, its inner workings, why it
Speaker 7:  was banned from something like Grok was, or why,
Speaker 7:  you know, it's responding a certain way. What its secret prompts are, most
Speaker 7:  of the time it's not unveiling secrets of its inner workings in its system.
Speaker 7:  It's just kind of making something up. 'cause that's what it wants to do.
Speaker 7:  It wants to make you happy, it wants to answer your question. It's searching
Speaker 7:  the web and just becoming a pattern generator and you know, picking the next
Speaker 7:  most logical word.
Speaker 5:  Right? So this grok thing, grok like briefly got banned
Speaker 5:  from X, which is and
Speaker 7:  Blue sky.
Speaker 5:  And blue sky. Oh, first off, I cannot believe Brock was allowed on blue sky
Speaker 5:  for a second. That's the craziest thing I've ever heard.
Speaker 5:  So it got banned on X for, for mysterious reasons,
Speaker 5:  even though it seems to be the main feature on X these days. And then people
Speaker 5:  started asking it why it was banned and they were just like, oh, okay, well
Speaker 5:  gu you say so, but it had like a bunch of different explanations.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like one was that it's stated that Israel and the US are committing
Speaker 7:  genocide and Gaza. And then another one said it was content
Speaker 7:  refinements by XAI. And then another one said,
Speaker 7:  oh, it's because I identified an individual in adult content. So basically
Speaker 7:  I ran the gamut. Yes. Like no one knew why I was really banned and it didn't
Speaker 7:  know either.
Speaker 5:  It's, I mean this, it makes so much sense, right? You're like, why couldn't
Speaker 5:  I ask the chatbot about itself? But I think this is like just at an even
Speaker 5:  more basic level, I don't even think you can ask a chat bot what model it
Speaker 5:  is. Like it doesn't even always know.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't.
Speaker 6:  I did ask chat GPT five today, like what's the difference between the old
Speaker 6:  you and the new you? And it did give me some examples of
Speaker 6:  like what it can do better. But then I was just like,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I still bully you pretty hard. So,
Speaker 5:  But this is the thing, it's, it's still basing it off of like what it can
Speaker 5:  read, right?
Speaker 7:  Like I read the blog post.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right, right, right. It just know, it knows the exact same thing that
Speaker 5:  you can read.
Speaker 7:  And I think that a lot of times, you know, again, this is a human nature
Speaker 7:  thing of us, like personifying things or whatever. But you know, on
Speaker 7:  TikTok I see a lot of trends of people like treating chatbots like an oracle.
Speaker 7:  They're like, oh, I asked when the world was gonna end and it said this.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Like it's just reading a random Reddit comment, just putting that out
Speaker 7:  there or saying like, you know, out of everything I've ever told you, what
Speaker 7:  do you think is next for this company? Or whatever. I mean, there's
Speaker 7:  basically people, it is good at finding patterns, but it doesn't know the
Speaker 7:  future and it doesn't know, like, I don't know.
Speaker 7:  I mean, unless you can find it on the internet, it's not gonna tell you besides,
Speaker 7:  sometimes you can get it to un unveil some of its system prompts or its secret
Speaker 7:  hidden instructions. But I mean, that's it.
Speaker 5:  So that's what's so tricky though, right? I think particularly when, when
Speaker 5:  the chatbots first started coming out, And I think this happened on Bing
Speaker 5:  where, right, I think most of the Chatbots aren given
Speaker 5:  instructions, you would think that this would be some like fancy code
Speaker 5:  o of constraints on how these things operate. But there's actually just like,
Speaker 5:  some engineers are just like, be nice to the user,
Speaker 5:  give brief responses and it's just like English language, plain
Speaker 5:  text stuff and they kind of just like put that at the top of the chat and
Speaker 5:  hide it. Yep. And so there have been these instances
Speaker 5:  where people will figure out that, okay, if you do the right things, we say
Speaker 5:  it, the chat bot will reveal some of its prompts to you, which
Speaker 5:  lets you figure out how it's been designed to operate. And so there are like
Speaker 5:  a very occasionally these secrets you can divine Yes.
Speaker 7:  Only about the system prompt.
Speaker 5:  And, and that's it though, right? It's, it's, it's extremely limited. And
Speaker 5:  then because of this, I think, I mean it's probably for a lot of reasons
Speaker 5:  that are mostly related to human psychology, but I think this sort of lens
Speaker 5:  credence to it, people sort of think, okay, anything it says, anything
Speaker 5:  it says about itself is gonna be true and you just, you can't believe it.
Speaker 5:  No, it's actually, it probably even knows less if it's like a breaking news
Speaker 5:  scenario.
Speaker 7:  Right, exactly. And it's also hard because, yeah, I mean the fact that it
Speaker 7:  can find patterns in like economic conditions or like travel
Speaker 7:  patterns, all these patterns that it finds people think that it and also
Speaker 7:  find patterns in like what's gonna happen in the future or what's happened
Speaker 7:  in the past. And it's very, it's just hard because I think, you know, it's
Speaker 7:  really good at something and it's really bad at others and you know, we have
Speaker 7:  to remember what it's bad at.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  But it speaks so authoritatively so it's
Speaker 7:  Hard to Exactly. It's to, it's gaslighting us.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, I mean, it just says things confidently and So if
Speaker 6:  you can't suss what it is or it's really hard to remember what it is
Speaker 6:  and it isn't good at for the average person, I think just
Speaker 5:  There's also, if you trace this far enough, I think this is how you, you
Speaker 5:  start to get to some of those stories where people are like, it told me I
Speaker 5:  could run through a wall and so I, I ran at the wall and it's like, like,
Speaker 5:  no, no, no, no, no. Like please, like, you have to approach these things
Speaker 5:  with common sense. And I, I, I think
Speaker 5:  very in, in complete fairness, the fact that the
Speaker 5:  bot can't explain to you what it is doing
Speaker 5:  is really confusing. Especially when you have, you have these reasoning models
Speaker 5:  and he's like quote unquote thinking models. They'll explain their reasoning
Speaker 5:  and it looks really, really like intelligent and sensible. And
Speaker 5:  for it then to be like just totally, I have no idea what model I am, I
Speaker 5:  have to make that up. Right? I don't know why I acted this way.
Speaker 6:  So I asked to, how many Rs were in strawberry? It said three, which is correct,
Speaker 6:  but then it said there are three Rs in strawberry.
Speaker 7:  Oh, you know what it can't get right is the number of Rs in any US
Speaker 7:  state. And it keeps labeling maps incorrectly too.
Speaker 6:  It's great.
Speaker 5:  One day, one day maybe get a second official opinion
Speaker 5:  on your medical information, particularly
Speaker 6:  Doctor, always every day get a second medical. Just don't
Speaker 6:  listen to
Speaker 5:  And make sure that doctor is not using AI is is related to.
Speaker 5:  That's it for The Vergecast. If you like what we do here, the best way to
Speaker 5:  support us is to buy a subscription to The Verge at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  We'd love to hear your questions and feedback. Let us know what you wanna
Speaker 5:  hear us talk about this summer. Email us at vergecast at VERGE dot
Speaker 5:  com or give us a call 8 6 6 VERGE 11. The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast is a production of The Verge and V Media Podcast Network.
Speaker 5:  Our show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer, Travis Uck, and Andrew
Speaker 5:  Marina. Jen Tui has a great episode coming up on Tuesday. It's about
Speaker 5:  whether we can make Rosy the robot from the Jetsons a real thing.
Speaker 5:  See you next week.