# Transcript
ID: 7c5bc0ee-e0f0-42bc-8ba2-353cbb218ac4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3089575337091773662/-762377046001843643/s93290-US-5059s-1744712778.mp3
Description: It's time, once again, to see what's what in the streaming wars. For the third year in a row, our hosts — this time Nilay, David, and The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes — have to build a roster of streaming options that will win awards, show 4K content, satisfy their live TV needs, and much more. First, the hosts decide who won last year's competition, and then they pick their favorites for 2025.
Make sure you listen to the episode before you read this, but here are the results of the draft:
Jake's picks:
Cheap: Tubi
Awards: Netflix
4K: Hulu
Live: Instagram Live
Niche: PBS Passport
Content: LoFi Girl
Wild Card: Kanopy
Nilay's picks:
Cheap: TikTok
Awards: Max
4K: Disney Plus
Live: Sunday Ticket
Niche: Kaleidescape
Content: CNBC
Wild Card: F1 TV
David's picks
Cheap: Peacock
Awards: Amazon Prime
4K: YouTube Premium
Live: YouTube TV
Niche: BritBox
Content: Stranger Things season 5
Wild Card: Paramount Plus
We want to know who you think won the draft! Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, or call The Vergecast Hotline at 866-VERGE11, and tell us all your thoughts. And if you want to catch up, you can check out our draft from 2024 and from 2023. A lot has changed, and nothing has.
The Vergecast was nominated for a Webby, which means we can win a Webby People’s Voice Award and that’s voted online by you! So we’d love your support. You can vote at the link:https://bit.ly/3DXFgpN
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (23 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of like the fifth
Speaker 1:  row of apps on your smart tv. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I'm sitting
Speaker 1:  here reorganizing my Roku. I end up doing this like once a year or
Speaker 1:  so, usually, actually it's around March Madness when I go to download
Speaker 1:  the NCAA March Madness app so that I can watch college basketball
Speaker 1:  only to discover that. In this case, I have 86
Speaker 1:  items on my Roku, and a bunch of them are things that I've never heard of
Speaker 1:  before. Like I have a freebie app. I don't think freebie exists anymore.
Speaker 1:  I have one called Fum, which is just awesome with an F at the
Speaker 1:  beginning. What is that? I have an app that's called Purple.
Speaker 1:  There's a thing here for the Food Network. Go and
Speaker 1:  HGTV go. I'm pretty sure those are not a thing. I have a dealer No Deal app
Speaker 1:  on my Roku y basically, I assume my smart TV
Speaker 1:  is like most people's, where my top few rows are, like the
Speaker 1:  apps I actually use, and then the rest just becomes chaos. And so every once
Speaker 1:  in a while I come in and I clean up the chaos. That is not what we're
Speaker 1:  here to talk about today. This is my lot in life, and hopefully it's not
Speaker 1:  yours. What we're gonna do on the show today is the annual Vergecast Streaming
Speaker 1:  Draft. Once a year, we like to get together and as a way of kind of taking
Speaker 1:  stock of the streaming industry, we do a draft. We see who
Speaker 1:  can put together the best collection of streaming services, which ones are
Speaker 1:  gonna succeed, which ones are gonna fail completely, which ones will be here,
Speaker 1:  which ones won't be here, who's gonna win, who's gonna lose? We're gonna
Speaker 1:  make a lot of bets about the next 12 months in streaming. All on this
Speaker 1:  episode. All that is coming up in just a second. But first, a, a
Speaker 1:  quick request for you. So The Vergecast is nominated for a Webby award, which
Speaker 1:  means a lot to us. We've, we've been nominated for this in the past, and
Speaker 1:  the reason we care a lot about this award is because it's voted on by you.
Speaker 1:  This is an award that you can give to us if you so choose. And
Speaker 1:  so if you're willing to, I'll put a link in the show notes. We'll put a link
Speaker 1:  in the container post on the site. Please go to the link. Vote for The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  work against, honestly, some really great competition this year. There are
Speaker 1:  a bunch of really good tech podcasts out there right now, but I really wanna
Speaker 1:  win. We, we would really, really like to have the Webby. It's this cool like
Speaker 1:  springy award thing, and it just means a lot to us. So if you're willing,
Speaker 1:  please go vote for us. We're gonna get back to The Vergecast. I'm gonna go
Speaker 1:  delete. I have like three Hallmark logos on here for some reason, so I'm
Speaker 1:  gonna fix that. Then we're gonna get to it. This is The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 1:  be right back.
Speaker 1:  with the Alex Kranz saga, which means you, you
Speaker 1:  either get to or are saddled with Alex's picks from last year, and
Speaker 1:  then we're gonna go forward. So, congratulations and I'm
Speaker 1:  sorry and welcome. I'm gonna do my best to honor the chaos of her
Speaker 1:  picks and bring that energy into 2025. They were truly chaotic.
Speaker 1:  So just to remind everybody how this works,
Speaker 1:  we have, we have made it slightly more complicated every year, and I'm very
Speaker 1:  proud of that fact. But basically what's going to happen is we're gonna decide
Speaker 1:  first who won last year's streaming draft. I'm gonna read out what
Speaker 1:  we all picked. We're gonna decide who won. This is based
Speaker 1:  on vibes, if we're being honest with each other. I looked up like,
Speaker 1:  can you find a report card? And it turns out Eli picked Sony Bravia Corps
Speaker 1:  and Billboard Pro does not spend a lot of time litigating the success of
Speaker 1:  Sony Bravia Corps. So we're just gonna read 'em all aloud. There's no need
Speaker 1:  to litigate it, David. It's the winner. Sure. So it's,
Speaker 1:  it's so obvious you don't talk about it. Yeah, I mean, it's, It is, It is
Speaker 1:  the air we breathe, and then we're gonna go through and we're each gonna
Speaker 1:  draft into, we have seven categories. So there's, I,
Speaker 1:  I'll read the categories in a minute again so everybody can remember, but
Speaker 1:  there's Cheap awards, 4K Live Niche, Wild Card,
Speaker 1:  and a new one this year, which is content. I'll explain all of those
Speaker 1:  once we order the draft. But the first thing we have to do here is decide
Speaker 1:  who gets to go first. Each service can only be picked once
Speaker 1:  it's a draft. This is how we do it. So last year,
Speaker 1:  NELI, you picked TikTok, the Disney bundle,
Speaker 1:  Sony Braco, yes. YouTube TV with Sunday Ticket
Speaker 1:  Motor Trends tv and Max. I'm
Speaker 1:  obviously the winner. I wanna be very clear, honestly, are we sh
Speaker 1:  that's a dominant performance in the draft.
Speaker 8:  Can I tell you something? Sony Braco is not even named Braco anymore.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I don't even think it was named Braco when you picked it, which,
Speaker 8:  whatever It is. I was looking up the FAQ for this thing. They can't even
Speaker 8:  explain what It is or how it works.
Speaker 1:  That's true. And that's why it's like explaining the internet, right? It's
Speaker 1:  just there when you buy a Sony tv. Also, I think MotorTrend TV is dead.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So I'm not, look, I'm just saying on, on its face.
Speaker 1:  This is a dominant performance with some, with some risks
Speaker 1:  thrown in the, in the mix.
Speaker 8:  You know, TikTok, you know, big, big winner there that really pulled
Speaker 8:  through. I i you're, you're maybe cashing out right on
Speaker 8:  time there.
Speaker 1:  There's a real chance that most of my picks don't exist by the end of this
Speaker 1:  conversation. We literally had to push recording this episode a week
Speaker 1:  to see if TikTok would still be here. This is, this is how tenuous things
Speaker 1:  are. But anyway, so those are ne last picks. Alex's picks, which Jake
Speaker 1:  are now your legacy. Welcome. Were Peacock, Hulu,
Speaker 1:  Netflix, the Channels app, crunchy Roll,
Speaker 1:  and Paramount Plus
Speaker 8:  I, to be honest, I did not know how to figure out what the Channels app was.
Speaker 8:  I just have a list that says channels.
Speaker 1:  Channels is, I would say like Imagine
Speaker 1:  Piracy.
Speaker 8:  Okay. But
Speaker 1:  Like less. Does that make sense? Channels is a good way. You can get all
Speaker 1:  the fast channels. That's good. You can, you can get a bunch of, you can,
Speaker 1:  you can sort of curate your own TiVo situation, but it's more complic. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  You have an antenna, you want channels to run all of that for
Speaker 8:  You. Well, lemme say something. Sounds like the two of you are pretty supportive
Speaker 8:  of channels as a pick. So I'm feel pretty good about that. It
Speaker 1:  Was, it was, it was a good one. It was a good Alex for
Speaker 8:  Sure. And lemme say this, for, for Peacock, not only did they announce
Speaker 8:  a new season of Poker Face, but it didn't stream last year, but it will
Speaker 8:  this year. This is true. And not only
Speaker 8:  are there Olympics, they'll have it eventually.
Speaker 1:  If NBC has its way, there will be Olympics every year for the rest of our
Speaker 1:  lives.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But, but I I, I'm not sure how big
Speaker 8:  that's been for them. So I I I think there's some ups and downs here. Hulu
Speaker 8:  I think is rock solid. Netflix, we had
Speaker 8:  what, last year we got a a, a season of Stranger Things season.
Speaker 1:  Squid
Speaker 8:  Game. I mean, yeah. That, that's just showing how
Speaker 8:  rock solid their service is. You know, Kres did pretty good.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, this is good. Okay. And then my picks were
Speaker 1:  YouTube, just base YouTube, apple
Speaker 1:  TV plus AKA, the severance pick Tubi, which
Speaker 1:  streamed the Super Bowl. Just saying Prime video, the
Speaker 1:  Criterion Channel and Instagram reels. And just really quick, I'm going to
Speaker 1:  say I didn't win because I picked Instagram reels. So I just immediately,
Speaker 1:  I'm not allowed to win because I picked Instagram reels. You have the real
Speaker 1:  like discount bundle here. I do. Right? YouTube. YouTube with ads.
Speaker 1:  Just like plain old YouTube with ads. Yeah, apple TV plus, which you get,
Speaker 1:  if you sneeze loudly enough in an Uber Tubi, which
Speaker 1:  is free Prime video, which is free,
Speaker 1:  essentially free. Yeah. Criterion is good, right? You got, you got the one
Speaker 1:  gesture in Instagram reels, which is just fully temu TikTok
Speaker 1:  knock off TikTok. Yeah. Yeah. But
Speaker 8:  It's not banned.
Speaker 1:  It's, it, It is here to stay
Speaker 8:  And it's not going to be banned theoretically.
Speaker 1:  So there, there is an argument to be made that I intend to make that Instagram
Speaker 1:  reels is actually a very compelling pick in this year's draft for precisely
Speaker 1:  that reason. But we're gonna come back to that. So it's pretty
Speaker 1:  clear to me that Alex Crans won the draft last year.
Speaker 1:  I would say, if you look at it, Peacock did the Olympics last year.
Speaker 1:  Huge success. Netflix is like, has won the streaming wars
Speaker 1:  Paramount Plus still exists, which was not guaranteed a year ago, but
Speaker 1:  it's still here doing stuff. By the way. Can I, can I be clear? MotorTrend
Speaker 1:  TV did fold, but then it was purchased by something called
Speaker 1:  the Velocity Network, which relaunched it as a regular cable channel.
Speaker 1:  So it's, it's an 87 on the Go. 90 scale immediately. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's like a private equity. Go 90. It's good. It's good. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Kranz is list is is filled with some, some, you know,
Speaker 8:  I'm not saying Paramount Plus is a, a huge winner. Huge. But this list
Speaker 8:  has just all of the channels. Like, it's, this is just everything that you
Speaker 8:  actually want to watch. I don't know how you guys allowed this
Speaker 8:  much to get,
Speaker 1:  I'm sorry. I have TikTok in the Disney bundle. I have a lock on everyone's
Speaker 1:  time.
Speaker 8:  You have, you have Bluey, which I think is, is big for a certain audience.
Speaker 1:  And I have Hulu
Speaker 8:  Y that's that's true. Yeah. I
Speaker 1:  Don't remember, I remember this being controversial that I got to pick the
Speaker 1:  bundle. It's sort
Speaker 8:  Of cheating.
Speaker 1:  I think Kranz picked Hulu with ads like solo or something. Mm.
Speaker 1:  I believe she picked just Hulu. Either Hulu
Speaker 1:  by itself or Hulu with live tv. I think that's the one
Speaker 1:  because you had to solve live. Right? Right. So I think
Speaker 1:  that's Hulu live tv, which is an important, which no longer
Speaker 1:  exists.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well
Speaker 1:  Fully gone. 90. All right. I'm advocating for myself. What a surprise.
Speaker 1:  I think TikTok, the Disney bundle and Sunday Ticket and Max
Speaker 1:  is a winning lineup regardless of my, my
Speaker 1:  Bravia core situation, which I hold dearly to my own heart.
Speaker 8:  If you wanna tell me that people who love anime weren't
Speaker 8:  the winners of 2024, then I, I
Speaker 8:  don't even know if we're in the same conversation.
Speaker 1:  And somehow here in 2025 with the opening eye situation, they're the
Speaker 1:  obvious losers this year.
Speaker 1:  Alright, David, you got, you gotta make the, actually, Jake, I mean, I, I
Speaker 1:  I I know you're repping crayons here, but you're the most neutral observer.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 8:  True. I'm absolutely not neutral here. Damn it. I'm all in on crayons. Can
Speaker 8:  I tell you something? I prepped my list assuming I was gonna go
Speaker 8:  last, so I have to completely retool
Speaker 1:  This now. Good. Even better.
Speaker 8:  I was just like, there's no way I won.
Speaker 1:  We're giving it to, to Jake both because I do think Alex won and
Speaker 1:  because you're new and it feels like a nice thing to do. So that's the reason
Speaker 1:  I'm okay with this. I appreciate that. I think that I won on the merits and
Speaker 1:  boy is that gonna make, I have the only 80 megabit per second streaming service
Speaker 1:  on this entire list. If you wanna watch Spider-Man movies,
Speaker 1:  neli wins. You have to buy a new TV every time
Speaker 1:  you wanna watch a movie. That's the rule. Like that's what I and
Speaker 1:  Sony's prices and with Sony's naming scheme.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. If you can name two Sony televisions correctly, you can win.
Speaker 1:  All right, Jake, you're it. So let me, let me remind everybody how this works.
Speaker 1:  So we, we are going to pick seven streaming services each.
Speaker 1:  This episode may take us several hours and
Speaker 1:  instead of just picking your favorite seven in order we each have to
Speaker 1:  fill categories. Some of these are very simple and some of them are very
Speaker 1:  complicated. So the seven categories are Cheap, which means it has
Speaker 1:  to have some tier under $10. It can be free, it can be
Speaker 1:  nine point 99. It just, you have to be able to access this service for less
Speaker 1:  than $10. That one's most of them. There's awards, which
Speaker 1:  means this service has to have won an Oscar. Any Oscar, big, small, I don't
Speaker 1:  care what it was, but it has to have won an Oscar 4K, which means it has
Speaker 1:  to offer content in 4K live. The service has to have some kind of
Speaker 1:  live element, which is actually going to be much easier this year than it
Speaker 1:  was even last year. Niche. It has to be a genre
Speaker 1:  specific service. This one's a little mealy, but we'll figure it out together.
Speaker 1:  There is content, which is a new thing this year, and that is you get to
Speaker 1:  pick a show or a movie from any streaming service
Speaker 1:  that you didn't draft. So if you don't have Netflix, but you really want
Speaker 1:  Squid Game, you can draft Squid Game as your thing. And that just goes on
Speaker 1:  your roster as something that counts for you. It has to be on something you
Speaker 1:  didn't draft, but it can be anything you want. And then there's Wild Card,
Speaker 1:  which is anything you want in the whole universe. Wait, is the content one,
Speaker 1:  the, the Torrent pick, like your one
Speaker 1:  escape valve is you get to Torrent one show? No, I mean, I
Speaker 1:  guess if you want, if it's like a weird European documentary you can't get
Speaker 1:  otherwise, then sure. No, I'm just saying like, if you don't pick Apple TV
Speaker 1:  plus, but you want severance, you can just pick it. And the assumption is
Speaker 1:  we're not gonna ask too many questions. Right. That that's, I that's what
Speaker 1:  I'm getting at. Right? Like it's, we are just like, I'm gonna sneak into
Speaker 1:  Ben Stiller's house and the dead of night and leave. Right. With some hard
Speaker 1:  drives and find, okay. The conceit here is, is is breaking and
Speaker 1:  entering. Yes, that's correct. I just wanna be clear. Yeah. Tiptoeing
Speaker 1:  around the category. Right? So each thing can only be
Speaker 1:  drafted once, not once in each category, once period. And once it's
Speaker 1:  gone, it's gone. So we are going to draft 21 unique things in
Speaker 1:  this draft. Does that make sense? Any questions? Ready to go? Let's roll.
Speaker 1:  All right, you're up first. Jake, what do you got? We're starting with Cheap.
Speaker 1:  Well wait, you don't have to start with Cheap. No, you can go in any order
Speaker 1:  you want. You just have to fill out the cart. I can anywhere if you
Speaker 8:  Can do anything you want. Guys, guys, this is David. This rule sheet
Speaker 8:  could have, could have been more detailed. Alright.
Speaker 8:  Who
Speaker 1:  I will say the, the key, just as someone who, as a veteran of this draft,
Speaker 1:  you should think about the service that is most likely to be competitive
Speaker 1:  and the category that is most likely to be difficult to
Speaker 1:  fill out later
Speaker 8:  In. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Those, those are the two things I would keep in your head early in the draft.
Speaker 1:  You know, David's a competitor. He's lying to you.
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna start, I'm gonna start strong and I'm gonna go for Awards.
Speaker 8:  And the Awards category is the, the category I hate the most because there
Speaker 8:  are three streaming services that have won Oscars.
Speaker 8:  It's not, not a long list. Normally I'm a, I'm a real hater of
Speaker 8:  this streaming service, but in 2025, Netflix
Speaker 8:  has the final season of Stranger Things, the final season of Squid Game
Speaker 8:  and a new Knives out movie. And I'm sure there'll be some other stuff that's
Speaker 8:  worth watching. So for those three alone, I'm gonna lock in Netflix
Speaker 8:  for the awards category.
Speaker 1:  It's a good choice. I do, I think, I think Netflix
Speaker 1:  deserves to be the first overall pick in this draft.
Speaker 8:  It's normally, I I, I'm very
Speaker 8:  subscribe on, subscribe on Netflix. I feel like they have some
Speaker 8:  long periods of some like,
Speaker 8:  reality ish stuff that I'm not super in love with.
Speaker 8:  But they've got a handful of really great series and I'm gonna be
Speaker 8:  subscribing at various points this year no matter what. So I feel pretty
Speaker 8:  good about opening with Netflix.
Speaker 1:  Are you consistently good at like, remembering to unsubscribe when
Speaker 1:  you're done watching something? I like Aspire to be that good at switching
Speaker 1:  streaming services and instead I just pay for too many of them. All
Speaker 8:  The amount of times that I look at the Netflix tile on my TV and go, oh,
Speaker 8:  got unsubscribe is like 10 times higher than the amount of times I actually
Speaker 8:  unsubscribe. Okay.
Speaker 1:  That makes me feel better. Like I just, I went to resubscribe to Paramount
Speaker 1:  Plus to watch Champions League soccer because I subscribed to it to watch
Speaker 1:  Champions League Soccer last year. And I was like, oh, I'll just resubscribe
Speaker 1:  and do it this month. And found that I had just stayed subscribed the whole
Speaker 1:  time. So you're welcome. For my like $150 Paramount Plus.
Speaker 8:  Hey, somebody's gotta keep them in business. Yeah. And lemme be specific
Speaker 8:  here. I'm paying for 4K. Ooh.
Speaker 1:  All right. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Okay. I'm, I'm not dealing with ads. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  That's very important. That is important. There was the first time we ever
Speaker 1:  did this draft, there was a like, overall price component, but
Speaker 1:  frankly it's too hard to track what these things cost anymore. So we just
Speaker 1:  gave up on that. It's just not worth it. And they'll all be different in
Speaker 1:  a year and who cares, but okay. You're, you're going high tier Netflix
Speaker 8:  Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1:  In the awards category. I like it for you. All right. Nila, you get to be
Speaker 1:  up second because Bravia cord is such a smashing success. Oh, don't
Speaker 1:  worry. I have more extremely weird choices to come. I'm starting
Speaker 1:  strong again with Cheap and going with TikTok.
Speaker 8:  Mm.
Speaker 1:  I've picked it first two years in a row. Yep. And I'm sticking with it.
Speaker 1:  You, you're not worried that this time next year there will be no TikTok
Speaker 1:  in the United States. I'm worried there won't be United States this time
Speaker 1:  next year, David. So I'm just, just gonna close my eyes and, and, and
Speaker 1:  you know, where we will watch the downfall possibly on TikTok. It's very
Speaker 1:  true. It's real. But yeah, I think, I think for the, the purpose
Speaker 1:  of this draft, you can't, you can't be worried about, you know, the nagging
Speaker 1:  ACL injury. You just gotta go, you gotta go with the consensus number one.
Speaker 1:  Do you think so like, I think Netflix is pretty undeniably
Speaker 1:  more powerful now than it was 12 months ago. Is TikTok,
Speaker 1:  has TikTok gone up or down since we last did this draft? Sideways.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Right. It it just remains, it, it's so
Speaker 1:  powerful. You can't get rid of it, but it's so
Speaker 1:  weak that at any moment it might disappear. Hmm. Right. It might just collapse
Speaker 1:  under its own weight or it might become this political pawn. But I think
Speaker 1:  in terms of where the culture is day to day, and it's still TikTok, no
Speaker 1:  one is, no one's opening Instagram reels to find new music. No one
Speaker 1:  is forced to contend with like everyday Olivia Rodrigo is in
Speaker 1:  a new South American country. And you just have to see it happen. Like
Speaker 1:  that's TikTok and like the music industry is still dependent on it. There,
Speaker 1:  there's just something. Ha White Lotus had its entire Parker pose moment
Speaker 1:  on the back of TikTok. It's TikTok. Is it weaker
Speaker 1:  than ever? Yes. As a, as a company, as an entity. I think culturally
Speaker 1:  it's still strong as it has been. I think that's right. I don't know if it's,
Speaker 1:  yeah, I I think sideways is probably right on that front. It's not, it doesn't
Speaker 1:  feel like it's more central to culture than it was, but I think that's just
Speaker 1:  'cause we're so used to how central It is to like the, the, there are fewer
Speaker 1:  people being excited about. Like, it breaks some
Speaker 1:  30-year-old song becomes the number one hit again. 'cause we're just, that's
Speaker 1:  just what happens. That's just how TikTok works now. Yeah. And the conspiracies
Speaker 1:  about it are even weirder. Like Meta secretly runs the algorithm. Is that
Speaker 1:  a conspiracy? Oh yeah. Like it was our, it's already been sold.
Speaker 1:  There's just like another ing like it's become more of just a platform that
Speaker 1:  everybody understands, to your point. But it still is the thing that creates
Speaker 1:  the cultural moments in a way that very few other platforms can do as
Speaker 1:  regularly as TikTok does. But I like it.
Speaker 1:  All right. You guys picked the two I was gonna pick Oh,
Speaker 1:  a decision on the Disney bundle. By the way, we're gonna treat the Disney
Speaker 1:  bundle as three separate things. There is no Disney bundle this year. You,
Speaker 1:  you can, you can take Disney Plus, you can take ESPN and you can take Hulu,
Speaker 1:  but you can't take all three at once. Sure. Simple enough. Right? Oh, by
Speaker 1:  the way, can I make one? Can I say one more thing about TikTok please? I've
Speaker 1:  watched a number of movies on TikTok this year. Oh yeah. It,
Speaker 1:  it might be all you need. I watched, do you know the Jason Statham movie?
Speaker 1:  The Beekeeper? Yeah. For some reason that is all over my TikTok
Speaker 1:  recently. That's amazing. Yeah. Every now and again, TikTok is like, you
Speaker 1:  know what, that's gonna happen. You're gonna watch a few Good Men and you
Speaker 1:  just do, it's fine. Love it. It's just, it's just what goes down.
Speaker 1:  It's great lately. It's like you, you, because of Al Comer, I've watched
Speaker 1:  both Top Guns, but intercut with each other. Oh, that's fun. In a very odd
Speaker 1:  way. Yeah. It's great. Sure.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I I'm gonna take in
Speaker 1:  live,
Speaker 1:  I hate this already. I'm going with it. I'm gonna take YouTube TV in live.
Speaker 1:  Woo.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah, because
Speaker 1:  I think live is one of the
Speaker 1:  trickier categories here because ev everything
Speaker 1:  it does It is, is equally available other places and it's gonna get messy.
Speaker 1:  And also YouTube TV is just kind of running away with it
Speaker 1:  in terms of like, what is the future of cable? The answer's just YouTube
Speaker 1:  TV. It is just winning this game. When you think about things of the future,
Speaker 1:  you think about cable pretty much, but it's for
Speaker 1:  everything else is turning into bundles and YouTube TV is already that bundle.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The, the one thing about YouTube TV that confuses me
Speaker 1:  is that Google has not just sold a YouTube TV
Speaker 1:  device. Like any Google TV that you buy,
Speaker 1:  it doesn't just light up with like YouTube TV is here,
Speaker 1:  they have integrations, right. It's still an operating system with apps and
Speaker 1:  tiles and like, yes, you can get to a guide, but they, no one has.
Speaker 1:  And I think only Google could do it just been like, it's a cable box,
Speaker 1:  right? Like I have the Google TV streamer right there. Yeah. And I love it.
Speaker 1:  It is a, It is a terrific set top box. But you're right. Like I, I want to
Speaker 1:  be able to log into YouTube TV and the very first thing it shows me is not
Speaker 1:  the home screen. It should show me YouTube TV. Yeah. And then I should back
Speaker 1:  out into the apps. Like that would make the whole experience better.
Speaker 1:  And I think more compelling. And it's funny 'cause Apple on the Apple TV
Speaker 1:  has the button on their remote and they are desperate to make their app the
Speaker 1:  actual interface. Yeah. But they don't have the content. And then Google
Speaker 1:  has all of the content and they haven't done it.
Speaker 8:  David, I feel like you're describing the old school, you
Speaker 8:  know, cable box where you just like went to on-demand content and like
Speaker 8:  navigated through this super sluggish and slow interface to like watch
Speaker 8:  whatever five movies are available for you. Which was not
Speaker 8:  my favorite, but It is, you know, you jump right into stuff.
Speaker 1:  It is, It is my strong belief that when you turn on your
Speaker 1:  television, the first thing it should show you is not a home screen. I
Speaker 1:  think that is like a disastrous product decision. We have let everybody make
Speaker 1:  that. When I turn on my tv, it shouldn't show me television. It should
Speaker 1:  show me television put keep on the last thing I was watching,
Speaker 1:  pick something for me and put it on. Like, I don't care what It is. It's
Speaker 1:  like I, I don't turn on my TV to scroll through apps.
Speaker 8:  David, are you pro Netflix autoplaying things? Yes,
Speaker 1:  But I'm not pro them doing it with volume. This
Speaker 8:  Is gonna get you canceled. This is, that's an unacceptable Take the
Speaker 1:  Tiles. This is, this is a conspiracy theory that I have not validated, but
Speaker 1:  believe to my bones when it autoplays in the tiles, It is 10
Speaker 1:  times louder than the actual volume of the program. Alright. We, we have
Speaker 1:  to keep going. I will say it tries me, and I've asked any number of streaming
Speaker 1:  executives this and I know David has to, all of them should make a fake TikTok
Speaker 1:  that when you're in the, that just shows you bits and pieces of middles of
Speaker 1:  movies. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. And then you can hit the button and it starts
Speaker 1:  playing on the tv.
Speaker 8:  Yes. That's good.
Speaker 1:  A hundred percent agree. Yeah. And they all love that idea and just absolutely
Speaker 1:  cannot figure out how to do it. Alright, so that's my pick YouTube TV.
Speaker 1:  Jake, you're up next. What's up?
Speaker 8:  All right. You guys got some good picks here. Those,
Speaker 8:  those sting,
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna head over to what I think is going to be the,
Speaker 8:  what, what feels like the next hardest category to me, which is 4K,
Speaker 8:  which is sort of all of them, but also lends itself to I
Speaker 8:  think, just big mainstream services. And I think there's a couple left
Speaker 8:  that, that feel pretty strong to me. I'm gonna,
Speaker 8:  guys, guys, I'm, I'm,
Speaker 1:  It's amazing how hard it gets so quickly,
Speaker 8:  Right. Second guessing myself as we speak, we're gonna
Speaker 8:  lock in on, on Hulu. Hulu is
Speaker 8:  trusty. It's reliable. It has a solid content of
Speaker 8:  old TV shows. There's always something to watch there. They don't necessarily
Speaker 8:  have big winners, but they have a solid movie selection. You know, I've
Speaker 8:  got Netflix for some new original content. I feel
Speaker 8:  good about having Hulu as a backup there. It's a, it's a, It
Speaker 8:  is a standby service.
Speaker 1:  I don't hate it. I feel like 4K is just turning into the name a
Speaker 1:  streaming service. Now
Speaker 8:  It is a little bit,
Speaker 1:  A little bit this, this category has gotten easier to, to match,
Speaker 1:  which is good. But I think you're right, Jake, that It is increasingly, it's,
Speaker 1:  it, this is another place to get one of the heavy hitters in here. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And so I think, I think you picked it, right? You,
Speaker 8:  You both took the, the, the top like, you know, social options,
Speaker 8:  I'm assuming, did, does YouTube TV include all of YouTube?
Speaker 1:  No. Regular YouTube is is still available.
Speaker 8:  Regular. YouTube is still available. If
Speaker 1:  You'd like to change you, you are welcome to
Speaker 8:  You regular YouTube is straight up on my list. Feel this feels like cheating
Speaker 8:  to change this, but I, if, if regular YouTube is available, I'm gonna make
Speaker 8:  that change. Okay. Please. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  What's, what's your category
Speaker 8:  Guys? No, I'm, I'm locking on, on Hulu. Forget this. Okay. We're, we're,
Speaker 8:  we're we're holding to it. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Hulu in 4K, Hulu,
Speaker 8:  Hulu. And It is in 4K people.
Speaker 1:  I think Hulu is kind of underrated these days. There's a lot of good stuff
Speaker 1:  on Hulu. Like the, the original, although I've been watching Paradise.
Speaker 1:  That's very good. Highly recommend. But there's just, it's like Hulu is
Speaker 1:  the one I go to where it's just like, there's just 1,000,030 minute sitcoms
Speaker 1:  that I'm going to enjoy. Yeah. It's because it's Fox. Yeah. Like fundamentally
Speaker 1:  it's Fox. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 8:  Hulu is the most boring pick. Nobody's ever like super hyped to open
Speaker 8:  up Hulu and see the new thing.
Speaker 8:  But it, it has the thing that you are going to watch after a long day and
Speaker 8:  you're just like, I need to put something on like when the TV auto plays
Speaker 8:  something, it should be whatever is on Hulu
Speaker 1:  Cat. You're picking catalog. Yes.
Speaker 8:  This makes sense. This is, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't hit it. I'm, I'm, I'm with it. It's a good one. Neli. What's
Speaker 1:  next? What do you got? I'm gonna put Max in awards.
Speaker 1:  Mm mm That's my move. Okay. Because because you, you get that
Speaker 1:  HBO I'm assuming the pit will will be up for awards this year.
Speaker 1:  They've got the movies, they've got the catalog of movies. Feel, it feels
Speaker 1:  correct to me. It's a little like, I I don't think Max Originals have won
Speaker 1:  Oscars yet, but it's like HBO. Yeah. It's, it's, the Lion
Speaker 1:  is straight enough that I'll I'll give it to you. Yeah, we'll, we'll allow
Speaker 1:  it. Why, why Max? Are you sure? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Is Max gonna still be here? That's, is America
Speaker 1:  still gonna be here David?
Speaker 1:  Like this is a very nihilistic draft for me. Like I'm thinking about tomorrow.
Speaker 1:  I'm not thinking about next year. Okay. Fair enough. But I, max has the depth
Speaker 1:  of content it has, it's funny, I have to log into someone
Speaker 1:  else's max account to get 4K. Right. It's like I can't put it in 4K
Speaker 1:  'cause I don't have it in 4K because I'm still grandfathered into my at
Speaker 1:  t free max subscription, which at t knows about because I
Speaker 1:  keep mentioning it on the show and they can't figure out how to stop giving
Speaker 1:  me free Max either. Perfect. But it's only in 10 80 p
Speaker 1:  which is just very weird. You know, I've got a daughter, the hair, the
Speaker 1:  Harry Potter movies are on Max. There's, there's a lot here. We've been watching
Speaker 1:  those together. They get a little too scary after four for a 6-year-old.
Speaker 1:  Mm. So we're just gonna wait to watch the additional four movies,
Speaker 1:  but we're gonna watch those first four over and over again. Love it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean like, it, it's just, it has the catalog and then it has HBO. So if,
Speaker 1:  if that white lotus righteous gemstones moment, that's
Speaker 1:  important to me. I'm not a, I'm not a like turn on any garbage TV watch
Speaker 1:  room. I'm a very intentful TV washer. Do you cancel services?
Speaker 1:  Like, do you like watch your show and then bail for a while until you wanna
Speaker 1:  come back? I've been trying to cancel Max like five years, least t's given
Speaker 1:  it to me free. I wanna cancel more.
Speaker 1:  The challenge is my wife watches tons and tons of comedy
Speaker 1:  specials and they're on every service. Right. And so
Speaker 1:  you're just kinda like, well I canceled the one you want today. And then
Speaker 1:  we just like start it again. Including recently Hulu, which is deep into
Speaker 1:  comedy. All of the sudden, I think they've all figured out this is like a
Speaker 1:  reliable source of Cheap content that they can get at
Speaker 1:  a cadence that people will watch. Yeah. And people will always watch. Yep.
Speaker 1:  And then clip it and put it on TikTok. And that's where I live, which is
Speaker 1:  the other thing that is all over my TikTok all the time is just like, stand
Speaker 1:  up. Like Nate Boetti is two thirds of my TikTok at any given
Speaker 1:  moment. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I worry I'm gonna run out of awards possibilities here. So I'm gonna take
Speaker 1:  Amazon Prime video in Awards because otherwise I think there's
Speaker 1:  a decent chance there's just not going to be anything left for me to pick.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. For too long. I think Prime
Speaker 1:  is working. It's like the, the football thing is going very well. They
Speaker 1:  way overpaid. They're gonna start doing bond stuff.
Speaker 1:  People seem to like reacher, I guess. Sure. That's a, that's a show.
Speaker 1:  Matt Bella from Puck just recently described it to me as guys with guns shows
Speaker 1:  and Amazon's very good at guys with guns shows. So
Speaker 1:  Prime is like, it's like the least interesting, totally
Speaker 1:  mainstream service, but I'll take it.
Speaker 1:  Have you been watching the Lord of the Ring Show?
Speaker 1:  No, I have not watched that one. And I have not watched Citadel, which are
Speaker 1:  the ones that Amazon spent all of its money on. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  maybe why they now have a new person in charge. Yeah. But I did watch
Speaker 1:  a bunch of like whatever weird stuff Jeremy Clarkson is up to these days,
Speaker 1:  I will always watch on crime video. So that works for me. He's like, we've
Speaker 1:  done something irresponsible with a cup. He bought a Lamborghini
Speaker 1:  tractor and made like three episodes of a TV show about that. And I was like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, I'll watch this. This sounds great. You are very much like whatever's
Speaker 1:  on you. Like that's why you just want the TV to start playing stuff at you
Speaker 1:  sometimes. So like my, my parents used to make fun of me because
Speaker 1:  I would, I could, I loved to take naps. I still do love to take naps, but
Speaker 1:  I always nap with the TV on.
Speaker 1:  It's just, it's like I can turn my brain off when I'm halfway listening
Speaker 1:  to a TV show I've seen before. And so there's like background
Speaker 1:  television is a bigger part of my life than I'm proud of. Like I do a
Speaker 1:  lot of like watching TV while I do other things
Speaker 1:  and that's where service is like prime video, where it's like a thing I've
Speaker 1:  seen before but, or something I haven't seen but like don't really need to
Speaker 1:  look at is very helpful. Can you write while you're listening to music with
Speaker 1:  words? God no. Okay. Absolutely not. I can't do anything creative in that
Speaker 1:  headspace. Like the language center of my brain does not let me listen
Speaker 1:  to music with lyrics while I am writing or communicating. No. And
Speaker 1:  it's the same. I can't believe you can do it with tv, but I guess you're
Speaker 1:  just like passed out. No, I can't, I can't do any like creative
Speaker 1:  act while something like that is on, but it's like if I'm, if I'm cooking
Speaker 1:  or cleaning or napping or whatever, like, I almost always
Speaker 1:  will have like an episode of the Office on in the background. It's like a,
Speaker 1:  it's basically a podcast. Like I, I listen to TV shows the way some people
Speaker 1:  listen to podcasts and I also listen to podcasts. This, this explains a lot
Speaker 1:  of your picks over the years. There you go. Alright, so
Speaker 1:  just to recap and then we're gonna take a break. Jake, so far has picked
Speaker 1:  Netflix in awards and Hulu in 4K. Eli
Speaker 1:  so far has picked TikTok in Cheap and Max in awards, and I have
Speaker 1:  YouTube TV in live and Amazon Prime in awards.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna take a really quick break and then we're gonna come back, do
Speaker 1:  some more categories. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  case against a streaming service anymore. Right.
Speaker 8:  I I think like genuinely this is not a problem for most people.
Speaker 8:  I mean, I listen, if they were interrupting the middle of the movie, I would
Speaker 8:  complain to the end of the earth that you would never hear the end of me.
Speaker 8:  But it's not bad at all. I've watched a handful of movies on it over the
Speaker 8:  past year. I think, you know, we've seen these free
Speaker 8:  streaming services continue to get more and more promotion. It feels like
Speaker 8:  there is more attention on them than ever. I don't necessarily know that
Speaker 8:  two Bs in for a big breakout year, but I feel good about it as a Cheap
Speaker 8:  pick.
Speaker 1:  Well, so, okay, this is, this is the thing. I was waiting until somebody
Speaker 1:  picked Tubi to ask because I've been thinking about this ever since the Super
Speaker 1:  Bowl, right? Tubi had the Super Bowl lots of people watched was a big hit,
Speaker 1:  did very well. The stream held up like Good job Tubi. Do you feel like
Speaker 1:  Tubi has held on to any of that? Right? Like the hope is
Speaker 1:  you get this big giant spike of interest and then it comes back down, but
Speaker 1:  it doesn't come all the way down and it like resets a little higher. But
Speaker 1:  I don't feel like even slightly more people seem to be talking
Speaker 1:  about Tubi than they were before the Super Bowl.
Speaker 8:  I do think that's a challenge. The, the, the way I end up on Tubi is that
Speaker 8:  I go to look up where I can watch a certain movie and then I'm
Speaker 8:  told that for whatever reason It is free on Tubi or the only place It is
Speaker 8:  available is on Tubi. But the act actually, I will say like the thing where
Speaker 8:  It is only available on Tubi happens more often than I would expect.
Speaker 8:  I think there is just this weird catalog of slightly less popular
Speaker 8:  movies. You know, somebody wants Top Gun that's gonna end
Speaker 8:  up on a major streaming service. I hope that's true. I haven't checked, I,
Speaker 8:  I watched The Long Goodbye very famous movie. I think it maybe won an Oscar.
Speaker 8:  Hopefully. That's right. You know, thi this is like a big movie back in the
Speaker 8:  day. It is only available I think on Tubi or something like that. And I think
Speaker 8:  like there's a whole collection of films like that that are overlooked by
Speaker 8:  these services that are extremely cutthroat on,
Speaker 8:  you know, is this going to hook my mainstream subscriber base?
Speaker 8:  And there's just stuff that you like cannot find. And since we're looking
Speaker 8:  for stuff that you can stream, I want to be, I wanna have those options.
Speaker 1:  I, I think the thing you said about like, I just Google it and it clicks
Speaker 1:  me to Tubi is like a underrated, powerful thing in
Speaker 1:  Toy's Favor. And it has been the thing forever, right? In most cases you
Speaker 1:  don't even have to log in. You don't have to have an account, you just click
Speaker 1:  the thing and it starts playing the movie. And there are almost no other
Speaker 1:  entertainment experiences outside of like social platforms
Speaker 1:  that work that way. Yes. Anymore. And that's kudos to
Speaker 1:  Tubi for pulling that off.
Speaker 8:  I am confused how they got the Super Bowl. That still is Well
Speaker 1:  They, they're owned by Fox
Speaker 8:  And they chose Tubi
Speaker 1:  Because they wanted to, they wanted to drive Tubi. I installed. Yeah. Because
Speaker 1:  they don don't have another streaming service. Yeah. I mean, Fox doesn't
Speaker 1:  have an app. Fox has like Fox Nation Live or whatever. Like you can't
Speaker 1:  drive, right?
Speaker 8:  Right. Those are not the same
Speaker 1:  Americans to that app. Right. So it's not a choice that Fox
Speaker 1:  can can make. I mean, so
Speaker 8:  They're like, the post show is
Speaker 1:  Where can we stream the Super Bowl? It wasn't the Fox Sports app, which is
Speaker 1:  like a cable login. It's our big mainstream
Speaker 1:  fast competitor.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And that, I think they got all those logins that way.
Speaker 8:  That works. It was very smart
Speaker 1:  Of them. Yeah, that roofer, Murdoch Wiley.
Speaker 8:  He knows what he's doing. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Fox now is apparently working on some other big streaming service that
Speaker 1:  I'm sure is gonna go super great for them. I think it's a good pick. I'm
Speaker 1:  in favor. I had to be very high on my list here. Neela, what's next for you?
Speaker 1:  What do you got?
Speaker 1:  I've been making a lot of a lot of decisions here while you guys were talking,
Speaker 1:  I've been working my board really hard. This motor. It's a
Speaker 1:  motor trend tv. I'm going back and forth between two of them. And
Speaker 1:  I think what I've decided is that there's no chance
Speaker 1:  that either of you will pick the thing that
Speaker 1:  I'm worried about. So I'm gonna go another way. And then when I make that
Speaker 1:  pick, I reveal what it was. Okay. All right. Does that work for you? Okay.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So for 4K I'm picking Disney Plus. Mm. Oh mm. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  that's what I was gonna do next. Yeah. I was, I was, this is me working the
Speaker 1:  board. Yeah. I'm a little surprised it lasted this long. Yeah, it's tough.
Speaker 1:  It's a, it's, it's a, if you have children, it's a requirement. It four
Speaker 1:  KI, we gotta work, we gotta talk about the 4K category as it exists
Speaker 1:  next year. But it's in 4K you get all the Disney movies in
Speaker 1:  4K. So it's slots in here. Well, bluey obviously
Speaker 1:  very important, but Frozen two shockingly important in my
Speaker 1:  household. Same, like, very important. I don't know how to explain
Speaker 1:  to Max that one song is basically just a Peter Satera song from the eighties,
Speaker 1:  but It is a song is called Lost in the Woods and it's a banger.
Speaker 1:  I'm like, you know, there's this band called Chicago and she's like, I don't
Speaker 1:  care about this. And then I try to make everybody listen to Chicago, which
Speaker 1:  I don't even like listening to, but I just have to make the point. And everyone's
Speaker 1:  like, what is happening in this house? So that's very important to us as
Speaker 1:  just a weekend cycle that we go through and then you get all, you get all
Speaker 1:  the Marvel stuff you get and or it's all there for you. Like Yeah, it, it,
Speaker 1:  it, Disney Plus the only other one I would say should have been a number
Speaker 1:  one pick. This is a shocking slide because you can, you can make a,
Speaker 1:  a good argument for number one. Yeah. I, I agree. I I
Speaker 1:  I think It is that is going to be the thing I picked if you didn't, so I,
Speaker 1:  I buy it. I will say I have one Bob Iger, I know you're listening. I have
Speaker 1:  one complaint I would like to make about Disney Plus, which is they just
Speaker 1:  launched like 24 7 Simpsons Stream. It's basically a fast channel, but
Speaker 1:  it's all Simpsons very good idea. Except for some reason my
Speaker 1:  2-year-old now, every time I open the Disney Plus app, It is,
Speaker 1:  It is right at like his pointing level and he runs over to it and goes
Speaker 1:  Simpsons. And it turns out that if you put on
Speaker 1:  Simpsons, someone will say the word hell within
Speaker 1:  six seconds. And so I can't watch it. But now he, every single
Speaker 1:  morning he just runs over and he just goes, Simpsons. And I don't, I
Speaker 1:  I don't know how to That's rough. Tell him that this cartoon is illegal for
Speaker 1:  him. We had the parental controls on ours messed up. We,
Speaker 1:  I had the messed up and for some reason I had set
Speaker 1:  it so that Unrated TV shows would show up on
Speaker 1:  Max's profile. And so she opened it and the first thing in front of her
Speaker 1:  face was the UFC. And I was like, this isn't, this isn't
Speaker 1:  right. This doesn't go next to Milana. Oh
Speaker 8:  Boy.
Speaker 1:  Like no, thank you and I, you gotta go dig through it. They, there's some
Speaker 1:  real messy Disney brand stuff happening
Speaker 1:  because the parental controls are so confusing. The
Speaker 8:  Gambling they've put next to Frozen is out of control.
Speaker 1:  It's true. ESP n bet is right there. Will she
Speaker 1:  pull it off this time? Like you, you say that, but we're we're like rapidly
Speaker 1:  veering towards that and especially now that all the
Speaker 1:  stuff is in there, right? Like Hulu is now totally integrated and ESPN is
Speaker 1:  totally integrated and all of the stuff is now just in Disney. Plus
Speaker 1:  there's some pretty like, racy stuff that shows up at
Speaker 1:  the top of the page while I'm looking to start Frozen two for the 85th
Speaker 1:  time. It's a little weird. Yeah. It's, it's just a weird brand. And
Speaker 1:  this is why they didn't do it. Right. This is why they had the other, this
Speaker 1:  is why they had Hulu and then they weren't getting, this is the same as
Speaker 1:  why did you go to Tubi? Like we'll just shove it on Disney Plus. Yeah. It's
Speaker 1:  a lot. Yeah. But I, I feel, I feel confident with, especially as a third
Speaker 1:  pick in the 4K category. Yeah. So I'm run. It's a good pick. I'm winning
Speaker 1:  so far. I just wanna be very clear about this. Yeah. We're, we're all really
Speaker 1:  proud of you Teli.
Speaker 1:  I, as much as I don't want to have two YouTube things,
Speaker 1:  I feel like at this point I have to pick like YouTube
Speaker 1:  man. It is, It is by a mile the most watched
Speaker 1:  streaming service. It is. Like it has won the internet. Yep.
Speaker 1:  I now have, I now have Amazon Prime YouTube TV and YouTube,
Speaker 1:  which makes me like the least interesting American consumer
Speaker 1:  of
Speaker 8:  All time. You know what that gets you though, not only does that get you
Speaker 8:  Mr. Beast channel, it gets you Amazon's Mr. Beast Reality
Speaker 8:  show.
Speaker 1:  That's true. I get Mr. Beast and Beast Games. Wait, what category are you
Speaker 1:  in? I'm trying to decide.
Speaker 1:  I think I'm gonna put it in 4K because
Speaker 1:  So you're paying for premium on principle? I'm paying for premium.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I, I like, I seriously believe
Speaker 1:  that no ads on YouTube is the best money I pay for entertainment
Speaker 1:  every month. And wait is premium 4K on TVs? Is that a thing on
Speaker 1:  YouTube? Yeah. Am I just making that up? It's not all, not everything is
Speaker 1:  4K, but It is, It is. You do get lots of 4K stuff and you don't, if
Speaker 1:  you have ads that, I don't know, I'm truly just paying for no ads.
Speaker 1:  I am, I am happy. So, but why does it, why does that go in the four K content?
Speaker 1:  Because I get four K content. I could put it in Cheap if I was doing
Speaker 1:  ads is my point. Right. But I'm not doing that. I'm, I'm saying you might
Speaker 1:  have to put this in Wild Card, but I get four K content because you're not
Speaker 1:  buying it for 4K. Oh, interesting. Well, no,
Speaker 1:  but it doesn't. I get 4K. There is 4K. We
Speaker 1:  gotta, we gotta rethink this whole category. Marques Brown's out here doing
Speaker 1:  it in like 16 k. I could have made that a category. So we're gonna rename
Speaker 1:  this crispy. Yeah, yeah. I mean, yeah, we can do that. You
Speaker 1:  wanna do that? Alright. I'm, I'm allowing it this year. Okay. But I, I think
Speaker 1:  the 4K category is under a lot of pressure. Okay. That's fair. Maybe,
Speaker 1:  maybe that is the one that, that needs to change. 'cause you're right that
Speaker 1:  access to four K content is increasingly just everywhere.
Speaker 1:  No, it's, it's, well, you, it's gated. It's, you have to pay for it
Speaker 1:  everywhere. Right. I don't know, you sent us your notes, but Jake
Speaker 1:  picked Hulu and you just get it on Hulu. So we're, we're, we're, we'll allow
Speaker 1:  it this year, but fair. This is under reconsideration for 2026 and, and I
Speaker 1:  would like to hear the feedback about it. Yeah, agreed. All right. So I'm
Speaker 1:  picking, I'm picking YouTube main or YouTube. YouTube main YouTube Premium.
Speaker 1:  I feel good about it. Jake, you're up. What do you got?
Speaker 8:  All right guys, I have a real problem here, which is
Speaker 8:  at this point, David's got YouTube, Neil's got TikTok. I don't really have
Speaker 8:  a social presence here. So I'm, I'm gonna throw something out there. I need
Speaker 8:  you to tell me if, if this, if this fits, if I'm combining too many things
Speaker 8:  or the, the requirement for the live categories, there needs to be some sort
Speaker 8:  of live content. I don't need that live content to be any good.
Speaker 8:  I just need this service. That's
Speaker 1:  Correct. It just needs to be live.
Speaker 8:  Listen, hit me up with Instagram reels is a perfectly fine
Speaker 8:  knockoff and there's some live streams in there. Oh, I don't, I
Speaker 8:  don't know what they're doing. They're selling some stuff. Whatever. I will
Speaker 8:  watch all your tiktoks two weeks later. And you know what you're
Speaker 1:  Going with Instagram Live for your live. Yeah. Okay. So this, this
Speaker 1:  is Neli makes the correct point. You can't have Instagram as a whole. I can
Speaker 1:  'cause Instagram as a whole is not a streaming service. Are
Speaker 8:  Are reels and live one thing.
Speaker 1:  No, which is your problem. You can have reels or you can have live, but you
Speaker 1:  can't have both.
Speaker 8:  You know what guys, because in
Speaker 1:  Classic Instagram fashion, they've made them two different products where
Speaker 1:  there are one product on, on, on TikTok. They are two different features.
Speaker 1:  Why are
Speaker 8:  They two different
Speaker 1:  Features? Because YouTube hates you.
Speaker 8:  Here's the thing, I'm locking it in Instagram Live.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 8:  It's rough. Listen, there's a big year ahead for Instagram. Tiktoks
Speaker 8:  getting banned. Instagram's gonna have to figure their product out. It's
Speaker 8:  gonna be one thing. And I'm, this is, this is a long play. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's just a long
Speaker 1:  Play in the decaying corpse of versus It
Speaker 8:  Is someone is gonna have
Speaker 1:  A
Speaker 8:  Rock and roll Instagram Live by the end of 2025.
Speaker 8:  This is gonna pay off. It's gonna be more interesting than if I had chosen
Speaker 8:  Sling Blue. So I feel good about this.
Speaker 1:  So Jake, the, the thing that might work for you here is that like you,
Speaker 1:  you now have to actively root for TikTok to be banned. That's, that is the
Speaker 1:  main thing you need for this pic to pay off. Because now there's all these,
Speaker 1:  all this reporting and rumors out there about, like, Instagram is once again
Speaker 1:  trying to capitalize on TikTok going away and like, maybe they're gonna do
Speaker 1:  a separate app again. And like there are people out there who are like, IGTV
Speaker 1:  was a good idea. We just, you know, bad timing and
Speaker 8:  They're finally making an iPad app. Maybe
Speaker 1:  It could happen. It really, it could happen. You have to know like, Instagram's
Speaker 1:  response to TikTok being banned is iPad app.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1:  What's going on? They
Speaker 8:  Can pull this off. They can get there.
Speaker 1:  Like, what are, what are we doing?
Speaker 8:  They're gonna buy Meka or something. Like they're gonna pull it all together.
Speaker 1:  Love it. I'm excited for you. But yeah, you are now I I,
Speaker 8:  This, this one I'm buying low, trying to sell high here.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Not sure. Again, everyone's very confused about by the stock market
Speaker 1:  and that might be us too, so that's fine. Yeah. So
Speaker 1:  I will say this means Instagram reels is still available.
Speaker 1:  You can still have it if you want. I can't You picked Instagram Live. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I'm like, okay. Yeah, no, I feel, I feel I feel absolutely fine about this.
Speaker 1:  It's funny 'cause I don't, I, my prediction is that reels will not get
Speaker 1:  picked over the course of this draft, but it's live. I've
Speaker 1:  got picked. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. I I agree with both of those assessments.
Speaker 1:  What was your
Speaker 8:  Third place? Live pick.
Speaker 1:  Oh, this is my, it's my pick now. Are you, are you, oh, this is, you're up.
Speaker 1:  Go for it. This is what I was, this is what I all, this is what I was trying
Speaker 1:  to game out against David. Okay. Because I know the NFL is important to
Speaker 1:  both of us. So I'm just picking Sunday Ticket
Speaker 1:  standalone. Mm. Which you can just buy. Yeah, you can,
Speaker 1:  you don't need YouTube TV. You can just buy it. It's a
Speaker 1:  million dollars. But that's my live pick. Yeah. You don't even need, I don't
Speaker 1:  even think you need YouTube Premium. You can truly buy it on its own. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And you just get it on like the YouTube page, which is a weird way to watch
Speaker 1:  football. Like it, that's just, we it's just that's a weird thing.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Yeah. But all of my games are out of market, so this works for
Speaker 1:  me. So yeah, I'm, I'm, I'm just picking dead ahead Sunday Ticket.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. All right. That's fair. I was not gonna pick it only because
Speaker 1:  God helped me. I cannot have another YouTube product. But,
Speaker 1:  but it's a good pick. And it seems to, it seems to be working. Do you get,
Speaker 1:  if you buy Sunday Ticket on its own, isn't it like $500 a season or something
Speaker 1:  insane. Yeah. It's like, it's like three 50 or something. It's, it's nuts.
Speaker 1:  It's all to watch the Packers lose the Wild Card round. It's, it's not, it's
Speaker 1:  nuts. Even, even if you like buy it in like the regular, like, I have
Speaker 1:  a real playoffs problem here. I mean, I gotta figure something out, but I'll
Speaker 1:  go to the bar, it'll be fine.
Speaker 1:  Okay. All right. So you got Sunday Ticket. I feel good about it. Go to the
Speaker 8:  Bar is Wild Card.
Speaker 1:  And, and by the way, it, even if you have Sunday Ticket, you,
Speaker 1:  the NFL is like, here's a game on Amazon Prime. Like, it's all bad.
Speaker 1:  So the, there's a reason I was asking you about that piracy, backstop. You
Speaker 1:  see what I'm saying? Yeah, it's good. All right. My next
Speaker 1:  pick, I think I'm going Cheap. I think I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  pick Peacock,
Speaker 1:  which I just confirmed. You can still get for $8 a month.
Speaker 1:  We're not publishing this episode for a few days, so that's plenty of time
Speaker 1:  for them to raise the price. But
Speaker 1:  Peacock continues to be the, like, play.
Speaker 1:  I watch the Office and Parks and Rec and
Speaker 1:  New Girl, and it's increasingly getting like pretty good movies pretty
Speaker 1:  quickly after they come out. It's just, it's kind of,
Speaker 1:  it's, it's, it's doing a thing. I suppose this is where we should disclose
Speaker 1:  that. Comcast, NBC Universal is a investor in our parent
Speaker 1:  company at Vox Media, round five. They do not pay for my
Speaker 1:  cock still exists. Round five. Yeah, exactly. Disclosure.
Speaker 1:  But yeah, I think, I think I, I'm doing it just because I
Speaker 1:  still haven't watched Wicked. And at some point this year I'm going to watch
Speaker 1:  Wicked and I need Peacock to watch Wicked, so I think I'm doing it. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Peacock. Eventually you'll watch Wicked
Speaker 1:  Dirty Comcast money well spent. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  Poker face. Jake, like you said.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I know. It's real, it's real. Poker face. They got some, they got that
Speaker 8:  one show.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of like SNL 50 stuff I still have to watch. Like there's, I
Speaker 1:  got stuff to do.
Speaker 8:  Which by the way is also on your other pick. YouTube. Oh,
Speaker 1:  Crap. You're right. That's okay. I'm just, I'm just SNL for
Speaker 1:  life now.
Speaker 1:  This is good. All right. I'm taking, I'm taking Peacock. All
Speaker 1:  right, let's do one more round before we take another break.
Speaker 1:  Jake, you're
Speaker 8:  Up. What you got? All right guys, are you ready for this? It's about to hit
Speaker 8:  the, the Niche category. Tell me, have
Speaker 8:  you ever thought to yourself, I would love to watch
Speaker 8:  a 14 hour documentary about the history of New York
Speaker 8:  City by Ken Burns brother,
Speaker 1:  By Ken Burns brother.
Speaker 8:  That's great. Have you ever thought
Speaker 1:  Zen Burns
Speaker 8:  Boy, these bootleg clips of Antique Road show that I'm seeing on TikTok,
Speaker 8:  I would love to check out the entire series
Speaker 8:  PBS Passport. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 8:  I'm telling you, this is a winner. All right. And if you need this specific
Speaker 8:  genre, I'm gonna say this is TV you can fall asleep to. I
Speaker 8:  think this is gonna be a big hit. You get to help
Speaker 8:  support public access tv, which hopefully will exist by the end
Speaker 8:  of this year.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Will not be here next year.
Speaker 8:  And you know what? Your subscription to PBS Passport will help.
Speaker 1:  All right. I respect it.
Speaker 8:  I feel good about this one.
Speaker 1:  A big theme here is that everyone is falling asleep to the tv.
Speaker 1:  Like, why are we all paying so much money for streaming services when mostly
Speaker 1:  what we're doing is passing out, oh,
Speaker 8:  I've got more where that comes from. Okay. Just, just wait.
Speaker 1:  That also appears to be how everyone watches tv. Like, do you, do you guys
Speaker 1:  ever see this thing that flips around every once in a while? That one of
Speaker 1:  the directives Netflix gives to people who are making a show is that
Speaker 1:  everyone has to always say what they're thinking and what's happening out
Speaker 1:  loud, because most people aren't watching the show. So they have to like
Speaker 1:  you, you can't, there can't be any unsaid important
Speaker 1:  details in a Netflix show because they understand that lots of people are
Speaker 1:  just sitting there looking at their phone, so they have to say everything
Speaker 1:  out loud and it drives creatives absolutely insane. But like, this is the
Speaker 1:  world we live in now.
Speaker 8:  This is horrifying. This is also what you just described earlier, where you're
Speaker 8:  just like, I have TV on in the background while I'm cooking all the time.
Speaker 8:  And this is like how you watch
Speaker 1:  And it's just people, everything doing exposition all day long in the background
Speaker 1:  of David Fs. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This Apple is delicious. Like there's a reason
Speaker 1:  that Hollywood is dying and it's that, and the Frame tv, which we will come
Speaker 1:  to it time. It's, it's bleak out there. All right. PBS
Speaker 1:  Love it. No notes. Neli, what do you got? All right.
Speaker 1:  My, I'm, it's, it's time, it's time for Neli to do a, a Niche
Speaker 1:  pick as well. Okay. So I am picking Kaleidoscope,
Speaker 1:  which is an ultra high Bitrate day in date movie server.
Speaker 1:  What?
Speaker 8:  Oh God.
Speaker 1:  What? You gotta have one. You gotta have one. Ugh. So run Kaleidoscope,
Speaker 1:  you have to buy a server called the Terra Prime, which you like put in a
Speaker 1:  rack in your basement. 'cause obviously you have a rack in your basement.
Speaker 1:  The Terra Prime for the 24 terabyte version is
Speaker 1:  $10,500. And then you need to buy
Speaker 1:  the Strato C or Strato V players for all the TV in your house. The Strato
Speaker 1:  C is the budget model. That's $3,000. The Strato V, which is a
Speaker 1:  player, and with an integrated server that's $4,000. And
Speaker 1:  then you get day and date, you can buy full quality movies.
Speaker 8:  How much is the movie?
Speaker 1:  The movies are tremendously expensive. Is this the service that like Tom
Speaker 1:  Cruise uses to watch theatrical movies in his, in his home
Speaker 1:  theater? There's a little bit of that going on. It feels like they're a little
Speaker 1:  later now than they used to be. Okay. There's this thing called the Bel
Speaker 1:  Air Circuit where all the houses in, in Bel Air have like screening rooms
Speaker 1:  in them, like get day and date. They used to be the circuit because they,
Speaker 1:  they run the physical reels around. Now there's digital distribution,
Speaker 1:  but the movies are not always expensive. It depends, right? Like, some of
Speaker 1:  them are $30, but some of them are like $200. 'cause their day and date.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm just, I'm on Kaleido Escape's webpage. And Jake, I just wanna read
Speaker 1:  you this paragraph. Okay. Which is the most neli coded thing I think I've
Speaker 1:  ever heard. It says, Kaleidescape movie experts annotate each movie with
Speaker 1:  data such as screen size and credit and intermission cues. This allows our
Speaker 1:  players to integrate with your home automation to dim lights, close shades,
Speaker 1:  and adjust seating when the titles roll and automatically screen mask to
Speaker 1:  match the ratio of each film, immersive experiences that streaming services
Speaker 1:  simply can't achieve. Like, I guarantee you Neli read this and just started
Speaker 1:  just slinging money at his computer screen. The, the
Speaker 8:  Worst part about this is that Eli's right? Like this is, this sounds awesome.
Speaker 8:  Easily the sickest thing. This sounds incredible. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like easily the sickest possible movie experience. I have stared
Speaker 1:  in a Kaleidescape so many times and like, I should sell one of my cars
Speaker 1:  and I can't, I don't watch enough movies.
Speaker 8:  One of us picked Tubi, the other pick
Speaker 8:  like $30,000 set up to watch a, A Wicked Yes. Hell yes.
Speaker 8:  Slightly early.
Speaker 1:  I have a cousin who sent me a picture of the rack in his
Speaker 1:  brother-in-law's house in Virginia with like five Strato
Speaker 1:  vs in it. And I was like, I'm going to this house. Like, let's go. Like,
Speaker 1:  I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 8:  What screens do we play
Speaker 1:  On? I've been winning this entire time to make this pick. God. When do you
Speaker 1:  do it? I could have, I could have done it. Number one, I've been on edge
Speaker 1:  this
Speaker 8:  Whole, some one of us could have gotten there first.
Speaker 1:  It's Yeah, easily the sickest movie experience you can have.
Speaker 8:  It sounds great.
Speaker 1:  It is realistic.
Speaker 8:  You watch it on the frame,
Speaker 1:  You watch it on the garbage. No, you have to build, you don't have to, but
Speaker 1:  you're supposed to build a theater so that
Speaker 8:  The, but It is optional at that point
Speaker 1:  So that the Strato v Yeah. Can send 12 volt triggers to various
Speaker 1:  home automation devices. I'm just imagining you being like, max, I'm so sorry.
Speaker 1:  You have to move out of your bedroom and turning it into the Kaleidescape
Speaker 1:  Theater.
Speaker 1:  It's very good. I'm very excited about this idea. I've never been more excited
Speaker 1:  about anything actually. That's good stuff. I think you might only need a
Speaker 1:  Strato V at this point. I don't know. It's just a lot of money. That's, that's
Speaker 1:  what I have for you. I honestly, if you sell your car, you will go fewer
Speaker 1:  places, so you'll have more time to watch movies. It's true. You'll
Speaker 1:  I'll just be alone in my house. Look, if anybody is listening and you wanna
Speaker 1:  tell us about your kaleidoscope, we will come to your house and watch movies.
Speaker 1:  I will be there. Yeah. This is not a question. It'll fine. And then you will
Speaker 1:  wake up and you'll be like, where did my kaleidoscope go?
Speaker 1:  All right. I am gonna go content and I'm gonna pick Stranger Things Season
Speaker 1:  five,
Speaker 1:  which I think is going to be enormous and humongous
Speaker 1:  and might win me this draft all by itself.
Speaker 1:  I think in terms of like stuff that is going to be on streaming services
Speaker 1:  in between now and next year, this one is the one that is like,
Speaker 1:  if I can't have Netflix, at least I get to have Stranger Things. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I think that's a, that's a, a big win for you.
Speaker 1:  The se the season might be awful. Like I, there's a, all these actors are
Speaker 1:  like in their forties now. Yeah. They've been doing this for forever. It's,
Speaker 1:  it's gonna, it's gonna be insane. But I I kind of feel like everyone on Earth
Speaker 1:  is gonna watch it.
Speaker 8:  It's also, it's like the biggest thing that Netflix will have maybe ever,
Speaker 8:  right? Like this is, is the single biggest show they've had. At least
Speaker 8:  like culturally,
Speaker 8:  this conclusion has been coming for years. I think a lot of people are very
Speaker 8:  hyped about it. I'm very hyped for it. I'm not even necessarily sure it's
Speaker 8:  gonna be amazing, but yeah, I'm excited. So, yeah. Good. I think, I think
Speaker 8:  that's a good get for you.
Speaker 1:  I I feel good about it. I'm a little worried it's not gonna come out this
Speaker 1:  year because it has been like imminent for a very long time. But I I
Speaker 1:  I have faith. Yeah. And I choose to believe that it's gonna happen.
Speaker 1:  I think
Speaker 8:  They can get it there. I almost
Speaker 1:  Picked Ted Lasso season four, but then I knew Nene I would make fun of me
Speaker 1:  for a really long time. Yeah. And I just don't need that in my life. Well,
Speaker 1:  I just wanna tell you that Kaleidescape streams in 65 megabits per second,
Speaker 1:  which is higher than a 4K Blue. I knew when you had not said anything in
Speaker 1:  a minute, it was because you were reading Kaleidescape. We've, we've, we've
Speaker 1:  lost Neli and Lossless Audio, my man. Come
Speaker 1:  on. It's just a $15,000 initiative.
Speaker 1:  Look, I love this for you. All right, we gotta take one more break and then
Speaker 1:  we got two more categories to do. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. We're five categories in. We got two more to go. Quick
Speaker 1:  recap before we finish. Jake has picked Tubi, Netflix,
Speaker 1:  Hulu, Instagram Live for some reason, and PBS Passport,
Speaker 1:  some choices in there. Neli has picked TikTok Max
Speaker 1:  Disney Plus NFL Sunday Ticket and Kaleidescape and
Speaker 1:  has ceased paying attention to this podcast since he picked Kaleidoscope.
Speaker 1:  I've done everything I need to do. Neli is finished and I have
Speaker 1:  Peacock, Amazon Prime Video, YouTube Premium YouTube TV, and
Speaker 1:  Stranger Things season five. We have two more categories each. Jake, you're
Speaker 1:  up.
Speaker 8:  Alright guys, it's gonna be a stressful year. We all need something to
Speaker 8:  kind of chill out. Relax too. I also note that,
Speaker 8:  you know, we're talking about video here, but I don't know what this does
Speaker 8:  for our, our ability to listen to music. So I've been thinking about that.
Speaker 8:  I don't have YouTube, so I'm gonna grab LoFi, Girl. Oh,
Speaker 8:  listen. All right.
Speaker 1:  Lock that
Speaker 8:  In. All right. While the world is burning, whoa. I'm gonna be in my
Speaker 8:  bedroom studying little scarf around my neck,
Speaker 8:  just sort of zenning out. I think this is gonna be a good one for 2025.
Speaker 1:  It's a strong pick, actually. 'cause if, if, if the shtick here is, these
Speaker 1:  are the only things you're allowed to consume this year,
Speaker 1:  you do need that. That's a, that's a strong pick. I like that for you.
Speaker 8:  I think it's not covered by anything else that I've got. You know, it, it's
Speaker 8:  providing I think a very distinct surface. So, yeah. I, I
Speaker 8:  feel good about LoFi Girl.
Speaker 1:  Which LoFi Girl Station do you listen to? There's like three or four of 'em
Speaker 1:  now.
Speaker 8:  We're just gonna go with the main for this pick. Okay. I I, I'm be honest,
Speaker 8:  I'm not a c you can have
Speaker 1:  The whole cha I'll give you the whole channel. I'm just curious which one
Speaker 1:  you listen to,
Speaker 8:  Whichever one comes up. I mean, I, I'm gonna be honest, not personally a
Speaker 8:  big LoFi Girl listener, which maybe defeats the purpose of this draft, but
Speaker 8:  I'm trying to think holistically here. Right? Sure. I wanna get some music
Speaker 8:  in. This is, I think the single hottest music channel
Speaker 8:  on streaming services that I know of. I don't think I can pick the
Speaker 8:  entire, like
Speaker 8:  channel for God. Does it even exist anymore? What was the
Speaker 8:  YouTube music video service?
Speaker 1:  Vivo.
Speaker 8:  Vivo. Yeah, that was, It is vi Yeah,
Speaker 1:  They broke it up into individual artists. Yeah. If you would
Speaker 8:  Have to pick like Billy Eish vivo, I'm not, right. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Billy
Speaker 8:  Eilish. Billy E's YouTube channel is not a bad pick.
Speaker 8:  Probably could just go with that. No LoFi Girl. Listen,
Speaker 8:  it's not necessarily my constant jam, which maybe
Speaker 8:  defeats the purpose of this pick, but It is. I I I think It is
Speaker 8:  the right tone for 2025. I
Speaker 1:  Like it.
Speaker 8:  That's, that's why I'm locking it in. I support
Speaker 1:  It. I also, for anyone who spends all of their time on the regular
Speaker 1:  Lofi channel, which is very good, the, the synth wave channel
Speaker 1:  also very good. Not nearly as popular. I'm looking at it now. It's like a
Speaker 1:  10th as many people on the channel right now. But it's called Synth Wave
Speaker 1:  Radio on LoFi Girl. It's very good. Highly recommend. There's also a jazz
Speaker 1:  one that I'm not nearly cool enough to listen to, but Jake, you could be,
Speaker 1:  you wear good sweaters. You could, you could listen to jazz.
Speaker 8:  Listen, now that I have lo-fi channel, I'll find out. I
Speaker 1:  Love this for you. All right, NELI, what do you got? I'm realizing that I
Speaker 1:  made an error and that I did not pick quite escape for every one of
Speaker 1:  these.
Speaker 1:  So for content, could I have picked just NFL
Speaker 1:  and gotten the out? No. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Could I have picked like Reddit slash NFL live streams
Speaker 1:  and gotten the out Can I pick that for Wild Card?
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  You see what I'm saying? Interesting. Because I made a very important pick
Speaker 1:  for live and I'm thinking, oh, I could've,
Speaker 1:  I might, there's only one reason I needed it. I'm gonna say no because I
Speaker 1:  think LoFi Girl qualifies as more or less a piece of content.
Speaker 1:  Like I think if you were to say under content, you're gonna pick the Super
Speaker 1:  Bowl, I'd give you the Super Bowl, but I don't think the NFL
Speaker 1:  sees. I think it's too big. Too big. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  the collected catalog of LoFi Girl is not too
Speaker 8:  Big. It it, that's a nonstop stream. That thing doesn't, she doesn't sleep.
Speaker 1:  Sometimes she gets a murder. Apparently. From what I understand, there's
Speaker 1:  some sort of like la situation.
Speaker 8:  I, I dunno about the, the meta story of the Fight Girl.
Speaker 1:  Every now and again, she disappears and people have to do a quest. It's like
Speaker 1:  a thing. Oh,
Speaker 8:  This usually a brand. I've got gamification built in here too.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Oh yeah. The lore is so much deeper than, you know, Jake. So the one
Speaker 1:  thing I don't really have here is any kind of news content. True.
Speaker 1:  Except for whatever extremely weird version of CNN they run
Speaker 1:  on Max, which It is not worth watching. 'cause it's not
Speaker 1:  actually CNN. Yeah. It's like, what if this was worse?
Speaker 1:  You're like, I don't want this, so here's what I'm picking. I'm gonna throw
Speaker 1:  it. I content I'm gonna throw,
Speaker 1:  I gotta put a news service here. Right. That's what you need live television
Speaker 1:  for, especially in, in this moment. And I feel like the
Speaker 1:  regular cable news channels have just become weird podcasts
Speaker 1:  unto themselves. So if I'm gonna pick a weird news podcast,
Speaker 1:  I'm picking my pals at CNBC and that's, I'm just putting that here in content.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Because if if line's gonna go down Yeah. And I'm gonna panic with a
Speaker 1:  bunch of weirdos. It's, it's my buddies. Okay. So that's my, my content.
Speaker 1:  I like, I'm glad we got a podcast in here. Yeah. Is It, is it a CNBC
Speaker 1:  like podcast stream? Like what? See the CNBC, literally,
Speaker 1:  if you go onto their homepage right now, there's a button that says
Speaker 1:  Watch Live Stream, which is an incredible button for a cable channel to have.
Speaker 1:  And then it says prefer audio, because I think they've realized
Speaker 1:  that It is just a weird podcast about a chart. Like what does
Speaker 1:  CNBC make every day? A podcast about a chart. Yeah. The hosts come and go,
Speaker 1:  but they're making a podcast about a chart. Sure. And so there's a button
Speaker 1:  where you can just listen to it. Okay. And they put out all the shows as
Speaker 1:  podcasts and mirror. I don't know if any of this is working strategically
Speaker 1:  and obviously they're being spun out of Comcast into their own.
Speaker 1:  They're gonna live whatever weird life in a company called literally Spinco.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I dunno if It is gonna happen, but I do know that if I wanna listen
Speaker 1:  to people panic about Line go down this, it, I would, I prefer that over
Speaker 1:  the general interest news channels. I can get that from my
Speaker 1:  bastardized CNN and Max. You see what I'm saying?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I like it. And I think CNBC is like, it's gotta be weird to program
Speaker 1:  a thing that, you know, many of your viewers are gonna watch with no sound.
Speaker 1:  And many of your viewers are only gonna listen to. It's like you, you, you,
Speaker 1:  like very few people seem to actively sit and listen and look at cable tv.
Speaker 1:  They all, it's one or the other. It's like you're in an airport with no sound.
Speaker 1:  Oh, you put audio stream here. I'm just saying. Well, yeah, you can have
Speaker 1:  the live stream. I don't care. You don't have live stream nbc. Yeah. My my
Speaker 1:  point is, all cable news podcasts are now weird podcasts.
Speaker 1:  Like, if you just look, if you look at what we do every week, like here's
Speaker 1:  some people talking to each other for a while about stuff and you like, watch
Speaker 1:  any major cable news. They're like, here's 35 people
Speaker 1:  in a grid talking about stuff. And it's just a podcast and
Speaker 1:  like everything is converging on this form. But you do need the like
Speaker 1:  live reactive to news in your content mix.
Speaker 1:  We need more charts on The Vergecast is, is what I'm hearing here, A podcast
Speaker 1:  about Chart, A live podcast where we panic about a chart is like, that's,
Speaker 1:  that's cable news in 2025. I'm, I'm ready for it. All right. That's a good
Speaker 1:  one. I will be watching as little news as possible over the rest of this
Speaker 1:  year. So I will, I will skip on that one. All right. I'm up next.
Speaker 1:  I have Niche and Wild Card left. I think I'm gonna pick
Speaker 1:  Wild Card and I'm gonna go Paramount Plus
Speaker 1:  with, with great sadness and trepidation, but I need
Speaker 1:  sports and Paramount Plus has a lot of very good sports.
Speaker 1:  Paramount Plus is how I watch March Madness. It's how I watch
Speaker 1:  the Masters. It's how I watch Champions League soccer. It is like, there's
Speaker 1:  just this like steady drumbeat of very important sports to me on CBS that
Speaker 1:  I can only get through Paramount Plus. And I don't love giving them
Speaker 1:  my money because it's not a good service. Other times. Although they do also
Speaker 1:  have the Mission Impossible movies, so that
Speaker 8:  Helps. That's gonna be big this year. They got another one coming up. You're
Speaker 8:  gonna have a a rewatch marathon. I think there's something there. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So I'm, I'm taking Paramount Plus,
Speaker 1:  but like I will probably cancel it three separate times
Speaker 1:  over the course of this year. That's right. But I wanna have it available
Speaker 1:  to me also. This is the Alex Kranz memorial pick
Speaker 8:  And,
Speaker 1:  content out there that you can get with your library card. Please don't close
Speaker 1:  all of our libraries.
Speaker 8:  Support your libraries people. That's
Speaker 1:  A good pick. I think Kanopy has come up before, but I don't think anyone
Speaker 1:  has ever picked it. So you, you've
Speaker 1:  live from F1 tv. That's how I prefer to experience this sport. It's like,
Speaker 1:  okay, so I'm gonna be taking a nap at home.
Speaker 1:  It's very good, strong correlation, by the way, between people who love video
Speaker 1:  games and F1 because they're just, they're just doing video
Speaker 1:  games stuff like, they're just like min maxing, like European boys. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I see that. It's very good. The Polygon. People love F1. It's a, it's, they're
Speaker 1:  always like, It is a spreadsheet game. It's a lot of,
Speaker 1:  it's, It is very much, It is like the nerdiest sport you could possibly imagine.
Speaker 1:  In all. It's all of the best ways. Well, this sucks 'cause now I don't know
Speaker 1:  what I'm gonna pick.
Speaker 1:  I wanna say, by the way, this officially means Apple TV is going to go
Speaker 1:  undrafted. I was, I was wondering,
Speaker 1:  I thought about taking it in Wild Card, but I think I need, I need
Speaker 1:  like Severances already happened, so like I'm good on Apple TV for a while.
Speaker 1:  Did anything happen, David,
Speaker 1:  I'm not doing this with you again.
Speaker 1:  Same, same conversation about White Lotus, by the way. It seems, it appears
Speaker 1:  Netflix has issued rules where everyone just has to be doing like Boldfaced
Speaker 1:  Exposition and Apple and Max have been like,
Speaker 1:  nothing happens for three episodes in the middle. But it's beautiful so people
Speaker 1:  can look at their phones. Yeah, yeah. Like huge gorgeous
Speaker 1:  establishing shots. The end. Yeah. End of episode.
Speaker 1:  Will this monkey murder someone? No, actually
Speaker 1:  nothing. Nothing will happened. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Also ESPN plus undrafted. Interesting. And I think
Speaker 1:  ESPN Plus doesn't count as a streaming service. That feels too mainstream.
Speaker 1:  Right? I don't think I can get away with that. I'm gonna take BritBox
Speaker 1:  as mine. BritBox is just an
Speaker 1:  unbelievable repository of, I believe BBC specific
Speaker 1:  British content.
Speaker 1:  A lot of good stuff. Like, oh boy, do you want people like quietly
Speaker 1:  solving murders in beautiful Countrysides BritBox has
Speaker 1:  you covered forever. A lot of good house shows on
Speaker 1:  BritBox. But really I'm taking it because I think
Speaker 1:  in, in a, in a time where people are looking for less America
Speaker 1:  in their lives, we're all going British. It's just, it's just gonna be me
Speaker 1:  and my BritBox homies just checking it out. Is that what we're
Speaker 1:  doing? That's what it's gonna be. That's the bet I'm making. I feel like
Speaker 1:  you ought to pick a Russian streaming
Speaker 8:  Service of it. We want ing again,
Speaker 1:  Like what's going on over there? Is it cool? Because it seems like we ought
Speaker 1:  to know.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm just looking at this now. I, there's a show called Douglas is Canceled
Speaker 1:  that I think I can watch
Speaker 8:  Anytime people tell me what they're watching on BritBox
Speaker 8:  truly just shows I've never known existed. I'm, I'm sure they're
Speaker 8:  delightful, but it's just, it's it's very goofy names.
Speaker 8:  They've been on for, for a decade. I've just never heard of them.
Speaker 1:  Jake, there's a show on here called Gardener's World that I'm pretty excited
Speaker 8:  About. Oh, you know what? That is a hit though. Gardner's World is, is the
Speaker 8:  number one
Speaker 8:  worldwide gardening competition series.
Speaker 1:  Monty and the team are back full of the best practical tips and advice for
Speaker 1:  gardeners. Five seasons. Yeah, let's go. This is the
Speaker 1:  cozy TV I'm looking for.
Speaker 8:  There there is a big contract negotiation issue with Monty, so that actually
Speaker 8:  was a big deal.
Speaker 1:  Monty actually got replaced in season three. Silently.
Speaker 1:  Look, David, extremely weird pick. That's what I tell you. Not good about
Speaker 1:  it. We really, really fizzled out here at the end where David just started
Speaker 1:  googling cool streaming services and realized that both
Speaker 1:  Kanopy and and LoFi Girl were taken
Speaker 8:  In person. You like gave a very solemn sigh after you did
Speaker 1:  Like, just like scoop it up the bottom of the barrel. Alright, that's fine.
Speaker 1:  I can, yeah, you, you picked this over Apple TV plus I think that's really
Speaker 1:  saying something. Apple TV plus doesn't, doesn't count in Niche. If I, if
Speaker 1:  I had truly, if I had known you were gonna pick F1 tv, I would've done
Speaker 1:  it backwards and then I would've had a real Paramount Plus
Speaker 1:  versus Apple TV plus debate to have. But I I,
Speaker 1:  I played myself. Only one of those has both Top Gun movies. David,
Speaker 1:  it's not a debate. I don't know what you're talking about. Ted Lasso Season
Speaker 1:  four is coming someday in the future. Yeah. Do you think he's gonna be optimistic?
Speaker 1:  Listen, do I every once in a while tap a wall and say believe to myself?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I do. This is who I'm, do I walk into a bars and just
Speaker 1:  blow people out of the water at darts every couple days? Yeah. That's why.
Speaker 1:  That's, that's be curious. Not judgemental. Nehi.
Speaker 1:  All right. To recap the 2025 Vergecast Streaming Draft,
Speaker 1:  Jake in Cheap, you picked Tubi in awards. You picked
Speaker 1:  Netflix in 4K, you picked Hulu in Live. Let's
Speaker 8:  Pause there, let's pause there. I
Speaker 1:  Have a draft and a
Speaker 8:  Really winning selection right there
Speaker 1:  In live. You picked Instagram Live. What? That's choice. Niche. Niche. You
Speaker 1:  picked PBS Passport in Content. You picked LoFi Girl and in
Speaker 1:  Wild Card you picked Kanopy. I think most of those are
Speaker 1:  strong picks. David described this as, as very
Speaker 1:  Brooklyn. I would describe this as guy who insists they don't watch tv.
Speaker 8:  No, this is, this is straight, this is accurate. I'm, this is the
Speaker 8:  cheapest slate. Right? I'm paying for two of these PBS Passport.
Speaker 8:  You just make a donation like once,
Speaker 1:  Like, I mean, it's good. I I'm not saying I wasn't the kid who
Speaker 1:  didn't have the tv, but there's a real vibe here.
Speaker 8:  No, that's, that's completely right. I, I wanna watch a bunch of old movies
Speaker 8:  that nobody else cares about that are only available with ads
Speaker 8:  on Tubi. 'cause nobody else wanted to pay for them.
Speaker 8:  I'm going to the library because it's the only place you can check out, you
Speaker 8:  know, the, the Peter Greenaway movies I wanna watch and then I don't know,
Speaker 8:  I'm not in touch culturally, and so I'm like, what's happening? Let's check
Speaker 8:  Instagram Live.
Speaker 1:  I just feel like you've also won the unofficial,
Speaker 1:  how many of these companies will send me a tote bag race
Speaker 1:  in, in pretty handly? Yeah. You get a LoFi Girl tote bag. That's the move.
Speaker 1:  There we go. Then you're the winner. All right, so Neli in Cheap, you pick
Speaker 1:  TikTok in awards, you pick Max in 4K, you picked Disney
Speaker 1:  Plus in Live, you picked Sunday Ticket In Niche, you picked the Kaleido Escape
Speaker 1:  in Content. You picked CNBC and in Wild Card you picked F1 tv.
Speaker 1:  This is a real like content monster lineup.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's strong.
Speaker 1:  I feel like I've outed myself as a dad in the worst possible way. This
Speaker 1:  this,
Speaker 8:  This is like, you have five TVs on a wall and they've all got something
Speaker 8:  going
Speaker 1:  On. Yes. Yeah. It's, it's a lot. And I, yeah,
Speaker 1:  I I needed one cool one and I didn't pick one. Instead I picked CNAC,
Speaker 1:  but I'm okay with it.
Speaker 8:  F one's up there. F one's cool. F1 is cool.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, It is. And it's way, you're like, I'm a nerd
Speaker 1:  who watches cars at three in the morning. That's me. It's so deeply me, but
Speaker 1:  yeah. Well, and you have TikTok, so you still get truck trucks jumping over
Speaker 1:  stuff. So I think, I think you've, you've represented yourself fairly accurately
Speaker 1:  here. Yeah. As a dad. Yeah. That's, that's, that's my choice.
Speaker 1:  And I have a cloud escape server, which is sick. I've won on strength of
Speaker 1:  streaming quality alone in terms of like number of
Speaker 1:  bits delivered to the house. You've won and it's not close. No question
Speaker 1:  about that. It's so many. You need an $11,000 server
Speaker 1:  just to download them overnight. Do you understand what I'm saying?
Speaker 1:  They, you know, it pre downloads a bunch of movies so you can buy them locally
Speaker 1:  and watch them right away.
Speaker 8:  They're just assuming you're gonna give them another 200 bucks every week.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They're just like, we're just gonna preload your Terra Prime
Speaker 1:  so you're ready to go. That's not bad. That's why you need the server in
Speaker 1:  the basement.
Speaker 8:  That's good service.
Speaker 1:  Look, if you're out there, I'm, I'm guessing it's Steve Kaleidescape.
Speaker 1:  Just gimme a call. Let's, let's work something out. I give it like 12 days
Speaker 1:  before you reappear on this show. So lemme tell you what I've been up to.
Speaker 1:  All right. And then my picks were in Cheap. I picked Peacock in awards. I
Speaker 1:  picked Amazon Prime in 4K. I picked YouTube Premium Live,
Speaker 1:  YouTube TV Niche, BritBox content, Stranger Things
Speaker 1:  Season five and Wild Card Paramount Plus I would call this the like
Speaker 1:  basic parentheses derogatory set of picks. Yeah. This is David is
Speaker 1:  passed out in the aisle of Best Buy. Like stuff is just happening to you
Speaker 1:  and you don't know why. There, there's
Speaker 8:  A real like beat your selection to the streaming. I don't want, I don't mean
Speaker 8:  to, to criticize you as a person, David, you're great. But
Speaker 1:  No, I'm looking at this and I'm like, no, this is pure, just like the
Speaker 1:  algorithms get to decide. Like I don't, I don't care what I watch. Just put
Speaker 1:  something on is like the energy I'm getting from my picks here.
Speaker 8:  There's an argument that YouTube alone tops everything else.
Speaker 8:  Like if, if you have YouTube, you can, you have access to the entire world
Speaker 8:  of content in some ways.
Speaker 1:  Frankly, the con the, the combo of YouTube Premium and Amazon Prime video,
Speaker 1:  like who is going to run out of content last? It's me by
Speaker 1:  Lifetimes. So I'm good on that. Yeah. But like, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  the ceiling's pretty low on David's picks over here. The
Speaker 1:  combo platter of Peacock and Paramount Plus ending up on your board, but
Speaker 1:  not Apple TV plus is perfect. You're like, I
Speaker 1:  could have, but I did not choose the one that has won an
Speaker 1:  Oscar. Yeah, it's good. There's that. You do get all of the weird Jurassic
Speaker 1:  Park movies.
Speaker 1:  And I'm not saying that they weren't successful. They've made billions of
Speaker 1:  dollars. Super weird movies. Can you name the titles of any
Speaker 1:  of them? It happened again.
Speaker 1:  Oh, no. More dinosaurs. Whoops. All right, we're done.
Speaker 1:  We gotta get outta here. Tell us who you think won the draft.
Speaker 1:  I guess we have like a year to really figure this out, right? So like, maybe,
Speaker 1:  we'll, we'll ask a bunch of overtime, but we, we should, we should put a
Speaker 1:  poll in the, in the post on the site about who won the draft.
Speaker 1:  Spoiler alert. It's, it's me. I won the draft, but
Speaker 1:  I, I don't know, I don't know that any of us did great this year, but we'll
Speaker 1:  see. And we have 12 months to figure it out. Maybe TikTok will still be here
Speaker 1:  and maybe Instagram Live will have taken over the internet. We'll see, I
Speaker 1:  just feel like I, my choices are very good and like by rides in the winter,
Speaker 1:  but I'm also wearing a quarter zip, you know what I mean? It's like,
Speaker 1:  it's rough. Yeah, it's rough. Yeah. Like the, the net worth of your picks
Speaker 1:  is very high. Do you know what I mean? Yeah. That's what I, you know. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's like I have a golf sponsorship now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I won. I'm I'm saying I won as, but you know,
Speaker 1:  but you're sad about it. I'm caveating my own victory. Yeah. I'm saying I
Speaker 1:  could have won in a cooler way. Yeah. Alright, we gotta get outta here. Jake
Speaker 1:  Neli. Thank you guys so much. This is really fun.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that's it. That's the show for today. Thank you to Jake and Neli
Speaker 1:  for doing that with me. And thank you as always for listening for lots more
Speaker 1:  on everything we talked about. If you wanna see our picks again, if you wanna
Speaker 1:  see previous drafts, if you want to just yell at us in the comments about
Speaker 1:  who won, head over to The Verge dot com. And seriously, I, I honestly do
Speaker 1:  want to know who won. You can also send us an email vergecast to The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com. Call the hotline. It's six six VERGE one one. All of your
Speaker 1:  feelings, everything about who we should have drafted sooner. If you think
Speaker 1:  it's like nuts that Disney Plus didn't go first. If you think I'm a lunatic
Speaker 1:  for picking BritBox, which I'm not, but if you think that I am,
Speaker 1:  tell us we want to hear from you. Leave us comments, everything. We, we see
Speaker 1:  it all and we love hearing from you. This show is produced by Eric Gomez,
Speaker 1:  Brandon Keffer and Will Poor Vergecast is VERGE production and part of the
Speaker 1:  Vox Media podcast network. Neli and I will be back on Friday to talk about
Speaker 1:  AI news, politics, news, tariffs, chaos, and everything else going on right
Speaker 1:  now. We'll see you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 1:  guys. I think this went poorly for most of us.