# Transcript
ID: 01b9e88a-0573-482a-b911-7aab48c6b7ed
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/714361278588658408/3603637360806701773/s93290-US-5258s-1738061806.mp3
Description: The Verge’s Victoria Song joins the show to talk about the most popular and most-bailed-on New Year’s Resolution of all: getting in shape. She tells us about the apps that help you work out more without being rude about it, the data you really need to care about in your fitness tracker, and much more. After that, we talk to Anna Valtonen, one of the curators and researchers behind the new Nokia Design Archive. She tells us about the concepts, presentations, and overall culture that made Nokia such an important company in the history of phones. Finally, we answer another question on the Vergecast Hotline about how audio works on your phone. It’s all still too complicated.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of immediately giving up
Speaker 2:  on every single one of your New Year's resolutions. It's the best way. Can't
Speaker 2:  recommend it highly enough. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and I am in sunny
Speaker 2:  West Palm Beach, Florida, where I'm here to see a thing called TGL Golf,
Speaker 2:  which is basically trying to take the game of golf, which is, you know, famously
Speaker 2:  played outside on grass and move it inside and make it
Speaker 2:  really technologically advanced with big screens and complicated
Speaker 2:  actuators and all kinds of new ideas about what watching
Speaker 2:  and playing golf can be like. We're gonna have more to say about that on
Speaker 2:  this show and on The Verge dot com in a couple of weeks, so stay tuned for
Speaker 2:  that. But it's nice to be outside. Whatcha gonna do. Anyway, we
Speaker 2:  have an awesome show coming up for you today. We're gonna do two things.
Speaker 2:  First, we're gonna talk to Vong about New Year's resolutions. She is a
Speaker 2:  person who thinks a lot about exercise and how people can do better
Speaker 2:  without making it so much work to do better. And right now
Speaker 2:  is the time of your people want to be healthier and want to get in better
Speaker 2:  shape and want to exercise more. So v and I are gonna try to figure out how
Speaker 2:  you can do that in a safe, sane, healthy way. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 2:  After that, we're gonna talk about this incredible new thing called The Nokia
Speaker 2:  Design Archive, which is this huge repository of
Speaker 2:  concepts, presentations, lifestyle videos, all
Speaker 2:  these different ideas back when Nokia was at the peak of its powers trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out the future of cell phones. Super fun and we're gonna get into
Speaker 2:  what's inside all of it. We also have a question on The Vergecast hotline
Speaker 2:  that's kind of a follow up to last week's question on The Vergecast hotline
Speaker 2:  about how audio comes and goes on your phone. Really fun one. Thank
Speaker 2:  you again to everybody who emails and calls. All that is coming
Speaker 2:  up in just a second. But first I honestly, I have to get outta the sun 'cause
Speaker 2:  this is the first time I've been outside in like three months and I think
Speaker 2:  I'm already starting to burn. This is The Vergecast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, I'm back from Florida. I have
Speaker 2:  suitably embarrassed myself trying to play on that gigantic simulator
Speaker 2:  in West Palm Beach. Let's get into it. So last week
Speaker 2:  I talked to Kevin Nguyen about how to read more books. It's a New Year's
Speaker 2:  resolution. A lot of people have, I think in a bunch of different directions,
Speaker 2:  right? There's the, I wanna read more books. There's also the, I wanna spend
Speaker 2:  less of my time scrolling on my phone and more of my time doing something
Speaker 2:  useful on my phone. So I talked to Kevin, who is the best
Speaker 2:  and most accomplished book reader I know about how all that worked. Super
Speaker 2:  fun. We got a lot of great feedback from people. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  enjoyed that and told us. So super fun to hear from all of you.
Speaker 2:  This week we're gonna do something similar on a very different topic. I
Speaker 2:  think If you had to pick a number one New Year's resolution, it is,
Speaker 2:  I want to get in shape. And again that comes in lots of different varieties.
Speaker 2:  Some people are like, I want to go for one walk. And
Speaker 2:  other people are like, I am going to get like Brad Pitt in
Speaker 2:  Fight Club level shredded in two weeks. Happy New Year,
Speaker 2:  let's go. I think most of those resolutions don't
Speaker 2:  work. People don't stick to them. Famously, there are
Speaker 2:  huge amounts of gym memberships that get bought the first two weeks of January
Speaker 2:  and canceled the second two weeks of January. Like this stuff is tough
Speaker 2:  and I think part of it is because we don't make it easy on people to
Speaker 2:  stick to these kinds of resolutions. So I recruited the Verges Victoria
Speaker 2:  song to come on and help me figure out how we can do a little
Speaker 2:  better. How you can use apps and wearables
Speaker 2:  and platforms and all of these different ideas about how to
Speaker 2:  exercise and be in better shape and do more healthy stuff in your
Speaker 2:  life to our advantage and not be sort of beaten down by them to the
Speaker 2:  point where we don't wanna use them anymore. V thinks about a lot of this
Speaker 2:  in a way that I really like. She is like the most happy
Speaker 2:  exerciser, but also thinks the whole idea of exercising is
Speaker 2:  absurd. And I love that. Like I think that's exactly right. So I knew she'd
Speaker 2:  be the right person to come on and do this with. So let's get into it. V
Speaker 2:  song, welcome back. Hello. Thanks for having me. There's just
Speaker 2:  a lot of stuff happening right now. I feel like we could talk about rings,
Speaker 2:  we could talk about other, I don't wanna talk about any of that stuff. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  none of it.
Speaker 2:  So we did this thing with Kevin Wynn last week where we basically tried to
Speaker 2:  break down one of the very common years resolutions into something that is
Speaker 2:  like achievable for regular people. And I think you
Speaker 2:  have an even harder job, which is we're gonna do this again with everybody's
Speaker 2:  number one New Year's resolution, which is, I'm going to get in shape,
Speaker 2:  It's that time of year. So
Speaker 7:  It it, it is that time of year let's let's destroy the New Year's
Speaker 7:  resolution fitness industrial complex. I'm here for it.
Speaker 2:  I like, I like that we're doing this kind of at the end of January
Speaker 2:  because there are a lot of people who have already lapsed on the gym memberships
Speaker 2:  that they signed up for. A lot of people who have like,
Speaker 2:  you know, they went on six runs and they were like, this is it. And then
Speaker 2:  we, and then it got cold and it stopped. And to all those people, I just
Speaker 2:  want you to know big same, like same exact
Speaker 2:  same,
Speaker 7:  Same from me too and I'm the running lady at at The Verge.
Speaker 7:  So like big, same like it's, it's it's fine.
Speaker 7:  Don't worry about it. Like I, you know, like if I can go off
Speaker 7:  on New Year's resolutions, particularly with relation to fitness,
Speaker 7:  like this year was particularly annoying just because
Speaker 7:  it was Apple and I think also Ladder, which is the strength
Speaker 7:  training app that I use. They both had these ad
Speaker 7:  campaigns centered on this idea of Quitter's day. And Quitter's
Speaker 7:  Day is the second Friday in January and it's the
Speaker 7:  day that statistically all these fitness apps have determined is the day
Speaker 7:  that most people quit their New Year's resolutions with relation to fitness.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting. And I think it's the biggest hawk of bullshit in, in
Speaker 7:  the world quitters day because what, this year it was
Speaker 7:  January 10th, I was flying back home from CES What do you mean
Speaker 7:  that by the 10th of January I've quit and failed
Speaker 7:  my like entire 2025 New Year's
Speaker 7:  resolution. There's like 265 days left in
Speaker 7:  the year. What are we talking about here? What is the concept of this? So
Speaker 7:  yeah, yeah, like I'm I'm not a about
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah, I'm completely with you. The idea that If you haven't been to the
Speaker 2:  gym every single day so far, you've failed and you should give up
Speaker 2:  is like the source of everything that is wrong with everything.
Speaker 2:  And it's actually a good segue because what, what I want talk about, you
Speaker 2:  and I talked to the founder of Zombies Run a while ago and
Speaker 2:  talked a bunch about this, like how do we find a saner way to help
Speaker 2:  people exercise more thing? And we got a ton of feedback on that episode.
Speaker 2:  People really liked it. And so I'm gonna, I wanna help people in kind of
Speaker 2:  that same way here. So I've been thinking about my own like
Speaker 2:  chiller exercise system for a while and have been trying to figure
Speaker 2:  out a way to do it that a doesn't shame me when I don't exercise for a
Speaker 2:  while, but also like is good and helpful and and useful and
Speaker 2:  productive. But I wanna know yours. Like you, you have a like
Speaker 2:  psychopath version of exercise I would say, which
Speaker 2:  is like, you wear a bunch of, you wear a bunch of rings, you use a bunch
Speaker 2:  of apps, you're like forever trying all of this stuff. But like regular
Speaker 2:  humans should not do that. No. Like where would you start a regular human
Speaker 2:  in this world?
Speaker 7:  I would would start a regular human not doing anything digital
Speaker 7:  actually. I would start a regular human with maybe
Speaker 7:  just a pen and paper and ask them like what their actual goals are.
Speaker 7:  Mm. Like what, what do you actually want to do? Because goals like
Speaker 7:  get shredded by June.
Speaker 7:  If you have already 19% body fat, okay,
Speaker 7:  maybe we can do that for you. But If you like you kind of just have to take
Speaker 7:  stock of where you are very honestly, right? And then figure out what your
Speaker 7:  goals are and then how do we break that? Like really it's about
Speaker 7:  goal setting. So
Speaker 7:  I used to do things like in a year I'm gonna run a marathon. Well guess what
Speaker 7:  guys? That that didn't happen right? Because like that just wasn't
Speaker 7:  achievable. If you're going from couch to marathon,
Speaker 7:  like you'll see all these influencers online and they'll say things like,
Speaker 7:  hey, it's totally doable within a year. It's doable within a year If
Speaker 7:  you wanna suffer and like do it badly. Yeah. Like it's technically doable
Speaker 7:  in a year, but do you wanna enjoy it? Like that's the thing that
Speaker 7:  none of these apps and digital things tell you is that they are just tools.
Speaker 7:  And my big beef is that all of the, all of them are coming out and saying
Speaker 7:  things like we have ai, we have an AI chat bot, it's gonna help you figure
Speaker 7:  out everything that you need to do that you don't know, which I'm empathetic
Speaker 7:  to because figuring out your own fitness routine, like, I
Speaker 7:  hate to tell you this, it's going to take you years. Yeah. It's not gonna
Speaker 7:  be something that happens in a few weeks. It's not gonna be something that
Speaker 7:  happens in a few months. It's gonna be a year's long
Speaker 7:  journey to get to absolutely shredded for that one summer.
Speaker 7:  So it's like, first of all, like slow your
Speaker 7:  role, figure out what your goals are and then once you've done that, like
Speaker 7:  just kinda look at yourself honestly and be like, how well do, like what
Speaker 7:  do I respond well to Hmm. In terms of coaching and in terms of
Speaker 7:  style. Because If you are looking for one of these apps to kind of help coach
Speaker 7:  you, like are you someone who responds well to drill sergeant stuff?
Speaker 7:  Are you someone who, like you just need your hand held and like be told
Speaker 7:  that you're great and that everything is wonderful and that it's okay?
Speaker 7:  I'm actually the latter. I don't respond well to drill sergeants. I was
Speaker 7:  just
Speaker 2:  About to guess that about you. I don't, yeah, I don't think yelling at you
Speaker 2:  is is the way to get you to succeed.
Speaker 7:  No, I actually was going to boxing classes for some period
Speaker 7:  of time a few years back and I had a drill sergeant in, in a class and he
Speaker 7:  is like,
Speaker 8:  I didn't say you could give up. And I was like, I didn't say I was giving
Speaker 8:  up.
Speaker 7:  And so I went really hard and then afterwards I vomited in
Speaker 7:  the locker room because I went too hard. I didn't listen to myself. Like,
Speaker 7:  I was like sweating and I like, my friend was like, are are you okay? I think
Speaker 7:  I think you went too hard. And it's like, yeah, 'cause the drill sergeant
Speaker 7:  made me angry.
Speaker 7:  So you have to be honest with yourself about like that sort of stuff. And
Speaker 7:  then from there you can kind of sort through the stuff that works
Speaker 7:  for you. And because I don't like drill sergeants because I don't like, I
Speaker 7:  am a perfectionist by nature, so I don't like feeling like I'm failing. I
Speaker 7:  do really well with the chill stuff. And so I have settled on using
Speaker 7:  an Apple watch or a Garmin depending on where I am in my testing cycle. This
Speaker 7:  is like, again, very specific to me that I only
Speaker 7:  have two wrists and I always have to be testing things. So I, I settle
Speaker 7:  on the trackers that for me as a runner offer me the
Speaker 7:  most running specific stuff that I can use
Speaker 7:  a running app which has like a, a little training program in there
Speaker 7:  for me. And I use gentler streaks a lot because
Speaker 7:  it uses the concept of streaks, but it also allows you to
Speaker 7:  take several breaks and you're not penalized for it. It
Speaker 7:  will basically be like, Hey, you pushed it really hard, maybe don't do that.
Speaker 7:  And then if you're kind of falling off it, it might pop up and say like,
Speaker 7:  Hey, you haven't done things for a while. How about we do something like
Speaker 7:  really fun and gentle to get back into things. And like I'll admit over,
Speaker 7:  over Christmas I got one of those notifications. I was like, no, shut up.
Speaker 7:  I thank you for reminding me that I forgot to put you on pause. I will be
Speaker 7:  going back to Christmas cookies presently. Right?
Speaker 2:  Somebody gave me advice one time that they, their, their like, main idea
Speaker 2:  for me was that If you have to lie to your exercise system, it's the wrong
Speaker 2:  exercise system and it goes for everything, right? Like If you, If you have
Speaker 2:  a personal trainer and you have to lie to your personal trainer, you have
Speaker 2:  the wrong, you either shouldn't have a personal trainer or you have the wrong
Speaker 2:  personal trainer. If you have to go in and like dial down the
Speaker 2:  settings in an app on your phone in order for you to be able to hit
Speaker 2:  your goal. You have, you haven't set up the incentives in the wrong
Speaker 2:  way. And I say this as somebody who has done both of those things and it
Speaker 2:  just, it, it should be a sign If you have to go into your streaks app and
Speaker 2:  be like, no, no, I did it yesterday. Wink wink. Just to keep the streak going.
Speaker 2:  Like this is a bad system for you.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no. Like you should be able to pause. That's why I was so happy last
Speaker 7:  year when Apple introduced pausing your rings. Totally. 'cause it,
Speaker 7:  it basically kind of ensures that
Speaker 7:  you can take breaks and that you can take rests and like there's, there's
Speaker 7:  a lot of stuff out there about how you should never
Speaker 7:  break your streaks. And the, again, this is bullshit because
Speaker 7:  life is life. You will break your streaks. It's a matter of not if, but
Speaker 7:  when.
Speaker 2:  I think a lot about you saying to me a while ago that you break yours on
Speaker 2:  purpose sometimes Yes. When you find yourself getting too attached to them.
Speaker 2:  And I think that's actually like weirdly good life advice.
Speaker 7:  It's, no, you should like, 'cause here's the thing, If you are so obsessed
Speaker 7:  with your streaks, and this is like therapy with v about fitness, that's
Speaker 7:  what we're here for. If you're so obsessed with your streaks, then at some
Speaker 7:  level you do not have confidence in yourself that you will go back to it
Speaker 7:  Like you are depending on the streak to say that you are consistent.
Speaker 7:  Now break your streak and trust in yourself that you will go back to it.
Speaker 7:  Like that's, that's how you prove to yourself that like the streak isn't
Speaker 7:  what matters. It's the, the knowledge that you have have built
Speaker 7:  some sort of consistent routine. And like, this
Speaker 7:  is like fundamentally what we're going to get at though is that all of this,
Speaker 7:  all of these things, they're tools, they're tools that you use. You are the
Speaker 7:  captain of the ship. You get to decide like what is gonna work for
Speaker 7:  you and like what you enjoy and what, what, like, it
Speaker 7:  it's basically tricking yourself into deciding like,
Speaker 7:  I enjoy this and until it's actually true. So like I didn't start
Speaker 7:  out running enjoying it. I, I'm telling you I was, I was running and I was
Speaker 7:  like, this is freaking torture. Who are these people who do this? And now
Speaker 7:  I don't feel good if I don't run per week. And I don't like that.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But I agree with every single thing you just said, but you're
Speaker 2:  describing like an end state, right? Like this is, this is the thing you
Speaker 2:  should get to. And I think every I I agree that that is a, an achievable
Speaker 2:  place for everybody to get and it's easier than you think. I think to
Speaker 2:  me the the biggest challenge is like, it's the the trough of
Speaker 2:  disillusionment, right? The thing where I've been on four runs
Speaker 2:  because I have, I have some internal discipline. Hooray for me, running
Speaker 2:  still sucks and I'm just gonna stop, right? And that is like
Speaker 2:  for me with, with exercise, that has been the thing that has killed me so
Speaker 2:  many times, right? Is like I get, I have, I have this much discipline and
Speaker 2:  so I will, I will use the discipline that I have to go out and
Speaker 2:  do something and then I, it doesn't immediately get
Speaker 2:  better or more fun or show results. And so I bail and I think
Speaker 2:  one of the things I have spent a huge amount of time looking for in
Speaker 2:  the fitness space as a result is the, like, the right
Speaker 2:  cadence of helping me improve and sort of reminding
Speaker 2:  me to improve. And one thing you mentioned the the like couch to marathon
Speaker 2:  pipeline. One thing that I have found that I love is couch to 5K
Speaker 2:  apps because like I, I actually, I I am,
Speaker 2:  I, I exercise enough that I'm not starting at the couch level, but having
Speaker 2:  the thing where it's just like, okay David, today what we're gonna do is
Speaker 2:  we're gonna go for a six minute walk and all you have to do is not die. Is
Speaker 2:  like, that's actually perfect for me. That it is like just the, the
Speaker 2:  tiniest bit of push to get out and then it's like, maybe I'll ignore the
Speaker 2:  app and keep running or maybe I'll do the six minute walk and go home and
Speaker 2:  feel good about myself because I've accomplished my goals for the day.
Speaker 2:  So few apps do that well because they're all either geared towards people
Speaker 2:  for whom fitness is like a lifestyle or they're trying to convince you that
Speaker 2:  fitness is a lifestyle because that's how they, you know, get you engaged
Speaker 2:  in buying merchant, buying their subscriptions and stuff. And this
Speaker 2:  like how to start and do better
Speaker 2:  without making it, your whole personality thing is so hard to find
Speaker 2:  in this space. And it is the thing that drives me the most crazy about it.
Speaker 7:  It is really hard. And so like I just, it's, it's difficult because
Speaker 7:  I don't think anyone does it particularly well for true beginners. Like
Speaker 7:  I think Fitness Plus does it Okay. Except for the fact that all
Speaker 7:  of their strength stuff still puts in pushups and like
Speaker 7:  no. Yeah. Just no. Like, excuse me. No. And they're like, you can
Speaker 7:  do it on your knees. No, we need to go to, to the part where you show someone
Speaker 7:  doing it on a wall because like wall pushups are like, where,
Speaker 7:  let's be honest, a lot of people are gonna be starting,
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna lie down while you do pushups. It's like, that's that's where
Speaker 2:  I'm at that's
Speaker 7:  Gonna like, I'm, I'm not at the point where I do knee pushups even still
Speaker 7:  like I'm, I'm at the wall like a lot of times And I think it's, it's just
Speaker 7:  allowing yourself to say, I'm going to do it so easy
Speaker 7:  that it feels like I'm not actually doing it. So like
Speaker 7:  one thing that I like from services like Fitness Plus is that you can do
Speaker 7:  10 minutes, you can do five, 10 minutes, just do five, 10
Speaker 7:  minutes three times a week. You can program it in there and you know, we
Speaker 7:  have this tendency to be like, go hard, go fast. No, go slow, go easy.
Speaker 7:  Like it should be easy. Like fitness should be easy. It should not be something
Speaker 7:  that is difficult. Like I all, like you
Speaker 7:  hear a lot of stuff about people saying things like, oh my god,
Speaker 7:  grind. Like no pain, no gain. And actually like I'm here to tell you
Speaker 7:  no do do a really easy thing. Like what I love about Couch to 5K apps, like
Speaker 7:  you said is that day one is a six minute walk. Yeah. Anybody can do a six
Speaker 7:  minute walk. And one of the things that really helped me out of a slump,
Speaker 7:  because it's a lie that If you are someone with established fitness
Speaker 7:  habits that you will not slump. I had a really bad slump last year where
Speaker 7:  I was just like not, I didn't wanna do any of it. I felt my fitness like
Speaker 7:  completely like 2023. Like my fitness era
Speaker 7:  was just like going so down. And it was super depressing because all of these
Speaker 7:  apps were just showing me and quantified data how slow I was getting,
Speaker 7:  how like the arrows were all down right. And I was not happy about it. And
Speaker 7:  so like one of the things you have to do is to be able to go like, this is
Speaker 7:  not working. An established system I have is not working. I then
Speaker 7:  went and downloaded this app called Fantasy Hike
Speaker 7:  and I love it. It's off-brand Lord of the Rings. You're
Speaker 7:  walking to Mount Mount Doom. Like
Speaker 7:  you're, you're competing with Mr. Underhill who's Frodo
Speaker 7:  but you know, copyright safe and you know, there's Harry Foot Potter
Speaker 7:  and John Snowflake and
Speaker 2:  So it's like a step tracker with like gentle competitiveness in
Speaker 7:  It. Gentle competitiveness. Oh I like that. You can, like, you could only
Speaker 7:  compete against Frodo who like walks really fast
Speaker 7:  like and absurdly. You're not gonna beat Mr. Frodo but you can
Speaker 7:  absolutely beat Harry Foot Potter who like is so like
Speaker 7:  his little description is like, he's really tired from like his life and
Speaker 7:  he's just going real easy. Yeah, he's a lot to you definitely can beat him.
Speaker 7:  You definitely can beat him. And so like, I've been using this app for a
Speaker 7:  little over a year now and I'm almost at Mor Door. Nice. And it's so nice
Speaker 7:  because it's just whatever I do during a day, like
Speaker 7:  it's not anything. There's a little bit of competition in there. So
Speaker 7:  I use it to be like, I gotta beat Alice. I'm definitely not gonna beat
Speaker 7:  John Snow, but like, maybe I won't be beat by him by too much.
Speaker 7:  I definitely wanna finish in between those two. So that's kind of my goal.
Speaker 7:  And then I, I, some days I'll be like, oh, I've moved,
Speaker 7:  not at all today. Let me just put a few miles between me and Alice
Speaker 7:  and it's great. Wait,
Speaker 2:  I really like that. So one of the things I was thinking about coming into
Speaker 2:  this is the, the thing that I have found is most
Speaker 2:  useful for myself is just step tracking. Like I find there's
Speaker 2:  a lot of like, you know, I wanna get stronger, I wanna get faster, whatever.
Speaker 2:  And like that you can focus on that. But in terms of like day to day
Speaker 2:  health maintenance, like it, it just is true that walking is very
Speaker 2:  good for your health.
Speaker 7:  Walking is the best.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And like the 10,000 step thing is, is sort of
Speaker 2:  nonsense but is also like a useful bar. Like If you walk that much, it
Speaker 2:  is good for your body to do so. But what I've always struggled with is
Speaker 2:  I'm like, okay, I get in the like eight range
Speaker 2:  just kind of by being alive most days, right? Like I have a kid that I chase
Speaker 2:  around, there's a coffee shop that is the exact right distance that I go
Speaker 2:  there several times all the time. It's like I, I get there and
Speaker 2:  so I'm like, okay, I'm gonna get like 12 or 15. And I find even motivating
Speaker 2:  myself to do that requires going out and doing something sort of on purpose.
Speaker 2:  And I don't because I'm lazy and don't want to, but this idea of
Speaker 2:  like, I'm, I'm gonna, not only am I doing this like for the
Speaker 2:  benefit of my health that there is this sort of game going on in the background.
Speaker 2:  I think that might work for me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's really great. 'cause every once in a while you hit a milestone,
Speaker 7:  I'm like, oh I hit the Dancing Pony or whatever the off-brand version is
Speaker 7:  like, right? It's like Riverdale, not Rivendale is
Speaker 7:  like the little castle and it's like, oh I've hit, I've hit the council.
Speaker 7:  Cool. So like love this. I'm, I'm in Mordor at the moment. I'm almost at,
Speaker 7:  I'm almost there and it's just like, oh and it, and like what I love about
Speaker 7:  that particular app, which is unfortunately it is iOS only and you do have
Speaker 7:  to pay to like move more than a mile a day. I find it worth it.
Speaker 7:  But like the thing I love about it is that it kind of very
Speaker 7:  visualizes your, it's very visual in seeing your progress. Hmm.
Speaker 7:  Because in a year I've walked maybe
Speaker 7:  1600 miles. Wow. All all I'm, I'm, I'm about to
Speaker 7:  get to 1600 miles 'cause that's the distance that they go. So you can
Speaker 7:  kind of see like, oh no, I, I actually did walk
Speaker 7:  from the Shire to, you know, more like that is,
Speaker 7:  that is like a very visual thing and it works for me. It tickles my brain
Speaker 7:  in such a delightful way.
Speaker 2:  It's such a good like context list number too because I have no idea
Speaker 2:  if in the scheme of things that is a lot or a little, but it sounds
Speaker 2:  like a lot and it feels like you've accomplished something and that's really
Speaker 2:  cool and that's kind of all it needs to do.
Speaker 7:  That's all it needs to do. Yeah. Because I love step tracking in the sense
Speaker 7:  that like I think it's a very, there there was like a push away from it because
Speaker 7:  like they said, 10,000 steps is just a number that they used for
Speaker 7:  marketing for a pedometer a long time ago. There's no scientific basis in
Speaker 7:  it. Which is, which is true. But it can feel mundane
Speaker 7:  to just like not hit your goal every day. Yes. Right. It can feel like a
Speaker 7:  little bit like failure. This there's, there's no daily prescription that
Speaker 7:  you have to do. You're just walking, you're just walking to more door. You're
Speaker 7:  just visualizing your progress over this time. And there's like a lot of
Speaker 7:  different ways to do kind of step count. I think
Speaker 7:  a lot of times it's tweaking what you viewed the metrics to be. So instead
Speaker 7:  of a daily step count, maybe you do a weekly one because that gives you a
Speaker 7:  little flexibility to be a couch potato once in a while. Yeah. So like
Speaker 7:  finding something that will let you track your steps weekly and
Speaker 7:  putting those widgets upfront instead of like, you
Speaker 7:  know, like Fitbit lets you customize which widgets you see and what you do.
Speaker 7:  So some, for some people steps may not be it, but like activity minutes
Speaker 7:  are so, okay, you put activity minutes up and the guided goal
Speaker 7:  is like 150 minutes of moderate activity per week is all you
Speaker 7:  really need. And like whatever it is, I think it
Speaker 7:  should feel so easy when you're starting out that it feels like cheating.
Speaker 7:  Like this can't possibly be correct. It it, it's good, it's all good, it's
Speaker 7:  all good. And then eventually over time you build it up. But like, it should
Speaker 7:  be easy. It should be like so easy that you feel bad not doing it.
Speaker 7:  Like, you know, sometimes you're in bed and you're like, oh I
Speaker 7:  should really, I don't know, check the mail. Like it should be that
Speaker 7:  degree of, of easy and you just like build it into your day over time
Speaker 7:  because like we like you, you, you pointed out
Speaker 7:  we're so eager to get to the end state and then
Speaker 7:  I have some bad news. You're never gonna reach an end state.
Speaker 7:  It's like, like I, I don't know what to tell you. You just never reach an
Speaker 7:  end state 'cause you hit one goal and then you're gonna wanna do another
Speaker 7:  because like that's just not what it's about. So
Speaker 7:  like for my quote unquote New Year's resolution, like my goal, which is a
Speaker 7:  carryover from last year is to do a 5K and under 30 minutes
Speaker 7:  I'm at 32 minutes for a 5K.
Speaker 7:  Which is great because I had had a slump way before and I
Speaker 7:  was like much slower than that for a while. And you know, there is a past
Speaker 7:  version of myself that was much faster. Like I was at one point doing five
Speaker 7:  Ks in 27, 28 minutes and I'm not that at that point anymore. And
Speaker 7:  I could feel bad about myself or I could just be like, oh this
Speaker 7:  app said good job. I did do a good job. I wait, I made it to Moreor.
Speaker 7:  Yeah I made it to Moreor. Or like we did Stompers as as an office
Speaker 7:  for a while. Which was just, which one is Stompers? Stompers is the,
Speaker 7:  the so and Ivinson app where you just whack each
Speaker 7:  other with with bats. Oh right. And for a while that was really fun
Speaker 7:  while people were into it. Now I feel like I'm the only person still doing
Speaker 7:  it and now I have to friend strangers and whack strangers in the middle of
Speaker 7:  the day. But it's nice because I'll get a notification and it's like someone
Speaker 7:  just passed you and I'm like, by how much? Oh not by much let's
Speaker 7:  walk a little bit and whack this stranger. And so like I have fun doing that.
Speaker 7:  I like that. It's just how can you trick yourself into having fun?
Speaker 7:  Like honestly it's fun. So like for you David, it just might be that you
Speaker 7:  haven't found a thing that you genuinely find is fun and or maybe walking
Speaker 7:  is a thing that's fun for you and do that you don't have to
Speaker 7:  run. I'm gonna say athletes are the most annoying people, especially
Speaker 7:  quantified fitness athletes because they're all on Strava and they're all
Speaker 7:  talking about all of these things. You have my full permission as the wearable
Speaker 7:  ladies to just turn off all your notifications for the rest of January. You
Speaker 7:  have my full permission to do that.
Speaker 2:  Let's talk about that piece of it for one second because I think again, all
Speaker 2:  of these things want you to make fitness to your entire personality and become
Speaker 2:  a Strava person. And If you wanna do that, that's fine. Just don't talk to
Speaker 2:  like leave me alone about it. But like there are lots of other people on
Speaker 2:  Strava who wanna talk to you about their Strava numbers. So like Godspeed.
Speaker 2:  But there is some quantification here that is
Speaker 2:  useful. Like I think If you're a person who is like, I wanna get in shape
Speaker 2:  this year, spending a lot of time worrying about your VO two max in 2025
Speaker 2:  is probably not useful.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  What is useful? Like what, what numbers should people pay attention to?
Speaker 7:  So the numbers that they should pay attention to are their baselines. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Like just figure out where you're at. Give yourself like two to four weeks
Speaker 7:  to figure out what your baseline is. And like you're gonna feel so
Speaker 7:  impatient 'cause you're gonna feel like you're not doing anything. You are
Speaker 7:  doing the most important thing, which is to just figure out what your baseline
Speaker 7:  is. Because if
Speaker 2:  Baseline in what sense? Like go go run an easy mile and just
Speaker 2:  see how that goes and start from there. Like that kind of thing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Okay. See how that goes. Just how long does it take you to run a mile?
Speaker 7:  Can you even run a mile? Like that's fine. What is your daily step
Speaker 7:  count like just naturally. Just as you are doing now? Like
Speaker 7:  just neutrally. You're not bad for having an
Speaker 7:  unimpressive step count. You're not bad. You just need to know where to start.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Because the thing about all of these tools is that they're like, here,
Speaker 7:  here, here we are. We're gonna give you all of these metrics. Yeah. Nobody
Speaker 7:  fuck all like what does, what do these numbers mean? Right? The most important
Speaker 7:  thing is for you to understand what your baseline is. So let's say you
Speaker 7:  baseline, in your average daily life, all you're doing is two to 3000
Speaker 7:  steps. Great. I love that for you. So next week
Speaker 7:  try 500 steps more per day. That's it. That's it. That's all you gotta do.
Speaker 7:  Just 500 steps more. That's like two minutes of walking maybe.
Speaker 7:  Like it's not a very long amount, but just 500 steps more.
Speaker 7:  Right. See, see how you do, see how, how that is is that easy for you? Okay,
Speaker 7:  cool. And then after two weeks of doing that, add
Speaker 7:  500 steps to that. Oh all of a sudden you're doing a thousand more and just
Speaker 7:  go until you hit a goal number and there are just gonna be some
Speaker 7:  weeks where you don't hit that goal. Okay. So then you just repeat it and
Speaker 7:  just repeat it until you can do that. Same thing with calorie. Like just
Speaker 7:  choose one thing. Just choose one metric to to be your metric. So
Speaker 7:  either choose activity minutes, how many minutes you're doing during a week.
Speaker 7:  Choose your your steps if that's what works. And for your brain the most.
Speaker 7:  Or choose like, If you are already
Speaker 7:  committed to working out at the gym, choose like a number of times times
Speaker 7:  you go to the gym. Like go to the gym, go on the
Speaker 7:  treadmill for 10 minutes and that's it. You can go home. Like, I just did
Speaker 7:  that with, with my spouse last night. We were both like, it's icy out. We
Speaker 7:  both prefer running outdoors but we can't 'cause we'll break our neck.
Speaker 7:  How about we go to the gym for 15 minutes
Speaker 7:  and if we do more, that's a success. We did 22 minutes and then we
Speaker 7:  left. That's it. I did, I did the world's most half-ass
Speaker 7:  treadmill run. 'cause I hate treadmills. And I was like, I did 20 minutes
Speaker 7:  on the treadmill. I am a God. And I left.
Speaker 2:  I had, I had a friend a while ago who's, he said his goal as like, I
Speaker 2:  can, I can check it off if I walk in the door of the gym
Speaker 2:  if like, yeah. Literally all I have to do, I have to walk in the front door
Speaker 2:  and I can turn around and leave and it counts. And I did it. And he was like,
Speaker 2:  I never actually just did it. But the point was like, make
Speaker 2:  the goal so easy that you're gonna hit it all the time. Yeah. Because it's
Speaker 2:  the knot hitting the goal that prevents you from stopping. Yeah. 100%. I
Speaker 2:  I think about that. I think about him all the time. It's just like all I,
Speaker 2:  like just, he just like walks in, opens the door to Planet Fitness, like
Speaker 2:  high fives the person behind the desk and leaves and he's like, great, what's,
Speaker 2:  what's that?
Speaker 7:  Everybody that's me. That, that's, that's me. That's, that's what I do too.
Speaker 7:  And it's, it's honestly like I just have to go get on the treadmill for five
Speaker 7:  minutes and I'm allowed to leave at that five minutes and I almost
Speaker 7:  never do leave at the five minutes. Maybe I'll do 10 or whatever. But
Speaker 7:  the the whole point is that you're just tricking yourself the entire time
Speaker 7:  and setting the goal. Like my, my number one tip for any of the
Speaker 7:  devices that you get is to one, pick a metric and then make
Speaker 7:  the goal so stupidly easy, you feel like you're cheating
Speaker 7:  and then you'll, you'll increase it over time. But like, I, I
Speaker 7:  really think that anyone who's a beginner should just start out doing like,
Speaker 7:  I wanna say 10 minutes, twice a week. That's it. That's it. You can do that.
Speaker 7:  Anybody can do 10 minutes twice a week and then
Speaker 7:  you just go up from there. And If you never go up from there and you're
Speaker 7:  just doing 10 minutes twice a week, that's still better than
Speaker 7:  doing nothing. Yeah. So you're still winning like in, in that, in that respect.
Speaker 7:  So like, really the key to fitness is to, to make it easy.
Speaker 7:  Just make it easy and make it fun. Like find a thing that's fun
Speaker 7:  and find a thing that's easy. If you enjoy doing walks, listening to audio
Speaker 7:  books, just do that. Hmm. Just do that. You do not have to like
Speaker 7:  run a marathon. That's, that's crazy. Like I, I haven't run a marathon yet
Speaker 7:  and I run a lot. So like, you don't have to do that if that's not for you.
Speaker 7:  A lot of people will say like, oh, the habit building the habit is hard.
Speaker 7:  Like the consistency is what these tools are for. Yes. But
Speaker 7:  you cannot be consistent unless you find the thing that you like. So find
Speaker 7:  the thing that you like first. Like that's, I mean it's it, all these tech
Speaker 7:  companies are gonna yell at me because I'm basically saying, your tools are
Speaker 7:  shit. But it's, it's, it's honestly what you're
Speaker 7:  doing is you're building the wisdom to use the tools effectively because
Speaker 7:  they're tools and you're gonna fall, you are gonna fall
Speaker 7:  into the trap of being obsessed with streaks. Break them, just break them
Speaker 7:  on purpose. Right? Break them on purpose and forgive yourself for breaking
Speaker 7:  them on purpose. If your exercise is supernatural in a VR headset, do
Speaker 7:  it. Do it. Play dance, dance. I know people who have lost 50 pounds just
Speaker 7:  going to the arcade and playing dance. Dance revolution. Yep. Do it. That's
Speaker 7:  exercise. It counts. Like have fun. It shouldn't be
Speaker 7:  work. It really should not be work. It should be something that does not
Speaker 7:  feel like work. Like for me, running, running is now
Speaker 7:  like a time where I get to think about a draft that is
Speaker 7:  bothering me. Mm. And like working out some stuff in my
Speaker 7:  head and it, it always works. Or like it's a time if I do have to go
Speaker 7:  to the dread, the dread mill is what I call it. I have a YouTube playlist
Speaker 7:  of K-pop videos. I haven't gotten around to watching. I get to watch K-pop
Speaker 7:  videos while I suffer. And that's a way that
Speaker 7:  you can make fitness more tolerable.
Speaker 2:  One of the best things I ever did was I had a show that I only allowed myself
Speaker 2:  to watch at the gym. Yes. It was just, I just decided this, I I
Speaker 2:  love the show and I'm watching it and I'm only allowed to watch it at the
Speaker 2:  gym. And the problem was, there weren't that many episodes
Speaker 2:  in the show, so I literally fell off as soon as the show ended. But it was
Speaker 2:  a surprisingly good way to a get
Speaker 2:  me there. 'cause I was like, oh, I like this show. I'm enjoying it. I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna go to the gym so I can watch it. And b it kept me on the treadmill
Speaker 2:  for longer. I just like had it on the iPad and I would watch, I would run
Speaker 2:  for a whole episode. And that was like that, that became part of
Speaker 2:  the process and I, I really enjoyed that. So like that little, that little
Speaker 2:  carrot for me was really productive.
Speaker 7:  Also allowed to quit. You are allowed If you don't en it's like
Speaker 7:  readers will say this about DN fing books. Don't waste your time on
Speaker 7:  an activity that you don't enjoy. Like you wouldn't spend all
Speaker 7:  that time trying to read freaking gravity's rainbow by t. Like I, I regret
Speaker 7:  reading that book. I hated it from like, clearly I hated it 200 pages
Speaker 7:  in, I forced myself to get through like the rest of the 800 page
Speaker 7:  book. But like those 600 pages I could have spent reading something enjoyable
Speaker 7:  that I liked. So I regret powering through that. The same thing with
Speaker 7:  exercise. Okay, you don't like running, don't do it. You don't like strength
Speaker 7:  training, don't do it. Maybe what you're thing is, is rock
Speaker 7:  climbing. Do that. And you know, some people will say that, I'm
Speaker 7:  telling you bad health advice just because there's benefits to strength
Speaker 7:  training, your muscles will atrophy as you grow older, yada yada
Speaker 7:  yada. What I found because I hated strength training, was that I wanted to
Speaker 7:  get faster at running. So now I do strength training because I wanna get
Speaker 7:  faster at running. It took me a really long time to get to that point, like
Speaker 7:  a really, really long time to get to that point. And that's okay. You'll
Speaker 7:  get to it eventually. It's fine. Just, it's fine. Maybe, maybe you like Pilates,
Speaker 7:  God, god bless you. Pilates people are a different breed of crazy
Speaker 2:  Pilates freaks me out. Yeah. Can't do
Speaker 7:  It. Like they're, they're a different breed of like, I, I was doing it for
Speaker 7:  a while and I've decided to quit. Like I decided to quit. Like, you're allowed
Speaker 7:  to quit If you don't like it, just quit. Find something else. Try something
Speaker 7:  else like walking. Just if walking is all
Speaker 7:  you do, just walk. Just walk walking's great. Like make it easy. Make it
Speaker 7:  fun.
Speaker 2:  I I like this. Okay. One, I, I have a recommendation that I just wanna
Speaker 2:  throw out 'cause this is a thing that I did last year that has worked very
Speaker 2:  well for me. And then I have one more question for you. The single best fitness
Speaker 2:  thing I did last year was by one single dumbbell
Speaker 2:  I bought. I, I just have sitting next to me at my desk, a a
Speaker 2:  25 pound dumbbell and have discovered that
Speaker 2:  with one weight and 15 minutes you can do a shockingly
Speaker 2:  complete workout. And it has been really useful for me as just like a thing
Speaker 2:  where if, if I'm like feeling tense or itchy or whatever, I can just like
Speaker 2:  stand up and, and work out for just like a couple of minutes and it helps.
Speaker 2:  It's not a full workout. No one is going to accuse me of being
Speaker 2:  shredded. But it is like that, that is a thing that like to your point of
Speaker 2:  like making it easy, I made that specific piece of working out really, really
Speaker 2:  easy and it really helped. And the like, Amazon basic
Speaker 2:  dumbbells are very cheap and the box is hilariously heavy and
Speaker 2:  I, I recommend everybody doing that. My last question to you before
Speaker 2:  I let you go is for people who are kind of like one level up
Speaker 2:  from just sort of learning how many steps they take in a day
Speaker 2:  and I'm like, I want to exercise more, I wanna be more consistent. I think
Speaker 2:  a lot of those people are looking for a place
Speaker 2:  to manage that, right? Like a, an app or a smartwatch
Speaker 2:  or like maybe the answer is a piece of paper or something. Like I, I am a
Speaker 2:  person who exercises a little and I wanna be a little more regimented and
Speaker 2:  intentional about exercising more. Where would you point
Speaker 2:  those people?
Speaker 7:  So unfortunately a lot of it is based on what you wanna
Speaker 7:  do. Like If you like strengths training, I really love the latter
Speaker 7:  app. It's what stuck with me because my, my problem
Speaker 7:  with strengths training and why I put it off for so long was I didn't know
Speaker 7:  what I was supposed to do. Like I wanted to strengths train as a runner.
Speaker 7:  I didn't know what exercises to do. I don't know how long to do it for. I
Speaker 7:  can turn my brain off with this app and it's great because
Speaker 7:  they have six week progressive overload programs and then a two week
Speaker 7:  break and they just repeat that ad in Finit. There's different
Speaker 7:  types of strengths training programs in there. So I'm in Move well, which
Speaker 7:  is like for beginners and it focuses on movements that are good
Speaker 7:  for runners. So it's like perfect and wow, I got faster at running. Oh my
Speaker 7:  God. And then that success kept me going. But if you're someone who wants
Speaker 7:  to get shredded, they have those things for people at the gym who are doing
Speaker 7:  the Scary Smith Mach, like all that sort of stuff. They have those programs
Speaker 7:  for you too. Different teams, If you're a yoga person and a
Speaker 7:  Pilates person, they have strength things that incorporate that. So there's
Speaker 7:  just like a bunch of different things that you can go to. I think if you're
Speaker 7:  a beginner or intermediate and you just don't wanna think about crafting
Speaker 7:  your own program or hiring a personal trainer, that's a great app.
Speaker 7:  It's been working for me. I love it. If you are
Speaker 7:  a runner, I think any running app
Speaker 7:  and you can like do research, I use Runkeeper. They have like little
Speaker 7:  training programs so they're like, oh, here's my goal, here's what I wanna
Speaker 7:  do. It generates a little training program for me based on weeks. And that's
Speaker 7:  how I've trained for marathon half marathons. And
Speaker 7:  my current goal of doing 5K,
Speaker 7:  basically I tell it how many days I wanna run what
Speaker 7:  my time goal is. And I wanna say after a really
Speaker 7:  solid seven month training block last year I
Speaker 7:  reduced my four mile time by 16 minutes. Good,
Speaker 2:  Good work. Which
Speaker 7:  Insane. And like I was showing up and like once you start
Speaker 7:  getting progress it gets a addictive. And I was like, oh
Speaker 7:  yay. Like that's there for me. Like I don't have to think about like
Speaker 7:  what kind of exercises and training I'm gonna do. It's all,
Speaker 7:  there's speed work in there, there's tempo runs in there, there's long runs
Speaker 7:  in there and there are so many different apps that do that. For runners specifically,
Speaker 7:  there's Run. Yeah, there's Nike Run club. So just pick
Speaker 2:  One. I'm gonna get emails for saying this. Yeah. But I think the running
Speaker 2:  apps are like a dime a dozen. They
Speaker 7:  Are, they
Speaker 2:  Are pick pick the one that is like start with one that's free. A because
Speaker 2:  a lot of these will try to make you pay very quickly and B, just
Speaker 2:  pick one. That seems fine. Right? Like there, there for like a
Speaker 2:  straightforward running plan. It's there are a million out there that will
Speaker 2:  work for you.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Now pick one that like a chill friend of yours is on.
Speaker 7:  That's the key. Like my chill friend was on Runkeeper, so now we just like,
Speaker 7:  like each other's activities and it's nice. That's smart.
Speaker 2:  The couch to 5K one I use by the way is called five K Runner and
Speaker 2:  I like it very much and it has one of those AI coaches that at the end of
Speaker 2:  every run is like, you did such a good job. And I'm like, you're lying. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I walked most of this and it's like, that's, I'm so proud of you. Oh's fine.
Speaker 2:  You're terrific. See you in a couple days.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna tell you, in most races that I've ever run, there are plenty of
Speaker 7:  people walking. So yeah, the idea that you have to do a long race
Speaker 7:  and just completely walk the entire time is bullshit. It's just bullshit.
Speaker 7:  You can, you can take a walk break, many professional runners take walk breaks.
Speaker 7:  It's very normal to do that. But yeah, so
Speaker 7:  find whatever. There's so much out there. Like I will continue to write about
Speaker 7:  the ones that I find that I like that helped me because I am
Speaker 7:  absolutely not the crazy, like DC Rainmaker
Speaker 7:  is a really nice guy. I love his stuff. I could never do what he does. And
Speaker 7:  I think most of us are in that boat. We're just normal
Speaker 7:  people trying to be relatively
Speaker 7:  not dying as a couch potato. And, and,
Speaker 7:  and because of that, you are not an Olympian. You do not have to do what
Speaker 7:  Olympians do. You don't, that doesn't make any sense. So
Speaker 7:  just, just relax. I really love your dumbbell hack though
Speaker 7:  because I think that's exactly the type of thing that counts.
Speaker 7:  Like, and most exercise research will say like you doing that
Speaker 7:  is probably like elongating your, your longevity
Speaker 7:  in your life by like an amount that is stupidly high
Speaker 7:  proportional of the work that you're putting in. It is, it's just like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think, I think walking five flights of stairs a day is enough to like
Speaker 7:  increase your like cardio health by a crap ton. Like you just have to
Speaker 7:  do five staircases a day. That's it most, that's doable for most people.
Speaker 7:  So yeah, it's just do, just do small, do small things. Don't make your goal
Speaker 7:  get shredded by June. Make your goal, get shredded by
Speaker 7:  June, 2040. Like, like, or something like that.
Speaker 7:  That's, that's actually my goal. My goal is to get shredded in four years
Speaker 7:  for my 40th. So that's it. That's it. I love that. I'm not doing it, I'm
Speaker 7:  not doing it in a year, I'm doing it in four years. Like that's, that's kind
Speaker 7:  of the the energy you need to have.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. I know. I I keep harping on this. Like, it it, the, there are
Speaker 2:  people who do this as a lifestyle thing and that's like, I feel like it's
Speaker 2:  useful to remember that that is, that is like a hundred on the zero to a
Speaker 2:  hundred scale. We treat it as like a zero and a one. Right. Like either
Speaker 2:  yeah, you're a couch potato who's gonna die in three days
Speaker 2:  or running is your life. Yeah. And like no, there's actually,
Speaker 2:  there's so much in between and you can just, there
Speaker 2:  there's, there are literally huge benefits to going from a zero
Speaker 2:  to a one or from a five to a six or from a 25 to a
Speaker 2:  26. Yeah. Like that's, and that's the way I've, I've tried to learn how to
Speaker 2:  think about this is like, don't, I don't need to become quote unquote a
Speaker 2:  runner. I'm just gonna go for a run that's, that's I'm gonna go
Speaker 2:  for a run and if I like it, maybe I'll run tomorrow and if not, I
Speaker 2:  don't know. I'll play more supernatural. It'll be fine.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like I, you know, I went to CESI brought four sets of workout clothes
Speaker 7:  and I was like, if I do one that's a success. I did two. So I
Speaker 7:  super succeeded. Like that's, that's how it goes. And like,
Speaker 2:  I appreciate the optimism of four outfits for it though.
Speaker 7:  I, yeah, it was very optimistic, but I was just like,
Speaker 7:  it was very optimistic. But I went for two, which I thought I was gonna
Speaker 7:  go for zero. I went for two. I fricking crushed it.
Speaker 7:  Like it's, it's snowing outside. I can't go for a four
Speaker 7:  mile run right now like I normally would. I'm gonna go for a
Speaker 7:  shitty, not very great run on a treadmill.
Speaker 7:  You know what, I'm crushing it. That's all that is. That's all it is. Just
Speaker 7:  like give yourself a participation trophy. Like
Speaker 7:  that's it. That's it. You don't need to win a gold medal, just get the participation
Speaker 7:  trophy.
Speaker 2:  Do you wanna know the best thing I this, I had not thought of this until
Speaker 2:  just now, but as you're talking about this, when my now wife and I first
Speaker 2:  started dating, she was a big runner and she got me to run with her
Speaker 2:  by always running to donuts. We, we found, found, there you go. We were
Speaker 2:  living in New York and we, we would just run to different donut shops all
Speaker 2:  over New York,
Speaker 2:  the single most consistently I have ever run. And part of it was because
Speaker 2:  like I liked her and wanted her to like me, but I also got to run to donuts
Speaker 2:  nuts. And I'm convinced that I ran faster and longer and more consistently
Speaker 2:  to donuts than I have ever run in my life. So like you
Speaker 2:  get your participation trophy. I get donuts, everybody wins.
Speaker 7:  The the donut is the participation trophy. Yes. Is what I'm saying. It's
Speaker 7:  perfect. Like just whatever your participation trophy is, go get it because
Speaker 7:  Love it. That's all you need.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I love it. All right vi thank you as always.
Speaker 7:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break, but then we're gonna come back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So a couple of weeks ago, a group at a
Speaker 2:  university in Finland launched this thing called The Nokia Design
Speaker 2:  Archive. And basically it is thousands of old
Speaker 2:  documents from Nokia from like the early
Speaker 2:  two thousands all the way back into the nineties. And If you
Speaker 2:  don't remember, Nokia was the cell phone industry
Speaker 2:  at the time. In a very real way, this was like the biggest, most successful
Speaker 2:  company in the early days of cell phones. And inside
Speaker 2:  this design Archive right now it's 755 documents
Speaker 2:  all about just the design and thinking
Speaker 2:  inside of that company about what phones should be. And there's all
Speaker 2:  kinds of truly incredible stuff in there. You go through and there's tons
Speaker 2:  of different just lifestyle images of like two
Speaker 2:  dudes sitting on a tennis court and one of them is talking on his
Speaker 2:  phone. And it's the kind of thing that now is like, that's just a picture
Speaker 2:  of two people. But that picture's from the nineties when it was
Speaker 2:  not common for two dudes sitting on a tennis court
Speaker 2:  to have cell phones in addition to all of the promotional
Speaker 2:  materials. There are tons of concepts. I think if, If you do one thing in
Speaker 2:  this design Archive, you should go through and look at some of the
Speaker 2:  concepts. And there are concepts for all kinds of things. Some of them are
Speaker 2:  phones, right? Like Nokia had big ideas about how phones
Speaker 2:  maybe should be squishy or how phones should maybe
Speaker 2:  be modular. There were lots of different ideas about what if a phone was
Speaker 2:  just a little kind of candy bar shaped thing that you could stick into
Speaker 2:  lots of different sorts of cases and maybe where, or have an
Speaker 2:  FM radio on top of, or any number of things. There's one that I
Speaker 2:  really like that's called Moonraker, and it was a Nokia smartwatch that never
Speaker 2:  made it on the market, never got shipped, but it's just an Apple watch.
Speaker 2:  Like I don't, I don't know how else to put it. It has a vertical ui, it looks
Speaker 2:  like an Apple watch. It's kind of a mix of the Apple Watch
Speaker 2:  and like the tile look of Windows eight.
Speaker 2:  Maybe that combination is not a super good idea, but it,
Speaker 2:  it's just fascinating. This is in 2014, so it's not like Nokia is, you know,
Speaker 2:  a million miles ahead of what Apple is doing. But everybody was thinking
Speaker 2:  about this stuff and one of the things that I think is so interesting about
Speaker 2:  all of this is to see how much
Speaker 2:  of what's going on in tech is actually going on everywhere. And the big
Speaker 2:  question is like how are these things supposed to work and how are you going
Speaker 2:  to use them and what do they mean in your life? One other thing you should
Speaker 2:  check out is called P-Tech clothing. That was one of these big modular
Speaker 2:  ideas that Nokia had and they had this idea that
Speaker 2:  maybe you'd wear your phone on a lanyard around
Speaker 2:  your neck and you'd have one that was like cool and Gucci
Speaker 2:  made during the day, but then you'd have one that was like rubbery and sporty
Speaker 2:  that you'd wear when you were, you know, out on the go. Nokia had so many
Speaker 2:  interesting ideas about how people would use phones
Speaker 2:  and I think that's really cool and it's not the kind of thing you see now
Speaker 2:  where everybody is trying to sell phones to, you know, 3 billion people all
Speaker 2:  over the earth. Now You see all these companies who are trying to sell phones
Speaker 2:  to, you know, billions of people at a time. And so we've gotten to the point
Speaker 2:  where so many phones in particular have just hit
Speaker 2:  kind of a lowest common denominator. I don't mean that as an insult,
Speaker 2:  they're just not different anymore. Even If you and I buy
Speaker 2:  different phones, you buy a Samsung phone, I buy an iPhone, you buy a
Speaker 2:  Huawei phone, I buy a one plus phone. They're just
Speaker 2:  slabs of glass at this point. They all have cameras in basically the same
Speaker 2:  place. They all do basically the same thing. And it's really fun to go in
Speaker 2:  and see Nokia reckoning with this idea of how do we change
Speaker 2:  everything? And there's this sense of like, phones aren't inevitably
Speaker 2:  this one thing. Like there's no sense inside of Nokia that they're building
Speaker 2:  towards this one specific platonic idea of a smartphone.
Speaker 2:  Instead they're just like, what if our phones kind of
Speaker 2:  looked like gaming handheld consoles? And then they have one that's
Speaker 2:  called Hitchhiker that is like a prop from a sci-fi
Speaker 2:  movie with the, the keys on the side and the screen in the middle. That one
Speaker 2:  actually was very cool and it's code named Hitchhiker, which I think absolutely
Speaker 2:  rules. Nokia had so many ideas about technology and I found
Speaker 2:  myself going through this wondering how unusual this
Speaker 2:  company really was. I think over the course of 20 years we get to see
Speaker 2:  all of this information and these concepts and these
Speaker 2:  presentations in which Nokia just tries to invent the future
Speaker 2:  in a thousand different directions. And maybe that's what
Speaker 2:  every company is doing, but maybe not. And maybe the
Speaker 2:  fact that we have glass slabs of smartphones is a
Speaker 2:  sign that we need more of this, more weird ideas, more trying to invent
Speaker 2:  the future in a thousand different directions all at the same time. I find
Speaker 2:  this whole Archive fascinating and I really think if you're listening to
Speaker 2:  this podcast, you are the kind of person who should go and just poke around
Speaker 2:  it for 20 minutes. You will find something you've never seen in here before.
Speaker 2:  I absolutely guarantee it and I truly cannot recommend
Speaker 2:  just poking around and looking at some of these different concepts. Enough.
Speaker 2:  I'll put a few of them in the show notes because frankly just everyone should
Speaker 2:  see these, but it's a really good time. All that said,
Speaker 2:  I knew immediately after getting into this that I wanted to talk to somebody
Speaker 2:  who actually worked on this and has seen all of these materials and can help
Speaker 2:  me make some sense of the story behind all this stuff. So
Speaker 2:  I called up Anna Altan, who is one of the researchers who actually put this
Speaker 2:  whole Archive together. She is a professor at Alto
Speaker 2:  University, which is where this Archive is being held. She also worked at
Speaker 2:  Nokia in the design department for a long time. She's seen all sides of this
Speaker 2:  and knows this space better than just about anybody. So I figured I'd have
Speaker 2:  her just bring me through the Archive a little bit and help me see if we
Speaker 2:  can figure out what lessons to learn. So let's just dive in. I
Speaker 2:  started by asking Ana to just explain her history a little bit and how
Speaker 2:  in particular she got started at Nokia.
Speaker 15:  Okay, well I started at Nokia a long time ago. I was
Speaker 15:  recently graduated, it was in the mid nineties or late nineties. So then
Speaker 15:  I worked there as in the design organization, it all sorts of different
Speaker 15:  kinds of roles for a good 12 or 13 years. But this project
Speaker 15:  actually started a lot later than that. So when I was still working
Speaker 15:  back in Nokia, we used to keep store, you know, things in
Speaker 15:  archived in a, in a big room in the basement of the new headquarters at
Speaker 15:  the time. But then when I started doing research
Speaker 15:  around this, I was really focusing on what do designers do and how do
Speaker 15:  they work and so on. So I was quite keen on on getting all the, the
Speaker 15:  material from there. And eventually we did when by the time
Speaker 15:  Nokia had sort of sold off its phone activities to Microsoft
Speaker 15:  and Microsoft was going to move out from Finland with their
Speaker 15:  phone design or I'm not even sure if they were going to continue doing phone
Speaker 15:  designs at all at the time. So we got the stuff and we,
Speaker 15:  we pulled it all over to the Alto archives or
Speaker 15:  basically a storage room to start with. We didn't really know what to do
Speaker 15:  with it
Speaker 15:  'cause it was a lot and it was, it was not very, you know, it wasn't organized
Speaker 15:  so it was big boxes with all sorts of things mashed up together. So
Speaker 15:  after a while we got a research project around it, got some funding so we
Speaker 15:  could hire people and hands and start documenting what we
Speaker 15:  had and put them in order and, and start understanding what relates to to
Speaker 15:  what and so on. And, and we've been an a really wonderful
Speaker 15:  transdisciplinary team working with that material for a good four years
Speaker 15:  now. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So what was your sense at the beginning of what might be
Speaker 2:  inside of this trove of stuff?
Speaker 15:  There's all sorts. There's everything from sketches to
Speaker 15:  physical mockups, early stage mockups, very early sketchy kind of mockups
Speaker 15:  and very finalized products or, or products close to launch. There's
Speaker 15:  documentation of, of what happened while people were working on these
Speaker 15:  ideas and so on. And I think to me at least they really, all
Speaker 15:  the material it shows the work that goes on behind a
Speaker 15:  finalized product or before you get that far. So can you use
Speaker 15:  design to start thinking of what could be or, or you know, provoke a
Speaker 15:  discussion of should we maybe be doing that or, or use it
Speaker 15:  for understanding what will people like or what would be important for them
Speaker 15:  or create a discussion and a debate around, you know, could we do something
Speaker 15:  completely new or different? And that's sort of what I'm hoping that
Speaker 15:  the Archive will do now when it's open for, for, for anyone
Speaker 15:  to, to dive in is if it creates or generates more of an
Speaker 15:  imagination of what could be or gets us to think of how could we
Speaker 15:  tackle these things that we don't quite know what they are yet. And, and
Speaker 15:  you know, in a sense I think we're in a similar situation now with new technology
Speaker 15:  AI coming and no one quite knows what it will be or how
Speaker 15:  it will be concrete in in our lives. So
Speaker 15:  we could at least imagine and we could try stuff and we could test it and
Speaker 15:  we can see what works.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. It, it's, I'm glad you brought that up because that was one of
Speaker 2:  the things that struck me most going through the Archive is there's this
Speaker 2:  real sense of questioning what a smartphone
Speaker 2:  is supposed to be and what technology is supposed to be and how we're
Speaker 2:  supposed to hold it and use it. And Nokia was obsessed with this idea of
Speaker 2:  like gadgets that go into little containers that change the features of those
Speaker 2:  gadgets. The, like, it just seemed like every designer at Nokia had some
Speaker 2:  idea about, you know, these modular gadgets.
Speaker 2:  Like do you remember those kinds of conversations back then when, when it
Speaker 2:  wasn't so obvious to everybody what a smartphone was? I think we think about
Speaker 2:  it now as sort of inevitable that like, this is what a smartphone
Speaker 2:  is, it's a slab of glass.
Speaker 2:  I don't think it was inevitable and I don't, and I think there were, there
Speaker 2:  were so many different ideas back then, like does it, does it bring
Speaker 2:  up some of those questions again to look at all these things now?
Speaker 15:  It was far from inevitable. There were so many, I remember many of
Speaker 15:  the discussions, one I remember particularly well was when
Speaker 15:  sometime far in the future there were going to be 3G networks.
Speaker 15:  They might make it possible to send a picture or you could even have a
Speaker 15:  video one day and, and some of the concepts were trying to,
Speaker 15:  to make that concrete. So what would it be If you could actually
Speaker 15:  talk with someone so that you would see them at the same time or,
Speaker 15:  or you could send content that would be visual, which today seems
Speaker 15:  completely self-evident right? And obvious and we're, we're having this
Speaker 15:  discussion today over, you know, we can see each other while we're talking.
Speaker 15:  So a lot has happened.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think it's just so interesting to think about going back to before
Speaker 2:  all of that stuff was so obvious and these questions of
Speaker 2:  like, what does it mean and, and how are we supposed to use it? And there,
Speaker 2:  one of my favorite things in the Archive is all these concept videos that
Speaker 2:  are in there that just absolutely don't make any sense. Like there's one
Speaker 2:  where there, there she, she's looking through a thing and there's an owl
Speaker 2:  in it and then all of a sudden there's an owl flying around in a room and
Speaker 2:  it's, I, I could not even explain to you what that is about, but there is
Speaker 2:  this open question and I think Nokia was very good
Speaker 2:  at this before almost any other company was thinking about it, about like
Speaker 2:  how the technology that you have and the real world that
Speaker 2:  you're in are supposed to interact. And, and I think
Speaker 2:  just now on the other end of, you know, 20 years of all of us being pulled
Speaker 2:  more and more and more into screens, it was just neat to go back and be like,
Speaker 2:  okay, this was, this was a question we had about these are things that should
Speaker 2:  exist in the real world that we should use in the real world
Speaker 2:  and that should interact with the real world. And I, I was just, I was so
Speaker 2:  struck by that way of thinking almost it felt more like science fiction
Speaker 2:  than product design in a lot of ways.
Speaker 15:  But what we're also bringing up is a very important point on the fact that
Speaker 15:  it takes time. That that, you know, there's, there's a long, it could
Speaker 15:  be a lot later in, you know, you might have a first idea of something
Speaker 15:  and then it goes through all sorts of levels of product development and
Speaker 15:  ideation and, and further refinement and whatnot. And then you get
Speaker 15:  a first product out and that might be years from when you, you know, first
Speaker 15:  were discussing it and then when the first product comes out it might still
Speaker 15:  not make a market or be self-evident
Speaker 15:  and then take five years later and everyone thinks that it's quite normal,
Speaker 15:  right? So it's maybe, or at least for me,
Speaker 15:  it's been really wonderful to hear people look at the Archive and they realize,
Speaker 15:  well this looks, you know, normal and then they look at the year and say,
Speaker 15:  oh, it was 10 years before it was on the market, or oh it was
Speaker 15:  in know 15 years before we thought that was normal. So
Speaker 15:  it shows you or hope, I'm hoping that it will give people the idea of
Speaker 15:  perspective too that yeah, technology doesn't just
Speaker 15:  appear we're actually all creating it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What do you think it was about Nokia in particular that so
Speaker 2:  many of those things were happening inside of that company
Speaker 2:  so long before they were out in the world? I think to some extent this question
Speaker 2:  of what if we can see each other on video has been on everybody's mind
Speaker 2:  since, you know, a century ago it's, it was, that was kind of an obvious
Speaker 2:  thing that would eventually happen, but there's so much of this in the Archive
Speaker 2:  that is just products we have now. And I I think
Speaker 2:  maybe that's true lots of places, but I, I was shocked going through it.
Speaker 2:  How much of 2024 and 2025 exists
Speaker 2:  in these drawings from like 2000. What do you think it was about
Speaker 2:  Nokia that led to that?
Speaker 15:  That's a very good question and, and it's, it's always easy to to be smart,
Speaker 15:  you know, hindsight, but I do think it was a wonderful working culture
Speaker 15:  of where there was an allowance for testing and for trying things
Speaker 15:  out out and almost an enthusiasm for, for what could be.
Speaker 15:  But I also think that many organizations have similar
Speaker 15:  activities with them today. It's just that we don't know about it
Speaker 15:  'cause we can't see into other organizations. So
Speaker 15:  that's why I'm so happy about this Archive, that it's, it's one glimpse
Speaker 15:  in, into what has happened for real. It's not
Speaker 15:  potential or maybe, or you know, it's, it's actual
Speaker 15:  empirical material of, of things that happened, right? Might miss pieces
Speaker 15:  in between, but at least it's there. The one area that
Speaker 15:  I really like, and this is probably because of my own research
Speaker 15:  and my own background, I really like that it makes the design
Speaker 15:  process very concrete that, that you can really understand
Speaker 15:  what happens in these teams because the teams are often big. They're, they're
Speaker 15:  multidisciplinary, there's a lot of people interacting and so on and, and
Speaker 15:  it's easy to talk about these heroic designers or something like that.
Speaker 15:  But, but this Archive actually shows that there's a lot of people involved.
Speaker 15:  And what do they actually do? Well, they come up with a mood board or they
Speaker 15:  come up with a sketch or they have a meeting where they talk about this.
Speaker 15:  So, so somehow it's so tangible to me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was struck by how iterative some of this stuff is where
Speaker 2:  there was one I was thinking of where it's a, it's a gaming machine
Speaker 2:  and it, it, it looks a lot like the Nintendo Switch, right? Like there's
Speaker 2:  a, there's a thing, I think it's from, it was either 2000 or 2003, I forget,
Speaker 2:  but it is, it is just straightforwardly a gaming handheld
Speaker 2:  and in it, there is just this one document of basically every imaginable
Speaker 2:  version of a gaming handheld and which I loved very much. It's like, here
Speaker 2:  are the six wild ideas about what this could be. And then you can sort of
Speaker 2:  see over time you, you you winnow it down slightly and then you expand it
Speaker 2:  slightly and then you winnow it down slightly and then you expand it and
Speaker 2:  it's like, that's the design process. Not someone
Speaker 2:  goes into a dark room and comes back fully formed with the Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 2:  It's like, this is how this work actually gets done. And I think you're right
Speaker 2:  that we don't see the way that these things get done because everybody wants
Speaker 2:  to come up at the end and say, here is this beautiful thing that emerged
Speaker 2:  from the earth fully formed and that's just not at all how it
Speaker 2:  ever actually works.
Speaker 15:  Yeah, exactly. So I'm hoping that people explore that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it, it was, it was a very fun, I kept going through looking
Speaker 2:  for gadgets that exist now that were in, were being
Speaker 2:  talked about back then. And you, you can find 'em everywhere. There's a thing
Speaker 2:  that looks like the Apple watch, there's a thing that looks like the Nintendo
Speaker 2:  Switch. There are every smartphone and PDA that you can imagine. It was very
Speaker 2:  fun. I I enjoyed that frame much.
Speaker 15:  There's probably 25 different kinds of smart watches right. From
Speaker 15:  different parts of the company and different times and different levels
Speaker 15:  of technology and, and you know, different user
Speaker 15:  ideas and so on. So it's not one, there's a lot.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So the, a lot of the folks listening to this show are, are
Speaker 2:  gadget people. This is what we do at The Verge for gadget people
Speaker 2:  doing all this research. Did you have any, any favorite gadgets or
Speaker 2:  concepts or wild quixotic quests that Nokia
Speaker 2:  went on that, that jumped out to you? Any sort of favorite historical artifacts?
Speaker 15:  Many For me, I think the, the most important ones were the
Speaker 15:  ones that I had no idea of Hmm. When I was there because it was a big company
Speaker 15:  and there's a lot of things happening and going, going on.
Speaker 15:  And also maybe, and let's see if, if what your audience
Speaker 15:  will think, I think the easy access point is to look at crazy and
Speaker 15:  wild concepts. But If you take a little bit more of an effort and you go
Speaker 15:  into the actual presentation documents that are attached to them,
Speaker 15:  that's where you really see the width of it. Ah, okay look,
Speaker 15:  they had this kind of background understanding and look, this is what they
Speaker 15:  thought about and, and oh they did five different ideas that were
Speaker 15:  completely different than what actually turned out in the end and so on.
Speaker 15:  So I'm wishing and hoping for that, that people would take the
Speaker 15:  time and effort to go a little bit beyond only cool gadgets. But
Speaker 15:  let's see.
Speaker 2:  There are so many cool gadgets though. You could, I, there's just so many
Speaker 2:  cool gadgets.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think, this is the thing I've been thinking about and and you've
Speaker 2:  spent more time in these documents than I have, so I'm curious If you have
Speaker 2:  any thoughts, why was Nokia so obsessed with these modular
Speaker 2:  gadgets? I mean truly everything is like, it's a thing that goes into
Speaker 2:  a case and becomes something else or bends around. There's one that was like,
Speaker 2:  you can put it on your ankle or around your wrist or hold it like a phone.
Speaker 2:  And there was this, this obsession with these sort of malleable
Speaker 2:  gadgets. Why do you think that was so pervasive?
Speaker 15:  There's probably many answers and I'm, I'm not sure that was always the,
Speaker 15:  the obsession either, but I think it's, it's good to remember
Speaker 15:  what did the real products look like when these concepts were made. So
Speaker 15:  many of the early modular concepts, the real products were actually
Speaker 15:  huge lumps that you were dragging along, right? You know, so
Speaker 15:  If you, If you did want to use it while using sports for
Speaker 15:  example, maybe you didn't wanna go jogging with something that
Speaker 15:  weighed a lot, maybe it would've been a lot easier If you could take just
Speaker 15:  a small part of something with you. So maybe people also
Speaker 15:  imagined
Speaker 15:  in relation to what they had at the time. Hmm. So so you take the
Speaker 15:  challenge with what you have then, and then you try to imagine
Speaker 15:  a solution that would be better than that. But now we only see
Speaker 15:  the proposed solution and we forget why they thought that was better
Speaker 15:  than what they had.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it, it's interesting to think that there was that kind of
Speaker 2:  thinking going at the same time as Nokia
Speaker 2:  was kind of at the peak of its powers though. I mean the company was so big
Speaker 2:  and so powerful and made the phones
Speaker 2:  everybody had, but still seemed to have this
Speaker 2:  sort of wildly experimental arm going on. And again,
Speaker 2:  maybe there's more of that going on in some of these companies than we think,
Speaker 2:  but my sense is now, especially
Speaker 2:  these gadgets are so big and so important and there's so much money in them
Speaker 2:  that I, I I just would bet there are not a lot of people
Speaker 2:  inside of Apple thinking about wholesale lifestyle changes to the iPhone,
Speaker 2:  right? Like the, these things maybe have just matured beyond that point,
Speaker 2:  but it's forever interesting to me that even at the moment Nokia is making
Speaker 2:  all of the bestselling phones on earth, all of them, it was
Speaker 2:  still in this phase of like, how can we reimagine everything all
Speaker 2:  the time?
Speaker 15:  Agree. But I can also contradict you a little bit. I think it's
Speaker 15:  actually normal because we have other research that shows that
Speaker 15:  in a moment of big pivots when everything is changing in the world where,
Speaker 15:  where technology shifts are happening, big shifts like we have today, then
Speaker 15:  that's exactly the moment where you need to be more creative. So
Speaker 15:  that's also the moment in time where you need to think
Speaker 15:  with a broader mindset. Hmm.
Speaker 2:  And and was there something about Nokia's sort of corporate culture that
Speaker 2:  pushed towards that with just people given permission to do that kind of
Speaker 2:  thing More than most?
Speaker 15:  I think there was, and I'm not sure they were given permission or if the
Speaker 15:  culture was just such that they dared to take the permission even
Speaker 15:  without getting so, so more of a culture
Speaker 15:  of of try it and, and see which
Speaker 15:  is great and which there's a lot of other scholars talking about today
Speaker 15:  that that's the kind of organizational culture that would be great to have
Speaker 15:  where people aren't afraid to try stuff or, or so, so,
Speaker 15:  so, but of course we don't know what other companies are doing at the moment.
Speaker 15:  Right. But
Speaker 2:  But hopefully they'll share now too.
Speaker 15:  Exactly. But there's something in, in the air today where
Speaker 15:  we are a little bit cautious, we're very afraid of doing wrong,
Speaker 15:  whereas I think it's wonderful when we can try things out that maybe
Speaker 15:  some of them can be right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. And is it, are there things to be
Speaker 2:  learned for tech companies now, do you think on, on how all of this worked?
Speaker 2:  I mean, to some extent some of this stuff is so
Speaker 2:  different in the world in which it was taking place than the one that we
Speaker 2:  live in now that
Speaker 2:  I, I wonder how like some of the, some of the sort of specifics are
Speaker 2:  probably not applicable, like Nokia's wild ideas, some of them
Speaker 2:  are less wild now and some of them are even more wild now. But do you think
Speaker 2:  if I'm a, if I'm a tech company in 2025, trying to think through how to
Speaker 2:  replicate processes like these, like are there lessons from Nokia in that?
Speaker 15:  Definitely and I think ways of working are still very valid. So say for
Speaker 15:  example that you are in a completely different company, a smaller one that's
Speaker 15:  starting with this kind of, of, you know, future technology thinking maybe
Speaker 15:  it's a good thing to be able to peak somewhere, but how did they do? Because
Speaker 15:  much of the ways of doing it are still very much the same. You try to
Speaker 15:  understand end users and you try to imagine what could be, and you develop
Speaker 15:  products which will be the best possible for whomever you're trying to approach
Speaker 15:  and so on. So, so I think, or
Speaker 15:  I'm hoping at least maybe one day it could be useful also for someone
Speaker 15:  who, who should know how it works but isn't quite sure, you know,
Speaker 15:  maybe it could be your backdrop so that you could, you could check how they
Speaker 15:  did before you go into a meeting of your own or, or something. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Do you think we are back at a similar moment because of ai? I think
Speaker 2:  we certainly have not had a moment as sort of
Speaker 2:  specifically culturally transformative since
Speaker 2:  cell phones and, and you can kind of write that timeline however you want,
Speaker 2:  but it's probably been somewhere between 15
Speaker 2:  and 20 years since we had a moment like that. Do you think we're back in
Speaker 2:  one of those moments because of ai?
Speaker 15:  Very much so. And I don't think it's only the arrival of new technology.
Speaker 15:  And that's what I'm hoping that this Archive will show too. It's society
Speaker 15:  only shifts when people shift how they, you know, interact
Speaker 15:  and are in the world too. And that's, that's where people come in and,
Speaker 15:  and that's I think what something that you can see from this material that,
Speaker 15:  you know, it really tries to understand what do people do with it and how
Speaker 15:  do they conduct their lives and what would make sense for them and so on.
Speaker 15:  And I think we are definitely in that societal pivotal moment
Speaker 15:  now where, where we, we know that new technology will be with us,
Speaker 15:  but we don't quite know how we will use it in our
Speaker 15:  everyday, it isn't very tangible yet. We don't know
Speaker 15:  how how we will conduct our lives differently through it. So, so
Speaker 15:  I think it would be a wonderful moment in time too to use similar methodology
Speaker 15:  and to, to to learn from at least what has been and
Speaker 15:  and and to try and be creative. Maybe
Speaker 15:  be optimistic or, or, or imagine what could be
Speaker 2:  A, a question I find myself talking about with, with product makers a lot
Speaker 2:  is just how far into the future is it even useful to think
Speaker 2:  about? And I increasingly, I talk to folks in tech
Speaker 2:  who are thinking about like 18 months from now and, and three years from
Speaker 2:  now because they're of the mind that it's just not useful to make
Speaker 2:  bigger, longer prognostications because the world changes very fast and also
Speaker 2:  who cares, right? Like, we'll figure that out when we get there.
Speaker 2:  But even again, just to go back to the science fiction comparison, there
Speaker 2:  is so much in this Archive that is just
Speaker 2:  pure sort of futuristic science fiction and, and I wonder
Speaker 2:  inside of a company what value that brings
Speaker 2:  for a company that is like shipping and making new products to also think
Speaker 2:  what is the world gonna look like in 10 or 20 or 50 years? And Nokia was
Speaker 2:  clearly doing a lot of that and, and I have forever kind of
Speaker 2:  wondered how valuable that kind of thinking is
Speaker 2:  inside of a company like that.
Speaker 15:  I think the important point is that the world doesn't happen. Someone
Speaker 15:  does something that changes something and, and
Speaker 15:  you know, the, this shows some examples of how that was done, but, but that's
Speaker 15:  exactly how, so this 18 month thinking
Speaker 15:  cycle, it means that you think that someone else will create the world and
Speaker 15:  you'll just be reacting to it. Whereas you can also think of what would
Speaker 15:  you want it to be or, or what would you not want it to be? And, and start
Speaker 15:  having a discussion around that and then hopefully maybe, you know,
Speaker 15:  coming out with something that makes sense in whatever you've imagined.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you think, do you think Nokia gets credit for moments like that
Speaker 2:  in, in some of the history you've been looking at? Are there kind of before
Speaker 2:  and after moments because of something that came out of this company?
Speaker 15:  I think Nokia got a lot of credit of all the great things it did when it
Speaker 15:  was
Speaker 15:  as its biggest. Then it got a lot of negative
Speaker 15:  sort of insights from, from when it didn't do so well. And we've been living
Speaker 15:  in that wave now with a lot of people trying to
Speaker 15:  think what went wrong and so on. But I'm hoping that we're sort of getting
Speaker 15:  beyond both of those now to a period where we can look at it with
Speaker 15:  more, not neutral eyes, but different eyes, you know, to see different
Speaker 15:  perspectives out of the material and, and different angles that we hadn't
Speaker 15:  thought of before and so on. So, so that's I think, quite typical
Speaker 15:  that near time we're always blind. So in the
Speaker 15:  Nokia case, I think we've been blind in both directions.
Speaker 2:  Looking through the Archive, I found myself torn between sort
Speaker 2:  of two overarching theories. One is
Speaker 2:  that there was kind of a, a unified theory
Speaker 2:  of Nokia about phones in particular and the future and
Speaker 2:  kind of how technology and people were supposed to interact.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like it, I could, I could sort of twist into like a,
Speaker 2:  a unifying theory of everything. And on the other side, I, I
Speaker 2:  was struck by the fact that actually what's going on is just this unbelievably
Speaker 2:  chaotic design process where everybody is trying to think about everything
Speaker 2:  and then you just throw it all in a pot and hope something cool comes out.
Speaker 2:  And that maybe that's actually the magic of design is that there is
Speaker 2:  something unknowably weird going on here.
Speaker 2:  Is it, is it either one of those two things? Is it something in between?
Speaker 15:  I think it's probably both. Okay. So it's of course it's messy and and creative
Speaker 15:  while you're at it. And of course there's always some structure into it,
Speaker 15:  but it can also depend on on who's who you will be asking or
Speaker 15:  when you will be asking and, and what the, the opportunities
Speaker 15:  to do something around you are. But, but it's definitely both of those,
Speaker 15:  it's, it's very rarely completely clear from the very beginning. It's, it's
Speaker 15:  very, you know, complex and messy and you try stuff
Speaker 15:  out and then at some point it has to get slightly clearer 'cause otherwise
Speaker 15:  you won't be an organization that actually produces anything.
Speaker 15:  So, so, so there's a, there's both.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I just think I, the, the unifying theory I keep coming back to and
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna, I'm gonna pause at this and then I'm curious how, what you
Speaker 2:  think about it. I think we live in a moment now where
Speaker 2:  technology is such a destination, right? Where everybody is
Speaker 2:  building metaverse worlds for you to go to and games you're supposed to
Speaker 2:  spend time in and screens you're supposed to stare at for hours at a time
Speaker 2:  and everything is supposed to sort of draw you in and engage you more and
Speaker 2:  more. And I feel like Nokia at, at that moment, and I'm thinking
Speaker 2:  particularly kind of right after
Speaker 2:  to the year 2000, kind of in that phase between cell phones were everywhere,
Speaker 2:  but smart phones were nowhere yet, right? In that moment, Nokia had this
Speaker 2:  very human centric idea of technology that it was a
Speaker 2:  thing that should fit onto you and be an accessory and be
Speaker 2:  around you, but was not meant to be this sort of all
Speaker 2:  consuming, engaging thing. It they were, it,
Speaker 2:  it, it all feels more like fashion than electronics in a way that I find
Speaker 2:  really interesting. And I, that's probably not everything, but I think that
Speaker 2:  to me just felt so different than what I'm used to in technology that I was
Speaker 2:  like, maybe this is just, maybe Nokia had a different idea about how we're
Speaker 2:  supposed to use technology than a lot of companies
Speaker 15:  Could be. And doesn't it always, every trend is always followed by
Speaker 15:  a counter trend and then back again. So If you have something that is,
Speaker 15:  you know, very focused on doing something well then you come
Speaker 15:  to a period when, where something should do everything for everyone. Hmm.
Speaker 15:  And then you might be coming back to a period where something should do
Speaker 15:  something well for someone. I can see the same, we have a lot
Speaker 15:  of people talking about how the digital era
Speaker 15:  made everything untangible and, and you know, just
Speaker 15:  pixels. And now I can also, in our students, I can see a trend back that
Speaker 15:  the haptic and the feeling of things and, and, and materiality
Speaker 15:  gained in importance again. So, so somehow these things also,
Speaker 15:  I don't know, but it seems like they're almost going in waves a little bit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I hope so. I mean, I, I look at so many of those concepts and presentations
Speaker 2:  and, and they're so obsessed with materials and, and
Speaker 2:  plushness and like they made electronics that were squishy. Nothing
Speaker 2:  is squishy anymore. I love that they were squishy. How does
Speaker 15:  It feel to your skin and how do you interact with it in
Speaker 15:  a Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, maybe. I hope we get
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So last week on the work cast hotline, we answered
Speaker 2:  a question about audio on your iPhone and basically why can't you listen
Speaker 2:  to two things at the same time on your phone? I got a lot of feedback
Speaker 2:  from that hotline question, which was really fascinating. And the biggest
Speaker 2:  thing I heard from a couple of folks from developers in particular is
Speaker 2:  that when you have the thing that you're listening to music or
Speaker 2:  a podcast or whatever and you open an app that isn't immediately playing
Speaker 2:  audio but turns off the audio, you were already listening to like a lot of
Speaker 2:  games do this, like, like I said on last week's show, the ESPN app does this.
Speaker 2:  That's bad development and I, I, I know that, but I don't think I hit that
Speaker 2:  hard enough that that is not how that's supposed to work. That the way that
Speaker 2:  these apps manage outside background, audio
Speaker 2:  input is up to them and they could all stand to do a much better job.
Speaker 2:  One thing I like is I think a bunch of games actually do this really well
Speaker 2:  where you can be listening to a podcast but
Speaker 2:  playing the game and it'll, it'll play the game over top of
Speaker 2:  the audio sometimes. But If you also just, you know, turn off all the audio
Speaker 2:  in the game, you can just play your podcast. So like this thing can work
Speaker 2:  and the fact that it doesn't is a little bit Apple's fault because I think
Speaker 2:  Apple tries to hold people's hand too much, but it's also
Speaker 2:  developer's fault for not caring about getting that right. So If you run
Speaker 2:  into an app that's not getting that right complain because they can do better.
Speaker 2:  All that said, we got a question from Gus along the same lines
Speaker 2:  that has had me thinking all week. Gus says, sitting
Speaker 2:  in the drain listening to last week's show, I had a question, you explain
Speaker 2:  the difficulties of combining audio sources to a single output. I wonder
Speaker 2:  why it's also complicated the other way around when I wanna share the audio
Speaker 2:  from my phone to two sets of Bluetooth headphones, this appears impossible.
Speaker 2:  Yes, you can share earbuds, but not headphones, ox, audio splitters
Speaker 2:  were a thing. Why is this not a thing with wireless? This is the most
Speaker 2:  fascinating question. So I looked into this a bunch and
Speaker 2:  I have a couple of theories, but my theories are actually not the most
Speaker 2:  interesting part. So lemme just get through that really fast. I think one
Speaker 2:  of the reasons this is hard to do on an iPhone in particular is again,
Speaker 2:  it's not a particularly popular thing and I think if
Speaker 2:  you're a company like Apple, having it set so that
Speaker 2:  you can send all your audio to all your headphones all at the same time
Speaker 2:  just feels messy. And so for Apple to be able to say it's essentially
Speaker 2:  one audio device at a time, you don't have to manage it. You don't have to
Speaker 2:  go in and turn them off, you don't have to mess with it. You just tap the
Speaker 2:  one that you want and you start listening. Like I think about the Sonos thing
Speaker 2:  where If you have a bunch of Sonos speakers, you can set up kind of
Speaker 2:  infinite overlapping sets of those speakers. You're like, okay, I want this
Speaker 2:  to just play in my bedroom and in the bathroom, but I want this to play in
Speaker 2:  the living room, the bedroom in the bathroom, and I want this one to be on
Speaker 2:  all of them. That's really handy. But it's a lot of work and
Speaker 2:  I think for Apple particularly because Bluetooth frankly does
Speaker 2:  get messy, it is not a particularly great protocol. So if you're trying to
Speaker 2:  send synced audio to a bunch of places at once, it can get really complicated.
Speaker 2:  There's actually a way to do this on Android. I'll put a link in the show
Speaker 2:  notes, but especially If you have a Samsung phone, this is a pretty easy
Speaker 2:  thing to do. One thing I've learned by the way through this process is that
Speaker 2:  Samsung phones are very good at just letting you do things. And I've come
Speaker 2:  to really appreciate that about Samsung phones. They're like overly
Speaker 2:  complicated in a lot of ways. They have too many settings, menus. But when
Speaker 2:  I look up like how do you do this hard thing on a phone? The
Speaker 2:  answer most of the time is like, you can't do it on iOS, you can kind of
Speaker 2:  do it on Android and Samsung just has a setting for it and I love Samsung
Speaker 2:  for that. But I wanna share with you the thing that I discovered, and it's
Speaker 2:  possible that I am the last person on earth to have learned this, but I learned
Speaker 2:  this and so I'm gonna share it. There's this thing on
Speaker 2:  iOS that lets you share audio from your device
Speaker 2:  to multiple sets of headphones at the same time. I had no idea this existed.
Speaker 2:  I have done the thing where my wife and I sit on the
Speaker 2:  bed and she has one AirPod and I have the other
Speaker 2:  AirPod and we just like share a pair of headphones that way we have to keep
Speaker 2:  our heads really close to each other, like that's bad. And I just had no
Speaker 2:  idea there was a better way. But it turns out that If you have a supported
Speaker 2:  device, which is basically any newish
Speaker 2:  iPhone or iPad, it doesn't seem to work on other devices.
Speaker 2:  You can actually do it on a Mac by using the, the
Speaker 2:  MIDI settings thing on the Mac that's a little more complicated. But
Speaker 2:  on an iPhone in particular and on on an iPad, which I think is where most
Speaker 2:  people would wanna do this kind of thing, basically you put on your
Speaker 2:  AirPods, this only works If you have AirPods or Beats headphones, but
Speaker 2:  If you put on your AirPods and then when something is playing, you
Speaker 2:  tap the, the like, I guess it's this sort of airplay
Speaker 2:  thing, it's the little triangle with the, the radial circles around it.
Speaker 2:  It's a, it's sort of a sharing menu sort of an of an airplane menu. I don't
Speaker 2:  really know what to call it, but it's an icon and you tap it and if someone
Speaker 2:  near you has headphones that you can bring close to your own
Speaker 2:  device, you get a thing that says share audio and you, you
Speaker 2:  tap share audio and it'll pop up a new set
Speaker 2:  of headphones as if you're pairing a new set of headphones to your device.
Speaker 2:  You then, at least what I've had to do in the past is press and hold the
Speaker 2:  button on the back of those AirPods like the, the pairing button on the case,
Speaker 2:  but then it, it actually syncs it up to your phone and you
Speaker 2:  can play through two sets of AirPods at the same time.
Speaker 2:  This blew my mind, like how is this not a more known feature? Maybe
Speaker 2:  I'm the last person on earth again to have discovered that this exists. But
Speaker 2:  this is just a thing you can do. You can do it in control center. It's
Speaker 2:  most accessible I've found by the the little live activity
Speaker 2:  notification on the lock screen where you can hit the share button that way.
Speaker 2:  But the idea that you can actually have your phone connected and
Speaker 2:  synced simultaneously to two sets of AirPods is very cool.
Speaker 2:  Again, it's only AirPods and beads headphones and it's only iPhones and
Speaker 2:  iPads of a certain recency, but odds are, I think they're, most
Speaker 2:  of them seem to be if your device still works,
Speaker 2:  it's new enough that it'll work. But this is nuts and this I think
Speaker 2:  will solve a lot of problems for a lot of people because the like iPhone
Speaker 2:  AirPods connection is pretty real. So if I have AirPods and an iPhone
Speaker 2:  and you have AirPods, we can both listen through our AirPods to the same
Speaker 2:  thing at the same time. It's kind of hacky and it took me like three tries
Speaker 2:  to get it to work the first time with my wife's AirPods. And then you have
Speaker 2:  to make sure that they're both checked when they're connected and they'll
Speaker 2:  kind of disconnect If you take one of your headphones off then 'cause then
Speaker 2:  the pause gets sort of wacky. And this is the kind of thing where I'm like,
Speaker 2:  okay, I get why Apple is not super excited about this. Like if I'm wearing
Speaker 2:  AirPods and I have it set so that when I take my headphones out,
Speaker 2:  my music will pause. Should it also pause for you if you're wearing AirPods
Speaker 2:  and we have our audio sync, this stuff is complicated and I don't think
Speaker 2:  it works super well. I've been testing this a little bit and it's not perfect,
Speaker 2:  but like the, the use case that I have is
Speaker 2:  I have a sleeping child in my room and we wanna watch something that we can
Speaker 2:  both listen to. This legitimately solves that
Speaker 2:  problem and I think that's very exciting. So I'm gonna share a link in the
Speaker 2:  show notes to Apple's support page for how this works. It's pretty helpful
Speaker 2:  and and does a good job of explaining how it works. But sharing
Speaker 2:  audio really works and you can do it on lots of different
Speaker 2:  devices and I highly recommend it If you wanna solve this
Speaker 2:  problem in a less hacky way. If you wanna solve this problem in a more hacky
Speaker 2:  way, you can do what I've been doing for years and just buy a headphone splitter.
Speaker 2:  I have been traveling with a headphones splitter for a very long time and
Speaker 2:  I just plug it into the iPhone. Plug two sets of headphones in.
Speaker 2:  Bob's your uncle, as they say, it's a useful hack, but this one's a little
Speaker 2:  more elegant, let's say. Anyway, I'm still fascinated by how audio works
Speaker 2:  on these devices. So If you have more funky edge cases or ideas
Speaker 2:  about how all of this should work, I got a lot of people who agree with
Speaker 2:  my theory that what Apple needs here is a really good now playing
Speaker 2:  app that lets you control this stuff more manually. I don't think we're ever
Speaker 2:  getting that, but If you solved this, I wanna hear all about it.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, for now, that is it for the first cast.
Speaker 2:  Thank you to everybody who came on the show and thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more on everything we talked about@thefirst.com. I'll put a
Speaker 2:  bunch of stuff in the show notes. I'm gonna link to as many of the apps and
Speaker 2:  things that V mentioned that I can find. I'll put some stuff for The Nokia
Speaker 2:  Design Archive in there. And as always read the verse.com. The news
Speaker 2:  continues unabated my friends. It's crazy out there. By the way, thank you
Speaker 2:  to everybody who's reached out with ideas about how we should cover politics
Speaker 2:  and how you use chat GPT. We're gonna talk about a bunch of that stuff with
Speaker 2:  Neli on Friday. So If you have more ideas and more thoughts, get 'em in.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna have a pretty hotline episode on Friday. I'm very excited about
Speaker 2:  it. And as always, If you have thoughts, feelings, questions about anything
Speaker 2:  else, you can always email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com. Call the
Speaker 2:  hotline eight six six VERGE one one. We truly love hearing from you. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Eric Gomez. Will Pour and Brandon Kiefer. The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is VERGE production part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neil, and I'll
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday, like I said to talk about chat GPT politics, people
Speaker 2:  raising tons of money. How big is Mark Zuckerberg's data center and a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch of other stuff? We'll see you then. Rock and roll.