# Transcript
ID: ec2871f2-5d84-4b2e-8bcc-68cd12bf1044
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2756368277327774047/-6278290828739312224/s93290-US-5798s-1758622348.mp3
Description: In all the tech news and world news last week, YouTube's Made On event got a little lost. So we circled back: The Verge's Mia Sato explains why YouTube is suddenly all-in on livestreaming, why it seems to be rapidly turning into a shopping mall, and whether all these AI features will improve YouTube or destroy it. After that, it's time for a second round of David's Summer Takes, in which he subjects The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes and Hayden Field to his thoughts on Threads, podcasts, and social media. Finally, Hayden sticks around to answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about the words we use when we talk AI.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna do two things. First, we're gonna talk about what's going on
Speaker 1:  with YouTube. The company had one of its biggest product announcement events
Speaker 1:  of the year last week, and shipped some stuff that I found
Speaker 1:  slightly confusing and slightly surprising. So Mia Sato on our team is gonna
Speaker 1:  come on and help me make sense of it. Then it's gonna be time for round two
Speaker 1:  of David's somewhat deranged Summer Takes, which I'm very excited
Speaker 1:  to shout into a microphone and have Jake and Hayden tell me how insane I
Speaker 1:  am. We also have a question for The Vergecast hotline. Lots of stuff to get
Speaker 1:  to. It's gonna be a really fun show. All of that is coming up in just a second.
Speaker 1:  But first I have to go buy more old gadgets on eBay because thanks to version
Speaker 1:  history, that's a thing I do now. This is The Vergecast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. Mia Sato is here. Hi Mia. Hi. Happy
Speaker 1:  Friday. Happy
Speaker 7:  Friday.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about YouTube ads.
Speaker 9:  Happy, happy Friday.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, we, we should say we're recording Friday afternoon. It's been a week,
Speaker 1:  but one of the things that I think actually got kind of lost in the shuffle
Speaker 1:  this week, which is one of the things I wanna talk about is made on YouTube,
Speaker 1:  YouTube sort of big annual creator event. And I think
Speaker 1:  a thing you And I agree on is that YouTube is culturally
Speaker 1:  way more important than it gets credit for generally
Speaker 1:  speaking. Like do you remember years ago when everybody was like, why isn't
Speaker 1:  YouTube getting dragged in front of Congress to answer for the content moderation
Speaker 1:  stuff? And like I agreed with a lot of that And I still think YouTube is
Speaker 1:  like a very important platform that we don't understand all that well, And
Speaker 1:  I think you understand it better than most. And so I just wanna talk through
Speaker 1:  some of the new stuff and see if you can help me make sense of it. Does that
Speaker 1:  sound good?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, yeah, let's do it.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so let's start with live streaming, which I think
Speaker 1:  surprised me a lot that it was a big focus at
Speaker 1:  Made on YouTube this year. This is basically like, I want everybody to picture
Speaker 1:  like a, a big beautiful room filled with
Speaker 1:  creators who love each other and YouTube. And that is like,
Speaker 1:  this is very much like an event to just sort of bring those people together
Speaker 1:  and tell them about all the lovely stuff that YouTube is doing for them.
Speaker 1:  And so it's a real sort of statement of intent from the platform to be
Speaker 1:  like, here is what matters on YouTube this year. And YouTube, as much as
Speaker 1:  anything picked live streaming just in principle, is
Speaker 1:  that as surprising to you as it was to me?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it was. It seemed kind of random, honestly. And there was like a
Speaker 9:  boatload of news this year specifically I thought even more than the other
Speaker 9:  years that I've covered. But you know, I think the way that they described
Speaker 9:  it was like, these are the biggest updates to live streaming that we've ever
Speaker 9:  made. And I was like, why? You know? Right.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it was, it was really random. Well,
Speaker 1:  So try and make sense of it for me. Like why I think there, there's a,
Speaker 1:  there's a cynical version of this that is like YouTube has already won everything
Speaker 1:  else and now it is focusing on live. And I think on the back of like
Speaker 1:  YouTube did an NFL game that went medium it, it is
Speaker 1:  very clearly invested in this idea of live events
Speaker 1:  being a thing on YouTube. And I think my read of this whole
Speaker 1:  industry has been that live never quite became the thing we
Speaker 1:  wanted it to be on the internet. There's lots of ways to live stream twitches
Speaker 1:  working, like there's tons of live stuff out there, but I don't feel like
Speaker 1:  live, at least in my brain, is next to like
Speaker 1:  short form vertical video or like, I don't know, blockbuster
Speaker 1:  movies in the sort of Yeah. Huge pillars of culture.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, YouTube clearly wants it to be. Why do you think that is?
Speaker 9:  I mean, okay, first I have to say I have, I have a quote I've,
Speaker 9:  I've come prepared with a quote.
Speaker 9:  If you look at YouTube as a series of products reverse engineered from
Speaker 9:  advertising budgets, the company's mini offerings start to make a kind of
Speaker 9:  sense. Do you know who wrote that?
Speaker 1:  That sounds like me.
Speaker 9:  It's you. And so like the first, you know, the first lens
Speaker 9:  that I would look at this is like, that's a lot of time for
Speaker 9:  ads, that's a lot of time for putting stuff
Speaker 9:  that YouTube gets a cut of. There are a couple things that YouTube announced
Speaker 9:  that I think like specifically goes go into this. Like one just, I think
Speaker 9:  this was a feature that already existed, but the ability to tag
Speaker 9:  products in streams. Think about like the many, many, I
Speaker 9:  mean at least for like my demographic beauty, YouTube is like a
Speaker 9:  huge place that is where kind of the modern beauty content creator,
Speaker 9:  influencer started is YouTube doing like tutorials. Now
Speaker 9:  all of those people do get ready with me streams on TikTok where they're
Speaker 9:  using the products, telling you what it is and hanging out for like an hour
Speaker 9:  and a half while they do their makeup. YouTube sees that obviously they want
Speaker 9:  a cut of that and even better if they can like put the products into it.
Speaker 9:  The other thing that YouTube announced was this sort of like
Speaker 9:  ad experience where it doesn't interrupt the stream. I was watching a
Speaker 9:  live stream on YouTube the week prior and it was really
Speaker 9:  annoying because I was watching a stream from like a news outlet carrying
Speaker 9:  a press conference and in the middle of them talking, it cut into an
Speaker 9:  ad, like a mid-roll ad. And I was like, wait, I need to know
Speaker 9:  don't do that please. But now YouTube is saying like, we can put
Speaker 9:  your face on one side, the streamer's face on one side, and then the ad next
Speaker 9:  to it and it's an uninterrupted experience. And this really to me,
Speaker 9:  like you see it happening on other media, on other
Speaker 9:  mediums as well. Like if you are a baseball fan, you know that
Speaker 9:  it doesn't matter if Aaron judges at the plate, they're gonna get a word
Speaker 9:  in from Taco Bell and it's gonna be like two seconds long and it's going
Speaker 9:  to be seamless. So that like, it, that's kind of like a
Speaker 9:  straightforward way to think of it is like this is more surface, this is
Speaker 9:  more ad surface.
Speaker 9:  The other thing I was thinking about was like, and this is kind of like a
Speaker 9:  dark example, but this video
Speaker 9:  in video experience where, you know, you can have one
Speaker 9:  streamer reacting to another stream, I feel like the value
Speaker 9:  proposition is just like so obvious because after Charlie
Speaker 9:  Kirk was shot, everyone wanted to watch
Speaker 9:  Hassan Piker react to it. Mm. And indeed they did go, thousands of people
Speaker 9:  watched his Twitch stream where he was just reacting to like CNN
Speaker 9:  or whatever. And you know, that's like,
Speaker 9:  maybe they don't wanna monetize that. Like that's kind of, you know, a, a
Speaker 9:  specific kind of event. But think about like the Met Gala
Speaker 9:  award shows, VMAs just happened, even the election
Speaker 9:  on TikTok on election night. People were just streaming for hours
Speaker 9:  watching returns come in and watching like counties and states being
Speaker 9:  called. So it really makes sense to me. And we
Speaker 9:  can talk about like the actual format of live streaming, but
Speaker 9:  considering YouTube really wants this experience of being on every screen
Speaker 9:  in your home, obviously they want this too.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think there's something to the sort of hang
Speaker 1:  being the like thing that knits all of these ideas together in a really
Speaker 1:  interesting way. And like, I'm glad you started by talking about the, the
Speaker 1:  makeup stuff because it's very clear that that is top of mind at
Speaker 1:  YouTube as they build product. And it was all over the place. It made on
Speaker 1:  YouTube. And I think with live in particular, like I confess, I'm not a
Speaker 1:  person who watches get ready with mainstreams, but I suspect you could go
Speaker 1:  like line by line through the live streaming announcements and every one
Speaker 1:  of them would make sense in context of get ready with mainstreams. Like yeah,
Speaker 1:  there's the, the practice before going live thing, which I think I think
Speaker 1:  is very smart and is is a good idea and like a fascinating sort
Speaker 1:  of reflection of culture that we should talk about. But there's the thing
Speaker 1:  where you can do horizontal and vertical lives simultaneously. Again, talking
Speaker 1:  about your your point, we wanna be on every screen possible. That's the kind
Speaker 1:  of thing that like most of these streams are just my face. That's a pretty
Speaker 1:  easy thing to make work. You have the side-by-side ads, like you said that
Speaker 1:  works. You have the AI tagging of products that
Speaker 1:  when a product shows on screen, rather than me having to tell you
Speaker 1:  what it is and how to go get it, it'll just be like, it's this and have a
Speaker 1:  link and send me out to buy it. That's like
Speaker 9:  Crazy. I have to fail
Speaker 1:  Though. All of this is perfectly designed for like, I am a person using products
Speaker 1:  in front of you and we're hanging out and we are going to monetize every
Speaker 1:  single inch of this in a way that like feels
Speaker 1:  grosser the longer you think about it, but also is just where all of these
Speaker 1:  platforms have been headed for a while.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, actually I just got a like push notification on TikTok today.
Speaker 9:  That was like there, by the way, did you know that there's a feature where
Speaker 9:  TikTok will scan your video and look for products using AI
Speaker 9:  and it will create like an outward, like an internal app link
Speaker 9:  to like more so if they see that I have like a record player in the background,
Speaker 9:  they'll create, I don't know if it's like the blue clickable links or what,
Speaker 9:  but it's like it will take you to a page where it's like searching for record
Speaker 9:  players and then if you're a viewer or a creator, you have the ability
Speaker 9:  to like turn that off And I need to still like figure out how to turn that
Speaker 9:  off because I don't really want my content monetized like that, but some
Speaker 9:  people do. Right. And it really feels like we're coalescing
Speaker 9:  around a thing that I have thought for a while, which is like every,
Speaker 9:  every piece of content that we watch online is an invitation to
Speaker 9:  buy something. And that's always been true because of like the ads supported
Speaker 9:  nature of these platforms. But it feels increasingly true
Speaker 9:  right now, especially like post TikTok ascendants
Speaker 9:  where it is really just like, it's a, it's a window into
Speaker 9:  commerce And I think that is, I mean we can argue about whether that's good
Speaker 9:  or bad, but it's, it's kind of unavoidable.
Speaker 1:  Let let's briefly argue about whether it's good or bad because I I I, I think
Speaker 1:  your your point is right that I think that's just where we are. And I think
Speaker 1:  one of the most fascinating things about TikTok was that it did the thing
Speaker 1:  everybody else is doing, which is use videos to sell you stuff. It just did
Speaker 1:  it so much more brazenly, like Instagram spent so long
Speaker 1:  trying to pretend that it was this sort of pure beautiful
Speaker 1:  place for art and they were just kind of doing commerce over there. And then
Speaker 1:  TikTok was like, what if all of the videos were just trying to sell you something?
Speaker 1:  Like what? And, and it turns out people still watched those videos of like,
Speaker 1:  people reviewing candy became a huge thing on like, yeah, it just, these
Speaker 1:  things have just smashed right into each other. And I think one of
Speaker 1:  the things that has been interesting about YouTube is that it has actually
Speaker 1:  been slower to some of that stuff that I think the, the,
Speaker 1:  they hold onto this idea that it is sort of the creator's
Speaker 1:  place to be creative and that that matters. And the idea that they're just
Speaker 1:  now really whole hog into this idea of like, we are going to
Speaker 1:  shop a bull eyes is the hell out of every single thing that you make
Speaker 1:  for you. It does seem like a tone shift on the platform.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I think also, you know, a lot of creators think of YouTube still
Speaker 9:  as sort of the place where polished work
Speaker 9:  goes. Hmm. And I've heard this come from a lot of like when
Speaker 9:  the TikTok ban seemed like truly imminent, I don't even
Speaker 9:  know, like six months ago, you know, there was a sense of like,
Speaker 9:  where will I go? And a lot of creators were saying, I'm trying to learn
Speaker 9:  YouTube. Right? Learn YouTube. Interesting. And that is because
Speaker 9:  there is more of like, you know, I think people still think of it as like
Speaker 9:  a mid to long form place. There's a little bit more like advanced editing
Speaker 9:  that's happening. You're not just like camera in front of you
Speaker 9:  yapping. You need some sort of like cadence. You need a
Speaker 9:  good title, you need a good thumbnail, you need a good description that's
Speaker 9:  like SEOed to hell. And so I think
Speaker 9:  there's a sense of like, you know, there is a barrier to entry for
Speaker 9:  YouTube And I think YouTube knows this also. That goes into like the
Speaker 9:  practice thing that goes into a lot of the AI driven
Speaker 9:  creator tools in the background that I wrote about earlier this week
Speaker 9:  for for made on. And yeah, I think that YouTube kind
Speaker 9:  of wants a piece of this, like off the cuff
Speaker 9:  easy, literally no production value
Speaker 9:  streams. And you know, the live stream stuff is
Speaker 9:  really interesting because to me that is truly like an
Speaker 9:  endlessly generative content style. What is different from
Speaker 9:  a stream is different from like a traditional video in that literally any
Speaker 9:  moment can be a stream. Like I have, I follow a few TikTok creators who
Speaker 9:  their whole thing is, they're just, they have like a selfie stick. They're
Speaker 9:  walking around New York City and they're just responding to comments for
Speaker 9:  hours and hours and hours and that pays the bills. And that is
Speaker 9:  something I think that YouTube rightfully sees as being like a
Speaker 9:  way that people consume content. Some people like to watch
Speaker 9:  streams because you don't have to swipe, like, you know, people are lazy.
Speaker 9:  Sure, yeah. Some people watch streams because they're really invested in
Speaker 9:  a specific person where if they can watch you do a thing
Speaker 9:  in real time, they will watch it and send you gif obviously that's a
Speaker 9:  big part of it. Yeah. And yeah, YouTube also had like a tool that, that
Speaker 9:  they announced where it will cut down pieces of your stream
Speaker 9:  to become other types of content like shorts or mid form or
Speaker 9:  whatever. I mean, it's kind of a no brainer, right?
Speaker 9:  They need more content, they want people to make more stuff. And so of course
Speaker 9:  they're going to one, tell people to stream for hours.
Speaker 9:  And two, give you an easy way to just like pull that out into more like
Speaker 9:  permanent content.
Speaker 1:  That's really interesting because that makes live streaming sound simultaneously
Speaker 1:  both really high stakes and really low stakes, right? Like
Speaker 1:  it's designed to be the most human off the
Speaker 1:  cuff version of this, but it's also like, it, it becomes the sort of
Speaker 1:  entry point for both a lot of your audience and a lot of your content, which
Speaker 1:  makes this practice thing even more interesting. Tell me why you think the
Speaker 1:  practice before you go live feature is, is fascinating. Okay.
Speaker 9:  I, this one truly perplexed me
Speaker 9:  because I think, like I understand the utility, right? If you are
Speaker 9:  maybe like a dancer and you're going to stream practice that day, right?
Speaker 9:  You work, you're, you are a dancer at one of these like viral, also like
Speaker 9:  popularized by YouTube dance studios and you're gonna just like stream your
Speaker 9:  practice. Sure. Maybe I like, I'm just making up a thing, but I understand
Speaker 9:  that. But also, it's so funny to me,
Speaker 9:  you're gonna practice to be off the cuff, you're gonna practice to be live
Speaker 9:  with your fans. You know, it's just like, it's so weird
Speaker 9:  And I kind of, I mean,
Speaker 1:  I hate to be the one to break this mirage for you Mia, But that is kind of
Speaker 1:  how it works.
Speaker 9:  Totally. Totally. But the idea that there needs to be like a
Speaker 9:  dedicated feature and kind of like a pulling back the
Speaker 9:  curtain moment where it's just like we're just gonna straight up say like,
Speaker 9:  none of this stuff is organic. None of this stuff is like authentic
Speaker 9:  really in the way that viewers might be led to believe. Like,
Speaker 9:  we're gonna just put a practice screen, you know, like a green room into
Speaker 9:  this. It's just, it's so funny to me.
Speaker 9:  And we can, I think this kind of feeds into another thing
Speaker 9:  I've been thinking about, which is just like, we can talk about it later.
Speaker 9:  I wanna hear what you think about practice, but this idea that tech
Speaker 9:  platforms and social media platforms have never been more open
Speaker 9:  with what they want. You know, it is just in a weird way.
Speaker 9:  And yeah, let's, we'll get into that later, but what do you think about practice?
Speaker 1:  We are very much in the like saying the quiet part Loud. Yes.
Speaker 9:  Loud as hell.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The, the practice feature made me think of like, did you ever have
Speaker 1:  that moment when you learned how reality TV
Speaker 1:  shows actually work and that there are like producers in the background being
Speaker 1:  like, you guys should fight about this. Or like, you see the, my wife And
Speaker 1:  I watch house shows all the time and there's always that moment where it's
Speaker 1:  like the couple sitting at a table drinking smoothies, like talking about
Speaker 1:  how much money they're gonna make from this house. And it's like you,
Speaker 1:  until you start thinking about it, it all feels sort of natural and normal.
Speaker 1:  And then it's like, oh no, this is like days later. They've already had this
Speaker 1:  conversation six times and a producer just sat them down and said, and now
Speaker 1:  talk about how much money you're gonna make from selling this house. And
Speaker 1:  it's, as soon as it like the, the veil is lifted,
Speaker 1:  it starts to feel weird. And now I watch these shows and my wife And I like
Speaker 1:  have made a game out of trying to figure out what's, what's off the cuff
Speaker 1:  and what isn't. And it just changes the way that you look at all of these
Speaker 1:  things. And it's like some of this stuff like the, the practice before going
Speaker 1:  live and even the way that we're talking about like AI product tag, it's
Speaker 1:  like this stuff has always been more
Speaker 1:  intentional and more thought out and more rehearsed and more
Speaker 1:  practiced than you want it to be. It's just that the, the
Speaker 1:  shame of that is completely gone. And I, in a lot of ways I think that's
Speaker 1:  fine. Right? Like we, we should stop pretending that this stuff is real life
Speaker 1:  Yeah. When it's not. Yeah. And I don't know that it actually changes the
Speaker 1:  appeal in a lot of ways that it's not real life, but it isn't, it never has
Speaker 1:  been. And we should, we should stop talking about it like it is. Yeah. But
Speaker 1:  it is interesting to see every platform. And I think YouTube
Speaker 1:  to your point is like the, the last one to really get on board with the
Speaker 1:  idea of like, this is a ruthless moneymaking machine and we're gonna start
Speaker 1:  showing it to everybody
Speaker 9:  And that's okay. And we're not sorry. No. You know what I mean? It's, it's
Speaker 9:  just this is what we're doing here. Yeah. Yeah. For sure. I wrote about this
Speaker 9:  in my piece that I published around Madeon when I was writing about
Speaker 9:  like behind the scenes creator tools. Mm. But it really feels
Speaker 9:  like it's a new era both for the platforms and also
Speaker 9:  for creators online. Like in that story I wrote
Speaker 9:  about how, I talked a little bit about how like, you know, we
Speaker 9:  historically we've really talked about platforms being black boxes
Speaker 9:  and to some extent that's still true. Like there's a lot in the algorithm
Speaker 9:  that we don't know. There's a lot in, you know, internal
Speaker 9:  conversations and discussions at these companies that creators aren't privy
Speaker 9:  to. We, there are things that we don't know about how they operate, but
Speaker 9:  also it feels like it's never been clearer. Right? And
Speaker 9:  it's because the platforms will just come out and say it what they want from
Speaker 9:  creators. And I think of it almost as like,
Speaker 9:  I, I see it as really mirroring what happened in SEO
Speaker 9:  and it's just like we're just gonna tell you what to make
Speaker 9:  and how to make it right. When TikTok changes its creator fund
Speaker 9:  where only people who make videos over one minute are eligible.
Speaker 9:  It's just saying make longer videos. We, we wanna compete with
Speaker 9:  YouTube. Stop making your little 15 second things. We want long videos,
Speaker 9:  we want long form, we want you to make videos in horizontal,
Speaker 9:  which is like a thing that they did at one point. YouTube is giving creators
Speaker 9:  tools to just like, use this and figure out which
Speaker 9:  thumbnail and title combination your viewers like best that lead to the highest
Speaker 9:  watch time. Just do it. Like, we'll tell you previously, that was all
Speaker 9:  stuff that creators had to kind of like figure out themselves
Speaker 9:  and you know, these, these optimizing this, this kind of like
Speaker 9:  ruthless optimizing is
Speaker 9:  beneficial for both parties, right? YouTube wants people watching
Speaker 9:  videos longer. They don't, I don't think they really care what videos they
Speaker 9:  are, they just want more watch time. Yeah. Creators specifically want people
Speaker 9:  to be watching their videos. And so, I mean, it makes sense. I can see why
Speaker 9:  creators wanted a tool like the thumbnail and title thing for so long, but
Speaker 9:  it's really fascinating to me, you know, YouTube is giving you an AI
Speaker 9:  chat bot that just tells you what's wrong with your content and is like,
Speaker 9:  change this, right? Like, you didn't do the intro, right?
Speaker 9:  Like, do change this next time. And yeah, like on
Speaker 9:  TikTok there will be like, sometimes when you search for things on
Speaker 9:  TikTok, there will be like a weird little box that
Speaker 9:  TikTok shows you that says like, Hey, there's not that much content about
Speaker 9:  this search term. Why don't you just make it like, interesting.
Speaker 9:  It's so funny to me. It's really, really interesting. And I think like
Speaker 9:  this is kind of what is happening with live on YouTube right
Speaker 9:  now. They're like, we don't think enough people are streaming here. We don't
Speaker 9:  like, maybe they don't like dislike, but you know, we want a different type
Speaker 9:  of streamer on here. They're trying to court those people. So now
Speaker 9:  they're like, just, why don't you just stream and just like make your videos
Speaker 9:  from your streams, right? That's what we want.
Speaker 1:  And what we've learned over the years is that these platforms have
Speaker 1:  all of the tools and all of the leverage in that debate, right? Like,
Speaker 1:  'cause you get to a point where it's like, okay, if I'm gonna keep making
Speaker 1:  what I want, even if it's against what quote unquote the platform wants
Speaker 1:  and what the algorithm wants, and I'm eventually just going to be making
Speaker 1:  videos into a void Because, because what, what the algorithm
Speaker 1:  will show people and what the platform wants has moved away from me. And
Speaker 1:  I think we, we've seen, and you And I both talked to a lot of people who
Speaker 1:  are stuck in that place of like, I know what works And I know what I wanna
Speaker 1:  do. And putting those things together is an
Speaker 1:  increasingly big challenge. And I think especially right now,
Speaker 1:  YouTube is being increasingly clear about what it wants and it has all of
Speaker 1:  the levers to pull to make people who do more
Speaker 1:  live streaming be more successful, right? Yeah. Like, it just, it just can
Speaker 1:  do that. Your, your lives don't have to be good. YouTube can still put them
Speaker 1:  in front of people and they can be great. And if YouTube doesn't put them
Speaker 1:  in front of people, you're, you're host. And so I think it's just
Speaker 1:  like we, we've seen YouTube going from sort of pretending that
Speaker 1:  creators lead the dynamic to, like you said, telling creators what to do.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And TikTok sort of to its credit
Speaker 1:  was the one that has enabled a lot of this because it never pretended otherwise.
Speaker 1:  TikTok always a place to ruthlessly optimize your content to be viewed by
Speaker 1:  as many people as possible. It was a marketing platform and it, it has been
Speaker 1:  an enormously successful one. And YouTube was always the one that was like,
Speaker 1:  okay, go get big audience discovery gaming the TikTok
Speaker 1:  algorithm and then come here and make your art. And that totally, it is completely
Speaker 1:  losing that pretense kind of every day.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. It's interesting because it's like, you kind of see
Speaker 9:  this dynamic play out in different ways on different platforms. Like
Speaker 9:  there's a reason why every Instagram photographer is now a reels like
Speaker 9:  an Instagram reels photographer or whatever, you know, it's just like, that
Speaker 9:  is what it is. And I think YouTube still
Speaker 9:  is trying to hold on to this idea that they
Speaker 9:  are the creator platform, like you said, and
Speaker 9:  some of the stuff, when you read it, it just like really punctures that veil.
Speaker 9:  And I think I'm, I'm just, I'm curious how
Speaker 9:  YouTubers react to it because I think it's true that like,
Speaker 9:  not everyone wants to stream, not everyone wants to be on live
Speaker 9:  and you know, there's like, I I just am, I'm curious like what level of
Speaker 9:  resistance really
Speaker 9:  is tenable, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like how much can you fight this and and still be viable on YouTube
Speaker 1:  is is gonna be an interesting question. Yeah. I have to let you go here in
Speaker 1:  a minute, but let's talk about AI just before we do. 'cause we've, we've,
Speaker 1:  we've talked a little bit about it and this is like the second or third year
Speaker 1:  in a row that AI was a big story of made on, and not just like
Speaker 1:  AI as a sort of behind the scenes tool to help you answer comments and manage
Speaker 1:  whatever AI as like a, a creative tool for shorts in particular. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And this year they're just like, just do a prompt and it'll make a short
Speaker 1:  for you and publish your shorts. Yeah. And it's like, what, what's your
Speaker 1:  I have not seen a ton of that. I, I was saying this on, on Friday show, but
Speaker 1:  I deleted Instagram and TikTok from my phone for the summer as a way to be
Speaker 1:  like, I'm on parental leave, I'm gonna spend my time with my child. And it's
Speaker 1:  very not on YouTube. Very. And what actually happened is I just watched a
Speaker 1:  lot of YouTube shorts. I encountered almost no
Speaker 1:  like generative AI stuff on shorts. But I, I understand that that's like
Speaker 1:  my own algorithm, but I'm curious like, are you seeing this stuff
Speaker 1:  take off this idea that like, upload a photo to YouTube and tell it what
Speaker 1:  to do and it'll use AI to add motion and turn it into a Jan challenge and
Speaker 1:  you can make that a short, like,
Speaker 9:  I don't know if it's like that level. I think there is a level of
Speaker 9:  slop and like, you know, I think a couple weeks ago or
Speaker 9:  a few, like a month ago, that was kind of the fear, right? That YouTube was
Speaker 9:  like tweaking something about its policies for monetization and people
Speaker 9:  freaked out because they thought that it meant anyone who's using AI and
Speaker 9:  their videos would be affected. And then they went back and clarified and
Speaker 9:  it's like, no, we're just updating what we mean by like
Speaker 9:  spammy content. Right? I think they changed the name to Inauthentic, but
Speaker 9:  yeah, I think they probably recognize that this is a way that people
Speaker 9:  have been filling the platform with garbage. I think that's true
Speaker 9:  across platforms, whether they're using the in-app
Speaker 9:  tools or not. Like TikTok is filled with
Speaker 9:  AI sludge one time actually, like I wrote a story and then I
Speaker 9:  found a video of an AI generated avatar
Speaker 9:  reciting my story back to me And I was like, whoa, what is happening?
Speaker 9:  It's interesting because I think that YouTube is kind of like talking out
Speaker 9:  of its mouth on one side, and then there's like everything else that's happening
Speaker 9:  in the background, which is that millions of YouTube videos
Speaker 9:  have been trained on without the creator's permission. Yep. And
Speaker 9:  YouTube has been sort of like staying out of it
Speaker 9:  for the most part. There is actually a great piece in The Atlantic
Speaker 9:  where you can search for creators and see, you know, what, what videos we're
Speaker 9:  trained on. And it's a lot of like how to content,
Speaker 9:  but at the same time it's also like encouraging content creators
Speaker 9:  to use these tools. And I have to, I really wonder how
Speaker 9:  creators feel about that. If you're, if this
Speaker 9:  bot can also like come up with video ideas, write the script
Speaker 9:  dub your lips, right? To like do the lip matching for voice, for like lip
Speaker 9:  syncing with dubs. What is your job? It can also
Speaker 9:  edit your shorts by the way. Right, right. Like, I'm, I'm just that's such,
Speaker 1:  That's such a good version of the question because I think like the, the,
Speaker 1:  the pro case for all of this stuff, which I'm it's actually
Speaker 1:  sympathetic to, is that it makes it easier to make stuff. And I think
Speaker 1:  what we have seen generally speaking is that when technology makes it easier
Speaker 1:  to make stuff, people make more stuff, some of it is bad, some of it is good.
Speaker 1:  And like the, the idea of these tools is like democratizing forces to help
Speaker 1:  creative people make more stuff, I think is awesome. But this question of
Speaker 1:  what is your job I think is, is like the question in front of
Speaker 1:  both the people making these tools and the people using them, because you're
Speaker 1:  right, like I could sit here, I could type one line into
Speaker 1:  YouTube's backend and it could, it could make the short, it could edit the
Speaker 1:  short and it could publish the short and it could optimize the short and
Speaker 1:  it could put it out. And that might get a lot of views.
Speaker 1:  It feels like a bad outcome for like big human ways that I
Speaker 1:  can't even necessarily describe That feels like a bad outcome. And I think
Speaker 1:  what seems to me is that a lot of creators are gonna have to spend the next
Speaker 1:  year or years trying to figure out what they do here
Speaker 1:  and what the thing is that makes them different. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 1:  it's like the, everyone is gonna have access to these same tools that do
Speaker 1:  the same mediocre job for you. Yeah. How, what do
Speaker 1:  you do here and how do you, how do you elevate this stuff? And I feel like
Speaker 1:  that just gets murkier and murkier with every one of these new tools
Speaker 1:  that gets added That is just a new thing you don't even have to do anymore.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And if you're just the person on the screen, well guess what? They
Speaker 9:  have something for that too. Like, it's just like, I
Speaker 9:  really, really wonder, we should have, we should have like a bunch of content
Speaker 9:  creators on here And I would love to ask like, do you feel the fear of like
Speaker 9:  job replacement, you know what I mean, that other workers do because you
Speaker 9:  are a worker
Speaker 9:  and Yeah, I don't know. It's really weird. It's really weird. And also do
Speaker 9:  audiences care, right? Do they care if your scripts are
Speaker 9:  all written by AI now that you're getting all your ideas from YouTube's like
Speaker 9:  in app,
Speaker 9:  like AI bot,
Speaker 1:  Right? I don't know. It's a great question. And how do they, how do those
Speaker 1:  viewers show you that they care too, right? Because it's like, what we keep
Speaker 1:  hearing is basically the numbers keep going up And I, I just
Speaker 1:  keep thinking about this company that, that, I forget the exact name of it
Speaker 1:  and I'm glad to not be able to say it out loud, but basically their thing
Speaker 1:  was, we're gonna make Infinity podcasts and every one of those podcasts
Speaker 1:  is going to get 10 listeners, but it's so cheap for us to make and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna do, it's such incredible volume that it's gonna make us money. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And on the one hand, that's probably gonna work,
Speaker 1:  on the other hand, that is a, that that sucks And I hate it And I
Speaker 1:  want that thing to not exist because what you're saying is we are going to
Speaker 1:  flood this thing with so much crap that it's gonna work
Speaker 1:  because it's gonna work because the, the volume will outplay the quality
Speaker 1:  and we're gonna keep making money off of it. And like, again, this is the,
Speaker 1:  that was the SEO play was we're just, we are going to ruthlessly optimize
Speaker 1:  our junk so that even if you click it by accident, it doesn't matter, we're
Speaker 1:  still gonna get paid. And you worry that, like
Speaker 1:  we as viewers who our main thing to do is scroll.
Speaker 1:  If if you hit the video, they're gonna make the money. Yeah. And so it's
Speaker 1:  like my incentive is actually to make more of this stuff if all I care
Speaker 1:  about is just getting views even even five at a time.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And so I, And I wonder, And I think, I do think these platforms know,
Speaker 1:  And I think YouTube knows better than most that if it lets itself be completely
Speaker 1:  overrun by this lop it, it will be a long-term bad decision.
Speaker 1:  Totally. And like if your platform's offerings are the NFL and
Speaker 1:  AI slop, you're in trouble. And, but I, I think every
Speaker 1:  creator is gonna have to figure this out for themselves. And these platforms
Speaker 1:  are gonna have to figure out like what is the line between useful thing we
Speaker 1:  can do to help creator and thing that in the long run will actually destroy
Speaker 1:  all of the quality stuff on our platform.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's a great question. It's also just like we,
Speaker 9:  we can't go operating at like where the goal is
Speaker 9:  as much content as possible because it is Right. That's not
Speaker 9:  good. There aren't enough people to watch it,
Speaker 9:  frankly. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like YouTube's, YouTube's good. Like at some point YouTube should just be
Speaker 1:  like, actually guys, everybody just like take a month off. We actually don't
Speaker 1:  need any more stuff. We're just gonna keep researching all the stuff people
Speaker 1:  haven't watched. There's 50 lifetimes of things everybody likes already available
Speaker 1:  to them. Y'all go take a vacation.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. I think nothing
Speaker 1:  Would change.
Speaker 9:  I don't think I I completely agree. I completely agree. Especially now
Speaker 9:  with this livestream stuff. I'm like, oh my God, who's watching this? I know
Speaker 9:  who can possibly watch this?
Speaker 1:  Seriously? But the answer is both of us watching Get Ready With Me
Speaker 1:  Streams, which you've now talked me into and is going to be this is, this
Speaker 1:  is gonna be my new thing.
Speaker 9:  They're oddly satisfying. I'll say,
Speaker 1:  I would like to get ready with somebody. Yeah. This is, this would be great.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. My process takes like four minutes and involves a t-shirt, so
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna need to improve my Get Ready with
Speaker 9:  Me. That would hit, it would hit on YouTube. I'm sure.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm gonna have the shortest put
Speaker 9:  It on shorts in history on
Speaker 1:  Love this for us. All right, Mia, thank you as always. It's good to have
Speaker 1:  you here. Let's, anytime we should, let's drag some creators on here over
Speaker 1:  the next few months and just talk through all this stuff. This will be fun.
Speaker 1:  Love it. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  All's
Speaker 1:  Do it. Until then, we're gonna take a break and then we're gonna come back
Speaker 1:  And I have some hot takes that are gonna get me fired. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  into a microphone and subjects other people to them live on The Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  Back with me to do this. Jake Cast. Hi Jake. Hey, good
Speaker 1:  to be here. Hayden Field, welcome back. So
Speaker 11:  Psyched. Thanks.
Speaker 1:  All right, so last week I, I threw a bunch of AI related takes
Speaker 1:  at both of you and in, in the spirit of our favorite show,
Speaker 1:  subway Takes your, your allowances were to either
Speaker 1:  100% agree or 100% disagree, or I
Speaker 1:  gave you the option to just bail because David is lighting his career on
Speaker 1:  fire And I want no part of this. Neither of you picked that either for,
Speaker 1:  for any of them last week. I would say a lot of people have had a lot of
Speaker 1:  feelings about my feelings And I'm okay with that And I have more of them
Speaker 1:  this week. This is the last one of these we're gonna do, and this is just,
Speaker 1:  I would say sort of unordered thoughts. I had strong opinions about over
Speaker 1:  the course of a summer, spent on my couch reading news,
Speaker 1:  talking to newborns and hanging out. So I have, I have seven
Speaker 1:  completely unrelated and Unordered
Speaker 1:  summer takes for the two of you. Are you ready? If,
Speaker 12:  If we're wrapping up, I have to assume it's because you get canceled at
Speaker 12:  the end of
Speaker 1:  This. Yeah, if we, if suddenly we only get through five of them,
Speaker 1:  you'll know that two of them were, I just immediately David
Speaker 1:  is removed from The Verge and that's the end of everything. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  You spent a long time talking to, to Annie on, on GR this summer, didn't
Speaker 12:  you?
Speaker 1:  Listen, you spend a lot of time on YouTube shorts and things just start to
Speaker 1:  get weird. Oh yeah. Okay. Summer take
Speaker 1:  number one is that podcasts should be listened to at one
Speaker 1:  x and all other fast speeds are wrong.
Speaker 1:  If you don't have time to listen to the podcast, listen to fewer podcasts,
Speaker 1:  it's fine. One x is the correct speed at which you should listen to a podcast.
Speaker 1:  All other speeds are insane.
Speaker 13:  I've gotta say 100% disagree for that one.
Speaker 13:  I have a life, I have a brain that goes
Speaker 13:  fast actually, I feel like, I don't know if my brain goes fast all the time,
Speaker 13:  but you know what, when I'm listening to people talk, it does, I'm a visual
Speaker 13:  learner, I can read really fast, but when I'm listening to people talk in
Speaker 13:  my ear sometimes they're getting, taking a while to get to the point. You
Speaker 13:  know, so I gotta listen to 1.5 x two X,
Speaker 13:  same with tiktoks. You know, I feel that I,
Speaker 13:  many people will agree with me about this and that,
Speaker 13:  David, you could have such like a
Speaker 13:  awakening if you could just, you know, be done with the podcast
Speaker 13:  in two ti like 0.5, the amount of time as you would
Speaker 13:  have before,
Speaker 1:  But just don't listen to the pod. It's so easy to not listen to a podcast
Speaker 1:  you're not interested in. And I realize I'm saying this to a large audience
Speaker 1:  of people who I assume listen to this podcast at faster than one x and me
Speaker 1:  being like, well, if you have to listen to it too fast, just don't listen
Speaker 1:  to it is the most like self owning thing I could possibly do. So
Speaker 1:  please know that I understand what I'm doing here. Just watch
Speaker 1:  and listen to less stuff. Like I, I I have come to a point where it's like,
Speaker 1:  to me listening to a podcast of two x is like looking at the
Speaker 1:  AI generated summary of a book and saying, you've read the book, you haven't,
Speaker 13:  I do have a a take here that is a follow up, okay for me,
Speaker 13:  it's not about that I wanna listen to more content. I'm not like, oh, let
Speaker 13:  me finish this podcast or this video so I can like see the next thing for
Speaker 13:  me. It's really, I think just the fact that I was raised in the Gilmore
Speaker 13:  Girls era of people fast talking on tv.
Speaker 13:  So I'm used to people talking quicker than they do on most
Speaker 13:  podcasts. And I'm like, I gotta amp this up to the Gilmore Girls speed.
Speaker 13:  That's what I was raised on. That's what I'm used to. You know,
Speaker 1:  That's a good take. My my wife is currently watching Gilmore Girls for like
Speaker 1:  the 55th time, which means I'm, because it's fun, of course currently watching
Speaker 1:  Gilmore Girls flex the 55th time that show rips and they do, they
Speaker 1:  talk So fast. That's okay. That's a decent take. Jake, you've been
Speaker 1:  suspiciously quiet here.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, you know, the, The Vergecast is a work of art And I think
Speaker 12:  like you wouldn't watch Oppenheimer on two x, you should not
Speaker 12:  listen to The Vergecast on two x every other podcast
Speaker 12:  though. Do it. Do what you please. I, I I strong disagree with you, David.
Speaker 12:  Listen, sometimes I just, I just wanna get that info. I
Speaker 12:  wanna get in and out. I'm not, I'm not here for the, the artistry for the
Speaker 12:  subtle p with, with deep, deep apologies
Speaker 12:  to our audio editing team who, who are are, are truly
Speaker 12:  masterful. Okay, wait,
Speaker 1:  So here, here's my follow up question for both of you. Is, are
Speaker 1:  you, do you have a setting like universally
Speaker 1:  I listen to all of my shows at 1.5 X, do you have like a setting per
Speaker 1:  show or is it a thing you like dial up and down as you're listening?
Speaker 13:  For me as I'm listening.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 12:  Oh, interesting. So
Speaker 1:  You'll start an, an episode of a show and be like, we gotta, we gotta keep
Speaker 1:  moving here and just crank it to two x.
Speaker 13:  It really depends on how slow the person is talking. You'd be so surprised
Speaker 13:  at how slow some people talk, you know, or it's, it's slower than
Speaker 13:  the my brain. Like I feel like I have to calibrate it with the
Speaker 13:  speed at which I think I'm like, if you're talking at the speed at which
Speaker 13:  I think great if you're talking like three times slower than I think I've
Speaker 13:  gotta dial you up.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Jake, what about you?
Speaker 12:  I would say like most YouTube videos would be improved by a default.
Speaker 12:  1.25 x like just a lit little bit more, little
Speaker 12:  bit more TikTok. Oh yeah, two x on everything. Just like
Speaker 12:  those things are, are going seriously, they made 'em, I, so I
Speaker 12:  set a 15 minute timer for myself on TikTok, so I can't watch too much every
Speaker 12:  day. And this way I can squeeze 30 minutes of TikTok in 15 minutes. Not
Speaker 12:  bad.
Speaker 1:  Okay,
Speaker 12:  That's ter it's terrible.
Speaker 1:  So what you've just said is, I don't wanna watch TikTok. So I've invented
Speaker 1:  ways so I can watch more TikTok in the time. I shouldn't be watching TikTok
Speaker 1:  and
Speaker 12:  Have a, have a worst time watching it. Just
Speaker 1:  Don't look at TikTok, Jake.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, yeah. This is, ugh, I gotta know what's happening on TikTok. How
Speaker 12:  will I know what Stanley water bottle to buy?
Speaker 1:  But like the, the world would be a better place if everyone only listened
Speaker 1:  to their podcast on one x is really kind of where I'm landing on this that
Speaker 12:  I a hundred percent agree with.
Speaker 13:  I mean, I will say that it is Zen to just
Speaker 13:  not care how fast this person is speaking and really live in the moment.
Speaker 13:  Maybe I need to meditate more and maybe my form of meditation will be
Speaker 13:  listening to podcasts on one x and just really living in the moment and
Speaker 13:  hanging on their every word. You know?
Speaker 1:  Do you guys have podcasts you listen to? Not because you, you know,
Speaker 1:  like the host or like the storytelling style or whatever, but for like Pure
Speaker 1:  informational reasons.
Speaker 13:  I'm a visual learner, so I feel like if I only want it for informational
Speaker 13:  reasons, I've gotta read it or it kind of doesn't stick with me.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I'm fully with you Aidan. Yeah, audio is like,
Speaker 12:  it's more for a, I don't know, there's like a hanging out vibe to it,
Speaker 12:  right? But yeah, trying, trying to get like news that way
Speaker 12:  it is not, not quite working for me. Okay.
Speaker 1:  So that's the one kind of podcast that I'm like, yeah, listen to that as
Speaker 1:  fast as you want. Right? It's, it's like, it's the audio version of like
Speaker 1:  skimming the headlines just like three x your way through whatever
Speaker 1:  headlines podcast you're listening to. But I think I've just only selected
Speaker 1:  for podcasts that I sort of like hanging out with and putting
Speaker 1:  those at two x feels weird. The problem is once you go up you
Speaker 1:  can never go back down because then you're like, why are you all talking
Speaker 1:  so slowly? What is like, why did you all do drugs right before you started
Speaker 1:  this episode? And you're just like, no, this is how fast they normally talk.
Speaker 1:  Like I've had people meet me in person and be like, you don't sound like
Speaker 1:  I'm used to it. And then they realize in the course of our conversation that
Speaker 1:  they only ever listen to the podcast at 1.5 or two x. So there used to
Speaker 1:  me just talking like this all the time and they're like, why don't you talk
Speaker 1:  like this all the time? It's insane. And I'm like, I can talk that fast.
Speaker 1:  Like we, we can do this. I can be this person.
Speaker 13:  Especially now that you're watching Gilmore Girls.
Speaker 1:  Oh my god. I mean it's, it's outta control. Also a very strange thing has
Speaker 1:  happened to me now that I have children as I identify with very different
Speaker 1:  people in those shows and now I'm like les's parents. Were basically right
Speaker 1:  about everything and, and Lorelei is kind of a menace, but that's
Speaker 1:  for Hayden when we record our Gilmore Girls podcast. We'll we'll come back
Speaker 1:  to that.
Speaker 13:  Perfect. Can't wait.
Speaker 1:  My second take is that Threads is good actually
Speaker 1:  that's it. That's the whole
Speaker 12:  Take. I'm gonna agree with you. I think Threads gets way too much hate.
Speaker 12:  And you know what, I'm gonna go even further. The algorithmic feed. It's
Speaker 12:  all right.
Speaker 1:  I agree.
Speaker 12:  Like I, I feel like I enjoy threads more
Speaker 12:  than X or Blue Sky, sorry,
Speaker 12:  Mastodon, that's not even on my radar.
Speaker 1:  Mastodon is, I'm sorry, David, full of good ideas and not full of interesting
Speaker 1:  people doing interesting things. Thread
Speaker 12:  Is is pleasant. I feel like people on threads, or at least the algorithm
Speaker 12:  on threads keeps things pleasant and
Speaker 12:  down the line. And I feel like on other social networks, people are
Speaker 12:  very raw and passionate and intense And I
Speaker 12:  don't need that all the time. Sometimes I just want a laid back take about
Speaker 12:  the new iPhone and like that's what I get on Threads.
Speaker 1:  Hayden,
Speaker 13:  I feel like I can't speak to this with actual knowledge
Speaker 13:  because for threads, like I get on and then I leave. Like I post my story
Speaker 13:  and then I log off. So I honestly haven't spent that much time
Speaker 13:  like scrolling on threads because I have so many social media platforms
Speaker 13:  that I have to be on now that I just Threads is the one that I like.
Speaker 13:  One had to fall and it's threads for me. It's like I go on, I post my stories,
Speaker 13:  I leave, I don't scroll.
Speaker 1:  Where do you scroll?
Speaker 13:  Blue Sky and Twitter. But yeah, threads
Speaker 13:  and LinkedIn for me both. I'm like, I go on, I post my thing And
Speaker 13:  I leave. I don't have any understanding of like
Speaker 13:  what's going on on there. Instagram, I scroll like personally
Speaker 13:  Blue Sky and Twitter XI scroll like for work.
Speaker 13:  And then the other two I just kind of let fall by the wayside and I'm there
Speaker 13:  technically, but not in actuality.
Speaker 1:  So to me, my experience this summer over and over was that
Speaker 1:  Twitter has essentially like lost its mind. It's it's, it's a 10 out of 10
Speaker 1:  like right wing cesspool all the time.
Speaker 1:  Blue Sky is like the same, but on the opposite end of the political spectrum.
Speaker 1:  Like I think there, there's a lot of fun to be had on Blue Sky, but I think
Speaker 1:  the thing where the culture has turned into a lot of people scolding each
Speaker 1:  other is real and true. It's
Speaker 1:  at least more full of people saying things that are real than Twitter is
Speaker 1:  at least on my feed. But like, I just don't find either one to be a particularly
Speaker 1:  good time and threads. I think Jake, I have the exact same experience that
Speaker 1:  you do too, which is like the, the temperature on threads is not as high.
Speaker 1:  And I think a lot of people in our business take that to mean, oh,
Speaker 1:  it's not real time, it's not lively, it's not exciting, it's not what's happening,
Speaker 1:  it's not the news. And to me I'm like, oh, I actually, when I come to this,
Speaker 1:  I don't want the news all the time. Yeah. It's just nice to have some people
Speaker 1:  posting about some things. And I think Threads has gotten better at being
Speaker 1:  timely. Like I'm seeing many fewer yesterday and four days ago
Speaker 1:  posts on my threads timeline every time I open the app. So they're like,
Speaker 1:  they're getting better with that algorithm. And it just like I, I have a
Speaker 1:  nice time on threads in a way that I no longer have a nice time on Blue Sky
Speaker 1:  or on Twitter. And I feel like that is, I just, I hit this point where I
Speaker 1:  was like, why am I subjecting myself to opening Twitter five times a day?
Speaker 1:  Like this is an insane waste of time because I feel some like
Speaker 1:  journalistic obligation to know what these Luna Hicks are saying to each
Speaker 1:  other. And it's just, I don't know, like I think
Speaker 1:  ultimately maybe the sort of boring middle is actually the right place
Speaker 1:  for social media to land. Can
Speaker 12:  I tell you, threads is actually the only other app on my phone that I
Speaker 12:  have a timer on and it's because wow, it is like, it is pleasant
Speaker 12:  and because it's algorithmic by default and it's like a decent algorithm,
Speaker 12:  you can keep going forever. And I do not wanna keep going forever. So yeah,
Speaker 12:  I, I think thread's like totally pleasant. It is not, it's true. It's not
Speaker 12:  as spicy and that's kind of nice.
Speaker 13:  Okay. Maybe I'll spend some more time on threads. You've convinced me,
Speaker 1:  It took me a while because it's actually like, you have to realize that being
Speaker 1:  slightly bored by it is actually a good thing and not a bad thing. Where
Speaker 1:  it's like, I don't open the app And immediately have like a fight or flight
Speaker 1:  response is, is probably a healthy thing for how we deal with our
Speaker 1:  lives on the internet, but feels very different than I think what we're used
Speaker 1:  to. Which brings me to my third take,
Speaker 1:  which is that it's actually pretty easy to quit social media And I think
Speaker 1:  many more people should do it.
Speaker 1:  I, I deleted Instagram and TikTok from my phone
Speaker 1:  basically right as I had a kid And I have actually had zero impulse to put
Speaker 1:  either one of them back. The thing Instagram does where if you click a link,
Speaker 1:  it won't show it to you until you open the app is really annoying. Oh yeah.
Speaker 1:  But has not actually caused me all that much trouble. TikTok
Speaker 1:  is fine. Somebody sends you a link, it opens in the webpage, you, you watch
Speaker 1:  the TikTok, you move on through day.
Speaker 1:  I, I have essentially stopped spending
Speaker 1:  time on Blue Sky and Twitter. And even Threads is like, it's there because
Speaker 1:  I feel a sort of obligation to be around. But like if, if you're,
Speaker 1:  most people are like in a place where they should spend less time on
Speaker 1:  social media and it's actually not that hard to do, and maybe we should just
Speaker 1:  all quit social forever right now. Let's do it. Agree or disagree.
Speaker 13:  I feel like you're right in that, of course we'd all be so much happier
Speaker 13:  if we didn't have social media. But
Speaker 13:  I will say, I think there are ways to use it
Speaker 13:  in ways that are a little less harmful. So one Jake's timer
Speaker 13:  idea. Amazing. Yep. Two, something that I do
Speaker 13:  that I has always like given me a lot of peace is
Speaker 13:  that I don't, I mean, let's use Instagram as an example. I don't look at
Speaker 13:  who likes my stuff And I don't look at who watches
Speaker 13:  my stuff so that I feel like I'm always just shouting it to the void in
Speaker 13:  a good way. Like, I am not aware of myself being perceived.
Speaker 13:  I'm not like, oh my God, this person from high school saw my
Speaker 13:  story of this. I wonder what they thought. Let's think about this through
Speaker 13:  their eyes. It's like, I don't know. So I don't care. I'm like
Speaker 13:  blissfully ignorant. I just feel like I'm posting, I, this is how I feel.
Speaker 13:  I think I would use Instagram the exact same way. If I had no followers,
Speaker 13:  like if I was just posting for myself, I think I would do the exact same
Speaker 13:  thing. And it's because I don't, since I don't see who's looking at
Speaker 13:  my stuff, I don't like, you know, really I'm not,
Speaker 13:  I'm blissfully ignorant of anyone looking at my stuff. However, I do like
Speaker 13:  to use it a lot as a messaging platform. Like a lot of times maybe it's
Speaker 13:  just like, you know, something about
Speaker 13:  people today, but it feels a little too intimate sometimes to ask for
Speaker 13:  someone's like number. So you ask for their Instagram, then you message
Speaker 13:  on Instagram. So I love using it as like a messaging app. Same with Twitter.
Speaker 13:  Like I can message someone on there and then we can move it to another platform
Speaker 13:  after. But I think all of these tools, their biggest values in their like
Speaker 13:  direct messaging features and then scrolling and infinite scroll
Speaker 13:  is like the thing that basically causes you internal turmoil. And
Speaker 13:  you have to find a way to, you know, address that. But I don't know, I mean,
Speaker 13:  I'm like, of course we'd all be happier if they, if we didn't use them as
Speaker 13:  much. But I also think there's some value in using it in a way that's like
Speaker 13:  measured if you can do that, which is hard.
Speaker 1:  So I, I agree. But I think even, even the premise of all of this is just
Speaker 1:  like, this is an unavoidable thing that we have to
Speaker 1:  manage the best way that we can. And I'm, I'm increasingly of the mind that
Speaker 1:  actually it's really easy to quit. Like I was shocked at how simple it was
Speaker 1:  to just not be on Instagram anymore and like, do
Speaker 1:  I occasionally feel like I'm missing something? Like honestly, no.
Speaker 1:  Like, I've probably missed some dms, but
Speaker 1:  that's fine. I think we do have a real like
Speaker 1:  messaging problem across all of these different
Speaker 1:  platforms. I've been using this at Beeper that we've talked about a lot on
Speaker 1:  this show to try and like manage all of the dms in one place and that like
Speaker 1:  almost kind of works. But in general it's just like, I don't know.
Speaker 1:  I, the thing that really shocked me was how, how easy it was to get rid of
Speaker 1:  and how few times I have missed TikTok and Instagram and
Speaker 1:  how rare it has been to like, want to be on Blue Sky this summer.
Speaker 13:  I did once quit social media for like a month and it was very easy. Like
Speaker 13:  it was weirdly easy. And I think it's just because yeah, I reverted back
Speaker 13:  to like my old life of just living in the moment.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. What a crazy idea. Jake, what about you? You've just been scrolling
Speaker 1:  TikTok this whole time. You're not even, you're not even
Speaker 12:  Listening to TikTok. Oh, sorry. Were you guys still still going?
Speaker 12:  You, you weren't going fast enough. This is the problem. I agree with you
Speaker 12:  David, but I kind of feel bad about it.
Speaker 12:  You know, I have never been very good about posting
Speaker 12:  to social media and there's a lot of,
Speaker 12:  I would say like acquaintances I follow, right? Like old friends from college,
Speaker 12:  people who, you know, we used to work with who
Speaker 12:  I, you know, I'm not gonna stay up to date with them day to day, week
Speaker 12:  to week. But by following along with their posts, I'm able to get some sense
Speaker 12:  of what's going on in their life. And there's this really weird thing that
Speaker 12:  happens where I'm like, oh, I know what's going on with you. I actually
Speaker 12:  still feel like somewhat close to you. You have no idea what's happening
Speaker 12:  with me. You like, and you will not because I'm not putting
Speaker 12:  anything back out there for you. And so there is this sort of like interesting
Speaker 12:  way that you can use this to maintain a friendship. Even if it's like,
Speaker 12:  even if I'm not really doing more than like liking a post, I think
Speaker 12:  that's nice. Like it lets you keep up with people. I just, I think all the
Speaker 12:  things that hate Hayden talked about where it's like, it shows you, everyone
Speaker 12:  who views it shows you everyone who liked it. It's like, I can't not look
Speaker 12:  at those things. And whenever I post an Instagram story, I'm like,
Speaker 12:  like, did I post this at the wrong time? Is this, is this inconvenient for
Speaker 12:  everybody? Nobody's seeing it. And I am like, I, I don't feel good about,
Speaker 12:  like, I don't, I don't feel good. Right? Like when I, when I watch other
Speaker 12:  people's stories, I'm like, oh, this is so nice. They're doing things, I'm
Speaker 12:  so happy for them. And I'm just like, I feel stress
Speaker 12:  when I'm posting. Yeah. So I would love for there to be a version of social
Speaker 12:  media that, that I enjoy. I feel bad And I think like
Speaker 12:  not engaging on social media is maybe sort of like a ne negative
Speaker 12:  for like, I don't know, friends society.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 12:  But but also like, is it easy to tap out and is it like maybe healthy
Speaker 12:  for a lot of people to tap out? Like yeah, you like the people
Speaker 12:  who I'm gonna hang out with. I'm texting with them anyway. It's fine.
Speaker 1:  You know what's so funny is what both of you just described as the ideal
Speaker 1:  outcome of this is original Facebook where I have a
Speaker 1:  wall, I post stuff on the wall and if you wanna know what's going on with
Speaker 1:  me, you go to my wall and you look and if you want to interact, you can.
Speaker 1:  And if not, no hard feelings. I'm not gonna know either way. That's how it
Speaker 1:  worked. That was, that was good. Like that was the right
Speaker 1:  thing. And then, and then they realized that people would use it more if
Speaker 1:  they made it feel worse to use. And now here we are 20 years later and everything's
Speaker 1:  a disaster. Like you both just pitched me on what if we had Facebook 1.0
Speaker 1:  And I think it's right.
Speaker 13:  I agree. But I will say I do remember in high school being
Speaker 13:  worried that my wall posts were like too old And I would call my friends
Speaker 13:  and be like, oh, can you post something on my wall? It looks like no one
Speaker 13:  cares about me this week. So that's fair. Even then we had some insecurities,
Speaker 13:  but I agree it was a better time. It was a better time.
Speaker 1:  That is very fair. Alright, my next take, and this is kind of
Speaker 1:  related to all of this, and I'm actually, this is the one I am least convicted
Speaker 1:  on and kind of wanna talk through, but my take here is that the, the
Speaker 1:  anti phone movement is real. And we,
Speaker 1:  and the tech industry should take it seriously. The, the people who are
Speaker 1:  actively trying to get away from technology and not just talking
Speaker 1:  about how terrific it would be to use technology less is it's a real
Speaker 1:  and growing and powerful movement and it's going to change things.
Speaker 12:  I I disagree with the first half of that. Okay. But I think
Speaker 12:  that you said two separate things actually. Okay. I think if
Speaker 12:  we're talking about the people who are like, I'm gonna get a dumb phone,
Speaker 12:  I'm gonna use the, oh God, what's it called? The light phone. The, the light
Speaker 12:  phone. Like, okay, there's a, there's a small,
Speaker 12:  small number of people who are gonna use these things. Smartphone is, is
Speaker 12:  fine. How you use the smartphone is not fine as far as like the
Speaker 12:  anti-technology. I'm worried about screen stuff more broadly
Speaker 12:  that I agree with you and that I think is real
Speaker 1:  Interesting. And you think those are separate groups of people?
Speaker 12:  Yes, because I think going for, you know, a dumb phone
Speaker 12:  or being, not having a phone and being disconnected, that's just
Speaker 12:  like arbitrarily inconvenient. And I think
Speaker 12:  like, I would like to be less connected at home,
Speaker 12:  so I read more books. Mm. That's different, right? Like,
Speaker 12:  you can still do that and be capable of sending, you
Speaker 12:  know, of making a FaceTime call to your mom.
Speaker 1:  I see. Okay. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  I agree with what Jake said. I mean, because everyone I
Speaker 13:  know that has a dumb phone or like a flip phone, it's one
Speaker 13:  of their two phones. So it's like they bring it when they go out or they
Speaker 13:  bring it when they go hiking or they have it in certain situations,
Speaker 13:  you know. But I don't know anyone that has switched it out completely
Speaker 13:  just because sometimes they need like Google maps, sometimes they, like,
Speaker 13:  even from a safety standpoint, sometimes they need some of those features
Speaker 13:  even if they don't really wanna use them. I know people that have kind of
Speaker 13:  turned their smartphone into a dumb phone in a way by like, you know,
Speaker 13:  bricking it during certain times or, you know, setting
Speaker 13:  timers on apps or deleting all apps except
Speaker 13:  like three, you know, or doing the black and white screen thing. So
Speaker 13:  there are ways, I think there's a lot of ways that people are trying to
Speaker 13:  be less connected and less reachable all the time. But I don't know anyone
Speaker 13:  that's just tossing their, you know, smartphone full-time for a
Speaker 13:  dumb phone. Yeah, that's
Speaker 12:  Fair. And I think if you look at like, you know, maybe kids shouldn't
Speaker 12:  have their phones in schools, people are like, oh, you know what? We went
Speaker 12:  a little far in that. And that's like, there's starting to be a shift there
Speaker 12:  And I feel like we're gonna see more of that where it's like these specific
Speaker 12:  places and instances where we have overstepped with technology
Speaker 12:  where we're like, we're maybe a little too connected, but I, I don't think
Speaker 12:  we're gonna like fully throw it out the door that that feels like
Speaker 12:  a little bit of an overreaction or Okay. Maybe like a niche
Speaker 12:  trend than, than an actual like, societal movement.
Speaker 1:  So you're, you're on the side of like sensible regulation, not like
Speaker 1:  let the Luddites take over the world.
Speaker 12:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I think that's probably right. I think I just keep being
Speaker 1:  struck by a, talking to a lot of people who are in the
Speaker 1:  situation that I'm in of like, you're, you're being busy young parents with
Speaker 1:  young kids and it's like trying to figure out
Speaker 12:  How many iPads you give them. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like, is is it okay to be an iPad kid is like a weird and complicated question
Speaker 1:  in, in life in front of a lot of people right now. And then I'm sitting there
Speaker 1:  next to my kid like scrolling Reddit and I'm like, what am I doing?
Speaker 1:  This sucks. And so I've hit this point where, and you read all these studies
Speaker 1:  about like every time they do a study that's like, we took the
Speaker 1:  cell phones away from a bunch of kids and their mental health scores went
Speaker 1:  through the roof. And it's like, there's just, there is something
Speaker 1:  bubbling here. And I think we've spent a long time listening to
Speaker 1:  companies essentially say, you can say whatever you want. We know how much
Speaker 1:  you use our product, and the more we give it to you, the more you will use
Speaker 1:  it. And as far as I understand, there's not a lot of
Speaker 1:  evidence that that's changing yet. But like, anecdotally, the
Speaker 1:  the smoke is real that like people in some meaningful way
Speaker 1:  are starting to pull out and fight back.
Speaker 1:  And I just think, I, I think we're, we're gonna start to see that show up
Speaker 1:  in meaningful ways. Because every time a company has even tried to like address
Speaker 1:  that, like Instagram had the thing where it was like, you're all caught up
Speaker 1:  and then do you know what happened? They got rid of it because they were
Speaker 1:  like, oh, actually we want people to keep scrolling and they will. And, and
Speaker 1:  I think, I think, And I hope we're about to see that start to
Speaker 1:  shift against some of that trend.
Speaker 13:  Definitely. I
Speaker 1:  Hope maybe I'm, maybe I'm wrong. Maybe, maybe we're all gonna like bitch
Speaker 1:  and moan about screen time as we ever increase our screen time until
Speaker 1:  we're dead.
Speaker 13:  You know? I think you're right though. I mean, I have a friend that's starting
Speaker 13:  like a movement for connecting in real life
Speaker 13:  and I'm going to one of her events this we this weekend or next weekend,
Speaker 13:  and I'm excited. It's like, you know, they're, we're seeing more like community
Speaker 13:  kind of almost activism I guess around
Speaker 13:  like connecting in real life and how to, how to just like hang out with
Speaker 13:  people, which is sad that we have to do it. Yeah. But it's cool that it's
Speaker 13:  happening.
Speaker 1:  A movement to hang out in real life is like a, just a terrifying concept
Speaker 1:  that that needs to exist at all. But I'm glad it exists.
Speaker 13:  Exactly. I
Speaker 1:  Don't know, I say this as I'm staring into my screen for the 15th hour today.
Speaker 1:  Like, I don't know.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, on one hand I feel like it has just been like enough years with social
Speaker 12:  media, with electronics that like, naturally it we're like kind of due for
Speaker 12:  a little bit of that pushback. On the other hand, I was at
Speaker 12:  the grocery store when TikTok got Unbound back in, what was
Speaker 12:  it? February and
Speaker 12:  the, the, the cashier at the at register was like,
Speaker 12:  Hey, she like said to her manager, she's like, Hey, can I leave like tiktoks
Speaker 12:  back online? And I'm like, yo, it was, it was banned for like eight hours.
Speaker 12:  Like, yeah, you're fine.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be all right. Yeah. Yeah. I think, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm hopeful, But that is like, as a reporter, very much a thing
Speaker 1:  I'm paying attention to now. It's like the, the, the smoke feels like it's
Speaker 1:  there in a way that it has not been before. All right, my next take,
Speaker 1:  this is the one I feel the most strongly about. All the streaming
Speaker 1:  services are bad and they should feel bad and they have made the experience
Speaker 1:  of trying to watch shows and movies. Awful.
Speaker 13:  I'll let Jake take this one first.
Speaker 1:  I will elaborate if you would like, but I feel this very strongly.
Speaker 12:  Oh man, there's just a whole lot bundled up in that.
Speaker 1:  Would you like me to make it simpler for you? Yes,
Speaker 12:  Yes, yes. I'm gonna take that lifeline. It's
Speaker 1:  Just the last thing at, at this moment in time, the experience
Speaker 1:  of trying to watch TV shows and movies is awful.
Speaker 12:  I mean, I disagree with that. Agree. Like, agree, it's fine, it's
Speaker 12:  fine. I, I have like a nuanced disagreement,
Speaker 12:  but like if there's a show that I want to watch on HBO or
Speaker 12:  Hulu or whatever, that's fine. I sign up for the service, I go to the service,
Speaker 12:  I click the button, it plays, it's fine. May maybe if my, if my,
Speaker 12:  you know, Google tv, whatever streamer is, is feeling good about it,
Speaker 12:  it might even remember that I was watching that series and just put the
Speaker 12:  next episode on my home screen. Might not, I don't know, but it's fine.
Speaker 12:  And
Speaker 1:  This is a good experience that you're describing this, this you're happy
Speaker 1:  about this. It's,
Speaker 12:  I I can get there. I can even, I can like use my voice to, I have to go
Speaker 1:  To some unknowable app that I pay an unknowable amount of money for. No,
Speaker 1:  no,
Speaker 12:  No. It's not un I it's easy enough to remember what,
Speaker 1:  How much do you pay for HBO max right now? Tell me off the top of your head.
Speaker 12:  Oh, it's too much money. It's like HBO O max is like $90 a month. I don't
Speaker 12:  know.
Speaker 1:  Do you know, I'm serious. Do you know how much you pay for HBO Max right
Speaker 1:  now
Speaker 12:  Off the top of your head? 20. I wanna say it's 20 for the 4K. It's too much
Speaker 12:  money. It's too much money for four. So, well this is, but I would, I would
Speaker 12:  make a distinction, right? Like is the experience good? Like yeah, I can
Speaker 12:  sign up easy, I can sign, I can like turn off my subscription easy
Speaker 12:  enough. The thing that I am like I wanna tell
Speaker 12:  everyone you should actually do, if you want to watch movies, do not just
Speaker 12:  sign up for Netflix. Do not just sign up for Hulu, whatever,
Speaker 12:  just pay $3 and rent them for the
Speaker 12:  weekend. Y you'll spend less than you would
Speaker 12:  if you were subscribing to a service for an entire month and you get a bigger
Speaker 12:  selection. You don't have to worry about which service you're on, which
Speaker 12:  service you're not on. But if we're talking about TV shows, it's a little
Speaker 12:  different.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, I agree with that. I mean for me
Speaker 13:  it's not a bad experience, you know, but
Speaker 13:  I will say I've been really into paying for physical media
Speaker 13:  in Brooklyn now. There is a DVD store
Speaker 13:  and it's so exciting to be able to go in there And I hope it survives.
Speaker 13:  It's only been open for like six months but I hope it survives and right
Speaker 13:  now you can go in and just buy your favorite TBDs and now you
Speaker 13:  know, I have a collection of my favorite ones that I watch over and over
Speaker 13:  because I am a chronic re watcher. I rewatch everything so many times.
Speaker 13:  I think it's like an anxiety thing. It's very comforting to me to rewatch
Speaker 13:  my favorite movies. So I have all my favorites And I can just do it at any
Speaker 13:  time. Even old ones that are no longer on streaming services like
Speaker 13:  childhood Mary Kay Nally movies, I can now watch them, you know?
Speaker 13:  But yeah, I don't think it's a bad experience to you know,
Speaker 13:  watch. I mean it's annoying to have to Google which streaming service I
Speaker 13:  watch whatever thing on. But you know, I think it's all about
Speaker 13:  diversification and everyone should buy some DVDs from their local
Speaker 13:  store to keep it alive. That's what I think
Speaker 1:  Hated. Let me tell you what I just heard you say. What I just heard you say
Speaker 1:  is actually streaming is fine but it doesn't have anything that I wanna watch
Speaker 1:  such that I have to leave my house and go buy a DVD so that I'm
Speaker 1:  able to actually watch the things that I wanna watch when I wanna watch them.
Speaker 1:  That's what you just said.
Speaker 13:  Listen, that's not, that's not the streaming services fault,
Speaker 13:  honestly. Yes, it's, there's a lot of weird, there's a lot of weird rights
Speaker 13:  issues with my childhood faves. Like there's a Tyra
Speaker 13:  Banks movie called Lifesize that no one could find on any
Speaker 13:  streaming service anywhere. Not even Prime video. So I had to order it
Speaker 13:  on eBay like a Luddite but or minus the eBay park. But yeah,
Speaker 1:  This is the problem. This is the problem. I
Speaker 1:  can't fi like imagine, imagine if you went on Spotify and just like four
Speaker 1:  out of 10 songs you wanted to listen to just weren't there and you were like
Speaker 1:  cool, I'll still listen to Spotify every day. Like no that might be the case
Speaker 1:  soon. This is, it's outrageous that this is where we have landed that that
Speaker 1:  you actually pay as however many services you wanna pay for And I pay
Speaker 1:  for a lot of them. You still can't reasonably expect to
Speaker 1:  watch the thing that you wanna watch and that it will be in the same place
Speaker 1:  when you go back to find it and that it will have all the stuff that you
Speaker 1:  want. I watch always Sunny on Hulu. There are just a bunch of episodes of
Speaker 1:  Always Sunny that Hulu doesn't have because it finds them objectionable.
Speaker 1:  Just is that this just don't exist. Is that the show that like that put you
Speaker 1:  over the edge? What was it? No, I've been over, I was over the edge all summer
Speaker 1:  because what I have is a toddler who wants to watch
Speaker 1:  the same movie 650 times in a row And I can
Speaker 1:  never remember where it is and the search never works and it drives me
Speaker 1:  insane and I'm paying a billion dollars a month to have
Speaker 1:  70 different apps that are all really slow on my Roku TV and none of
Speaker 1:  them put the continue watching ro in the same place. And the search sucks
Speaker 1:  across all. Like it's just, there is more content available to all of us
Speaker 1:  than ever and it is being put together in the stupidest, most hostile
Speaker 1:  way and it drives me nuts.
Speaker 13:  The solution is putting K-pop demon hunters on a loop forever and
Speaker 13:  never switching to any other movie. And then your toddler, you will be thrilled.
Speaker 1:  I also blame Netflix because it took Netflix like 10 days to put
Speaker 1:  K-pop demon hunters on my home screen And I was just sitting at home unaware
Speaker 1:  of K-pop demon hunters for far too long.
Speaker 13:  Unfortunately my entire Spotify rap this year is going to be
Speaker 13:  K-pop demon hunters the soundtrack. And I, I'm, I accept that but I'm not
Speaker 13:  gonna be sharing my Spotify raft this year. That's,
Speaker 1:  I don't think there's anything wrong with that at all. Also, Jake, by the
Speaker 1:  way, I just checked and you're paying $21 a month for HBO max.
Speaker 12:  It's too much. I don't even know what I'm watching on HBO right now.
Speaker 1:  And David Zoff recently said it's way underpriced so that number's probably
Speaker 1:  gonna go up.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, that's not exactly, sorry. That's why I listen, I subscribed to this
Speaker 12:  thing for like a month at a time and then I'm turning it off. 'cause that
Speaker 12:  is way too much money.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, because what's a better user experience than having to like balance
Speaker 1:  your checkbook against streaming 16 times a year?
Speaker 12:  It is rough. Yeah. I would pay a subscription fee for somebody to just manage
Speaker 12:  these for me And I would probably come out ahead. I'm like, I'm coming
Speaker 12:  around I, I'm
Speaker 1:  About this
Speaker 12:  One. I'm a hundred percent agree with your anger. Even if I don't necessarily
Speaker 12:  a hundred percent agree with this in practice,
Speaker 1:  I don't care whose fault it's the streaming to be so clear whether or not
Speaker 1:  all of this is Netflix's fault, the fact that there literally is not a
Speaker 1:  way for me to watch the movie The Nice Guys, which I tried to watch the other
Speaker 1:  day. Yeah. It literally does not exist in a digital
Speaker 1:  streaming service. And I pay for all of them that is dumb and
Speaker 1:  bad and everyone should feel bad.
Speaker 12:  This is what
Speaker 13:  Kills me. I'm gonna buy it for you at my DVD store instead of tv. Yes please.
Speaker 1:  And then I will buy a DVD player because one of those in forever.
Speaker 1:  And then my life will be good again. I have come back around to like, especially
Speaker 1:  for shows that I wanna watch again, there are a couple of streaming services
Speaker 1:  I basically subscribe to for like one or two shows and
Speaker 1:  I'm getting to like, I'm just gonna buy those shows on
Speaker 1:  DVD or digital or whatever and then just watch them and like,
Speaker 1:  who needs the streaming service anymore? Okay, I need to calm down.
Speaker 1:  I've, I should have done that one last and then I could have like, I could
Speaker 1:  have like relaxed into the break. I'm gonna give you a calmer take. My calmer
Speaker 1:  take, and this is the second to last one is I think we will look back
Speaker 1:  on 2025 as the year self-driving cars actually
Speaker 1:  happened. And I, I'm not sure we're talking about it like we're, we're in
Speaker 1:  sort of the like boiling frog state of like city by
Speaker 1:  city, company by company. Waymo is starting to pull this off. Like the
Speaker 1:  the we've, we've been lied to about self-driving cars for a full decade,
Speaker 1:  but I think they did it now And I think, I think this is the year they're
Speaker 1:  doing it. What do you guys think?
Speaker 13:  I mean it's hard when you have a nuanced take on these things. You know,
Speaker 13:  I, I've been covering it not allowed. I remember.
Speaker 13:  I mean it's like, I guess I disagree because
Speaker 13:  I don't believe that they've done it now. I think they've made strides.
Speaker 13:  Waymo is testing vehicles in New York City, which they never did before
Speaker 13:  because they said there were too many crazy
Speaker 13:  factors that they couldn't really control for and they always want some
Speaker 13:  uncontrollable factors, but there were just too many in New York City. Now
Speaker 13:  there aren't. So I do think they made a lot of strides, but I won't really
Speaker 13:  say they've done it until it's something that
Speaker 13:  most people I know do to get to work like city
Speaker 13:  bike or like until it's as common as biking in general.
Speaker 13:  I don't think I will say that they have done it, but I know in SF everyone
Speaker 13:  is loving Waymo's. I've heard of some parents like putting their kid in
Speaker 13:  a Waymo to take them somewhere. That certainly is, you know, it
Speaker 13:  does mean that it's come a long way, but I think for me until it's as
Speaker 13:  common as say like biking, which, you know, I have a handful of friends
Speaker 13:  that bike everywhere. I feel like when self-driving cars
Speaker 13:  reach that status, I will say they've done it. Okay.
Speaker 1:  That's a good take. Jake, what do you think? I think
Speaker 12:  You're right at least that the, that 2025 might be a turning point.
Speaker 12:  You know, it's not, it's not clear to me what has improved, right?
Speaker 12:  Like, I don't know if the technology got better or if the regulations just
Speaker 12:  got a little fuzzier and they're like, oh, let's see what happens. But
Speaker 12:  I I it's, it's Waymo in particular, I I do not
Speaker 12:  count the ro robax. I, I'm sorry. No, but
Speaker 12:  right like Waymo, which I assume cares more about
Speaker 12:  their reputation and
Speaker 1:  Safety of people. Yes. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 12:  Like I've been hearing a ton about their rollout in San Francisco
Speaker 12:  and yeah, now they're in New York. So I've, I've been hurt hearing about
Speaker 12:  at least some pushback to them. I believe it was Waymo rolling out in Boston,
Speaker 12:  right? Like once, once stuff starts happening, like that means that the
Speaker 12:  technology is improving, right? If they're putting it in a place that the
Speaker 12:  average person can experience 'em, it doesn't necessarily mean everybody's
Speaker 12:  gonna use them, But that feels like a turning point. I
Speaker 12:  have not gotten a chance to ride one yet. I don't know how the experience
Speaker 12:  is. I don't know if they really are all there yet. And it does seem like
Speaker 12:  there's still quite a few limitations to where they can go and what
Speaker 12:  environments they're good in. But I I am like changing your take
Speaker 12:  a little bit, David, but it it, I I think you, you may
Speaker 12:  well be onto something that like 2025 something happened this year.
Speaker 13:  I agree that it was a turning point.
Speaker 12:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I think there will be like a chapter in the book about
Speaker 1:  how self-driving cars happened. That is 2025 and it'll be like
Speaker 1:  the, the year real people started taking it seriously.
Speaker 12:  There is nothing for a dec, right? We got, we got, we went from zero
Speaker 12:  self-driving to like, we can basically do self-driving but actually they're
Speaker 12:  not safe enough to put on real roads and that was 10 years and now this
Speaker 12:  year they're like, we're just gonna roll it out to a bunch of cities. And
Speaker 12:  like, I don't know what changed here. Uber and
Speaker 1:  Lyft were promising that it was gonna be 2020. I would, I would remind everyone
Speaker 1:  that those companies made a huge amount of noise and a huge
Speaker 1:  amount of money lying to everybody about how close we were to
Speaker 1:  self-driving cars. Tesla has been doing the same thing for a very long time.
Speaker 1:  And I think personally I got so jaded by all of
Speaker 1:  that that I got to the point where anytime somebody would like be bullish
Speaker 1:  on self-driving cars, they'd be like, oh congratulations. Like, whatever,
Speaker 1:  I don't care. Now I kind of buy it. Like IIII agree with
Speaker 1:  you Hayden, that I think we're a ways away from it being like ubiquitous
Speaker 1:  in a really important way And I think the, the sort of world tilt
Speaker 1:  towards self-driving cars is gonna take a really long time.
Speaker 1:  But at this point it's the, like do I think a person who doesn't pay
Speaker 1:  any attention to this might get in a Waymo in 2025? I think the answer is
Speaker 1:  yeah, And I think that's already happening And I think that's a big deal
Speaker 1:  that like, it just becomes a way to get somewhere, not a
Speaker 1:  technology story.
Speaker 13:  I think they had, like you said, we did have 10 years without,
Speaker 13:  not without a lot of progress. But I do think for me it's
Speaker 13:  like I was getting all the press releases of the tiny incremental changes
Speaker 13:  that they were making every year. Like they were testing in a new city,
Speaker 13:  they were suddenly starting to test in snow for the first time, right? They
Speaker 13:  were suddenly starting to test somewhere with a lot of pedestrians and crowds
Speaker 13:  that were a little more unpredictable. So I think for me it's like I've
Speaker 13:  seen incremental progress year after year, but it was nothing to write home
Speaker 13:  about. And 2025 I think is when kind of the snowball
Speaker 13:  effect happened. Like all that incremental progress that was like kind of
Speaker 13:  not worth writing about sometimes, but came worth
Speaker 13:  it. And you know, I did drive in a couple waymo's last year And
Speaker 13:  I have to say my favorite thing about it was honestly that I could just
Speaker 13:  be completely alone. I didn't have to talk to anyone. I didn't have to worry
Speaker 13:  about playing my music aloud. I was just like in my own little room,
Speaker 13:  you know? So that's my favorite part, just being solo and being able to
Speaker 13:  play, you know, k-pop demon hunters that it wasn't out yet,
Speaker 13:  but that's what I'd be playing. Now
Speaker 1:  Are you guys nice to your Uber drivers? Like do you, are you, are you people
Speaker 1:  who like get in the back and like hang with the driver the whole time? Or
Speaker 1:  do you just like wear headphones? No talking wave and get out?
Speaker 12:  I say, I say like a very, I'm always like, Hey, thanks for coming by, I
Speaker 12:  appreciate it. And then, then we're done. The, the thing is they're in New York,
Speaker 12:  they're on the phone with somebody, they don't wanna talk to me
Speaker 1:  Always. Yeah, yeah, that's very true. I, I used to like try and talk to people
Speaker 1:  and then I saw a thing that was like a meme of somebody being like, so how
Speaker 1:  long have you been doing this for? And the Uber driver like leaping out of
Speaker 1:  a window And I was like, oh no, I asked that question to all of my Uber drivers.
Speaker 1:  So now I don't talk very much.
Speaker 13:  I just get in And I say, Hey thanks. And then I put in my headphones and
Speaker 13:  don't talk. 'cause yeah, New York, I mean they don't want you to talk, you
Speaker 13:  don't wanna talk. There's no false pretenses. But you know what, whenever
Speaker 13:  I take an Uber in Atlanta, I am in the longest
Speaker 13:  conversation of my life every single time. I don't know what it is, but
Speaker 1:  I have invented phone calls to get out of those conversations before. That's,
Speaker 1:  I'm not proud of that, but
Speaker 13:  I'm gonna call you next time.
Speaker 1:  Oh, that's a perfect segue. That was not intentional. But this is a perfect
Speaker 1:  segue to my last take, my final summer take of 2025
Speaker 1:  is that we should bring back phone calls as like a normal thing that people
Speaker 1:  do to each other all day every day. But I wanna bring back phone calls in
Speaker 1:  one very specific way And I wanna bring back phone calls like cops do
Speaker 1:  in movies where there's no, hello, how
Speaker 1:  are you? Let's small talk for 60 seconds before we get into it. We don't
Speaker 1:  even say goodbye at the end. You, you call me Hayden, you call me,
Speaker 1:  I pick up the phone And I say, hey, you say, hey, I have a, was it in Brooklyn
Speaker 1:  or Manhattan? I say Brooklyn and you say cool and you hang up the phone,
Speaker 1:  done the end. We, we should call like we text
Speaker 1:  and we should do it all the time.
Speaker 13:  I could not agree more. I 100% agree. I
Speaker 13:  think it's because my friends And I don't like phone calls that much, but
Speaker 13:  we call each other a lot. So we have defaulted to that. Literally. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  I'll call and be like, hi, you know,
Speaker 13:  literally what you just said. I'll be like, hi, blah, blah blah. There's
Speaker 13:  no pleasantries, there's nothing. And we know the love is there, it's, we
Speaker 13:  know what's going on. Yes. And then if I'm calling for like, you know, just
Speaker 13:  to catch up, I'll be like, hi, I have no reason to call.
Speaker 13:  I'm just like calling on a whim and then I set the expectations then we
Speaker 13:  can small talk and catch up about our lives. But like most of our calls
Speaker 13:  it's like if I pick up a call from my friend, I know it's gonna be within
Speaker 13:  like under one minute or five minutes and that's amazing. And then if
Speaker 13:  it's a whim call, great.
Speaker 1:  If you could assume that every time you got a phone call, the average duration
Speaker 1:  of it was gonna be like 45 seconds. I think everything about making and
Speaker 1:  receiving phone calls would get better. That sounds wonder like, Jake, I
Speaker 1:  just wanna be able to call you and be like, Jake, you'd be, you'd be like
Speaker 1:  hey. And I'd be like, hey two 30 or three and you'd be like three And I'd
Speaker 1:  be like cool. The end done, done. We're moving on with our lives. The
Speaker 13:  No goodbye is a key part. I love that. Just saying cool. Nobody
Speaker 1:  Ever says goodbye in movies and it drives my wife crazy because every time
Speaker 1:  we're watching a movie she's like, why didn't they even, they didn't even
Speaker 1:  say goodbye. And I'm like, well that's not like an interesting part of the
Speaker 1:  movie. People like small talking on the phone, but I think we should do it.
Speaker 1:  And you're just like, cool. Hang up, get done
Speaker 12:  David, you should absolutely start communicating with me this way because
Speaker 12:  I a hundred percent agree with you. Yes dude. I hate text
Speaker 12:  messaging. Text messaging is so tedious. The amount of time
Speaker 12:  and energy that goes into like deciding on a restaurant over text.
Speaker 12:  No, no. Get on the phone. You'll be done in 30 seconds. Yes.
Speaker 12:  People are so afraid of phone calls. Yeah. And
Speaker 12:  it is so much easier to get anything done.
Speaker 12:  Do it. Yes. Call your friends, it's great
Speaker 1:  And stop saying how are you? Stop saying hope all
Speaker 1:  is well. Stop saying what's new? No, if you have a question for
Speaker 1:  me, ask me the question and then when I've answered your question, hang up
Speaker 1:  the phone. Which means we need all these companies to make it a louder
Speaker 1:  noise when you hang up the phone again because I need to know when you've
Speaker 1:  hung up on me. So that's a, that's a product change I need these companies
Speaker 1:  to make is like, I want a loud click now that the phone is over
Speaker 1:  to let me know that you're gone and
Speaker 13:  That's it. I really miss my Motorola razor where I could, no, sorry,
Speaker 13:  not the, well I missed the razor. Yes. But what I'm actually talking about
Speaker 13:  is that I miss my juke because it was even cooler. You remember, you like
Speaker 13:  flip it up like that and then you'd flip it down like that. It was so cool.
Speaker 13:  It was like
Speaker 1:  A cool, you were like, it was like a comb from Grease that you were like
Speaker 1:  flipping open. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  It was so cool. And the funniest part is I never even had any music on my
Speaker 13:  Duke phone. I only bought it because I loved the way you could like, oh
Speaker 13:  answer a phone call and hang up a phone call. Incredible
Speaker 1:  The rules. This is good. I'm glad we agree this. I think, I think we have
Speaker 1:  the power to start a nationwide movement to call like we
Speaker 1:  text and it will just make everything better.
Speaker 13:  I'm in. Love
Speaker 1:  It. Alright, we need to take a break. Thank you both. I, I have no more summer
Speaker 1:  takes. I've gotten all my feelings out And I appreciate you both being here
Speaker 1:  to absorb and reflect my feelings back at me.
Speaker 13:  That's an honor
Speaker 1:  If, if I'm fired it. It's been a pleasure to do this with both of you.
Speaker 1:  Alright Hayden, you're gonna stick around for a minute 'cause we have a question
Speaker 1:  from The Vergecast hotline that you are the perfect person to answer. Jake,
Speaker 1:  you can go. We're gonna take a break. Thank you Beth. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  lot about ai. We got a bunch of good questions about AI and we're gonna talk
Speaker 1:  about one in particular. But first I just want to give a shout out to Remy
Speaker 1:  who sent us a very good question that included this paragraph. I wanted to
Speaker 1:  say, I love your AI coverage, especially since Hayden joined, who is a star.
Speaker 1:  Just wanted you, just wanted you to know that's so sweet. Shouts to Remy
Speaker 1:  who may or may not be Hayden's burner Gmail, but we'll, we'll talk about
Speaker 1:  that later. So the, let's do a question from the hotline as always. It's
Speaker 1:  Vergecast The Verge dot com is the email 8 6, 6 version one. One is the
Speaker 1:  hotline. You can call, you can text me, you can stop Hayden on the
Speaker 1:  street and yell questions at her, whatever you want. We love hearing all
Speaker 1:  of your questions. This one comes from, I believe it's pronounced
Speaker 1:  Philippo, and it says, I listened to David's answer to a listener's question
Speaker 1:  who asked if Apple might not even believe in ai? The answer was measured
Speaker 1:  and insightful as usual. Thank you. Philippo, this is not my burner Gmail
Speaker 1:  I should say, but it inspired one intuition. Shouldn't we differentiate much
Speaker 1:  more the term ai? Like literally use more words to describe
Speaker 1:  clearly the different applications and products it fuels slash enables Using
Speaker 1:  only the general AI term is, I feel doing us a disservice in terms of our
Speaker 1:  understanding of the technology it's value and use and separating buzz from
Speaker 1:  reality. This is the thing, Hayden, you, you And I have talked in bits and
Speaker 1:  pieces about for a long time, but I'm, I'm curious, you're the person on
Speaker 1:  our team who has to live in this space all day every day.
Speaker 1:  It really feels to me like we desperately need a new vocabulary to
Speaker 1:  talk about ai. Do you agree?
Speaker 13:  Yes, I really do because it is something that it, it's
Speaker 13:  tough because for me, like colloquially, you know, the public
Speaker 13:  understands things is just being ai. So I often have to write in
Speaker 13:  that context, you know, just AI and keeping it simple.
Speaker 13:  But I remember even when I started on this beat almost six years ago
Speaker 13:  when I would write articles about ai, and this was before, you know, generative
Speaker 13:  AI was as much of a thing, chat g PT wasn't out, et cetera. But when
Speaker 13:  I would write articles about ai, I remember when I would do my fact check
Speaker 13:  calls, researchers would be like, Hey, you know, you should really
Speaker 13:  specify the type of AI we're talking about here. AI is a catchall term.
Speaker 13:  It doesn't really mean anything anymore. It means everything, which means
Speaker 13:  it means nothing. I of course kind of did just have to say AI because
Speaker 13:  you know, if I get really jargony right away, no one's gonna know what I'm
Speaker 13:  talking about. But I do remember I had to write a lot of like
Speaker 13:  encyclopedia type articles defining a lot of different terms. And I think
Speaker 13:  that we need more of that. I think we need more mentions of
Speaker 13:  what the sub categories of AI really are.
Speaker 13:  You know, people are confused about a GI, they're confused about
Speaker 13:  super intelligence, they're confused about ai, they're confused about
Speaker 13:  deep learning, reinforcement learning, recursive
Speaker 13:  self-improvement, all these terms that really will help people have a
Speaker 13:  better understanding of how this technology works and
Speaker 13:  exactly how it responds to you and why it
Speaker 13:  responds the way it does. I think if we had a better vocabulary for
Speaker 13:  talking about ai, it would actually be really, really helpful for
Speaker 13:  combating, you know, some of the misconceptions about
Speaker 13:  AI that are out there right now with people kind of thinking sometimes their
Speaker 13:  emergent beings inside it or thinking that it knows more
Speaker 13:  than it does, or thinking that it's almost sometimes an oracle that can
Speaker 13:  predict certain things. Like is it a good pattern matcher? Yes.
Speaker 13:  And can it find amazing insights and trends within a large
Speaker 13:  amount of data and you know, give great answers. Yes. But
Speaker 13:  you know, with the rise of, you know, some of the mental health concerns
Speaker 13:  we've seen recently, I think that would be helped a lot if we could just
Speaker 13:  use the actual terms and define them on like, you know, how different models
Speaker 13:  are trained and why, and also these methods are changing
Speaker 13:  all the time. So it'd be great to just have kind of like a, you know, constantly
Speaker 13:  updating vocabulary, showing people how AI is
Speaker 13:  advancing and how fast it's moving and then exactly
Speaker 13:  how it works. Even though we don't know everything about how it works, we
Speaker 13:  can explain a lot more than is currently being explained.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, the, the struggle for me with all of this has been that the
Speaker 1:  solution just requires so much learning on the
Speaker 1:  part of the, the consumer, right? That like to
Speaker 1:  reckon with the differences in how these systems are trained,
Speaker 1:  it's just a lot to ask of people, right? And it's like, I remember we were
Speaker 1:  even going through this in like the early days of talking about virtual assistants
Speaker 1:  and that kind of thing where it's like, okay, I have to teach you the difference
Speaker 1:  between reinforcement learning and neural networks and
Speaker 1:  when those things overlap and when they don't. And it's like, I'm, I'm having
Speaker 1:  to sort of give myself and everybody else like a computer science degree
Speaker 1:  in order to understand how Google assistant works. And that is,
Speaker 1:  that's just a lot to ask. And I feel like we're still in that place where
Speaker 1:  it's like the only way to be more specific than AI is with
Speaker 1:  a sort of increasingly complex scientific terms. And
Speaker 1:  I just don't know that that's ever gonna work. And I think this is the thing
Speaker 1:  that we've struggled with is how do we talk about this stuff in a way that
Speaker 1:  is like you're saying, accessible and understandable that
Speaker 1:  doesn't feel like school, but is still accurate.
Speaker 1:  And I think, like, I know one thing we've talked a lot about here at The
Speaker 1:  Verge is, is when do we call something AI versus when do we
Speaker 1:  call it like a large language model versus when do we call it a chat bot,
Speaker 1:  right? Because like a thing I hate my, my least favorite thing
Speaker 1:  that everybody does in AI is refer to the AI as if it's like a
Speaker 1:  character. Oh yeah. That is not a thing. The AI does not
Speaker 1:  exist. It it, it is either some like interface on top of
Speaker 1:  ai, maybe it's a chat bot, maybe it's whatever. But the, the AI as
Speaker 1:  a, as a being is such a bad mental image for people to
Speaker 1:  have for all the reasons that you're talking about. Or
Speaker 13:  N
Speaker 1:  Ai Yeah. Or n ai, like any of these things, it is not, AI is
Speaker 1:  not an object and we should stop treating it as such, but it is really hard
Speaker 1:  to know what else to call it. Especially now it feels like in so many
Speaker 1:  ways that the toothpaste is outta the tube on this stuff and like
Speaker 1:  maybe that just is gonna be what it's called even though it's wrong, but
Speaker 1:  it feels wrong
Speaker 13:  For me it's about kind of peppering And I don't know if this is right, but
Speaker 13:  what I try to do is pepper in these types of definitions in pieces
Speaker 13:  that I write whenever I can as like a quick
Speaker 13:  parenthetical, you know, like when I define a GI in a
Speaker 13:  piece, like I can't go without, you know, doing a quick like parenthetical
Speaker 13:  phrase saying what that is. And you know, with reinforcement learning, deep
Speaker 13:  learning all these methods, it, it's helpful to just have a
Speaker 13:  quick like, you know, one sentence or like seven
Speaker 13:  word way of describing it, even if it's oversimplified that can kind
Speaker 13:  of help people understand what's really going on here and the different
Speaker 13:  ways in which the tech is advancing and how it changes and how it's trained
Speaker 13:  and all these things. I think it's hard because sometimes you do oversimplify
Speaker 13:  it and then people are like, well that's not 100% right. But also, okay,
Speaker 13:  you're trying to do it in like seven words, so you have to be accurate and
Speaker 13:  simplify without oversimplifying it. It's, it's tough but I think it's something
Speaker 13:  we can do if we just like start bringing these terms
Speaker 13:  into the public eye more. One example is large language models, right? I
Speaker 13:  remember back when I couldn't say that term without it being too jargony.
Speaker 13:  Totally. So I just have to say AI now large language models is
Speaker 13:  a household term. I think maybe I'm just in my own bubble, but I think it
Speaker 13:  is. And so I can say that without defining what that is now usually in an
Speaker 13:  article. And so I think we can get there with other terms. So
Speaker 13:  you know, hopefully we just keep building our vocabulary, do it a little
Speaker 13:  bit at a time and we get, you know, to where we are with large language
Speaker 13:  models, with other terms and we just kind of like increase public understanding
Speaker 13:  of this stuff. Because the cool thing is, like you said, I mean
Speaker 13:  consumers, we don't wanna put the burden on the consumer to, you know, go
Speaker 13:  to school basically and learn all this stuff. But the other cool thing is
Speaker 13:  that consumers do wanna know, you know, people are
Speaker 13:  super curious about this. And so I think with the combination of
Speaker 13:  people wanting to know more about what is and isn't
Speaker 13:  AI and what falls into every category and what's just data science and what's
Speaker 13:  just, if this then that rules and all these things and us being
Speaker 13:  able to, you know, give them like kind of simple explanations and then if
Speaker 13:  you wanna dive deeper, here's more I think we can get there. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Is there another term like LLMs? Like if you could just wish another one
Speaker 1:  into like mainstream acceptability that would make your life as a reporter
Speaker 1:  and writer easier, what would the next one be?
Speaker 13:  It's hard because it changes like by the month and by the year, you know,
Speaker 13:  it really does. Like I remember there was a time when
Speaker 13:  like deep learning would've been my choice and then I remember there was
Speaker 13:  a time when reinforcement learning would've been my choice. Mm. But
Speaker 13:  now I think it would be
Speaker 13:  recursive self-improvement. Ooh. So yeah, I think
Speaker 13:  it would be cool if people could know how these models are
Speaker 13:  making themselves better and also the societal
Speaker 13:  implications of that and the economic implications of that
Speaker 13:  and what that might mean for jobs and things like that. I'm hearing that
Speaker 13:  phrase a lot and it's something that I think it would be great if the
Speaker 13:  public could know more about. So I would say, yeah, for me, the phrase that
Speaker 13:  I would want to make a household name changes by the like three month period,
Speaker 13:  but right now it's that
Speaker 1:  I think recursive self-improvement is also like a very good memoir title
Speaker 1:  that you should maybe just lay claim to right now. Perfect.
Speaker 13:  If Hayden feels copyright it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I love, love it, love it. Alright Hayden, thank you as always, I appreciate
Speaker 1:  it.
Speaker 13:  Thanks.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast. Thank you to everyone who is on the
Speaker 1:  show today and thank you as always for watching and listening. If you have
Speaker 1:  thoughts or questions or feelings or want to just like call me
Speaker 1:  and say something really short and then hang up immediately just to prove
Speaker 1:  a point, you can always call the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one one. Send
Speaker 1:  us an email Vergecast at The Verge dot com. I wanna hear all of your summer
Speaker 1:  takes. Also, if you just have a feeling that is just burning up inside of
Speaker 1:  you, call me, hit us up And I will either
Speaker 1:  a hundred percent agree or a hundred percent disagree or just cancel you
Speaker 1:  entirely. We'll see what happens. Get at us. Like I said, please subscribe
Speaker 1:  to version history, the first eight episodes. The whole first season is gonna
Speaker 1:  be on The Verge feed. So if you're hearing or seeing this, odds are
Speaker 1:  you will encounter version history when it launches on October 5th. But also
Speaker 1:  please subscribe to the feed. That's an important thing that we look at in
Speaker 1:  terms of like whether we get to keep making this thing. So please subscribe.
Speaker 1:  I think you're gonna really like this show. Also, The Vergecast is The Verge
Speaker 1:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, and Travis Uck. We will all be back on
Speaker 1:  Friday to talk about whatever's going on in the A OI world because there's
Speaker 1:  always stuff going on in the AI world. We have some Google News coming, we
Speaker 1:  have some Amazon news coming next week. Pure chaos in the
Speaker 1:  tech industry right now. And we have an awful lot to talk about until then,
Speaker 1:  rock and Roll
Speaker 21:  And Doug
Speaker 22:  Limu