# Transcript
ID: a05bbe30-a6e6-4a1d-921a-8c886b0bdfd7
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-944293368521402032/-8255042202452313748/s93290-US-4092s-1759224942.mp3
Description: Sure, you could drive to the grocery store and to school. But wouldn’t you rather grab a few hundred of your friends and bike-bus everywhere? The Verge’s Andy Hawkins joins the show to tell us all about his adventures with electric cargo bikes, and why he thinks they’re the ride of the future. After that, Lauren Feiner calls in from just outside a courthouse in Virginia, where she’s watching the remedies trial in Google’s adtech monopoly case. Google already lost the case; what happens next is still anyone’s guess. Finally, David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about how to feel about summarizing YouTube videos with AI. The short version: you should feel a lot of things.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of bike buses, which are,
Speaker 1:  it turns out exactly what you think they are. I'm your friend David Pierce,
Speaker 1:  And I am sitting here doing a thing I never thought I would be doing, which
Speaker 1:  is updating and using the rabbit R one. This is
Speaker 1:  the truly terrible AI gadget that
Speaker 1:  somehow is still an ongoing concern. It's been like a year and a
Speaker 1:  half now, and they just put out a sort of fascinating
Speaker 1:  new software update for the thing that completely changes the interface.
Speaker 1:  It's all touch now. It has some new ideas about how to do like little apps
Speaker 1:  that you can make with prompts. The thing is still bad and you shouldn't
Speaker 1:  buy one. To be clear, I have one that is like unopened in a drawer over here
Speaker 1:  because I think someday it'll be like a museum piece of weird ai.
Speaker 1:  But I, we're still in this phase where I don't think anybody knows anything
Speaker 1:  about how AI gadgets are supposed to work, or even if they're going to be
Speaker 1:  a thing, And I confess as, as bad as this thing is, I, I
Speaker 1:  genuinely admire the hustle. But anyway, we are not here to talk about this
Speaker 1:  delightful little orange thing. We're gonna do two things On today's Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  First, we're gonna talk to Andy Hawkins about his experience with
Speaker 1:  electric cargo bikes and basically what it means to take your
Speaker 1:  car drives and turn them into bike rides. He is,
Speaker 1:  you will learn very passionate about this. We're gonna have some fun After
Speaker 1:  that. I'm gonna talk to Lauren Finer about what's going on in the Google
Speaker 1:  Ad Tech remedies trial. Google was declared a monopoly in ad
Speaker 1:  tech and now has to fight to see what's gonna happen next.
Speaker 1:  She's been in court all week. We're gonna talk about it. I'm very excited.
Speaker 1:  We also have a fun question from The Vergecast hotline. Lots of good stuff
Speaker 1:  to get to, but first I'm gonna make some apps on this
Speaker 1:  thing and tell you if it's any good. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Andy Hawkins is here. Hi, Andy. I'm
Speaker 7:  Here. Hello.
Speaker 1:  Andy. I have brought you here for a selfish reason. I, I just feel obligated
Speaker 1:  to tell you this right up front. Every once in a while, I bring a person
Speaker 1:  onto The Vergecast to solve a specific problem for me, specifically.
Speaker 1:  Okay. This problem that I'm having is that I cannot convince
Speaker 1:  my wife to allow me to buy a very expensive e-bike and use it
Speaker 1:  to carry my children and my stuff everywhere all of
Speaker 1:  the time. You have successfully done this in your life. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  I have brought you here to teach me your ways.
Speaker 7:  Well, I think maybe the first, the first problem that I'm detecting here
Speaker 7:  is that you are looking for your wife's approval. I, I never sought that.
Speaker 7:  I, I just ran rough shot over my wife's feelings
Speaker 7:  and her aspirations. No forgiveness,
Speaker 1:  Not permission. I love, I love this for you. Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  No, no, it, this is a problem that I, I hear a lot from
Speaker 7:  my friend group, my social circle, my neighbors.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's something that a lot of people have come to me with. It's, which
Speaker 7:  is that like, I wanna get a cargo bike, but I don't know if it
Speaker 7:  will act like can afford it, if it's gonna fit in with my lifestyle.
Speaker 7:  You know, drivers are crazy in my town, you know, they're
Speaker 7:  expensive. Where do I put it? There's, people seem to have like lots of
Speaker 7:  concerns about this purchase in their life, which is so fascinating
Speaker 7:  to me because you, you people will just get up and buy a
Speaker 7:  car, buy two cars Yeah. Without any hesitation, right? They'll, they'll just
Speaker 7:  be like, oh, I love Subaru. I'm just gonna get another Subaru. And I'll have
Speaker 7:  two Subarus. Because I think it's sort of a reflection of the world
Speaker 7:  that we live in, right? That we live in a world that is sort of built for
Speaker 7:  cars and for car drivers and for driving as sort of the primary
Speaker 7:  mode of transportation. And it's not built for, for e-bikes. And we're, and
Speaker 7:  we're looking for ways in which to kind of like shoehorn an e-bike into our
Speaker 7:  lives. Totally. And we have some concerns about that. So, yes. I'm just,
Speaker 7:  just, just to say that I hear this a lot from people. This
Speaker 1:  Actually makes me feel a lot better, I have to say. But, so you, you just
Speaker 1:  did a big story for The Verge about your adventures as a, as a cargo bike
Speaker 1:  guy. But I'm, I'm curious, sort of rewind a little bit for me. Like, you're
Speaker 1:  a, you're a car guy, like professionally,
Speaker 1:  you, you car for a living in, in some ways.
Speaker 1:  How did you become a bike guy? When, when did this start for you? I, I,
Speaker 7:  I've always been a bike guy and I've only just recently kind of like
Speaker 7:  been forced to become a car guy as the transportation editor. Okay. But the
Speaker 7:  bike guy is my, my default setting that's been been I
Speaker 1:  See, okay.
Speaker 7:  The way I've lived my life for, for a long time. I grew up in the suburbs,
Speaker 7:  you know, in the Midwest, riding my bike everywhere with my friends. And
Speaker 7:  it does feel like in some ways that, like we did have a little bit more free
Speaker 7:  range as kids growing up in the eighties and nineties to bike around
Speaker 7:  that kids these days don't seem to have, which we can
Speaker 7:  touch on. But yeah, I always been a bike guy, grew up biking in,
Speaker 7:  in the, in my, in my suburbs. And then I moved to New York and biked
Speaker 7:  all around New York. And now I move, I'm back in the suburbs again and I'm
Speaker 7:  like, oh man, I, I have to become a a an SUV guy now. But I,
Speaker 7:  I didn't want that to happen. And fortunately the timing was
Speaker 7:  great because cargo bikes have been really sort of on this
Speaker 7:  trajectory of popularity in the us They've been a, a thing in
Speaker 7:  Europe and China and elsewhere for a very long time. But I would
Speaker 7:  say prior to the pandemic, and then definitely over the course of the
Speaker 7:  pandemic, cargo bikes became a lot more popular. And then we're selling at
Speaker 7:  a, at a lot, at a, at a higher rate than they were before.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. And what, what makes a cargo bike? A cargo bike? Just to, just
Speaker 1:  to quickly define our terms here a little bit. Yes. You're specifically talking
Speaker 1:  about the thing you got is an electric cargo bike, And I think I know what
Speaker 1:  makes a bike electric, what makes a bike cargo.
Speaker 7:  So it is the ability to carry cargo, whether or not that is
Speaker 7:  items, grocery items, packages, whatnot, or children,
Speaker 7:  potentially even multiple children.
Speaker 1:  But we're not talking like little basket on the front. I can put a Trader
Speaker 1:  Joe's bag in. That's not that, that's not a cargo,
Speaker 7:  No, but there are cargo bikes that do feature a front bucket
Speaker 7:  that extends out past the handlebars that are called back
Speaker 7:  feets. It's a Dutch term. And that is one, one style, one
Speaker 7:  form factor of cargo bikes. Many other ones are, are sort of what,
Speaker 7:  what are called long tail cargo bikes. It's sort of an extended rear rack
Speaker 7:  on the bike that can support payload, a lot of weight
Speaker 7:  depending on the frame and, and whatnot. So yeah, it's just any
Speaker 7:  bike that has an electric battery and a motor and that can carry
Speaker 7:  a lot of cargo. And it's, it's been great. It's been great for my life. It's
Speaker 7:  been great for a lot of people's lives. It's allowed them to replace car
Speaker 7:  trips for errands for, for, you know, taking kids to,
Speaker 7:  you know, to school and to, to activities and, and friend and friend play
Speaker 7:  dates and things like that. So it's, it's really been a remarkable thing.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's honestly, it's, it's changed my life for the better. I am the
Speaker 7:  kind of guy who I'm concerned about things like climate change and
Speaker 7:  traffic safety because we live in a time in which, you know,
Speaker 7:  many more people are being hurt and injured in car accidents and car
Speaker 7:  crashes. And I think that one of the solutions to those things is just
Speaker 7:  taking more cars off the road and replacing them with more sustainable modes
Speaker 7:  of transportation. And the cargo bike is a, is a, is a great way to do that.
Speaker 1:  So why do you think cargo bikes have had such a huge rise in
Speaker 1:  the last few years? I mean, I think part of the reason I'm fascinated by
Speaker 1:  this space is I've been covering various versions of these like
Speaker 1:  last mile vehicles for forever, right? And I think for all the reasons you
Speaker 1:  just laid out the idea of I have somewhere to go that is
Speaker 1:  close by, that actually doesn't require my car, but literally
Speaker 1:  the only way I have to get there is my car is a, is a bad situation that
Speaker 1:  we have found ourselves in, in a sort of unique way, especially in the us.
Speaker 1:  And so I'm, I'm all four ways to solve that.
Speaker 1:  And you know, I've covered the weird like hoverboards
Speaker 1:  and the one wheels and the scooters. I got really into scooters for a really
Speaker 1:  long time. Yeah. And I will, I will go to that for scooters for forever.
Speaker 1:  But there's something about the cargo bike in
Speaker 1:  particular that feels like an answer to the question in,
Speaker 1:  in a different way. Like, why do you think that's the thing that really caught
Speaker 1:  on for people?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think it's a couple of sort of trend lines that are intersecting.
Speaker 7:  I think one of which is, you know, sort of the technology, right?
Speaker 7:  E-bike technology has improved. We've now are seeing,
Speaker 7:  you know, lithium ion batteries being developed that can power vehicles
Speaker 7:  for, you know, these, these, these e-bikes for, you know,
Speaker 7:  20, 30, 40, 50 miles of range. They're powerful.
Speaker 7:  You can get up to, you know, 20, 25 miles per hour.
Speaker 7:  And I, you know, I think as we saw sort of an influx of imports
Speaker 7:  from, from China mainly of e-bikes and people
Speaker 7:  realizing that this is something that they could, you know, start to use
Speaker 7:  as a way that, you know, it's not like a traditional bike. You don't end
Speaker 7:  up sweaty and bedraggled at the end of your ride because it, you know, sort
Speaker 7:  of takes a lot of that effort out of it. And yeah, I think a lot of, you
Speaker 7:  know, sort of people in the cycling community would see that it's cheating.
Speaker 7:  But, you know, my argument, my rebuttal to that is that, you know, transportation
Speaker 7:  doesn't need to be exercise, nor should it be exercise. You know, it's,
Speaker 7:  it's really just about getting from point A to point B in the, in the car,
Speaker 7:  in the e-bike. And especially the cargo bike is a great way to do that. It's
Speaker 7:  the utility of it, right? That it's, you know, it's sort of in this form
Speaker 7:  factor, but also you can take up, you could sort of throw on a lot of stuff.
Speaker 7:  You know, it's, it's more than just the passenger. When you can add passengers,
Speaker 7:  you can add cargo, you could add, you know, sort of all the things that you
Speaker 7:  need to carry that you would need to as part of, you know, the errands that
Speaker 7:  you're running. So the utility of it has been I think, a real positive aspect
Speaker 7:  of it. And then I think also the pandemic had a lot to do with it as well.
Speaker 7:  You know, we were all cooped up in our houses. We were looking for ways to
Speaker 7:  get out, socially distanced ways to get out of our houses. And e-bikes were
Speaker 7:  a great way to do that. So a lot of the sales were peaking
Speaker 7:  during the pandemic. They flatlined a little bit, but then they've sort of
Speaker 7:  since recovered in, in, in sales are backup to sort of
Speaker 7:  that pandemic level. So I think it's been a, a bunch of different things
Speaker 7:  there that have sort of led to this, this growing popularity of
Speaker 7:  electric cargo bikes.
Speaker 1:  I so envy people who picked up like active outdoor activities during the
Speaker 1:  pandemic. Like I just, I really earnestly admire all of those people. I
Speaker 1:  got like way too into one very specific
Speaker 1:  version of the FIFA video game. That's what I did during the pandemic. And
Speaker 1:  I learned how to juggle, like those are the, those were my pandemic hobbies.
Speaker 1:  It was,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Or the sourdough people, right? Like are they, do they still have their
Speaker 7:  sourdough?
Speaker 1:  What's going on with that? If I had put that into biking, everything would've
Speaker 1:  been better. So I'm curious for sort of your own experience. 'cause I
Speaker 1:  think I want to touch on a lot of what you said about the kind of like macro
Speaker 1:  way in which these fit into the world. But you've had this thing for a while.
Speaker 1:  You've been using it for a while. Like what, what's actually on the list
Speaker 1:  of like, things that a cargo bike has solved for you day to day?
Speaker 7:  It's really just been like an incredible, you know, thing in my life.
Speaker 7:  You know, we've, we're a one car household, which in the suburbs is really
Speaker 7:  hard to do. But having that cargo bike as a way to sort
Speaker 7:  of allow us to make those trips when my wife has the car or I
Speaker 7:  have the car, she's able to, to take the bike out or I'm able to take the
Speaker 7:  bike out and go pick up the kids or go to the grocery store or what have
Speaker 7:  you. And it's a way of sort of, you know, reducing our own carbon
Speaker 7:  footprint to some degree, which is, you know, I think pretty great.
Speaker 7:  I think it's, everyone's looking for ways in which to I think
Speaker 7:  drive less and to, you know, sort of be more climate
Speaker 7:  focused. And, and this has been our way of doing that.
Speaker 1:  How long did it take to redo your routines? Like, I,
Speaker 1:  I think about a while ago I bought, I bought a scooter And I was like, I'm,
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna be a person who just like takes a scooter to all of
Speaker 1:  the things. 'cause most of the things I need are too close to drive. Like,
Speaker 1:  it's gonna be great. And then I would forget, I would, I would find myself
Speaker 1:  in the car halfway to the grocery store and I'd be like, oh crap, I was supposed
Speaker 1:  to take the scooter. And there, I think I, the thing that I came away
Speaker 1:  from that experience with was just realizing how
Speaker 1:  car-centric everything is, like including our lives. And
Speaker 1:  like, did you, did you have to spend months sort of deliberately being like,
Speaker 1:  I am going to do this on the cargo bike before it felt like a natural part
Speaker 1:  of your routine?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I think that's, that's a really great question because it, it did
Speaker 7:  take I think a little bit of a psychological shift, right? That there was
Speaker 7:  a lot of stuff that we would probably just naturally have taken the car
Speaker 7:  out to do that I had to be like, okay, no, let's, let's take the cargo bike.
Speaker 7:  You know, let's sort of like try to figure a way to like repack the things
Speaker 7:  that we were gonna take with us if we were going to the town pool or we were
Speaker 7:  going to a playground or, you know, we were going to some sort of, you know,
Speaker 7:  afterschool activity or whatnot. It definitely took a little bit more, you
Speaker 7:  know, like it's, it's gonna get dark soon, right? We have to make sure we
Speaker 7:  have our lights and our reflector vests and all these other things to make
Speaker 7:  sure that cars can see us when we're out of the road. And I do think a lot
Speaker 7:  of that adjustment has to do with, you know, making sure that you feel safe
Speaker 7:  while doing that. Because so many people have have told me, you know, since
Speaker 7:  this video has come out and also just, you know, over, over the years of
Speaker 7:  covering this, this industry that they would love to adopt a cargo
Speaker 7:  bike, but they just personally don't feel safe enough doing it because that
Speaker 7:  where they live is just not, you know, not bike friendly, that the
Speaker 7:  drivers are particularly crazy. There's just not enough infrastructure around
Speaker 7:  to support that kind of lifestyle. And to that I say I, I
Speaker 7:  totally feel that And I understand where those people are coming from because
Speaker 7:  yes, broadly across the United States, it's, it's not really safe to,
Speaker 7:  to have a cargo bike or to bike in general as
Speaker 7:  part of your normal day-to-day lifestyle. And so
Speaker 7:  I would say that, you know, I found like a group of people in
Speaker 7:  my town in particular that were also very interested in biking. We
Speaker 7:  started a bike bus and that sort of created a community around cycling,
Speaker 7:  especially with kids to school every, every Friday. But
Speaker 7:  no, yeah, it's like you, you, you ride in a, in a big group, right? And the
Speaker 7:  sort of the idea being that there's safety in numbers, right? Because it
Speaker 7:  is kind of daunting when you're, you know, we've got little kindergartners
Speaker 7:  on their, on their bikes riding, you know, in the street
Speaker 7:  alongside of huge trucks and SUVs and buses and all of this
Speaker 7:  kind of stuff. But we're, you know, we're biking with them, you know, it's
Speaker 7:  a big group. We're all biking together, the kids are laughing and talking
Speaker 7:  amongst themselves. We were inspired by a man named Sam
Speaker 7:  Balto, who's since become a, a, a friend of mine who is a,
Speaker 7:  a, a PE teacher out in Portland, Oregon. And so he had a cargo bike. He
Speaker 7:  was taking his, his kids to school and decided, hey, what if other people
Speaker 7:  want a bike as well? And just started doing it on a weekly basis,
Speaker 7:  playing lots of fun music on the ride. They'll sometimes have,
Speaker 7:  you know, special guests come along. And
Speaker 7:  it really grew into like this incredible thing where he was having like hundreds
Speaker 7:  of kids ride ride with him. Oh wow. So we're like, oh, we could do that in
Speaker 7:  our town as well. So we started with just like five parents and their kids
Speaker 7:  biking to school. And now, you know, it's been three years of doing this
Speaker 7:  every Friday throughout the school year we have, you know, upwards
Speaker 7:  of 400 kids that ride to all seven schools in our town.
Speaker 7:  We have multiple routes, we have an interactive map on our
Speaker 7:  website and all this stuff. And it really is just sort of brought the town
Speaker 7:  together in a way that has been, I think, really positive. And you can just
Speaker 7:  see it in the kids' faces when they get to ride to school. You know,
Speaker 7:  we're blasting K-pop demon hunters and chapel Rowan and all the things that
Speaker 7:  they love. And I, it's just like they get a little physical
Speaker 7:  activity and they also get to experience the world outside of a car, right?
Speaker 7:  Because like so much of this is about, you know, long car lines
Speaker 7:  in some communities to drop it off and pick up kids. It's just such a a,
Speaker 7:  a depressing thing I think for so many parents. What's a way that we can
Speaker 7:  sort of make this a little bit more joyful and a little bit more, you know,
Speaker 7:  beneficial for, for, you know, community building? 'cause especially in
Speaker 7:  kids feel so isolated and lonely these days, and it's a
Speaker 7:  way of sort of bringing them together. And I do think honestly and truly
Speaker 7:  that the cargo bike was really an important factor in helping us sort
Speaker 7:  of build this, this thing that we did. That's
Speaker 1:  Really cool. I do think that interaction with like the rest of the road
Speaker 1:  is, is a big piece of the puzzle here. And, and you've touched on this a
Speaker 1:  little bit, but it seems to me that like what you're
Speaker 1:  describing is, is very familiar sounding to anyone who has like,
Speaker 1:  lived in sort of a, a bike centric city in Europe where like, everybody
Speaker 1:  bikes everywhere. Or like, I I think about the, the
Speaker 1:  countries in Asia where the, those like Vespa style scooters are absolutely
Speaker 1:  everywhere. And it's just the, this stuff is just much more sort of
Speaker 1:  intermingled and interactive. And in the US it is just cars. It's,
Speaker 1:  it's just cars. And so I think one of the
Speaker 1:  questions, and this is the thing I, I talked spent a lot of time thinking
Speaker 1:  about in talking to people about, with scooters in particular is like, yes,
Speaker 1:  there is a technology product problem here, but there's
Speaker 1:  also like a human social problem. Like, where do I write
Speaker 1:  this thing? Where do I put it? What's the right if I I'm, am
Speaker 1:  I supposed to be in the bike lane and are the people in the bike lane not
Speaker 1:  riding e-bikes allowed to be pissed at me for it? Or am I supposed to be
Speaker 1:  in the road and pissing off all the people who are in cars that wanna go
Speaker 1:  faster? Like I, I guess the problem with this is
Speaker 1:  there's no way to solve the problem without causing a problem. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But I, I do wonder, like, do you think we're making any kind of
Speaker 1:  progress figuring out how all of these different things are supposed to interact
Speaker 1:  with each other?
Speaker 7:  So it's been a really interesting phenomena because I do think that
Speaker 7:  one of, one of the aspects that's been really fascinating to watch with sort
Speaker 7:  of the, the rise in popularity of e-bikes is all of the tensions
Speaker 7:  that has, has resulted in that, right? Yeah. So for the longest time,
Speaker 7:  you know, the cities that did have bike lanes, they were the exclusive realm
Speaker 7:  of, you know, normal cyclists, right? The either the people who did it
Speaker 7:  recreationally or the people who did it for transportation. And then you
Speaker 7:  had sort of the, the rise of the delivery workers using e-bikes and
Speaker 7:  places like New York and even in the suburbs, like my suburb out here in
Speaker 7:  New Jersey, we have a lot of guys riding e-bikes, riding electric mopeds,
Speaker 7:  delivering food, and then became, you know, sort of like
Speaker 7:  the, the rise of the, you know, sort of the, I would call it the
Speaker 7:  e-bike teen. And the e-bike teen has, has,
Speaker 7:  has led to a lot of very
Speaker 7:  panicked Facebook posts, I would say across the country
Speaker 7:  as well as some, you know, some very like, you know,
Speaker 7:  desperate conversations on places like Nextdoor and other places like that
Speaker 7:  where everyone is now up in arms over these teenagers
Speaker 7:  riding very high powered electric
Speaker 7:  mopeds and sometimes even motorcycles in some cases.
Speaker 7:  And, And I do think that it, it has raised a lot of people's,
Speaker 7:  you know, concerns over safety. You know, you've, and
Speaker 7:  to which I would say it's good that kids are riding bikes, it's good
Speaker 7:  that they're riding e-bikes. They should be safe while doing it. They should
Speaker 7:  wear helmets and they should follow the, the, the rules of the road. But
Speaker 1:  What are the rules of the road? Like I, I don't know that it's as simple
Speaker 1:  as you just said it, right? Like, I was out the other day and there were
Speaker 1:  these two kids riding, I mean, they couldn't have been more than 12. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And if you had just shown me the things that they were riding, I would've
Speaker 1:  been like, that's a motorcycle. Yeah. Like, it just, yeah. It just is. And
Speaker 1:  so we're at this point now where like, I, I don't know where
Speaker 1:  you're supposed to be. I don't know how fast you're supposed to, I like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know whether to yell at this kid who's cutting me off on the street
Speaker 1:  while I'm, you know what I mean? Like Yeah. I think all of this stuff, and
Speaker 1:  especially once you get to these very powerful electric bikes that go, you
Speaker 1:  know, in some cases like 25 plus miles an hour, like you could make a pretty
Speaker 1:  compelling case that that's a car and should be treated like one
Speaker 7:  Or a motorcycle. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Or a motorcycle, right? And so I think all this, all these things are so
Speaker 1:  blurry and it feels like we, until we have some kind of answers, everybody's
Speaker 1:  gonna hate everybody.
Speaker 7:  I think it really exposes that there's this sort of, this huge gap in our
Speaker 7:  regulatory environment right now that if you just throw, you know,
Speaker 7:  pedals on something and ca you can, you can legally call it a bike. And it
Speaker 7:  doesn't matter if there's 750 watt or a thousand watt motor
Speaker 7:  underneath the thing. Sure. And that the, that the person using it will actually
Speaker 7:  never a end up actually pedalling that they can just use a throttle. I
Speaker 7:  think that there's this, there's a pretty solid argument that that is not
Speaker 7:  a bike that is a, a moped or a motorcycle and that it should be, you know,
Speaker 7:  you know, the rules that apply to mopeds and motorcycles should also apply
Speaker 7:  to, to this, to this vehicle, right? But that's not the case, right? Because
Speaker 7:  we, there's this, there's this giant loophole that exists and the
Speaker 7:  regulators are not keeping up with it. So, And I do
Speaker 7:  think that a, aside from sort of like the consumer safety aspect of it all,
Speaker 7:  the infrastructure also is a huge piece that we're lacking
Speaker 7:  towns today. There's, you know, it takes years and years and years to get
Speaker 7:  anything protected infrastructure wise built in any kind of town because
Speaker 7:  it has to be endlessly debated. There has to be 10,000 community
Speaker 7:  meetings, you know, and everyone is so concerned about parking and the
Speaker 7:  loss of, you know, space for cars. But fundamentally, we've already given
Speaker 7:  over all of the space that we have to cars. And we're gonna have to take
Speaker 7:  some of that back if we're gonna have enough infrastructure to support all
Speaker 7:  of these new rider and these new vehicles that are cropping up. So that's
Speaker 7:  something that I talked about in the video with some of the e-bike folks
Speaker 7:  that I reached out to. And they, they acknowledged that the little space
Speaker 7:  that has been allocated to bikes is now pa you know,
Speaker 7:  it, it's at capacity. And we need to either figure out how to get
Speaker 7:  more space so that there can be both enough room for the
Speaker 7:  e-bikes and also the analog bikes and for the drivers, because we
Speaker 7:  fundamentally just need to get everyone out of each other's way. Right? The
Speaker 7:  cars, the cars want their own way. The bikes want their own way. And
Speaker 7:  when they all start mixing and intermingling, that's where
Speaker 7:  danger comes from. And, and, and people get injured and people get killed,
Speaker 7:  especially children and, and teenagers. So I, I do think
Speaker 7:  that we are not prepared at the moment.
Speaker 7:  You're starting to see more towns that are
Speaker 7:  committed to making themselves more bikeable. That was some of the, that
Speaker 7:  that I, I, I found in the research that more towns
Speaker 7:  have become more bikeable, but there's still a long ways to go. And
Speaker 7:  I do have concerns that, you know, sort of like what is safe today
Speaker 7:  is is only gonna get worse if we just keep ignoring this problem. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Well one of the reasons I think cargo bikes are specifically interesting
Speaker 1:  on this front is that there's something about doing it
Speaker 1:  in a way that is explicitly useful that I think changes the
Speaker 1:  conversation in actually really productive way. And so, like in the town
Speaker 1:  I live in, in Virginia
Speaker 1:  last year, 2024, they did a big project to
Speaker 1:  expand and essentially block off a bunch of bike lanes, right? They just
Speaker 1:  put up those like little white poles to just put a little space between the
Speaker 1:  bike lane and the cars and people flipped out and, and it's,
Speaker 1:  and and of course they do, right? Like everybody loses their mind about everything.
Speaker 1:  But, but the one piece of the argument that I thought was so interesting
Speaker 1:  on the pro car lobby was essentially, I, I'm in my
Speaker 1:  car because I need to go somewhere and you're gonna make traffic worse for
Speaker 1:  me so that some, you know, some loser on a bike
Speaker 1:  can, can have their delightful outdoor exercise. And I like, I think to some
Speaker 1:  extent that's like disingenuous And I think study after study has proven
Speaker 1:  that it doesn't actually increase traffic. So like that is what it is. But
Speaker 1:  I think the idea of, of a bike like this, that is,
Speaker 1:  it is, it is, I'm gonna the grocery store in my car and you're going to the
Speaker 1:  grocery store on the bike and actually you're not, you're not out for a joy
Speaker 1:  ride. You are out to do something. And the only difference in our goals is
Speaker 1:  the mode of transportation we used to get there. I actually think like resets
Speaker 1:  some of that debate in a way that is really productive. And so I
Speaker 1:  wonder if the rise in all this is actually gonna make that stuff easier to
Speaker 1:  talk about.
Speaker 7:  I, I completely agree with you And I, And I can tell you from, from personal
Speaker 7:  experience that that's the case. Because I feel like if I was going
Speaker 7:  into my town council meetings during the public comment period and talking
Speaker 7:  about we need more public, you know, more bike lanes and more protected infrastructure
Speaker 7:  And I was wearing spandex and like racing gear and like
Speaker 1:  Just like, get a job.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They would laugh me out of the room and they'd say, you know, forget
Speaker 7:  this guy. But if I, but instead I go in wearing my bike bus vest
Speaker 7:  And I'm dressed normally And I have my kids with me and I'm like, Hey,
Speaker 7:  here's my kids. We bike to school every Friday. We think it's a great time.
Speaker 7:  We wish that we could do this more often, you know, all the time.
Speaker 7:  And it would be great if the, if you would support lower speed limits,
Speaker 7:  you know, livable streets protected infrastructure. And that has had
Speaker 7:  a serious impact. It has had an effect. We have
Speaker 7:  gotten through, I think, to some of the people who are in charge through,
Speaker 7:  through the, through the presentation of our argument. I feel like because
Speaker 7:  we are saying we wanna use this for the utility aspect,
Speaker 7:  for the, the, the social aspect because we just wanna get around in
Speaker 7:  a way that doesn't contribute to climate change and that's better for everybody
Speaker 7:  around us. And that takes cars off the roads. They, they, they, I think that
Speaker 7:  that that argument, it really has a lot more sway. And so I do think
Speaker 7:  cargo bikes have a way to do that as well because they, you know, that's
Speaker 7:  not something that you're just, you're using out of a, a sense of recreation.
Speaker 7:  You're using it out of a sense of utility, out of a sense of, you know, like
Speaker 7:  how can I make my life a little bit better while using cars less? And I do
Speaker 7:  think that that's been sort of a real game changer.
Speaker 7:  And I feel in sort of a lot of these local conversations that are
Speaker 7:  being replicated and going on all over the country right now.
Speaker 1:  I do remember one really eye-opening part of my brief
Speaker 1:  schooner opening experience was
Speaker 1:  suddenly you, you've like, noticed differently how annoying it is
Speaker 1:  to drive all the time in a way that I think is actually,
Speaker 1:  we just don't notice it 'cause we just do it, right? Yeah. It's just life.
Speaker 1:  And I think when you suddenly are sort of pulled out of the amount of time
Speaker 1:  you spend looking for a parking spot and then looking for your
Speaker 1:  car and sitting in traffic and waiting for red lights and other cars are
Speaker 1:  idiots, like just having your eyes open to that a little
Speaker 1:  ha made everything else seem more appealing that it's like, oh
Speaker 1:  sure, I'm gonna have to do like a little bit more work to like find the lights
Speaker 1:  so that I can get home afterwards. But I get to park my bike right
Speaker 1:  out front of the damn grocery store. Yeah. And that is a
Speaker 1:  pretty big win. Alright, I need to let you go here in a minute, but first
Speaker 1:  you, you've now had a lot of experience with this. So if I'm, if I'm shopping
Speaker 1:  for a cargo bike, which I hopefully will be very soon, as soon as Anna hears
Speaker 1:  this and agrees that this is a terrific idea and good for the world,
Speaker 1:  what's, what's the most important thing, like having used one of these for
Speaker 1:  now? Like what matters most if you're trying to buy a cargo bike?
Speaker 7:  I, I would say maintenance and repairability. Making sure that whichever
Speaker 7:  company you're buying from that has some sort of either a relationship with
Speaker 7:  a local bike shop and a way that you can get your bike tuned up and
Speaker 7:  repaired. Because you know, the, the thing about e-bikes and especially cargo
Speaker 7:  bikes, they get used a lot more than regular bikes. That's sort of like their
Speaker 7:  magic power. Their secret power is that you use them all the time, so they
Speaker 7:  wear down a little bit. They're gonna need to get tuned up, make sure that
Speaker 7:  your local bike shop is able to do that. And then I would also just say,
Speaker 7:  if you have a little bit of money to spend and you don't mind
Speaker 7:  shooting for something that a little bit topnotch, anything with a Bosch
Speaker 7:  motor is pretty incredible. That company has a fantastic
Speaker 7:  service reputation. Their, their e-bikes are
Speaker 7:  the motors that they, that they build are really far and away a lot better
Speaker 7:  than than most others. So those are the things I would say to look for.
Speaker 1:  That's good to know. Do you think there's a path towards these things getting
Speaker 1:  less expensive? I think I've been waiting for years as
Speaker 1:  they've risen and lithium ion technology has gotten great and
Speaker 1:  EVs are everywhere. I've been waiting for these things to sort of hit a,
Speaker 1:  a price point that feels plausible and like, I
Speaker 1:  know you're gonna say, well, it's cheaper than buying a car. And like, I'm
Speaker 1:  sure that's true. Yes. These are really expensive bikes. Yeah. Like, do you,
Speaker 1:  are we, are we, is there a glimmer of hope that it might get
Speaker 1:  more affordable over time? So
Speaker 7:  There are definitely a range. You can get bikes that are more budget
Speaker 7:  and affordable that, you know, won't break the bank. You can get
Speaker 7:  a a, a good car, a decent sized cargo bike for, you know, I would say around
Speaker 7:  $2,000. You don't have to spend six, $7,000 on the premium model.
Speaker 7:  But that said, you know, like I said, make sure there's a an
Speaker 7:  adequate customer service and maintenance and repair and and repair system
Speaker 7:  in place. But yeah, I I, I, I do have concerns because
Speaker 7:  the vast majority of bikes come from China. I think like over
Speaker 7:  95% of bikes are built in, made in China. And I think as
Speaker 7:  long as we have this tariff structure and trade war situation going on,
Speaker 7:  I, I don't see a, a lot of hope for the future. There have been legislatively
Speaker 7:  some efforts to kind of try to bring onshore some of that bike
Speaker 7:  manufacturing offer some credits and some incentives to people to
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. Coming to you live from a
Speaker 1:  Panera outside of a courthouse in Alexandria, Virginia,
Speaker 1:  where it is time for Google to fight for its life in the ad
Speaker 1:  tech world. Lauren Finers here. Hi Lauren. Thanks
Speaker 10:  For having me.
Speaker 1:  So you're on lunch break. Describe us the scene, where are you, what are
Speaker 1:  you doing? You're on audio only. Just paint us a word picture of your life
Speaker 1:  right this second.
Speaker 10:  Yes, I am outside the beautiful Panera in
Speaker 10:  Alexandria, Virginia, which has really great broccoli cheddar
Speaker 10:  soup. That's
Speaker 1:  True.
Speaker 10:  And you know, it's, it's pretty nice out here And I can use my phone. So
Speaker 10:  that's something that I can't do inside the courtroom.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So this is, I just wanna say just an incredibly rude
Speaker 1:  thing that, that this courthouse is doing to you.
Speaker 1:  You And I have both spent a lot of time in courtrooms over the last couple
Speaker 1:  of years. Yes. Covering Google trials. You unfortunately, much more than
Speaker 1:  me. But the thing where you can like
Speaker 1:  sit in a media room and watch a stream of it while you're on your computer.
Speaker 1:  Nice, lovely. Delightful. Totally manageable. The thing where they like
Speaker 1:  scream at you until you turn off all of your devices and you sit and you
Speaker 1:  write with a pen on paper, like a, like our
Speaker 1:  ancestors did just cruel and mean And I did not appreciate it.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. It it's pretty archaic, but yeah. Yeah. I'm not a fan,
Speaker 1:  But, so the, the trial that you're in right now is the remedies
Speaker 1:  trial for the Google Ad Tech case. And this is not
Speaker 1:  the other Google antitrust case, it's the other other Google
Speaker 1:  antitrust case. But just real quick for, for people who have not been
Speaker 1:  following the twist and turns of, of the ad tech thing, kind of catch us
Speaker 1:  up to the beginning of this particular trial. Like
Speaker 1:  how in the, give us the sort of CliffNotes versions of what this fight has
Speaker 1:  been about.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, so I think the Google antitrust trial that most people
Speaker 10:  are will remember is the one over search, where recently we got the
Speaker 10:  court ruling saying that Google doesn't have to spin out Chrome
Speaker 10:  in order to remedy its search monopoly. That's a separate case.
Speaker 10:  This case was filed during the Biden administration
Speaker 10:  and is about Google's ad tech monopoly. So basically
Speaker 10:  Google owns a series of tools
Speaker 10:  that work in different sides of the ad buying and selling
Speaker 10:  market. And the judge has found that Google
Speaker 10:  monopolized two markets with two of its tools
Speaker 10:  and also illegally tied together those tools. And why does any of this
Speaker 10:  matter? This all sounds really complicated. Basically
Speaker 10:  I think, you know, the thing I often remind myself as I'm sitting there
Speaker 10:  listening to all of these really complicated terms and acronyms
Speaker 10:  is really what this whole case is about is
Speaker 10:  the revenue stream that funds a lot of journalism and a lot
Speaker 10:  of websites across the internet. So the, the
Speaker 10:  portion of advertising we're talking about is what is referred to
Speaker 10:  in the trial as open web display ads, which are
Speaker 10:  those ads that appear in kind of like boxes on
Speaker 10:  websites you visit, like probably in the middle of a page or on the side
Speaker 10:  of a page of like the New York Times for example. Or you know,
Speaker 10:  some other publisher site. And you might be thinking those are really annoying,
Speaker 10:  but they are something that is an important revenue stream for a lot of
Speaker 10:  publishers.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think that the, the thing you said is, is important to keep
Speaker 1:  remembering that Google already lost this case, right? That that yeah,
Speaker 1:  they, they, they will inevitably appeal and it's weird that we have to go
Speaker 1:  through the remedies before they can get to the appeal, but there's a lot
Speaker 1:  of like logistical nonsense in all of this stuff. But
Speaker 1:  as with the search trial, Google lost and the question now is,
Speaker 1:  is what do we do about it? And so the trial is
Speaker 1:  now a few days old And I think you've gotten to get a real sense of what
Speaker 1:  both sides want to do here. So let's start with the government. What does
Speaker 1:  the government at this moment think the right answer is at the end
Speaker 1:  of this trial?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, so at a high level, the government wants to
Speaker 10:  impose both some behavioral changes on Google and what
Speaker 10:  it's allowed to do, not allowed to do in terms of its use of ad tech
Speaker 10:  tools. And then it also wants to impose what are called structural
Speaker 10:  remedies or what colloquially we'd call a breakup. So it wants to do
Speaker 10:  a few different things. And basically the judge found that Google illegally
Speaker 10:  monopolized the markets for two basically publisher side
Speaker 10:  tools. So you have the market for publisher ad servers, which
Speaker 10:  Google's double click for publishers or DFP operates in.
Speaker 10:  And that is a tool that publishers use to basically manage
Speaker 10:  their inventory, manage those boxes on their website that they're selling
Speaker 10:  for advertising. And then it also monopolize the market
Speaker 10:  for ad exchanges. And that's a tool that basically
Speaker 10:  publishers use to get bids from advertisers
Speaker 10:  that want to place ads on their website. So it's like the exchange where
Speaker 10:  literally these transactions are kind of meeting in the middle.
Speaker 1:  Right. And that's, it's worth saying that that's like, that's two out of
Speaker 1:  the three parts of the process. And so, right, like the, the way that I think
Speaker 1:  I've come to understand it is basically there's, there's how the advertisers
Speaker 1:  say what they want to buy, there's how the people with ad space
Speaker 1:  publishers and whatnot say what they have available. And then there's the
Speaker 1:  thing in the middle that connects buyers and sellers. And the, the argument
Speaker 1:  the government made the whole time was that Google is the most popular and
Speaker 1:  important player in all three of these things and it uses that power to make
Speaker 1:  all three of those things more expensive and worse to enrich Google. And
Speaker 1:  the fact that it lost on two of the three parts of the puzzle
Speaker 1:  is a pretty big deal. Right? Like, it, it seems like to me at least
Speaker 1:  coming out of that trial, it was like, oh, Google lost this in a
Speaker 1:  pretty meaningful way. Right. Is that how it felt to you? Okay. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  No, definitely. And I, we should say that, you know, Google did
Speaker 10:  win on one count about its buyer side tools,
Speaker 10:  the advertiser side tools where the judge said that the
Speaker 10:  DOJ didn't prove that it had a monopoly on that side of the market. But
Speaker 10:  you know, that side of the market is still obviously relevant to how
Speaker 10:  these other tools work because you know, part of the issue
Speaker 10:  is that the judge found that Google illegally tied together its
Speaker 10:  publisher ads or DFP and adx, it's ad
Speaker 10:  exchange and ADX has unique access to
Speaker 10:  Google's buy side of the platform as well.
Speaker 1:  Right. And the, the government's case is basically like
Speaker 1:  you own all three of these things, you should not be allowed to own all three
Speaker 1:  of these things. And so we are going to take at least one, but maybe
Speaker 1:  two of them away from you and thus there will be more competition. Right.
Speaker 1:  Like is it, it's kind of, is it kind of that straightforward?
Speaker 10:  Pretty much. There's a little bit of complexity. So I think the most straightforward
Speaker 10:  is that they want to have Google divest adx, it's ad exchange
Speaker 10:  that sits in the middle there and then it says After
Speaker 10:  that we also want Google to have to open source
Speaker 10:  what it's calling the final auction logic that sits within
Speaker 10:  DFP. Oh interesting. And so that's also a structural remedy.
Speaker 10:  And basically what that means is that if DFP is
Speaker 10:  where the final decision happens of who is
Speaker 10:  going to get to place this ad on the publisher website. So you
Speaker 10:  have bids often from other exchanges that might come through with thing
Speaker 10:  called pre-bid or header bidding. And then you have a, gets
Speaker 10:  to decide if it's gonna bid. And then you also have what's called direct
Speaker 10:  demand, which is, you know, deals that had already been negotiated
Speaker 10:  and the publisher has to decide, you know, when it's gonna place those.
Speaker 10:  And that final decision between those three things happens
Speaker 10:  inside of DFP, which publishers say is basically a black
Speaker 10:  box and they don't know why anyone wins or loses besides, you know,
Speaker 10:  on price.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So you, you mentioned obviously this is a different trial from the
Speaker 1:  other Google trial And I think you And I have both had sort of
Speaker 1:  beaten into our heads the idea that one trial is not necessarily indicative
Speaker 1:  or predictive of another even when they're happening simultaneously. But
Speaker 1:  it does feel like the, the bones of what the government is asking for is
Speaker 1:  the same in both cases where the, the one thing is like, okay, you have to,
Speaker 1:  you have to divest the thing that makes you powerful or at least one of the
Speaker 1:  things that makes you powerful and then you have to give everyone
Speaker 1:  kind of the secret sauce. Right? And this is a big thing in, in the search
Speaker 1:  trial too, right? Was the idea that like, actually what other
Speaker 1:  search engines need is Google's ranking data and, and some
Speaker 1:  like real transparency into how Google actually
Speaker 1:  built the thing that is so successful so that they can go and do it too.
Speaker 1:  And Google fought that tooth and nail and basically Google's argument
Speaker 1:  in the search case was like, actually there's tons of competition, nothing's
Speaker 1:  wrong, you're all idiots, everything's fine. Is that Google's argument here
Speaker 1:  too,
Speaker 10:  In a way? I'd say it's a little bit different here in the sense that I think
Speaker 10:  Google has, you know, some of their behavioral remedies look somewhat
Speaker 10:  similar to the governments. I I'd say, you know, there's definitely significant
Speaker 10:  differences. Just
Speaker 1:  The fact that there are behavioral remedies in Google's mind is is something
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Yeah. I think like in the search case it was more like, we'll do
Speaker 10:  we'll stop doing these sorts of contracts that were found to be
Speaker 10:  illegal.
Speaker 1:  They took the word exclusive out of some contracts and were like, is that
Speaker 1:  enough?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. Here they would be, I'd say somewhat
Speaker 10:  substantially changing the ways that its ad tools bid into
Speaker 10:  different places and it would change a good amount of processes, open things
Speaker 10:  up a bit more, but not as far as the government wants to go.
Speaker 10:  And I should also say that a contingency that the DOJ has is that
Speaker 10:  they wanna reserve the right to force Google to also divest
Speaker 10:  DFP if it's other remedies don't do enough.
Speaker 1:  Got it. Okay.
Speaker 10:  But here I'd say that, you know, different from the search case,
Speaker 10:  the tools that it's trying to get Google to
Speaker 10:  divest or have really been central to the case throughout where
Speaker 10:  during the search trial, you know, Chrome was obviously an important
Speaker 10:  place where search is distributed, but it wasn't like the
Speaker 10:  central tool that was like at issue in the trial.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This would be much closer to if the search app was like, or the search
Speaker 1:  trial was demanding that Google sell search. Like that's, yeah.
Speaker 1:  That way it's much more direct in that sense. And I think that that
Speaker 1:  might be why it has always felt like Google is on more
Speaker 1:  aggressive defense on this one because it is like you're not just
Speaker 1:  trying to kind of prop up competitors and, and you know,
Speaker 1:  slap us on the wrist for bad conduct. You're trying to take away
Speaker 1:  the thing that makes us all of our money. Like this is, you know, you mentioned
Speaker 1:  this is, this is how a lot of the money moves around the internet. This is
Speaker 1:  also how Google makes a lot of its money. Yeah. This is like, it does a lot
Speaker 1:  of, you know, first party ads and stuff, but this is like a, a true money
Speaker 1:  machine for Google and has been for a really long time and
Speaker 1:  the way that this stuff works is a huge economy and so far the biggest
Speaker 1:  beneficiary of it has been Google. And so yeah, it's
Speaker 1:  just, it's just been fascinating to me to see Google seem less worried about
Speaker 1:  losing Chrome than it seems about losing adx. But I'm actually curious on
Speaker 1:  that front, what it has felt like in the courtroom. 'cause you've now been
Speaker 1:  in both of the remedies trials and you've gotten a sense sort of the,
Speaker 1:  the vibes and the feelings coming from both sides.
Speaker 1:  What has this one been like compared to the search trial? How does it feel
Speaker 1:  just listening to the people talk in the courtroom?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think that's an interesting question. You know, it's obviously the
Speaker 10:  different attorneys have, you know, somewhat different styles. So there's
Speaker 10:  a little bit of just that probably contributes to it. But, you know, I think
Speaker 10:  this is a case where the divestiture of Chrome
Speaker 10:  maybe felt, you know, I don't know if this was a feeling that was coming
Speaker 10:  from within the courtroom or just a general sense of, you know, it,
Speaker 10:  it's such a big ask and it's such a big part of the business and that would
Speaker 10:  change so much. So I think just the scale of that felt different in a way.
Speaker 10:  Although I think, you know, it, it feels possibly
Speaker 10:  like this might be a more attainable ask for the government in this case.
Speaker 10:  So in a way it feels like there's a lot of practicalities
Speaker 10:  being discussed about how this would work. And you know, I
Speaker 10:  think something that I've been thinking over the past few days is there's
Speaker 10:  times where I almost have to remind myself like what you said
Speaker 10:  earlier, David, of like Google did lose at least most of this case,
Speaker 10:  right? And I think the Google attorneys at times are, you
Speaker 10:  know, kind of, they're doing an a decent
Speaker 10:  job of kind of making you forget that in a sense,
Speaker 10:  because totally we're talking about, you know, I, I think there's suggestions
Speaker 10:  of what would be fair to make Google do and you know, how much engineering
Speaker 10:  work would be involved in some of the remedies that the DOJ proposed. But
Speaker 10:  you know, we also have to remember that Google lost this case
Speaker 10:  because it was engaged in anti-competitive behavior for
Speaker 10:  a decade. And Google is also arguing things like that
Speaker 10:  this whole category of advertising is declining. But,
Speaker 10:  you know, some of the, the witnesses for the DOJ are saying, well
Speaker 10:  yeah, because it's been a market that's been dominated by one
Speaker 10:  player and you have to go through this one player's tools to do
Speaker 10:  these transactions. So it's less attractive to a lot of
Speaker 10:  stakeholders and it's, you know, not a place that people have
Speaker 10:  been wanting to innovate or invest in because the
Speaker 10:  sense is that, you know, all road roads lead back to Google.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, actually I, I was curious about this, there was this whole sort of
Speaker 1:  kerfuffle at the very beginning of this because Google said an a legal filing
Speaker 1:  essentially in as many words that the open web is dying. And part of their
Speaker 1:  defense is who cares? The open web is dying. And
Speaker 1:  then they went back and amended it to be like, no, no, no, no, just the advertising
Speaker 1:  market on the open. And it's like, well first of all those are the same thing.
Speaker 1:  And second of all, you said what you said friend os has
Speaker 1:  that come up? Like has, has this sort of existential crisis of the internet
Speaker 1:  been part of the conversation this week? That
Speaker 10:  Hasn't really come up directly. Yeah, I don't know. You know, it's hard
Speaker 10:  to know what Google really meant in that filing in the first place. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  they did revise it to say, I think open web display advertising, which is
Speaker 10:  like the main term that is being used in this case and to describe this
Speaker 10:  like segment of advertising. But yeah, I think it's come up
Speaker 10:  in the sense that, you know, Google wants to point out that
Speaker 10:  this category of ads is on the decline and you know, maybe
Speaker 10:  this won't even be relevant in several years. And of course, you know, we're
Speaker 10:  hearing about AI and what role does AI play, but really
Speaker 10:  not, not at all to the extent that we heard about AI in the Google search
Speaker 10:  remedies trial, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. AI was, Google's whole defense in the search remedies trial was that
Speaker 1:  none of this matters because AI is making the, even if we did do all
Speaker 1:  of this for 20 years, it doesn't matter anymore because AI is so important
Speaker 1:  and so powerful that it's upending the market anyway. And I think to a large
Speaker 1:  extent, judge Meta in that case was sympathetic to that.
Speaker 1:  And I think one of the things I've been thinking a lot about this week is
Speaker 1:  that the, the listening to the questions that the judge
Speaker 1:  was asking in that case actually gave a lot of
Speaker 1:  information away about what was gonna happen in that case. And he was asking
Speaker 1:  a lot of questions about what overreach would look like and, and whether
Speaker 1:  divesting things was actually gonna accomplish the things that they claim
Speaker 1:  to be accomplishing. So it makes me wonder, what,
Speaker 1:  what is the judge saying? What kind of questions is the judge asking this
Speaker 1:  week? Has anything kind of piqued your interest?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. I, I think she's asked some really interesting questions. You
Speaker 10:  know, she has made it very clear that she really wants to hear
Speaker 10:  from technical experts about the feasibility of this. And I think
Speaker 10:  especially the DOJs breakup proposals and you know, what would be
Speaker 10:  involved here. And you know, when one industry expert was on the
Speaker 10:  stand, she kind of was dismissive of it and said, you know,
Speaker 10:  this is window dressing. You don't need to concern yourself with window
Speaker 10:  dressing. Speaking to the attorneys. She's kind of done with the industry
Speaker 10:  witnesses who are just testifying about the impact on them because she heard
Speaker 10:  a lot of that in the liability trial. So she really wants to get
Speaker 10:  down to the nitty gritty. And I think, you know, there's been questions
Speaker 10:  that are probably good for Google, good
Speaker 10:  for the DOJ in maybe relatively equal measure.
Speaker 10:  You know, at one point she kind of said something like, the devil
Speaker 10:  is in the details and worried that the, you know,
Speaker 10:  actual implementation of the technical things here
Speaker 10:  would be a lot more complicated than what's being presented
Speaker 10:  and wondering if the user experience might be different if some
Speaker 10:  of these tools are migrated to another buyer, for example. But
Speaker 10:  we've also heard her ask today about, you know, how
Speaker 10:  exactly it would work to open source the final auction logic
Speaker 10:  and where that would live and getting an understanding of like what that
Speaker 10:  actually involves. And I think one thing that came up yesterday that
Speaker 10:  was really interesting was there was a Google witness on the stand
Speaker 10:  who helped craft Google's remedies proposals.
Speaker 10:  And this executive also had been involved
Speaker 10:  in a couple of projects that Google did to analyze potentially
Speaker 10:  spinning out atex and you know, kind of doing some of the structural things
Speaker 10:  that the DOJ is talking about in slightly different ways.
Speaker 10:  And Google found that they actually considered shutting down
Speaker 10:  ATX altogether, right? And that seemed to pique the judge's interest. And
Speaker 10:  she asked, well, wouldn't that be a very simple and elegant solution here?
Speaker 10:  Because the Google executive was raising the concern of, you know, who's
Speaker 10:  gonna buy ATX and doesn't just recreate the problem if another ad exchange
Speaker 10:  buys it or another big tech company buys it. So, you know that
Speaker 10:  that was a really interesting thing, especially because that's not even
Speaker 10:  something the DOJ is asking for here.
Speaker 1:  So rather than force them to sell it, just just shut it down altogether.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, because you know, there're,
Speaker 1:  That would be
Speaker 10:  Fascinating. It would because there are actually a lot of ad exchanges
Speaker 10:  that are out there that have testified in this trial, right? It's just that
Speaker 10:  they don't have the same access to Google demand as ADX
Speaker 10:  does. And you know, it, it's different from the publisher ad servers
Speaker 10:  where Google is pretty much the only player in that market,
Speaker 1:  Right? Yeah. And I think that's, that's again, a key difference between
Speaker 1:  this trial and, and the search trial, right? So much of the search trial
Speaker 1:  hinged on why are there no other good players in this
Speaker 1:  market? Like why is it impossible to build a successful search engine? And
Speaker 1:  I just like, I, I will never be able to get Satya Nadella, Microsoft CEO
Speaker 1:  out of my head on the stand saying, I would give you all of this
Speaker 1:  for free just to have the query data. And like every, we are all so far
Speaker 1:  behind now, there's not a chance anybody can catch up. This is different
Speaker 1:  in that it does seem like it would be more straightforward to
Speaker 1:  just blow the market open and say, well everybody, there are a million potential
Speaker 1:  competitors out there, we're just gonna give them the same access that you
Speaker 1:  have. And then we'll have a competitive market. Like I just, I grant that
Speaker 1:  I'm very unsophisticated when it comes to how the ad tech market works, but
Speaker 1:  it does seem to me that it would be an easier thing to just
Speaker 1:  sort of throw the doors open on this one than it would be to like
Speaker 1:  gin up a way to create 10 new search engines from scratch.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. I think at a high level that that's pretty much correct. I think,
Speaker 10:  you know, there are things in place here that just, you know, there, there
Speaker 10:  need to be different pathways opened and that's kind of what they're looking
Speaker 10:  at how exactly to do that. But some of the actual tools do
Speaker 10:  exist.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So what do you think there is to learn from the other trial? Is
Speaker 1:  there, is there, obviously, again, these are different things, different
Speaker 1:  judges, every trial is different, on and on and on. Did
Speaker 1:  you, do you see anything happening now that is like rhyming with some of
Speaker 1:  the other trials that you've, you've been sitting in? Is there anything that
Speaker 1:  you feel like is being carried forward here?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I mean I, I think in a way it, it's hard to make that assessment
Speaker 10:  yet because we have this one data point of this kind of like new era
Speaker 10:  of tech antitrust and that data point is that the judge was willing
Speaker 10:  to call a Google monopoly but wasn't willing to break it up, right?
Speaker 10:  And I think we're kind of in the midst of the second data point and
Speaker 10:  you know, so far it definitely was notable to me that the judge seemed
Speaker 10:  wary of, you know, doing something that might further harm the
Speaker 10:  market, create a new problem, do something that's just technically
Speaker 10:  not feasible and you know, kind of nonsensical from a technical
Speaker 10:  sense. So, you know, I could see that potentially
Speaker 10:  being an issue where she worries that some sort of breakup would be
Speaker 10:  too complicated. But on the other hand, perhaps she
Speaker 10:  does end up agreeing with the government that a breakup is really
Speaker 10:  the simplest way to go. That's long been the argument from people who favor
Speaker 10:  structural remedies is, you know, rather than having behavioral changes
Speaker 10:  that require a court to appoint someone to
Speaker 10:  look after a lot of changes and make sure that the company's staying
Speaker 10:  compliant, that, you know, structural changes, it'll take some
Speaker 10:  time to get there, but once it's done, it's done. It's a separate company.
Speaker 10:  It's not owned by Google anymore. Right. So I think it'll be interesting
Speaker 10:  to see which way that goes and whether Judge
Speaker 10:  Meta's ruling is instructive to that or if it
Speaker 10:  is ultimately an outlier.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think the behavioral remedies piece of it to me is really interesting
Speaker 1:  because it, it's so much of what has happened in this trial
Speaker 1:  has been about bringing to light the shady stuff that nobody knew that Google
Speaker 1:  was doing. Yeah. And I think about like all the, the first look and last
Speaker 1:  look stuff that Google was giving itself, which to me is like the most sort
Speaker 1:  of straightforward version of what you're able to do when you control the
Speaker 1:  whole ecosystem, which is Google would run a whole fair bidding process and
Speaker 1:  then give itself a last chance to win. Yeah. And it was just like,
Speaker 1:  what if you could see the winner of every auction and just decide whether
Speaker 1:  you wanted to win it is like pretty clearly unfair and
Speaker 1:  is is not the kind of thing that Google was like, you know, advertising that
Speaker 1:  it was doing. And so I think this idea that suddenly someone is gonna be
Speaker 1:  able to come in and like immediately suss that stuff out just seems
Speaker 1:  suspicious. And so I like it, it seems obvious to me that that's what Google
Speaker 1:  would want because you're like, we're gonna have this person who part of
Speaker 1:  their job is to try and see what we're doing and
Speaker 1:  yeah, you can see why it is cleaner to just be like, no, just, just stop
Speaker 1:  having adx be yours. But also why that causes a whole set
Speaker 1:  of other problems. So I think, yeah, I, where this judge lands on
Speaker 1:  sort of feasibility versus success, I think is gonna be really fascinating
Speaker 1:  and seems hard to know at this point.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, and that's something that the DOJ brought up in their opening arguments
Speaker 10:  actually, actually that, you know, this is such a complicated space and
Speaker 10:  you know, it, it's not hard to imagine Google being able to
Speaker 10:  bury some code or some change that's difficult to detect
Speaker 10:  that kind of recreates a problem all over again.
Speaker 1:  All right, so you have another week of the Google trial and then some
Speaker 1:  amount of time and then we'll get an answer from the judge. Is that, is that
Speaker 1:  what we're in for here?
Speaker 10:  That's what we're in for and you know, remember this is the rocket docket
Speaker 10:  in the Eastern District of Virginia, right? So, you know, that is
Speaker 10:  speedy in terms of legal time, not in terms of real people
Speaker 10:  time, but you know, that said, we could get a decision,
Speaker 10:  you know, if you think about in the search case, which is, you know, not
Speaker 10:  known as a speedy court, we had the remedies trial,
Speaker 10:  I believe in March or April, and then we got the decision I
Speaker 10:  think at very beginning of September. So, you know, if I would think
Speaker 10:  maybe a much shorter timeframe than that to get a decision here.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So it, it does seem like this is, this is one where there's
Speaker 1:  just a lot hanging
Speaker 16:  power user of YouTube as I listen to several minutes,
Speaker 16:  sometimes hours a day, a lot of my
Speaker 16:  podcasts, a lot of just general content on there.
Speaker 16:  It's basically my main source of media consumption.
Speaker 16:  And lately I've noticed that Gemini does
Speaker 16:  an incredible job of summarizing these videos And
Speaker 16:  I never realized the extent to which, especially as a busy
Speaker 16:  family man who has very few
Speaker 16:  minutes or hours to spare in the day. I never knew how much
Speaker 16:  I watched YouTube videos just to get information. And the reason I know
Speaker 16:  this is because I started asking Gemini
Speaker 16:  to summarize videos for me and it gives me a quick,
Speaker 16:  accurate, factual breakdown of the main points of a video.
Speaker 16:  Is this an existential concern for YouTube creators? Am
Speaker 16:  I the only weird one doing this? Could this become a trend?
Speaker 16:  Would love your thoughts.
Speaker 1:  Okay, I I love this question for a bunch of reasons because one,
Speaker 1:  Roy, you are not the only person doing this. Two, this is
Speaker 1:  incredibly intended behavior. This is what Google and all of these companies
Speaker 1:  want you to do is summarize things with ai. And three
Speaker 1:  summarization is one of the things that AI is actually very good at. I think
Speaker 1:  if you ask open-ended questions of an AI bot or a large language model of
Speaker 1:  any kind, you, you run all kinds of risks, right? Things get really
Speaker 1:  complicated, things go off in weird directions, but if you just give it a
Speaker 1:  body of work and say, make this shorter, it's actually very
Speaker 1:  good at that. And so you see a lot of these tools out there now that are
Speaker 1:  like feeding a book to an AI model in order
Speaker 1:  to get a summary back. And then it's like, well, you've now read
Speaker 1:  the book and like you haven't, you've read a summary of the book and that's
Speaker 1:  fine, but the summaries are often very good. And I've even started doing
Speaker 1:  it in my own research with a lot of like white papers and studies. It's a
Speaker 1:  really great way to just like quickly digest a lot of information. And I
Speaker 1:  think one of the fascinating things about YouTube is that it is
Speaker 1:  both a very good and a wildly inefficient way
Speaker 1:  to just consume information, right? Like if you wanna watch a video because
Speaker 1:  it's fun or it's interesting or it's visual or you like the people or whatever,
Speaker 1:  that's fine. But like my favorite example of this is always when
Speaker 1:  I have like some very small DIY house project to do And
Speaker 1:  I just want to know how to take the thing out and
Speaker 1:  then put the other thing in without burning my house down. And what I have
Speaker 1:  to watch is eight minutes of intro video
Speaker 1:  before I get there. And another version of this that exists on the internet
Speaker 1:  is like the recipe websites where it's like I go to a recipe site And I have
Speaker 1:  to read 2000 words and scroll past 12 ads just to get to the recipe.
Speaker 1:  Like that exists, not because that's what the creators wanna
Speaker 1:  do, but because that's how they have to make a business out of it, right?
Speaker 1:  Like all of the data on that recipe webpage is structured in such a
Speaker 1:  way that Google will find it and rank it so that you will click on it and
Speaker 1:  see it. And YouTube is very much the same way, right? Like videos are longer
Speaker 1:  so that people can show more ads in the middle. The longer videos
Speaker 1:  are the more watch time they get, which means they'll get surface more. And
Speaker 1:  it's just this incredible flywheel of things you have to do in order for
Speaker 1:  the platform to give you the kind of audience and access that you need in
Speaker 1:  order to be successful. So it is a
Speaker 1:  Gemini summary of a YouTube video, an existential threat to the creator of
Speaker 1:  that YouTube video. Absolutely unequivocally yes, if, if everyone
Speaker 1:  stops watching YouTube videos and starts getting summaries of those YouTube
Speaker 1:  videos,
Speaker 1:  it's the end of that business for people on YouTube. We, you
Speaker 1:  become a, a person who is making training data, not a person who
Speaker 1:  is making content that people want to actually consume on YouTube. So
Speaker 1:  like cast it out long enough and make that activity
Speaker 1:  mainstream enough and it absolutely all falls apart. The whole thing falls
Speaker 1:  apart. And this is what, this is what nobody in this industry is reckoning
Speaker 1:  with right now is if all of this stuff works, it all collapses.
Speaker 1:  But that is, that is an existential crisis of my own that we don't have to
Speaker 1:  do right now. So I think what, what I would say, and,
Speaker 1:  and this is just my own way of thinking about like how do I support the
Speaker 1:  internet in a way that works for everybody, is like,
Speaker 1:  watch the videos as as many as you can and as often as
Speaker 1:  you can, but also understand that if what you want is a piece of
Speaker 1:  information and that if the video is not giving it to you in the most efficient
Speaker 1:  way, you shouldn't feel bad about not watching
Speaker 1:  the whole video. You are not obligated to watch things just because they
Speaker 1:  exist. And if what you want is a piece of information on how to take something
Speaker 1:  out of your wall, it's okay to find the most efficient version
Speaker 1:  of that information. And frankly, I think the fact that 10 minute YouTube
Speaker 1:  videos is the most efficient version of information is like insane on its
Speaker 1:  own. But watch the things that you wanna watch, go
Speaker 1:  actively consume the things made by the creators that you like.
Speaker 1:  That that is the thing, the all of the rest of the business and
Speaker 1:  the system and the economy of it all works. If you consume
Speaker 1:  the stuff that you like as often as you can, it, I like
Speaker 1:  it. It is not exactly that simple, but it's close enough to that simple that
Speaker 1:  that's reasonable advice that I can give you. Is it, when
Speaker 1:  you're looking for a piece of information, look for it in the most efficient
Speaker 1:  way possible. And I think in many ways, as we've talked about on this show,
Speaker 1:  AI search engines are really powerful for that. If what you need is sort
Speaker 1:  of a, a piece of data in the haystack of the internet,
Speaker 1:  AI bots and AI search are better at that than Google. And
Speaker 1:  that is a thing that is going to change a lot about how the internet
Speaker 1:  works and how money flows around the internet. And we haven't fully shaken
Speaker 1:  that out yet, but you as a consumer should not feel bad using the best product.
Speaker 1:  But if what you care about is that the creators who make the things that
Speaker 1:  you like, continue to be able to make the things that you like, consume those
Speaker 1:  things, don't summarize the things and let that be enough because it's not,
Speaker 1:  you should be engaging with the things that you like as often as possible.
Speaker 1:  And also like tell your friends and put the video on in the background and
Speaker 1:  mute your computer and just let it play on their playlist for a long time.
Speaker 1:  This is like do it with VERGE videos. If you wanna watch 700
Speaker 1:  consecutive hours of The Vergecast without ever watching any of it on YouTube,
Speaker 1:  I have no problem with that. I would love that. We'd be very grateful. All
Speaker 1:  of this is to say yes, it's all an existential crisis. And
Speaker 1:  no, it's not generally your problem to fix it by
Speaker 1:  never touching AI summaries. And I think if you feel morally
Speaker 1:  icky about some of these things, you're right to, and you should lean into
Speaker 1:  that. But you also are not required to feel bad all the time. I hope
Speaker 1:  that helps. Welcome to my own existential crisis. This is what we do here.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, that's it for The Vergecast today. More existential crises to come,
Speaker 1:  presumably in every episode forever. But for now, The Vergecast is The Verge
Speaker 1:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer, and Travis Uck. You can always email us
Speaker 1:  vergecast at The Verge dot com. You can always call the hotline, send me
Speaker 1:  non malware filled Google Drive links with selfie questions to your videos.
Speaker 1:  We love hearing all of them. We'll be back on Friday with
Speaker 1:  lots more news. We've got a lot of smart home stuff to talk about this week.
Speaker 1:  Some big stuff going on. We're gonna talk about all of it. All the AI stuff,
Speaker 1:  all of our feelings, and all of our existential crises. Until then,
Speaker 1:  we'll see you next time. Rock and roll.