# Transcript
ID: 602bcc82-7fa2-4703-b07f-339902cd2252
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6652102845231757977/1465140288834336480/s93290-US-4632s-1744108581.mp3
Description: Last week, The Verge's Ash Parrish got to play with the new Nintendo Switch 2. We got over our outrageous jealousy long enough to ask her all about it: what it's like to hold, how the screen looks, whether the mouse-control is any good, and much more. Ash gives us the good news, and the bad news, on everything we now know about the Switch 2. (We do talk about the price, but we recorded before the Trump administration launched its massive new tariff push — so you can consider the price even worse news than we thought.) After that, The Verge's Tom Warren joins the show to talk about Microsoft's 50th anniversary celebration, how the company has stayed so resilient for so long, and whether AI is really the next five-decade project for one of the world's biggest companies. Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline (866-VERGE11, or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about how you should change your shopping habits in a tariff-filled world. It's hard to know where we'll be in a few months, but it sure doesn't look like gadgets are getting any cheaper.
Speaker 2:  I also wanna know what those games are for you. I, I sort of immediately
Speaker 2:  regret asking this because if I have like two more of these in my life, I'm
Speaker 2:  just never gonna get anything done again. But I wanna know what are the games
Speaker 2:  that for you, you can, like, you sit down at at two o'clock
Speaker 2:  and you're like, I'm gonna play a little bit of this game, and then suddenly
Speaker 2:  it's seven and you're like, how am I still playing this game? I didn't, how
Speaker 2:  has it been? Five hours? Those are the games I wanna know about. Email us
Speaker 2:  vergecast to The Verge dot com. Call us eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 2:  I wanna hear everything. Tell me everything. Anyway, that's not what we're
Speaker 2:  here to do on this show today. We are gonna do two things. First, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk to Ash Parrish about the Nintendo Switch too. She was there,
Speaker 2:  she was in New York Last week. She's seen the Switch two, she's played the
Speaker 2:  Switch two. She did the weird mousy thing. She has a lot of thoughts and
Speaker 2:  I, I caught her like immediately after the event because I wanted her, her
Speaker 2:  sort of first immediate reactions to using the Switch two. And she had some
Speaker 2:  good ones. We're gonna talk about that also. We're gonna talk to Tom Warren
Speaker 2:  who was there for Microsoft's 50th anniversary celebration Last week,
Speaker 2:  which was interesting. There were protesters,
Speaker 2:  Steve Ballmer was weird. There's a lot going on. So we're gonna talk to Tom
Speaker 2:  about that and also just kind of take stock of Microsoft as it enters its
Speaker 2:  sixth decade as a company. Also, we have a hotline question about
Speaker 2:  tariffs that I'm very excited about. We, this is a question we've heard a
Speaker 2:  lot of and I think the answer is both really simple and really complicated.
Speaker 2:  So we're gonna get into that. All of that is coming up in just a second,
Speaker 2:  but first I have to go play GP again. I just can't, I have to play
Speaker 2:  one more game. I'm gonna do one more race, I promise, just one. And then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna podcast. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  switch world. That's a fair,
Speaker 8:  That's very fair. Yeah, I did sleep
Speaker 8:  a little bit, but not that much. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That sounds right. So, okay, so what I, what I wanna do is
Speaker 2:  I want to kind of go through the, the good and the bad of what we know about
Speaker 2:  the Switch two. Right? Okay. We, we talked when we first got some information
Speaker 2:  and there was still a lot we didn't know, we know a lot more now.
Speaker 2:  We talked a bunch about it on, on Friday show, but I'm really curious, there's,
Speaker 2:  we got a lot of games, we got a lot of spec announcements, we got a lot of
Speaker 2:  like weird new ideas about things from Nintendo that I wanna talk about.
Speaker 2:  So what I asked you to do is basically like, give me some good news and give
Speaker 2:  me some bad news. And we're gonna, we're gonna go through like, I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about some of the, the stuff we're excited about and some of the stuff that
Speaker 2:  we're worried, concerned, confused, have feelings about.
Speaker 2:  Let's start with the, let's start with the good news. What, what is some
Speaker 2:  of the stuff from the announcement that you are like particularly excited
Speaker 2:  about?
Speaker 8:  The good news is, is that upgrading your switch one to a switch to
Speaker 8:  makes sense. Hmm. I just remember
Speaker 8:  I got to the chance to play Breath of the Wild on the Switch two and
Speaker 8:  I had the thought like, oh, this is what this game should have looked like
Speaker 8:  eight years ago. Oh, interesting. It, yeah, the Switch two is fulfill, it
Speaker 8:  feels like it's fulfilling the promise of the Switch one, like we all tricked
Speaker 8:  ourselves into believing like, oh, this game looks great on the Switch one.
Speaker 8:  No, it actually looks like what it's supposed to on the switch two. And it's
Speaker 8:  like, yeah, it, I'm not a person who early adopts
Speaker 8:  consoles at all. Like I just don't care about them all that much.
Speaker 8:  But this is this Seeing Breath of the Wild specifically and even
Speaker 8:  Mario Kart World on the Switch too made me like, yeah, this is a day one
Speaker 8:  purchase for me.
Speaker 2:  Wow. W was it just like bigger, better screen just does
Speaker 2:  the job. It's
Speaker 8:  The whole package. It's the bigger, better screen. It's the frame rate
Speaker 8:  improvements, it's the HDR, it's the 10
Speaker 8:  80 p, it's all of that bundled together. Like we know
Speaker 8:  that Nintendo doesn't, is not like the spec hound. Like they,
Speaker 8:  it's not a big deal if they have like tariff flops of whatever,
Speaker 8:  like, because people still buy and play their games and, but
Speaker 8:  now like seeing this, It is like there's a reason why Xbox
Speaker 8:  and PlayStation are so focused on letting us know that you're gonna get the
Speaker 8:  Crispiest graphics and textures. And now that Nintendo has finally like
Speaker 8:  gotten to, you know, the base level of that, it's like, okay, yeah, this,
Speaker 8:  this feels like something that's supposed to compete at least with a
Speaker 8:  PS four and an Xbox One. If not, you know, the new consoles out right
Speaker 8:  now.
Speaker 2:  I always, I just feel like both things can be true at the same time. Right?
Speaker 2:  Like the Nintendo always says, you know, people don't love our games because
Speaker 2:  they're the highest graphical fidelity and they do the best rate tracing
Speaker 2:  that there are more important things about building great games than just
Speaker 2:  that. And like of course that's true. Yes. Unquestionably, I agree with that.
Speaker 2:  And yet wouldn't it be better if it looked better, right? Yes. Both things
Speaker 2:  can be true.
Speaker 8:  Not only look better, but like play better too. Like I remember at the, you
Speaker 8:  know, now that we're at the end of the Switch is lifecycle that some of these
Speaker 8:  games that are coming out for the original switch, like it shows the age
Speaker 8:  of the console, like with the 30 FPS and you can see it chugging and you
Speaker 8:  can see like the little tears on the edge of models and things like that.
Speaker 8:  But seeing like a buttery smooth 60 up to one 20
Speaker 8:  FPS on the switch too, it's like, oh, okay, I get it
Speaker 8:  now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that is, that is very exciting. And I think one of the things I've
Speaker 2:  been wondering, like I have not touched the thing yet, and you have is
Speaker 2:  it's, It is a much larger piece of equipment, right? But
Speaker 2:  it's, it seems like it's worth it. My worry has been like, I actually think
Speaker 2:  the size of the switch is, is if not exactly right, like pretty
Speaker 2:  close. It's comfortable to hold in one hand or in two hands for a long time.
Speaker 2:  It's like it fits in most places. It feels good. And so I was like, oh no,
Speaker 2:  if they made this thing like a lot bigger, maybe it kills one of the things
Speaker 2:  that I really like about it. But it sounds like maybe the trade off's worth
Speaker 2:  it, even if it does do that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it, it was really hard to get like a good feel for like what the console
Speaker 8:  actually will feel like, you know, out in the wild because Nintendo had them
Speaker 8:  like weighed down with those anti-theft anchors Sure. That make everything
Speaker 8:  super heavy. So I couldn't
Speaker 2:  Like, like being in an Apple store trying to Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly. So I couldn't get a, a good idea of like what this feels like,
Speaker 8:  but I don't mind the bigger switch. Like, it, it, it's
Speaker 8:  not big enough to where it like registers like, oh, this is a much bigger
Speaker 8:  machine. Like it just feels the same to me. Okay, I'll take that. And same
Speaker 8:  with the controllers and the joycons. They just feel the same. They didn't
Speaker 8:  do anything ergonomically different there. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I'm that, that all feels like what I would've hoped for. I've been saying
Speaker 2:  all along, and I think you, you, you've said this too, that like, give me
Speaker 2:  better switch. Don't give me wild new ideas about the future of gaming and
Speaker 2:  I'll be very happy. And
Speaker 8:  And that's exactly what they did. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm glad. All right. What else? What other, what other good news came outta
Speaker 2:  this for you? I wanna talk about games too. Okay.
Speaker 8:  I was gonna say like the, the games are also a good news.
Speaker 8:  So there were a lot of the games that you saw
Speaker 8:  in the direct were at the presentation. You can get a hands on there.
Speaker 8:  So you had like Hades two was there and Street Fighter six.
Speaker 8:  And we got to try some game cue games for Nintendo Switch
Speaker 8:  online. So Win Waker was there. We also got
Speaker 8:  some of the new Nintendo Switch exclusive games like the Super Mario Party
Speaker 8:  Jamboree TV expansion, donkey Kong Bonanza Metro Prime
Speaker 8:  Four, the three V three basketball game Drag and Drive
Speaker 8:  was also there to demo. So there was a, a healthy mix of
Speaker 8:  games that we got to try and playing the games myself and talking
Speaker 8:  to all of my journalist friends that were there, I'm pretty sure like the
Speaker 8:  best in show was Donkey Kong Bonanza, which is y
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Which is exciting because, you know, we would've thought that Mario
Speaker 8:  Kart world would've been everyone's number one. And to be clear, it's, it's
Speaker 8:  up there. It's definitely number two. But everyone that I spoke
Speaker 8:  to when I asked them what was your favorite game, it was Donkey Kong Bonanza.
Speaker 8:  And It is, it's this cute game that feels like
Speaker 8:  it will fill the hole that Mario leaves behind because we've got this new
Speaker 8:  Nintendo console coming out, but no game
Speaker 8:  dedicated to like Nintendo's big dude. Like there's no new 3D Mario and we
Speaker 8:  haven't had one since sip of Mario Odyssey. I mean, we can quibble about
Speaker 8:  Bowser's Fury or whatever if you want, but I'm not gonna do that right now.
Speaker 8:  So like, I was thinking like I had on my personal bingo sheet, like, okay,
Speaker 8:  they're gonna announce the 3D Mario here, and they didn't. And I'm like,
Speaker 8:  well that's odd. I mean, it's not out of character for Nintendo, but I, I'm
Speaker 8:  thinking it's odd because it has been so long since we've gotten a brand
Speaker 8:  new, not DLC of a 3D Mario game and still we
Speaker 8:  don't, but Donkey Kong Bonanza kind of like fills that hole. Like, I
Speaker 8:  played this and I'm thinking, oh, this is Donkey Kong Odyssey.
Speaker 8:  Like that's what this feels like. And, and and, but not like, you know,
Speaker 8:  Mario Odyssey with a Donkey Kong colored campaign. It, it's
Speaker 8:  different enough but still feels like that quintessential Mario
Speaker 8:  platforming experience. And I'm like, this, this is pretty gas,
Speaker 2:  I'm really excited about it. This this, this statement is going to age me
Speaker 2:  in a very specific way, but Donkey Kong country on the
Speaker 2:  Super Nintendo is probably still to this day in my top three
Speaker 2:  most played video games of all time.
Speaker 8:  It's a great game. It should be.
Speaker 2:  It's so good. Like I love that game to pee. I could probably still play most
Speaker 2:  of that game with my eyes closed and
Speaker 2:  the idea that It is still kind of on the level
Speaker 2:  of like the most important Nintendo characters, just that fact alone,
Speaker 2:  like the, the fact that it was the last thing in the announcement and like
Speaker 2:  the, the signal that that sends about how much Nintendo cares about
Speaker 2:  this game and this character and how much it matters to the ecosystem. That
Speaker 2:  alone made me so happy. It's like Donkey Kong is like so back in, in the
Speaker 2:  best way. Oh
Speaker 8:  Yeah. We are so back. And he is got like a brand new character design that's
Speaker 8:  really fun and expressive and I am, I'm looking forward to playing more of
Speaker 8:  that game. It was a lot of fun. That's awesome.
Speaker 2:  I'm also really excited just to hear that you could play that many games.
Speaker 2:  I feel like we've, we've been burned a lot recently by
Speaker 2:  coming soon games and in the coming months games and,
Speaker 2:  you know, in development games and everybody who like announces and then
Speaker 2:  announces and then announces and then announces games. So the fact that these
Speaker 2:  are like done games or at least done enough games that you could play them,
Speaker 2:  I, I feel like speaks very well to what the next few months are gonna look
Speaker 2:  like here.
Speaker 8:  My my cynical thought before I got into the event yesterday was that we were
Speaker 8:  just gonna get a bunch of switch one games on the Switch two. Like I didn't
Speaker 8:  think they would have the, the breadth of games that they did have there.
Speaker 8:  I was quite surprised.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I'm, I'm psyched
Speaker 8:  About that. Oh, do you, do you wanna know a fun little insider secret? Yes.
Speaker 8:  That I thought was really funny. So one of the games that they announced
Speaker 8:  at the direct was a switch port of Hogwarts legacy and that went
Speaker 8:  over like a lead balloon, like nobody cave a crab when we were watching it
Speaker 8:  all together in the presentation. I didn't
Speaker 2:  Even notice that. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Exactly. And then when we got onto like the demo floor, like there
Speaker 8:  were some stations set up to demo Hog Works legacy and nobody touched it.
Speaker 8:  And I thought it was the funniest thing,
Speaker 8:  like throughout the time I was there it was empty.
Speaker 2:  I love that. Just giant crowds around everything except two stations. Yes.
Speaker 2:  That's amazing. Exactly. That's that's very good. What else? Are there
Speaker 2:  other good news, other surprising excitement coming out of the, the announcement?
Speaker 8:  So one of the things that I thought and on the game side that was
Speaker 8:  like really interesting that I, when I first saw it, I had like kind of like
Speaker 8:  a lukewarm response to it, but then when I saw it in action, I'm like, actually
Speaker 8:  this works is the Nintendo Switch to welcome tour,
Speaker 8:  which is the game that you, I guess
Speaker 8:  Nintendo made to like introduce you to the switch to. So it, it tells you
Speaker 8:  like how it works and all these different new features with a bunch of
Speaker 8:  mini games. It is very much Nintendo's Astros playroom and getting my
Speaker 8:  hands on it. It's actually really cool and informative. Like
Speaker 8:  we don't get to see very much how the sausage gets made. We have like Mark
Speaker 8:  Cerney talking about PS five tariff flops and things like that and your eyes
Speaker 8:  cross and you're like, I have no idea what you're talking about. None of
Speaker 8:  these words are in the Bible, but seeing Nintendo really break that down
Speaker 8:  with how their joy cons work or you know, what
Speaker 8:  explaining frame rates, like there was a tutorial or a little quiz or
Speaker 8:  little info thing that explained like, here's the difference between
Speaker 8:  30 FPS and 60 FPS and 120 FPS. And it's, it's something like, you
Speaker 8:  know, intellectually and you can see the difference, but actually having
Speaker 8:  a technical explanation for why 30 FPS looks different than 60
Speaker 8:  X ps FPS was like really informative and I really appreciated that.
Speaker 8:  So that was one of those like little weird stand that's like, oh okay, this
Speaker 8:  is actually better than I gave it credit for. So kudos to Nintendo on that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's cool. And I was actually gonna ask you about that 'cause there
Speaker 2:  was some
Speaker 2:  surprise maybe at the fact that this is a paid game that it's like you, you're
Speaker 2:  gonna make me pay to like play the manual for the console.
Speaker 2:  But even just describing it as like Nintendo's version of of Astro's play
Speaker 2:  kind of makes that make a lot more sense.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  I still think it should maybe be free, but that's neither here nor there.
Speaker 8:  The way that we, you know, set this up. You told me like give me three good
Speaker 8:  things and three bad things. Yeah. Nintendo Switch welcome tour is on my
Speaker 8:  good and my bad side. Ah, fair enough. Okay. And the bad part is because
Speaker 8:  It is not a pack in game like Astro's playroom was is something that you
Speaker 8:  have to pay for and that just doesn't make sense to me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's that's very fair. All right, so let's switch to, let's switch
Speaker 2:  to some bad news. Okay. I, I have, I have a couple that
Speaker 2:  I want to ask you about specifically. Okay. But give, give me your list first.
Speaker 2:  So the Astros player room shenanigans available. Yeah. The
Speaker 8:  Nintendo Switch tour is, is the bad news because there's no rhyme or reason
Speaker 8:  that that is a paid game and just not included. It is the list. The other
Speaker 8:  bad news, which I have a feeling is gonna be on the top of yours and everyone's
Speaker 8:  list is the price. Like, what are we doing here,
Speaker 8:  folks? Like I know what we're doing here and I think we have a good idea
Speaker 8:  why we're doing what we're doing here, but holy crap, you're gonna ask
Speaker 8:  people to pay an additional 150 bucks for
Speaker 8:  this thing. And then the thing with that is, is you're actually gonna ask
Speaker 8:  people to pay $500 for this because you're gonna want the
Speaker 8:  bundle that bundles Mario Kart world and the Nintendo Switch two because
Speaker 8:  that game all by itself will be 80 of God's own
Speaker 8:  dollars. And that isic you get a $30
Speaker 8:  like price cut if you buy it bundled and it just doesn't make
Speaker 8:  economical sense to do it other than that. And then they're making a limited
Speaker 8:  amount of it when it's done, It is done. They're not gonna do that anymore.
Speaker 8:  According to Nintendo. They might, it would make sense for them too, but
Speaker 8:  they said once those the, they run out like, we're not gonna restock this.
Speaker 8:  So you gotta get your pre-orders in. God. I just probably started a rush
Speaker 8:  on Nintendo such two pre-orders. I'm sorry,
Speaker 2:  I may or may not have already filled out the form that promised to alert
Speaker 2:  me when pre-orders are available. Okay. I'm, I confess I'm slightly
Speaker 2:  torn on the price because on the one hand It is much more
Speaker 2:  expensive. I think I expected it to be a little more expensive, but
Speaker 2:  I would've probably pegged the price at like, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  3 79 instead of four 50.
Speaker 2:  But, you know, whatever inflation tariffs, the world is chaos. Some of this
Speaker 2:  is probably Nintendo's doing, some of It is probably not.
Speaker 2:  Consoles in general have gotten more expensive over time. So like I I sort
Speaker 2:  of under, I do think the combination of substantially more expensive
Speaker 2:  console and,
Speaker 8:  And substantially more expensive games is the thing.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Normalizing 70 and $80 games I think is a real, real,
Speaker 2:  real bummer.
Speaker 8:  It's turbo bad. Like it's, it's the one-two punch is
Speaker 8:  is really hard. And a lot of families, especially now with everything that's
Speaker 8:  going on with these brand new tariffs that hit just today, it's gonna make
Speaker 8:  a lot of families like pe people are already choosing
Speaker 8:  between, you know, buying their groceries and doing other things and overwhelmingly
Speaker 8:  people are gonna buy their groceries. This is gonna do nothing but hurt those
Speaker 8:  families that buy these consoles. It's, it's just, that's a tough, tough
Speaker 8:  ask from Nintendo right now, but everybody's asking more money from
Speaker 8:  all of us everywhere, so I understand it. Well, and
Speaker 2:  I think what's, what's weird is it puts Nintendo into the
Speaker 2:  kind of like direct competition with Sony and
Speaker 2:  Microsoft that it has always kind of enjoyed not doing right? Like Nintendo
Speaker 2:  has just al like, we make fun of Nintendo because like the gaming business
Speaker 2:  is over here and Nintendo is just like all the way over there doing whatever
Speaker 2:  Nintendo's doing and they're like inching closer to this other sort of
Speaker 2:  messy loot boxy, take all of your money no matter what world
Speaker 2:  in a way that I I I don't love.
Speaker 8:  The funny thing is is they completely leaped over the competition because
Speaker 8:  they're advertising $80 games. Like we just blew past
Speaker 8:  70 all the way to 80. And I'm hearing some places
Speaker 8:  like overseas are gonna charge $90, $90
Speaker 8:  for the physical edition of Mario Kart World. And my eyes kinda like bugged
Speaker 8:  outta my head like, yeah, back in, you know, 1999 we were paying 120
Speaker 8:  bucks for Nintendo 64 cartridges, but holy crap,
Speaker 8:  like we've had the $60 has been normalized for a good long time,
Speaker 8:  but, and to see a $30 price jump all at once is just gonna create
Speaker 8:  a sticker shock for a lot of people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. This goes from being like a, a thing you can buy a console and
Speaker 2:  a couple of games for like a good Christmas
Speaker 2:  present down to like, you're, you, you're gonna run this thing into like
Speaker 2:  a thousand dollars without trying very hard.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And the the other thing attached to the
Speaker 8:  games, not necessarily, you know, their price that makes this suck even more
Speaker 8:  is that some of these physical games won't even have the game data
Speaker 8:  on them, but they will be required to be inserted into the switch to run
Speaker 8:  the games. I'm seeing things called game keys where
Speaker 8:  you actually, you put the cartridge in, you still have to download the game
Speaker 8:  online, but you still need the, the cartridge to run. And I'm like, what
Speaker 8:  are we doing here? Like, this sucks. Like I'm already planning to go
Speaker 8:  fully physical for the switch to, because I am seeing the
Speaker 8:  shenanigans that these console companies are getting up to with like
Speaker 8:  revoking digital game access and things like that. Like I have been completely
Speaker 8:  physical media pilled, but now you're making it so that the physical
Speaker 8:  cartridges don't even have the games on them anymore. You're just selling
Speaker 8:  us plastic with just a little bit of thing that we still need.
Speaker 8:  Like this is terrible for game preservation first of all. And it's anti-consumer.
Speaker 8:  It doesn't make any sense. I hate it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So that the, the game key thing was actually one of the ones I was gonna
Speaker 2:  ask you about because it, I I think, I just don't
Speaker 2:  understand what Nintendo is trying to do here because
Speaker 8:  I have no idea. It
Speaker 2:  Is, It is one thing to like, you know, have, have digital
Speaker 2:  games that are DMed in some way. Like Sure. Whatever. And I think we're all
Speaker 2:  sort of becoming increasingly physical media pilled as a result. Like watching
Speaker 2:  all of the stuff that happens to emulators and the way that games go away
Speaker 2:  and the way that, that all of this stuff is just being lost to time over
Speaker 2:  time. Like, you, you should buy cartridges. I'm fully pro cartridges.
Speaker 2:  I kind of don't get the point of the game key thing. Like I
Speaker 8:  Don't either, I can't see it
Speaker 2:  Except if Nintendo is trying to just be
Speaker 2:  more in control of everything. The idea is like we, we've seen
Speaker 2:  Nintendo crackdown on emulators, we've seen Nintendo like really start to
Speaker 2:  push to stop people playing its games that it doesn't want to play its games.
Speaker 2:  And maybe this is just yet another way to do that, but I don't know, it feels
Speaker 2:  like there has to be something I'm missing here or this just sucks.
Speaker 8:  So my boss Andrew Webster is probably sitting right now in a meeting with
Speaker 8:  Doug Bowser and that is definitely one of the questions on his list. So hopefully
Speaker 8:  Doug will give us a not mely mild answer for that.
Speaker 2:  I don't, I don't have a ton of hope on that, but if if they do, if, if we
Speaker 2:  do get a real answer, we'll we'll come back and talk about it. What else
Speaker 2:  is on your bad news list?
Speaker 8:  The, the last thing on my bad news list is actually the mouse controls. So
Speaker 8:  the big new gimmicky thing that Nintendo is in bundling with this console
Speaker 8:  is the fact that you can turn your JoyCon into a mouse. And I hate it,
Speaker 8:  I hate it right now. Okay. I didn't see anything
Speaker 8:  that there that made me think, oh, this game is why this
Speaker 8:  feature makes sense. So they had Dragon Drive, which is the three V three
Speaker 8:  basketball thing and it's kind of cute to put the joy cons like on a table
Speaker 8:  and do like this motion like you're pushing a wheelchair,
Speaker 8:  but It is so awkward to hold in your hand like this. It's just
Speaker 2:  You basically, like you, you pull the joycons out, sort of turn them sideways
Speaker 2:  and stick them down on. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 8:  And this is not a natural position No. To hold a JoyCon in
Speaker 8:  because there's a reason why we design mice to be flat so your hand can kind
Speaker 8:  of like rest in this neutral position as you move it around. And the
Speaker 8:  joy cons as mice don't fit that natural
Speaker 8:  neutral position profile. So I don't have any issues with like carpal
Speaker 8:  tunnels or like joint pain in my shoulders or whatever, but just doing this
Speaker 8:  for a little bit, like I could feel like pain and tension start to like
Speaker 8:  aggravate my arm and I'm like, if you have any kind of like wrist issues,
Speaker 8:  like this is gonna play hell on your joints. It, it's painful. I didn't like
Speaker 8:  it at all and I just, I don't, I don't see it. Like there's nothing that
Speaker 8:  made me go, oh, this is good. And I tried it again for
Speaker 8:  Metro Prime four and one of the things that that an annoyed me about that
Speaker 8:  was that they have, you know, the two different control schemes,
Speaker 8:  you could either play it like with Gyro controls with the split joycons one
Speaker 8:  in each hand, or you could split it where one is a mouse and one JoyCon
Speaker 8:  is like free on your hand and nothing with like a traditional controller
Speaker 8:  setup. Like, no, I didn't have that option or at least at the station I was
Speaker 8:  at, I didn't have that option. Interesting. And I wish I did because I think
Speaker 8:  I would've enjoyed the demo a lot more and it's just, you've got lock
Speaker 8:  on still, but like I was just having a hard time trying to like figure this
Speaker 8:  out and aim and move and it seems like at least with Mouse controls
Speaker 8:  and Metro Prime four, that there's gonna be a steep learning curve to get
Speaker 8:  that right in order to play the game effectively. But then I realized
Speaker 8:  like y'all played the first three metro primes on
Speaker 8:  the damn wee using waggle phases, so it's like, oh shit, we're just doing
Speaker 8:  that shit again. Well, so that's kind
Speaker 2:  Of what I wonder is I look at the mouse controls and I, I can't decide if
Speaker 2:  that's just a thing Nintendo occasionally does and all
Speaker 2:  really all these gaming platforms do, which is they just sort of invent a
Speaker 2:  weird thing that you can build into your game if you want to and no one really
Speaker 2:  does. And eventually they phase it out. It's like the, they, the move controllers
Speaker 2:  or the Connect or whatever, like everybody has tried to come up with some
Speaker 2:  new gimmick and they're like, maybe this will be fun for your game. And there
Speaker 2:  are a few games that like really make use of it, but for the most part they're
Speaker 2:  just not part of the system at all. Or if this is a thing,
Speaker 2:  Nintendo is going to try to make like an actual sort of
Speaker 2:  first class part of how people play Nintendo games. And as
Speaker 2:  somebody who mostly sits here at my computer with my switch plugged
Speaker 2:  in into the dock with a, with a full on controller,
Speaker 2:  that would be a real bummer for me.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I
Speaker 8:  I have a feeling that Nintendo is gonna make this like their
Speaker 8:  flagship like feature of this console in addition to like the chat and
Speaker 8:  the the video chat thing that was also announced,
Speaker 8:  but whatever they have right now is not there to
Speaker 8:  really demonstrate this is the vision that we have for this. Like, you've
Speaker 8:  got drag and drive, which is essentially a, a, you know, a paid tech demo
Speaker 8:  for this, for this function, but that didn't really
Speaker 8:  wow me or sell me on it. But I, I just, not a
Speaker 8:  faith, but I have this inkling because Nintendo, at the end of the day, they
Speaker 8:  kind of really, sometimes they really do know what they're doing in terms
Speaker 8:  of like hardware and gimmicking and stuff like that because, you know, the
Speaker 8:  WiMo was, you know, we all complained about wacko physics, but at the end
Speaker 8:  of the day that was kind of fun. Not implemented all the time in the best
Speaker 8:  ways, but it was still fun and unique and innovative. And I have a feeling
Speaker 8:  this will be too, we just need to give them time to cook and figure out something
Speaker 8:  that really makes it pop.
Speaker 2:  I do worry about the, just the ergonomics of it on that front. It's not good.
Speaker 2:  Right? 'cause I think you're right that when n when Nintendo is like, when
Speaker 2:  they're all in on something, they're right a lot, right? Like it's usually
Speaker 2:  when it's kind of weird is when Nintendo is just like, here's a thing kind
Speaker 2:  of off to the side, do what you want with it. But when Nintendo is like,
Speaker 2:  this is how we play games now, it's usually right, right. Yes. Like the,
Speaker 2:  the, the DS universe is like that, that's one version of that where they're
Speaker 2:  like, this is how you do it. And it was, it was pretty right. But just the
Speaker 2:  sheer like what it feels like to even just looking at like pictures of people's
Speaker 2:  hands trying to hold the joy con on it. It just doesn't
Speaker 8:  Look right. It's not, it's awkward. Your hand isn't
Speaker 8:  meant to do that. The, the, the Joy con is too small, so your
Speaker 8:  fingers kind of curl around the back and then you get like this claw hand
Speaker 8:  situation versus something where you can just lay your hands out like completely
Speaker 8:  flat like this on a mouse. It just, it just does not feel good. So
Speaker 8:  the idea is either they will figure out something that will
Speaker 8:  make this work or Nintendo's about to pump out a bunch of
Speaker 8:  accessories that you can buy that actually makes the mouse make sense.
Speaker 2:  Fair. Yeah. There's definitely a, there's like a holster you could make for
Speaker 2:  that thing that would make it a lot more
Speaker 8:  Workable. Yeah. Like we're about to get those little, remember those little
Speaker 8:  plastic diapers we used to wrap the We Modes in or
Speaker 8:  whatever. We're about to get something like that for those joy cons.
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent. Okay. I have two more things Sure. That I wanna know if
Speaker 2:  they're good news or bad news. And then I'm gonna let you go. First thing
Speaker 2:  is the switch to is kind of obsessed with the Game Cube.
Speaker 2:  There's a Game Cube controller for the switch to, there's a bunch of Game
Speaker 2:  Cube games coming. It's like this is a real game
Speaker 2:  Cube ance happening with this console. Is that, is that good news or
Speaker 2:  bad news?
Speaker 8:  It's a little bit of both. Okay. The Game Cube is, has
Speaker 8:  not been adequately represented on the Nintendo Switch online offerings.
Speaker 8:  So that's good news. I mean, I know a lot of people are really excited about
Speaker 8:  having Soul Caliber two with Link in it available to play again.
Speaker 8:  And, but I personally, my pet, you know, tinfoil Hat theory is that
Speaker 8:  Nintendo got really tired of a bunch of people being like,
Speaker 8:  where's the win Waker remaster? And I'm like, best I can do is just give
Speaker 8:  you win Wake again and you're gonna pay $80 for it.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Yeah. And I think the Game Cube is always very funny
Speaker 2:  to me. 'cause like in my own gaming experience, I really jumped
Speaker 2:  straight from the N 64 to the we, so the Game Cube was just never quite
Speaker 2:  in my world. But I sort of feel like everybody loves the Game Cube in
Speaker 2:  retrospect more than they actually like, loved it when they owned it.
Speaker 8:  Yes. I think that's correct.
Speaker 2:  But It is also like the, the true old head gamers are
Speaker 2:  the ones who seem to love the Game Cube the most. Which
Speaker 8:  Is weird because that, well It is old, but it it's not old
Speaker 8:  head. Right? Like, oh, that's just so weird to say. Like, I
Speaker 8:  was a, I think I was a teenager when the N 64 came out, and you're right,
Speaker 8:  like my mind completely glosses over the Game Cube and I went right from
Speaker 8:  Nintendo 64 to the Wii. But
Speaker 8:  some of those games are really fun. Yeah. Like we've got a new Kirby Air
Speaker 8:  ride game. Like wasn't that a Game Cube game? So yeah, we're, we're, we're,
Speaker 8:  I guess that's where they are as you know, they're going back in their history
Speaker 8:  and now it's time for the Game Cube to come back. 'cause they've already
Speaker 8:  done the, the Nintendo and the Super Nintendo. They've got
Speaker 8:  some We stuff and now it's like, okay, yeah, we gotta go back and get the
Speaker 8:  Game Cube and bring that up to speed too.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. I have heard a bunch of people who are very excited just
Speaker 2:  to have F zero GX back, which
Speaker 2:  like, sure. Kudo, I'm happy for all of you. Okay, last one.
Speaker 2:  This console is really into video chat, like
Speaker 2:  game chat in particular, but specifically video chat.
Speaker 2:  Good news or bad news.
Speaker 8:  Good news. Yeah. Yeah. What this is, this is one of the things, so, you know
Speaker 8:  that comic where it's like, you know, it's a hot guy knocking on a
Speaker 8:  lady's like cubicle and she's like, Hey there. And, and the lady's like,
Speaker 8:  oh, aren't you cute? And then it's like a less attractive guy who's like,
Speaker 8:  Hey there. And she's like, human resources, this is the Nintendo
Speaker 8:  doing that is like the same thing between the connect and the video chat.
Speaker 8:  So like the connect is like human resources. Hello. What? But now that Nintendo's
Speaker 8:  doing It is like, oh, okay, yeah, this is cool. I get it. They're so many
Speaker 8:  years late, but they are executing on this
Speaker 8:  so much better. It's just like, I, they can't keep getting away
Speaker 8:  with it. And yet they are like, it does these really cool things like
Speaker 8:  where you can put your body in a game, like in the Super Mario Party
Speaker 8:  Jamboree TV expansion. Like it takes a picture of you and it puts you in
Speaker 8:  the game and you can like, do all kinds of weird cool things that look cool
Speaker 8:  that families are just gonna love. Like, I can look at that and see like,
Speaker 8:  yep, families with young kids are gonna have a blast with this.
Speaker 8:  And you know, one of the things that we were talking about here at The Verge
Speaker 8:  was like, oh, we can do meetings on this now. Mm. Like, let's, let's hold
Speaker 8:  like our weekly standup meeting and then switch to video chat. Like, and
Speaker 8:  that's something that you could do. And honestly, it's a really cool
Speaker 8:  idea and I want to do that. Like, I think that would be great to, you know,
Speaker 8:  I'm playing Zelda, whatever, and you know, it's time to have
Speaker 8:  a meeting with my boss and I can just hit the button and be like, Hey, you
Speaker 8:  know, working on this review right now and you can see me playing in the
Speaker 8:  background. I just think that's cool. I I I totally buy it. It's just cool
Speaker 8:  when Nintendo does it, when everybody else does it, it's like, ugh. But when
Speaker 8:  Nintendo does it, it's cool. I'm sorry. It's just the double standard. That's
Speaker 2:  Fair. And I'm, I'm I'm with you on it. Except I think the, the only part
Speaker 2:  of it that makes me nervous is I think Nintendo is
Speaker 2:  one of the last companies doing a really great job of building
Speaker 2:  games to play by yourself. I feel like everyone else has gone to like,
Speaker 2:  everything is a giant world. Everything is open, you're supposed to, everything
Speaker 2:  is multiplayer all the time no matter what. And then Nintendo is just like,
Speaker 2:  do you wanna play Mario Tennis by yourself for six hours? Like, here you
Speaker 2:  go, let's do that. And I worry, like, I think I'm, I'm probably
Speaker 2:  overshooting my fear that video chat leads to the
Speaker 2:  death of one player games. But that is the thing I worry about.
Speaker 8:  I disagree because I think if anything this kind of
Speaker 8:  shows, Nintendo understands that the thing people do a
Speaker 8:  lot nowadays is play with their friends. But some people don't wanna do that,
Speaker 8:  but they still want the experience of, you know, communing
Speaker 8:  and this is a way to play separately together. Hmm. So, you know,
Speaker 8:  your friend, one friend is playing Breath of the Wild, another friend is
Speaker 8:  playing some other game. You guys can play your two separate games,
Speaker 8:  but still like talk to each other in this interface. And I think that's what
Speaker 8:  Nintendo is doing and I think that's really smart.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, I agree. And I like the idea that It is sort of social
Speaker 2:  first and not just game first. Exactly. Which is not how, how anybody else
Speaker 2:  does it, which I agree is, is pretty cool. It almost like, it's sort of learned
Speaker 2:  a lesson both from multiplayer games and from Discord all at the same time
Speaker 2:  in a way that I kind of think is, is neat. I'm with you. I also want that
Speaker 2:  camera. I just like for the, I I I I'm with you in the sense that like, I've
Speaker 2:  put other cameras in my living room and they all creep me out and I don't
Speaker 2:  want any of them. And then I see Nintendo's little camera on a stick and
Speaker 2:  I'm like, well that's adorable. I would put that next to my television. Did
Speaker 8:  You see that they are having third party cameras and one of 'em looks like
Speaker 8:  a piranha plant. What?
Speaker 2:  No.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Really?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's really cool. It's a third party one. It's in our slack, but
Speaker 8:  it looks really cool. And I'm like, I want that.
Speaker 2:  That's such a good idea. I I love that already. I want one that's Yoshi,
Speaker 2:  but it's like Yoshi with his mouth open and the camera's just coming out,
Speaker 2:  but it's tongue sitting
Speaker 8:  Out. Oh, like an egg. That would be cute.
Speaker 2:  That'd be good. All right, so are you, you're gonna buy one of these, right?
Speaker 2:  Like would you, you're gonna get one for professional reasons, but like,
Speaker 2:  as as a gamer. Is this It? Is this? Yeah. We're there.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. As a gamer, I was already sold. I'm like, yeah, like
Speaker 8:  Mario Kart world is really cool. Like, I've never had the desire to
Speaker 8:  play a Mario Kart game. Like they're fun to play with friends, but that's
Speaker 8:  like a party game. Like, you know, you're going to a party with a bunch of
Speaker 8:  friends and you wanna play video games, like Mario Kart is one of those games.
Speaker 8:  But playing Mario Kart World make me like, I actually
Speaker 8:  want this, I want this for myself. I want to play this for myself. And then
Speaker 8:  seeing all of these switch two versions of switch one games, I'm like, I
Speaker 8:  want that too. Like I want to experience these games the way that they should
Speaker 8:  have experienced them when they were launched. So the, the calculus has already
Speaker 8:  been decided for me. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean I was, I was the same way that like, I was gonna end up buying this
Speaker 2:  thing no matter what. But I think the thing that's really exciting for me
Speaker 2:  is I want this thing on day one way more than I wanted the switch
Speaker 2:  on day one. Because this thing is gonna feel huge on day one, which I
Speaker 2:  think is like very much to Nintendo's credit, there was not that much to
Speaker 2:  do on this switch on day one.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That, that, that's how they get you, that's how they justify their
Speaker 8:  450 and $500 price is because they know
Speaker 8:  we're gonna be there no matter what because it's Nintendo
Speaker 8:  and damn, if they don't know how to sell a console with these new bells and
Speaker 8:  whistles, it just works.
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry, it's a real problem. It's like watching the thing. I'm like, okay,
Speaker 2:  you showed Mario Kart, you showed a oh oh seven trailer that showed nothing
Speaker 2:  but is a oh oh seven game and then you ended with Donkey Kong. I'm like,
Speaker 2:  name your price. Like I don't, I'm, I am powerless at this point. I have
Speaker 2:  nothing left.
Speaker 8:  They're really good at that.
Speaker 2:  Ash, thank you as always.
Speaker 8:  Thank you for having me.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about Microsoft. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Tom Warren's here. Hi Tom. Hello there. You just
Speaker 2:  made it home like very recently. Literally this morning. Yeah. Okay. So
Speaker 2:  you, you I feel like this is a real, like I cannot be held accountable for
Speaker 2:  any of my words on this podcast kind of thing. Yeah, this is, this is a Jet
Speaker 2:  like podcast, so if I say something wrong that's why I'm excited about
Speaker 2:  it. So you were there for the, the occasion of Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  50th anniversary. Yeah. And I have some like big heady Microsoft stuff I
Speaker 2:  wanna talk about. But first just tell me about the event. This was like a,
Speaker 2:  I would say a, a weirder wilder anniversary party than anybody expected it
Speaker 2:  to be. What was it like to be there?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I wasn't really sure what it was gonna be like when I like agreed
Speaker 11:  to go and stuff. I was like, they didn't really tell me much about it. And
Speaker 11:  then I was like, hmm. So on the day I was thinking, oh, it's just gonna
Speaker 11:  be like a party atmosphere and all that sort of stuff. So it, it kind of
Speaker 11:  kicked off with like Microsoft ai, CEO,
Speaker 11:  Mustafa Solomon. So he started talking about
Speaker 11:  co-pilot and all the new features, all the stuff that we've covered. And
Speaker 11:  Sat del and Microsoft CEO came on stage as well to sort of talk about the
Speaker 11:  future and, and co-pilot stuff as that was going on. Sort of,
Speaker 11:  I'd say about 15 minutes in, we had our first protestor.
Speaker 12:  I hear a protest. Thank you.
Speaker 13:  Shame on you. You are war profiteer. I hear you. Stop using
Speaker 13:  AI for genocide. Musta, stop using AI for genocide in our
Speaker 13:  region. You have blood on your hands. All of Microsoft
Speaker 13:  has blood on its hands. How do you all celebrate when Microsoft
Speaker 13:  is dealing?
Speaker 11:  Which kind of like threw the whole vibe of the event off
Speaker 11:  slightly.
Speaker 11:  'cause obviously it was a Microsoft employee that, that that was protesting,
Speaker 11:  which is super unusual, right? Like usually you go to a tech event and there
Speaker 11:  might be a protester about the company's policies or, or have their technologies
Speaker 11:  used, et cetera. But it's not usually, you know, the company's
Speaker 11:  employee that's that's doing it. So that, that was, that was super strange.
Speaker 11:  So yeah, that, that happened and then we quickly moved
Speaker 11:  on to like, it was like a party atmosphere really.
Speaker 11:  And they, they brought out Brenda song, she was like hosting it. Okay.
Speaker 11:  And it was all, this part of it wasn't streamed live, so this was employee
Speaker 11:  only essentially and the rest of the world's press that was in the audience.
Speaker 11:  So yeah, she sort of hosted it. She brought up like Bill
Speaker 11:  Gates individually, Steve Barer individually, and then obviously Satya
Speaker 11:  and then they all came on together all free. So they, they were kind of
Speaker 11:  getting questioned individually and then all together about the history
Speaker 11:  of Microsoft and, and all that. And Steve Bmore obviously came on,
Speaker 11:  did his usual, you know, developers, developers, developers. We were expecting
Speaker 11:  that.
Speaker 2:  But did he actually, he actually did the developers. Developers.
Speaker 11:  Oh wow. She screamed it out. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Okay. This is something that I'm gonna get in a lot of trouble with
Speaker 12:  with my wife who I sit see sitting there. But
Speaker 11:  He was like, he like looked at his wife in the audience, was like, I'm gonna
Speaker 11:  get in trouble with my wife. And then he just immediately did it.
Speaker 2:  I kind of love Steve Ballmer for doing it like I have to. Yeah, that was
Speaker 2:  such a like silly moment in the history of Microsoft that I
Speaker 2:  kind of love him for just being like, this is my legacy now. I'm I'll do
Speaker 2:  it, I'm here for it.
Speaker 11:  If you, if you look at our video that we did of it, I think Veen or
Speaker 11:  edited it pop like the old Ballmer on the bottom as well
Speaker 11:  and they couldn't look further apart. Like he looks really well now as well
Speaker 11:  and he, and he wasn't swinging, you know, buckets on stage when he did did
Speaker 11:  it this time. So that helped. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It helps when you're, you have all the money in the world but don't have
Speaker 2:  to run a company anymore. I feel like that that tends to be good for your
Speaker 2:  health I think.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. He also made up a new chart which he was screaming, which was
Speaker 11:  50 more, 50 more. Oh that's good. Which
Speaker 11:  was, it was just crazy. That's really funny. Yeah, and he was, I think he
Speaker 11:  was kind of like the highlight, if I'm honest, of the pa party
Speaker 11:  atmosphere. So Brenda sort of interviewed them all individually and
Speaker 11:  then Cleo Abram came on for the explain series
Speaker 11:  to interview all three of them together. And then
Speaker 11:  they were probably, probably about halfway through I guess that and
Speaker 11:  another protestor, another employee protestor appeared on to the side of
Speaker 11:  the stage. So, well I
Speaker 15:  Think thank you all. You're all hypocrites. I'm a Microsoft worker
Speaker 15:  and I do not
Speaker 15:  dare
Speaker 2:  So was your, was your sense of this whole thing that it was
Speaker 2:  kind of a, a congratulations to us we're so fantastic thing or like
Speaker 2:  a, you know, onward charge forward thing because it's, it's a, it's a
Speaker 2:  weird thing to celebrate 50 years as a company. 'cause on the one hand you're
Speaker 2:  like, well we did it, we're old and we're,
Speaker 2:  we're we're on the down slope now. But on the other hand, it's like Microsoft
Speaker 2:  is like bigger and more powerful maybe than it has ever been
Speaker 11:  True. And
Speaker 2:  In the middle of lots of change on lots of fronts. So I'm, I'm like what
Speaker 2:  was, what's your sense of like the vibe they were going for in that sense?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 11:  The vibe is definitely, definitely party celebration vibe. Okay. Rather
Speaker 11:  than like, you know, like the future stuff came into it quite a lot 'cause
Speaker 11:  copilot, you know, they, they kind of tied the copilot news to this event,
Speaker 11:  so it was kind of always like linked. But yeah, no, there was a lot of like
Speaker 11:  looking back at the old stuff and, and Bill Gates when he first appeared,
Speaker 11:  he came on and was like nerding out, like full on nerding
Speaker 11:  out recounting pie, you know, like it was Oh it was that sort of nerding
Speaker 11:  out. Yeah, it was, talk about qubits. So it was, yeah, it was
Speaker 11:  kind of, it was kind of funny. But yeah. And then they had like a, a game
Speaker 11:  show thing where they had a few Microsoft employees come up and stuff and,
Speaker 11:  and so, and one of one Microsoft employee won a slot on
Speaker 11:  the front row of the party. They had to come over from some other
Speaker 11:  building. So yeah, so it was a very game show vibe for
Speaker 11:  sure.
Speaker 2:  I mean I kind of get that like fifties a big thing and it also, it, it helps
Speaker 2:  that Microsoft remains Microsoft and it's like if you're, yeah. If you're
Speaker 2:  like, I don't know, not to pick on IBM but like this party would be a lot
Speaker 2:  more embarrassing if it was I ibm, do you know what I
Speaker 11:  Mean? Yeah, it's true. They're still somewhat relevant Microsoft in, in
Speaker 11:  in many markets, but whereas yeah, IBM have gone full enterprise,
Speaker 11:  but I think if they hadn't have done this sort of party vibe then it would've
Speaker 11:  been a bit weird. I, I dunno what they would've done otherwise because it
Speaker 11:  would've been like, you know, awkward Bill Gates coming on stage, Steve
Speaker 11:  Baer like making all the noise and then Satya, who's quite like, you know,
Speaker 11:  it's quite reserved. So, so I, I dunno how they would've treated that
Speaker 11:  dynamic without there being like a big host, you know? Yeah. A big party.
Speaker 11:  So I think that they kind of had to go this way either way. So Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That makes a lot of sense. So I I do, you mentioned the co-pilot thing and
Speaker 2:  I, I think it was really interesting to me that they tied these two things
Speaker 2:  together that they were like, yeah, Microsoft is turning 50. It's a huge
Speaker 2:  moment. And also we have some pretty big
Speaker 2:  AI news, right? What do you make of that connection? Like, is this, should
Speaker 2:  I take this as like a statement of values at Microsoft right now that like,
Speaker 2:  this is the push to the next 50 is about AI and copilot,
Speaker 2:  or am I just kind of overstating two things that happened to happen on the
Speaker 2:  same day?
Speaker 11:  No, I absolutely think so. They, they, they tied those together for a reason,
Speaker 11:  right? And it was very much apparent that that was
Speaker 11:  every time that Satya talked to it was, you know, about AI and, and, and
Speaker 11:  Bill Gates joked that, you know, Microsoft has had three CEOs and
Speaker 11:  then the next CEO EO might be co-pilot. You know, like, so there, there
Speaker 11:  was, there was jokes and like ties to it all day regardless of that sort
Speaker 11:  of first 30 minutes or so focusing role on it. But it very much
Speaker 11:  felt like, yeah, copilot is our future or AI
Speaker 11:  is our future. Yeah. Like that's our next 50 years for for sure. That
Speaker 11:  was definitely what they were getting at. That's
Speaker 2:  Really interesting. I mean that's a, that's a big thing to say. I guess I
Speaker 2:  shouldn't be surprised that Microsoft is that all in on AI at this point,
Speaker 2:  but like that's a pretty meaningful statement of purpose to make
Speaker 2:  at an event like this where you don't have to, right? Yeah. Like you can
Speaker 2:  make it about Windows 95, but they, like, they, they,
Speaker 2:  it seems like they went out of their way to be like, no, we, we are an AI
Speaker 2:  company and that is where we are going.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, definitely. And, and they even treated it like, you know,
Speaker 11:  like you go to a product launch like an Apple launch or Microsoft stuff
Speaker 11:  where they have a new surface and you see it on stage and then you go hands
Speaker 11:  on. So they had that with copilot, they had all these like pods set up with
Speaker 11:  experiences that, with the new features that had just gone live. Like they,
Speaker 11:  they had the muse AI model, which generates gameplay and stuff, so
Speaker 11:  you could check that out. Copilot vision. And they, that copilot vision
Speaker 11:  actually was an interesting one because that one is
Speaker 11:  obviously open now, has done it, Apple's doing it, visual intelligence,
Speaker 11:  all that sort of stuff. But it's interesting how Microsoft's doing it because
Speaker 11:  it's like constantly rolling so it knows you don't have to like constantly
Speaker 11:  hit a button or like really focus it at something very
Speaker 11:  obvious for it to pick it up. Like I had one example where I had a game,
Speaker 11:  there was a game boy in front of me and I was like, tell me how to power
Speaker 11:  the game boy on. And it was like, I'll pop, you know the batteries in the
Speaker 11:  back and then you flick the switch at the top. So I flick the switch at
Speaker 11:  the top and it was like, oh, you've turned it on. 'cause it realized that
Speaker 11:  the LED had lit up. Oh, wow. Or, or it just assumed I was doing
Speaker 11:  that and just, yeah. And guessed. But that was an interesting
Speaker 11:  one. I was like, okay, this is really, does feel like it's watching what
Speaker 11:  you're watching. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It was really interesting to see the, the copilot stuff. It is kind of just
Speaker 2:  like a grab bag of all of everybody else's ideas about ai.
Speaker 2:  And I don't mean that as like a denigration of any of this. Like it
Speaker 2:  everybody has the same ideas. Right. So I think it's fine. Yeah. But it was
Speaker 2:  like, they did the shopping stuff. They're, they're doing some age agentic
Speaker 2:  stuff. They had the, the sort of of multimodal vision stuff. It's just like,
Speaker 2:  yeah, Microsoft keeps doing this thing that like slightly drives
Speaker 2:  me crazy where they're like, actually copilot is a million things. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And then they're like, nevermind, copilot is one thing. And then they're
Speaker 2:  like, nevermind it's a million things. And this felt like another sort of
Speaker 2:  bring all the copilots back together and they're like, this is, we want to
Speaker 2:  make sort of one holistic thing out of all of these many
Speaker 2:  features inside of copilot.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It always feels like they're like almost one step behind because they
Speaker 11:  take the open AI model. So open air does their streams and you know,
Speaker 11:  wows everyone with the new features. And then Microsoft sort of rolls 'em
Speaker 11:  out like a couple of months later or something. So this was very much that,
Speaker 11:  although it's, it's always interesting how they roll them out 'cause it
Speaker 11:  does feel like they do them in a slightly better way and a better
Speaker 11:  user experience, which is not usually what Microsoft does. So,
Speaker 11:  yeah. So they, they are doing pretty good with, with how they're rolling
Speaker 11:  it out. But yeah, you're right. It's, It is like taking the, the top features
Speaker 11:  of what everyone else has got. Yeah. And then polishing them essentially.
Speaker 11:  Which
Speaker 2:  Is not, I mean that is, to be fair, that's like, that's also Google strategy
Speaker 2:  and Apple strategy. Yeah. And it's just
Speaker 11:  Like everyone's doing the same, take the,
Speaker 2:  Take the good ideas and roll them into your bigger products. It it does kind
Speaker 2:  of work. Yeah. So you've spent a bunch of time over the last few weeks sort
Speaker 2:  of reckoning with Microsoft at 50 and this is a company you've been covering
Speaker 2:  for a really long time. And I'm curious like how,
Speaker 2:  where sort of Microsoft is in, in your head right now. Like do you have
Speaker 2:  sort of a grand theory of five decades of Microsoft coming out of all of
Speaker 2:  this retrospective and research?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I think I wrote about like reflection of
Speaker 11:  the last 50 years and, and like what Microsoft's kind of stood for and,
Speaker 11:  and where they are now. And I think It is a matter of, they were obviously
Speaker 11:  born as micro soft, which is like, you know, microcomputers and
Speaker 11:  software and I think we're still sort of in that era, but
Speaker 11:  it's, it's just they're very focused on software now. Mm.
Speaker 11:  They do have, you know, surface and stuff, but they, they, they seem to
Speaker 11:  be kind of playing it safe with that stuff. And then you've got Xbox, which
Speaker 11:  obviously was a big one of their hardware hits and that's kind of going
Speaker 11:  in the software direction as well. And it's obviously going, going towards
Speaker 11:  AI as well. And then you've obviously got the AI push as well, which is
Speaker 11:  driven partly by, by hardware advances and a lot by
Speaker 11:  software at the moment as well. So I think it's keeping true to
Speaker 11:  that software stuff where Mike thought is gonna go, I spoke to
Speaker 11:  one of their, he, he described himself as this mad scientist, deep Stevie
Speaker 11:  B is, is what we call him. And he
Speaker 11:  basically broke it down in the, in in the sense of like, Microsoft would
Speaker 11:  write traditionally write code once, right? So, so say they shipped
Speaker 11:  Word, they'd write that piece of code and then someone would install
Speaker 11:  it and maybe customize it however they want. Now they have to write a piece
Speaker 11:  of code for every person on the planet to use their software
Speaker 11:  with, with ai. So they're kind of like, that's the way they're looking at
Speaker 11:  it in this like agent push so that you'll have your own personal
Speaker 11:  agent that knows you and that's built for you.
Speaker 11:  So that's obviously a different, a very much a different challenge to how
Speaker 11:  they've built software before. So I think they're the early phases of that.
Speaker 11:  And like e even Stevie, like admit there's a
Speaker 11:  bunch of AI concepts out there, even Microsoft's doing them, but no one's
Speaker 11:  really kind of put them all together. And I think that's really where Microsoft's
Speaker 11:  gonna go for the next sort of 10 years is figuring out all those
Speaker 11:  distant concepts, bringing 'em together and then putting them in something
Speaker 11:  that is a lot more coherent.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well I think there, there's an interesting sort of parallel between
Speaker 2:  that and I actually think that's, that's about as sort of clean a straight
Speaker 2:  line as I've heard someone draw through Microsoft that It is like fundamentally
Speaker 2:  this is like a, It is a software company that actually sort of thinks about
Speaker 2:  people in a very coherent way across time. But then
Speaker 2:  like I look at, you know, we did the, the 50 best things Microsoft has ever
Speaker 2:  made and, and you ran down a bunch of kind of the the weird ideas that it's
Speaker 2:  had over time. And also this is a company that is just like fundamentally
Speaker 2:  all over the place all the time. And yeah, they have tried so many things.
Speaker 2:  Some of them have worked in huge ways, some of them have not. And I think
Speaker 2:  it was really interesting to read 'cause I don't think about Microsoft as
Speaker 2:  a sort of wacky experimental company in the way that like when
Speaker 2:  Amazon launches a hundred things running Alexa, right? Nobody thinks that's
Speaker 2:  weird, right? That sort of culturally makes sense inside of Amazon. And when
Speaker 2:  Google is like, here's 17 new messaging apps, you're like, oh Google. But
Speaker 2:  I don't think Microsoft has quite that same
Speaker 2:  reputation and yet it has tried and failed at
Speaker 2:  maybe more big things than almost anybody. And I think
Speaker 2:  one of the things that you argued is that Microsoft's sort of core competency
Speaker 2:  is that it, it actually like moves and pivots really fast. And so it's
Speaker 2:  just been, it was so interesting to just see those two things against each
Speaker 2:  other. It's like Microsoft kind of had one idea 50 years ago that it was
Speaker 2:  even more right about than it realized and it has carried it all the way
Speaker 2:  through and then around the edges it's just like pure chaos.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, It is. It's it's tried to respond sometimes successfully.
Speaker 11:  Like I'd say when they moved to the cloud that was, that was obviously very
Speaker 11:  successful and it's kind of set them up for where they are now. And it's
Speaker 11:  sometimes like spectacularly unsuccessfully, like missing the mobile era,
Speaker 11:  which probably cost them, I think 'cause the estimate is like 600 billion
Speaker 11:  or something. So quite a lot of money. Well
Speaker 2:  You put it like that.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Okay. So yeah, but they've navigated
Speaker 11:  throughout those like sort of eras. I I, I'd break them down really by
Speaker 11:  CEOs to be honest. 'cause you had the Bill Gates era, which is the PC on
Speaker 11:  every desk and Steve Bomber, which was kind of like the cloud and launching
Speaker 11:  Xbox and all that sort of stuff. And then you had sat Nadella, which was
Speaker 11:  very, which is very much the AI in the era now. Yeah. And, and sort of resetting
Speaker 11:  their culture as well. But yeah, they, they've navigated interestingly
Speaker 11:  throughout that 'cause there's so many things they've done like connect,
Speaker 11:  like the Zoom, like Barney toys. There's,
Speaker 11:  there's just so much that they've kind of experimented with. But I think
Speaker 11:  my point when I wrote about some of that stuff is that even though some
Speaker 11:  of those things are like blatant failures, like connect like
Speaker 11:  the HoloLens is that they take parts of that technology and then they
Speaker 11:  use it elsewhere. So it's like they are learning from those mistakes and
Speaker 11:  then they'll be like, well all the silicon work we've done on HoloLens is
Speaker 11:  now our quantum work. Oh, interesting. The the connect stuff, you know,
Speaker 11:  like some of that early connect work went into Windows. Hello.
Speaker 11:  Where you look at your laptop and it signs you in now. So there's all these,
Speaker 11:  there's all these sort of like through lines and even Cortana like help
Speaker 11:  them do the surface Pro X and some of the windows on arm stuff with windows
Speaker 11:  phone. So it's, there's yeah, there's, there's always failures, but then
Speaker 11:  there's successes through those failures, which is also, I don't think it's
Speaker 11:  very obvious when you look at the product you think that was a massive flop.
Speaker 11:  And it's like, yes, it was, but it also, you know, went on some like
Speaker 11:  Skype helped power Microsoft teams. Like there's, there's so many instances
Speaker 11:  of it. You could, you could make up another 50 lists. So. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think that's, that actually speaks really well of Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  culture. And I think Microsoft, Microsoft's culture has been,
Speaker 2:  I would say fairly correctly raked over the coals several times over
Speaker 2:  the years. But that, that fact, 'cause this is the thing we see a lot at
Speaker 2:  other companies. Something goes wrong, everybody leaves or gets fired and
Speaker 2:  all the work that they did just sort of gets mothballed. They're like, well
Speaker 2:  this is a mistake. Yeah. Moving on. We're gonna, we're gonna go over this
Speaker 2:  way now. And they sort of overcorrect in the wrong direction and some and
Speaker 2:  try something else. Right? And so that ability of Microsoft to actually like,
Speaker 2:  say like, okay, this thing didn't work, but what did we do that might work
Speaker 2:  somewhere else. It is actually a, it's a hard thing to do and it's, it's
Speaker 2:  impressive that Microsoft has done that so well so many times over the years.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, It is. And when I spoke to Stevie B for that, for that story,
Speaker 11:  it was, it was funny just going through the years of like, because
Speaker 11:  he, he's been instrumental to a lot of the stuff like the touch computing,
Speaker 11:  like even, you know, do you remember the first surface table that they did?
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. Where
Speaker 11:  They had it at like Cs and it was like the
Speaker 2:  Like pool table looking thing. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Yeah, yeah. And then they eventually had it in like a bunch of Vegas restaurants
Speaker 11:  and stuff. It was, yeah, it was wild. But he, he was the instrumental tool
Speaker 11:  of that sort of stuff and, and helping with connect and, and everything.
Speaker 11:  But when I spoke to him, it was interesting because he, he went through
Speaker 11:  all the sort of successes and the failures and how they experiment with
Speaker 11:  hardware and software. And then I, and then I was like, what is your favorite,
Speaker 11:  like paint? And he's sitting in his office and he is like,
Speaker 11:  and then he just reaches down and like clears like a path to the bottom
Speaker 11:  of his shelf and It is all the paint cubes are sin. Oh wow. He's like pulling
Speaker 11:  him up going, I like this one and this one led to whatever. That's pretty
Speaker 11:  cool. And he was just like, yeah, it was, it was just interesting seeing
Speaker 11:  the sort of like, 'cause he's been there for so long, it's just interesting
Speaker 11:  seeing the, the various stuff that they have patented and how
Speaker 11:  they've, you know, they've learned from those, those failures. Yeah. If
Speaker 2:  You will. Well it's also, I, going back through that list of 50 things is
Speaker 2:  like, it, it keeps occurring to me that maybe no company
Speaker 2:  in tech is better at missing by a little bit than
Speaker 2:  Microsoft. Yeah. Like Microsoft has been almost right so many
Speaker 2:  times. Yeah, I was looking, it's like, like Clippy is just
Speaker 2:  what we're doing now, right? Like Microsoft has been trying to do this thing
Speaker 2:  in various iterations for forever. That's true. And it, it, it, it was in
Speaker 2:  the right place at totally the wrong time.
Speaker 11:  Here's, here's something that Stevie said. He said, everyone is right if
Speaker 11:  you wait long enough.
Speaker 2:  So Yeah, I think that's right. I mean, and there's like, and there's a million
Speaker 2:  of those like what was the, what was the smartwatch that Microsoft was working
Speaker 2:  on like way before
Speaker 11:  The spot stuff? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right idea, wrong time and the tablets and the HoloLens. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  Cortana, it's like Microsoft is is always just 10
Speaker 2:  degrees off. Yeah. And it fits every time and then it occasionally hits it,
Speaker 2:  right? Like with the Xbox and you, you see what happens and it hit it right
Speaker 2:  with Azure and you see what happens and it's just,
Speaker 2:  it's track record of almost hitting and just missing is like
Speaker 2:  epic over its history.
Speaker 11:  But this, I guess it's the same for anything, isn't it? Right. Place at
Speaker 11:  the right time is just so, such a, like a common thing.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. They, they've definitely had the right ideas, but yeah, the timing
Speaker 11:  has has definitely been not quite right. So, but look at like HoloLens,
Speaker 11:  that was like, that was like genuinely like wow moment when I tried that
Speaker 11:  on, I was like, I couldn't believe it. And then 10 years later and
Speaker 11:  Meta's still trying to make that, that sort of experience of reality, right?
Speaker 11:  So it's not easy.
Speaker 2:  No. And it's, it's, there's so many of like did you ever watch that General
Speaker 2:  Magic documentary? No, I didn't. It's very good. I recommend it.
Speaker 2:  I'll put the link in the show notes. But it was basically this group of
Speaker 2:  people in like the early nineties who built a cell phone
Speaker 2:  and it, it had, it had all of the ideas that smartphones would later
Speaker 2:  have. They were just trying to build an iPhone, but they were trying to ship
Speaker 2:  the thing 13 years before the iPhone and the world wasn't ready, the technology
Speaker 2:  wasn't ready and it was like, oh, everyone saw it. And it's just a
Speaker 2:  matter of like being the one who makes the right thing at the right time,
Speaker 2:  that is actually what hits. And it's not like some magical
Speaker 2:  thing just happened. And I feel like there's so much of this in Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  history that is like, somebody sitting in the building was right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And they just, they just didn't, they were, they were too early
Speaker 2:  or they were like, they missed one piece of the thing that wasn't quite right.
Speaker 2:  They just, they just were one turn away from having it. Right. And there's
Speaker 2:  like, there's a fascinating like apple like hardware story that
Speaker 2:  almost happened inside of Microsoft. Like almost.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It's, it's like the ebb and flow of software and hardware, isn't it?
Speaker 11:  You get those hardware advances and that software that you were trying to
Speaker 11:  build, you know, a decade ago then becomes suddenly very relevant like
Speaker 11:  Cortana and Clippy and stuff. Like that's, that now
Speaker 11:  is where, where you could do a personal system, it would actually make sense.
Speaker 11:  Totally. Which, funny enough, that's all exactly what they're doing again,
Speaker 11:  which they kind of teased on stage at this 50th anniversary. Oh really?
Speaker 11:  They, they're, yeah, they're bringing like characters to co-pilots. You
Speaker 11:  have your individual and it visually will look different. So
Speaker 2:  I feel like they can't get away with bringing Clippy back. I just think it
Speaker 2:  would be, that's like a funny joke, but I don't think you can do that seriously.
Speaker 2:  But I think they could bring Bob back, right? You could, you could do Bob
Speaker 2:  again.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, well they did show Clippy at the end of the montage of characters
Speaker 11:  and I don't know if that means the paperclip is
Speaker 11:  back or, I dunno,
Speaker 2:  That would be the, the true ultimate sign of confidence in AI is
Speaker 2:  like, we we're doing clippy again, but we're we're doing it well this time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's like, it's, that's
Speaker 11:  I feel, I feel like they do it just to get people to download copilot
Speaker 11:  because that's gonna, like everyone will write the headline about that.
Speaker 2:  Right. So I mean, I would use it, I would, I would spend one whole day with
Speaker 2:  new clippy for sure. I get it. Yes.
Speaker 11:  You can now talk to Clippy. Right.
Speaker 2:  I'd be down, I'm ready for it. So I'm
Speaker 2:  really fascinated by this moment of like seeing the three different eras
Speaker 2:  and the three different CEOs sort of sitting next to each other on stage.
Speaker 2:  And like you described, there's three very different people who ran the company
Speaker 2:  three very different ways, but it still kind of keeps being
Speaker 2:  Microsoft and obviously there's no indication that Satya Nadel is going anywhere
Speaker 2:  anytime soon. No, he's, he's
Speaker 2:  relatively young. He's doing very well. Company's going fine. Like I feel
Speaker 2:  like that is that dude's job for a long time. Yeah. But what, what is your
Speaker 2:  sense of kind of the next turn for Microsoft? Is there, is there some
Speaker 2:  big shift coming or we in the middle of it already because it's the AI
Speaker 2:  story?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I think, I think we're in the middle of it if I'm honest. It's just
Speaker 11:  the way they talk about it and the investments they're making is clear
Speaker 11:  that that's their next big bet and they do these big bets
Speaker 11:  occasionally. They got kind of go all in because, and I think
Speaker 11:  we saw it with the augmented reality stuff and then HoloLens and stuff.
Speaker 11:  They really went for that because they, they genuinely thought, you know,
Speaker 11:  computing was gonna go in that direction.
Speaker 2:  Do you think, was that at the same level as this though? I was trying to
Speaker 2:  think like what, what in their history feels as
Speaker 2:  big a swing as AI does right now? And like I cloud definitely Cloud one
Speaker 11:  Is Yeah. Is the only one, isn't it? The
Speaker 2:  Whole Azure thing. And I was, I was debating this with HoloLens
Speaker 2:  and ar 'cause they certainly made a lot of noise about it, but there wasn't,
Speaker 2:  it didn't feel like the future of Microsoft was
Speaker 2:  inside of HoloLens in the way that it does with AI to me. But I don't know,
Speaker 2:  maybe, maybe you feel differently.
Speaker 11:  They did like a big swing with Windows eight. That's
Speaker 2:  True.
Speaker 11:  They really tried to, to make it so that apps would go across phone and
Speaker 11:  exports and that and that, that that failed spectacularly. Yes, it did.
Speaker 11:  Especially the design.
Speaker 2:  But another one, I I this is, this is the hottest take I will say on this
Speaker 2:  entire podcast. I think history will be kind to Windows eight. I think Windows
Speaker 2:  eight had some good ideas.
Speaker 11:  It did, yeah. It did have good ideas. It was just, it was just too much
Speaker 11:  for the, you know, the traditional power users of Windows. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think if they had done like Windows 11 and then 10 and then eight,
Speaker 2:  it might have worked a lot better.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Maybe
Speaker 2:  Instead of, instead they're just like doing it in reverse. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Yeah. But it, it definitely feels like AI
Speaker 11:  is their natural next sort of transformation. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  It was interesting just all three CEOs being on stage, like you were saying,
Speaker 11:  and them trying to interact with each other and you could, they, they were
Speaker 11:  talking about, you know, the the hits and misses and what they
Speaker 11:  liked about each other, which Bill Gates was like, I like
Speaker 11:  the fact that Steve Palmer and SATs and de are good with people.
Speaker 11:  It's like, which is funny. That's pretty good. And and Steve
Speaker 11:  Palmer was like, just Satya doing a great job because he is like, you know,
Speaker 11:  tripled my stock. So that's real. Yeah. Which is, which is true.
Speaker 11:  But they, they all, they all kind of talked, well, especially Bet
Speaker 11:  Gates talked about AI and he's made some pretty big statements about
Speaker 11:  ai, you know, replacing jobs and stuff, which I don't think many
Speaker 11:  technologists are, are kind of exactly agreeing on right now.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I've got the sense that AI is the, the next transformation and that's,
Speaker 11:  that's where they're putting everything. Like they, they're putting $80 billion
Speaker 11:  in, right? Yeah. And they had like a town hall a few weeks ago where they,
Speaker 11:  where they talked to employees about it all and employees were kind of like
Speaker 11:  challenging them on why are we investing so much money in this
Speaker 11:  AI thing? And they were like, well we have 300 billion
Speaker 11:  of contracts that are lined up for the next few years. So, and, and a lot
Speaker 11:  of those involve cloud and ai so we're gonna get our
Speaker 11:  return essentially is what they're saying. So
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting. Yeah, and I think if you're Microsoft,
Speaker 2:  the question for me always with Microsoft is how desperately is it going
Speaker 2:  to try to be consumer relevant? Because I think, and and
Speaker 2:  we've talked about this a lot, there is this thing where it's like, I, I
Speaker 2:  think if you think of Microsoft as like the leading B2B AI company
Speaker 2:  that feels totally plausible to me, right? That like it's, it's gonna, it's
Speaker 2:  gonna build the sort of enabling technology. It's gonna have the cloud infrastructure,
Speaker 2:  like that's where all the money is gonna be for the foreseeable future anyway.
Speaker 2:  But if, if Microsoft is happy being like the Microsoft of
Speaker 2:  AI then then you're fine. But Microsoft has
Speaker 2:  never been able to turn off this thing where It is desperate to be like mainstream
Speaker 2:  relevant to regular people outside of work in their day to day. And
Speaker 2:  I feel so much of that tension in copilot where Microsoft is like, we, we
Speaker 2:  want you to use this at work and we know you will and we know how to do that
Speaker 2:  'cause that is like Microsoft's core competency. But also when you go home,
Speaker 2:  we want it to be your best friend and we want you to hang out with your family
Speaker 2:  like in teams. Like I just, people will not use teams in their day-to-day
Speaker 2:  life. I just don't believe it. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  Absolutely not.
Speaker 2:  I hope that I'm wrong. I guess if you do it with your family, I'd love to
Speaker 2:  hear from you. But like, and that's fine if you're Microsoft, but like, it,
Speaker 2:  it just can't help itself in some ways and I'm so curious to see where it
Speaker 2:  lands.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, it's interesting you mentioned that because that's another part of
Speaker 11:  the vibe that we didn't really touch on that was kind of the vibe of the
Speaker 11:  event was there was like a very influencer, you know, that sort of
Speaker 11:  vibe. They, they invited a bunch of people that I've never seen
Speaker 11:  at Microsoft event before. So, you know, doing like
Speaker 11:  selfies of everything and it was very much that it did feel like
Speaker 11:  that for the whole day. It felt like a party influencer vibe
Speaker 11:  and YouTubers and there's some, there's some folks there that, that have
Speaker 11:  covered Microsoft a bunch. Like I Justine and Austin Evans and yeah,
Speaker 11:  there's some of the big names but there was just a bunch of influencers
Speaker 11:  and like lifestyle influencers, you know,
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting.
Speaker 11:  It was an interesting, it felt like everything I've been seeing
Speaker 11:  kind of where Microsoft are going where they want people to focus on copilot
Speaker 11:  in, in an event. So it was definitely an interesting sort of sub vibe
Speaker 11:  to the things. Yeah. Do you affiliate it with co-pilot where you mentioned
Speaker 11:  that you, they want it at work and at home. The co-pilot at home is is like
Speaker 11:  so different to the work one, right? Like the work one is just doesn't have
Speaker 11:  the same UI at all. So there's there's, there's tension there and I dunno
Speaker 11:  how they're gonna resolve that. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and I feel like I get the work one, right? Like I I I can sort of see
Speaker 2:  where that's going. It makes sense to me and like obviously there, there
Speaker 2:  is such a super high ceiling if you can build the consumer one, but
Speaker 2:  the, the path to get there and even what that looks like is just
Speaker 2:  vastly less clear to me. But It is, It is like the shiny object to everybody
Speaker 2:  definitely even OpenAI, which could just like happily sell subscriptions
Speaker 2:  to developers forever and make all of its money. It is like how do we make
Speaker 2:  Chad GPT yell at you so that it's more fun to use. Like this is, I don't
Speaker 2:  know what, I don't know what problem we're gonna solve there, but everybody
Speaker 2:  is desperately trying to figure it out.
Speaker 11:  They're all trying to do it. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And it's gonna, it's gonna
Speaker 11:  be interesting.
Speaker 2:  Alright, I'm gonna let you go here, but tell me about the 50th anniversary
Speaker 2:  surface and then I'm gonna let you go.
Speaker 11:  Oh yeah, so they've done a 50th anniversary surface. It's not too crazy
Speaker 11:  different. It is basically got a golden accent on the, on the logo
Speaker 11:  at the back and then it's got the, you know, 1975 disco
Speaker 11:  balls stuff on the, on the etch on the palm rest. Oh, that's cool. The old
Speaker 11:  like retro logo, so that's cool. But they're not selling it so you'll have
Speaker 11:  to win one or I think they're probably gonna sell them to employees as well,
Speaker 11:  so.
Speaker 2:  All right, well if you have one and wanna sell it to us, I have, I got 50
Speaker 2:  bucks with your name on it, so send us an email and also we, we
Speaker 2:  think are, we are, we're getting surfaces this year hopefully, right? Are
Speaker 2:  we, are we due for surfaces? Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Build is what, in six
Speaker 2:  weeks?
Speaker 11:  Yes. I might be back out to Seattle again. I
Speaker 2:  Think you might
Speaker 11:  Be, we could be speaking like this again.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right. Well for now Tom, thank you as always.
Speaker 2:  Good to see you go get some sleep. Thank
Speaker 11:  You.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to a question
Speaker 2:  from The Vergecast hotline. Be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast hotline. As
Speaker 2:  always, the number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is
Speaker 2:  vergecast at The Verge dot com. Thank you by the way, to everybody who reached
Speaker 2:  out with thoughts about minimalist phones doing that exercise with Allison
Speaker 2:  Last week was so much fun and you all had so many good, smart thoughts about
Speaker 2:  it that I think I'm actually gonna compile a bunch of them and throw them
Speaker 2:  all at Allison again and we're just gonna have to rerun that whole thing
Speaker 2:  in a couple of weeks. So stay tuned for that. For now, we have a
Speaker 2:  question from our email from Katie. Lemme read it to you. Katie writes,
Speaker 2:  I'm sure I won't be the only person asking this question true. By the way,
Speaker 2:  we got this question a bunch of times. This is very much a thing on people's
Speaker 2:  minds. The tariffs are projected to hit the car and tech industries the hardest
Speaker 2:  in thinking about preparing for this. I'm wondering if I should invest in
Speaker 2:  a new phone now rather than waiting till mine reaches obsolescence
Speaker 2:  potentially in a time when phones become much more expensive. To give you
Speaker 2:  an idea of the consumer, I tend to be, I currently have a pixel six, which
Speaker 2:  is working just fine. I'm not a person who is looking for the highest end
Speaker 2:  product or who upgrades unless my phone ceases to function. I'm very conscious
Speaker 2:  of the environmental impacts of the industries associated with the materials
Speaker 2:  and phones. I just don't wanna find myself in a bind in a year or two if
Speaker 2:  things keep going the way it looks like they're going. Thanks. This is,
Speaker 2:  this is the question right now and, and I think I I will say two things.
Speaker 2:  The two things that I should say right at the very top are that a,
Speaker 2:  who knows if any of this is real, right? The, the Trump administration's
Speaker 2:  tariff policy has been on and off and on and off and on and off that if you
Speaker 2:  were to ask me to bet whether these were going to stay
Speaker 2:  in effect the way that they are forever, I would say I absolutely have no
Speaker 2:  idea. I think what we've learned from the Trump administration, even just
Speaker 2:  over the last several days is that they are, they're very serious about these.
Speaker 2:  Donald Trump loves tariffs as a, as a weapon. He also loves them
Speaker 2:  as a negotiating tactic. And if this is just a way to force all of these
Speaker 2:  companies and all of these leaders and all of these politicians to come see
Speaker 2:  him and, you know, bend the knee and make a deal so that there's no more
Speaker 2:  tariffs, maybe that's where this lands. It'll be really messy in the interim,
Speaker 2:  but maybe fast forward three months from now, and most of
Speaker 2:  this is back to the way that it was with just a lot of chaos in between.
Speaker 2:  There's, there's a lot of precedent for that arc in the Trump administration,
Speaker 2:  but that is one possible outcome. Trump has also continued to say that he
Speaker 2:  believes in tariffs like he has said it all along. He said it in his campaign,
Speaker 2:  he has said it as president, like he, he believes tariffs are
Speaker 2:  good and that they work. And so I wouldn't rule out any
Speaker 2:  possibility here. And so all we can do is I think operate with the
Speaker 2:  facts on the ground right now and the facts on the ground right now suggest
Speaker 2:  that things are about to get a lot more expensive. And I think a bunch of
Speaker 2:  folks on our team, particularly Alison Johnson on our team, who has been
Speaker 2:  doing a lot of really great work reporting on phone tariffs in particular,
Speaker 2:  the general consensus seems to be that the phones
Speaker 2:  today are not likely to get vastly more expensive for a bunch of
Speaker 2:  reasons, right? Like if you're, if you're Best Buy, you have a bunch of inventory,
Speaker 2:  it's also just really hard to like raise the price on an existing
Speaker 2:  device. What is much more likely in many of these cases is
Speaker 2:  that the next round of these phones is going to be more expensive. So we
Speaker 2:  have the, the iPhone 17 coming in the fall. We have the Pixel 10 coming
Speaker 2:  probably in the fall. We have new Samsung stuff coming this summer. There's
Speaker 2:  just a round of new phones due in a few months. And I think there is a
Speaker 2:  strong chance those phones will be substantially more
Speaker 2:  expensive. So I think it, frankly, if you're the person who is like happy
Speaker 2:  to be a few generations behind, it doesn't strike me as totally
Speaker 2:  wrongheaded to buy this year's phone on the bet that
Speaker 2:  next year's phone, even if it's better, is also likely to be significantly
Speaker 2:  more expensive. That goes against my normal buying advice, which is like,
Speaker 2:  buy the best device that you can and then keep it forever if there is a
Speaker 2:  chance that the next iPhone is going to be several hundred dollars more expensive,
Speaker 2:  which again, I, I wouldn't bet on it, but I also wouldn't bet against it.
Speaker 2:  I can see why you, you might look at a 16 and be like, okay, price to value,
Speaker 2:  this might be the best phone we're gonna get for a minute here. And
Speaker 2:  that is a, a reason to do it. If you're on a Pixel six, I think you're,
Speaker 2:  you're probably good for another year or two if you're happy with your phone.
Speaker 2:  Now there's also ways you can upgrade you. You can replace the battery, you
Speaker 2:  can replace the screen by itself. Like you, you can make devices last longer.
Speaker 2:  And that's my other piece of advice for anybody who's trying to think about
Speaker 2:  how do I make sense of like my gadget options here.
Speaker 2:  I would say frankly buy the stuff that you know you're
Speaker 2:  gonna need quickly because I think it's possible we're gonna run
Speaker 2:  into supply constraints as companies scramble to figure this stuff out. It's
Speaker 2:  possible that the, the makeup of some of these devices is gonna change as
Speaker 2:  things like costs change. And as supply chains change, the, the
Speaker 2:  gadget you want may not be the same gadget for forever.
Speaker 2:  Prices might go up. So I think there, there is a real impetus to say, okay,
Speaker 2:  if I have a thing that works, how do I make it work longer? Like, I'll just
Speaker 2:  give you an example. I have these Bose quiet comfort headphones
Speaker 2:  and they're like, they're fine, but the, the ear cups on them
Speaker 2:  are just starting to wear, right? And so I've been sitting around being like,
Speaker 2:  okay, do I just upgrade? I think it's these, these are a bunch of
Speaker 2:  years old now. They're still fine, but I would like a better pair of
Speaker 2:  headphones. And so I'm like, okay, maybe, maybe these wearing out is a good
Speaker 2:  excuse to just go out and upgrade anyway. Now my answer is I'm gonna buy
Speaker 2:  new ear cups and I'm just going to keep using these headphones for as long
Speaker 2:  as I can. And I'm, that's just is what it's gonna be.
Speaker 2:  Headphones are expensive, they are potentially going to get more expensive
Speaker 2:  and I just, I'm gonna choose not to worry about that and put off that purchase
Speaker 2:  for as long as I can. So I think where I've landed personally amidst all
Speaker 2:  this chaos, all the advice I can give you is where I've landed is the things
Speaker 2:  I know I'm gonna need to do soon. I'm gonna do now. And
Speaker 2:  anything I can put off, I'm going to try and take steps to put off as long
Speaker 2:  as possible because it does feel like wherever we're headed is
Speaker 2:  gonna be messy, right? Like, I'm gonna try and make as few 20, 25
Speaker 2:  purchases as I can and I'm gonna try and make them all right. Now,
Speaker 2:  I don't know if that's the perfect strategy. I, I don't know if we're gonna
Speaker 2:  end up in like a, do you remember that early phase of the pandemic where
Speaker 2:  people were like, ho hoarding toilet paper? I don't know that a
Speaker 2:  run on that kind of thing in the gadget world is the right thing, but I do
Speaker 2:  know that It is a time of incredible uncertainty and it does feel
Speaker 2:  like things could go sideways. So I would look at it and say, okay, do
Speaker 2:  I think I'm gonna need a new phone in the next six months? And if the answer
Speaker 2:  is yes, I think just buy it now. There's not a great reason not to anyway.
Speaker 2:  The, the Pixel nine's a great phone. There's a bunch of good stuff out there.
Speaker 2:  I think there's a strong chance that whatever comes next is gonna be a lot
Speaker 2:  more expensive. I just go for it. I bought my wife a, a Pixel eight. She
Speaker 2:  likes it a lot. Great price, no notes. Very happy to have
Speaker 2:  solved that before we get outta here anyway, I would also
Speaker 2:  love to know what you think about this. By the way, if you have thoughts
Speaker 2:  or have made purchases or put off purchases or thinking about how to manage
Speaker 2:  this stuff, I'd love to hear from you. Vergecast to the virgin.com 8, 6, 6
Speaker 2:  Virgin one, one is the hotline. This is like a complicated
Speaker 2:  question and it's a very VERGE question. We like talking about what you should
Speaker 2:  buy and when and for how much. And I think this is a wrinkle we have
Speaker 2:  not dealt with many times in, in the course of being on The Verge is
Speaker 2:  how is global politics going to change the price of your phone? It
Speaker 2:  always does, but it does much more directly now than I think most of us have
Speaker 2:  realized in the past. Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you
Speaker 2:  to everybody who came on the show and thank you as always for listening as
Speaker 2:  ever. If you have questions, thoughts, feelings, games that you can play
Speaker 2:  forever or purchases that you want, talk about if you want us to help you
Speaker 2:  figure out what to buy and when. Frankly that's what we're here for. So hit
Speaker 2:  us up. Vergecast at The Verge dot com is the email 8 6 6 VERGE one one is
Speaker 2:  the hotline. We check on both. We love hearing from you. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. Vergecast is The Verge
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neil, and I'll be back
Speaker 2:  on Friday to talk about, I don't even know what Brendan Carr gadgets,
Speaker 2:  more ai, chaos, probably more tariffs, let's be honest with each other and
Speaker 2:  everything else. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.