# Transcript
ID: 2f0f53ed-dc34-4387-bc86-8e6181ed3cc1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8267171490980933325/4690319473789287517/s93290-US-6786s-1748222745.mp3
Description: Bad news if you don't care about AI: this week was absolutely chock-full of AI news. First, Nilay, David, and The Verge's Alex Heath talk about the news that OpenAI and Jony Ive are teaming up to build... something. A gadget, for sure, maybe lots of gadgets. We don't know much, but we have a lot of thoughts, and a lot of questions. After that, the hosts talk through all the news at Google I/O, including what's new with Gemini, Google Search, Project Astra, Project Mariner, and the countless other ways Google is putting AI absolutely everywhere. Finally, in the lightning round, we buckle up for another round of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, talk through some late-breaking Apple gadget news, and marvel over the future of conference calls.
Speaker 4:  Hello. Welcome to our chest, the flagship podcast of Alex Heath and I
Speaker 4:  trying to talk to Sergei Brynn and being deflected at every opportunity.
Speaker 4:  It was rough. It was bad.
Speaker 4:  Hi your friend Neil. Alex Heath is here. Hey, what's going on? David Pierce
Speaker 4:  is here. Hello. So Alex and I were at IO at google io. It's big news of the
Speaker 4:  week. Google announced a bunch of stuff. We're gonna talk about it where
Speaker 4:  there was this moment where Sergey was in the AI
Speaker 4:  sandbox, like the demo area. He was there last year too and he like talked
Speaker 4:  to reporters for a long time just riffing about ai. So he was there at the
Speaker 4:  end this year and I kept describing it as like the sword
Speaker 4:  in the stone. Like all these reporters kept on trying to talk to him and
Speaker 4:  just like failing, including me,
Speaker 4:  including both of us. This
Speaker 5:  Makes me think somebody must have given him a speech not to talk to reporters.
Speaker 5:  'cause the other thing that Strike a Bri likes to do is just say some truly
Speaker 5:  wild stuff that is not helpful if you're Google.
Speaker 5:  But he likes to talk to people. So I assume somebody gave him a stern speech
Speaker 5:  not to talk to reporters.
Speaker 4:  No, I don't think it was that Actually he was working on a demo. Like
Speaker 4:  he was in the demo. Right. He was like playing with the stuff. Right. And
Speaker 4:  he, it was flow, the new video tool that Google released that runs on VO
Speaker 4:  three where it's like, it's basically just, it's like iMovie for AI video.
Speaker 4:  Right. And he was trying to get it, I think to make
Speaker 4:  himself like he was prompting it to make himself. I miss
Speaker 4:  missed that. That's that's really good. That's what I heard. Like secondhand.
Speaker 4:  But he was, I, I mean I watched him using it and say out
Speaker 4:  loud like, this isn't working the way it should. And then someone else, you
Speaker 4:  know, then all the Googlers were like, this isn't working. And he looked,
Speaker 4:  he was very locked in on whatever was doing. And then someone else told me
Speaker 4:  that it's not supposed to make Sergei brand. So he was trying to make it
Speaker 4:  make Sergey
Speaker 5:  Brand. That's amazing.
Speaker 4:  So he was like totally focused on this thing not working, which is why he
Speaker 4:  wasn't talking to anyone. And then he went over to do the glasses demo. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Is that the AI executive of like Googling yourself every once in a while?
Speaker 5:  You like train the new model and then see how successfully it can
Speaker 5:  replicate you and that's, that's your model of how big a deal
Speaker 5:  you are.
Speaker 4:  It is it? Yeah, probably. I mean how often do you think Ssar Googles himself?
Speaker 4:  I like that must be crazy making 'cause you are the one person who can
Speaker 4:  actually just change the search rankings and be
Speaker 4:  likes like Sundar Pecha is, is super cool. Dot com is gonna be the first
Speaker 4:  result.
Speaker 5:  Everything is an episode of Silicon Valley, Eli, every single thing.
Speaker 4:  I mean, it was just very funny 'cause everyone saw him. He was just like
Speaker 4:  in the middle of the room and I had just failed. I walked over and
Speaker 4:  I was like, Hey man. And he was like, whatever. And I just like left and
Speaker 4:  then like three other reporters had that experience. And then Alex, you know,
Speaker 4:  star reporter Alex, he like super confidently saunters over there.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, he's gonna, he's gonna try to pull that sword out the stone
Speaker 4:  man. He just like did, didn't happen. The
Speaker 6:  Eye roll that I got from a Google Communications executive as I approached
Speaker 6:  Sergei was was was really good. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It was good. But later he crashed. He crashed a another keynote.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like Demi, the ceo EO of Google DeepMind was doing a like a keynote
Speaker 4:  interview type deal, fireside chat and just like came
Speaker 4:  on stage with him and everyone's like, here I'm, and then he did in fact
Speaker 4:  say just bonkers things. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Including like, I just get to tell this guy what to do and
Speaker 6:  we live. We may be in a stack of simulations. Yeah. There was a lot. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. His answer to do we live in a simulation was if you think we live in
Speaker 4:  one simulation and the people who made that simulation also live in a simulation
Speaker 4:  and you have to deal with that. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Neli, you've been going, you've been going to IO for longer than me. Did
Speaker 6:  this feel like a return to early IO for you? Like I
Speaker 6:  heard a few people be like, especially the Sergei talk, but
Speaker 6:  it just felt like 10 years ago. Like, I don't know, I don do
Speaker 6:  you, do you see what I'm saying there?
Speaker 4:  I do. It was different. Google's just more corporate now. Yeah. In
Speaker 4:  in that way. We'll come to it. I think it was very confident and I think
Speaker 4:  that's what people were picking up on.
Speaker 5:  Google's feeling itself again in a, in a real way that we should talk about.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They were like, we can do stuff. And they haven't felt that way like
Speaker 4:  for like the past several years. Like here's what we've done. We've added
Speaker 4:  one feature to Android and Samsung is gonna use it. And that has been IO
Speaker 4:  and this was very different. There was a lot of confidence in IO this year.
Speaker 4:  We should After that. We're gonna come to that in a second. I, we, I think
Speaker 4:  we have to start with Johnny, ive and Sam Altman
Speaker 4:  trying to upstage IO by announcing a company called io. Like
Speaker 4:  literally the next day before we get into all the news, we're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  about that. We're gonna talk about, like I said, Google io. There's lightning
Speaker 4:  round. Brendan has Brendan, two pieces of housekeeping.
Speaker 4:  One, we have a survey about The Vergecast, what you want from us, what you
Speaker 4:  want from our podcast. That's a vme.com/survey. Go go take the survey.
Speaker 4:  Someone will make a chart and then we'll, we'll, we'll listen to them.
Speaker 4:  I think we're obligated to say that. We'll listen to 'em. I think you, you
Speaker 4:  know the truth.
Speaker 5:  Here's what I promise is that if you take the survey, I will give a
Speaker 5:  readout on this podcast of Neli yelling at whoever presents us the chart
Speaker 5:  at the end of this process. So do the survey.
Speaker 4:  No one can tell me what to do. That's what we sell here. And then second,
Speaker 4:  speaking of no one can tell us what to do. One of the ways that we protect
Speaker 4:  ourselves from being told what to do is by having a direct financial relationship
Speaker 4:  with you, the reader slash listener and VERGE subscriptions are on sale
Speaker 4:  for Memorial Day. 'cause we're like, why not have a sale? They're 40% off,
Speaker 4:  which means they're $35 a year. That's The Verge dot com slash subscribe.
Speaker 4:  And what you were buying, just to be very clear, yes. A bunch of great reporting.
Speaker 4:  David getting increasingly redder on the YouTube channel every week. That's
Speaker 4:  something that we provide for that, that money. And then, you
Speaker 4:  know, our ethics, what we fundamentally sell here is our ethics policy. You
Speaker 4:  just can't tell us what to do. We don't do brand integrations, sponsorships.
Speaker 4:  I don't think a phone casemaker in, in the middle of the review videos. 'cause
Speaker 4:  no one can tell us what to do. And we, we get to do that 'cause you pay us
Speaker 4:  the money directly and then take a survey and then we don't listen to the
Speaker 4:  survey. It's a weird feedback loop, but it works. Works. I think it's been
Speaker 4:  working for us. It's
Speaker 6:  Good. 30 $35 is good too. That's like a salad in Mountain View.
Speaker 4:  It really
Speaker 6:  Is.
Speaker 5:  That's one era, one smoothie. Yeah. In LA terms it's
Speaker 4:  Good. We're, we don't, we're, you know, we're new to this particular game.
Speaker 4:  This is our first ever sale. I've, we, I feel like, I literally feel
Speaker 4:  like I'm trying to sell you a Cadillac right now. But we have,
Speaker 4:  we are learning all these moves and it's like kind of fun. It's like new,
Speaker 4:  new problems to solve. So let us know how we're doing and by let us know
Speaker 4:  how we're doing. I mean spend $35 a year on our product. Thank you.
Speaker 4:  Is that how you sell anything?
Speaker 5:  Doing great.
Speaker 6:  Eli's on three hours of sleep. Guys, we just, I just wanna say that going
Speaker 6:  into this show,
Speaker 4:  My flight was delayed coming home from IO and so it effectively turned
Speaker 4:  into a red eye and I'm just super loopy. I'm, I'm
Speaker 4:  drinking coffee at during the afternoon Vergecast for the first time in years.
Speaker 4:  So we're gonna get through it. It's gonna be great. Okay,
Speaker 4:  let's start with Johnny. Ive in
Speaker 4:  his arms,
Speaker 4:  I mean that's what they announced. They announced Johnny Ives walk, right.
Speaker 4:  Sam Altman, Johnny Ive released a video. I think they got scooped a little
Speaker 4:  bit. Alex like, I think the Journal and Bloomberg kind of had it
Speaker 4:  and then they, they like put out this video to announce it. That's, that's
Speaker 4:  my sense of it.
Speaker 6:  They had some embargoed stuff. Johnny and Sam Altman did
Speaker 6:  a couple interviews. They did one with Bloomberg, one with the Times and
Speaker 6:  then in a very good spot people saw Johnny
Speaker 6:  actually filming this video that he did with Sam on
Speaker 6:  May 2nd, like early May. That's, so this
Speaker 6:  video was done almost a month ago.
Speaker 4:  So there's this announcement that the basics of the announcement is near,
Speaker 4:  as I can understand It, is that Johnny Ives started a new company that
Speaker 4:  is staffed by a bunch of his star former Apple designers. That company
Speaker 4:  is called io. Very funny because this company lasted for
Speaker 4:  two minutes and it has been sold to OpenAI
Speaker 4:  for 6.5 billion in OpenAI stock. Which is also a very complicated
Speaker 4:  idea. And then Johnny, ive himself is not
Speaker 4:  going to go work at OpenAI. He's gonna stay at his design agency love
Speaker 4:  firm, which will now have no other clients except for OpenAI
Speaker 6:  At some point. Yeah. The
Speaker 5:  Only tick that's more complicated than that is that open AI's
Speaker 5:  investment firm I believe was associated with io.
Speaker 5:  But OpenAI will tell you that open AI's investment firm is not part of OpenAI.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Fun fact, a thing I found out this week is that the OpenAI startup
Speaker 6:  fund is not part of OpenAI.
Speaker 5:  None of this makes any sense. It's all pretend like the thing to remember
Speaker 5:  at the beginning of this is all the money is pretend like all the money that
Speaker 5:  Sam Altman can raise is always pretend all of the different machinations
Speaker 5:  of how the money moves around is pretend whether OpenAI is or is not a for-profit
Speaker 5:  company is pretend this new company they created is pretend like it's,
Speaker 5:  it's all made up.
Speaker 4:  And the, the products that they've announced the most pretend of all. Yes.
Speaker 4:  So they, they released a video so they announced this deal, they're gonna
Speaker 4:  work together, they're gonna make a new generation of hardware products.
Speaker 4:  I think they're coming the first start coming next year. You gotta,
Speaker 6:  So I would say like announced at the end of next year in shipping in
Speaker 6:  2027 if I
Speaker 4:  Had to guess. But what they really shipped was this video.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  And I, I think the reason my adult, my sleep deprived brain
Speaker 4:  is like there the video was the people, lots of people saw them making this
Speaker 4:  video in early May and I think everybody understood something was up.
Speaker 4:  And I, the fundamental thing they announced in this video is that Johnny
Speaker 4:  Ive walks around like he owns the place.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  You just have, you just have to watch it. It isn't, It is literally one of
Speaker 4:  the most confident walks in history. It's
Speaker 5:  Very good
Speaker 6:  And it's this very, you know, grandiose thing and it looks like they're just
Speaker 6:  walking through San Francisco, you know, with a camera following them and
Speaker 6:  it, you know, it's just the normal city street on a given day. And then you
Speaker 6:  see people shooting when they were actually filming and people were like
Speaker 6:  filming the, the set and it's all staged. Like everyone walking
Speaker 6:  across the like intersection with Johnny with his arms swinging. Like
Speaker 6:  every it, it wasn't made by AI but it also wasn't,
Speaker 4:  Yeah it does have a lot of advice. Lots of people on, on various social platforms
Speaker 4:  are like counting the wine bottles behind them. I saw one person fully crash
Speaker 4:  out being like the cups are moving from shot to shot And it's like, yeah
Speaker 4:  it's 'cause it's a lot of different shots they edited together. It's fine
Speaker 4:  you guys. Anyway, the video is those two sitting in a a
Speaker 4:  restaurant having little cups of espresso together basically
Speaker 4:  saying that they love each other and that there's a new class of
Speaker 4:  computing devices to be made with AI and then Johnny's going to
Speaker 4:  do that in some way with open ai. That is the sum
Speaker 4:  of the announcement in the video.
Speaker 6:  Also San Francisco is awesome. There's a lot of love for San Francisco
Speaker 6:  and just generally like what if we change the world? You know, like
Speaker 6:  it's, it's just this big like, you know, idea of two guys changing
Speaker 6:  the world. I mean Yeah. Who doesn't love that?
Speaker 5:  I think the only like specific thing I can think of that comes out of
Speaker 5:  It is there is one device that already exists
Speaker 5:  in some form. They have made a thing together. Yes. And there's been
Speaker 5:  reporting that these two have been working together on hardware for a long
Speaker 5:  time now. So something exists, I don't know how many of them there are, I
Speaker 5:  don't know how finished It is, but like It is clear that there is one
Speaker 5:  product in actual honest to God development. But their plan
Speaker 5:  is to build a whole family of devices.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Altman actually says in the video that he just took the prototype
Speaker 6:  home, right? So this was in early May. You just got to take the first device
Speaker 6:  home. I think we should talk about the reporting on the device and how it
Speaker 6:  may or may not work. I just wanna really quick through, really quickly run
Speaker 6:  through how this whole thing came about. 'cause I think this probably
Speaker 6:  surprised a lot of people when they saw this. So I've talked to
Speaker 6:  OpenAI and Love from now and the rundown is basically that
Speaker 6:  two years ago Sam and Johnny were
Speaker 6:  introduced about a year ago, actually almost exactly a year ago.
Speaker 6:  They decided to start a new division inside Love from to work on
Speaker 6:  AI devices together. And that division includes a bunch of
Speaker 6:  legendary early Apple design leaders that worked under,
Speaker 6:  ive including Evans Hanky who ran the industrial design group at Apple
Speaker 6:  after he left. And then she left in 2023 and went to
Speaker 6:  Love from, and they were doing this for several months and then employees
Speaker 6:  at Open Eye, employees at OpenAI were starting to come in and work
Speaker 6:  at Love from together with them. And then towards the end of last year,
Speaker 6:  love from was thinking about raising a lot more money for
Speaker 6:  io, this division of the company doing hardware. And that
Speaker 6:  was when Altman was like, what if we just buy you guys fully? So they had
Speaker 6:  already invested in this love from subsidiary through
Speaker 6:  the OpenAI startup fund that is not owned by OpenAI
Speaker 6:  and they just bought the rest of it. And so now a team of about
Speaker 6:  55 people who are a lot of early Apple design
Speaker 6:  people are going over to OpenAI and a new hardware
Speaker 6:  division that's rolling up to directly to Sam. And Johnny is
Speaker 6:  staying at love from with his design team but will now also
Speaker 6:  oversee all of design at OpenAI, not just hardware.
Speaker 6:  And Johnny also works with Airbnb. He
Speaker 6:  helps Brian Chesky on high level design stuff. He works with Ferrari. He's
Speaker 6:  actually designing the first ever electric Ferrari. And I
Speaker 6:  think he wants to keep doing other things. But I think once there are projects
Speaker 6:  that they're doing, you know, end, they're gonna be almost fully devoted
Speaker 6:  to open ai. But he's also staying independent. So
Speaker 6:  pretty unusual because if
Speaker 4:  You're Johnny I the idea that you'll ever have another boss has to just not
Speaker 4:  even, yeah it's just like not a square on the bingo card that exists.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But also like Nila, your point about the thing that they made is this
Speaker 5:  video is the thing, right? Like this is, this is the
Speaker 5:  cache that OpenAI literally couldn't buy for any amount of
Speaker 5:  money except to give it all to Johnny. Ive there is like this company is
Speaker 5:  desperate to convince people that it can make good, interesting, cool products
Speaker 5:  and that It is not going to get lapped by big tech companies as all of the
Speaker 5:  like science behind this stuff gets closer and closer and like
Speaker 5:  the way to win here is to convince everybody that your Apple and that
Speaker 5:  you're gonna do the hardware software services thing. And boy is there
Speaker 5:  not a better way to do that than to put Johnny Ive and his confident walk
Speaker 5:  in your video. So like, I frankly would be shocked if it, at the end of all
Speaker 5:  of this Johnny Ive is like day-to-day involved in making products with OpenAI.
Speaker 5:  But it doesn't matter. This, this today it was like the
Speaker 5:  announcement was the thing and that's, that's all you need from Johnny.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Literally just need his voice in their keynote Right.
Speaker 4:  For you know, being like plastic's inevitable and like it's fine. He'll be,
Speaker 4:  he'll be fine. But I, before we get into the device,
Speaker 4:  'cause there's some reporting about what it might be there, we have a lot
Speaker 4:  of guesses over what it might be. The idea here is that Sam Halman is Steve
Speaker 4:  Jobs, right? Yep. That it's very clear. Like even in that video
Speaker 4:  he's like, I'm, everything in my life has led to this moment.
Speaker 4:  Altman makes reference to the iPhone and the MacBook Air and he is like,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna build the next version of this. And then, you know, they just
Speaker 4:  spend a lot of time looking deeply into each other's eyes and talking about
Speaker 4:  working together in California. And you're like, oh, I know exactly what
Speaker 4:  they want people to take from this. Right? It's, it's just very clear
Speaker 4:  they, they want to be Apple and they hired Apple's legendary design team
Speaker 4:  and then you're gonna position Altman as the next Steve Jobs and Altman
Speaker 4:  revere Steve Jobs, he's best friends with Brian Chesky, who also revere
Speaker 4:  Steve Jobs. Chesky was just on decoder. He talks about Apple as though he
Speaker 4:  is like the world's foremost PhD student of Apple. It's like very funny.
Speaker 4:  Also, that episode doesn't come out, it'll come out next week by the time
Speaker 4:  you're listening to this. I asked Ju very directly about Ive
Speaker 4:  and Alman and all he said was, I'm very proud to have introduced them. Good
Speaker 4:  Dodge. I told, I congratulated him on that dodge. But
Speaker 4:  there's some big like foundational things to point
Speaker 4:  out about wanting to be the next Steve Jobs with AI is
Speaker 4:  the foundational technology for the next device. And I think the most important
Speaker 4:  one is that the AI systems don't work well yet.
Speaker 4:  Like you just have to acknowledge it, right? Like
Speaker 4:  I've and Jobs together, the first thing they
Speaker 4:  made was the iMac, right? That's the first big hit product that those
Speaker 4:  two combined to make. And the iMac
Speaker 4:  was an right, it was just an all in one CRT. It is a piece of hardware.
Speaker 4:  Like the big innovation was that it was blue and the thing that made it
Speaker 4:  a hit was that the web existed, right? That
Speaker 4:  was the whole thing of the iMac was there's a new
Speaker 4:  application, there's a new killer app for desktop computers and
Speaker 4:  we're gonna sell you this blue one with a handle and it's easier to set up
Speaker 4:  than the Windows pc. And that rejuvenated Apple and
Speaker 4:  the, the technology bet was that people wanted to get on the internet and
Speaker 4:  that worked. That was just there, it was, it was happening. The
Speaker 4:  next one was the iPod. And I, it's easy to forget now, but the
Speaker 4:  technology bet there was John Rubenstein went and found a tiny
Speaker 4:  Toshiba hard drive and Phil Schiller invented the click wheel
Speaker 4:  and and they were able to package that together into the iPod. The, but the
Speaker 4:  core technology was Toshiba made this little hard drive and they don't know
Speaker 4:  what to do with it. And you can like go read Stephen Levy's book,
Speaker 4:  it's called the, the, the Perfect Thing, is that what it's called? But it's
Speaker 4:  literally like, what are we gonna do with this hard drive? And the music
Speaker 4:  player, the iPhone was like, we invented Multitouch and that is a
Speaker 4:  thing. We're gonna make a whole phone outta this and you just keep going
Speaker 4:  on up. There's these like big core technologies that I was able to
Speaker 4:  package into new kinds of products with a visionary who was like, I
Speaker 4:  know what kinds of technologies will lead to products
Speaker 4:  like the iPhone for example. They were doing the iPad first and Steve Jobs
Speaker 4:  was like, no make phone then we'll do come back into the iPad. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  that's the dynamic between the two characters here.
Speaker 4:  AI isn't that product yet. Like this is like, I made an
Speaker 4:  iPod and sometimes the hard drive just lies to you,
Speaker 4:  right? Like that would be weird. I may, I invented the iPhone, but the
Speaker 4:  screen sometimes tries to bang Kevin Rus is
Speaker 4:  like that. That is the, the level of capability that the core
Speaker 4:  technology they're trying to build these products has. And I,
Speaker 4:  I, I'm just, I find myself just like utterly full of skepticism
Speaker 4:  that open ai, open AI as it's presently configured, having lost
Speaker 4:  a bunch of its research people and its product people
Speaker 4:  can, can turn the corner. I don't I'm I
Speaker 4:  the it like maybe I'm just like very sleepy, you know, and
Speaker 4:  more cranky than usual. But I'm just like all of the hit products
Speaker 4:  had a core technology innovation that definitely worked
Speaker 4:  right? And people were like really skeptical of some of them. People were
Speaker 4:  really, really skeptical of typing on a Multitouch keyboard
Speaker 4:  and the thing they were able to do was design their way through that and
Speaker 4:  make it good.
Speaker 5:  I mean I think that's a, a lot of credit to give to the first generation
Speaker 5:  of all of those technologies, which in many, like the first iPhone was not
Speaker 5:  good. It was like fascinating and cool, but it was like it was bad
Speaker 5:  at a lot. But
Speaker 4:  Multitouch worked.
Speaker 5:  Multitouch worked. I think so. Okay. Here's, here's what's wild to me and
Speaker 5:  I think this, this is gonna be a theme of today's episode, is I think
Speaker 5:  your assessment of how good AI is is correct
Speaker 5:  and I think most people don't care. I think most people think AI is very
Speaker 5:  good. Yeah. And I, I increasingly don't know what to
Speaker 5:  do with that. That like people, the the like approval rating
Speaker 5:  of chat GPT is actually very, very, very, very high. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Whether or not it's any good or lies to you or not
Speaker 5:  is is relevant but also in a weird way sort of beside the point at
Speaker 5:  this point, like people are so enamored with this stuff
Speaker 5:  that they're willing to look past all that stuff. And so maybe it doesn't
Speaker 5:  matter and I'm like this, this is where I'm so torn on all of this that like
Speaker 5:  the big question about all of these AI devices, right? Is like a do
Speaker 5:  people want another device that they have to buy? I think the answer
Speaker 5:  to that is yes. Like everybody always wants know their device to buy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that's fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Point and shoot cameras have made a comeback. David, I think we can
Speaker 5:  Can, but people got onboard with, with smart watches when there was a reason
Speaker 5:  for smart watches, people got on board with wireless headphones that are
Speaker 5:  really expensive. Like people will keep buying new gadgets if there's a reason
Speaker 5:  for them. The question is, is there an AI specific thing to do?
Speaker 5:  And I think to me that is both a, like is the tech any good question
Speaker 5:  and is there a UI for this? That makes sense. Question. The UI for this that
Speaker 5:  makes sense I think is still a wildly open question. But like is
Speaker 5:  the tech good enough for people to want to use it all day every day? I think
Speaker 5:  the answer's yes. Whether it should be or not is a different question, but
Speaker 5:  I think It is
Speaker 6:  The UI is voice and I, I think back to Eli's point, like there was a key
Speaker 6:  tech bet of how people wanted to use it with each of the things
Speaker 6:  that Johnny did with with jobs. I think here people do want to
Speaker 6:  talk to chat GPT, they want to do advanced voice mode and they
Speaker 6:  don't want to have to configure the action button on the iPhone and wait
Speaker 6:  three seconds for it to load up and connect to the internet to actually work.
Speaker 6:  I think if you had a always on listening
Speaker 6:  ambient aware thing that you could have a conversation with,
Speaker 6:  I think people would do that. I mean, my wife told me yesterday, she was
Speaker 6:  like, I just said thank you back to CHATT and it made me feel very
Speaker 6:  strange like unprompted, you know, like yep. People are building real,
Speaker 6:  I mean we were hearing this at io like afterwards like people are having
Speaker 6:  real almost relationships with these AI
Speaker 6:  and yeah, if you introduce something that you can just talk to all day long,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's the her concept, which Sam Altman is obsessed with the Spike
Speaker 6:  Jones film. And you know what I've heard about this product and the form
Speaker 6:  factor is, is a little mushy is basically the
Speaker 6:  ideas that bike demo we saw at IO this week where
Speaker 6:  a guy's trying to fix his bike and he's talking to the AI throughout it and
Speaker 6:  it knows what he's looking at and it's guiding him through it. And
Speaker 6:  if it does work, if it's not hallucinating, that is just fundamentally a
Speaker 6:  more human way to use technology. It's just like talking to it
Speaker 6:  and it's helping you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Does it lie? Does it get things wrong? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Does it matter and will it be good enough maybe?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's very funny how many tech demos at every stage of
Speaker 4:  technology involve trying to fix something. Like my
Speaker 4:  first ever Microsoft HoloLens demo, they had me change a spark plug in an
Speaker 4:  A TV. Yeah. And they're like weird. This is the future of changing these
Speaker 4:  spark plugs and like we're just doing it again. And lots of people have change,
Speaker 4:  lots of spark plugs without like data centers in overdrive. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's only like three ideas, right? It's like every new technology is
Speaker 5:  is for playing Assassin's Creed, fixing your car more
Speaker 5:  successfully and buying elaborate vacation
Speaker 5:  plans. Like that's it in Spanish. That's all hundred percent
Speaker 4:  Percent in Spanish. Yeah. Yeah. Those are the three. Which one is it? You
Speaker 4:  just tell me which one. It's right. I get all that. I, I you know, my
Speaker 4:  skepticism about AI is not do people like it? I've, I've really come around
Speaker 4:  to there is a widening gulf between how people talk about
Speaker 4:  how much they hate AI online and then people using it in
Speaker 4:  real life and how much they use it. How much they like it, it,
Speaker 4:  you can sense it, it's there is a turn Sundar io on
Speaker 4:  stage said we're entering a new phase of the platform shift.
Speaker 4:  And what he meant was the products are coming out now, right? That we're
Speaker 4:  not just talking about model scores. Like here's a bunch of new products.
Speaker 4:  I think chatt PT is that product for OpenAI, but it does it chat GB as It
Speaker 4:  is currently configured will never return on the massive amount of investment
Speaker 4:  that OpenAI has taken. Correct. They need to be Apple, they need the iPhone,
Speaker 4:  they need the app economy of the iPhone. They need to be the richest company
Speaker 4:  in the world. But this literally that is the only target that makes sense
Speaker 4:  for their level of investment. That's a big problem. And I'm just,
Speaker 4:  again, I'm just coming back to does the core technology let them
Speaker 4:  do the thing they wanna do or is it people just like it so much that they
Speaker 4:  will skip over the fact that it's brittle And
Speaker 4:  what I've has traditionally been successful at is designing
Speaker 4:  to the limitation, right? He makes, he makes the
Speaker 4:  limitation the the most successful part of the product. It's a little hard
Speaker 4:  drive. The whole thing looks like a little hard drive. Yeah. And we're gonna
Speaker 4:  talk about how many songs it has. Remember unapologetically plastic,
Speaker 4:  like these are his moves, right? Like he says, I
Speaker 4:  I made it feel inevitable. And the thing that's inevitable is the limitation
Speaker 4:  of the technology is the product and you don't feel the
Speaker 4:  limitation 'cause it's designed to make that the, the thing that makes the
Speaker 4:  product good. And you might think that I'm just like a, a sleepy man who's
Speaker 4:  rambling, but think about the first iMac and how it was translucent. So you
Speaker 4:  could see that CRT display that was the limitation of the product.
Speaker 4:  They, they had to build it around this giant vacuum
Speaker 4:  display and he made it the centerpiece of the product so
Speaker 4:  that over the lifetime of the product they made that plastic clearer and
Speaker 4:  clearer. That was the investment in the materials was to do the appropriate
Speaker 4:  EMF shielding in the plastic itself to be transparent instead of just translucent.
Speaker 4:  And so that the CRT became the center of this, that that's, ive like at the
Speaker 4:  highest level that is Johnny Ive, we're gonna make the antenna the band of
Speaker 4:  the iPhone four. So you can't, if you hold it wrong, the signal drops. That's
Speaker 4:  Johnny Ives stuff. Right. How do you design to the limitation of AI
Speaker 4:  is it currently exists. I, I think the
Speaker 5:  Question of how much credit for that kind of stuff Ive gets is going to be
Speaker 5:  one of the pieces of this that is really interesting because if you look
Speaker 5:  at the Johnny Ive era at Apple after Steve Jobs,
Speaker 5:  it's a lot less of what you just described. Yep. And It is a lot more of
Speaker 5:  Johnny Ive pursuing things that are aesthetically lovely for the sake of
Speaker 5:  making things that are aesthetically lovely and that's, that's fine. That's
Speaker 5:  a perfectly good approach to doing a lot of things. That's also how you get
Speaker 5:  the butterfly keyboard and it's how you get like laptops that literally
Speaker 5:  just stopped working for people for a gen. Like they just made a series of
Speaker 5:  bad decisions about laptops in order to make pretty laptops.
Speaker 4:  It's how you get a mouse that you have to charge upside
Speaker 5:  Down. Right. That's just the thing that happened. And I think about even
Speaker 5:  like the, the Apple watch, which was a true, like Johnny
Speaker 5:  I've led project Johnny I've decided to build a
Speaker 5:  watch and then worked backwards towards the Apple Watch and they landed in
Speaker 5:  the wrong place. They, they landed in a place that I think is really fascinating
Speaker 5:  but it, it took like two pivots from the first idea before Apple
Speaker 5:  had a hit product. And So I think this question of like
Speaker 5:  Johnny's capability to make beautiful things
Speaker 5:  is like beyond question.
Speaker 6:  Well we'll see he's doing the electric Ferrari. We'll see how good that looks.
Speaker 5:  I mean nobody's perfect every time. Right. But I think like in terms of
Speaker 5:  I would bet, I would bet a lot of money on whatever they make
Speaker 5:  looking and feeling great.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think that's the bet that has to be the, I mean look, so Sam Altman
Speaker 6:  had this meeting inside OpenAI that was reported on by the Wall Street Journal
Speaker 6:  and he told them that this 6.5 billion acquisition
Speaker 6:  has the potential to add 1 trillion in value to OpenAI. Sure.
Speaker 6:  Which is just like, you know, making up numbers, you can
Speaker 5:  Just say things,
Speaker 6:  But like this is where he started to talk a little bit about those
Speaker 6:  limitations neli that you're talking about. He said the device isn't going
Speaker 6:  to be a pair of glasses and that it's something
Speaker 6:  to wear. Although it sounds like they're not gonna want to call it a
Speaker 6:  wearable. And then, you know, he's saying we're
Speaker 6:  not gonna ship a hundred million devices literally on day one. Duh.
Speaker 6:  But he does think they'll get there faster than any company ever.
Speaker 6:  And you know, Alman is just, this is, he's great at hype, right? Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  this is obviously he's hyping this up to employees who are like, why did
Speaker 6:  we just give Johnny Ive $6 billion and he's not joining us.
Speaker 6:  But he did. So this is from the meeting he said that the product will
Speaker 6:  be capable of being fully aware of a user's surroundings and life will be
Speaker 6:  unobtrusive able to rest in one's pocket or on one's desk
Speaker 6:  and will be a third core device a person would have after
Speaker 6:  a MacBook Pro and an iPhone. So here we go. This is like a better
Speaker 6:  humane pin.
Speaker 4:  I mean not for nothing. The Humane pin was designed by two
Speaker 4:  former Apple designers who regretted their work on the iPhone,
Speaker 5:  Many of whom were called legendary when they started this company. Imran
Speaker 5:  Chowdry as legendary as it comes coming out of Apple. Did
Speaker 6:  You get Altman gave them millions of dollars in funding. He
Speaker 5:  Was the single biggest investor in the company. Like it's just, we're doing
Speaker 5:  Humane again. But now it's Johnny I've
Speaker 4:  I did say that Humane Pin was a poor product which tracks with
Speaker 4:  your review, David. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And the Truth. That's right. Good call by Johnny.
Speaker 4:  I would say that I called that watching the first demo video the Humane pin
Speaker 4:  and maybe I've, maybe I've lost some friends forever because of that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I've also called the Rabbit a poor product, which I think Jesse, Lou
Speaker 4:  and Rabbit loved because Johnny I knows who they are
Speaker 4:  and they released a a long statement being like, we love that the pie is
Speaker 4:  growing and I Good
Speaker 6:  Luck guys. Let me read this. Jesse sent us a statement, it's actually amazing.
Speaker 6:  He says it's an honor to get mentioned by Johnny Ivan, Sam Altman, however
Speaker 6:  we don't like to be put side by side with Humane. A company that stopped
Speaker 6:  trying got acquired and shut down. That's
Speaker 4:  Very good. That's brutal.
Speaker 5:  You can call us shit, but don't compare us to Humane.
Speaker 4:  That's very good.
Speaker 6:  That's very good Jesse.
Speaker 4:  That's really good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You can tell that he wrote that not not the robot. You know, like you can
Speaker 4:  tell when it's like that's human. Like don't compare me to Humane
Speaker 4:  but that those are the products and there's a million of them. David, you
Speaker 4:  reviewed a bunch of like note taking products, right? Like I'm gonna have
Speaker 4:  a microphone that's talking like recording all the time. Yeah. Last time
Speaker 4:  I saw Joanna Stern, she was wearing a wristband that records everything and
Speaker 4:  the lights were backwards. Yeah. It was red when it was off.
Speaker 5:  It's called the B vs. Reviewed it for us. It's, it's, it's a delightful and
Speaker 5:  terrible product,
Speaker 4:  Right? I mean there's just like a million of these devices that's like what
Speaker 4:  if we just feed input into an AI and then it does
Speaker 4:  something. Yeah. Right? It's summarized or talk to you or whatever. And that's
Speaker 4:  what I mean by the limitation. Like the limitation of those products is very,
Speaker 4:  very obvious. Right? The ais can't, they can't take actions for you. Right?
Speaker 4:  The agents don't work yet. Maybe they will. We'll talk about that with io.
Speaker 4:  Like there's a lot of activity around how to make the agents work and
Speaker 4:  go do stuff for you when you ask them to do it. The ai right? They don't
Speaker 4:  actually know a bunch of stuff that the search features don't work as well
Speaker 4:  as they should. Like there's just a bunch of stuff where the limitation of
Speaker 4:  the product is so obvious because the interface is
Speaker 4:  so good. Yeah, I'm just gonna talk to this thing and it's gonna talk to me.
Speaker 4:  And then everything beyond that is like house of cards and I, I just,
Speaker 4:  yeah, okay. Maybe we can make a more beautiful humane pin and we won't call
Speaker 4:  it a pin. Maybe we can make earbuds that talk to you like her, which
Speaker 4:  Altman really has been obsessed with for a long time. What's it gonna do?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That makes it valuable. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I do, I do come back to that Google bike demo. I think the idea is just always
Speaker 6:  on ai. That can be your girlfriend, boyfriend or your
Speaker 6:  assistant on the device itself. Mxi quo who's a pretty
Speaker 6:  reputable analyst, he, he covers Apple.
Speaker 6:  He's saying that mass production for this is expected to start in 2027.
Speaker 6:  The current prototype is slightly larger than the AI pin with a form factor
Speaker 6:  as compact and elegant as an iPod shuffle. Okay.
Speaker 6:  And then one of the intended use cases is wearing the device around the neck.
Speaker 6:  It'll have cameras and microphones for environment detection, no display.
Speaker 6:  It's expected to connect to smartphones and PCs. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's one of these just always on listening AI devices but made from
Speaker 6:  brushed aluminum. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Eli, to your point, this is everybody's idea, right? Like this is, this is
Speaker 5:  the thing everyone is, is pushing towards. I have, I have four of them on
Speaker 5:  my desk right now that are like a, a little thing with a microphone in
Speaker 5:  it that you wear on a lanyard. Yeah. That goes around with you. And I think
Speaker 5:  in a lot of ways that is actually probably the correct format for this
Speaker 5:  kind of stuff Right now if the goal is just like lots and lots of AI input,
Speaker 5:  especially if this thing is gonna have a camera, which I think it has to,
Speaker 5:  to come even remotely close to what Sam and
Speaker 5:  Johnny are talking about here. Sure. Like a little thing on a lanyard makes
Speaker 5:  a lot of sense. I will say I went back this morning and watched the, the
Speaker 5:  intro to the original iPod Shuffle, which was from 2005. And
Speaker 5:  Steve Jobs like shows off the thing, does a, a great reveal the whole thing.
Speaker 5:  And then they have this giant set of promotional photos of people
Speaker 5:  wearing it around a lanyard like Apple really wanted to make this the thing
Speaker 5:  that you would wear it. They had the white lanyard. It was like the, the
Speaker 5:  cap for the USB port was also the cap for the lanyard. It looked so
Speaker 5:  stupid and just looking back, I'm like, I don't think I ever once saw a
Speaker 5:  person in the wild wearing an iPod shuffle around their neck. The shuffle
Speaker 5:  became like a pocket device. And the problem
Speaker 5:  with like the humane pin, maybe not above all else, but one real
Speaker 5:  problem with the humane pin was that it, it sat right here. It was a thing
Speaker 5:  you had to look at all the time and it was looking at you all the time. And
Speaker 5:  this is very similar to that. I think you have to do it if you want to have
Speaker 5:  a camera. But that is a, that's just a high bar to clear for any
Speaker 5:  of these kinds of products.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Also anything that size does not have a battery or a chip in it
Speaker 4:  that can do any of the things that they want it to do.
Speaker 5:  I will say I think if you, there, there are a lot of ways to do this
Speaker 5:  and one of them is just to like offload a ton of that onto your phone
Speaker 5:  and just do all the work over like Bluetooth and local
Speaker 5:  wifi and not worry so much about it. Which is like that's what
Speaker 5:  meta's glasses do. Humane didn't do it and it was a huge mistake
Speaker 5:  and I suspect anyone who is doing this going forward will learn that lesson
Speaker 5:  of like, this thing actually isn't ready to be a fully self-contained device.
Speaker 5:  But I think if you just take it as like a pure input system
Speaker 5:  and do all of the work on your phone,
Speaker 5:  I can sort of see how you'd get a battery that could last.
Speaker 4:  So you're selling 100 million Johnny, ive designed
Speaker 4:  microphones and cameras that can, that require an iPhone to use. You know
Speaker 4:  what
Speaker 5:  It makes me think of? Do you remember the Google Clips camera? Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  gonna be that with a microphone.
Speaker 4:  I mean there's, you know, there's a couple of players in there who have a
Speaker 4:  vested interest in not letting Johnny I supplant their products.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, right. One of 'em is Apple. They're, they're stumbling around lately
Speaker 4:  but I think after this video in which Johnny I have referred to his own products
Speaker 4:  as legacy devices that are 10 years old and should be replaced are not
Speaker 4:  going to show up and be like, yes you can have preferred Bluetooth access
Speaker 4:  to it. You're always on chat GBT, like good luck. No, no watchmaker in
Speaker 4:  history has gotten that access to iOS and maybe,
Speaker 4:  you know, maybe governments around the world will shatter Apple into a thousand
Speaker 4:  pieces and let this happen. But you, you've now made a $1 trillion bet on
Speaker 4:  that. So good luck.
Speaker 5:  Well the deep irony of all of this is that is the exact thing that
Speaker 5:  OpenAI and all these other companies are desperate to get around. They're
Speaker 5:  like, we have to build the next platform so that not everything is, you know,
Speaker 5:  intermediated by your phone and these two operating system makers
Speaker 5:  and yet they all are going to have to be completely intermediated by
Speaker 5:  your phone, otherwise the hardware's gonna be bad.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then the other one is Android, which is more open and would allow
Speaker 4:  many, many more of these things to happen. But Google is as we'll
Speaker 4:  talk about in the next segment, a pretty ferocious competitor to
Speaker 4:  OpenAI when it comes to AI products.
Speaker 4:  And then your market in Lucy the United States is people with Android phones.
Speaker 4:  Good luck, Johnny. Like I, there's just a problem there like to solve like
Speaker 4:  either all the compute is in the device, which is what Meta is pushing towards.
Speaker 4:  And I mean we've heard Zuck, I think Zuck has said it to you, Alex, like
Speaker 4:  he's furious that Apple won't give him access to the Bluetooth stack on the
Speaker 4:  iPhone. Yeah. And the glasses are worse on the iPhone than on Android. I
Speaker 4:  I don't think Altman's gonna get that deal. Like the, I
Speaker 4:  again, I'm just like, what are the limitations? Johnny has great success
Speaker 4:  and maybe he did a better job at it when Steve Jobs was there than after.
Speaker 4:  But his great success is designing to the limitations. Making the limitations
Speaker 4:  feel like they're not there because they're so apparent in, in having
Speaker 4:  covered Apple for all of that time, right? In like
Speaker 4:  gadget blog days where we would obsess, we would write thousands of words
Speaker 4:  about screen radius on on LCD screens like we did it
Speaker 4:  and we, I I we are immersed in the culture that that
Speaker 4:  developed but it's now the design culture everywhere. Part of the problem
Speaker 4:  for Ive like in a big way is every product company has
Speaker 4:  a design culture that is his design culture. Right? Like
Speaker 6:  Why is that a problem?
Speaker 4:  'cause he has to do something new. He has to stand out. Like his moves are,
Speaker 4:  you know,
Speaker 4:  when I was like learning to play the guitar, my guitar teacher was trying
Speaker 4:  to teach me how to play Guns and Roses and Van Halen and I was like, this
Speaker 4:  stuff is whatever, it's a garbage. It is like, it's so cliche. And he was
Speaker 4:  like, that's 'cause they invented it and now everything is this. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's Johnny I, Johnny I is Eddie Van Halen. But you listen to like Van
Speaker 4:  Halen now you're like, this is going, this is some campy stuff And at the
Speaker 4:  time it was like a revolution and it's because it's everything. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like it's the foundation for everything And like he's got, he's gotta reinvent
Speaker 4:  some moves here and I just, I'm just, I'm focused on
Speaker 4:  there are some real limitations to these products in making the limitations,
Speaker 4:  the strengths. Maybe he'll do it. I'm not a great designer. Right. He's the
Speaker 4:  legendary designer. But what's, we've seen a lot of shots.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I am going to remain cautiously
Speaker 6:  optimistic about this just because of I the fact that
Speaker 6:  I do think a lot of people would talk to Chad GPT in
Speaker 6:  a device like this if it worked, if it was a good looking version of the
Speaker 6:  humane pin that actually worked, that didn't take five minutes to
Speaker 6:  load, that didn't also like blow up after five minutes 'cause the battery
Speaker 6:  doesn't work. Like if all of that is fixed, which has is a huge if
Speaker 6:  and you get access to you know, the leading chat PT models and it syncs
Speaker 6:  with your chat chat PT account that by the way already knows everything about
Speaker 6:  you 'cause you are saying thank you to it even when you don't need to.
Speaker 6:  That's interesting. And you know, one of the things that Altman said in this
Speaker 6:  meeting that really stuck out to me was he said, we both got excited about
Speaker 6:  the idea that if you subscribe to chat PT we should just mail you
Speaker 6:  new computers. Sure. And he actually said something else at
Speaker 6:  a VC conference I caught a couple weeks ago where he said the goal
Speaker 6:  for open AI is to now be the core AI subscription for your life.
Speaker 6:  So my prediction, and this is an informed prediction, is that
Speaker 6:  chat p subscribers will just get these devices or they'll get them
Speaker 6:  heavily subsidized and he's gonna build a subscription model
Speaker 6:  around not just software but hardware, which everyone has tried.
Speaker 6:  Apple has tried, it didn't really work. I mean they have the installment
Speaker 6:  program but they wanted to bundle everything more and that program never
Speaker 6:  got off the ground. We'll see if they can make it work.
Speaker 4:  Do you know why that program never got off the ground? 'cause the cell carriers
Speaker 4:  wouldn't let them get it off the ground. Ah,
Speaker 6:  There you go.
Speaker 4:  The cell carriers want that recurring revenue.
Speaker 6:  And that's another thing is like, do they need cell carriers for this? Right.
Speaker 6:  How does that change things? TBD probably
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A a different set of gatekeepers. Yeah. Who are
Speaker 4:  even worse to deal with than Apple. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The question of how ambitious this thing sets out to be, I think is gonna
Speaker 5:  be just as interesting as anything else because like
Speaker 5:  Alex to your point, there are, there are a lot of pieces of the puzzle here
Speaker 5:  and OpenAI and Johnny I have together control more
Speaker 5:  of those pieces than anybody else has. Right? Yeah. Like in terms of
Speaker 5:  being able to actually make the whole stack work together, that's a lot of
Speaker 5:  the stack, but it's not all of the stack and a lot of the stack
Speaker 5:  is either out of their control or will require like honest to
Speaker 5:  god like physics breakthroughs that no one has made yet.
Speaker 6:  If there's no display, the physics breakthroughs are probably not as bad
Speaker 6:  as we think. I mean they probably have disassembled humane and figured out
Speaker 6:  exactly everything they did wrong and are gonna learn from it. And Sam saw
Speaker 6:  that as like a I'm gonna invest in this thing to see how it doesn't work
Speaker 6:  and I'm gonna do it the right way with Johnny. We'll see,
Speaker 5:  I mean Humane was not full of dumb people. No, It is like the cautionary
Speaker 5:  tale of Humane is, it's like, like one of the things Conan O'Brien always
Speaker 5:  says is it takes a lot of really smart people working really hard to make
Speaker 5:  a bad movie. Yeah. And like the humane pin is, is the
Speaker 5:  perfect version of that. To me it's like a lot of people doing their best
Speaker 5:  who are very smart and very capable and have really long track records who
Speaker 5:  made a horrible product. Yeah. And there's like, that's such an easy way
Speaker 5:  to go. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We should, we should not beat up on Humane too much more. I just am saying
Speaker 6:  like
Speaker 4:  Disagree. No, I think you should read the Jesse statement again actually.
Speaker 6:  But like if by the end of next year there's an option in chat GPT to
Speaker 6:  get this, you know, Johnny I Polka Deck e
Speaker 6:  mailed to your house for an extra $20 a month and your pro subscription
Speaker 6:  and it'll automatically hook into everything chat. GPT already knows about
Speaker 6:  you and it's an always on listening device for talking to chat
Speaker 6:  GPT. Do I think people will want that? Yeah, I think a lot of people would
Speaker 6:  want that.
Speaker 5:  I I totally agree. We'll see if you're Sam Altman, you've looked at how many
Speaker 5:  people happily ponied up $200 a month just to use your cool stuff.
Speaker 5:  And I think the, the like subscription is
Speaker 5:  whatever they want it to be for this kind of stuff. I think It is where they're
Speaker 5:  headed.
Speaker 4:  All right. We should wrap this up. I will say that I can already hear the
Speaker 4:  people furiously writing us tweets and emails about the iPhone upgrade program,
Speaker 4:  which it currently exists. What we are talking about, just to be a hundred
Speaker 4:  percent clear, is that Apple wanted to bundle getting a new iPhone every
Speaker 4:  year into Apple One. And they were not able to do that.
Speaker 5:  Also, subscription hardware is a bad idea and everyone should feel bad about
Speaker 5:  doing it. Do you remember when Logitech said A Forever Mouse? And we laughed
Speaker 5:  at them. This is a forever Mouse.
Speaker 4:  Sam Altman's Forever Mouse sounds like an incredible movie. I just swear
Speaker 4:  like I would go watch whatever that is, that's a stage spectacular that I
Speaker 4:  would absolutely go watch. I don't know what It is. It feels like one of
Speaker 4:  those like places in London that's like next to the wax museum. Sam Altman's
Speaker 4:  Forever Mouse. Like what I was You ask chatt PT to render that, email that
Speaker 4:  to us instead of your angry emails about the iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Great. There we go.
Speaker 4:  I bad give you. All right, we gotta take a break and we're gonna talk about
Speaker 4:  the other side of io, which is actually Google io. See
Speaker 4:  what I did there. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. We gotta talk about Google io, which if not
Speaker 4:  for Johnny Ivan, Sam Altman literally trying to upstage Google io
Speaker 4:  with their own company called IO would've easily been the o like only thing
Speaker 4:  we talked about in the today. 'cause so much happened there.
Speaker 5:  I do feel a little bad. We, we allowed open AI and Sam Altman to get away
Speaker 5:  with this by putting it first in the show. They
Speaker 4:  Did it again. That was you by the way. I wanna be a hundred percent clear.
Speaker 4:  That was David's decision. Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  I I did that and I stand by it and I am deeply annoyed that
Speaker 5:  I'm giving Johnny and Sam what they want.
Speaker 4:  It was, it was interesting timing because Google had a great io
Speaker 4:  like by all accounts. Yeah, I think they announced a bunch of stuff that
Speaker 4:  people were excited about. The demos are all really good. They announced
Speaker 4:  a bunch of stuff that is shipping soon. Like we got to try a bunch
Speaker 4:  of this stuff in including the glasses, which are, you know,
Speaker 4:  they're just more prototype AR glasses. But they were there and we people
Speaker 4:  got to try 'em. There's a video with V wearing them and they
Speaker 4:  Googled just everyone from Sundar on down just full of
Speaker 4:  confidence. David, run us through the, the big news
Speaker 4:  and let's get into it. Oh
Speaker 5:  Boy. Okay. So I think the, the overarching story
Speaker 5:  of Google IO is Google is absolutely convinced it's winning at
Speaker 5:  ai. Yeah. And especially I talked to a bunch of the folks over there
Speaker 5:  ahead of IO including De who runs DeepMind and all their AI stuff
Speaker 5:  and they are like really feeling themselves with
Speaker 5:  Gemini 2.5 and are are convinced that not only are they ahead, but
Speaker 5:  they might be ahead in a way that is hard for others to quickly catch
Speaker 5:  up with. Which I think is fascinating. And so now Google is like, okay,
Speaker 5:  we have, we have what we perceive to be the best model. We have
Speaker 5:  vast distribution everywhere on the internet and we are going to put AI in
Speaker 5:  front of you in every single imaginable way all the time.
Speaker 5:  Everywhere. So there were a bunch of things, there were new models,
Speaker 5:  new Imagine and video models to make images and video,
Speaker 5:  which were like not super impressive. I don't know how they felt in in the
Speaker 5:  crowd at Shoreline, but like watching some of those on YouTube, it was like,
Speaker 5:  this is like not as cool as you think. It's
Speaker 6:  You're talking about the video stuff? Yeah. Oh no, I disagree.
Speaker 6:  Some
Speaker 4:  Of the video stuff was cool, but the part where they demoed the,
Speaker 4:  like the the woman, the filmmaker who made a video about herself being born
Speaker 4:  and it was called Ancestral and I was like, this is a horror movie. Do you
Speaker 4:  know that you made a horror movie?
Speaker 6:  It's Darren Aronofsky. Yeah, yeah. I agree that what they showed on stage
Speaker 6:  was not as compelling, but the stuff I've seen on like x that people have
Speaker 6:  been making with this for sure, for sure is mind blowing. It's like full
Speaker 6:  on reality is over
Speaker 4:  Stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, some of It is very good. So anyway, so there were a lot of like
Speaker 5:  new things coming to existing products, sort of improvements inside of Gmail.
Speaker 5:  But I would say the biggest things we heard a lot about were
Speaker 5:  AI mode, which is the, the new tab inside of search that is
Speaker 5:  basically just a full AI experience next to
Speaker 5:  traditional search in a way that is messy and complicated and we should talk
Speaker 5:  about. There's also,
Speaker 5:  Gemini is now being baked into Chrome, which is
Speaker 5:  fascinating in the context of everything else going on with Google, which
Speaker 5:  may or may not have to sell Chrome at some point in the very near future.
Speaker 5:  The Gemini app continues to get better. So the Google has set it up so that
Speaker 5:  there's Project Astra, which is, it's like, they called it a concept car
Speaker 5:  of an AI assistant and that's where they try all their like truly wild stuff.
Speaker 5:  And it was Astra where they're showing off all of the like
Speaker 5:  wild demos where it's like watching you do stuff as you live your life and
Speaker 5:  then can speak up. But as stuff gets better from there, it all graduates
Speaker 5:  into the Gemini app, which got a bunch of new stuff. There's new features
Speaker 5:  for Gemini Live, there's now like some of the live stuff is also in
Speaker 5:  the search app. It's very confusing.
Speaker 6:  You were saying this like it makes sense and it does not.
Speaker 4:  No it
Speaker 5:  Doesn't, none of it makes any sense.
Speaker 4:  There's one part, there's one little part that makes sense, which is
Speaker 4:  Google has figured out a vocabulary for
Speaker 4:  what things are shipping mainstream products
Speaker 4:  and what stuff is weird Google ideas. Yes. Right. So there are projects
Speaker 4:  of which there are too many and all of their names are confusing because
Speaker 4:  it's Google. The projects are like, here are the demos, right? Here's this
Speaker 4:  thing Project Mariner, the is the tech demo of we're gonna
Speaker 4:  let our agent go click around the website. And then the
Speaker 4:  verb which David just used is that stuff graduates to the
Speaker 4:  actual products like search. And then there's like weird hybrids where search
Speaker 4:  has the new AI mode tab, which is not a project but an actual thing that
Speaker 4:  rolled out to everybody in the United States. But eventually things in AI
Speaker 4:  mode will graduate to the main search experience. So they're, they've just
Speaker 4:  introduced, I'm not saying it, it, it's great. I'm saying they've
Speaker 4:  introduced a verb to make sense of like how
Speaker 4:  Google does stuff, which is instead of shipping products,
Speaker 4:  they now just graduate. Right. Oh my God. Like, like you graduate from
Speaker 4:  preschool. Cool. It's very simple guys. Project Astra is the Google lens
Speaker 4:  to Gemini's AI mode.
Speaker 5:  Jesus. That's true. I hate that. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's a lot. But but that little once you like understand that
Speaker 4:  Google needed a way to make people stop asking when the
Speaker 4:  thing would become the real thing
Speaker 4:  and they came up with the word graduate, like some of it clicks into place
Speaker 4:  and then everyone at Google would be like, yeah, it's still pretty bad though.
Speaker 4:  Right? The
Speaker 5:  Important thing though is that there are essentially two places
Speaker 5:  that really matter to Google. One is the Gemini app and one is search. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And so every other thing it's working on is at some point
Speaker 5:  moving towards one of those two places. And the Gemini app is
Speaker 5:  designed to be your assistant, right? Like that's the thing. It's trying
Speaker 5:  to be what? What chat GPT is for lots of people it's competing with Claude.
Speaker 5:  Like It is the all in one operating system for your life thing that
Speaker 5:  Google is trying to do. Search is search and and
Speaker 5:  AI mode and all this stuff is, is a big bet in a slightly different
Speaker 5:  direction that it can be what search has been for
Speaker 5:  25 years but like much better. And I think Gemini and search are
Speaker 5:  actually, they overlap in sort of how you can use them but they are different
Speaker 5:  things in Google's mind. Yes. But those are the two places that all of this
Speaker 5:  is designed to end up.
Speaker 4:  Gemini is the big age agentic assistant that goes and
Speaker 4:  does things for you. That's the demo. Right? Alex has been talking about
Speaker 4:  the bike demo. If you go watch the video of that demo in particular,
Speaker 4:  it's the guy's got his phone open, he's looking at his bike, he says
Speaker 4:  pull up the instruction manual Gemini goes and does a search, gets the
Speaker 4:  PDF of the bike's instruction manual. And he says scroll to the page about
Speaker 4:  whatever breaks. And it finds that we scan like you have to
Speaker 4:  believe that Huffy has produced an OCR capable PDF but like whatever,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of steps in there. But it scans the manual finds a thing, you
Speaker 4:  watch it literally scroll the phone in the background, it calls the bike
Speaker 4:  shop and has a whole interaction on the phone with the bike shop. That's
Speaker 4:  agent stuff like big hairy agent stuff. And
Speaker 4:  then search is like the vision for AI mode
Speaker 4:  is that every search result page you get is a custom built
Speaker 4:  application all the way down to like we can build charts for you.
Speaker 4:  We might actually build custom code apps. Like you ask a
Speaker 4:  question about stats in the NFL and we, we will build a data visualization
Speaker 4:  app for you on the fly. Yep. And show that to you as a search result. Which
Speaker 4:  is a big, a huge idea but not an agent. Right. And at
Speaker 4:  some point they're gonna overlap.
Speaker 6:  Gemini can do that. This is what I don't understand. I mean the reason these
Speaker 6:  products are separate is because Google makes all of its money from search.
Speaker 6:  Sure. That that's, and they are shipping their org chart quite literally,
Speaker 6:  which is like Demis has his fiefdom of DeepMind and now the
Speaker 6:  app and he's brought product into his org. So now he controls the app fully.
Speaker 6:  He doesn't control search. That's a whole nother org that is 10 times as
Speaker 6:  large that is the most profitable software business in the history of the
Speaker 6:  world. And they cannot disrupt that to the degree that they're willing
Speaker 6:  to do wild stuff in Gemini. And should these
Speaker 6:  be one products? Like does OpenAI say no, we have a separate
Speaker 6:  app for you to search with chat GPT? No they don't. It's just one big product
Speaker 6:  and it's actually, it's way simpler to understand. And Google's struggle
Speaker 6:  I think was that from this IO is that yes they have the best models,
Speaker 6:  they suck at product, they suck at making it work
Speaker 6:  holistically and making it simple for people to understand. And that's still
Speaker 6:  something they're, they're working through. That's
Speaker 4:  Google. Google loves to ship its org chart and it was even on like a parent
Speaker 4:  on stage at IO where like different executives got to announce the same product
Speaker 4:  in different ways. Yeah. 'cause everybody needed a bite, you know, like this
Speaker 4:  stuff happens. But from the product perspective,
Speaker 4:  what I actually saw was all of their big bets
Speaker 4:  that they've taken over time and all of their data about people
Speaker 4:  is now resulting in products that look like they might work. Which
Speaker 4:  again has been my criticism of AI for a long time. I don't know if they're
Speaker 4:  actually gonna work but they have Gmail. Yeah. They just have
Speaker 4:  Gmail. And so a lot of their like personal context boils down
Speaker 4:  to well we ha we we we're just gonna read your email. Right. Like we know
Speaker 4:  when your flights are 'cause there it's in your email so we don't have to
Speaker 4:  do anything else. Like what if we were just better at reading your email
Speaker 4:  to you is like an incredible product for AI to solve. And now Google has
Speaker 4:  all this like research and the models to do it and then you can just
Speaker 4:  productize that. And I think the search piece of it,
Speaker 4:  I, yeah I do think there's two different org charts and that's all their
Speaker 4:  money so they can't screw with it too much. But there's a world in which
Speaker 4:  you would make that decision anyway because
Speaker 4:  you don't want every search to be like agentic.
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  Right. You do just want some information presented back to you without like
Speaker 4:  the emotional package of your agent like reading your email to you. And I,
Speaker 4:  I don't know where that line is and I think it's actually useful for Google
Speaker 4:  to know like on some timeline they converge
Speaker 4:  but not know when or how and just see how it plays out.
Speaker 5:  I also think if you're at Google there is very little evidence
Speaker 5:  to suggest that you need to overhaul search soon.
Speaker 5:  Google like the, the everybody is like, oh you have to cannibalize your own
Speaker 5:  product or somebody else to do it for Google just continues to destroy
Speaker 5:  everybody at search and and everybody's like, oh you know
Speaker 5:  Zoomers use chat GPT and and and Google is just like show us in the
Speaker 5:  market share friend os like
Speaker 6:  So there's they are playing games with their
Speaker 6:  metrics. Yeah. Pretty flatly. 'cause you know Eddie Q
Speaker 6:  was at, at the search remedies trial and he
Speaker 6:  said look, you don't need to do this Search is already under threat searches
Speaker 6:  in iOS Safari have gone down for the first time in 22 years. And Google's,
Speaker 6:  we talked about this Google stock price dropped like that day 'cause everyone
Speaker 6:  is waiting Yeah. For the pin to drop. Right. So
Speaker 6:  Sundar is on decoder, you'll hear it on Monday. And So I asked about that
Speaker 6:  directly and we'll just, we'll just play the clip at EQ
Speaker 6:  on the stand and the trial the other day said search in Safari for the
Speaker 6:  last month dropped for the first time in 22 years. That's a big
Speaker 6:  stat. Obviously your stock price was affected by it. And there was a
Speaker 6:  statement is that trend bearing out that the standard Google Search is, is
Speaker 6:  dropping from devices and different kinds of searches are increasing?
Speaker 9:  No. Look we've been very clear. We are seeing overall query growth in search.
Speaker 9:  You know, it looks,
Speaker 6:  But have you actually seen the drop in safari?
Speaker 9:  Look we have a comprehensive view of how we look at data across the board.
Speaker 9:  There's a lot of, there can be a lot of noise in search data, but
Speaker 9:  everything we see tells us we are seeing query growth
Speaker 9:  including across apple's devices and platforms. And
Speaker 9:  specifically, you know, I think we quantified the query growth from AI or
Speaker 9:  views and what's what's healthy is that the query growth
Speaker 9:  is continuing to grow over time.
Speaker 6:  So first of all children, if your parents ask you how you did on your report
Speaker 6:  card, you should just say I have a comprehensive view of the data. That's
Speaker 6:  good. That's really good. Incredible answer. That whole, that whole interview
Speaker 6:  coming on Monday was a good one. But Alex you weren't laughing 'cause he
Speaker 6:  keeps saying query growth. Yeah and I don't, from what I
Speaker 6:  have gathered from our conversations over the past couple days, you're, you're
Speaker 6:  very skeptical of this. Well so two things can be true. So overall queries
Speaker 6:  for Google can be growing but the growth rate can be declining. So
Speaker 6:  yes. Do I think that queries in Google products or across
Speaker 6:  everywhere that search touches have just like literally gone negative
Speaker 6:  like year over year? No. Like in aggregate is it probably growing? Yes. Is
Speaker 6:  it growing as fast? Google will not say. And also like
Speaker 6:  are the amount of searches done per person growing or are fewer people
Speaker 6:  doing more searches? Right. There's a lot that they are not saying
Speaker 6:  and they're just trying to flat out say like broadly query growth is growing
Speaker 6:  because the moment you drill down into what's actually happening, maybe you
Speaker 6:  learn, oh wait, like maybe in North America in
Speaker 6:  a key cohort for advertisers, which is like, you know 20 to 35,
Speaker 6:  a significant chunk of people are doing increasingly commercial intent searches
Speaker 6:  on CHATT PT And that's like if you actually try to drill down into how
Speaker 6:  search works, which they don't wanna do, they wanna just talk about it at
Speaker 6:  a high level, you maybe learn stuff like that And you know, we saw
Speaker 6:  that reaction in the stock price because I think investors are so on edge
Speaker 6:  and you can see it in the way Google just how the stock is traded. Like it's,
Speaker 6:  it's heavily discounted relative to its peers because there
Speaker 6:  is this fear not only of will the company be broken up but
Speaker 6:  is chat GPT and these other AR products actually eating
Speaker 6:  into search in a meaningful way. And so far Google's answer is,
Speaker 6:  are types of queries are expanding, people are using search in
Speaker 6:  deeper new ways. Which yes that's true. That's how these AI products work.
Speaker 6:  You wanna thank it and have a conversation with it. That doesn't mean
Speaker 6:  that overall query volume is growing like it did.
Speaker 5:  I'm just not sure there's any evidence to suggest either way. Right. Like
Speaker 5:  the all, all we know is that
Speaker 5:  people like chat GPT, right? Like
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  Mean no there's there is, I mean there's the fact that like 500 million
Speaker 6:  people use chat GPT every week and people also
Speaker 6:  use all these other AI chat bots. There was like a bunch of things that did
Speaker 6:  not exist three years ago that now exist that directly
Speaker 6:  do what Google used to do. And like we all see it and I bet a lot
Speaker 6:  of our listeners feel it like in their daily lives.
Speaker 5:  You think all 500 million of those people every week are firing up chat GBT
Speaker 5:  to do web search.
Speaker 6:  I think I'm getting answers from chat GBT that I've normally used Google
Speaker 6:  for. Whether it's like searching the web or not. It could be like
Speaker 6:  do a math equation. For me it could be like what is a time zone conversion?
Speaker 6:  Like there's a ton of things you use Google for and yes chat GT doesn't do
Speaker 6:  the commercial shopping stuff especially yet though I think they will And
Speaker 6:  that's when it really gets potentially scary for Google. But
Speaker 6:  yeah. Do I and my family members and my friends, are we using
Speaker 6:  chat GPT? Like we used to use search. Absolutely. And I think a lot of people
Speaker 6:  are, there's
Speaker 4:  Also other search replacements. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Perplexity last
Speaker 4:  Year we talked about TikTok a bunch, right? Like people just search in TikTok
Speaker 4:  and TikTok has search surfaces whether or not they're useful.
Speaker 4:  Like I think TikTok search has like dramatically declined in quality since
Speaker 4:  all these other products at the scene. I, I think the point is like to
Speaker 4:  connect this to, there's Gemini in their search, they need search
Speaker 4:  to remain competitive and vital. Yeah. And that's why you don't
Speaker 4:  make your big bet on Gemini. 'cause then you are head up against chat
Speaker 4:  GPT and perplexity and whatever else, right? But you're saying, oh actually
Speaker 4:  this thing is just really good. Like you don't need to open this other app.
Speaker 4:  Like Google Search is now just incredible and when assistance happen
Speaker 4:  we're gonna have one ready for you.
Speaker 5:  The real fear for Google here I think is less
Speaker 5:  about how sort of meaningful a competitor chat GPT is right now
Speaker 5:  and how good a brand chat GPT is like the, the
Speaker 5:  thing that no one has ever been able to touch with Google is like a sheer
Speaker 5:  awareness. And Chad GPT is like running at
Speaker 5:  it really fast in terms of like when I need to do something, where do I go?
Speaker 5:  The answer for 20 years has been Google and
Speaker 5:  like the, the Omnibox in Chrome was the most important surface on the internet
Speaker 5:  for two decades. And chat GPT is is pushing
Speaker 5:  at that about as fast and hard as you could possibly imagine And like
Speaker 5:  chat GPT is a is a terrible business and has many
Speaker 5:  limitations as a product. But like again It is, It is hitting
Speaker 5:  that like mainstream Kleenex isation
Speaker 5:  like kind of at record speed. And I think if I'm Google that's the thing
Speaker 5:  I'm afraid of And that's the reason Neil, to your point, that's why you don't
Speaker 5:  bet on Gemini because your brand is Google and so what you, what you want
Speaker 5:  everybody to think of is you want to think of Google as the thing that is
Speaker 5:  like chat GPT, not Gemini. Gemini is like off here doing other stuff.
Speaker 4:  But I really think like the, the confidence we saw from Google this
Speaker 4:  last week is 'cause it's there like
Speaker 4:  they have a lot of products Yeah. That are good.
Speaker 4:  Not just chat CPT, right? Like yeah SOA is
Speaker 4:  not a great video generator yet.
Speaker 6:  SOA doesn't exist yet. You know what I mean?
Speaker 4:  Like it's like it's around like some people have used it sometimes
Speaker 4:  VO three is just like you can just screw with it. Yeah. I watched Serge Brain
Speaker 4:  try to generate his own face for a while.
Speaker 4:  At least that's what I was told. Like it's just people are using it today
Speaker 4:  and it will lead to some outcomes. I think some of those outcomes might be
Speaker 4:  like negative for the film industry. Like who knows? But the products exist
Speaker 4:  and the changes are gonna happen around them. Some of the age agentic stuff,
Speaker 4:  like I just literally watched a live demo of Project Mariner
Speaker 4:  like look for jobs and it was just clicking around a remote
Speaker 4:  desktop chrome session and you know, I have a lot of
Speaker 4:  questions about that. Like why would any of those services agree to that?
Speaker 4:  Like I don't know, is that pretty brittle and like should you just use
Speaker 4:  some of these new technologies like MCP, like I don't know maybe, but
Speaker 4:  it works like it's there and the rate of
Speaker 4:  improvement is so fast that Google is like oh we're gonna,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna do this. Yeah. Like this is definitely just happening for us.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 6:  Have the best models and that is a tremendous advantage. I was talking to
Speaker 6:  someone who works in another big AI lab and they were saying model quality
Speaker 6:  impacts usage of the products more than anything we, we don't
Speaker 6:  think it does. But if you release a shittier model in a chat bot, people
Speaker 6:  use the chat bot less people can feel how these models react
Speaker 6:  and what they want to get out of them in a way that maybe we just broadly
Speaker 6:  discount and how we cover them. And Google is objectively leading
Speaker 6:  in model quality right now. And that was like the first thing Sunar came
Speaker 6:  out on stage and talked about was like, we're number one on all the leaderboards.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, that is true but is everyone talking about Gemini? Is
Speaker 6:  Gemini like the thing I hear when I go home for like Memorial Day weekend?
Speaker 6:  No, no one even knows Gemini has an app except like early adopters and
Speaker 6:  certain, you know, pockets like chat GBT is the Kleenex of all this
Speaker 6:  and that's a problem for Google unless we hit a GI like
Speaker 6:  Demis once and none of this matters anyway.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And Demis the only one left standing just openly being like I'm
Speaker 4:  doing a GI. Yeah. That's what this is all for. I'm on stage with Sergei brand
Speaker 4:  being like the a GI moment is coming, we're we're taking bets
Speaker 4:  on whether it happens before or after 2030 and they were six months on like
Speaker 4:  either side of the line,
Speaker 4:  You know, like every other company stop talking about it 'cause they have
Speaker 4:  have to make some products to make some money to justify all this huge investment.
Speaker 4:  And Google's like, yeah we did it already. You know, I think Google
Speaker 4:  maybe last year, particularly two years ago was incredibly
Speaker 4:  insecure. Yes. About having done all of the research investment like
Speaker 4:  we've been joking for years now that if you say chat GPTA Google
Speaker 4:  comms person like leaps out of a bush and It is like the T and chat GPT was
Speaker 4:  invented at Google. Like yeah, they're over that, right? They're like, okay
Speaker 4:  we're we caught up Like we we're gonna ship products that are
Speaker 4:  good. But I think the interesting part of that, Alex is maybe
Speaker 4:  chat PT has the brand name Google has the distribution. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 4:  So they're loud about AI overviews being the most single most popular
Speaker 4:  generative AI product at scale.
Speaker 6:  Right. Hundreds of millions of people. I think you could disti you could
Speaker 6:  remove popular and used like Yes. Yeah. Do people know what they're using?
Speaker 6:  Do they know that ASRA is the lens to deep minds, you
Speaker 6:  know, AI mode? No, but like that's the problem is like yes.
Speaker 6:  I I think it's more of a ego thing honestly. And I think it's a recruiting
Speaker 6:  thing and I think for Google, yeah they're seeing metrics that are not
Speaker 6:  as bad as everyone thought, but this, this race, this
Speaker 6:  perception of the race, this perception of how far ahead chat GPT is and
Speaker 6:  just consumer mind share is it, it's an ego problem
Speaker 6:  for them. It's maybe a long-term strategy problem and I think it just hits
Speaker 6:  them more in that realm. I don't think it actually, it's clearly not hitting
Speaker 6:  them on the business and that's what you and I were feeling being on site,
Speaker 6:  but like is it still a problem for them in that they are not winning
Speaker 6:  at at all? Yes. There I met, I was with a Google exec who's been there forever
Speaker 6:  at one point yesterday and they were like, yeah, you know, just like a
Speaker 6:  thing we really have a problem with is like not being first, you know, like
Speaker 6:  that's, and that's like every company, but I think Google for so long just
Speaker 6:  had this perch that was untouchable. Yeah, right. They just ran the
Speaker 6:  internet and now they're getting challenged on all sides. And I think
Speaker 6:  that just that that messes with the, with the ego a little bit
Speaker 6:  in, in a way that makes it seeps into the products. It
Speaker 6:  seeps into the decisions they make. But yes, as the business may be doing
Speaker 6:  better than we thought. Yeah. I mean I thought it was crazy like at the very
Speaker 6:  end of the keynote Sunar mentions Waymo for like 30 seconds. It's like,
Speaker 6:  you know, they may have a trillion dollar company in Waymo that has solved
Speaker 6:  self-driving and is now doing more rides in San Francisco than Lyft. Like
Speaker 6:  that is happening in one part of Google. Yeah. YouTube is
Speaker 6:  unshakeable, YouTube is probably gonna eat the entire entertainment industry.
Speaker 6:  So they have all these products that are just huge and dominant
Speaker 6:  and I think they were feeling that, yeah.
Speaker 4:  At the end of the keynote. So I just casually mentioned their satellite constellation
Speaker 4:  to detect fires and he literally was like, it will be fully operational
Speaker 4:  by your end. And I was like, that's how they announced the the second death
Speaker 4:  star. I wanna be
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 4:  That's, those are the words they used for the death star dude. And then he
Speaker 4:  was like, come good I everybody and I laughed
Speaker 6:  Also. I think they're feeling really great because you know, Dieter is more
Speaker 6:  famous than Giannis, so that's
Speaker 4:  True. Dieter got the biggest single biggest cheer at the io keynote. Shout
Speaker 4:  out to Dieter. It was very fun seeing him as a popular
Speaker 4:  Google executive on that stage. Also when he came out
Speaker 4:  we were, we were all sitting next to each other live blogging and V just
Speaker 4:  goes Dieter. Like it's like totally quiet,
Speaker 6:  Right? Like
Speaker 4:  She just screams teeter like incredible moment.
Speaker 4:  That's awesome. It was very good.
Speaker 4:  There's the distribution, right? That we have AI over reviews.
Speaker 4:  Everyone's using 'em as it popular, does a brand work on some timeline, it
Speaker 4:  doesn't matter because they're just there and they get really, really good
Speaker 4:  and then you just, you know, the next new person never even thinks to get
Speaker 4:  chat GPT and that feels like a big part of this bet, right? That's where
Speaker 4:  AI mode really comes to play, where you've got this big new search
Speaker 4:  experience and over time things will graduate to the main search experience
Speaker 4:  and then maybe no one's ever using chat CPT 'cause yeah, the
Speaker 4:  people who have yet to experience AI are just like, whatever, Google just
Speaker 4:  does this. Like I'm looking at this other, you want me to use this app that's
Speaker 4:  doing the thing that's already happening? It could
Speaker 6:  Be like stories, it could be like how meta copied Snapchat and Yeah, Snapchat
Speaker 6:  got big and it's still big, but it never became a multi-trillion dollar company
Speaker 6:  because a company with tremendous scale just copied it quickly and
Speaker 6:  leveraged its distribution. Yeah, that definitely
Speaker 5:  Could happen. Well this is, this is where Google shipping its org chart I
Speaker 5:  think is is hurting it pretty badly because the thing I can't figure out
Speaker 5:  and that no one at Google will give me an honest answer to is do they care
Speaker 5:  about Gemini as a like public facing
Speaker 5:  brand? Like is It, is it important to Google that we know
Speaker 5:  and care about Gemini? Yes.
Speaker 6:  It's funny they wouldn't tell you that. I think it's because they know they're
Speaker 6:  nowhere near where they need to be and they don't wanna say that I'm, but
Speaker 6:  I mean
Speaker 5:  They, they all say yes, but I don't believe them.
Speaker 6:  No, it's, it's, it's actually Sundar told employees at the beginning of there
Speaker 6:  that It is the top goal for the company is that Gemini like wins the
Speaker 6:  chatbot race. Like, like we
Speaker 4:  Need. So
Speaker 5:  I people to think of Geminis. So I believe that. But I think like if, if
Speaker 5:  it were, if Google were a different company where it was
Speaker 5:  easier to succeed by making things good and not by launching new things
Speaker 5:  Mm. Would it have made a lot more sense to just do all of this
Speaker 5:  work inside of AI mode from the very beginning? Yes.
Speaker 5:  And and you go back to how can we make google.com the most important thing
Speaker 5:  on the internet again forever. And you, you, yes. You just, you pull this
Speaker 5:  thing from a tab slowly into search. Like the thing I think they're doing
Speaker 5:  with AI mode makes a lot of sense. And the fact that it's not called
Speaker 5:  Gemini doesn't make any sense. And so I'm just lost on this thing about like
Speaker 5:  Google is actually trying to point you in so many places that I think
Speaker 5:  It is risking like diluting the actually interesting work that it's doing.
Speaker 6:  It's 'cause it's the money search is the money they can't, yeah. They can't
Speaker 6:  do this. Like they can't disrupt. This is classic innovator's dilemma. This
Speaker 6:  is what open AI is attacking head on. Yeah. Is that Google cannot change
Speaker 6:  its business fast enough for the consumer awareness
Speaker 6:  and just attention sucking that chat GPT is doing right now.
Speaker 6:  And yeah, just put it in the chat. That is exactly what it should be. Gemini
Speaker 6:  should be searched. There should be no distinction. The problem is, is that
Speaker 6:  Google isn't a company. It's a combination of like 14 companies with
Speaker 6:  its own, their own CEOs. Right. You know, and Yeah. Should West Us
Speaker 6:  like run it all? Probably like would things run smoother? Yes. But there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of lords and they all have their own,
Speaker 5:  I mean I even think about like there's, there's a, there's a Google app
Speaker 4:  That was a seamless Game of Thrones
Speaker 5:  Reference that was really good. But like there's a Google app in which you
Speaker 5:  can either do Google Search or with one button go to Gemini and then
Speaker 5:  there's also a Gemini app. And in no sane world, do both of those
Speaker 5:  things need to exist? No,
Speaker 4:  I can't, I cannot believe I'm the person who's saying this. I don't think
Speaker 4:  any of this shit matters. I really don't. I
Speaker 5:  It might not.
Speaker 4:  Like, I think the main search experience is gonna get better.
Speaker 4:  People are gonna see the words AI mode and like click it 'cause it just says
Speaker 4:  AI mode and that is a clicker thing than the word Gemini,
Speaker 4:  which means nothing. Then they're gonna be like, wow, people are using AI
Speaker 4:  mode and that's gonna become the main thing. And at some point
Speaker 4:  they will do the thing that Google is uniquely capable of doing
Speaker 4:  and say, click this link to download the Gemini app and they will just
Speaker 4:  get Gemini distribution. Yeah. And that will all just happen.
Speaker 4:  Like they're, they are uniquely capable of doing that. One of the
Speaker 4:  they have, and yes, they got the innovators still have problem. Like they
Speaker 4:  can't burn down the most lucrative business in favor of the the cheap
Speaker 4:  disruptive thing. That's almost good enough. But works better for some people,
Speaker 4:  right? Like yeah, they have, they got that problem. I think there other problem
Speaker 4:  is they're basically gonna torch
Speaker 4:  the web. Like along the way the web as we know It is
Speaker 4:  coming to an end. And they are, you know what Shar will
Speaker 4:  tell you, it's not a zero sum game that the web is growing. They're crawling
Speaker 4:  more web pages than ever. You'll hear that in decoder next week. Every
Speaker 4:  Google executive there is like more stuff is happening on the web.
Speaker 4:  There, there are more and better applications on the web than ever.
Speaker 4:  Like the web is the place where you deploy new apps.
Speaker 4:  High point of like maybe of all time. Yeah. Because of all this app store
Speaker 4:  ruling and the Epic case, the web is the place where you go to buy stuff
Speaker 4:  about to become incredibly important again. Right? All these apps are
Speaker 4:  gonna kick you out of in-app purchases to the web and we're gonna all be
Speaker 4:  buying stuff on the web. 'cause you don't have to pay the Apple Tech. Like
Speaker 4:  it's all that stuff is great, but like the web is a media platform where
Speaker 4:  the new information is. It is like, it's already under pressure from all
Speaker 4:  these tools, right? It's already dying because of these tools. You can see
Speaker 4:  it every day. All that, all that new information is on. I
Speaker 4:  mean you're, you're listening to this in your podcast player or on YouTube,
Speaker 4:  like it's in these other weird platforms. It's on
Speaker 4:  TikTok and Google has to figure out how to get that information
Speaker 4:  or it has to figure out how it's agents can go and look at all those databases
Speaker 4:  and make that worthwhile for people. And I don't,
Speaker 4:  I don't know if that stuff makes sense yet. I don't even, it makes sense
Speaker 4:  for OpenAI, but at least they're the upstart, right? Like yeah.
Speaker 6:  If their
Speaker 4:  Core business fails, like Sam Altman will just lit, lit a bunch of money
Speaker 4:  on fire and that's kinda what we expected him to do. If Google can't pull
Speaker 4:  it off, like a lot of things go wrong, but they have to, they have to work
Speaker 4:  that curve of like the web is the place where the
Speaker 4:  information is. Yeah. Is quickly getting abstracted away to the
Speaker 4:  web. Is the database that the new AI Google Search
Speaker 4:  synthesizes for you?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I heard that too at io I heard the execs saying like, no, like
Speaker 6:  the content on the web is bigger than it ever has. We have more to crawl
Speaker 6:  than we ever have. And I just was thinking like, wait, isn't that all AI
Speaker 6:  slop? Like, isn't the reason you have more to crawl is because your models
Speaker 6:  are producing a bunch of garbage? And I I really think they view data
Speaker 6:  like, like sand. Like it's just like the beach has gotten bigger,
Speaker 6:  but it's like Yeah, but there's like a bunch of dead animals in it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like that's kind of how they view data.
Speaker 4:  Look at the amount of rubble we're standing on. It's like, well this, you
Speaker 4:  blew up the city. It's
Speaker 6:  A real problem. So I guess in aggregate, is there more data for them to crawl?
Speaker 6:  Probably. How much of that is human? How much of that is high quality? We
Speaker 6:  know we feel this as people in the media business. Like all of the best content
Speaker 6:  is going behind paywalls. It's, it's gonna be hard for agents to get to this
Speaker 6:  stuff. And how does that work? How do you solve the fundamental
Speaker 6:  business tension of people who make the good stuff cannot support
Speaker 6:  what they do on the web as it exists today?
Speaker 4:  Well actually let's take a, like a tiny detour into MCP 'cause David
Speaker 4:  wrote about it in the context of Microsoft Build This week we had
Speaker 4:  Kevin Scott, Microsoft, CTO, under Dakota this week. MCP
Speaker 4:  is like a phenomenon, right? It's a standard from Anthropic that
Speaker 4:  is basically here's how an agent shows up to a website or a database and
Speaker 4:  interacts with, it's basically just an API replacement. Like it's, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's not more complicated than like we made some APIs for agents to go do
Speaker 4:  stuff and if you just run it all the way to the end, it's kind of
Speaker 4:  like, oh, you don't need websites anymore. You just have, you need off and
Speaker 4:  maybe payments to databases and then the agents can just
Speaker 4:  like go and API into the databases and come back and give you stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I, I, I just, I don't know how that business works, but David, you wrote
Speaker 4:  about it this week.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think built into the way that you're talking about It is the assumption
Speaker 5:  that everyone will access every part of the web
Speaker 5:  via some chatbot,
Speaker 5:  which is what a bunch of these companies would like you to believe. But I
Speaker 5:  don't think is true and I don't really think has ever been true.
Speaker 5:  The, the theory is that like, okay, what we, what we
Speaker 5:  can do in one of two ways is help
Speaker 5:  plug AI into the web, right? And I think that's like
Speaker 5:  MCP stands for model context protocol. And basically the idea is it's like
Speaker 5:  a structured way for me to say I have a bunch of information on my website
Speaker 5:  here is how to give the model access to that information in order to
Speaker 5:  be able to do things fine. Microsoft is also working
Speaker 5:  on this thing called NL Web that I think is very cool. Which is basically
Speaker 5:  an open version of a protocol like that that says,
Speaker 5:  okay, what if I could actually run all of that AI stuff on my website?
Speaker 5:  And so now instead of going to chat GPT to talk to my website or go to Claude
Speaker 5:  to talk to my website, you come to my website to talk to my website. And
Speaker 5:  that is like, as somebody who believes in the open web, that is a future
Speaker 5:  I am much more interested in over time. But I think
Speaker 5:  to Alex's point, I don't think these companies care
Speaker 5:  about the information on the internet. Like I think a lot about, I think
Speaker 5:  Mark Zuckerberg has said a few times, which is that like everybody talks
Speaker 5:  a lot about news content on Facebook and that is like a vanishingly small
Speaker 5:  portion of what people do on Facebook. And so eventually they just stop caring
Speaker 5:  like, this is no longer worth our time and investment and energy
Speaker 5:  to care that much about what happens with news content because it doesn't
Speaker 5:  matter that much to our platform. And I think most of these companies feel
Speaker 5:  the same way that actually most of this is just headache and what
Speaker 5:  people come to Google for is to like find Adele music videos
Speaker 5:  and chocolate chip cookie recipes and not read politics news. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  there are all kinds of terrifying downstream effects from the fact that they
Speaker 5:  don't really care, but I think they don't really care. And, and the idea
Speaker 5:  that what they're gonna do is set up a world in which everybody who owns
Speaker 5:  a website has to stop thinking about Google distribution and go build
Speaker 5:  themselves into a destination people go to on purpose. And that that's
Speaker 5:  gonna require reprogramming 20 years of behavior of how we do the internet.
Speaker 5:  Like it's a mess and it's gonna kill a lot of the web. And
Speaker 5:  I just don't think these companies care because It is, there's new stuff
Speaker 5:  to do. I think
Speaker 4:  Google wants you to believe that it cares, but it on on
Speaker 4:  the longest timelines that Google thinks it does not.
Speaker 5:  So I would say it the other way. I think Google cares a lot about the web
Speaker 5:  and very little about websites like the making
Speaker 5:  sure that websites that exist today get to continue as they exist today.
Speaker 5:  I don't think Google cares that much about that. Oh sure.
Speaker 4:  No, we're agreeing. But I I I think Google cares about the web. Is this like
Speaker 4:  really the web is a miracle. Like I just, like
Speaker 4:  straightforwardly the web is a miracle we have in the world a giant
Speaker 4:  interconnected, interdependent, mostly open application
Speaker 4:  platform. That's weird.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, right. Thank you. Government spending,
Speaker 4:  You can just, yeah, like, right. Yeah. We like, we just horse-powered
Speaker 4:  this thing into existence because honestly, mark Andreessen got a
Speaker 4:  bunch of government funding in the middle of the country. Like that's a thing
Speaker 4:  that happened. Like that's mosaic it and it turned into Netscape and like
Speaker 4:  here we are and it's all here and now Figma exists and like
Speaker 4:  Johnny, ive legendary designer probably opens a web
Speaker 4:  app to do a bunch of design work That's crazy.
Speaker 5:  Now he uses pages for everything.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's funny you brought up Andreessen. I actually talked to open AI
Speaker 6:  to their MCP lead this week because they joined the SN committee for MCP.
Speaker 6:  So they're now working with basically every AI lab has agreed that this is
Speaker 6:  the new standard. And I ac actually came away thinking we are actually
Speaker 6:  still pre Netscape on agents as it relates to the actual plumbing
Speaker 6:  that it takes to hook them together. So this OpenAI lead was like,
Speaker 6:  there's still no registry. Like there's no, there's no discoverability
Speaker 6:  mechanism for a developer to even know who has an MCP server.
Speaker 6:  Like we know there's a few of them, there's like Stripe and Zendesk or whatever,
Speaker 6:  but no one's even built the interface for then the developer to go,
Speaker 6:  okay, X model go make this happen with this server
Speaker 6:  and that that will happen. It'll probably happen this year, but we're not
Speaker 6:  even at the browser point. It is funny to be talking in these words because
Speaker 6:  like yes, agents are supposed to like replace browsers, but like we are not
Speaker 6:  in the browser phase of agent building yet. Like this is not
Speaker 6:  even been connected in that way. It's still very, very early and
Speaker 6:  it will be enterprise and very developer focused first. It's not
Speaker 6:  like we're gonna be getting some all powerful agent that can just like go
Speaker 6:  and order a bunch of stuff for you and talk to a bunch of apps like anytime
Speaker 6:  soon. Even though Google showed that off. Like this is gonna be a developer
Speaker 6:  replacing function calling with telling a model to go talk to an API.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I and that's really interesting. That's interesting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  You can see there's a new web you would build on that. Like Yeah, and that's
Speaker 4:  what I mean, like I agree with David, I think they care a lot about the web.
Speaker 4:  'cause this big interconnected application platform where you can like
Speaker 4:  instantly deliver complex applications
Speaker 4:  to a runtime like Chrome is a miracle. And
Speaker 4:  I think Google is very invested in that particular miracle, I think
Speaker 4:  as a media platform where you read a bunch of text and it's a doc, they don't
Speaker 4:  care about that at all. And like I know this 'cause Alex and I were sitting
Speaker 4:  in the audience for the de asaba and Sergey brand
Speaker 4:  fireside chat with Alex Kantrowitz and Kreitz asked,
Speaker 4:  what do you think the web is in 10 years? And Sergey was like, who knows?
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 6:  Right. He was
Speaker 4:  Like, the world will, I'll live it, like hit the singularity. Like I will
Speaker 4:  be one with the sun like off in space. And Demis said
Speaker 4:  it's, it's a good question. And then quote, I think the web in the near term,
Speaker 4:  the web is going to change a lot. If you think about an agent first web.
Speaker 4:  Do the agents have to see renders in things that we need to see as humans
Speaker 4:  website? Do we need to actually render webpage? Do we need
Speaker 5:  Websites? That's the question. And he's, I mean his answer clearly is no.
Speaker 4:  His answer is no. And then I asked Sundar a riff on this question, I read
Speaker 4:  him that quote and he was like, what is the web but a series of databases,
Speaker 4:  which first of all is the Verst VERGE answer of all time. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Like I literally started, you're gonna hear him. And I just started laughing.
Speaker 4:  I was like, thank you. Like I feel very validated. Like what are we, but
Speaker 4:  a series of dine
Speaker 5:  Out on that one for a while,
Speaker 4:  But like if you reconceptualize the entire interconnected application
Speaker 4:  environment of the web, It is just a bunch of databases that you can go ask
Speaker 4:  for stuff. And some of those databases have Toyota's Camrys in them and some
Speaker 4:  of them have vacation houses in them and some of 'em have sandwiches. It's
Speaker 4:  like, oh, those are just businesses that are going away. Right?
Speaker 6:  Or they're businesses that get funded through API calls instead of
Speaker 6:  ads on their web pages. Like will the incentives figure themselves out? Because
Speaker 6:  do agents need things to do? Yes. So like
Speaker 6:  if everything that an agent would talk to suddenly goes away because
Speaker 6:  its business model is destroyed. Like guess what? Agents don't work. So
Speaker 6:  will this get figured out? Will it be super messy? Will a lot of companies
Speaker 6:  go away? Will whole new categories of companies get invented? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yes. That's all true. Right? But do I think like the fundamental
Speaker 6:  building blocks of the plumbing of the web, like content and
Speaker 6:  things that, that an agent could do will go away? No. 'cause then there's
Speaker 6:  no agent. And what Google and Chat GBT are both racing to be is the interface
Speaker 6:  to interact with all those databases on your behalf, which is like the greatest
Speaker 6:  abstraction of technology I think maybe we've ever seen like in our lifetimes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If that happens at scale and the value that will accrue to the interface
Speaker 6:  is arguably greater than the value that Google gets now from running ads
Speaker 6:  on search.
Speaker 5:  I mean this is, this is the funny thing is like Alex, you and I have now
Speaker 5:  spent a lot of time on this podcast in the last week talking about display
Speaker 5:  ads. But like the fundamental question here is what is
Speaker 5:  what happens when display ads don't work anymore? What is the business of
Speaker 5:  the internet without display ads for the people who have traditionally
Speaker 5:  relied on display ads
Speaker 6:  Paying 250 a month for Google Ultra?
Speaker 5:  And maybe that's the answer. Maybe Google, maybe the end of this is Google
Speaker 5:  and open AI pay websites directly that
Speaker 5:  I don't love that. But that is one possible outcome of this. But if,
Speaker 5:  if the web is a series of un rendered databases, the whole
Speaker 5:  business of the web is suddenly immediately gone.
Speaker 4:  Ben Thompson, by the way, wrote about this this week based on MCP and
Speaker 4:  he was like, this is what stable coins are for. And like a like full
Speaker 4:  body grown basically is
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I ha I boy I hate that. Right? Oh man, I hate so much. But
Speaker 4:  Like, this is the idea that we'll, we'll have these like crypto microtransactions
Speaker 4:  pegged to the dollar in some way that make all that happen.
Speaker 5:  I would just say we, we have, if one more person says micro transactions
Speaker 5:  are the answer, I'm gonna send everyone a thousand links to
Speaker 5:  all the times we've tried Microtransactions and it didn't work. And then
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna heave myself out of a window.
Speaker 4:  I I I will Again, full body cringe in reading that Stablecoin said the answer,
Speaker 4:  but he did make one good point. Benson made it at one particularly excellent
Speaker 4:  point here in that the web already runs on
Speaker 4:  thousands if not millions of microtransactions every second because that's
Speaker 4:  how the ads work.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it's not me.
Speaker 4:  All of those banner ads are, are microtransactions.
Speaker 5:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  But but it's there. It's
Speaker 6:  You just hate stable coins. I get it. I
Speaker 4:  No, but that's whatever those are that's,
Speaker 5:  That's sure all of that exists. But if you made me type
Speaker 5:  in the IP address of every web website I wanted to go to that wouldn't, that
Speaker 5:  doesn't work either. Like making users, you're not gonna,
Speaker 6:  A model's gonna do it falls apart. You'll be like, go order me a sandwich
Speaker 6:  and it's gonna be like, or
Speaker 4:  Or you have some subscription to one of these centralized indexes that needs
Speaker 4:  to get built and that subscription like has the weird
Speaker 4:  Spotify model where it's like you get a penny and you get a penny and
Speaker 4:  Taylor Swift gets most of the pennies and like, maybe that's how it plays
Speaker 4:  out. But you can see just at io in the conversations they're
Speaker 4:  having, the the web we have today is, is
Speaker 4:  reaching, its like termination point. And this Yes. New other kind of web
Speaker 4:  is definitely like the thing they all want to build. It's the thing Microsoft
Speaker 4:  wants to build. It's right. That's why they're doing NL Web. It's the thing
Speaker 4:  Google is just sort of openly talking about. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's what OpenAI needs to have happen to make its dreams realize like if
Speaker 4:  you wear your Johnny Ive iPod shuffle and it can't do anything,
Speaker 4:  you're kind of stuck, right? Like it, it needs that whole
Speaker 4:  ecosystem to be developed and built and for the money to all work for that
Speaker 4:  product to be as useful as they want it to be. And I, I think this is a marker.
Speaker 4:  And I think part of Google's confidence is they think they can horsepower
Speaker 4:  into existence while sort of preserving the best of
Speaker 4:  the old web and bridging the revenue into the future. I will say publishers
Speaker 4:  are furious about this. Yeah. Oh, they're super mad. We have a
Speaker 4:  statement on our site from the news media alliance
Speaker 4:  disclosure, Vox Media News and the News Media Alliance along with Conde Nast.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's the business side of the company, but
Speaker 6:  We're also taking money from open ai.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's true. We have an open deal. It doesn't, it's a good disclosure.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't even occur to me. I also had a Netflix show. You should watch
Speaker 4:  it. It's great
Speaker 4:  that that's relevant, right? It's not just me bragging
Speaker 6:  Google wanted to buy Netflix. That that's true. Google,
Speaker 4:  There you go. Sooner announced that Google and wanted to buy Netflix at one
Speaker 4:  point,
Speaker 4:  but the publishers are like, the whole point of this deal was us getting
Speaker 4:  traffic and now that's gone. Yeah. And then they called it theft. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  that is, that is what the publisher industry, the news industry is saying
Speaker 4:  about AI mode. And I think Google is like, well, it'll be
Speaker 4:  sad when you're dead. Like that's kind of how it feels. Yeah. And I, I,
Speaker 4:  I think that will get litigated even harder. Not to mention the fact that
Speaker 4:  they might have to sell Chrome, which I don't know what will happen if they
Speaker 4:  have to sell Chrome.
Speaker 6:  I don't think they're gonna have to sell Chrome. No one, I got no vibe that
Speaker 6:  anyone was worried about Chrome at io. Well,
Speaker 4:  What are they gonna, they're not gonna like wander around their own party
Speaker 4:  being like, well this is gonna suck.
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. But like, you know, like when you're, when you're actually like
Speaker 6:  having a drink and you're staring at someone's face a few feet away and you
Speaker 6:  ask them like, are you worried about Chrome? Like yeah, you're trained, but
Speaker 6:  like you do it enough and you kind of get a vibe. And I did this on a few
Speaker 6:  topics and like, I was very curious like, are they worried about this?
Speaker 6:  Like up and down the, the chain. And
Speaker 6:  I think they know they're gonna have to stop just like
Speaker 6:  mafia style buying out search distribution, like that's gonna go away.
Speaker 6:  But do they think they're still the best search engine? Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  I don't think they think they're gonna have a divestiture. And that's another
Speaker 6:  topic. I mean, on the website thing, I'm curious what you guys think about
Speaker 6:  this. Our website's just going to become like driving a vintage car.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be this thing you do because it's a luxury. It feels
Speaker 6:  good. It's like a really bespoke, unique like visceral experience.
Speaker 6:  It's not as efficient, but you do it and you spend more money. Like,
Speaker 6:  I kind of feel like that's the direction websites are gonna go.
Speaker 4:  I do like thinking of The Verge dot com as like a cranky vintage Jaguar.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. It's kind of always broken, but you love it. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I don't know. I, there's other kinds of web,
Speaker 4:  like, you know, Substack and Ghost are, are web properties, blue Sky,
Speaker 4:  like at Protocol built on a lot of web ideas. And
Speaker 4:  the thing about Google is that all of these websites are effectively addicted
Speaker 4:  to Google as distribution. Right? That's why SEO has polluted the web so
Speaker 4:  badly. There wasn't another choice. And so like, yeah, maybe agents are gonna
Speaker 4:  turn everyone in a day basis. Like I think if you're a retailer, if you are
Speaker 4:  Walmart or Target or Macy's or whatever, and you're looking at Google's
Speaker 4:  new try on mode, which looks very cool, like the promise there
Speaker 4:  is, once you've tried on the clothes, virtually the
Speaker 4:  demo was you set a price and then at some point Google just
Speaker 4:  buys the clothes when it hits a sale. If you're a Target, you just totally
Speaker 4:  got disintermediated. Now you're, now you're just doing high frequency trading
Speaker 4:  with a Google bond. Like this is a really weird business to be in.
Speaker 4:  And Google's kind of answer there It is. Like, oh, well, we'll talk to them
Speaker 4:  and make sure that we show some of their webpages sometimes. And I said,
Speaker 4:  well, what's that negotiation gonna look like? And Google's like, it won't
Speaker 4:  be a negotiation, it'll be a conversation. This is ice cold,
Speaker 4:  right? Like there's a whole universe of businesses that
Speaker 4:  are gonna have to get reconfigured and a lot of 'em are gonna wanna say,
Speaker 4:  well actually we don't want anything to do with the salt. We want you to
Speaker 4:  come to our website Substack for, you know, it's many, many faults
Speaker 4:  is a web property. It's expressed on the web. There's not like a Substack
Speaker 4:  desktop app. And the innovation is they've solved distribution inside of
Speaker 4:  their own middle network. And that is really, really lucrative for a lot
Speaker 4:  of people on Substack.
Speaker 5:  All of that is the optimistic case, right? The the pessimistic case is, is
Speaker 5:  yes, websites die and everything becomes the high frequency
Speaker 5:  trading. You're, you're essentially fighting for Google scraps. The upside
Speaker 5:  is, for the first time in two decades, everybody's gonna have to care about
Speaker 5:  their website because it has to be, I mean this is, this is The Verge bet,
Speaker 5:  right? Like this is, this is the thing we've been talking about for a while
Speaker 5:  that like, the bet is we have to make something that
Speaker 5:  you come to on purpose or else we can't be that upset when nobody comes.
Speaker 5:  I think I think maybe that's a place we're gonna land. And a and a lot of
Speaker 5:  that's gonna make things harder for a lot of the way. There's gonna be a
Speaker 5:  lot of pain along the way. But like, if, if we do
Speaker 5:  this correctly,
Speaker 5:  I think, and the, the, this guy Guha, who I was talking to about all of the
Speaker 5:  NL web stuff, he's like, the fact that the web trends towards
Speaker 5:  centralization is bad and it has been bad several generations
Speaker 5:  in a row. And we have to stop it. And the only way to stop It is to distribute
Speaker 5:  the good technology everywhere. And I think there, like the way
Speaker 5:  we think about like the, the federated social networks, the way we think
Speaker 5:  about MCP, the way we think about NL Web, like bringing some of this AI stuff
Speaker 5:  to websites is like, maybe there's a chance that actually this ecosystem
Speaker 5:  gets bigger. Instead of you just going to google.com landing on a webpage
Speaker 5:  you've never heard of and then never going back because like that's what
Speaker 5:  we've been doing. But you could argue that's not the correct outcome,
Speaker 5:  but it's like it's an outcome.
Speaker 4:  I mean, what is this index of MCP servers accept
Speaker 4:  incredible centralization on the web that will reemerge. Right, right.
Speaker 5:  I mean, there's a reason the AI labs are the ones doing this, right? Like
Speaker 5:  this is not Tim Burner's lead being like, this is great for the internet.
Speaker 5:  This is anthropic being like, this is how we get internet access. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because they can't, I mean, you know, their first shot at it was what if
Speaker 4:  we click around your website? Right? Which is just incredibly brittle. Like,
Speaker 4:  it, it just, it's never, that is, that is never gonna work. That will
Speaker 4:  be the backup plan for all of this. And MCP will be plan A.
Speaker 4:  We'll see, I again, we like, we walked around Google io and they were
Speaker 4:  all feeling it like they're riding hide. Like their theme they kept saying
Speaker 4:  was research and reality. And it's like, what they mean is you didn't believe
Speaker 4:  us for a long time that we had all this stuff in the labs that we were working
Speaker 4:  on it, that it was coming to fruition. And now here all like all at once,
Speaker 4:  here's all of it. And you know, so it has to ship
Speaker 4:  and, and you know, people are, I'm confident we're gonna get feedback on
Speaker 4:  this part of the episode that's like they're stealing our jobs and boiling
Speaker 4:  the ocean. There are some really weird downsides to all this stuff
Speaker 4:  happening.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Both of those things are true by the way. They're they're true. They
Speaker 5:  are true.
Speaker 4:  But the weirdest one is that we are staring at the beginning of a
Speaker 4:  wholesale re-architecture of the internet. Yep. And that
Speaker 4:  we should probably pay a little more attention to that to make sure it's
Speaker 4:  good this time because last time like four people just got to be in charge
Speaker 4:  of everything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If
Speaker 4:  We, and like I might take the trade off if you can actually
Speaker 4:  decentralized a little bit more. We'll see. All right. We gotta take a break.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna come back. We the lighting round. We'll right back.
Speaker 4:  off this week. Next
Speaker 5:  Week it'll say Sponsored for flavor
Speaker 5:  and then we'll make new t-shirts.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be Doritos, it's gonna be great. You guys actually, does anyone
Speaker 4:  know anyone at Doritos? Listen, we should reach out.
Speaker 5:  Yes, I will eat Doritos constantly through an entire first cast
Speaker 5:  if Doritos would like to pay for
Speaker 4:  That. It's funny, you know, our great rivals for podcasts within a podcast,
Speaker 4:  my brother, my brother and me, they were once sponsored, I believe, by to
Speaker 4:  Tostitos Pizza rolls.
Speaker 5:  They were, they made a whole Totinos episode and it was excellent
Speaker 5:  content, if that makes sense. So myself, we've got a lot to live up to on
Speaker 5:  that front.
Speaker 4:  We do, we will never do that. I I just wanna be clear, you can't pay us money
Speaker 4:  to tell us what to do. That's where the flavor comes
Speaker 5:  From. I guess in this case this would be Brendan Carr, the Dummy brought
Speaker 5:  to you by the FCC.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of which it's time David,
Speaker 5:  Let's do this one more time just for this week and then
Speaker 5:  hopefully never again. Every week I root for it to be the last
Speaker 5:  version of Bread and Carr as a Dummy for a
Speaker 4:  Lot of reasons he
Speaker 5:  Won't. And every week It is not, It is time, once again for
Speaker 5:  2026 Webby award-winning podcast within a podcast
Speaker 5:  bread and a Carr is a Dummy neela, you've slept for three hours. I expect
Speaker 5:  this one to be very, very good.
Speaker 4:  There's, there's only, there's only two items in this one. The first one
Speaker 4:  is so stupid,
Speaker 4:  like, so, so stupid. And the other one is so disappointing and that's
Speaker 4:  really the heart of Brennan Carr is a Dummy, right? How can you disappoint
Speaker 4:  me in ever more stupid ways? So this week, Brennan Carr, America's number
Speaker 4:  one sensor who continues to make such a splash
Speaker 4:  as a wood, be speech cop that like more and more
Speaker 4:  profiles in coverage of him emerge. Politico wrote a profile this week.
Speaker 4:  John Oliver did an entire segment that is basically Brendan Carr is a
Speaker 4:  Dummy. Thank you to John Oliver for validating us and thank, thank you everyone
Speaker 4:  who sent that in. He
Speaker 5:  Is a real test of all presses. Good press. Our, our buddy Brendan,
Speaker 4:  It's not, you're a traitorous. More on Brendan. And I know this because this
Speaker 4:  week he has started to open an investigation
Speaker 4:  into NBC over Kamala Harris appearing on Saturday Night Live
Speaker 4:  disclosure NBC
Speaker 4:  investor and our parent company Vox Media. Just putting that out there you
Speaker 4:  can do it. That what you will again air mind you, no one can pay me to say
Speaker 4:  anything. Stop where subscriptions are on sale.
Speaker 4:  Hey, do you guys know who won the election? Do you remember who it was?
Speaker 4:  That doesn't matter.
Speaker 5:  I forget. Yeah, it's, it's so
Speaker 4:  Long ago. It is. Do you, do you remember who lost definitively lost and is
Speaker 4:  not the president? Do, do you know who, who that is? It was Kamel here. I
Speaker 4:  believe that she lost right? She right. Yeah. She did not win. We can
Speaker 4:  agree that she's not currently the president of the United States, correct.
Speaker 4:  Yes. The other guys. Okay, well Brendan here in
Speaker 4:  mid-May of 2025 has decided the most pressing
Speaker 4:  speech issue in the country is whether Saturday Night Live
Speaker 4:  violated the equal time rule for broadcast television stations
Speaker 4:  by having Kamala Harris appear on on the show.
Speaker 4:  Do you know what I also know definitively is that Brendan knows they didn't.
Speaker 4:  But yet he has decided here in May of 2025 to reopen an
Speaker 4:  investigation which was closed into whether
Speaker 4:  NBC and Saturn Night Live violated the equal time rule by having Kamala
Speaker 4:  Harris and Saturn live. The equal time rule is like an archaic broadcast
Speaker 4:  rule. It says if a broadcaster that uses the public airwaves
Speaker 4:  to broadcast content gives time to one candidate, they gotta give equal time
Speaker 4:  to other candidate. It's a little more complicated that, but that's right.
Speaker 4:  It's called the Equal time rule,
Speaker 5:  Which NBC did the next day.
Speaker 4:  NBC had Donald Trump on the next day. He got a bunch of time during NASCAR
Speaker 4:  race.
Speaker 4:  I reported on this while it was happening, right. 'cause Harris showed up
Speaker 4:  on SNL. There was a bunch of like MAGA tweets and then Brendan was
Speaker 4:  Brendan before he was auditioning for the job. He was like, I will arrest
Speaker 4:  everyone when I made the FCC Commissioner. Great.
Speaker 4:  I reported it out at the time. And what I heard from
Speaker 4:  sources in the FCC was the only
Speaker 4:  program that regularly deals with this is Saturday Night Live.
Speaker 4:  They are the best at it because politicians are always showing up on Saturday
Speaker 4:  Night Live. Oh, interesting. Like they have the infrastructure for dealing
Speaker 4:  with the equal time rule. 'cause no one else gives a shit. So of
Speaker 4:  course they filed the equal time notice of the FCC and of course they offered
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump time the next day because they're good at it. Like, this is
Speaker 4:  a thing Saturday Night Live is the best at of all of the shows on all of
Speaker 4:  the broadcast networks. And so sure enough, Brendan,
Speaker 4:  there's, you know, his emails were FOIA because he was threatening this in
Speaker 4:  this, this investigation before he was ever made the FCC Commissioner. And
Speaker 4:  he emailed Fox News producers, here are the, here's the
Speaker 4:  equal time request from NBC Saturday Live.
Speaker 4:  Like he, he know, I know he knows it 'cause I'm reading his email saying
Speaker 4:  he knows it. They complied. Former FCC chair Jessica Rosen
Speaker 4:  war. So looked at this and dismissed this 'cause of they had complied, you
Speaker 4:  know, and I know they complied 'cause Trump was on the air during the NASCAR
Speaker 4:  race. The next day, E equal time was, was given. Well
Speaker 4:  here we are. May, 2025 election has been won. We have accepted a
Speaker 4:  jet from the government of Qatar. Like we're definitively passed
Speaker 4:  Saturday Night Live booking Kamala Harris having any effect on anything that
Speaker 4:  happens in the country. And Brendan is running around trying to punish
Speaker 4:  NBC for violating the equal time rule finding ways legally
Speaker 4:  to reopen this investigation. Just to put more pressure
Speaker 4:  on NBC for its alleged coverage
Speaker 4:  of Donald Trump being lost. This is just speech police stuff.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, it's over, like the election is over.
Speaker 4:  Whatever harm you may have felt, the Trump campaign felt that Carr
Speaker 4:  felt for his, his boss and Buddy Donald. It's over.
Speaker 4:  They, they won but like the harm has passed. Right.
Speaker 4:  The, the opportunity for that to sway the election has come and gone and
Speaker 4:  it didn't work. And he knows, we can see
Speaker 4:  his emails, we reported on his emails that he knows
Speaker 4:  that they didn't break the rule and yet he's trying to reopen. I mean this
Speaker 4:  is just moronic, right? Like he's doing it to be a cop, to be,
Speaker 4:  to chill the speech of these news divisions that are reporting on Donald Trump.
Speaker 4:  Maybe 'cause NBC owns MS NBC even though Comcast is spinning that off into
Speaker 4:  a new company called NT I haven't even talked about yet. But like that's
Speaker 4:  why he is doing it so stupid. So like I will,
Speaker 4:  I will, we'll put it in the show notes. We have his emails where he's telling
Speaker 4:  Fox producers, they complied with the rules and yet he's gonna reopen this
Speaker 4:  investigation just 'cause he wants to be a cop. He's not even trying to hide
Speaker 5:  The fact that this is what it's about. It's very straightforward.
Speaker 4:  It's very straightforward. So that's one that's very stupid.
Speaker 4:  Here's the very disappointing one. We've talked a lot about how
Speaker 4:  Brendan threatens deals that are in the pipelines and tries to
Speaker 4:  companies to comply with whatever he wants. Whether it's their coverage,
Speaker 4:  which he says is biased, whether it's DEI policies, which he says are not
Speaker 4:  racist enough, whatever It is, he gets what he wants by holding up deals.
Speaker 4:  So last week Verizon completed its acquisition of
Speaker 4:  Frontier, another fiber provider. And it got that through the
Speaker 4:  FCC by sending a letter to Brandon Carr saying it was walking
Speaker 4:  back all of its DI efforts.
Speaker 4:  Super disappointing, right? That Verizon just rolled and said we're gonna
Speaker 4:  give up on our DEI efforts. This is Brendan at work,
Speaker 4:  right? He, he, he went and threatened the business over something has nothing
Speaker 4:  to do with the business and Verizon caved like, just
Speaker 4:  straightforwardly caved and said this is a government regulation that we're
Speaker 4:  gonna deal with even though the FCC telling us who to hire
Speaker 4:  and fire is kind of a straightforward infringement of its like rights as
Speaker 4:  a business. And the thing that is particularly disappointing to me
Speaker 4:  is that whenever the FCC has tried to do something good to Verizon,
Speaker 4:  they have fought it tooth and nail. They're the primary legal antagonist
Speaker 4:  who net neutrality for a decade. Every court case,
Speaker 4:  every challenge. Verizon was there. Whenever you talk about
Speaker 4:  increasing broadband access, Verizon fights that stuff tooth and nail. Verizon
Speaker 4:  takes money and promises Fios will be rolled out in New Jersey and
Speaker 4:  they just never do it. And then they get sued and they fight it tooth and
Speaker 4:  nail. We had the, the CEO of Verizon Wireless on decoder. I don't know
Speaker 4:  why enterprise software CEOs or telecom CEOs show up
Speaker 4:  on the show, but they just, they came on the show and I asked him, are you
Speaker 4:  gonna fight Brendan Carr in these weird regulations? As hard as you have
Speaker 4:  fought net neutral, you just run the clip. I wanna be very clear, very explicit
Speaker 4:  about this. When the government passed net neutrality rules, it wasn't, we
Speaker 4:  have to follow the rules of the land. It was we are going to file lawsuits
Speaker 4:  for a decade to get out of these rules 'cause we think they're dumb. And
Speaker 4:  in this case you're saying Brendan Carr who has been openly censorious,
Speaker 4:  openly chilling of speech, openly hostile to companies because they have
Speaker 4:  diversity initiatives. You're saying you just have to follow his rules. We
Speaker 4:  have
Speaker 10:  To follow the rules of the land. I don't think those are his rules. Those
Speaker 10:  are rules of the land and administration. Are
Speaker 4:  You gonna file a decade worth of lawsuits about these rules?
Speaker 10:  We don't know. We are gonna work constructively with them to follow rules
Speaker 10:  that are needed. But at the end of the day, look, our role is to ask stakeholders
Speaker 10:  that we have, you know, my stakeholders are my shareholders, my customers,
Speaker 10:  my employees and society at large. We have to manage and we are gonna deliver
Speaker 10:  for those stakeholders what's needed for us. And we will do whatever's needed
Speaker 10:  with the administration to deliver to all the stakeholders. It's a balance.
Speaker 10:  When you run a large company our size, you have to balance the different
Speaker 10:  stakeholders and we will balance those stakeholders. We've done it extremely
Speaker 10:  well in the last 25 years that we've been Verizon and we'll continue to
Speaker 10:  do that going forward.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. To balance the stakeholders guys, we have
Speaker 5:  A comprehensive view and we have balancing the stakeholders and you can
Speaker 5:  get out of almost anything that sucks. Yep. That is 60 seconds
Speaker 5:  of him being like, yeah, when he says those aren't Brendan Carr's rules,
Speaker 5:  those are the rules of the land. That sucks.
Speaker 4:  That's a, I mean that's straightforwardly a lie. Yeah. Those are Brendan
Speaker 4:  Carr's rules. He said, I'm gonna hold up this deal unless you walk back your
Speaker 4:  DEI initiatives and Verizon instead of fighting, which they
Speaker 4:  always do when it comes to consumer protection or broadband deployment,
Speaker 4:  they always fight here. They rolled and
Speaker 4:  it's, it worked. And the thing that kills me is it doesn't have to work.
Speaker 4:  Like if you stand up to these bullies in particular, they tend to roll over
Speaker 4:  and br Brendan getting a win is just like the most disappointing
Speaker 4:  outcome. And it's particularly funny 'cause it's, Verizon always
Speaker 4:  fights, Verizon looks at government regulation and is like, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 4:  no. One decade. And here they rolled. And I just think, I think it
Speaker 4:  sucks. I am, I am incredibly disappointed that it worked in this way. I'm
Speaker 4:  also, you know, not for nothing. It's another merger of
Speaker 4:  ISPs and it will result not in greater service and lower prices.
Speaker 4:  You, you know how it's gonna go. Yeah. Like we all know how this is gonna
Speaker 5:  Go. I was wondering about this in the context of there was news this week
Speaker 5:  that at and t is paying I think five and
Speaker 5:  $5.75 billion to buy lumens, fiber business
Speaker 5:  and a bunch of cities all over the place. And the timing of this is so
Speaker 5:  suspicious to me because it really seems like at t looked at this and said,
Speaker 5:  oh, all we have to do is write a letter about DEI and this'll get done.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, I hope that's not how this goes, but it sure seems like at
Speaker 5:  and t is about to just run the same playbook in order to get this thing done.
Speaker 4:  I think there's a, a renewed sense that some mergers are allowed to
Speaker 4:  happen. You know, there was a lot of excitement even in the tech
Speaker 4:  industry, right. That like deals are back. Yeah. Biden and Le Kahn, were
Speaker 4:  not gonna let any deals happen and now the deals are back. And that actually
Speaker 4:  wasn't the case early on. Like Andrew Ferguson, the new
Speaker 4:  chair of the FTC is kind of a trust buster. He kind of hates big companies.
Speaker 4:  He hates big tech. Brendan is just like, give me an
Speaker 4:  ounce of blood. You know, just, just like
Speaker 4:  bloviating away, moronically like these deals aren't happening. And I think
Speaker 4:  there's, people are starting to figure out like there's a path forward and
Speaker 4:  it involves trading your values to get the deals right.
Speaker 5:  And over and over they're doing it. They're so happy to do it.
Speaker 4:  Well I think the next one we're gonna see is CBS in
Speaker 4:  Paramount settling their case with Donald Trump over 60 minutes to get the
Speaker 4:  Skydance deal done. And that will be a dark and sad day for American journalism.
Speaker 4:  Yep. To the point where it's like, oh, that's over. You shouldn't trust that
Speaker 4:  network anymore. That's brutal. As always, Brendan,
Speaker 4:  if you're listening and I super know you are,
Speaker 4:  you can come on the show. You know, I got your press release today. I wrote
Speaker 4:  back to your, your people and invited you on. He put out a press release
Speaker 4:  about how much more spectrum he is opening for satellite networks. Great.
Speaker 4:  He loves it. It's his favorite thing to do. Congrats on him. You come on,
Speaker 4:  you can, you can defend this stuff. The, the, the fanciest CEOs in the industry,
Speaker 4:  telecom CEOs come on to coder and answer the questions
Speaker 4:  because they can defend themselves. Sampath the CEO of Verizon Wireless.
Speaker 4:  He gave maybe the single best answer to the decision making question on a
Speaker 4:  coder we ever had. Even though I completely disagree with, we have to manage
Speaker 4:  for our stakeholders. They can defend themselves. They're, they're smart.
Speaker 4:  I think you're stupid so you're not gonna show up. But if you want to, you
Speaker 4:  can, we're available, you can be on the show, you can be on decoder. But
Speaker 4:  for now that has been Brendan Carr's Dummy America's favorite podcast within
Speaker 4:  a podcast.
Speaker 5:  That's beautiful. I've decided to take a comprehensive view to Brendan Carr.
Speaker 5:  I'll get back to you on what that looks like. I have a comprehensive
Speaker 4:  View
Speaker 5:  Of data. Can I offer you some breaking news as a pal Clinton? Yes. Mark
Speaker 5:  Erman from Bloomberg just published a big story about
Speaker 5:  Apple with two very interesting pieces of information that I think are germane
Speaker 5:  to what we've been talking about. Thing number one is he reported that Apple
Speaker 5:  has been working on smart glasses and has like really ramped up its effort
Speaker 5:  to sell smart glasses and hopes to do so by the end of next year. And he,
Speaker 5:  he, he cites one person presumably inside of Apple who said
Speaker 5:  they will be similar to the meta ray bands but Better Made, which is
Speaker 5:  that's Tim Cook. Terrific. So yeah, presumably he called
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook and Tim told him that. And here we are. So that's piece of information
Speaker 5:  number one is that Apple Smart Glasses, which we have been hearing for a
Speaker 5:  while we're, we're sort of being pushed further and further off may have
Speaker 5:  been pulled back up in the roadmap. And the other one is that
Speaker 5:  we've been hearing for a while about the idea of an Apple watch with an integrated
Speaker 5:  camera and that is apparently shut down and that will no longer
Speaker 5:  be a thing. Which is a shame because I wanted to know very badly how any
Speaker 5:  of that was going to work in the real world.
Speaker 5:  But this is, this is Apple pushing on the same kind of stuff, right? Like
Speaker 5:  multi multimodal AI assistance is the name of the game here and Apple
Speaker 5:  seems to be on the smart glasses trend along with
Speaker 5:  at this point kind of everybody other than open AI and Johnny, I,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I can tell you why they're doing it. It's because these smart glasses
Speaker 6:  are hitting decent scale. They're doing single digit million sales a year.
Speaker 6:  The meta raybans are, they may get to double digit
Speaker 6:  millions.
Speaker 5:  They're also like good and people like them, which I think is an important
Speaker 4:  Oh I think everyone's super confused and most of all meta about why people
Speaker 4:  like them RayBan glasses. Oh
Speaker 5:  That's true. But sure. But they are good and people do like them. Yeah. People
Speaker 5:  are
Speaker 4:  Buying them. They they are. But what people like is having glasses with a
Speaker 4:  camera in them. Sure. In a shutter button. They don't like
Speaker 5:  Ai. But that's also, if you're Apple, that's a, that's a core competency,
Speaker 5:  right? Like that's a reason to do it if you're Apple.
Speaker 4:  But it, that's not, I don't think they're an AI distribution platform the
Speaker 4:  way that Meta wants 'em to be. No, but but
Speaker 4:  they're don't have a display in them yet. And that's what everyone else is
Speaker 4:  demoing. Right? I'm Apple Smart Glasses. If they don't have a
Speaker 4:  display, they're, they're one kind of product. If they do have a display,
Speaker 4:  they're a very different kind of product and no one has cracked that display
Speaker 4:  problem yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wait. Least
Speaker 4:  Of all Google the one we saw the Android xr it it, It is so a prototype,
Speaker 4:  It is not a display.
Speaker 5:  You saw these right? I'm gonna talk to VA bunch about all this stuff on,
Speaker 5:  on Tuesday and the glasses, but I am curious you, you got to try 'em, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, just
Speaker 6:  Really quickly. It was like a five minute demo and it was basically Gemini
Speaker 6:  on your face. The weird thing about these prototypes is the wave guide is
Speaker 6:  very small and not high resolution but it's in the dead center of the lens.
Speaker 6:  Whereas I was expecting like a heads up to the side thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, the like glassy, glassy
Speaker 6:  Kind of like up here. Yeah. 'cause it's literally, yeah it's literally just
Speaker 6:  a Gemini icon and then it reads back what it's saying to it and what you're
Speaker 6:  saying, which is like I don't, I don't need that. The, the best thing was
Speaker 6:  the map stuff where like you could turn your head down and it would show
Speaker 6:  where you were, your pin would move like it had GPS and tracking and who
Speaker 6:  knows, maybe the room was like set up for that but, and then the other thing
Speaker 6:  was like oh you, when you take a picture with it, you see the picture like
Speaker 6:  you can see how you're framing it because it shows it to you. Whereas the
Speaker 6:  Met Raybans obviously you have to take your phone out to see what you shot.
Speaker 6:  That's cool. Yeah, the hardware's not super compelling yet. The software's
Speaker 6:  very bare bones. I think they will actually start shipping these next year
Speaker 6:  and they got Warby Parker and Carrying, which makes
Speaker 6:  Cartier and like Gucci glasses and they got another cool, the name
Speaker 6:  escapes me another cool glasses company out of Asia that V was very excited
Speaker 6:  about. They got them on board. So basically Meta has hitched its wagon to
Speaker 6:  elsewhere Luxottica, which makes Ray Band and Oakley and a bunch of other
Speaker 6:  brands. And Google tried to get that deal. I reported that they
Speaker 6:  tried very hard and they failed and now they're going for basically every
Speaker 6:  other eyewear partner that they can to get Android as the platform instead
Speaker 6:  of meta. So I think we're gonna see this AI platform, smart glasses
Speaker 6:  battle between Meta and Google with their partnerships
Speaker 6:  strategy. Gemini's a better AI meta has a head start. We'll see
Speaker 6:  how it shakes out. The demo though at IO is like kind of meh. I do wanna
Speaker 6:  quickly say though a demo that was awesome and that I'm very excited about
Speaker 6:  and we have a great video about that I did with Veen is Beam. Oh yeah. Which
Speaker 6:  project? Starline and is basically Google's answer to what if virtual
Speaker 6:  meetings suck less.
Speaker 5:  Starline has been one of those ideas that Google has had that seems to like
Speaker 5:  get cooler every 18 months but also less and
Speaker 5:  less likely to ever be a real thing.
Speaker 6:  It was really cool. Like they invited Vera and I to the lab where they made
Speaker 6:  it. We were the first ones in their like labs hardware prototype room
Speaker 6:  externally. And got to see like how they moved all the tech into basically
Speaker 6:  what is it started as like it filled a room five years ago and now it's
Speaker 6:  basically a DVD player and everything is streamed through Google Cloud. So
Speaker 6:  they built this proprietary volumetric 3D AI model
Speaker 6:  that makes you look like a hologram basically through a 2D. Very
Speaker 6:  fancy. I tried to get them Neli to really explain the panel. It's a highly
Speaker 6:  customized panel that's doing a bunch of fancy
Speaker 6:  pixel work, but I couldn't get a lot of detail out of it. But it's a reference
Speaker 6:  design now that HP will actually start deploying into offices
Speaker 6:  later this year. So they've got Salesforce, Deloitte, some other
Speaker 6:  companies that have committed to installs and I asked, I was like, is this
Speaker 6:  expensive because companies will not buy this if it's not, you know, just
Speaker 6:  as like cheap as their existing video conferencing software. And they're
Speaker 6:  like, Nope, that's why we did the AI work. It's on the cloud and it costs
Speaker 6:  about the same as the video conferencing setups you see in offices today.
Speaker 6:  So I think there's a real chance we start seeing Beam and people who work
Speaker 6:  in offices start seeing Beam over the next couple years. And It is, It is
Speaker 6:  wild. Like go watch the video. It's on our YouTube veering. Got to try it
Speaker 6:  for the first time. I had done it a couple times 'cause we had it at code
Speaker 6:  and then it was at IO a few years ago and it was starline and
Speaker 6:  Veering tried it and it's just this like holy shit moment every time someone
Speaker 6:  tries it for the first time. I mean, NELI, you remember? I do. And yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's cool. It's like one of these classic Google things. Like, it reminds
Speaker 6:  me of Waymo, they just toil away as like with the resources that only
Speaker 6:  a company like Google can to invent this wild new thing. And then five
Speaker 6:  to 10 years in they're like, it's ready. And it's like now the cars are driving
Speaker 6:  themselves. Now we have holograms that we're like putting into
Speaker 6:  Deloitte offices. Like it's just happening. So that was pretty cool. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  My understanding of the screen, by the way is the reason they're not talking
Speaker 6:  about it in detail is it It is more standard
Speaker 6:  particular display than not. I think there is some,
Speaker 6:  a lot of custom stuff going on there, but usually when you have the big tech
Speaker 6:  innovation, you talk about it a lot. Yeah. And the reason they're like, it's
Speaker 6:  a secret is like, it's kind of a 3D display. Like, and it all the
Speaker 6:  actual happening is in the camera, but eventually these are gonna be out
Speaker 6:  there and we can go look at them and figure it out. Yeah. But It is very
Speaker 6:  exciting to see that out. Yeah. On the glasses, the display is not
Speaker 6:  solved. No meta Orion, like they spent billions of dollars on the
Speaker 6:  wrong technology and it didn't scale to make those displays. Right. Turns
Speaker 6:  out growing crystals doesn't work at scale. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We're just crystal farmers out here guys. I don't know. I mean, I, I
Speaker 6:  don't know who's gonna build those displays. I don dunno where they're gonna
Speaker 6:  come from. No one, no one's cracked it yet. And it, it's, It is just one
Speaker 6:  of these things like what is the core technology that's gonna enable this
Speaker 6:  next generation of products? You need the displays to make the smart glasses
Speaker 6:  or you don't, or you're Johnny, Ivan, you make a fancy aluminum polka x and
Speaker 6:  like, that's like,
Speaker 6:  all right. That's, we are way over. I'm, I'm, I'm so sorry to everyone
Speaker 6:  for, for the Rams today. I mean, what did we expect? Like this week, the
Speaker 6:  after, I know we got a lot on the site. Tons and tons of coverage.
Speaker 6:  V is gonna be back next week to talk more about the glasses demo. She just
Speaker 6:  published a story. Trying to guess what Johnny is willing to way more coverage
Speaker 6:  than The Vergecast from her coming up Sundar on Monday.
Speaker 6:  Get ready. It wasn't, it's not. I will tell it's not as tense as it was last
Speaker 6:  year, but there's some moments. I think you're gonna like it. All right.
Speaker 6:  That's it. That's Vergecast. Bye.
Speaker 11:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 11:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 11:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 11:  Our show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 11:  that's it. We'll see you next week.