# Transcript
ID: 43d54cd6-9b74-40af-9903-213ae3dd3092
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3221695638614094388/-5250048170232783525/s93290-US-5768s-1738927965.mp3
Description: Nilay, David, and Richard Lawler take on a big week in confusing news stories. First, they talk through the latest from Elon Musk's DOGE, which is running rampant through government computer systems with little pushback. Then they explain the latest on the US government's tariff strategy, and the mass confusion it's causing across tech. Then they pivot away from politics and talk about streaming: the Super Bowl coming to Tubi, the deeply confusing forthcoming Fox streaming service, whatever Comcast is doing this year, and more. Finally, in the lightning round, they talk about Sonos's streaming box, Brendan Carr's latest assaults on free speech, OpenAI's "new" logo, and more.
Speaker 4:  flagship podcast. The cost of about Hard fork. Our greatest rival. Ooh,
Speaker 4:  wouldn't that be great?
Speaker 5:  People would pay for that.
Speaker 4:  I think people would pay you thought you wanted no ads. What you really wanted
Speaker 4:  was unvarnished hard shots at Casey Newton
Speaker 4:  for us,
Speaker 5:  Do we have a podcast enemy? I feel like it like naturally it should be hard
Speaker 5:  fork, but Casey used to work at The Verge. We
Speaker 5:  love Casey. We love Kevin. Like every Kevin
Speaker 5:  needs more people on his side because just Bing is out here just trying to
Speaker 5:  ruin his life and marriage.
Speaker 4:  Right. I'm saying Kevin needs more human beings to love him a hundred percent
Speaker 4:  because the robots Yeah, are aggressively trying to love that
Speaker 5:  Man. Yeah. So like Kevin, we're here. So like who's our enemy?
Speaker 5:  Can you email us and suggest an enemy for us? I would like to have one
Speaker 4:  And I'm down for fake beef. Like you want us to do a WWE style fake beef.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely. Like you let us know. The problem is that many of our wouldbe
Speaker 4:  rivals are also our friends and people who used to work here.
Speaker 4:  This is what happens when you build the network. This is my theory of true
Speaker 4:  power. Richard is like ready to go, by the way.
Speaker 1:  Enemies.
Speaker 4:  You need more friends as Rob Poka says. Alright, it's The Vergecast. I'm
Speaker 4:  your friend Neli. That's Richard Lawler making a triumphant reappearance
Speaker 4:  on The Verge House. What's up buddy? Hello. And as always, David Pierces
Speaker 4:  here. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  There's a lot going on this week, including, like I said, just a number of
Speaker 4:  random shots at Hard Fork throughout this episode. I keep saying this and
Speaker 4:  now we have to deliver on it. We, we did not plan to actually take a bunch
Speaker 4:  of shots at Hard Fork on this episode, but we'll try. We'll, we'll do our
Speaker 4:  best. There is in fact a lot going on this week. Elon Musk has taken over
Speaker 4:  the government that seems notable. There's tariffs which
Speaker 4:  seem boring, but we'll dramatically affect the prices of basically every
Speaker 4:  tech product in big and small ways. We gotta talk about those a little bit.
Speaker 4:  Sonos has like a new streaming box. The Go 90 Scale
Speaker 4:  is here on our rundown triumphant return of the Go 90 scale. And then we
Speaker 4:  got a lightning round unsponsored because I'm gonna continue using lightning
Speaker 4:  round to dunk on Brendan Carr, our truest enemy.
Speaker 4:  I, I've come all the way around and realized that we do have an enemy here
Speaker 4:  on the vir chest. And it's FCC chair Brendan
Speaker 5:  Carr. Yeah, but he's not a podcast enemy. Brendan, start a podcast so you
Speaker 5:  can be our podcast enemy.
Speaker 4:  Don't give him ideas.
Speaker 5:  Could he investigate his own podcast?
Speaker 4:  This entire part of our lives, like of American
Speaker 4:  History is tire some bureaucrats with podcasts pretending they're the voice
Speaker 4:  of the people. Don't, I mean it's fine. Alright, let's start with
Speaker 4:  whatever is going on with Elon Musk and Doge. It has been a long week,
Speaker 4:  A long week with high highs and lows of this news cycle.
Speaker 4:  Stuff that isn't real, stuff that seems very real lawsuits.
Speaker 4:  The Doge being blocked from access to treasury department, payment systems
Speaker 4:  getting only read only access or big fight about that. Senator Ron
Speaker 4:  Wyden was on decoder this week and he said For all practical purposes,
Speaker 4:  I'd call that a coup. We're all over the place. David, you have
Speaker 4:  been sort of an impartial observer. You're just taking it all in. Explain
Speaker 4:  what's going on and how people should think about it. It's simple task, really.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that the simplest way I can put this
Speaker 5:  in, in like honest human terms is that Elon Musk and
Speaker 5:  a small group of people he appointed or hired or
Speaker 5:  I don't know, met on the internet in some way have like in a relatively meaningful
Speaker 5:  way, taken over the federal government over the course of,
Speaker 5:  I would say especially the last 10 days. But like it, it sort of
Speaker 5:  ramped up all this week they've gone from
Speaker 5:  agency to agency and essentially barged in demanding
Speaker 5:  complete access to everything. Like you said, they, they've been demanding
Speaker 5:  payment information at the Treasury department, which has obviously gigantic
Speaker 5:  ramifications because that's where all the money is in the government and
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of money in the government. They've been in noaa, the, the
Speaker 5:  Oceanic and Like
Speaker 4:  Atmosphere.
Speaker 5:  The atmosphere. Thank you. Yeah. They've been in noaa, the Oceanic and Atmosphere
Speaker 5:  Agency, which is the one that does all the weather stuff. By the way, If
Speaker 5:  you have never read Michael Lewis's book, the Fifth Risk, he has a whole
Speaker 5:  thing about the fact that they do all the interesting work on weather and
Speaker 5:  that a bunch of lobbyists have made it so that they're not allowed to do
Speaker 5:  anything with it. And so that's why you pay money for weather forecasts.
Speaker 5:  That's a random aside, but is a perfect microcosm of like the disaster of
Speaker 5:  all of this stuff. They've essentially, for all
Speaker 5:  intents and purposes, shut down usaid while Elon Musk has been
Speaker 5:  tweeting conspiracy theories about how it's a criminal organization.
Speaker 5:  There's just all kinds of weird stuff going on. So a lot of it
Speaker 5:  is
Speaker 5:  bad, but in a way we don't totally understand. There, there is a, there is
Speaker 5:  a sort of incredible amount of access
Speaker 5:  and information that these unelected, unqualified people
Speaker 5:  have access to. What that is going to mean in the
Speaker 5:  short, medium and long term is still in some ways hard to know. It means
Speaker 5:  a lot of people are out of jobs. It means a lot of your information is available
Speaker 5:  to people to whom it should not be available. But I think we're still at
Speaker 5:  the very beginning of a people understanding that this
Speaker 5:  is really happening. Like the big other push this week was a lot of people
Speaker 5:  being like, how were you allowing this to happen? And we spent the whole
Speaker 5:  week I think of a lot of people, Democrats in particular sitting there being
Speaker 5:  like, this can't be real. They're not. Are they, would they or would they
Speaker 5:  wouldn't, would they? And then they're like, oh my God, they did. And so
Speaker 5:  now they're starting to fight back and there are real legal tests and the
Speaker 5:  question of how far this Doge group is actually going to be allowed to go
Speaker 5:  and what they're going to be allowed to do, I think anyone telling
Speaker 5:  you they know the answer to that is lying to you. But right now it feels
Speaker 5:  bad. But in a complicated and hard to fully wrap your head around way,
Speaker 5:  which I think in a lot of ways is the point.
Speaker 4:  Right? And there's also what I would call a bunch of fake transparency in
Speaker 4:  the mix because the transparency is real, but the
Speaker 4:  purposes are, are fake or misleading. So, you know, they,
Speaker 4:  they tore down this agency, U-S-A-I-D-U-S-A, which is an agency
Speaker 4:  exists by, by creation of congress in statute, it's funded by Congress.
Speaker 4:  The Executive ranch is not supposed to just show up and tear those things
Speaker 4:  down. It it, that's illegal. It's not illegal when the judge
Speaker 4:  says it's illegal. It's just illegal. Like right. They're not allowed to
Speaker 4:  do that. That's a big problem. That's a constitutional crisis all on
Speaker 4:  its own. And then right next to that is what I, what I keep thinking of is
Speaker 4:  fake transparency, which is Elon and a bunch of
Speaker 4:  right wing grifters on X are looking at a website that has
Speaker 4:  existed for a long time, also created by the government called USA
Speaker 4:  spending.gov. It exists, it is the literally the official source
Speaker 4:  of spending in the US United States government. It's basically just a searchable
Speaker 4:  database of spending. They're looking up numbers
Speaker 4:  and recipients of government spending. They're
Speaker 4:  manipulating the date ranges in, in bizarre ways. And then claiming
Speaker 4:  things like Politico got $8 million from USAA. Right?
Speaker 4:  Which is just flatly not true. Right? Over 17
Speaker 4:  years, the government has spent a lot of money in Politico subscriptions.
Speaker 4:  But those subscriptions are for Political pro, which is their data service.
Speaker 4:  And it costs like $20,000 per year per seat because government
Speaker 4:  bureaucrats and policy professionals and lobbyists all depend on
Speaker 4:  pretty boring like gray suit data, people doing hardcore policy
Speaker 4:  analysis of Politico. It is not the front facing politico that's all about
Speaker 4:  like what some senator said in the hallway right before they retired.
Speaker 4:  It's their data organization, right? Much like Bloomberg, like you know,
Speaker 4:  like people I think are more familiar with Bloomberg than Politico Pro Bloomberg
Speaker 4:  is a very expensive terminal subscription that stockbrokers use to
Speaker 4:  chart trades. Like it's a high speed data service that fronts
Speaker 4:  a famously money losing newsroom in magazine, which is the like
Speaker 4:  media arm of the organization. Like the part of Bloomberg, and I'll just
Speaker 4:  call it Mark Erman 'cause I'm sure all of our listeners know who Mark Erman
Speaker 4:  is. Like amazing Apple Reporter gets all the scoops is there're gonna be
Speaker 4:  a new iPhone this year. Mark Erman knows that there's gonna be any
Speaker 4:  iPhone this year. That whole part of the organization, Bloomberg
Speaker 4:  Media loses money 'cause it's just brand building for the
Speaker 4:  terminal, which prints money at a huge rate. Many, many media
Speaker 4:  organizations have this kind of relationship. Politico has one of
Speaker 4:  them. So you're just like looking at what this like fake transparency.
Speaker 4:  People are like googling the word New York, they see the word New York Times
Speaker 4:  and they're adding up the numbers for everything that has gone to
Speaker 4:  anything with the word New York in the name and saying U-S-A-I-D has funded
Speaker 4:  the New York Times $47 million. This is just not true. The New York Times
Speaker 4:  is a public company. If they had one customer that was paying
Speaker 4:  $47 million a year, we could actually verify that very quickly. This would
Speaker 4:  be a, a scandal with its own, with its own shareholders,
Speaker 4:  right? But what you're getting is these like screenshots of transparency
Speaker 4:  that were not created by Doge created by another government agency that existed
Speaker 4:  forever by statute funded by Congress. And there
Speaker 4:  it's being used to propel a narrative that Doge is doing something at all
Speaker 4:  when what we do know they're doing reported by Wired,
Speaker 4:  lots of great reporting coming in Wired by the way, reported by the New York
Speaker 4:  Times, some of our own reporting. They're showing up in these
Speaker 4:  systems, they're showing up these agencies, they're setting up their own
Speaker 4:  email servers, which is very funny given the history, the contentious
Speaker 4:  history of email servers and, and Slack
Speaker 5:  Servers
Speaker 4:  And Slack servers. They're forcing people outta their systems.
Speaker 4:  They're writing their own code to take control of the payments and they're
Speaker 4:  basically saying, oh, we realize the government runs on computers.
Speaker 4:  If we take over the computers, we will run the government.
Speaker 4:  Which is the most VERGE thing to say. Like, what is the government? It's
Speaker 4:  a bunch of computer systems. Yeah. That it makes sense. Like
Speaker 4:  I think intuitively to us in our newsroom, I think it
Speaker 4:  intuitively made sense to the wired newsroom, which is why they've done so
Speaker 4:  much great reporting. Like who runs the computers is really who runs
Speaker 4:  your company, who runs your country. And so
Speaker 4:  obviously Elon Musk knows this as well. So he showed up and took control
Speaker 4:  of the computer. So now question is can he do that? Is he allowed to do that?
Speaker 4:  Can anyone stop him? Do any of these people even know
Speaker 4:  what it means to run the computers and what it means to have read only access,
Speaker 4:  which is a real, real DOGE of terminology, right?
Speaker 4:  If you all, If you have read only access, but you are in
Speaker 4:  charge of someone has right access, it doesn't matter
Speaker 4:  Right. What your individual permissions are. So there's, I think there's
Speaker 4:  a lot of moves here that I think are confusing, but it boils down to like
Speaker 4:  a very VERGE idea, which is yeah, If you run the computers,
Speaker 4:  you actually run the thing. But pretty simply, and I don't think a lot of
Speaker 4:  elected officials realize that the country is just a bunch of computers.
Speaker 5:  It's a bunch of computers that are operated by people
Speaker 5:  who have and would like to keep having their jobs. Yeah. Right? Like over
Speaker 5:  and over and over. The, some of the pushback on this has been like, well,
Speaker 5:  why aren't the people in these jobs doing anything about it? They're just,
Speaker 5:  they're just bureaucrats. Why aren't they stopping them? It's like, what?
Speaker 5:  'cause they can't, because Elon Musk rolls in and is like, you're fired and
Speaker 5:  I'm going to tweet to 200 million people your
Speaker 5:  name and information. And that turns out to be pretty
Speaker 5:  threatening to a lot of people If you do that.
Speaker 5:  And so it's, it's become this thing where this, this tiny group of people
Speaker 5:  is like, it, it is just wild to me how far we got
Speaker 5:  by everybody just assuming like something like this wouldn't happen.
Speaker 5:  It's like, like Dan Hanh who worked for the federal government as a longtime
Speaker 5:  tech guy, had a whole big long thread on Blue Sky, I think
Speaker 5:  yesterday talking about this stuff. And, and he just kept coming back to
Speaker 5:  this point that this is like fundamentally, it, it is people sitting in front
Speaker 5:  of computers and people can be e easily
Speaker 5:  told what to do because people have like jobs and needs and things
Speaker 5:  to do. And it's very easy when you're standing over somebody's shoulder to
Speaker 5:  convince them to do what you want. But also If you just come
Speaker 5:  in and are not afraid of breaking the technology, you can do pretty much
Speaker 5:  anything, right? We have the, all of these like very old brittle computing
Speaker 5:  systems that touch like hundreds of millions of people. And so
Speaker 5:  people like things don't change and, and everybody gets very mad about government
Speaker 5:  websites, but If you come in and you're just like, screw all of this, we're
Speaker 5:  just taking it over, we're gonna blow it up. It turns out you have pretty
Speaker 5:  quick like unilateral authority to do just about anything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Actually, Senator Wyden, it's not out yet. You're people
Speaker 4:  will be listening to this over the weekend. The decoder interview with Senator
Speaker 4:  Wyden will come out on Monday. We ran the, it's a coup clip
Speaker 4:  on TikTok. It felt important to get out to the senator
Speaker 4:  thinks it's a coup, you know, we just like ran it early. But inside of that
Speaker 4:  conversation, which again will come out on Monday, he says, no
Speaker 4:  one thought anyone would go attack the treasury system in this way. Right?
Speaker 4:  And I, that's, that's one of those things where it's like, yeah, because
Speaker 4:  it's so illegal. Like it's, it's so illegal
Speaker 4:  to send in the unelected 25 year olds
Speaker 4:  into the treasury system to fire the people who say they shouldn't have
Speaker 4:  access to it or put them on leave and then give them access to it.
Speaker 4:  Prompting a number of court cases. U
Speaker 4:  usually you don't do that usually. And this, by the way, is in even inside
Speaker 4:  of like the Doge framework, right? The, the
Speaker 4:  Vivek Ramas Swami versus Elon and Vivek gets pushed out
Speaker 4:  even inside of their own narrative. This is the tension
Speaker 4:  because Vivek is on record saying I wanted to do it
Speaker 4:  through legal means, and Elon wanted to do it through
Speaker 4:  technical means. And it's like, oh yeah, brute forcing
Speaker 4:  a computer takeover is vastly more efficient than doing it
Speaker 4:  through the legal process.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I, I mean I think this, this is where the specific
Speaker 5:  person that is Elon Musk becomes so interesting. And this was the, the thing
Speaker 5:  that Liz Lipato on our team wrote a really great piece about this week, which
Speaker 5:  is essentially Elon Musk has a pretty
Speaker 5:  broad swath of evidence now that suggests that the rules don't exist.
Speaker 5:  And in fact, he can do whatever he wants. And he is now
Speaker 5:  in this position where like the, the president has appointed him to this
Speaker 5:  role and there's no evidence to suggest that he is going to
Speaker 5:  be stopped from doing this. And also Elon Musk just has done whatever
Speaker 5:  he wants for a really long time and like it mostly works out for him. And
Speaker 5:  so you have this combination of this like specific opportunity and this specific
Speaker 5:  person who is like, I am more or less invincible
Speaker 5:  in every sort of meaningful way and this is what happens.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Two more things on this, then we should move on to terrorist, which
Speaker 4:  are much more sort of immediately impactful in people's lives.
Speaker 4:  The constitution of getting run run over is a big deal. I don't want to de,
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna minimize that in any way, but you can't buy mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboards. I think for virtue readers much more immediately impactful. That's
Speaker 4:  just life. Like I, yeah, that's the way it goes. But two more things on this
Speaker 4:  before we talk about tariffs.
Speaker 4:  One, there's a lot of just sort of general chatter about wired
Speaker 4:  naming the 20 somethings and teenagers who are working for Doge.
Speaker 4:  And a lot of it is, I think mistaken, the mistaken
Speaker 4:  sense that there's just pure criticism of of their age, right?
Speaker 4:  Young people shouldn't do stuff is like a lot of the Silicon Valley backlash
Speaker 4:  to why you're naming these people and their ages. That's not it. It's
Speaker 4:  when you're that young and then you're given the keys to the trillion dollar
Speaker 4:  treasury payment system, people are going to worry about whether you have
Speaker 4:  the expertise and knowledge to operate it correctly, especially when it's
Speaker 4:  running. It's written in cobol, like an ancient programming language,
Speaker 5:  But also like whoever you are, we should know your
Speaker 5:  name. Like I don't, I don't care how old you are or what where you come from
Speaker 5:  or what you do professionally. Like If you have the keys
Speaker 5:  to the federal budget, I should know your name.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that's the second part, right? Which is people are saying it's
Speaker 4:  doxing to know. No, they're now they're government employees. Yeah. And that
Speaker 4:  is life. And Elon loves naming government employees and directing
Speaker 4:  harassment at them has done it several times, has bullied
Speaker 4:  government employees out of their jobs with internet harassment, including
Speaker 4:  the former FAA administrator Wild, right? So
Speaker 4:  like there's a double standard here, which is the most Elon Musk thing of
Speaker 4:  all, where whatever he does is fine and, and just, and lawful and righteous.
Speaker 4:  And whenever anyone else does the same things, it's illegal. And he literally
Speaker 4:  is out there saying, this is a crime, Mr. Free sweet's absolutist is saying,
Speaker 4:  naming government employees as a crime is ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  I, if you've been listening to the show, you know, I'm on red alert about
Speaker 4:  the First Amendment. We're gonna come to that later in our Brendan Carr is
Speaker 4:  a dummy segment.
Speaker 4:  But just that's like, it's the most important
Speaker 4:  thing here is there's a pressure on just transparency and
Speaker 4:  accountability for these guys to make that seem unlawful
Speaker 4:  or illegal. And that is the most important thing. Like that's how the
Speaker 4:  government works. It, it's based layer, like the American
Speaker 4:  government is supposed to be transparent and accountable people. That's why
Speaker 4:  there is a website called USA spending.gov. And so when you
Speaker 4:  see people tweeting information that was already public and
Speaker 4:  pretending it was a secret, you should immediately
Speaker 4:  distrust that person. Like, that information has been available for a long
Speaker 4:  time and and saying, I'm revealing it now, or it leaked now. Or Elon made
Speaker 4:  it transparent now, especially when you see a screenshot of that website
Speaker 4:  in particular, that's how you know they're grifting you. And like X is
Speaker 4:  particularly platform for Grifters and it's okay to know the names of people
Speaker 4:  and be worried that 19 year olds who have signed up
Speaker 4:  to scrub the all menus of DEI from government websites might be
Speaker 4:  compromised in some way is pretty normal. Like
Speaker 4:  the young men who want to get rid of racism on
Speaker 4:  websites, they come from a, a stock of young men.
Speaker 4:  And historically movements are built around that kind of feeling. It's okay
Speaker 4:  to say young men doing that is problematic for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying. Okay, so that's Doge, we're gonna do more reporting on it.
Speaker 4:  We have a lot of ideas about how, how to report on that stuff.
Speaker 4:  Again, it's a computer takeover. It's in our zone, it's in Wired Zone, it's
Speaker 4:  in 4 0 4 zone. They've done a lot of good reporting on this as well. So we're
Speaker 4:  gonna stay focused on that. It's funny, this show comes out on
Speaker 4:  a Friday and I know by Monday something else will have happened, but oh yeah,
Speaker 4:  we'll stay focused on it. Then there's the other thing that happens
Speaker 4:  simultaneously. This pretty much rocked the tech world, although
Speaker 4:  not as publicly as Doge, and that's tariffs. And I think
Speaker 4:  there's the sense that Trump is doing a trade war for
Speaker 4:  fun while Elon does a coup. You know, like they just hand him stacks of paper
Speaker 4:  to sign and he's having a good time while Elon does a coup. But the
Speaker 4:  tariffs are real, even though the Mexico and Canada tariffs came and
Speaker 4:  they got delayed for 30 days. The tariffs on China really did hit,
Speaker 4:  and the di minis exception, the trade exception for packages under $800
Speaker 4:  really did hit. And it seems David, like the world of e-commerce is about
Speaker 4:  to change dramatically.
Speaker 5:  I agree. But we should, we should back up and explain what's actually happened
Speaker 5:  here. Because going back through and and putting all of this together, I
Speaker 5:  was struck by how many like twists and
Speaker 5:  reverse, like reverse Uno cards have been played over the last several days.
Speaker 5:  Richard, have you been tracking this closely? Can you Yes. Can you like
Speaker 5:  walk us through the timeline a little bit?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so Trump promised tariffs, of course throughout much of his
Speaker 6:  campaign. He started a trade war when he was president before,
Speaker 6:  unsurprisingly he wanted to do it again, wanted to do it very quickly, said
Speaker 6:  that he would, and we have been kind of waiting, we were waiting as,
Speaker 6:  as soon as his administration started, he then said that he
Speaker 6:  was going to establish these tariffs against Canada and Mexico and China
Speaker 6:  and blamed it on fentanyl for some
Speaker 6:  reason, that that's what he's got. And then Canada and
Speaker 6:  Mexico said, okay, by the way, we've announced some things already that we
Speaker 6:  were doing to stop the fentanyl trade. How about that? And he said, cool.
Speaker 6:  And did not tariff them. And, and maybe some small
Speaker 6:  things around the edges that are, that are new or, or may be negotiated.
Speaker 6:  So those are our pause for 30 days. However, he did not pause the changes
Speaker 6:  that were coming to the tariffs on China, which included a 10%
Speaker 6:  tariff, also included instituting previously
Speaker 6:  suspended tariffs. So it's, it's more than 10%. It kind of adds up and
Speaker 6:  stacks up. And in addition, as, as you noted this di minimis
Speaker 6:  rule that maybe none of us have ever thought about, but if you've ever ordered
Speaker 6:  things on Temu or or wherever where they shipped them
Speaker 6:  directly from China to the United States, there was kind of a loophole that
Speaker 6:  avoided these fees and now that's gone. So those prices are about to
Speaker 6:  change drastically in a lot of ways. Shipping
Speaker 6:  products from China to the US is changing a lot of ways
Speaker 6:  very rapidly. The USPS did not know what was going on on Wednesday,
Speaker 6:  stopped everything, then unstopped everything. And now we, we just
Speaker 6:  we're, we're kind of waiting to see how much the prices go up. It does
Speaker 5:  Seem like right now the confusion is the thing,
Speaker 5:  and I don't know if this was deliberate or not, but this all happened so
Speaker 5:  fast. Everybody was waiting for there to be tariffs, like you said, Richard.
Speaker 5:  And then the prevailing theory for a long time
Speaker 5:  among like economists and stuff was basically like Trump wouldn't possibly
Speaker 5:  do that. It's, it's ridiculous. Tariffs are self-defeating. Everybody
Speaker 5:  agrees. Tariffs actually help. No one, there is no point in
Speaker 5:  this. He won't do it. And then he did it
Speaker 5:  very quickly and in a different way than anybody expected. And
Speaker 5:  so all of a sudden everybody is just thrown into chaos. Like you're saying,
Speaker 5:  like the Nila you mentioned the story of this keyboard manufacturer, this
Speaker 5:  company called K Keys that basically just like
Speaker 5:  got the news called up DHL and was like, what are we doing? And
Speaker 5:  DHL was like, okay, you're gonna need, I think it was 50% of the
Speaker 5:  purchase price as a customs deposit. And then there's going to be
Speaker 5:  a huge new fee as this stuff gets imported into the US
Speaker 5:  And the, the company was essentially like, all right, we're just gonna stop
Speaker 5:  shipping while we figure this out. Like, nobody knows what to do with this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so, so so much of
Speaker 5:  what we do and the stuff that we buy and the stuff that we get is
Speaker 5:  going to be caught up in this confusion. And I think it, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's a going to get more expensive. That's gonna get messy. And like, again,
Speaker 5:  there are lots of economists who have gamed this out and pretty much everybody
Speaker 5:  who thinks about this stuff agrees that tariffs are pointless. And we can
Speaker 5:  get into why if we want to, but the very first thing that's going to happen
Speaker 5:  is a bunch of your stuff is gonna get more expensive. But I think at the
Speaker 5:  same time, stuff is just going to stop appearing because
Speaker 5:  there are just going to be a lot of companies and drop shippers and whoever
Speaker 5:  who just decide the smart thing to do in this moment is just nothing.
Speaker 5:  Because there is a sense that even what's happening now is impermanent and
Speaker 5:  will change. And the, the back and forth with Mexico and Canada has
Speaker 5:  already taught a lot of people that maybe if I just wait this out. So like
Speaker 5:  I think this idea of like, we're just gonna stop shipping for a minute until
Speaker 5:  we figure out what's going on might become more pervasive pretty quickly.
Speaker 5:  I don't think that's true of like Apple, which has like gigantic teams of
Speaker 5:  people who do this for a living, but like the, the Sheens and Timus of
Speaker 5:  the world that that all that stuff is gonna just start to
Speaker 5:  wither away both because it's just more expensive and it's just more
Speaker 5:  complicated. So
Speaker 6:  I I'm
Speaker 5:  I'm curious about that.
Speaker 4:  She and Timo are built on this regulatory exception. They've built entire
Speaker 4:  businesses in this country on the back of the de minimis exception,
Speaker 4:  which
Speaker 5:  Is $800, right? If it's eight, $800, it escapes the customs fees essentially.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You don't have to go through customs inspection, you don't have to pay extra
Speaker 4:  fees. What you just send the package over and here you go. I've bought, I
Speaker 5:  Didn't know about this and I'm struck by thinking $800 is kind of a lot of
Speaker 5:  money. That's a, that's a lot of stuff that would get
Speaker 4:  Under eight. It's just for a great hall video.
Speaker 4:  Like you live in a, in an economy, in an
Speaker 4:  information ecosystem that is built around $800 limits
Speaker 4:  on customs inspections. That's the size of a she and all
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 4:  Real. Like that's, it's so real. It's, it's, it, it's
Speaker 4:  everywhere. I've bought stuff on these sites
Speaker 4:  and they come direct from China and it's just wild, right? That you get a
Speaker 4:  package directly from China, you haven't paid any customs. And now we're
Speaker 4:  in a situation where I have seen people who are
Speaker 4:  like the drop shippers want my social security number so that
Speaker 4:  the custom service has accountability. 'cause they have required a social
Speaker 4:  security number for a shipper on this end. That's just, I mean, that's the
Speaker 4:  end of these if that's really the rule. And again, the uncertainty is the
Speaker 4:  point. If that's really the outcome, like these companies definitely go away.
Speaker 4:  I don't know that it will definitely be the outcome. There are, they obviously
Speaker 4:  have built large companies around a weird regulatory loophole
Speaker 4:  that could have been closed at any time. And certainly the Biden administration,
Speaker 4:  even the the first Trump administration people talked about closing this
Speaker 4:  loophole there. They might find a way around it, but all of those ways
Speaker 4:  will increase cost. Where it's really gonna hit is a bunch of small companies,
Speaker 4:  right, who don't have big compliance offices like Apple, who
Speaker 4:  don't know what to do and are just gonna say, we're just pausing shipments
Speaker 4:  until something gets resolved. Right? I have this thing called the to shine
Speaker 4:  in my house. I love it. It's one of my favorite little gadgets. It's just
Speaker 4:  a super low res, like LLED
Speaker 4:  display that you connect to whatever streaming service and it displays album
Speaker 4:  art.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I've seen this thing. Cool.
Speaker 4:  It's like ultra pixelated.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's like a light bright for album art. It's pretty cool. It's a light
Speaker 4:  Bright for album. Yeah, it's su it's super fun. I have been meaning to write
Speaker 4:  about forever. I actually asked to buy a s butler that it's one guy
Speaker 4:  who quit his tech job to build these things in his spare time. I love
Speaker 4:  this. I should have written about it ages ago, but I asked him a while ago,
Speaker 4:  how will tariffs hit you? And he basically said, I would love
Speaker 4:  to switch to more US made parts, but the quotes I've gotten in the past are
Speaker 4:  300 to 400% higher Wow. Than what I pay now
Speaker 4:  from Chinese to get Chinese parts. And a few of the parts don't get made
Speaker 4:  anywhere but China. So like this little company, just a guy who quit his
Speaker 4:  job to like build, build album art light brights, he is like, my parts are
Speaker 4:  gonna go up 300, 400%. And then he says, I could also
Speaker 4:  increase production by 20 to a hundred times of
Speaker 4:  what he makes. Now he makes 'em all by hand, so that's hard. But in order
Speaker 4:  to do that, I would've to pay $200,000 upfront. So
Speaker 4:  he just has to write a $200,000 check in order to front the increase
Speaker 4:  in production that would cover his
Speaker 5:  Tariffs. What you just described is the difference between being in business
Speaker 5:  and being out of business. Right.
Speaker 4:  And then he
Speaker 5:  Like, it's, it's that simple.
Speaker 4:  I'll, and I'll, I'll run, I'll, I will actually put this in a story I've
Speaker 4:  been meaning to follow with Tobias now that there's this actual tariff. I
Speaker 4:  emailed him before and so I, I promise I'll publish this story.
Speaker 4:  I'm assigning myself this own my own story because I do love my tunes shine.
Speaker 4:  But he's, he handed his note to me by saying I'm hopeful that a big company
Speaker 4:  like Apple will have enough sway in the administration to point out how much
Speaker 4:  more expensive so many products will get overnight and prevent tariffs from
Speaker 4:  going into place. Here we are. Like they're in place.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like this ecosystem is already under pressure. The little
Speaker 4:  companies are already feeling it or will already feel it. And the big companies
Speaker 4:  like Apple are staring down a barrel of, oh, are we gonna have to just
Speaker 4:  increase iPhone prices by 10%? Because Apple
Speaker 4:  is very capable of just subtly increasing prices in September to cover the
Speaker 4:  bill, right? Yeah. And they might just do it or they might increase iCloud
Speaker 4:  prices. Hey, you know, like it's you, you're at five gigs of iCloud storage,
Speaker 4:  like now it's $8 instead of seven. Like they can make these moves
Speaker 4:  to eat it or they can do what we have always seen Tim Cook do.
Speaker 4:  They can buy themselves a tariff waiver, which he has done several times
Speaker 4:  in the past. The problem is this time Trump is threatening
Speaker 4:  tariffs on chips from Taiwan. He's threatening tariffs on the
Speaker 4:  eu, which apple's in a fight with the, the political dimension of this is,
Speaker 4:  is actually much more complicated for Tim Cook to navigate. And I have no
Speaker 4:  idea what he's gonna do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I I'm sort of at the point where I don't know how to handicap that
Speaker 5:  either. But I also think if you're Apple, you can afford to do
Speaker 5:  all those things you just described, right? Like the idea of iCloud
Speaker 5:  prices going up a dollar and, and, and that pays for all of this is
Speaker 5:  like real, like that's, that's a, those are moves Apple has, those are
Speaker 5:  not moves most companies have. Like this all just rhymes to me of
Speaker 5:  like the zero interest rate phenomenon stuff we've been talking about that
Speaker 5:  there was all this stuff that was possible when everything was
Speaker 5:  cheap and everybody had more access to more money all the time. And then
Speaker 5:  as soon as that went away, all these companies who were operating at a loss
Speaker 5:  based on being able to get more investment or were making these like teeny
Speaker 5:  tiny margins die, like those companies are gone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because money stopped being free and, and it's like people
Speaker 5:  underestimate how big a change everything is now
Speaker 5:  10% more expensive to customers is because
Speaker 5:  it's not as simple as you ship a finished product to a person and it charges
Speaker 5:  them 10% more. And that even if it were that, that's problematic.
Speaker 5:  But the way a trade works, it everything moves in so many directions all
Speaker 5:  the time that this stuff is just going to cost
Speaker 5:  more than you think. Every one of these is going to be more expensive than
Speaker 5:  you think. And Richard, like you're talking about this stuff is starting
Speaker 5:  to stack. And so we're getting to the point where so many of these
Speaker 5:  tariffs for big companies are gonna be like a big
Speaker 5:  quarterly earnings headache. And like, if I'm being completely honest, I
Speaker 5:  don't worry existentially for like Apple and Google's ability, ability to
Speaker 5:  weather tariffs, like they'll be fine. It'll be more expensive for us and
Speaker 5:  that will suck. But there's, there's a whole huge
Speaker 5:  slew, like if you're a hardware startup right now, your host
Speaker 5:  like this, this is an existential crisis for anyone in that position right
Speaker 5:  now. And that sucks.
Speaker 6:  And that's the thing, like these companies that make these devices that aren't
Speaker 6:  in huge numbers that aren't in Apple production, that rely on maybe
Speaker 6:  contract production or, you know, they're go, they're going on some website
Speaker 6:  just to find components the same as you and I can, they just
Speaker 6:  suddenly don't exist. Like you get to a point where as, as you said, they
Speaker 6:  just stop existing and you, you can't, you can't get around
Speaker 6:  that. And that, and what that means is that even if the tariffs were repealed
Speaker 6:  the day after, those companies don't just come back into existence. Like
Speaker 6:  it does, it does not work that way. Right.
Speaker 5:  And of course all these other countries have moves to like,
Speaker 5:  you know, Canada immediately launched retaliatory tariffs. Mexico said it
Speaker 5:  was gonna do stuff. China is now like antitrust investigating Google,
Speaker 5:  which is hysterical.
Speaker 4:  That's actually the funniest one of these all like Google doesn't operate
Speaker 4:  there weird. You know,
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah. Like Google has a monopoly in China despite not
Speaker 5:  existing is like, oh, so
Speaker 4:  Google does have offices there, they have some like AI researchers
Speaker 4:  there, but they don't have any products there. What they have is Android,
Speaker 4:  which is forked by Chinese phone makers into whatever custom version of
Speaker 4:  Android they all wanna run. I don't know that's a monopoly. It is just very
Speaker 4:  funny that they were like, ah, Google, there was a report today that they
Speaker 4:  might start investigating Apple's app store fees. And that's the big
Speaker 4:  retaliation. And that is also the danger for the eu, right? The
Speaker 4:  EU famously loves to regulate Apple. They're like, make the icons blue and
Speaker 4:  apple's like, I hate you. And that's a very challenging relationship. And
Speaker 4:  we've heard from Apple in various ways that one of the reasons that,
Speaker 4:  you know, Tim Cook called Trump before the inauguration, all this stuff was
Speaker 4:  to warm up that relationship so that he might fight EU
Speaker 4:  regulation. Mark Zuckerberg has openly said, yep, he would like Trump to
Speaker 4:  advocate for American companies in the face of EU regulation. Trump has said
Speaker 4:  he'll put tariffs in the EU if the EU responds to those tariffs by
Speaker 4:  saying, no, we're gonna do more investigations, actually we're gonna turn
Speaker 4:  up the heat on American companies. Like I don't know that this actually
Speaker 4:  solves the problem. I don't know that this begets in negotiation. I think
Speaker 4:  it just gets more and more tense until something breaks in a way
Speaker 4:  that maybe never goes back together.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean it, it, it certainly seems like we are more likely to
Speaker 5:  be headed in that direction than everyone just caves and gives
Speaker 5:  the Trump administration something fair. It's not super clear
Speaker 4:  To me
Speaker 5:  Victory looks like even
Speaker 4:  Mean to on tariffs. The Trump administration has caved like immediately caved
Speaker 4:  Well, yeah, right to Mexico, China. But in, you know, it's a 30 day pause
Speaker 4:  the same way the TikTok ban was a 75 day pause. And at the scale
Speaker 4:  of these companies and the scale of global trade and the scale of tech industry,
Speaker 4:  you cannot run these things in these weird liminal states
Speaker 4:  between yes and no. You should not operate a business the size of TikTok
Speaker 4:  in a 70 day pause of being illegal. Like
Speaker 4:  that's not the way to go. You're not like, well it's illegal to sell drugs,
Speaker 4:  but for 75 more days, we're doing the purge. Like that doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 4:  Like these companies have people there who like, have families and
Speaker 4:  mortgages and jobs and careers and you, you can't be like, well
Speaker 4:  for 30 more days you're off the hook. The American automotive
Speaker 4:  supply chain is off the hook for 30 more days and then something might happen.
Speaker 4:  And the most likely thing that happens is it gets, it gets extended for another
Speaker 4:  30 days. That's just, that's no way to do it. Like the economy
Speaker 4:  actually won't accept that amount of instability. So, we'll, we'll see,
Speaker 4:  because that's very much the Trump way of doing things, but something is
Speaker 4:  gonna have to give, and I, I suspect the reason big business is so in
Speaker 4:  bed with Trump is because they, they need to get to those table outcomes
Speaker 4:  and like, no matter what they say or how disingenuous they sound in public,
Speaker 4:  they're not stupid about the money. Right. You, you can count on, you can
Speaker 4:  count on the money being self-serving in that, in that specific way and they
Speaker 4:  will demand some kind of stability.
Speaker 5:  Richard, what's your, what's your guess of what happens next here? It does
Speaker 5:  feel like we're due for another turn here fairly
Speaker 5:  quickly with
Speaker 6:  The tariffs. I don't know because it's so complicated and I think that's
Speaker 6:  the thing that you struggle on and how this affects Apple in particular,
Speaker 6:  for example, because they have their production in China. They have, and
Speaker 6:  they have started to move some production into other places. But like so
Speaker 6:  many companies, they produce so many things in China, they're such a big
Speaker 6:  American company. All of the biggest American companies that we're talking
Speaker 6:  about, Nvidia, what's going to happen to their chips.
Speaker 6:  These are all, and these are also inevitably the same executives that have
Speaker 6:  tried to curry favor with Trump who wins and who
Speaker 6:  is actually in control in, in the White House. What, what does, what does
Speaker 6:  China decide to do? China said that they're gonna sue at the w wt o which
Speaker 6:  may or may not mean anything.
Speaker 6:  I think, I think things are going to get worse before they get better.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I I just wanna say one thing before we go, which is that like
Speaker 5:  a, a thing I say to you Neli all the time because I want you to like be more
Speaker 5:  outrageous in public is that you can just say things, but
Speaker 5:  this has become like a mantra for me over the last few weeks is that you
Speaker 5:  can just say things and like people, people just say things and
Speaker 5:  I think we are like trained to believe that people mostly
Speaker 5:  say things that are like true and considered and thoughtful and that they
Speaker 5:  believe. But you can just say things and so much of
Speaker 5:  pe what people say is just them saying things like, president Trump
Speaker 5:  was like, I have a different air traffic control
Speaker 5:  when I fly than everybody else
Speaker 4:  Made by a foreign government made by, right? And everyone was like, Israel.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, whatcha talking about
Speaker 5:  What
Speaker 4:  Richard?
Speaker 5:  Do you know the answer to this? Can you explain this to me? Is this a real
Speaker 5:  thing?
Speaker 6:  I know the answer, but I can't tell you. It's, there
Speaker 4:  You go. That's
Speaker 5:  Right. You can just say things and like, I think a, a thing
Speaker 5:  we've talked about a lot with Elon Musk over the years, and I think we talked
Speaker 5:  about a lot during the first Trump administration was how to sort out the
Speaker 5:  difference between somebody just saying things
Speaker 5:  and actual reality. Like I saw this great TikTok
Speaker 5:  this morning where it was like this guy sitting in like, you know, podcast
Speaker 5:  pose. He is got the microphone, he's talking into it and he's like, studies
Speaker 5:  say that If you get three to four hours of sleep
Speaker 5:  that actually your life expectancy goes up. And he's like, Harvard studies,
Speaker 5:  Yale studies these whole thing and he goes through the whole thing and then
Speaker 5:  it, the camera pulls back and he goes, put some inspirational music behind
Speaker 5:  that. Everybody will believe it. Yeah. And it's like, shit. Everybody does
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 4:  Believe it. That man was Andrew Huberman.
Speaker 5:  This is, you can just say things and I think like
Speaker 4:  It's, it's how much a one did you buy after you saw that?
Speaker 5:  That's what say. I haven't slept for four hours in, in months since I saw
Speaker 5:  that. But like I, again, I, I think it's so
Speaker 5:  important for us as like journalists, but also just as like people in the
Speaker 5:  world right now to spend a lot of time going, people can just say
Speaker 5:  things and most of the time that's all it is. And if all that's all it is,
Speaker 5:  it doesn't matter at all. High stakes, low stakes,
Speaker 4:  Would I? But I would say that the, with Elon, Elon loves to just say things.
Speaker 4:  Remember when he was gonna build a a, a hyperloop in Chicago to the airport?
Speaker 4:  Sure. Remember when the cars were gonna drive themselves? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  He just, he loves saying stuff, loves it. And you can't,
Speaker 5:  You can just say things and
Speaker 4:  Usually the stakes are pretty medium. Like I think the people of Chicago
Speaker 4:  knew there would never be a hyperloop to the airport. Like I I I spent
Speaker 4:  a lot of time in that city. No one was like, they're gonna build a hyperloop
Speaker 4:  to the airport. People were more like, we'll shoot you If you come here.
Speaker 4:  Like, it was very different. The, the reaction was very different.
Speaker 4:  The stakes from the president says, I will build a hotel in Gaza
Speaker 4:  and turn that into the Riviera of the Middle East. The the stakes of that
Speaker 4:  are World War iii.
Speaker 5:  But that's the thing is I'm not sure they are because he, it's not real.
Speaker 5:  He's just saying things. You can just
Speaker 4:  Say things. They, these are the most powerful men in the world right now.
Speaker 4:  Elon is the richest man in the world. He might be in control of the government.
Speaker 4:  President Trump nominally is the most powerful person in the world. He can
Speaker 4:  launch a nuclear strike if he wants to. There's a lot going on here where
Speaker 4:  I I hear you and certainly less than the first Trump administration is you
Speaker 4:  can just say things. You can just say, I'm gonna put 25% tariffs on Canada,
Speaker 4:  Mexico, and then back off two hours before they go into effect. Because
Speaker 4:  both of those governments promise to do things they're already gonna do and
Speaker 4:  everyone can adapt to that. There's just a, there's a new
Speaker 4:  level of crazy that comes with x as it is right
Speaker 4:  now with Elon realizing that he can just say stuff about the government.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's what I'm worried about. Like, and then
Speaker 4:  Trump is Trump like I, he, he is just the
Speaker 4:  most I anyone can say anything. He, he said Google was gonna make a website
Speaker 4:  to track the coronavirus. We tracked it every single day for a year and
Speaker 4:  that never happened.
Speaker 5:  Wonder how many days? It's been thousands of days at this point.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, we we can wrap this one up. I I I hear you. And you can just say
Speaker 4:  things and I believe I should start saying more or just things. Do you know
Speaker 4:  The Verge is making a phone?
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be great. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  Love The Verge could make a website to track Coronavirus. I'm just
Speaker 4:  Saying we thought about it
Speaker 4:  somehow you could get the, the bleach under the skin to just kill it. It
Speaker 4:  would be great. Our very powerful light. Do you remember
Speaker 4:  this? This happened. We've lived through this. Some of you our greatest
Speaker 6:  Institutions are being doubted. Man, nobody believed shams when he said that
Speaker 6:  Luca was being traded. Yeah. People doubted
Speaker 4:  Shams can just say, actually let's end it here. Richard, I I want your take
Speaker 4:  on this. Do you think Luca on the Mavs was a zero interest rate phenomenon?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Obviously
Speaker 4:  That's why they
Speaker 6:  Had trade
Speaker 4:  Him. That is a deep cut for a small cross section of our listeners, but
Speaker 4:  I know you appreciated it. We gotta take a break. It is true by the way.
Speaker 4:  People can just say things and we will do our very best to call out when
Speaker 4:  people just say things here. But boy, get used to it. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  loves it and the prices go down all the time. It's fabulous.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's start. Let, let's start with Tubi. Can we start with Tubi?
Speaker 5:  Wow. That is the first time. What a, what a day for Tuby. That just was,
Speaker 5:  nobody's ever said that about Tub. I'm
Speaker 4:  Excited for them.
Speaker 6:  They've got the Super Bowl, man.
Speaker 4:  They're coming. They got the Super Bowl, the Super Bowls on Sunday,
Speaker 4:  you know, that's exciting. Given that we, we've already seen
Speaker 5:  You guys watching Z Suite yet,
Speaker 4:  What's the Z Suite?
Speaker 5:  So Z Suite is I think probably
Speaker 5:  toy's, like biggest original programming ever.
Speaker 5:  And the shtick as I understand it, is it's a, I think it's like a marketing
Speaker 5:  agency in New York and it all the, all the older like Gen
Speaker 5:  Xers are forced out and the Zoomers come in to run it. And
Speaker 5:  so it's called the Z Suite and
Speaker 5:  it has, what's her name? Lauren Graham Lorelei from Gilmore Girls.
Speaker 5:  I'm excited. Sure.
Speaker 4:  I would say that Cranky Gen Xers get forced out and the Zoomers come in to
Speaker 4:  run. It is both my nightmare and my dream at this point in time. Like please
Speaker 4:  depose me. I'm ready to go. Just anytime you want.
Speaker 4:  Also bad day for Tuby when I'm like, let's talk about Tuby and I didn't know
Speaker 4:  the name of their biggest show.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean listen, Richard is an aficionado, so it's fine. Richard and
Speaker 5:  I after this are gonna record our, our Z Suite recap podcast.
Speaker 4:  Finally.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm, I'm still on the golden arm man, real head to know.
Speaker 4:  I feel so bad that I know what the golden arm is. Dear Sweet Quibi. Okay,
Speaker 4:  so two B is having its big moment. A lot of you have asked us,
Speaker 4:  I think because they assume that we pay attention to badly named streaming
Speaker 4:  services in this way. Why Tuby has a Super Bowl. And the fascinating
Speaker 4:  answer to this question is that Fox owns Tuby and they don't
Speaker 4:  make a show of this, but we've had Tuby, CEO Angelie sued on
Speaker 4:  decoder. She's talked about the relationship. Tuby is just there to be
Speaker 4:  like always on like it, it's just an on-demand free
Speaker 4:  streaming service. It is doing pretty well. It's growing it bundle
Speaker 4:  with a lot of TVs and streaming devices, putting the Super Bowl there for
Speaker 4:  Fox as a growth strategy. If you recall the last time Fox had the Super Bowl,
Speaker 4:  Tubi had an ad because Fox owns
Speaker 5:  Tuby. That was the one, the ad that it like popped up the interface over
Speaker 5:  the tv, right? Yep. That was a good ad. It tricked a lot of people into being
Speaker 5:  like, what's going on with my tv?
Speaker 6:  And that was when people found out what Tubi is.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. It's the malware on my television.
Speaker 4:  So this is their second big growth they're gonna give away for free. It's
Speaker 4:  also really interesting it, because traditionally this should be a horrible
Speaker 4:  way to advertise your service because you would be competing with the
Speaker 4:  free television that most people already have, which is their antenna Fox
Speaker 4:  is just distributed to most people over there for free. But you can't count
Speaker 4:  on that anymore. So watch two be on your phone is actually a
Speaker 4:  meaningful free television proposition now in a way
Speaker 4:  that, you know, even 10 years ago wouldn't be. So that's a big deal for
Speaker 4:  Tubi, which is just a weird thing to say. We'll see if
Speaker 4:  it drives signups and downloads and all that stuff. But it comes right next
Speaker 4:  to Fox announcing it's gonna launch another streaming service by the
Speaker 4:  end of this year.
Speaker 4:  What is going on here? Like if you're about to put all this money into, why
Speaker 4:  is Fox doing this other thing? You
Speaker 5:  Sense of this for me? I have nothing. I truly, I have, I cannot answer
Speaker 5:  that question. I have a lot of thoughts about the Fox streaming service,
Speaker 5:  but the why on earth would you do this? And especially why would you do it
Speaker 5:  now? I got nothing.
Speaker 6:  What's like, I think that it's like Google and messaging services,
Speaker 6:  you always need one more
Speaker 5:  And it's run by two teams that have no knowledge of each other and have never
Speaker 5:  ever spoken.
Speaker 6:  There is an executive who believes his way is the way and and says and is
Speaker 6:  looking at Tubi and saying, yeah that's great, but what about, what if it
Speaker 6:  were just sports?
Speaker 4:  No, this is paid for it. I will, I will, I'll, I'll read to you.
Speaker 4:  Lachlan Murdoch, the CEO Fox said the subscriber expectations
Speaker 4:  will be quote modest,
Speaker 4:  which is great tough and it'll price the service accordingly.
Speaker 4:  But we do wanna reach consumers wherever they are. And there's a large population
Speaker 4:  now they're outside of the traditional cable bundle, whether cable, whether
Speaker 4:  cord cutters or cord nevers. And the plan is to offer them a
Speaker 4:  holistic streaming package featuring sports and news from the
Speaker 4:  existing brands. So this is gonna be a weird combo platter of Fox
Speaker 4:  News and FS one, the marriage made in heaven,
Speaker 5:  Which is basically all Fox has at this point. Like I actually went through
Speaker 5:  it and I was like, okay, what pro, what properties does Fox have that might
Speaker 5:  sell this? And Fox News is certainly one of them. Fox News is the dominant
Speaker 5:  cable news platform.
Speaker 5:  There's Fox Sports, which has some things. Fox Sports is like the
Speaker 5:  one that like it's four times a year. I have to redownload the app to watch
Speaker 5:  something that's my Fox sports experience. And then it's pretty
Speaker 5:  bleak after that. Dude like Fox sold most of its
Speaker 5:  entertainment assets to Disney many years ago. Famously, yes,
Speaker 5:  2017 I think that was in
Speaker 5:  but arguably terrible deal for Disney, which I think massively overpaid for
Speaker 5:  all of that stuff, but got all of that stuff. So like all of the
Speaker 5:  streaming content that you think of as like Fox and fx, most
Speaker 5:  of that is now Disney's. And so what Fox has left is essentially
Speaker 5:  those two things you just named and what runs on the Fox channel on
Speaker 5:  your television. And can I read you guys some of the most successful shows
Speaker 5:  on the Fox Network on television? Oh boy. And what I would like to do is,
Speaker 5:  Richard, I'm gonna make you do this. I'm gonna read you the name of a show
Speaker 5:  and you're going to explain to me what it's about. And I'm not going to tell
Speaker 5:  you if you're right or wrong. We're just gonna move on. How's that sound
Speaker 5:  into
Speaker 4:  It? Love
Speaker 5:  It. Okay. The number one show on Fox in fall of 2024, the ot,
Speaker 4:  That's football over time. No, that's what, that's a group of Zoomers
Speaker 4:  take over an ad agency.
Speaker 5:  Okay. 9 1 1 Lone Star.
Speaker 5:  I'm not making any of these up,
Speaker 4:  It's so important to me why that you know this Why Lone Star
Speaker 4:  is there? It's a group of Cowboy Zoomers.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I watch that.
Speaker 5:  It's all have iPhone. iPhones good.
Speaker 4:  Like that's a hit show. So yeah, I, I believe that.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Then we have the Mass Singer, which I think every everyone knows
Speaker 4:  I've the 9 1 1 Lone Star Outranking. The Mass Singer is also
Speaker 5:  Weak. Tough beat. Yeah, it's tough. Beat Rescue High Surf
Speaker 4:  Is that It's Zoomers, but they're Baywatch.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I'm sorry. I think it's Rescue Hawaii Dash Surf.
Speaker 4:  Ah, well see, there you go. Did you just read the word Hawaii wrong? It,
Speaker 4:  it's,
Speaker 5:  It's, it's in all caps. It's hard to tell what's wrong. Sure. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then can I interest you in the floor at number five?
Speaker 5:  This is my point. This is if you're Fox,
Speaker 4:  Just,
Speaker 5:  Just call the thing Fox News. It's the only thing anyone is
Speaker 4:  Gonna come for. They have a Fox News app and they have Fox Nation
Speaker 4:  the streaming service. This is what I mean. Okay. Take it back. If you're
Speaker 4:  about to do the Super Bowl in Tubby, which in the NFL does not let you do
Speaker 4:  that for free. Right, right. It's not just like a little side show like,
Speaker 4:  oh, we're, well, to be fair, think
Speaker 5:  Have to do that. If you're Fox like 'cause to
Speaker 4:  Point, let's build up the, the one we have with the Super
Speaker 4:  Bowl that we're gonna give to a bunch of cop and Cowboy
Speaker 4:  Zoomers for free on their phones. That's just my belief.
Speaker 4:  Now
Speaker 4:  why on earth are you launching this other one? So you can stream the mass
Speaker 4:  singer to six to a modest number of subscribers.
Speaker 4:  I'm, this thing is al this thing is at 80 on the go, 90 scale. This is
Speaker 4:  Thursday night dinner. It's, it's, it's just what you have. It's just you
Speaker 4:  gotta do it.
Speaker 5:  It's just, it's yeah. You open the fridge, throw some stuff in.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this is like succession style. Like Lachlan Murdoch has his own children
Speaker 4:  who wanna run something and he is like, do a streaming service. And it's
Speaker 4:  like, fine, you can just like putter along. Okay. Go 90 scale of
Speaker 4:  Doom streaming services, the, the classic Vergecast scale
Speaker 4:  of how likely a streaming service is to survive. Zero is alive, 90 is
Speaker 4:  dead. Named after Go 90 Verizon's streaming service in which
Speaker 4:  they wanted young people to join a gang to compete with YouTube.
Speaker 4:  I'm not kidding. That was all real. That's
Speaker 5:  Literally what it was. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There was a button that was like, join a crew. It was very silly.
Speaker 4:  I'm putting whatever this Fox Sports thing is an 80. And then just
Speaker 4:  because it exists, I think Tubi clicks up to like a 70.
Speaker 5:  I I would leave Tubi lower. I think I'm putting Tubi at like a 35 just because
Speaker 5:  Tubi is a working, and BA totally different
Speaker 5:  business.
Speaker 4:  Right. But once, once you start messing with all these other ones, the idea
Speaker 4:  that you're gonna roll Tubi into this other thing and read brand like the
Speaker 4:  Door's open now. Oh,
Speaker 5:  That's fair. Okay. The, the ongoing existence of Tubi
Speaker 5:  might be in, in threat because it'll
Speaker 5:  all just get rolled into Fox Plus or whatever.
Speaker 4:  Right. Do we want Fox Nation and the Fox Sports app and Tubi and this
Speaker 4:  new one?
Speaker 5:  I mean, given Fox's history hell yeah. More apps, more fun.
Speaker 4:  I, I'm just saying like, this is the thing that, like you, they've kept by
Speaker 4:  the way, the Fox Sports app and the Fox Nation app apart for a long time
Speaker 4:  just because of the, the political reality that a lot of people will not
Speaker 4:  download a, a Fox sports app to watch.
Speaker 5:  Well, but also those are things that you log into with your cable subscription.
Speaker 5:  Right. And I think there's a really interesting world of
Speaker 5:  like the TV everywhere promise that never came to fruition.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 4:  Man, Richard and I lived through the TV everywhere Wars, man,
Speaker 5:  My, my hottest take is that TV everywhere was actually the correct idea
Speaker 5:  and that everyone who blew it should be fired because TV
Speaker 5:  everywhere was a good and right. And we're just gonna do
Speaker 5:  it again, but the interface
Speaker 4:  Gonna be worse. But somewhere some like ancient grizzled TV executive popped
Speaker 4:  up out of a coffin like Dracula and was like, I knew it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Somebody like the History Channel is like, that's what I've been saying.
Speaker 4:  No way, dude.
Speaker 5:  But I'm, I'm putting the idea of like a standalone
Speaker 5:  Fox streaming service if it's more than just the cable channel
Speaker 5:  over the internet, which, or the broadcast channel over the internet, which
Speaker 5:  it might be like the, was it the Weather Channel? I think that just put out
Speaker 5:  a thing that they were like for $5 a month here is just, it's just the Weather
Speaker 5:  Channel. You can have that, that I think is fine.
Speaker 5:  That can live forever and no one will subscribe to it, but it's not a lot
Speaker 5:  of like, marginal, extra work. So it'll be fine. But if Fox is like, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna do Netflix with Fox Properties on a strong,
Speaker 5:  like 82 from day one. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Richard, where are you at?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that comes out in 81 for me. I'm still putting Tubi down
Speaker 6:  at like 20 I I believe in Tubi. Alright. I, I just, I I think, I
Speaker 6:  think they've got it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, you love shows about Zoomers taking over ad agencies. There's
Speaker 4:  one thing I know about you, Richard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The, the Z suite. It's gonna make it, I I'm going to be fascinated
Speaker 5:  to see what happens to Tubi right after the Super Bowl because I think
Speaker 5:  the thing that's gonna happen is that a lot of people are going to discover
Speaker 5:  A, that Tub B exists, and B, that there is a
Speaker 5:  streaming service that you don't have to log into or pay for that just has
Speaker 5:  things on all the time. All
Speaker 6:  That stuff you used to watch on Netflix, it's there.
Speaker 5:  Right. And, and there, there is something different
Speaker 5:  about the appeal of these free fast services that
Speaker 5:  I think we don't talk about enough that is like, it, it's actually
Speaker 5:  in a lot of ways, like the antidote to I'm paying for too many streaming
Speaker 5:  services is just go to Tubi and pick something. And I think there, there's
Speaker 5:  like a real thing there that I think a lot of people are about to be turned
Speaker 5:  onto.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And you can go listen to that decoder with Angel. 'cause she makes
Speaker 4:  that case very loudly. Yeah. Like this is, this is, there's growth here and
Speaker 4:  we can see it. And, and the numbers are real. I think she's, right now she's
Speaker 4:  got the Super Bowls, see how it goes. By the way, this is all next to Disney
Speaker 4:  Head earnings this week. Disney plus their streaming division posted
Speaker 4:  a profit, which is a big deal for Disney. They have not done that for a long
Speaker 4:  time. But then they're also like ESPN has become a very expensive
Speaker 4:  subscription sports product. And it's like, Ooh. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Richard, you and I were both reading this trying to decide whether
Speaker 5:  to be, I think, surprised by the way that Disney
Speaker 5:  is betting on ESPN or if this was just like, obviously the way it was gonna
Speaker 5:  go. And of course Disney just took a weird path to get here. But basically
Speaker 5:  venue is gone. Disney sold off.
Speaker 4:  I, like you said, venue is gone. Like anyone knows what venue was.
Speaker 5:  We did a whole, you know, listen, If you don't know what venue was, it doesn't
Speaker 5:  matter 'cause it's gone Now. Venue, which was gonna be the like big sports
Speaker 5:  bundle never came alive in the first place. Disney sold
Speaker 5:  off the Hulu with live TV thing to fuo, which is now still mostly
Speaker 5:  owned by Disney. But like that's a separate thing that runs on itself now.
Speaker 5:  And Disney is basically just like we are all in on ESPN as
Speaker 5:  the primary brand. They're launching this flagship thing later this year.
Speaker 5:  They're integrating fantasy and betting and it's like, that's the big bet.
Speaker 5:  And it's very weird to me that it took Disney this long to
Speaker 5:  realize, oh, ESPN is an enormous brand and we should probably just
Speaker 5:  bet everything on it and not this weird distribution thing we're trying to
Speaker 5:  do. I
Speaker 6:  Wonder where they got that idea to have like a bundle of content that's centered
Speaker 6:  around ESPN and sports that people will pay for on a monthly basis
Speaker 6:  to watch. Huh. I just,
Speaker 5:  It's a pretty good idea.
Speaker 6:  So it's a cool concept if they can make it work.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Here's the weird thing though, right? The, the majority of ESPN's
Speaker 4:  daytime programming now is the Pat MV show, which is
Speaker 4:  also just streaming away on YouTube. You don't have
Speaker 4:  to pay for ESPN to get that show, which is again, the bulk
Speaker 4:  of the afternoon on ESPN. I
Speaker 5:  Think of that as like if ESPN could go back to the days where like cable
Speaker 5:  channels just turned off for periods of time, I think EPN would happen to
Speaker 5:  do it. Like, and it's just, it, it is the most filler
Speaker 5:  content of all time and it's fine. And ESPN just
Speaker 5:  rolls at the, like, it's ESPN's whole thing is is games, right? Like
Speaker 5:  that's, they, they need places to show you stuff. And for EPN to be like,
Speaker 5:  oh, we're gonna make everything available to everywhere all the time always
Speaker 5:  seemed weird. But instead it's like, do you want the Disney bundle? Come
Speaker 5:  here and watch sports. It's like, that's, that's cable. And it
Speaker 5:  worked super well for Disney for literally decades. It's
Speaker 4:  Fascinating that you think that ESPN is games when I think of it as yelling
Speaker 4:  guys.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's, it's also yelling guys.
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's so much yelling guys. Yeah, right. It's, it's Stephen A. Smith.
Speaker 4:  Like it's, but for a long time you can only get Stephen A. Smith on ES espn
Speaker 4:  and I think McAfee show is just a weird one for them because it's,
Speaker 4:  it's yelling guys, but they're also available for free on YouTube. And I
Speaker 4:  think a bunch of streaming companies are starting to realize that they just
Speaker 4:  need to make nice with YouTube. Like Warner put a bunch of full movies
Speaker 4:  on YouTube for free this week. Fascinating. And I, I, I couldn't tell you
Speaker 4:  why, but I think they're like, it's better to get pennies from our catalog
Speaker 4:  on YouTube than $0 and lose to YouTube.
Speaker 6:  I think that's exactly it. I think that for e, espn, the Pat McAfee show
Speaker 6:  on, on YouTube is better than you listening to, you know, a podcast
Speaker 6:  or Sports Star Radio that isn't owned by e espn.
Speaker 4:  Well I think they would be very, very, everyone would be very careful to
Speaker 4:  say that they don't own the Pat McAfee show and in fact can barely control
Speaker 4:  it and can barely influence anything about it at
Speaker 4:  any time. It's just a weird moment. I it's a weird moment for sports.
Speaker 4:  You know, the Super Bowl sort of always brings everything to a head. There's
Speaker 4:  always rights negotiations going on, but it does seem like you're
Speaker 4:  gonna end up with a bunch of to be like things or a bunch of
Speaker 4:  free fast services and then a bunch of very expensive sports
Speaker 4:  subscriptions. Yep. Like that feels like the, the breakdown of the,
Speaker 4:  the streaming industry right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It really does feel like that's where we're headed. And we've come
Speaker 5:  out of an era where there was a running theory that maybe if we had enough
Speaker 5:  really great high-end premium content that people would
Speaker 5:  pay a lot for. It turns out that's a bad business. So we're just
Speaker 5:  back to sports. We're just doing sports and reality TV again. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 5:  gonna get messy. Oh, and gambling now, which is the real ESPN thing. That's
Speaker 5:  why you make the app If you s espn is for gambling. Richard,
Speaker 4:  What do you think about the, the rumor that the Mavs or tanking
Speaker 4:  so they can move to Vegas? Another deep cut.
Speaker 6:  I I think, I think there's a lot to it. I mean, if, If you, If you look into
Speaker 6:  it, there's a lot there.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's just more conspiracy theories from Richard dying gas
Speaker 4:  for the cable industry by the way, at Super Real Time. Comcast, which
Speaker 4:  I should disclose through NBC Universal is a minority investor
Speaker 4:  in our parent company. Vox Media. I'm gonna finish this segment, you'll understand
Speaker 4:  why that's I relevant information. Comcast in a dying
Speaker 4:  gasp per relevance here at the Super Bowl is they announced this week
Speaker 4:  they're gonna, they're gonna broadcast the Super Bowl in
Speaker 4:  4K Dolby vision. And now for the first time, Dolby Atmos
Speaker 4:  and I, a lot of people send this to us because everyone knows that all I
Speaker 4:  want in my life is for all of the lights semi receiver to light up
Speaker 4:  with all of the formats. If I could listen to Atmos and
Speaker 4:  Butcher HD at the same time, I'd be so happy. And DTSX, like
Speaker 4:  just all the lights, just light 'em all up. That's all I want. I'm barely
Speaker 4:  watching the movie. I'm just looking for the lights. This should
Speaker 4:  make me happy 'cause I can finally
Speaker 4:  get all the lights watching the Super Bowl. Here's the problem. Comcast is
Speaker 4:  a regional cable monopoly and they're not available where I live here in
Speaker 4:  New York state. So problem number one. So they're dead to me. Problem number
Speaker 4:  two, super fake, super fake.
Speaker 5:  The Atmos is fake,
Speaker 4:  Atmos is fake. The 4K is fake. The HDR is well sort of fake. So
Speaker 4:  Fox is doing the Super Bowl in 4K, they're adding more 4K cameras
Speaker 4:  to the production this year, including their Slowmo cameras, which they didn't
Speaker 4:  have before in 4K, but then they produce it in 10 80
Speaker 4:  PHDR and then upscale it at distribution.
Speaker 4:  And this is because Fox broadcast is at seven 20 P. So they
Speaker 4:  just picked the middle format so they could go over the air at seven 20
Speaker 4:  p and then out to streaming at upscale 4K. This is the worst compromise of
Speaker 4:  all time. It make it, I hate it. I hate it. So the actual
Speaker 4:  4K feed from Fox is upscaled
Speaker 4:  4K from 10 80 p in, I believe it's
Speaker 4:  H-L-G-H-D-R, just some other format. It's the best format for live.
Speaker 4:  Comcast is taking that feed in, in it's, I believe in
Speaker 4:  5.1 Adobe Digital Comcast is taking that feed.
Speaker 4:  They are
Speaker 4:  wrapping the HLG into Do Vision so they can claim they have Adobe vision.
Speaker 4:  So it's not right, it's, it's weird. That's just a weird thing they're doing.
Speaker 4:  And then they're upmixing the audio from 5.1 to Atmos.
Speaker 5:  It makes me think of those people who just like pour tap water into
Speaker 5:  bottles and then sell it as bottled water.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 5:  Was like, did we actually, did we accomplish anything here?
Speaker 4:  It's good. I love the idea and I, I don't know they're doing this. I will
Speaker 4:  forgive Comcast for doing this weird fake up mixing.
Speaker 4:  If they actually have a guy with like a, an audio joystick
Speaker 4:  like making swooping atmos sounds right? Like his job is
Speaker 4:  to track the ball in flight and be like, it's over you, it's behind you.
Speaker 4:  Like I'll find, show me that guy.
Speaker 5:  Okay, different idea. It's just Tom Brady running around your living
Speaker 5:  room.
Speaker 4:  That's right. I'm saying like, show me the guy with the track, the atmos
Speaker 4:  track pad. You know, like, I dunno if anybody, If you ever seen like
Speaker 4:  a logic mixing setup PR atmos, it's like they have a sound field and you
Speaker 4:  can move the sound object. Just show me the guy with the mouse just like
Speaker 4:  moving the sound objects in real time.
Speaker 4:  I'll believe you. I don't think it's happening.
Speaker 5:  Should the ball always be sneaking up on you? Like is that the, is that the
Speaker 5:  right answer?
Speaker 4:  That's what I'm saying. I don't actually, I don't know what either
Speaker 4:  quarterback's cadence is, but I'm just imagining Dak Prescott doing, here
Speaker 4:  we go. And it's like right behind you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you're the center and it's right behind your head yelling at you.
Speaker 4:  I don't know man, but there, this is, this is Comcast effort
Speaker 4:  to get you to sign up for a, a cable package is fake atmos envision.
Speaker 4:  And again, if they wanna, you know, they wanna call me and complain,
Speaker 4:  I'll hear 'em out. But there's a, there's a specific image I'm looking for
Speaker 4:  and it's the guy whose job it is to realtime pan the sound of the football
Speaker 4:  around the sound field. No, you would take that job. It's not, it's not the
Speaker 4:  guy. It's, it's a, it's someone moving Taylor Swift's voice very
Speaker 4:  specifically around mistaken. She's like, that's the thing. She's up in the
Speaker 4:  crowd.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Taylor's just strapped to the sky cam thing moving around the field
Speaker 4:  All there. Or, or I'll, I'll just, I'll I'll throw this one out there and
Speaker 4:  I know people are gonna have feelings about it. A guy who, or a button in
Speaker 4:  the interface that lets you select Tom Brady's voice
Speaker 4:  in the sound field and turn it off.
Speaker 7:  Ooh,
Speaker 5:  Now you're talking,
Speaker 4:  You and the, the real head snow.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's take a break from this. We'll come back with lightning round.
Speaker 4:  Someone else will say your company's name and then we'll do whatever we want.
Speaker 4:  It's a great deal. And I'm confident our previous sponsors have received
Speaker 4:  numerous signups, whoever they were. Okay, we we, there's
Speaker 4:  one thing in the streaming section that we didn't talk about, talk about
Speaker 4:  not quite super old streaming but pretty interesting. Sonos has been
Speaker 4:  going through just convulsions. Patrick Spence, the former
Speaker 4:  CEO who we've talked to many, many times over the years is gone after the
Speaker 4:  AP debacle. They have a new CEO Tom Conrad who we have also known
Speaker 4:  for a long time. Speaking of which Richard, he was the CTO of
Speaker 4:  Quibi and before that Pandora. Yeah, he's been everywhere.
Speaker 5:  He was everywhere. He was also at Snap for a minute I think. Like he's just
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he's that that dude. His
Speaker 4:  Stories. Tom's a smart guy. Yeah, we've invited him on the show. I think
Speaker 4:  when things settle down at Sonos, we, we'll, we'll definitely talk to him.
Speaker 4:  He's been on their board forever, but he's come into the company and
Speaker 4:  you know, his first move is, he's like, we need to be smaller and flatter
Speaker 4:  and more nimble. They're laying off 200 more people. So this company is,
Speaker 4:  some stuff is happening there. But then Chris Welch this week
Speaker 4:  got more details about the streaming box that we've been hearing about for
Speaker 4:  a long time. It, it sounds pretty good. David,
Speaker 4:  what's going on here?
Speaker 5:  I, I agree. This is sort of the streaming box you would
Speaker 5:  want there to be in the world, which I find very exciting. So the thing
Speaker 5:  is called Pinewood, that's the code name that Chris watch has heard. Mark
Speaker 5:  Germin also I think reported a while ago that it was called Pinewood. I assume
Speaker 5:  that's not the name because everybody gives their actual products worse names
Speaker 5:  than the code names. But that's the code name. And I would say
Speaker 5:  the two biggest features of it are that a, it
Speaker 5:  apparently has actual honest to God universal search
Speaker 5:  across lots of different streaming services. So you can look for
Speaker 5:  things across all of the services that you subscribe to, which essentially
Speaker 5:  doesn't exist on any other platform. Everybody has some section of them,
Speaker 5:  but nobody really has everybody. So if in theory Sonos
Speaker 5:  has actually pulled all of your streaming into a single unified
Speaker 5:  interface, that would be very cool.
Speaker 4:  What do you think the possibility of that actually is?
Speaker 5:  Low, I'm super skeptical of that for a bunch of reasons. One,
Speaker 5:  I don't know why any of these companies would sign up for that. For
Speaker 5:  Sonos in particular. It's possible that Sonos is paying pretty handsomely
Speaker 5:  for this. Krista's reporting says that it's gonna cost somewhere between
Speaker 5:  200, $400 for the box, which is a lot. And maybe there's a real
Speaker 5:  part of that baked in that is Sonos paid for this search product to
Speaker 5:  be great. But I doubt it. Like I just don't think these companies have any
Speaker 5:  incentive to play nicely together, specifically with Sonos and
Speaker 5:  to do it here. You, you lose all kinds of leverage. Like
Speaker 5:  suddenly Apple is just gonna show up at your door and be like, listen, here
Speaker 5:  we go.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, famously Apple cannot get Netflix to play in its search product.
Speaker 5:  Right? There's also the fact that this operating system
Speaker 5:  is being built either in partnership or just licensed from a
Speaker 5:  company called the Trade Desk, which is a digital advertising company. It's
Speaker 5:  very weird. Like I, I would not say I have a ton of faith in this interface
Speaker 5:  period. Sonos is not famously great at user
Speaker 5:  interfaces. I wouldn't say not anymore. So the idea that this is, they were,
Speaker 4:  They were, I mean this is is why they were a dominant player in their little
Speaker 4:  space for a long time. Like they, no,
Speaker 5:  They're really great at networking their speakers. Which brings us to the
Speaker 5:  other thing that Pinewood is apparently gonna be very good at is it's, it's
Speaker 5:  going to be a mix of an HDMI switch
Speaker 5:  and a way to connect your whole Sonos system.
Speaker 5:  So it seems like one of the animating principles for this device was a bunch
Speaker 5:  of Sonos people being annoyed that it was hard to connect your TV
Speaker 5:  to your Sonos devices and to all of your other home theater devices.
Speaker 5:  And that by building the thing in the middle they could solve this problem
Speaker 5:  and make it easier to do things like build a home theater setup out of your
Speaker 5:  Sonos gear and all kinds of different stuff that would be very
Speaker 5:  compelling to Sonos people. And I can understand why there would be people
Speaker 5:  who would pay for that, make it easier, make it better to
Speaker 5:  connect all my stuff to my tv. Sure.
Speaker 5:  That is the thing. Sonos does very well and has done well for a long time
Speaker 5:  until it screwed up its app really bad. So I have, I have reasonably high
Speaker 5:  hopes that it could pull that off. But then the overarching question here
Speaker 5:  is like, does all of that add up to the most
Speaker 5:  expensive set top box on the market being worth
Speaker 5:  it? Richard,
Speaker 4:  Let me ask you this. And again, Richard and I are our old heads together.
Speaker 4:  We've covered a lot of home theater ideas over the years in a way
Speaker 4:  that I think when we're older and retired, we will just tell war stories
Speaker 4:  like on a porch somewhere to children who don't care. Like that's where Richard
Speaker 4:  and I are together on this journey. But let me ask you this, did they just
Speaker 4:  make a receiver? 'cause you squint at this thing and you're like, oh, it's
Speaker 4:  a receiver with a Roku in it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's just a, an Atmos receiver that is more expensive
Speaker 6:  and has the apps built into it with universal search, which I'm
Speaker 6:  pretty sure people have tried before. Right?
Speaker 4:  And but, but by the way, it doesn't have any amps in it so you need to buy
Speaker 4:  their wireless speaker, right? It's a receiver that only works with
Speaker 4:  one company's wireless speakers. But
Speaker 6:  Hasn't that been their business model basically the whole time? So to be
Speaker 6:  fair,
Speaker 4:  Right, I'm just getting at, I, you know like a lot of people
Speaker 4:  want to plug game consoles directly into their TVs to get
Speaker 4:  quick media switching and VRR and whatever else you wanna get out of it,
Speaker 4:  right? Lower lag. Those are the
Speaker 4:  people who do not wanna buy a receiver. 'cause you don't want to pass through
Speaker 4:  and introduce the lag of a receiver and maybe downgrade your ports and blah
Speaker 4:  blah blah blah blah, blah blah. Putting the Sonos box there keeps you from
Speaker 4:  plugging in directly into the tv, which is really the only thing people are
Speaker 4:  plugging into TVs anymore. Like maybe you have a streaming box,
Speaker 4:  but the reason people want high-end ht y ports on their
Speaker 4:  TVs is game consoles. Like at the end of the day, that's really the main
Speaker 4:  thing. Yeah. And so like Sonos being like, here's our soundbar, it plugs
Speaker 4:  into your ER port and it plays the audio, it just solves the problem already
Speaker 4:  it that we should make a 400 streaming box. It's like half a receiver, but
Speaker 4:  not quite seems, it just seems on its face very complicated to me.
Speaker 4:  Especially when I don't know if they can fix the user interface in a specific
Speaker 4:  way that they're claiming to fix the user interface.
Speaker 5:  The reason I'm skeptical of the user interface is because this is the promise
Speaker 5:  that everybody makes. Yes. Everybody who makes one of these things
Speaker 5:  says we have solved content discovery and no one solves content
Speaker 5:  discovery. I will say I've become a huge fan of the Google TV
Speaker 5:  streamer, which I think does a better job of smooshing all the stuff together
Speaker 5:  than almost anybody. And even it does a shit job of it because this
Speaker 5:  stuff gets delayed. It's not able to get that stuff in real time from the
Speaker 5:  services that you're watching. It always updates in wacky ways. And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  I don't wanna, what my kid is watching on YouTube in the morning does not
Speaker 5:  need to be the first thing that appears on my television when I turn it on
Speaker 5:  at night. Like, this stuff is hard. So I'm like, I'm not, I don't say this
Speaker 5:  to denigrate any of these companies. This is hard and there are a million
Speaker 5:  conflicting interests in it, but everybody always says they've solved it.
Speaker 5:  And so Sonos, which again, not famously
Speaker 5:  fabulous at building user interfaces and software.
Speaker 5:  I just, I I hope they're telling the truth, but I'm not gonna
Speaker 5:  believe it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I dunno man. We'll, we'll see, like I said, we're Tom's a smart guy.
Speaker 4:  He is. Obviously he's made cuts. Hopefully they can fix the app, but this
Speaker 4:  is one where you've gotta do something that's so much better to
Speaker 4:  get people outta the ecosystems they're already in, especially when Rokus
Speaker 4:  are basically free and whatever software's coming on your ties frame TV is
Speaker 4:  already free.
Speaker 5:  There's also some reporting in Chris's story that this thing is actually
Speaker 5:  a little bit divisive inside of Sonos. There are a bunch of people who think
Speaker 5:  making an extremely expensive streaming service or an
Speaker 5:  extremely expensive streaming box is not the right thing for Sonos to
Speaker 5:  be doing right now. Which after making an extremely expensive pair of
Speaker 5:  headphones seems like a reasonable argument to make.
Speaker 4:  I'm just surprised this thing isn't a soundbar unto itself. I think if it
Speaker 4:  was the soundbar, you would, you could make some different arguments, but
Speaker 4:  you have to buy this and the Sonos soundbar, it starts to get really complicated,
Speaker 4:  especially at $400. That's
Speaker 5:  A good point. I think the, the Roku soundbar,
Speaker 5:  I know a bunch of people who have it, including my in-laws and it's a big
Speaker 5:  hit with people who, it's just like you just plug the thing in and it instantly
Speaker 5:  makes everything about your TV a little bit better. Like it's a pretty good
Speaker 5:  win. But that's also not Sonos game. Sonos is not
Speaker 5:  doing the like plug this thing into your TV and it's super easy
Speaker 5:  and it just works and it's fine thing. And so I just, I don't
Speaker 5:  know, I kind of can't figure out what Sonos angle is here and why this would
Speaker 5:  work. But again, I hope I'm wrong. Like what it's describing is the set top
Speaker 5:  box that I want. So hopefully it is that. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I mean I look, I I love a dumb TV gadget again, my shirt. I'd
Speaker 4:  been through a lot of this.
Speaker 5:  Sonos should have just built a television, right? We're in agreement on this.
Speaker 4:  They, maybe everyone should just build a TV because the TV market right now
Speaker 4:  is bananas.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's bananas. And David, you need to buy a new one. And we can talk
Speaker 4:  about that later. All right, I'm gonna segue from this version of
Speaker 4:  streaming, this streaming conversation into our new segment. Brendan Carr
Speaker 4:  is a dummy. I'm gonna do it seamlessly.
Speaker 4:  Alright. TV industry under a lot of pressure, lots of
Speaker 4:  consolidation, lots of deals being done. CBS
Speaker 4:  Paramount desperately wants to sell itself to a company called Skydance,
Speaker 4:  owned by Larry Ellison's son, the Trump
Speaker 4:  administration putting pressure on this deal. And in
Speaker 4:  particular, the pressure has come in from our friend Brendan Carr.
Speaker 5:  That was less of a segue than like a free association slam
Speaker 5:  poetry kind of thing. You just did, but I liked it. It's a group of Amy come.
Speaker 5:  I'm into it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I I I brought you home. All right. To our new segment, Brendan
Speaker 4:  Carr is a dummy and the biggest threat to the First Amendment this country
Speaker 4:  currently faces.
Speaker 5:  If you would like to compose theme music to this segment, I will play it
Speaker 5:  every single time. I, I promise Brendan,
Speaker 4:  If you're listening, just know you're welcome on decoder anytime
Speaker 4:  it'll be a good time. Alright, so Brendan Carr putting pressure on this
Speaker 4:  deal saying the FCC is allowed to review the sale of CBS because CBS owns
Speaker 4:  some broadcast licenses for some of its stations, not all of its stations,
Speaker 4:  some of its stations. And that means they get to review some of the deal.
Speaker 4:  In particular, he's putting pressure on them for this interview
Speaker 4:  of Kamala Harris on 60 Minutes in which
Speaker 4:  one part of an answer was aired in one part of a show. And another part of
Speaker 4:  an answer was aired later on CBSI think evening news. So they had one
Speaker 4:  big interview and they chopped up the interview and aired different bits
Speaker 4:  in different parts,
Speaker 5:  Which is what everyone does with every piece of content
Speaker 5:  everywhere all the time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I dunno If you have ever watched anything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like how dare you only show this one play of the basketball game on
Speaker 5:  Instagram. You have to show the whole game or else it's illegal.
Speaker 4:  I demand a full uncut Avengers
Speaker 4:  end game. The whole thing. I wanna see all of it.
Speaker 4:  And you know, deceptive editing and news is a problem. I'm not gonna shy
Speaker 4:  away from it, but it, it's just everywhere. You wanna see some deceptive
Speaker 4:  editing and news. You could watch Fox News. They do it all
Speaker 5:  The time. Oh, I thought you were about to do a cool thing. We'd have to edit.
Speaker 5:  That's all right. We'll get 'em next time.
Speaker 4:  I deceptively edit everything. Do you know where we're starting? Where the
Speaker 4:  merger is launching a phone.
Speaker 4:  So he's putting all this pressure on CBS. He says it's news distortion.
Speaker 4:  The Trump administration has sued CBS for $10 billion. I would
Speaker 4:  remind all of you that they are the winners. They, they won the election
Speaker 4:  and they are currently in power. And so this is just some pure sore winner
Speaker 4:  stuff.
Speaker 4:  But CBS wants to sell itself. They want to make this deal.
Speaker 4:  So instead of doing what their newsroom wants them to do, which is
Speaker 4:  ferociously fight a government speech regulation and
Speaker 4:  government overreach into protected editorial speech, which is what they
Speaker 4:  should do. That's just some First Amendment stuff. You're a government speech
Speaker 4:  regulator. You show up to a newsroom, the newsroom should say F off.
Speaker 4:  This is what you should do that And people do it all the time. Nope,
Speaker 4:  they're gonna roll. So they gave the full unedited interview to the
Speaker 4:  FCC Brendan Carr published it and now of course right wing grifters are seizing
Speaker 4:  on the dumbest stuff to quote unquote prove that the thing was edited. Even
Speaker 4:  though you can see for yourself, CBS ran the first part of an
Speaker 4:  answer in one show and the second part of an answer in another show. And
Speaker 4:  it was just a long answer and they just picked the answer they thought was
Speaker 4:  most relevant to those audiences. But now you have it, you can see it,
Speaker 5:  You could ironically argue that that's actually good journalism because they
Speaker 5:  ran the whole answer. Because you get to see more of the
Speaker 5:  answer than
Speaker 4:  You would I think you can be very critical of CBS for not making it clear
Speaker 4:  that this was one long answer and they cut it and then getting caught and
Speaker 4:  then like being shady about like I I do think there was some weirdness there
Speaker 4:  from CBS. Okay. I do think the, Hey, we had a long conversation. We ran some
Speaker 4:  part of the answers. You can read any profile of any famous person in any
Speaker 4:  magazine and they're only running the parts of the answers that are relevant
Speaker 4:  to the story that is being told on profile it's reality. Yeah. Right. In
Speaker 4:  60 Minutes in particular, it's not like a podcast, right. They're like
Speaker 4:  tightly edited little story packages. They're very good. They're, they're
Speaker 4:  famous for them. CBS 60 Minutes also not famously a bastion of like
Speaker 4:  wild leftist ideas. It's a news magazine for old people. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  it is a very conservative program
Speaker 5:  But also like as as journalistically buttoned up as any organization you
Speaker 5:  will find anywhere.
Speaker 4:  Yep. So that's one. So he's pressuring CBS and CBS is caving
Speaker 4:  because Paramount wants to make a deal with Skydance. Very
Speaker 4:  dangerous. Like I don't, I actually don't care what your politics are.
Speaker 4:  That is First Amendment fire territory. Right? You just don't want the government
Speaker 4:  interfering with speech in this way
Speaker 4:  and the idea that because they have a broadcast license that Brendan Carr
Speaker 4:  can invent some public in. No, you just don't do it. We haven't done it for
Speaker 4:  years. For years Republicans and Democrats
Speaker 4:  alike have said this should not be the business. The FCC. The FCC should
Speaker 4:  be in the business of getting people connected to the internet. And we're
Speaker 4:  not doing that anymore. We're doing, we're gonna go interfere with CBS's
Speaker 4:  speech 'cause they wanna make a merger weird all the way around. Weird. Do
Speaker 4:  not trade the first Amendment for a merger. It's not gonna work anyway. By
Speaker 4:  the way, you're already at 80 on the go 90 scale. Yeah. Like horrible second
Speaker 4:  Brendan Carr same deal started an investigation this
Speaker 4:  week into KCBS 7:40 AM in San Francisco
Speaker 4:  because their news program reported on the location
Speaker 4:  of an ice raid in San Jose. So they said we're we're
Speaker 4:  reporting we, there's an ice raid going on, we see this thing is happening,
Speaker 4:  here's the cars or whatever. And he said, oh you're interfering with immigration.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna investigate your broadcast license. I'll tell you right now,
Speaker 4:  every single day on social media, people are telling you where their ice
Speaker 4:  raids. Yeah. It's just happening on every on x whatever platform you want.
Speaker 4:  This is happening because it is a public interest that this is happening
Speaker 4:  and it is in fact happening. So to go into a news
Speaker 4:  organization and say you are interfering with law enforcement and that's
Speaker 4:  somehow a crime that should lead to the FCC investigating your spectrum
Speaker 4:  license another five alarm First Amendment fire.
Speaker 4:  Especially when the exact same content distributed on social media.
Speaker 4:  Not he can't, he has, he can't say anything about it. This is just Brendan
Speaker 4:  who has some power, who's invented a new way of using power because he doles
Speaker 4:  out broadcast licenses to say I can interfere with speech
Speaker 4:  and I promise you he is coming for the internet. He's not gonna be done here
Speaker 4:  with the broadcast companies. He's gonna find out if this
Speaker 4:  works. If I've doled out a broadcast license and I can
Speaker 4:  go interfere with speech and chill news organizations, he's gonna find out
Speaker 4:  if it works. And then he will invent a way to say the
Speaker 4:  FCC should look at the content being distributed by internet service
Speaker 4:  providers. And it is already happening in a variety of ways. They've tried
Speaker 4:  it several times. SOPA and pep. We don't want copyright infringement, we
Speaker 4:  don't want pornography, we want the kids online safety. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  find some hook for the first amendment to come and regulate the concept
Speaker 4:  of internet service Section two 30, Brendan too hard. The author
Speaker 4:  of the project 2025 chapter on the FCC says the FCC should
Speaker 4:  just reinterpret section two 30 for the courts to give him power over
Speaker 4:  internet providers. All this stuff. You might not care about 60
Speaker 4:  minutes, you might not care about some AM radio station. These are all little
Speaker 4:  trial balloons to see if Brendan Carr can meet the speech police for the
Speaker 4:  country.
Speaker 4:  And can I just say, while he is doing all this in the background, he's putting
Speaker 4:  out blog posts that are super friendly, full of jokes about how he's a chiefs
Speaker 4:  fan saying his this is real. He, he released a blog post this week saying
Speaker 4:  his biggest priority was a rulemaking to see if there
Speaker 4:  are steps the FCC can take to make sure TV viewers aren't inundated by
Speaker 4:  exceedingly loud TV commercials.
Speaker 5:  Oh no, this is a real like worst person, you know. Makes a good point kind
Speaker 5:  of thing though. Like I do agree with that. I taking a nap the other day
Speaker 5:  and a commercial woke me up and I was like pretty annoyed by it.
Speaker 4:  Oh and he also wants to stop spam calling, which this commission has been
Speaker 4:  trying to do since 500 years. Yeah, they, they're not able to do it 'cause
Speaker 4:  they won't, 'cause the telecom companies basically own them so
Speaker 4:  they won't actually do anything. Like there are no spam calls in Europe or
Speaker 4:  the Europeans on our team are like, what are you talking about? We're like,
Speaker 4:  no, no, no. If you just answer a phone call, someone will steal your identity.
Speaker 4:  That's how America is now. You have to shoot your phone when it rings.
Speaker 4:  But it's because Europeans regulate their telecom companies and we have this
Speaker 4:  revolving doors of weirdos and now the biggest weirdo of all brand car.
Speaker 4:  I'm telling you there's a lot of bad Trump administration stuff and you
Speaker 4:  might hate my politics, whatever you think my politics are, but I have been
Speaker 4:  very consistent on this show for over a decade. The government
Speaker 4:  speech regulations are bad. And this is, here
Speaker 4:  they are, they have a face, they have a name. It is Brendan Carr.
Speaker 4:  He is trying to pressure and news organizations using the idea that
Speaker 4:  the FCC can regulate the airwaves to, to regulate speech
Speaker 4:  directly as a trial balloon for how can the FCC regulate what's on the internet,
Speaker 4:  Brenda?
Speaker 5:  And it's also not that big a gap from one to the next. Like it doesn't, it
Speaker 5:  sounds like a big leap from one to the other, but it's not,
Speaker 5:  it's the same playbook you can run in both places.
Speaker 4:  And meanwhile he's putting out blog posts saying he's gonna make the TV commercials
Speaker 4:  quieter. I'm just saying Brandon, If you wanna come Onder I know, I know
Speaker 4:  you listen, I pay attention. I know you Google your own name. I know this
Speaker 4:  because you've, I I I just know I've gotten the incoming before.
Speaker 4:  Come on to Cutter to try to defend this. It's indefensible this, this is
Speaker 4:  First Amendment on fire territory and it has a face in it. So we're gonna
Speaker 4:  just do this every week unfortunately because this is very dangerous
Speaker 4:  stuff and I I I just think we should all be far more protective of
Speaker 4:  the First Amendment. This especially 'cause he keeps talking about it in
Speaker 4:  the language of free speech. Why is he punishing CBS because
Speaker 4:  of free speech. That makes no sense. Yeah. Okay. Sorry.
Speaker 5:  I can buy Brendan Carr as a dummy.com for $19 and redirect it to the first
Speaker 5:  cast if I
Speaker 4:  Don't want you to be arrested.
Speaker 4:  That's how you get arrested. Alright. Sorry. This is supposed be a lightning
Speaker 4:  round.
Speaker 4:  Richard, what's your lightning round item? I'll, I'll stop dunking on Brendan
Speaker 4:  now.
Speaker 6:  Oh, my favorite story of the week, dummy opening as new logo.
Speaker 4:  No, Richard,
Speaker 4:  can I tell you, so we published, start out the new logo and I'll let Richard
Speaker 4:  describe it. We got a bunch of commenters being like, this is clickbait.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what you're talking about.
Speaker 4:  Is that real? 'cause you real can't tell super real.
Speaker 6:  They're like, we changed like, like we had a dis we had a long
Speaker 6:  discussion in New
Speaker 4:  Room
Speaker 6:  And with me just asking what they said they
Speaker 6:  like and I mean specifically. So they got a new typeface,
Speaker 6:  OpenAI Sands. Okay, whatever fonts, typefaces,
Speaker 6:  you got 'em, it's, it, it's words. You, you can read it.
Speaker 6:  They also have that little like design that they have that
Speaker 6:  you're supposed to not use by itself I guess. But that little, what is it?
Speaker 6:  It's three triangles, interlocking, I guess
Speaker 4:  They're not triangles. It's, it's like a, it's their bubble. It's got a hexagon
Speaker 4:  in the middle.
Speaker 6:  They say it's triangles, but they don't line up. So they're not triangles.
Speaker 6:  I don't know what it's, no, they
Speaker 4:  Look like chain links. It's a triangles, it's a clover. It's like a clover
Speaker 4:  leaf field. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's a clover. Yeah, that's good. And so they cleaned it up, but they didn't
Speaker 6:  make it line up so that it's triangles like they say it is. So
Speaker 6:  If you, If you look very closely, I guess you can figure out what is different
Speaker 6:  about it, but it looks the same. No,
Speaker 4:  Richard,
Speaker 5:  Can I tell you what's different? They made the lines a little thicker. That's,
Speaker 5:  that's
Speaker 4:  It. No, the lines, lines are No, no, David, the lines are thinner.
Speaker 6:  See, see,
Speaker 4:  You're right.
Speaker 6:  No, and that's why this is my favorite story.
Speaker 4:  But by far, Richard, I need you
Speaker 5:  To describe the photo of the words in the
Speaker 5:  sky
Speaker 4:  Because this is the greatest thing I've ever seen.
Speaker 6:  It is, I mean, it is OpenAI
Speaker 6:  in front of clouds taken from a mountain above the
Speaker 6:  clouds. Why? I don't know. This is what was in
Speaker 6:  their video to tell you about their new design, which I'm sure they spent
Speaker 6:  a lot of money on and congratulations to them for that. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, do you guys
Speaker 5:  Remember the Chairs Are Like Facebook ad?
Speaker 6:  I do not. You, you, you
Speaker 5:  Remember the chairs like
Speaker 6:  Facebook ad. I had no clue what that was.
Speaker 4:  Well, what's the other way? It was Facebook was like a chair. No
Speaker 4:  chairs like Facebook.
Speaker 5:  The video is titled my friend Chairs Are Like Facebook.
Speaker 4:  You know, it's funny that a decade later I've recognized this to make slightly
Speaker 4:  more sense. And you're right,
Speaker 5:  It is insanity. I, I'll put this link in the show notes, but it is one
Speaker 5:  of the most unhinged pieces of brand advertising
Speaker 5:  I have ever seen in my entire life. It, it was, it was a
Speaker 5:  TV commercial that Facebook came out with in I think 2012 when it hit a billion
Speaker 5:  users that literally compared chairs
Speaker 5:  to Facebook. And it is, it is like an ayahuasca trip of
Speaker 5:  an advertis, an advertising plan. And it's insane. And
Speaker 5:  this is what this made me think of because Richard, in addition to the one
Speaker 5:  you just described, there's another image in which a bunch of
Speaker 5:  words are just randomly superimposed on a like
Speaker 5:  California mountain thing and it just says artificial general
Speaker 5:  intelligence that benefits all of humanity.
Speaker 5:  Also, they didn't use AI to
Speaker 4:  Design this.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yeah. Which is absurd. Like have some faith in your own products, people
Speaker 5:  come on.
Speaker 4:  Okay. It's one thing I wanna say and I will leave this as a puzzle for the
Speaker 4:  listener. It's so
Speaker 5:  Good.
Speaker 4:  The lines in the clover are both thicker and thinner.
Speaker 4:  And I will allow you, everyone can go evaluate what that means on themselves,
Speaker 4:  but it's true, they're both thicker and thinner. So David, you were half
Speaker 5:  Right,
Speaker 4:  But not all the right and
Speaker 5:  That makes me angrier. Like I like that less than what I was just wrong.
Speaker 5:  I don't like this.
Speaker 4:  The other piece of the puzzle here that I is just funny if you're a design
Speaker 4:  nerd is like all rebrands, they have a custom font, you know, it's like
Speaker 4:  all the stuff they're doing. It's called OpenAI sands, all, all whatever.
Speaker 4:  They announced it in wallpaper with like the usual words
Speaker 4:  of we made a design system and now we have to pretend that it means something
Speaker 4:  like it's more organic and more human. But it's funny that they announced
Speaker 4:  in wallpaper because wallpaper is where Johnny, ive has always gone to
Speaker 4:  talk about design and apple's designers have always gone to talk about design
Speaker 4:  and like, If you wanna read long stories about the Apple
Speaker 4:  design lab in which nothing is said like wallpaper is for you. It's, it's,
Speaker 4:  I love like I want to Yeah, I'm saying with all sincerity, I love it and
Speaker 4:  I want them to publish that every day so I can read it because I will just
Speaker 4:  take it in. I like, I love it with all my heart, but it's, it's not, there's
Speaker 4:  nothing, there's never anything in there. Yeah. But Johnny, ive
Speaker 4:  working famously with Sam Altman on some weird OpenAI hardware device.
Speaker 4:  So OpenAI doing a big rebrand and talking in all these design words
Speaker 4:  about why they're more human and announcing in wallpaper. That's a lot of
Speaker 4:  Johnny Ive and also a bunch of other Apple designers
Speaker 4:  now at OpenAI. So yes, Richard, it is very silly. But there's,
Speaker 4:  there's just a little evidence here that, you know, there's some Johnny I
Speaker 4:  in the mix, by the way, OpenAI also announced deep research this week, their
Speaker 4:  actual product, not just a weird logo with lines that are both thicker and
Speaker 4:  thinner than the old logo. Have you used it at all?
Speaker 5:  Only in tiny bits and pieces so far. I got it. I got the
Speaker 5:  $200 a month Chad, GBT mostly so I can test operator
Speaker 5:  about which I have many feelings that I'm, I'm not ready to talk about yet
Speaker 5:  because it will send me down a rabbit hole I'm not ready for. But
Speaker 5:  it, it's, it's really good. I mean it's, it's a huge leap
Speaker 5:  towards, again, what if we let these things be slow
Speaker 5:  and kind of confusing and convoluted in the name of making them better.
Speaker 5:  And I think in a really interesting way that is not
Speaker 5:  how most people make product that, like if everybody just said,
Speaker 5:  what if we made our apps slower?
Speaker 5:  A lot of things might get better, but also people wouldn't do it. But
Speaker 5:  I think OpenAI is like on this interesting push towards what if,
Speaker 5:  what if this stuff is actually like useful and
Speaker 5:  tells the truth? And there are a lot of people out there who are, are using
Speaker 5:  it for really complicated research things who are impressed with what they're
Speaker 5:  getting. So I think there's something here, it appears to be very slow
Speaker 5:  and very expensive to run. So I don't know what
Speaker 5:  to make of that exactly. But, but the idea that you can do things
Speaker 5:  that make these systems work better appears to be true,
Speaker 5:  I think is really interesting.
Speaker 4:  Well this is why Sam Altman needs $500 billion,
Speaker 5:  Right? Well, and this is like the, I think the great deep seek legacy
Speaker 5:  will be pushing everybody towards, oh, what if these things were better?
Speaker 5:  What If you tried harder? I mean it's like what you said on the show last
Speaker 5:  week, NELI, right? Like there's this fundamental idea that all we have to
Speaker 5:  do is throw more compute at it and it'll ev it'll eventually
Speaker 5:  all work itself out. Like the scaling laws will fix it. And I
Speaker 5:  think pretty quickly everyone has come around to like, no, we actually need
Speaker 5:  some new ideas here. Yeah. And we're starting to see the fruits of that
Speaker 5:  really fast.
Speaker 4:  I, I've done a little bit of playing with the research tool and man, you
Speaker 4:  know, it's still, it's based on searching the open web and
Speaker 4:  it, it's like, I just don't, I just don't trust any AI tool. It's like, I
Speaker 4:  learned this on the internet. It's like that
Speaker 5:  Is a real question of like, how useful is this to me? Because I still have
Speaker 5:  to go fact check everything it came up with. But yeah, there's,
Speaker 5:  there's something, I don't know, I'm still struck by how many of our listeners
Speaker 5:  we were like, I don't care if it's wrong sometimes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's that. I will say another funny superb bowl note,
Speaker 4:  Richard, this week you sent an email to a professor of cheese science.
Speaker 4:  Can you explain what's going on here? Yes.
Speaker 6:  So the thing that Google is doing for their AI ads for the Super Bowl, they've
Speaker 6:  got like one for each state. So it's like whatever your state's big
Speaker 6:  business is, your marquee business. And of course for Wisconsin Cheese,
Speaker 6:  it's my people. And so they, they're partnering with this cheese company
Speaker 6:  and they're showing them using like Gemini to do whatever it is that
Speaker 6:  they're doing. And at one point they're generating texts for like emails
Speaker 6:  or something and it says something about guta and how that's like the most
Speaker 6:  popular cheese.
Speaker 4:  Now I believe it specifically claims it's 50 to 60% of the cheese in the
Speaker 4:  world is
Speaker 5:  Guta.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And, and someone on the internet notice that and they, they, they would
Speaker 6:  not let that one slide. They said, no, no, no, it's
Speaker 6:  not that math just doesn't work. And so
Speaker 6:  we, we heard about this, we looked into it, this was the subject of a
Speaker 6:  long write a thread like 10 years ago, people, 10 years ago, this exact question
Speaker 6:  from the same exact website that the Gemini seemed to have gotten
Speaker 6:  this answer from perfect completely unsourced other, other than this
Speaker 6:  kind of spammy website. Was it
Speaker 4:  Like cheese fax.com? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Because of it was, it was like cheese.com or something like that. Something
Speaker 6:  very SEO on point. And they've got like a page
Speaker 6:  about each cheese and every cheese is the most popular on its page.
Speaker 6:  Wait, wait,
Speaker 4:  Is that true?
Speaker 6:  I they, they're like very carefully worded. Like If you, If you go to like
Speaker 6:  mozzarella it, it's, it seems like mozzarella's the most popular cheese.
Speaker 6:  Mm. But so
Speaker 4:  Every, every page on cheese.com is just gassing up different cheeses.
Speaker 6:  So I, I I, I said, alright, we need some experts. And I'm,
Speaker 6:  you know, there's like councils and, and professors who study like
Speaker 6:  dairy and the business of dairy. And I emailed this guy on a Friday at like
Speaker 6:  4:40 PM you know, everyone is getting ready to go
Speaker 6:  basically immediately got back like six paragraphs on the cheese business
Speaker 6:  and why Google's AI was wrong about cheese. In fact,
Speaker 4:  He was ready, he was in the Reddit thread.
Speaker 5:  Okay, this is such a total diversion from
Speaker 5:  what we're talking about. But I'm now on cheese.com and
Speaker 5:  like we talk about like PhD thesis of internet
Speaker 5:  websites, go to cheese.com/cheddar and it will describe
Speaker 5:  to you everything about how the internet works.
Speaker 5:  There's an H two, which is a signal to Google of what's important. What is
Speaker 5:  cheddar cheese? Why is cheddar orange? The answer is cheddar cheese is a
Speaker 5:  popular type of cheese that originated in the village of cheddar in Somerset,
Speaker 5:  England. It is known for its distinct flavor, versatility and vibrant orange
Speaker 5:  color. Bunch of that's already not true. In this article, we will explore
Speaker 5:  what cheddar cheese is made of it's taste, shelf life, nutritional value,
Speaker 5:  and its origins. And there's one of these for every kind of cheese.
Speaker 5:  This poor Ian Jackson who wrote this and I think is
Speaker 5:  maybe a real person I don't know, has written an alarming number of these,
Speaker 5:  this is blowing my mind,
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry. On cheese.com. You can embark on a cheese adventure by exploring
Speaker 4:  the database of 2048 different types of cheese. You can also buy cheese
Speaker 4:  gifts and make someone happy. I love this website. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 4:  And I understand why the robot was like, screw it, 50 to 60% of the world's
Speaker 4:  cheese is gda. Anyway, so Richard, you got an email back. What'd the email
Speaker 4:  say?
Speaker 6:  Basically, it's hard to say with the most popular cheeses because,
Speaker 6:  and also we were speaking to our, our, our colleagues from Europe again,
Speaker 6:  who have a very different opinion of cheese and, and wanted to make sure
Speaker 6:  that everyone knows that American cheese is apparently not cheese.
Speaker 4:  Now you don't understand, we have Thomas Wicker, our our deputy editor lives
Speaker 4:  in the Netherlands. He lives in Amsterdam, which is where Goa's from. And
Speaker 4:  he was like, I don't know about gda, but I know your cheese is shit. Which
Speaker 4:  is just such an immediately aggro response. He
Speaker 5:  Europe
Speaker 4:  Like, bro, I wasn't even fine.
Speaker 6:  The temperature on this discussion went way up very quickly.
Speaker 6:  And, and like I didn't know that we were having an international trade war
Speaker 6:  on cheese and I just stepped right in the middle of this
Speaker 6:  completely unexpectedly. It, it, it went places. But there
Speaker 6:  are lots of cheeses and you know, I don't know if you've heard of like
Speaker 6:  other countries, but everywhere has their favorite cheese and for any, for
Speaker 6:  basically anyone to be 60% of the market, probably not,
Speaker 6:  probably. And if it
Speaker 5:  Was, it would definitely be mozzarella, right? Like
Speaker 4:  What America
Speaker 6:  Doing. But we don't eat as much cheese as they do appar. Apparently
Speaker 6:  there are countries that eat way more cheese per person than we do. So just
Speaker 6:  letting you know,
Speaker 5:  That's why they're better countries.
Speaker 4:  So we published this story.
Speaker 4:  We got a a bunch of comments like, why do you care? Which is very funny.
Speaker 4:  Why do you keep criticizing AI for people, for getting it wrong? People get
Speaker 4:  things wrong all the time, which is the new line.
Speaker 4:  But I will say Richard and Emma who wrote the story, this is impact journalism.
Speaker 4:  Google has changed the ad. They have removed the guha stat
Speaker 4:  from the Super Bowl ad.
Speaker 6:  When, when, when you watch the Super Bowl on Sunday in Wisconsin, in
Speaker 4:  Wisconsin,
Speaker 6:  You'll not be misinformed about cheese.
Speaker 4:  I do think Gem and I learned this from an SEO website that's designed to
Speaker 4:  just sell you cheese and tell you every cheese is the most popular cheese.
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean. It's like I just, that's their feedback loop.
Speaker 4:  Not,
Speaker 5:  Not to make this bleecker than a delightful
Speaker 5:  cheese incident really is. But the comment we got
Speaker 5:  from Google, from the cloud apps president Jerry Disher
Speaker 5:  basically says that in a way that I found really bleak. His, his response
Speaker 5:  was not a hallucination. Gemini is grounded in the web and users
Speaker 5:  can always check the results and references in this case, mul in this case,
Speaker 5:  multiple sites across the web include the 50 to 60% stat. So what he's
Speaker 5:  saying is, this is a feature, not a bug.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 5:  The thing got it wrong and it's not our fault because somewhere on the
Speaker 5:  internet the wrong information exists and thus we cannot be blamed.
Speaker 4:  David, to your point, people can just say stuff, you can just, people can
Speaker 4:  just say things. You can just say, Guta is 50 per to 60% of the world's
Speaker 4:  cheese on your weird website. That gets scraped over and over again for a
Speaker 4:  decade. And then at the end of that, AI will say, you know
Speaker 4:  what? Fine. That's true.
Speaker 5:  Yep. People can just say things. And If you can, If you, If you build your
Speaker 5:  life based on everything that people say, you will, you will end up lying
Speaker 5:  about cheese.
Speaker 4:  Watch out Elon. Alright, new goal for The Verge team.
Speaker 4:  We have to get Elon to claim that Guta is 60% in the world's cheese
Speaker 4:  consumption.
Speaker 4:  That's it. We're, we're, we're, we're aiming real low, but I think we can
Speaker 4:  do this together as a team.
Speaker 5:  I love it. Alright,
Speaker 4:  That's it. I, we gotta we gotta wrap. We've, we, we've been places on this
Speaker 4:  episode of Birch Cast. Richard, thank you for coming on this journey with
Speaker 4:  us
Speaker 6:  Every time.
Speaker 4:  Please en enjoy the Super Bowl. Stop watching the news for even five minutes.
Speaker 4:  Like heal, heal yourself, root for the team, the
Speaker 4:  right team. You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 5:  If you have big tuby feelings after your first Tuby experience, I
Speaker 5:  sincerely
Speaker 4:  Want to hear about them. Also, If you are in a Comcast service area
Speaker 4:  and you have the Atmos experience, just let me know. How many of your
Speaker 4:  lights lit up? Tell us. I'm dying to know this information.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's it. Happy Super Bowl. That's the B Cha Pro.
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 9:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 9:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 9:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And that's
Speaker 9:  it. We'll see you next week.