# Transcript
ID: 58a36544-d9d8-4a70-8eb8-83c1b150becd
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6261764156788320702/3301823439796085132/s93290-US-5343s-1752227712.mp3
Description: Summer phone season kicks off with Samsung’s latest launch. Jake, Vee, and Allison talk about Samsung’s new lineup of foldables, including the very thin new Z Fold 7 and Allison’s disdain for the Z Flip 7 FE. Vee has impressions of Samsung’s new Galaxy Watch 8 lineup and its squircle-y new redesign. Then, it’s time to talk Big Tech shakeups. Apple’s COO is leaving, Zuckerberg is buying himself an AI dream team, X’s CEO is out — and its chatbot Grok is on a rampage. Finally, big things are in store for the Lightning Round… which shall henceforth be known as the THUNDER ROUND. Lots to talk about, including Lorde’s CD problems, Apple’s Liquid Glass changes, and HBO Max finally becoming HBO Max again.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of everyone you
Speaker 4:  work with. Having a baby at the exact same time and going on
Speaker 4:  parental leave. That is right. Both David Pierce and Neli Patel
Speaker 4:  are at home with newborns. We are so happy for both of them. They're both
Speaker 4:  gonna take some time off, spend time with their families. They'll be back
Speaker 4:  later this year. And in the meantime, you've got me. I'm Jake Kakis,
Speaker 4:  executive editor of The Verge. I'm gonna be joined by an all-star cast from
Speaker 4:  across The Verge every week, starting with two of the best
Speaker 4:  reporters in business. We've got the song, hello
Speaker 4:  and Allison Johnson. Hello. We've got a Lots to talk about today.
Speaker 4:  There were some big executive shakeups at Apple, at Meta
Speaker 4:  at X Rock. Went on a tear called itself Mecca
Speaker 4:  Hitler. I, I believe not good. I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna go on a little bit of a power trip now that Eli's gone. I'm rebranding
Speaker 4:  the lightning round. I love this. The lightning round. I love this is done
Speaker 4:  as we know it. But first we've gotta talk about Samsung. Samsung was the
Speaker 4:  big thing this week. They announced a whole bunch of new phones and smart
Speaker 4:  watches. The two of you were there.
Speaker 4:  But first I just wanna, before we get into this, I wanna read what Samsung
Speaker 4:  said about Brooklyn and his press release. So, so they had their event in
Speaker 4:  Brooklyn, and this is how they described Brooklyn, the
Speaker 4:  borough in New York City. They called it quote, a borough with extraordinary
Speaker 4:  spirit and a distinctive history. Brooklyn is where
Speaker 4:  visionary thinking and bold ideas shape the future. A
Speaker 4:  place known for its culture, creativity, and collaboration.
Speaker 4:  Did you guys get that feeling? Did you feel cultural creativity and collaboration
Speaker 4:  at Samsung's event?
Speaker 5:  No, not really. No. No. I mostly felt angry.
Speaker 6:  Angry, hot, irritated. Yeah. So it was like
Speaker 6:  a gazillion degrees with bajillion humidity. Yeah. On Wednesday
Speaker 6:  when we went to Unpacked, so if you are
Speaker 6:  a New York City native, And I tell you that this was
Speaker 6:  hosted at a couple of warehouses in Brooklyn Navy Yard,
Speaker 6:  you will be groaning at this point in time. But if you're not a New York
Speaker 6:  native or you haven't been to this area of Brooklyn is the most inaccessible
Speaker 6:  area of Brooklyn by public transit. So there's just a line
Speaker 6:  of Ubers trying to get in and very stressed out Uber drivers. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So you know that that was, Hmm, that was something. And then
Speaker 4:  I live in Brooklyn. I do not know how to get to the Navy yard. I like, it's
Speaker 5:  Like that I design, they're not meant to
Speaker 6:  Knows, it's like a mile walk from any public transit station. So
Speaker 6:  you either are gonna make a cha make the choice of taking public transit
Speaker 6:  to this event and having to walk a mile from the closest
Speaker 6:  train station or braving the New York City bus system, which I'm
Speaker 6:  a lifelong New Yorker. And No,
Speaker 6:  or you're gonna take an Uber and like the vast majority of people that I
Speaker 6:  took the, I took an Uber And I think the vast majority of people you were
Speaker 6:  stuck in, you were stuck in traffic. I was
Speaker 5:  For like, I was stuck in Brooklyn trying to get to Brooklyn because they
Speaker 5:  were doing road work outside my hotel. So I was in gridlock
Speaker 5:  for the first, it was just a mess all around. We,
Speaker 6:  We were texting like, are you there yet? Are you there? Oh my God. Like we're,
Speaker 6:  it was, it
Speaker 5:  Was like, it was just getting more and more desperate. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  And so what even is this venue? Like what I
Speaker 6:  Said, Brooklyn Navy Yard is just a Navy yard. It's like a bunch of
Speaker 6:  industrial brick buildings, like shipping container type
Speaker 6:  warehouse buildings, fully metal. So
Speaker 6:  it was just, you know, Samsung branded. There was a lot of Unpacked flags
Speaker 6:  going in there, but it's also a maze. So you can go into the Brooklyn Navy
Speaker 6:  yard, probably have terrible signal and just be like, oh,
Speaker 6:  there's a bunch of just brick buildings with numbers attached to them
Speaker 6:  and you're just hoping the GPS is gonna get you to the right place.
Speaker 6:  And I mean, there were signs and everything and you just had to follow the,
Speaker 6:  the Korean influencers. There was a huge amount of K
Speaker 6:  Korean influencers. And I really, you know, And I was telling Allison this,
Speaker 6:  oh, 'cause you know, Samsung has a history of inviting K-pop
Speaker 6:  stars. So I was like, I did my makeup. I was like, there's an off chance
Speaker 6:  that a K-pop star is gonna come to this event. I love K-Pop.
Speaker 6:  We did not get K-pop stars. We got influencers that look like K-pop
Speaker 6:  stars and the K-pop Demon hunter soundtrack just blasting. And
Speaker 6:  I was like, okay. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, I've heard good things. The,
Speaker 6:  The soundtrack is fire. I love the soundtrack. It was great. That put me
Speaker 6:  in a good mood. But then we were going into the, or I was going into the
Speaker 6:  main, the main green, it's called Dug Greenhouse.
Speaker 6:  This main wear metal container thing that we're going into.
Speaker 6:  And I have my hot box of water because they were being sustainable with the
Speaker 6:  water bottles and they were providing for everyone there. My hot box of water,
Speaker 6:  it was not cold at all, but I was like, I need to hydrate. This is hot, this
Speaker 6:  is humid. I'm not dressed like a Korean demon hunter, grim
Speaker 6:  reaper situation. These influencers, I'm telling you. They were, they went
Speaker 6:  all out. They went all out. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Wait, I'm sorry. The, the influencers were like in cosplay
Speaker 4:  for a phone launch
Speaker 6:  It. They were dressed to the nines. No, no. There was this one guy I pointed
Speaker 6:  him out to, to Allison And I was like, I'm happily married, but look at this
Speaker 6:  man. He had perfectly coed hair. Yeah, I'm fairly certain. He had
Speaker 6:  beautiful, he, I was like, this man has to be wearing some sort of makeup.
Speaker 5:  They were not sweating.
Speaker 6:  They were not sweating somehow. Yeah. But they were like in full like
Speaker 6:  kind of grim reaper regalia, like Korean grim
Speaker 6:  reaper regalia. There was like this one girl and she had like huge
Speaker 6:  heels on and just like this modern handbook, which is like Korean traditional
Speaker 6:  wear. And I was just like, I I, we got some cosplay in house.
Speaker 5:  I was like a sweaty
Speaker 6:  Puddle. Yeah, we, we were, we were there going like, oh my god, what?
Speaker 4:  So you guys did not dress up?
Speaker 6:  We did not dress up. We didn't wear our demon hunter costumes. We didn't
Speaker 6:  at all. I left mine at home. Yeah, yeah. Like we were not aware. But then,
Speaker 6:  you know, we're going into the venue because you tech event, you gotta run
Speaker 6:  to grab a seat. And so I'm trying to get in with my hot box of water
Speaker 6:  and the, the venue guy's like, mam, mam, mam ma'am, no water,
Speaker 6:  no beverages, no food. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  and then we get in and it's super packed full of influencers. So they had
Speaker 6:  their own line and their own badge influencers. And then there's like the
Speaker 6:  media section, And I don't know if you had this Allison, but there was a
Speaker 6:  guy, like there was this guy, he didn't speak any English, but he's obviously
Speaker 6:  Samsung staff and he's just like, media section here. Hmm. You can only sit
Speaker 6:  here. And there were people inside with like little media paddles. And
Speaker 6:  the one media paddle lady I talked to, she's like, if you find a seat, God
Speaker 6:  bless, just take it. And so it was a little bit of a battle
Speaker 6:  to get a seat. There were a bunch of people who didn't. So it was like super
Speaker 6:  packed. The, you know, it was a metal container so the wifi wasn't working
Speaker 6:  And I Oh my God was like, oh my god, how am I supposed to live vlog this
Speaker 6:  with, no, no. I gotta say watching Allison
Speaker 6:  though, she had the Z the previous Z fold and she was
Speaker 6:  blogging from the foldable. I did
Speaker 5:  Quick posts two WordPress from the folding
Speaker 6:  Phone. It was, this is inspiring. It was inspiring.
Speaker 4:  I feel like you broke a law of physics I to, to accomplish this.
Speaker 6:  Probably did. It was just like the entire time just looking at her doing
Speaker 6:  it. And I was like, oh my god. Yeah, Samsung, you don't need this
Speaker 6:  event. Just put a live stream on Allison. You know, I, this is, this
Speaker 6:  is the best ad for a foldable phone you could possibly have.
Speaker 5:  I'd be happy to provide that service. It was, it was, I'm amazed that
Speaker 5:  it worked, but it was inspiring. Yeah. Like hotspotting our
Speaker 5:  computers, so the phones was not working for some reason V couldn't even
Speaker 5:  airdrop a photo from her.
Speaker 6:  I couldn't, I was trying to airdrop computer. I had two phones 'cause I'm
Speaker 6:  be beta testing the iPhones right now. And so I had one with Apple
Speaker 6:  intelligence and one without. And I'm just like trying to airdrop from either
Speaker 6:  phone to my laptop. Just a picture of Allison. It was unreal vlogging on
Speaker 6:  this. It took like, it took 15 minutes. It was really bad.
Speaker 4:  I'm glad you discovered a use four folding phones at the folding phone event.
Speaker 4:  This, this, this is like the big question. I like they, they frigging look
Speaker 4:  awesome. Yeah. And I'm like, I don't know what I'm doing with that inside
Speaker 4:  screen. I just know I want it. Okay, so what do we see on the foldables
Speaker 5:  Front? So we got three new foldables. We have the Z fold
Speaker 5:  seven, the Z flip seven and then the Z flip
Speaker 5:  seven FE, which I continue to forget about,
Speaker 5:  but basics are Z fold seven got super
Speaker 5:  thin. It is 8.9 millimeters thin. It's
Speaker 5:  26% thinner than the Z fold six.
Speaker 5:  It's way lighter. You just, you feel it when you pick it up. The Z flip
Speaker 5:  seven got a bigger screen on the front. That's the
Speaker 5:  clamshell style foldable. And the, the Z
Speaker 5:  flip seven FE exists
Speaker 5:  for 8 99. It's like, it's the affordable version.
Speaker 6:  We live in a world where that's affordable.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. That's my problem with it. So
Speaker 5:  big hardware changes the inner screen's like eight inches now
Speaker 5:  even more room to not know what to do with.
Speaker 5:  But we lost in that process the S pin support,
Speaker 5:  which
Speaker 6:  Too thin I know. So that you can't like stick
Speaker 5:  It in. Yeah, they, well they've never had a good solution for,
Speaker 5:  they were like supported the spen, but you had to buy a special spen
Speaker 5:  because a regular spen would like scratch the screen. Oh my god.
Speaker 5:  And they've never had, like, you could buy a case that would hold the spen,
Speaker 5:  but it's not like the ultra where you can just pop it in.
Speaker 5:  So it's a little bit of like, and they're like, oh, people weren't really
Speaker 5:  using it. We could make the, the screen thinner if we didn't have that digitizer
Speaker 5:  layer. So that's what they did.
Speaker 5:  So I am a moment of silence for, you know, the spen. But
Speaker 5:  other than that it's got a 200 megapixel camera,
Speaker 5:  so it should be pretty capable. They got rid of the,
Speaker 5:  it used to have a, on the inner screen, an
Speaker 5:  under display selfie camera.
Speaker 4:  Actually I think this is so interesting, right? They got, yeah, they got
Speaker 4:  rid of the under display camera. Yeah. And now it's just a regular one. Right.
Speaker 5:  It's just a regular little hole punch. And honestly
Speaker 5:  it seems backwards, but I notice it way less with the
Speaker 5:  hole punch because that under display always had like a weird
Speaker 5:  kind of like rainbow tearing thing that would happen when I would
Speaker 5:  glance at something at that part of the screen. And it looks to me like
Speaker 5:  the, the aura you get when you get a migraine or like an egg. So it
Speaker 5:  like freaks me out. Like that's a me problem. But this,
Speaker 4:  This feels like a good change to me because I feel like for, I don't know,
Speaker 4:  several years companies discovered under display cameras
Speaker 4:  And I, this thing always happens where the tech is kind of
Speaker 4:  bad but it looks a little bit cooler and so a bunch of companies run at it
Speaker 4:  and that felt like what was happening with under display cameras and they
Speaker 4:  were just universally like, meaningfully worse. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  I, maybe it's just me. I don't think the whole punch cutout looks bad. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Same. I think we're used to it.
Speaker 4:  I would so much rather have a whole punch cutout in a good camera than
Speaker 4:  like this cool slight ever so slightly cooler thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like it's in the corner, it's not so gonna cut.
Speaker 6:  I mean it has to function first and foremost. Like I think if you're gonna
Speaker 6:  choose form over function, that's usually not the winning vet. It should
Speaker 6:  be form and function. And if you have to only pick one, it should be function.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's my, my my spiel. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I am, I was glad to see the under display camera go.
Speaker 4:  Okay. This is, this is the first time I've picked this thing up and this
Speaker 4:  is incredible. This thing is,
Speaker 6:  It's so much nicer. Wild.
Speaker 5:  And I do have to do a big caveat that like
Speaker 5:  if you live in a different country that isn't the United States of America,
Speaker 5:  you have access to folding phones that are roughly
Speaker 5:  the size from like honor and oppo. So
Speaker 5:  there's a little bit of the rest of the world being like, okay, you guys
Speaker 5:  finally cut like Samsung finally caught up for you.
Speaker 4:  Well that's sort of only like a this year thing, right? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like, you know, it feels like a ma major
Speaker 4:  turn is happening in folding phones. It's sort of funny, like when this event
Speaker 4:  was coming up, I was like, oh yeah, they're doing another folding phone.
Speaker 4:  What are we on Like, like the, the Z fold three. And it's like, it is the
Speaker 4:  seventh one they've been doing these for coming up on a decade
Speaker 4:  now. Yeah, it's wild. Which is crazy because they have like barely made a
Speaker 4:  dent
Speaker 4:  and you know, Allison, you had a story and you kind of pointed out they really
Speaker 4:  haven't changed much and this year. And I'm thinking
Speaker 4:  maybe even this model feels like the first time they're kind of
Speaker 4:  meaningfully changing and, and it, it's not like a, a
Speaker 4:  major form factor changes. They really just slimed down a little bit.
Speaker 4:  But somehow all it, this feels so
Speaker 6:  Different, feels so much nicer. It does in your hand. Like, 'cause you know,
Speaker 6:  I've never had a folding phone, but I've been to these events all the time
Speaker 6:  And I like play around with them. It doesn't feel heavy. It doesn't
Speaker 6:  feel fragile. It just feels like a phone. Yeah. Which is cool though. The
Speaker 6:  whole thing, like, I don't know if you can see it there. Like it won't sit
Speaker 6:  because of the camera bump being so ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  So that's kind of rough. That's that's rough. But
Speaker 6:  I don't know, maybe it's a good thing. 'cause you put it face down then and
Speaker 6:  then you don't look at the screen.
Speaker 5:  It does encourage me to put it face down and then I don't get Yeah. Caught
Speaker 5:  up in my phone. Yeah. I think it was a year of like, I mean like
Speaker 5:  fold four, five and six were kind of a snoozefest as far as like
Speaker 5:  they added a few millimeters here and they did this to it.
Speaker 5:  And basically the same on the, the flip phone. Like
Speaker 5:  I think maybe the four got the bigger cover
Speaker 5:  screen, but they still, you know, so the flip
Speaker 5:  the clamshell style this year got a full
Speaker 5:  like edge to edge screen on the front cover. And previously it sort of
Speaker 5:  like was this file folder shape that went around the cameras,
Speaker 5:  which was just sort of weird and awkward. It was like, Motorola gives us
Speaker 5:  the whole screen, we're grownups. Like, let us, let us have it.
Speaker 5:  So this did feel like a year where Samsung was like, okay,
Speaker 5:  like here, here's the feedback we've been getting. We're gonna make these
Speaker 5:  bigger moves. And obviously, you know, like a lot
Speaker 5:  of r and d and time goes into making a phone
Speaker 5:  slim like that. I I heard that the, you know, the
Speaker 5:  edge, the Galaxy S 25 Edge really kind
Speaker 5:  of like paved the way for this. Like if wouldn't exist
Speaker 5:  without making the the slim bar phone first.
Speaker 4:  Did people like the edge? I feel like the edge was like despised. No. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Well right, that was one with the curving sides.
Speaker 5:  No, no, no. Well, no,
Speaker 4:  No. There's a thin one.
Speaker 5:  Thin thin one. Okay. Yeah, that is, it's it's the same
Speaker 5:  case of this. You're like, is it really like, am I
Speaker 5:  gonna notice the weight difference? Is it really that slim? You know, you
Speaker 5:  see the specs on paper, you're like, what? What's the big deal? And then
Speaker 5:  you pick it up and you're like, oh, I get it. This, this really is
Speaker 6:  Different. It's very tactile because I, I'll admit to be one of the people
Speaker 6:  that looks at those things and, and I'm just like, whatever. It's thin. Do
Speaker 6:  we not remember exploding batteries? What are you doing? Oh, Samsung
Speaker 5:  Remembers. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Samsung remembers exploding batteries. But then you hold it in your hand
Speaker 6:  and you go like, oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's actually quite nice. It's, it's, it feels kind of funny to
Speaker 6:  say like, oh, you have to hold it or you have to see it. But I think you
Speaker 6:  should. I know. I think you should. And
Speaker 5:  It is true. It's, I'm seeing that a lot this year and it's
Speaker 5:  irritating. So I apologize. It's,
Speaker 4:  Well, it is like, I mean there are probably a couple of things that are,
Speaker 4:  are preventing people from adopting these, like the
Speaker 4:  folding phones, at least this, this sort of fold out style.
Speaker 4:  And one is definitely the size, right? Like this one is, I
Speaker 4:  think about as close as you can get to just a regular
Speaker 4:  phone. I look this up, this is what I,
Speaker 4:  it's it's not even a full millimeter
Speaker 4:  thicker than the iPhone 16 pro. It's, it's like there's a, a
Speaker 4:  very small difference. Yeah. And so it feels like a regular phone, which
Speaker 4:  goes a really long way. But then I think there are like two other things
Speaker 4:  that I, at least like for me, I don't quite get. And one is
Speaker 4:  I love, I I love it. It's freaking cool. Like if you could, if I could trade
Speaker 4:  my phone out for a foldable right now, no problem. But like, I
Speaker 4:  don't, I don't totally know what I would use it for. And then
Speaker 4:  the other part of that is like the price and this one, it
Speaker 4:  is two grand. Is that right? Two grand. Two grand. Yeah. Like that's,
Speaker 4:  that's that is the price of two other phones. Yes. Which it is, it is
Speaker 4:  sort of two phones table together. Budget. Yeah. Four if you're going budget,
Speaker 4:  which, you know, you can do some crazy things if you just, you know, tape
Speaker 4:  a few phones together.
Speaker 6:  I four pixel
Speaker 5:  90. Wild. It's wild. Wild.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I would love to see two phones taped together and see if that would work
Speaker 6:  as
Speaker 5:  Ful, you know. But that's
Speaker 4:  Funny. You know, you might, are you finding it to be useful as a thing as
Speaker 4:  like a tablet? I mean you, I can't believe you live blog in
Speaker 4:  WordPress. This is No,
Speaker 6:  I was trying, oh my god. I was like, I was watching her do it And I was like,
Speaker 6:  should I try doing it on my phone? I could not do it. No. Just because like
Speaker 6:  of all the like little,
Speaker 4:  I can't even log into WordPress on my
Speaker 6:  Phone. It's, it was pretty rough. I was trying to do like, we have Okta,
Speaker 6:  so I was trying to get the Okta code from one phone and putting it on the
Speaker 6:  other phone. And I swear to God I felt like this
Speaker 6:  was the ad that Samsung should have. They should have just been
Speaker 6:  zeroing in on me and Allison and just me being like, oh,
Speaker 6:  what am I doing? My laptop and two phones aren't working. Allison iss
Speaker 6:  just like, cool compose, compose. I'm watching her take a photo and
Speaker 6:  then like, she had Slack on one side and WordPress open
Speaker 6:  on the other side and just checking things. And then like, when she needed
Speaker 6:  to write, like, I'm sorry if I was stalking you watching this, but please,
Speaker 6:  I was just like mesmerized as watching her do this And I was like, oh my
Speaker 6:  God, this is the first time I've actually understood why I might want a foldable,
Speaker 6:  I want a fold foldable phone. I don't know, maybe could this be a work expense?
Speaker 6:  Like could we just have like foldable phones for, for, for live blocking?
Speaker 6:  I was like, oh, I
Speaker 5:  Approve that you didn't get the memo. I decided we can all have a
Speaker 6:  Photoable phone. Okay, cool. That
Speaker 4:  Also, Hey Jake. Okay great. That's what I think. I think so I'll just, let
Speaker 4:  me just check with a couple
Speaker 6:  People
Speaker 4:  That really fast. I Eli's gone like, who's gonna stop
Speaker 4:  us? There's no rules now that I think about charge Jake. So there are no
Speaker 4:  rules. No, don't. If it's a responsibility's on me, then I have a problem.
Speaker 4:  We do need to, to start expensing stuff before new life's back though. That's,
Speaker 4:  yeah. That's what's important. This is really like, it is
Speaker 4:  true. You see this one and you go, okay, like this. Listen, we're
Speaker 4:  the reasons we're all here is because we have a problem of looking at gadgets
Speaker 4:  and going on. I Yeah. But like the, you know, this is
Speaker 4:  the first foldable where I've really been like, that's a problem
Speaker 4:  that like, it looks great. The, okay, that
Speaker 4:  being said, like the foldables that I see out in public
Speaker 4:  nine times outta 10, it is the clamshell style. Yeah. Yeah. Which I
Speaker 4:  feel a lot more popular than, than
Speaker 4:  I, I I don't know. I would imagine they would be. Yeah, I
Speaker 6:  Just think they're familiar. Right? 'cause we all, well maybe not all of
Speaker 6:  us. There might be Jins who didn't have the flip phones from back in the
Speaker 6:  day, but I feel like a certain nostalgia with the, the flip. Yeah. Also the
Speaker 6:  flip is just really cute. It's like you look at in person, you're like, oh
Speaker 6:  my God, this is so cute. And even with the Marola phones, you just go, oh
Speaker 6:  cool. And then when it folds open, it's a form factor you're used to using.
Speaker 6:  It's the same thing. Whereas with the, with the fold open like a tablet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean I think tablets as a device even, I'm not sure what to
Speaker 6:  do with my iPad half the time.
Speaker 5:  Same. Yeah. I think that's
Speaker 6:  The Yeah, I think that's the, the, the prob the quote unquote problem with
Speaker 6:  the tablets. Yeah. Oh. If you watch KDRs, there's always just a random
Speaker 6:  person who shouldn't be able to like, afford foldable. Just going like,
Speaker 6:  oh, let me have my foldable and use it in this way. Because Samsung,
Speaker 6:  I mean Samsung runs Korea. So like, they're just like, here we go, we're
Speaker 6:  gonna put foldables and random K dramas. And I, whenever it pops
Speaker 6:  up, I'm like, I I That's not believable. Samsung. Yeah. This is the poor
Speaker 6:  girl being courted by the rich guy. How does she have a foldable phone?
Speaker 5:  Well, she could buy the FE flip phone. I
Speaker 5:  love that segue. Which 8 99 instead of ten ninety nine?
Speaker 5:  No, the the flip phones. I think you're right. It is a really familiar form
Speaker 5:  factor. They are a little less expensive. Like a thousand dollars
Speaker 5:  is what a phone costs. So you're, you're not making that leap to like, I'm
Speaker 5:  buying two phones And I think the use cases are a little more like
Speaker 5:  immediate. Like you prop it up, you take a selfie with
Speaker 5:  the, the main camera that doesn't suck. And like you get
Speaker 5:  that immediately. And I love 'em. Like I
Speaker 5:  run apps on the front. I'm like starting my little Strava
Speaker 5:  cycling rides. I, you know, check the bus schedule.
Speaker 5:  I do all kinds of things on the flip phone
Speaker 4:  Really quickly. I just wanna ask, why do you hate the FE so much?
Speaker 5:  It's just, okay, I
Speaker 6:  Keep,
Speaker 5:  I keep forgetting about it because this is a two phone event. You know, we
Speaker 5:  have a flip and a fold, but it's also like
Speaker 5:  8 99 is not that much cheaper, you know? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Is it just last year's phone? Like it's
Speaker 5:  Like, pretty much, yeah. Yeah. I think they, they maybe like rearrange some
Speaker 5:  parts, but yeah, I'm like, okay, so you can buy last year's phone for
Speaker 5:  eight ninety nine. Motorola sells one for 6 99. Yeah, that's, come
Speaker 5:  on. That's
Speaker 4:  Okay. Okay. So then they did the phones then whole bunch of watches.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Alright. What do we see from Samsung on the watches front?
Speaker 6:  So we saw a, the Galaxy Watch eight series,
Speaker 6:  which includes the Base Galaxy Watch eight and the Galaxy Watch eight classic
Speaker 6:  and an extremely minorly updated Galaxy Watch Ultra,
Speaker 6:  basically Squirl are everywhere. Huge redesign. And
Speaker 6:  then Gemini is on the wrist now thanks to wear OS six. And there's
Speaker 6:  a bunch of new health features. The, I think the big marquee one that they
Speaker 6:  played up a bit was a running coach. It, it's just a running
Speaker 6:  coach. You take a 12 minute run test and it grades you and then
Speaker 6:  creates an AI generated program for you. And then the antioxidant
Speaker 6:  index, which is their foray into nutrition and kind of telling
Speaker 6:  you, are you eating healthily? You probably know
Speaker 6:  the answer to that already. And then, you know, there was a bit of a price
Speaker 6:  bump. So the eight got about $50 more
Speaker 6:  expensive and the starting price. And the classic unfortunately is about
Speaker 6:  a hundred dollars more at 4 99. So the ultra
Speaker 6:  stayed the same, which is good news because it literally got a new color
Speaker 6:  and a storage bump. So that's it. That's the Squircle squad.
Speaker 4:  It's a total redesign. Right?
Speaker 6:  Total redesign. So Samsung has always been known for these circular
Speaker 6:  watches, which stand in complete contrast to the Apple
Speaker 6:  watches, which, you know, I mean, I got it right here, right? So like the
Speaker 6:  Apple watch is squareish and then we have this, which is
Speaker 4:  Confusing. Confusing.
Speaker 6:  This
Speaker 4:  Is what I would say. I'm looking at it And I don't know what shape I'm seeing.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 6:  You are seeing a squirkle my friend because the, the
Speaker 4:  The the the, they couldn't decide and they did both. They
Speaker 6:  Couldn't decide they did it both. This is the circle watch face on
Speaker 6:  a square, what they're calling it is a cushion, it's a square
Speaker 6:  cushion. Mm. And they have three reasons for that. Three reasons.
Speaker 6:  One is that it allows the, the watch to sit flatter on your
Speaker 6:  wrist. So better contact with the sensor underneath. Two,
Speaker 6:  it allows it to be thinner. So this is supposedly eight 11%
Speaker 6:  thinner than last year's. And then three, you can house
Speaker 6:  a slightly bigger battery inside and don't get too excited. It's like we're
Speaker 6:  talking like 10, 10 milliamp hour more, or
Speaker 6:  like somewhere between 10 and 20 is what, 'cause I was going through the
Speaker 6:  spec sheet and looking And I was like, oh, that, that's like an extra hour
Speaker 6:  maybe of battery life that we're looking at n nothing too special
Speaker 6:  there. So yeah. Squi goals, I think, I mean
Speaker 6:  based on on the comments that I've seen from people already, a lot of people
Speaker 6:  hate it. Okay.
Speaker 4:  I watched your video yesterday And I was like convincing my,
Speaker 4:  I was try, I was trying to gear, I was like, you know what, maybe I like
Speaker 4:  this. Maybe this is cool. I mean I was like, I'm gonna come in and I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  be the positive one and now I'm seeing it in person And I cannot do it. It
Speaker 4:  is not,
Speaker 6:  That's not great because I think this is the best looking of the Squirkle
Speaker 6:  watches. No, because it's slightly no. Well this one or the classic
Speaker 6:  because on the classic they have the rotating bezel. So
Speaker 6:  I love the rotating bezel. It is such a storied part of the Samsung
Speaker 6:  watch design because it'll, you know, it rotates and it's so satisfying.
Speaker 6:  It's so cliquey and like when you think about going through menus, you're
Speaker 6:  not touching the screen with your grubby finger oils. So it's, it's actually
Speaker 6:  quite nice. This is the base.
Speaker 4:  It was it, the hardware looks really polished.
Speaker 6:  It does look
Speaker 4:  Really polished. It, it, it's the design. I'm gonna put question mark this
Speaker 4:  question
Speaker 6:  Mark this, this is the sleek ITT looking of them. And when I had all of them
Speaker 6:  in person And I had like the comparison to the last six
Speaker 6:  classic and looking at them I was like, okay, you know, I dunno, I don't
Speaker 6:  think it's Stockholm syndrome. 'cause I had Allison try it on and she was
Speaker 6:  like, yes, it does sit flatter and it it is more comfortable. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  okay. I could, it's not so egregious. But I still think that the
Speaker 6:  ultra, which they, they basically took this design idea from the
Speaker 6:  ultra, it's Ogo. It's
Speaker 4:  Fogo Ogo. Yeah. It's really
Speaker 6:  Big. It's really big. Like, not this one, but like when you, when I put the
Speaker 6:  Ultra on Owen, our video guy was like, wow, you could
Speaker 6:  drive a truck through those lugs gaps. 'cause like here you don't really
Speaker 6:  see the lug gaps on my tiny little wrist. But on the ultra,
Speaker 6:  I, I think last year I tested And I could stick three chopsticks in the gaps.
Speaker 6:  So like six total too many. It's, it's, it's too many chops.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, it's a lot. I don't feel Stockholm
Speaker 6:  syndromed by this one. I think I could get to.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. That's, it's,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's,
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, I think it's confusing because you look at it and you're like,
Speaker 4:  wow, that's a really well made confusing shape. It's
Speaker 4:  like it's, it is like, they did a great job. I just don't know
Speaker 4:  what they did.
Speaker 6:  I think it looks best on this one because it still maintains like a thin,
Speaker 6:  sleek look on the classic. It's just like,
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm swayed by the rotating bezel. At least that's still there. And on
Speaker 6:  the ultra, I, I still can't, the ultra,
Speaker 6:  like I still can't, the blue color does make it look slightly
Speaker 6:  better.
Speaker 4:  But did the ultra, there's no, it's just, it's just like a processor bump.
Speaker 4:  What what's,
Speaker 6:  Oh, not even a processor bump. This, this is what you get. It's blue.
Speaker 4:  It's blue. Mm.
Speaker 6:  And double the storage.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That's okay.
Speaker 6:  That's my main concern on a watch.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So you can have more songs on there and apps I guess.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, double the storage. The classic, the only hardware
Speaker 6:  updates on the classic is that it gets the ultra's third quick button,
Speaker 6:  which is like a thing that you can use to launch an
Speaker 6:  extra shortcut or something on that. And then all of the watches have a new
Speaker 6:  lug system, which I know everybody loves a new lug system for easier
Speaker 6:  swapping.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's always good when the lugs change.
Speaker 6:  Oh, not, not always. Yes. 'cause like I do have a bunch of readers going,
Speaker 6:  well there goes the investment I had and all of these
Speaker 6:  straps. Mm. And which is why I say be careful with
Speaker 6:  how many straps you invest in and from where because yeah. Don't fall in
Speaker 6:  love with the strap. Don't fall in love with the straps too much. Because
Speaker 6:  a lot of times they will change these designs and the lug systems and then
Speaker 6:  you're stuck with straps that can't be carried forward.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I wanna ask you about something else. I saw that there is an
Speaker 4:  antioxidant. Oh boy
Speaker 6:  Sensor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, every year, like a
Speaker 4:  new sensor is added to smartwatches. And first I go, that's crazy.
Speaker 4:  I didn't know we could measure that. Like on the skin.
Speaker 4:  Antioxidants are on your s like through I I didn't know that. The next
Speaker 4:  thing I go is, I don't know what to do with that. Like, that sounds so
Speaker 4:  cool. And I don't know what,
Speaker 6:  Okay, so like here's
Speaker 4:  V's are the runners psyched for this?
Speaker 6:  No, here's v's. Runner. No, not runner, but here's
Speaker 6:  v's. Health tech soapbox. So is it very
Speaker 6:  cool that, so they introduced this new bioactive sensor last year, which
Speaker 6:  has a bunch of different colors of LEDs. Normally it's red, infrared and
Speaker 6:  green. But this one has stuff like purple, yellow, blue. And that's supposed
Speaker 6:  to enable like new things. So the way the
Speaker 6:  antioxidant thing works is that it uses a combination of
Speaker 6:  a few of the sensors, I think like blue, yellow, maybe another one.
Speaker 6:  And you actually have to take the watch off for this, this
Speaker 6:  pass feature to work pass pass. Already. You have to take the watch off and
Speaker 6:  you put your, your little thumb on it and then it, it reads the
Speaker 6:  carotenoid levels in your skin. And carotenoids are a type of
Speaker 6:  pigment basically that are, it's a type of antioxidant pigment in
Speaker 6:  like betacarotene. It makes plants like
Speaker 6:  orange. That's the thing in carrots that make 'em orange. It's the thing
Speaker 6:  that makes bell peppers like red and yellow. And
Speaker 6:  so when you eat, they get into your skin, you know, if you have too much
Speaker 6:  carrots you might turn orange. So it's picking up the
Speaker 6:  carotinoids in that. And you know, I'm, I'm there in this
Speaker 6:  round table with the Samsung execs talking about it. And in my head I'm going,
Speaker 6:  okay, well what if you eat berries because
Speaker 6:  berries don't have carotinoids in them but they have antioxidants and they're
Speaker 6:  very good for you. Are they, is that gonna show up in your thing? Because
Speaker 6:  I went And I did the demo and it said I had very low antioxidants And I was
Speaker 6:  like, that doesn't make any sense. I had so many berries over the weekend.
Speaker 6:  It's 'cause there's no carotinoids or like very low levels of OIDs in
Speaker 6:  there. And because it's reading it from your skin, it could take as many
Speaker 6:  as a couple, like two weeks for it to actually show up. So
Speaker 6:  fundamentally what this thing is doing is saying, are you eating
Speaker 6:  enough fruits and veggies? You already know the answer.
Speaker 4:  If they had to advertise this as a carrot sensor, I would've been
Speaker 4:  so much more excited. Like, let it be dumb, let it be
Speaker 4:  silly. Let it be unimportant. As of like right now, all the smart watchers,
Speaker 4:  they just keep adding sensors that and then being like, we don't know what
Speaker 4:  to do with them. Here they are, here here's
Speaker 6:  More quantified data free.
Speaker 4:  If they had just said carrot sensor, great. Like, everyone would be like,
Speaker 4:  cool. This like the, it works as functioned. We, we,
Speaker 4:  first off, I need you to test this. I will,
Speaker 6:  I need you to,
Speaker 4:  I I'll be testing a lot of carrots.
Speaker 6:  You test it on a carrot.
Speaker 4:  What is, oh my god.
Speaker 6:  What will happen? I'll try. Okay. We'll see what happens. I'll just like
Speaker 6:  smush a carrot into the sensor. That's, that's a thing I'm gonna do.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, so my, my main beef with this is that we all
Speaker 6:  generally know that you should eat more fruits and vegetables. And so all
Speaker 6:  this is telling you is whether or not you're eating fruits and vegetables
Speaker 6:  to an adequate amount. And I think we all deeply know in our hearts whether
Speaker 6:  we are so, I mean they were saying that
Speaker 6:  fevers or drinking alcoholic drinks could cause your score to lower
Speaker 6:  well, you know, that fevers and alcoholic drinks are, you know,
Speaker 6:  going to maybe cause your data to dip. Like, whoa, wow.
Speaker 6:  Wow. Thanks, thanks.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think some people might enjoy it and find it useful. But
Speaker 6:  I'm sort of like a duh
Speaker 4:  Quiles antioxidants, I would, I'm gonna say
Speaker 4:  confusing year for, for the smart watch line. General. General and general.
Speaker 4:  Okay. They have
Speaker 6:  Gemini Geminis on there, which I still think will confuse people because
Speaker 6:  it's replacing Google Assistant on the watches.
Speaker 6:  And you know, you have generative AI on your watch.
Speaker 6:  What are you gonna do with generative AI on your watch?
Speaker 6:  Samsung is very like focused on diets basically. 'cause the
Speaker 6:  examples they were giving me were like start a run for, for
Speaker 6:  exactly the number of calories in a slice of pizza. And I was like, that's
Speaker 6:  diabolical. Why,
Speaker 4:  Why does it have access to your health data?
Speaker 6:  Theoretically? Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is theoretically
Speaker 6:  Yes. So it it
Speaker 4:  Could, it could,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I like, from what I can tell the Gemini aspect of it is that
Speaker 6:  it can handle more complex queries that might require multiple apps in a
Speaker 6:  sequential order. Mm. So you can say something like, find
Speaker 6:  the coolest coffee shop near here and message the
Speaker 6:  location to Allison and it'll do that directly from the wrist. I like that
Speaker 6:  provided that you are logged into all the relevant apps. Because
Speaker 6:  in the demo space I was trying it like away from the, the people who had
Speaker 6:  the guardrail demos where it would be guaranteed to work. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  hey, there's a little one with Gemini, let me see if it works. And it
Speaker 6:  was like, well you're gonna have to log into YouTube music to make this playlist.
Speaker 6:  And I, it was like, oh, okay. So you have to log into a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 4:  You know, that reminds me of what Apple's Craig Federici said. He
Speaker 4:  was talking to Joanna Stern from the Wall Street Journal and she asked him
Speaker 4:  about OpenAI buying io, which is Johnny Ives
Speaker 4:  new hardware startup. And you know, they're working on some sort
Speaker 4:  of AI device and Joanna's like, well what do you got? And Craig
Speaker 4:  go says, Hey, I think we have a really personal device already.
Speaker 4:  And he is like, you know, pointing to the Apple watch. And So there is something
Speaker 4:  there, right where Apple is sort of pointing to actually the trajectory for
Speaker 4:  AI is wearable and Samsung is, you know,
Speaker 4:  big asterisk but like, maybe, maybe getting there first
Speaker 6:  Sort of Yes. Sort of, sort of getting there first. Yeah. I've gotten a few
Speaker 6:  demos. So I got a demo with Google earlier this week as well for, And I was
Speaker 6:  just like, gimme ideas for what? And I would love if our listeners also had
Speaker 6:  ideas to Yeah. To send me, because it's such a fundamental
Speaker 6:  difference in thinking like writing AI prompts, you're kind of teaching
Speaker 6:  your brain to have a different language and putting it on
Speaker 6:  the wrist when your muscle memory is so strong to just like, oh, I need to
Speaker 6:  look up a thing. Lemme just grab my phone. So now you're teaching yourself
Speaker 6:  a different muscle memory or like, I'm not gonna grab my phone, I'll just
Speaker 6:  ask it on my watch. When would I do that? Versus
Speaker 6:  just pulling out my phone, which is faster. And so
Speaker 6:  I think that's gonna be an, an interesting tension to kind of work with
Speaker 6:  while I review it. But I, I'm, I'm not saying it's gonna be bad,
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna say I'm, I think, I don't know
Speaker 6:  personally how it's going to work for me yet. And like what part of the
Speaker 6:  generative features Yeah. Will be most useful. So
Speaker 6:  we'll see.
Speaker 5:  Do you, do you talk to AI or do you like to type more? I
Speaker 6:  Like to type, so like my thing Yeah. Is like, and you know, it's different
Speaker 6:  for different people. I know low and blind vision people really value the
Speaker 6:  voice aspect of it. But for me, I don't want people hearing, I
Speaker 5:  Know my stupid questions. It's embarrassing. I
Speaker 6:  Have some very stupid
Speaker 5:  Questions. I don't even wanna hear it myself. I would rather just keep it
Speaker 6:  Quiet. Yeah. And like the thing about Gemini that they're saying is that
Speaker 6:  it's natural language, but then now I have to undo my muscle
Speaker 6:  memory of how I talk to assistant. Because when you talk to assistant, it's
Speaker 6:  like, hey, And I'm not gonna say the wake word because we've had enough
Speaker 6:  of our listeners say, you said the wake word. So like, hey
Speaker 6:  AI assistant
Speaker 6:  send message and then you have to dictate it. Yeah. So like, I think
Speaker 6:  one of the things that you're supposed to be able to do is like, be like,
Speaker 6:  oh, I'm late. Can you send a message to this person telling them I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  be late and make the tone polite or apologetic and that's
Speaker 6:  a thing that you can do and it'll just write the message for you and you
Speaker 6:  don't have to dictate it. And I'm like, cool. But I'm
Speaker 6:  kind of used to dictating it. So it, it's really,
Speaker 6:  I I I think people are just gonna have to be open to changing
Speaker 6:  their muscle, like memory and then changing muscle memory is really difficult
Speaker 6:  to do. So I think that's the, the big challenge with Gemini on the wrist.
Speaker 4:  That's real. Okay. There's one other Samsung thing that was like
Speaker 4:  around the event, but not, I believe it was not at the event, which is
Speaker 4:  there was a big leak that they're having a, a tri-fold foldable.
Speaker 4:  And they did, they, they didn't say anything about this? No,
Speaker 5:  Not a thing. And I was ready for it because she was, they've done,
Speaker 5:  here's what I wanna see. They've done kind of a one more thing. But I guess
Speaker 5:  that was at the January unpack. 'cause they did it for the ring, they did
Speaker 5:  it for the edge.
Speaker 5:  I was like,
Speaker 6:  They were wrapping, they were wrapping up and Allison just has her thing
Speaker 6:  up and she goes like, I don't believe you is
Speaker 5:  What she says. I know. I was like, you can't fool me tm.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, they fooled me. Okay. There was no,
Speaker 4:  So there's, there's more to come in in Samsung foldables. It's potentially
Speaker 4:  even this year it sounds like.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. It sounds like they told
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. There were a bunch of really big
Speaker 4:  executive changes this week at Apple, at Meta
Speaker 4:  at x gr went absolutely off the rails, Lots to talk
Speaker 4:  about. I wanna start with Apple where their COO Jeff Williams
Speaker 4:  announced plans to retire. This is really
Speaker 4:  interesting because Jeff Williams was, I guess until
Speaker 4:  Tuesday,
Speaker 4:  you know, one of the leading people who was seen as a
Speaker 4:  possible Tim Cook successor if it came to that. Right. And
Speaker 4:  I think this is happening in like the most Apple way possible, right? It's
Speaker 4:  a long, slow thing.
Speaker 6:  I mean, does Apple do anything quickly? I don't think so. They're very
Speaker 6:  intentional about everything, right? So yeah, no, but Jeff Williams,
Speaker 6:  he's always in those like big presentations at the
Speaker 6:  iPhone event. Like he's one of those FE he's maybe not
Speaker 6:  Craig Feig Federighi where he has his own hair meme at this point
Speaker 6:  where you go to dub dub and they're referencing his hair and, and the filmed
Speaker 6:  parts. But he's, he's pretty well known if you're into Apple. So that's a
Speaker 6:  big one. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I think like as C-O-O-C-O-O is one of those,
Speaker 4:  I think quieter but actually mission critical positions. Yeah. At Apple.
Speaker 4:  Like Apple is, in many ways it is a supply chain company,
Speaker 4:  right? Like Tim Cook was the COO before he was
Speaker 4:  C-O-C-E-O. And I think he has in many ways
Speaker 4:  reshaped apple around that role, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Every single product is, you know, how do we make sure there
Speaker 4:  are exactly three versions that we are optimizing the parts and we're using
Speaker 4:  what came last. And, you know, it makes sense
Speaker 4:  that they would've seen Jeff as the possible next guy. And I
Speaker 4:  think like the, the going, you know, speculation from what I've
Speaker 4:  seen is that perhaps Jeff Williams is a
Speaker 4:  little, little too old, right? He was 62.
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook is 64. And so if Tim Cook is going to step down
Speaker 4:  at some point, I mean, I don't know. He could, he could Berkshire ha
Speaker 4:  Hathaway this and like, you know, stick around like Warren Buffet until he
Speaker 4:  is like in his nineties, which like, you know, if you're a shareholder,
Speaker 6:  I mean Tim Cook is secretly sw like,
Speaker 4:  Is he, is he,
Speaker 6:  He's secret there. If you look up the Slate article from the past, it's like,
Speaker 6:  it's an investigation into how SW Tim Cook is. He's very
Speaker 6:  swol. He like famously exercises a lot. Like, oh my God, he, a lot of the
Speaker 6:  Apple Watch stuff and the health stuff is because Tim Cook is like super
Speaker 6:  into that stuff. So I don't know. He doesn't look like
Speaker 6:  he's aged. No. Do,
Speaker 4:  Do we know his workout regimen?
Speaker 6:  I think he wakes up at like 4:00 AM and works out like he's, I don't know
Speaker 6:  the exact of it, but if you look real close and Zoom, he's very modest
Speaker 6:  in his, his attire. But if you zoom in on those biceps,
Speaker 6:  I am a believer that Tim Cook is swollen. So he
Speaker 6:  could be, he could be, he could be good for a while.
Speaker 4:  He's good for Okay. He's sticking around. Think he's good for a while. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 6:  He's a healthy dude. How SW was Jeff Williams? You
Speaker 6:  know, honestly, no, no slate articles. No slate articles
Speaker 6:  investigating Jeff Williams'. Unknown level of swollenness. Yeah, no, that
Speaker 6:  is one of my favorite articles though is Tim k sw. I come back to it every
Speaker 6:  once in a while just 'cause the beat I'm on. And also because when I see
Speaker 6:  him every year I'm like zooming in with my eyes and just going like,
Speaker 6:  yeah, no, I think, I think he's sws real swollen.
Speaker 4:  Okay, so, well I guess now I know why, why Jeff was passed over. I mean,
Speaker 4:  you right, this, this is what one assumes if you don't retire. If, if
Speaker 4:  they're like, hey, you might be CEO soon, right? Yeah, yeah. I, it
Speaker 4:  it, to be clear, like it's not like there is a rumor that, that Tim Cook's
Speaker 4:  retirement is imminent, but like, you know, he's, he's been doing it since
Speaker 4:  2012. It's a long time. It's a long time long run.
Speaker 4:  And I think Apple, you know, because they move so carefully,
Speaker 4:  surely they're, they're planning this in the background. So their new guy,
Speaker 4:  they're bringing in Sabi Khan who cook
Speaker 4:  called one of the central architects of Apple's supply chain. Like they're
Speaker 4:  clearly trying to be like, nothing's changing, we're all good, everything
Speaker 4:  is safe, it's in safe hands, right? He's,
Speaker 4:  you know, this guy again has been, he's, he joined Apple in 1995. Jesus.
Speaker 4:  So right. This is like, this is a, a still a jobs era guy
Speaker 4:  who they're bringing in.
Speaker 6:  I mean, supply chain stuff is really important right now with like the, the,
Speaker 6:  the ever looming tariff situation going on. And
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I think you have Apple fans who are kind of
Speaker 6:  split into romanticizing the jobs era and like the vision of it all the,
Speaker 6:  the jobs and Joni I vision of it all. And then you have other people who
Speaker 6:  are like, nah, Tim cook's a guy who gets it done. Mm. And like he's a
Speaker 6:  guy who knows supply chains and that stuff's boring, but that's what makes
Speaker 6:  money. So I think having SoCon there,
Speaker 6:  it just feels stable at a time where supply chain is a thing that
Speaker 6:  we think about and something that investors are super invested in
Speaker 6:  is having a stable supply chain. So I think that
Speaker 6:  is a signal there too.
Speaker 4:  The, the Trump and tariff stuff feels like part of this too, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like they are, they're actually, this thing has been running very smoothly
Speaker 4:  for a very long time. And now Trump is saying, Hey, tariffs
Speaker 4:  on everything. And so Apple is scrambling to move things around.
Speaker 4:  Supply chain is actually more important than ever.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of work to do. If you're Jeff Williams, eh, maybe
Speaker 4:  this is a good time.
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 4:  Was a good, you
Speaker 6:  Know, it's like a cat and mouse game, right? Because they're like, ah, tariff
Speaker 6:  on new country and apple's like, haha, we moved to this other country. And
Speaker 6:  then they'll go, ah ha tear on that country. And apple's like, haha, we'll
Speaker 6:  move to this other country. Or like, that's what it seems. They'll find a
Speaker 6:  way like it's been happen. They'll find a way. And so they need, they need
Speaker 6:  a supply chain guy to know what country to move the factory to. So they love
Speaker 6:  a supply chain guy. Yeah. They love a supply
Speaker 4:  Chain guy. Yeah. Okay. They, they do love a supply chain guy, which, which
Speaker 4:  I think is interesting because, you know, the, the going rumors
Speaker 4:  of who, who might succeed cook again like some
Speaker 4:  years out whenever this happens, I believe it's, it's Mark Germond at
Speaker 4:  Bloomberg says that John Turn, who's their hardware
Speaker 4:  guy, is the leading contender right now.
Speaker 4:  Which is very interesting, right? That, that feels to me
Speaker 4:  like there's potentially a very different shift in a world where he's
Speaker 4:  leading it because Tim Cook, at least like my read on it, is that he is not
Speaker 4:  a product guy in the way that jobs was and probably not a product guy in
Speaker 4:  the way that turn is.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And arguably that's what Apple needs too, because
Speaker 6:  we're at a point where, I think I was talking about this with Todd, our reviews
Speaker 6:  editor, WD editor where the iPhone is
Speaker 6:  like, what, 17 years old? There are people who can vote and fight
Speaker 6:  for our country who don't remember a world without iPhones. So it's like
Speaker 6:  not a new product or technology anymore.
Speaker 6:  So I think, you know, with the AI hype, everybody's looking to what's next.
Speaker 6:  Maybe you want a hardware guy in there who can really shape what
Speaker 6:  the next vision of that's gonna be. So maybe if you think about
Speaker 6:  vision versus maintenance, maybe it's like a thought process
Speaker 6:  with Turn is going back from maintenance to vision again and doing
Speaker 6:  the stuff that made Apple splashy to begin with. Who knows, I'm not a,
Speaker 6:  I'm not a business forecaster. I don't have like a crystal ball, but I think
Speaker 6:  that's maybe something that TUR has. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And the didn't they change, like the design team now
Speaker 5:  reports directly to Tim Cook too. Yeah. So I don't know
Speaker 5:  if if those things are related, but it would make it kind of sense to have
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  Like Tim Cook is also surprisingly into sneakers.
Speaker 6:  So like, you know,
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook is a hype beast. Is this where we're we're headed? Oh my God, he's
Speaker 4:  full, he's a hype. He's
Speaker 6:  Full and
Speaker 4:  He has like, oh my god,
Speaker 6:  Stone designer like sneakers, a couple of conferences back and like, it was
Speaker 6:  in the Hype Beast article about how he had these like special, I, I believe
Speaker 6:  it was Mikey. And so I, you know, on the face of it,
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook ha has his uniform. You wouldn't
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Keeg him as like the design guy. But he, he's into sneakers
Speaker 6:  and he swol
Speaker 5:  So maybe they're, yeah, maybe they're making some sneakers.
Speaker 6:  Maybe there's multitudes to cook that we haven't, like Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook, Tim Cook is gonna retire from Apple Takeover
Speaker 4:  Supreme. Yeah. And have a have a like whole second
Speaker 4:  career after this. I love
Speaker 6:  It. I I believe it. You're you're hearing it now, Tim, you have,
Speaker 4:  You do a hard pivot. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. He's gonna be, he's just gonna be on the board of Gentle Monster,
Speaker 6:  which that's sunglass company from Korea with like the really interesting
Speaker 6:  silhouettes. He's just gonna, he's gonna be a fashion icon.
Speaker 4:  I I would love this, I love this, love this. I really want, like Cook is
Speaker 4:  the driest executive, like in public and if
Speaker 4:  like, you know, steps out and is like, I'm gonna live a different life now.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  I, oh, there's like a quiet,
Speaker 4:  He's earned it.
Speaker 6:  A quiet fired Tim Cook. This is my fantasy
Speaker 5:  Quiet fire.
Speaker 6:  My
Speaker 4:  Gosh. So the next big piece of corporate changeup happened
Speaker 4:  last week while we were off, which is that Mark Zuckerberg finally
Speaker 4:  announced his big AI superintelligence
Speaker 4:  group. This is like, it is a super group of AI
Speaker 4:  researchers, which I wanna, may I think, I think sounds cool
Speaker 4:  when you put it that way.
Speaker 6:  Does it, it also could sound like, yeah, the AI Avengers,
Speaker 6:  but it is,
Speaker 4:  It's the AI of he should
Speaker 5:  Have Oh no, that's terrifying.
Speaker 6:  AI Avengers, the AI
Speaker 4:  Avengers and famously when the Avengers created ai, it went well, right?
Speaker 6:  Oh, there it's not, that's not totally the plot of Ultron. That's not
Speaker 6:  Hmm. You know, famed beloved, critically acclaimed
Speaker 6:  Avengers movie Ultron that everyone loved. I didn't know that.
Speaker 6:  That they didn't, they didn't. They they hate that movie.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  Didn't know that was a movie. You know what, that's, that's the correct,
Speaker 4:  It's it's all right. It's all right. They made a, yeah, so
Speaker 4:  this is, this is weird. This is a little wild. Like Zuck is sort
Speaker 4:  of just like power tripping here. And first he
Speaker 4:  paid $14 billion to buy half
Speaker 4:  of scale ai, which is mostly, it appears that he can
Speaker 4:  hire their CEO, Alexander Wang
Speaker 4:  Wang is becoming meta's chief AI officer. Sure.
Speaker 4:  And then he's just paying out hundreds of millions of dollars
Speaker 4:  to individual researchers. He's just going around to every
Speaker 4:  AI lab, OpenAI, Google Anthropic, and
Speaker 4:  giving people these incredible offers that, that just
Speaker 4:  like bogle the mind that you would pay somebody this much to convince them
Speaker 4:  to come over, which tells you two things. Number one,
Speaker 4:  it is hard to convince people to come work at Meta, right? Yeah, yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  that is Hayden Field. Our AI reporter just ran a story where
Speaker 4:  she talked to some people who got some of these offers and the thing they
Speaker 4:  told her was, yeah, we care about the
Speaker 4:  mission, which is why we're staying at, you know, the ones who
Speaker 4:  turn this down don't want to go to Meta and have to do whatever they
Speaker 4:  want us to do. Oh
Speaker 6:  Boy.
Speaker 4:  Oh, you know, you're, they're gonna get paid. Okay. Anywhere.
Speaker 4:  But I Zuck is just spending boatloads of
Speaker 4:  cash to build this, you know, huge team of
Speaker 4:  super capable researchers, right? He's got the, the former CEO of GitHub,
Speaker 4:  he's got a, a co-founder and the former CEO of Safe
Speaker 4:  superintelligence. He got people from Anthropic, from Sesame.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's all over the place. And these dollar figures are
Speaker 4:  mind-boggling. And what's really interesting is like, okay, okay,
Speaker 4:  I get it. So you now have one of the most capable AI leadership
Speaker 4:  teams in the, in the world.
Speaker 4:  The idea is you'll go and build some sort of fancy AI
Speaker 4:  thing, superintelligence, whatever you wanna call it with that. But, but
Speaker 4:  there is sort of a question, right? Like the technology exists,
Speaker 4:  or much of it does, people are building it. Is it these specific people?
Speaker 4:  Or, or like, are they, do you just buy the people and therefore you get the
Speaker 4:  good ai?
Speaker 6:  I mean, that's obviously what his, his strategy is. He's
Speaker 6:  just throwing money around. He's just like, I've got money. Come work for
Speaker 6:  me, do the thing. And I think he's getting thrifted on some level
Speaker 6:  because I no hate to any of these people getting these,
Speaker 6:  what, $300 million over four year packages? Like, get the
Speaker 6:  bag. I love that for you. Yeah, this is your time, but
Speaker 6:  at the same time, you look at that cost and it's just like,
Speaker 6:  are you getting your money's worth? How, how much did you spend on that metaverse
Speaker 6:  gambit bud?
Speaker 4:  I mean, this is what I'm thinking about, right? Where it's like, okay, let's
Speaker 4:  think, let's think about the last time Zuck sort of like went ham and
Speaker 4:  spent a ton of money on some initiative that we were like, I don't know if
Speaker 4:  This's gonna work out for you. It is the Metaverse.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There, there's still no legs in the Metaverse. So where did
Speaker 6:  all that money go? I didn't
Speaker 5:  Announce the legs.
Speaker 6:  They announced the legs, but did the legs ever come?
Speaker 5:  The legs never shipped. It's a
Speaker 4:  Can. I never can I tell saying nobody signed on to check.
Speaker 5:  There could be legs.
Speaker 4:  Like that's, you know, he made the wrong, but, but also,
Speaker 4:  it's not even that he made the wrong bet at the wrong time. Like that, that,
Speaker 4:  you know, I feel like you could have easily foreseen that. Yeah. When talking
Speaker 4:  about the metaverse, it's that he put in a boatload of money and it was
Speaker 4:  bad.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And like, they're kind of doing that with, with Llama already.
Speaker 4:  And this feels like number one, it's funny, they've, they've for for
Speaker 4:  months been talking of Llama how great it is. There was that scandal
Speaker 4:  a few months back where they ran a special, like,
Speaker 4:  optimized version of Lama to like game some tests. Oh yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  If you've used Meta ai,
Speaker 6:  Which I have,
Speaker 4:  How is it v
Speaker 6:  Not great. I mean, on the one hand, so I mostly use Meta AI through the
Speaker 6:  glasses when I'm testing new features or whatnot. My favorite thing about
Speaker 6:  it is that I can make it sound like John Cena.
Speaker 4:  Oh no, it's not bad. It's not
Speaker 6:  Bad. Yeah. Yeah. But that's my favorite thing about it. Yeah. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  like, I've tried the live ai, which has its pros and cons. I
Speaker 6:  think the multimodal thing is really smart. But the
Speaker 6:  live translations, for example, that, that was
Speaker 6:  not, I tried, sorry Allison, I have to talk
Speaker 6:  about Amelia Perez again. Oh, it's my favorite.
Speaker 6:  I tried months back, just like seeing like, oh, could I use this to
Speaker 6:  translate content that I'm watching? So I put on a clip of one of the terrible
Speaker 6:  songs and Emelia Perez, and it got some of it, and then others
Speaker 6:  bit, it was just, so it was John Cena just saying very
Speaker 6:  wrong things. Oh, no. About the Spanish. So
Speaker 6:  yeah, in my experience, not great.
Speaker 5:  It, it sort of feels like there's a, a moment coming. I don't know if it's
Speaker 5:  like the chips are down or it's like,
Speaker 5:  what's the game where you have to get a chair? Do you have
Speaker 6:  To like mu musical chairs,
Speaker 5:  Musical chairs. It's like musical chairs. And everybody's like, okay,
Speaker 5:  it's about time to figure out this AI stuff. Yeah. Like Apple, they're like,
Speaker 5:  can we build it or should we just buy a company? And there's a little
Speaker 5:  bit of that going on, and Zuck is like, I'm buying all these chairs.
Speaker 5:  I'm covering all my bases.
Speaker 6:  So I spent all the stuff on the Metaverse, and apparently that's not what
Speaker 6:  people want. So I didn't spend everything on ai. So money,
Speaker 6:  here you go. But that's, that's what this feels like. There you go.
Speaker 4:  Thinking about the Ray bands is really interesting too, because there,
Speaker 4:  right now it's like, it's this very simple product and we're like, Hey, these
Speaker 4:  are nice headphones. And they are really bullish on
Speaker 4:  actually their AI glasses.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  They, and it's, is it Right? Like they, in fact, they have to build the
Speaker 4:  ai,
Speaker 6:  They do in fact have to build the ai. So, you know, there are communities
Speaker 6:  that really do love the Meta glasses
Speaker 6:  and the AI in them. Spoiler alert, that's what my next host episode
Speaker 6:  on Tuesday is gonna be about. But you know, by and
Speaker 6:  large, most people are not really thinking of it
Speaker 6:  in that way. But I do, every single time I write them as smart glasses.
Speaker 6:  I, I'm, I've got a good relationship with the PR people at Meta, but they're
Speaker 6:  like, would you be open to calling it AI glasses? And it's like,
Speaker 6:  no, they're smart glasses. But so to to, to, like,
Speaker 6:  the reason I tell that story is to say that like, they are super bullish
Speaker 6:  on glasses being a vehicle for ai. They really believe that
Speaker 6:  glasses are like, what are gonna get people thinking about ai? And you know,
Speaker 6:  Google's kind of jumped on that train too with Android xr. So
Speaker 6:  they still gotta build the AI first. So
Speaker 6:  we'll see.
Speaker 4:  We'll see. Yeah. It's, it is, it is not a bet in a vacuum. It's, and it's
Speaker 4:  like so easy to think of it that way. I think particularly because like OpenAI,
Speaker 4:  like it is, it exists as a website. Like it is, it is a bot on its own.
Speaker 4:  That's it. And Meta is trying to
Speaker 4:  productize it. Yeah. And the product is okay and the AI is
Speaker 4:  not Okay.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I thi this is going to be, I think just one of the clear,
Speaker 4:  like give this a couple years obviously, but it is going to be
Speaker 4:  a fascinating experiment to see if you can just buy your
Speaker 4:  way to a, a great product. 'cause I cannot remember, obviously people
Speaker 4:  will just buy companies. I mean, it's funny. Yeah, actually a lot
Speaker 4:  of the big company acquisitions do not work. No, they don't. There is a culture
Speaker 4:  clash, right? I'm thinking of like Google buying Motorola,
Speaker 4:  which like, and then selling it a few years later,
Speaker 4:  right? So this is sort of a version of that. He is just buying what
Speaker 4:  he thinks is all the best people and who by all, by all accounts are supposed
Speaker 4:  to be, be incredibly talented researchers. Can you buy your way
Speaker 4:  to the best product? We're gonna find out. And it's gonna be really interesting
Speaker 4:  to see. And if it does not pay off, like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. At least this is a better bet, I think than the metaverse.
Speaker 4:  It it, yes. I think that is, that is fair, right? Like there is a product
Speaker 4:  to be had here that people want some doesn't. That some people
Speaker 4:  want. Some people the question is, can, can they build something? Llamas
Speaker 4:  is aggressively fine.
Speaker 6:  It's, that's, I think that's the best way to describe it. 'cause I've been
Speaker 6:  using a bunch of them and it, is it the best one? No. Is it the worst one
Speaker 6:  also? No. Yeah. It's safely fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Safe. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of ai, that is not the best. Oh
Speaker 6:  God. Oh
Speaker 4:  My, the other big change this week happened
Speaker 4:  at x where there was also some grok news
Speaker 4:  to discuss. So ex CEO Linda Ya
Speaker 4:  Carino announced this week that she was stepping down. Elon
Speaker 4:  replied with a a, I'm gonna say terse tweet
Speaker 4:  saying thanks for your contributions.
Speaker 6:  Who could have seen this coming?
Speaker 4:  When Linda posted about her announcement, she was like, you know, look at
Speaker 4:  all that we've done. We've done such a great job. You know, we made it the
Speaker 4:  everything app. We've like cracked down on safety. We've, we've done free
Speaker 4:  speech. And j Peters on our team just looked at all these things and
Speaker 4:  he is like, actually, like under Ja Carino, none of this stuff has happened.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I remember using the X
Speaker 5:  app as an everything app. You know, just yesterday I ordered
Speaker 5:  a pizza. I, no, that's not
Speaker 6:  True. No, she lasted longer than I thought she would though. 'cause I thought
Speaker 6:  like when she was announced that I was like, oh, this'll be over in six months
Speaker 6:  and she lasted four times that. Yeah. So, you know, that's true. Y
Speaker 6:  yeah. I'm, I might just might be me, but I don't know if I could have
Speaker 6:  lasted as long as she did. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Given
Speaker 6:  So we circumstances. So
Speaker 5:  We think she just got fed up.
Speaker 6:  Right. I, I think she just was like, that's
Speaker 5:  The thinking.
Speaker 6:  I think she was just like, yeah, I didn't sign up for this.
Speaker 4:  See, I, I don't, it takes a certain type of person to
Speaker 4:  volunteer to work for Elon. And she was pretty gung ho about it up
Speaker 4:  front. Yeah. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. She was, she
Speaker 4:  Was. And so that, so I, I don't know. I'm very, very
Speaker 4:  interested in finding out what happened there.
Speaker 6:  Do you think she knew about the whole like trumpet turn that he was gonna
Speaker 6:  do Doge and all of that? Do you think she just finally went like,
Speaker 6:  I signed up for, like, I signed up for stuff. I didn't sign up for that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And she's just finally been like, okay, and I'm
Speaker 6:  done.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, I mean, she spent a lot of her time.
Speaker 4:  I think so, right? Because she spent a lot of her time defending him. And
Speaker 4:  her job when she came on was, advertisers are
Speaker 4:  fleeing this platform because everyone hates Elon and he keeps saying
Speaker 4:  inappropriate stuff. Right? Yeah. And so, you know,
Speaker 4:  and she, you know, didn't quite get
Speaker 4:  that. Like there are some adv, the the platform still exists.
Speaker 6:  It's there.
Speaker 4:  But the other thing is that when she signed on X was an independent company,
Speaker 4:  it is now owned by XAI, which means there are even,
Speaker 4:  you know, she was always the CEO and it always felt like it was in air quotes.
Speaker 4:  Like, Elon owns a place, Elon runs the place
Speaker 4:  X also announced a, a new head of product recently. They put
Speaker 4:  Nikita beer in charge. He was the co-founder of TBH, which
Speaker 4:  Metabo And I believe then shut down. And also Gas, which was acquired by
Speaker 4:  Discord. I have, I, the apps as I'm told, I believe are
Speaker 4:  for teens. And so I did not use them. I
Speaker 6:  Don't, you know what, that's just being age appropriate. And on the teen
Speaker 6:  apps, teens
Speaker 5:  Are using gas.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure about that. These are words. I can't prove that words.
Speaker 4:  So X you know, it's got some, it's got some, they didn't announce a new CEO.
Speaker 4:  They didn't, they didn't say anything. They're just like, Linda's gone. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And, and then in the background of all of this
Speaker 4:  grok, I I, I kind of, there's something
Speaker 4:  about X as a platform right now where it
Speaker 4:  just, there's sometimes there are rainy days and thunderstorms
Speaker 4:  and you're just like, oh yeah, the chat bot that lives in the platform
Speaker 4:  is being racist and calling itself Mecca Hitler today. And you're like, well,
Speaker 4:  where does it like, oh, it does that sometimes. And it's like that, this
Speaker 4:  is the point we have gotten to with X, where we're like, number one,
Speaker 4:  it's still, it still functions number two. Yeah. You can just ignore
Speaker 4:  Mecca Hitler, like, yeah. Oh yeah. They, they'll deal with it. It's fine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Mecca Hitler, that's the, do you remember when we used to call, like
Speaker 6:  back when it was Twitter, we used to be like, this is the main character
Speaker 6:  of the day. Yes. And now gr is the main character of the day as Mecca
Speaker 6:  Hitler. But don't love that.
Speaker 4:  No, I, it, the, the Mecca Hitler thing is
Speaker 4:  perhaps the more, the lighter part of it, it, it was being like
Speaker 4:  actively super antisemitic and racist and offensive
Speaker 4:  and just like going off for a couple days and eventually they like shut it
Speaker 4:  down. This all ends with Elon
Speaker 4:  hosting a live stream turnout's Rock four, which may or may not
Speaker 4:  be live at this point. It wasn't unless I checked it's,
Speaker 4:  I, I don't, I don't really get it. Like x as a product
Speaker 4:  is, I think bewildering to me at this point. Like, I,
Speaker 4:  I think the grand proclamations of Doom, I
Speaker 4:  guess I would argue did not quite, yeah.
Speaker 6:  There's like a ton of people who are still on X. Yeah. Surprisingly. The,
Speaker 6:  like the, the 10 seconds I'm on there every so often. I'm like, oh,
Speaker 6:  right. So, and so I used to follow, they still be posting
Speaker 6:  up a storm on X. Yeah. So that's, you know, it's still there.
Speaker 6:  People are still have not left, which is wild
Speaker 6:  to me, but Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And like, you know, I don't wanna, I shouldn't give him too much credit for
Speaker 4:  this, but like, Elon fired most of the company and like, it's still,
Speaker 4:  you know, the a the website is still online most of the time. Right? Like,
Speaker 4:  okay, okay, they've got that. Is
Speaker 4:  it succeeding? Not right. The thing it
Speaker 4:  has succeeded at is creating a whole bunch of competing
Speaker 4:  platforms, including Threads, which there was data out this week that it
Speaker 4:  is like nearly catching up That's wild on mobile app
Speaker 4:  usage. Wow. Right.
Speaker 6:  That's absolutely wild. Considering how awful Threads is like, I'm sorry,
Speaker 6:  like I go to Threads for very specific things, which is K-pop because apparently
Speaker 6:  my algo there is just like, all you care about is K-pop. And I'm like,
Speaker 6:  are they wrong? They are only partly wrong. I care about other things, but
Speaker 6:  I'm just like, that's my entire feed on threads is just K-pop from, but like
Speaker 6:  K-pop news from five days ago. Oh, so like not.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's
Speaker 6:  What you go to threads for. Something happens. That's what you go to Threads
Speaker 6:  for five
Speaker 5:  Days ago, everywhere. I wonder how much of it is Meta just
Speaker 5:  aggressively pushing people to threads, which has been,
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's so aggressive in Instagram now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Scrolling through and you're like, oh, do I wanna look at a, a
Speaker 5:  threads post from three days ago? I think I'm good
Speaker 4:  Threads also very aggressively pushes the, like for You
Speaker 4:  page or whatever it's called, the Discover page. Whereas, you know,
Speaker 4:  other platforms are nice and give you options or let you choose your
Speaker 4:  right. The I go on threads And I get frigging sucked in. 'cause it
Speaker 4:  is just like showing me all this stuff from people who I don't follow. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, I, this is why Facebook succeeds. Yeah, yeah. Right. I'm not,
Speaker 4:  I'm not, I'm not actually saying it's bad necessarily, but like Yeah, I see.
Speaker 4:  I see why it's doing okay and somehow they've got enough stuff.
Speaker 6:  They don't have a Mecca Hitler though.
Speaker 4:  I, well, you know what Zuck just spent a lot of money on.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Okay. We might have a Mecca Hitler down the line, but, oh
Speaker 6:  eh,
Speaker 5:  How close are we to Mecca Hitler? That's a new metric for,
Speaker 5:  oh God. For your ai
Speaker 6:  That's dystopian. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Sorry.
Speaker 6:  And on that happy
Speaker 4:  Note, on that happy note, it's time for a break. When we get back,
Speaker 4:  we are rebranding the lightning round. Get ready for it.
Speaker 11:  Alright,
Speaker 4:  We're back. So I have a problem. I have a problem with the
Speaker 4:  lightning round. I don't know if you guys know this. Oh my goodness. But
Speaker 4:  Neli and David every week they've got the lightning round. They've got a
Speaker 4:  whole bunch of stories. And the point of the lightning round is you, you
Speaker 4:  get through all this, it's fast paced lightning round, right? What
Speaker 4:  happens Goes
Speaker 5:  Long.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, goes long. They don't get to all the stories. They gotta cut 'em.
Speaker 4:  That ends today. Okay. We are cha era. The
Speaker 4:  lightning round is done. We are changing it.
Speaker 4:  It is henceforth known as the thunder round.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God.
Speaker 4:  Let's do this. Okay, here's what's gonna happen. Unlike
Speaker 4:  the lightning round, the thunder round gets stuff done, it
Speaker 4:  keeps moving. We've got 15 stories,
Speaker 4:  15 minutes, and I have given Eric Gomez
Speaker 4:  our producer, the Power of Lightning. Oh, thunder,
Speaker 4:  that one's wrong. That's
Speaker 5:  Wrong. Well, you, you have one, you have the other. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Okay. He's got the power of something to make us
Speaker 4:  move along and he is gonna come in with
Speaker 4:  some, some rolling, some crackling thunder, some crashes
Speaker 4:  to keep us moving if we, if we go a little too slow.
Speaker 5:  I love that. Okay. And I love this. So ready? I'm ready. I'm gonna jump a
Speaker 5:  million
Speaker 4:  Times. All right people, let's do this. The first ever
Speaker 4:  thunder round, we're gonna get through all of them. You ready? I believe
Speaker 4:  in this. Okay. Story number one. I really wanna talk about this.
Speaker 4:  Allison, you covered Project Indigo, which is this Adobe
Speaker 4:  camera app for the iPhone, right?
Speaker 5:  Yes. It's kind of a beta product. It is a camera app.
Speaker 5:  It's made by Mark LaVoy, who some people may remember as like
Speaker 5:  the brains behind the Pixel camera. The idea is it's computational
Speaker 5:  photography, but it doesn't make your photos look like HDR Hell
Speaker 5:  is how I would say the sales pitch is. And I played with it. It turned
Speaker 5:  my phone into a,
Speaker 5:  a, a piece of fire. I don't know, it, it's, it's very beta.
Speaker 5:  It heats your phone up. Oh my God. Not a great like,
Speaker 5:  everyday camera amazing photos. Like, loved it so much. The photos
Speaker 6:  In your story were so, like, they had such intense mood and like a
Speaker 6:  vibe
Speaker 5:  Contrast, like beautiful.
Speaker 4:  I've liked really this doesn't happen that often. The entire VERGE newsroom
Speaker 4:  stopped and was like, what? What, what are these photos? Yes, photos from
Speaker 4:  a phone. Yeah. I have not seen phone photos like this in,
Speaker 4:  in years. Yeah, it's Mark LaVoy really feels like the guy who,
Speaker 4:  who Google like getaway. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I know.
Speaker 4:  What did they do here?
Speaker 5:  And he's like a fellow at Adobe. What a gig. Yeah, you just hang
Speaker 5:  out, make a camera app
Speaker 4:  Making the camera app we all want. Yeah. So at, was this like, were these
Speaker 4:  like specially curated the photos that you posted or 'cause like they, they
Speaker 4:  were in Incred
Speaker 6:  The Thunder.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. So I, next story,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna move along here. Ikea announced a lamp with a speaker in it and
Speaker 4:  it looks cool and it connects to Spotify. The main thing is they drop
Speaker 4:  Sonos.
Speaker 6:  This is the correct move to drop Sonos. You like this. I like Sonos has
Speaker 6:  had kind of a, Sonos has had a year that the app
Speaker 6:  has not been great. And I think, you know, if you think about what most people
Speaker 6:  use, they're using Bluetooth and they're using Spotify. So just go where
Speaker 6:  their people are, make it cheaper. You don't have to have like a whole licensing
Speaker 6:  issue with Sonos for this. And Sonos is like,
Speaker 6:  you know, it's, it's, are they doing great stuff?
Speaker 4:  Sonos and Ikea always felt like a weird pairing to me. Mm. Right. It is the
Speaker 4:  highest end of, of connected speakers and
Speaker 4:  the like lowest end of stuff for your home. I mean, I love Ikea. That is
Speaker 4:  not enough. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And Ikea is more expensive than they used to be. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  You know, it's just, no, but that is like a weird dichotomy and like
Speaker 6:  ikea's foray into the smart home has always been about simplicity and
Speaker 6:  keeping things affordable. So yeah. Kind of
Speaker 5:  The speaker's cute.
Speaker 6:  The speaker is cute. Isn
Speaker 5:  That bad? Or that's not the lamp. There's a lamp.
Speaker 4:  I would buy a bunch of these.
Speaker 5:  Wow. Okay. I want some No beds. Okay. I was just shaking out
Speaker 6:  The thunder. God does not appreciate Speaker Doc.
Speaker 4:  Ve do you wanna take this one?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Perplexity has launched a comment web
Speaker 6:  browser, so a web browser for perplexity, which is the
Speaker 6:  AI search engine, which fashions itself as I always get
Speaker 6:  confused by the, the pitch for ity over the other ones. But the whole idea
Speaker 6:  is that it's researching things in real time. So you're supposed to be able
Speaker 6:  to trust the results more. Sure. It has a web browser now.
Speaker 5:  Love it. Have you
Speaker 4:  Used, have either of you used either like Gemini and Chrome or Dia yet?
Speaker 4:  What's,
Speaker 6:  I haven't used Dia, but I, I'm a, a long time user of Arc and the
Speaker 6:  original Arc. Yes. Yeah. So like I get the whole AI browser thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So my, okay, so AI browser's super hot right now. They also,
Speaker 4:  OpenAI is supposed to be launching an AI web browser too. My whole thing
Speaker 4:  is like, they don't work yet, right? Like, I
Speaker 4:  tried Dia and I'm like this, it's just a permanent chat bot tab. Like
Speaker 4:  why, oh, what am I, I like, I'm like pretty on board with like
Speaker 4:  chat GPT being useful. But it's like you just, you
Speaker 4:  just added a tab to my browser. Yeah, I I I get it. They're trying to, they're
Speaker 4:  trying to beat Google. They're trying to replace it. And to do that you gotta
Speaker 4:  be the
Speaker 6:  Default's a different version of AI overviews I feel. Which is,
Speaker 6:  eh,
Speaker 5:  It's more aggressive.
Speaker 6:  It's much more aggressive
Speaker 5:  AI mode. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I will say like sometimes in the arc browser, when I have like a thing that
Speaker 6:  I'm looking up and it gives me the summaries, I'm like, oh, it's helpful
Speaker 6:  to have summaries, but now I gotta look it up and make sure it's like Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Accurate. So you gotta check it's work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's work
Speaker 5:  AI mode is like, what if you could talk to and interact with a page
Speaker 5:  of search results? I'm like, Hmm, I don't think I've ever wanted that. No,
Speaker 5:  no, no.
Speaker 6:  That's what I asked for.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Cool.
Speaker 6:  The Oh, right, okay.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Sorry.
Speaker 6:  I, I brain froze. But anyway, so Yeah. Yeah. AI
Speaker 6:  browsers, they're not,
Speaker 5:  Not sure We like it. Yeah. Not sure
Speaker 4:  We like it. Allison. Alright. Ein
Speaker 5:  Okay. Ein is on a laptop for some reason.
Speaker 5:  So there's a laptop, but instead of a touchpad, it has
Speaker 5:  an ein e-reader for AI apps.
Speaker 6:  I hate this. I I hate everything about
Speaker 4:  This. Thi this felt like they were just trying to find an angle on their
Speaker 4:  own pro. Like they were like, we could put an a, an e-reader on the touch
Speaker 4:  on the track pad. Yeah. And they're like, nobody's gonna buy that. What if
Speaker 4:  we put AI next to it? Yeah. Hate this. I don't, I don't. Why would you wanna
Speaker 4:  read on your track pad?
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 6:  I don't. There's no, there's no reason for that. And then also just,
Speaker 6:  okay, I'm sorry. I'm gonna quote Ron Swanson from Parks and Rec.
Speaker 6:  Whole ass one thing, don't half ass two things. This
Speaker 6:  is two half ass thing. I have an e-reader, I have
Speaker 6:  a laptop touch pad and AI is in everything,
Speaker 6:  but I don't want to read on my touch pad where my FIEs
Speaker 6:  go. So
Speaker 5:  That's my, because sometimes you're,
Speaker 6:  You sometimes you're eating and
Speaker 5:  Then you're gonna get it all smmi
Speaker 6:  And then it's gonna be on your a IE reader. Yeah. In the middle. Just
Speaker 5:  Get a folding phone.
Speaker 6:  Just, I don't know about that.
Speaker 5:  Then you have a bunch of screens. I don't
Speaker 6:  Know if I'm gonna go that far, but Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Get a $2,000 folding whole
Speaker 6:  Ass one touch pad. That's, that's my spiel. There you
Speaker 4:  Go. I support that. Yeah. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Next thing.
Speaker 4:  Did you guys see, or can I say, did you not see
Speaker 4:  Lord's s new CD? Oh, which is transparent.
Speaker 6:  It's transparent. You made
Speaker 4:  Made it transparent and see it. Okay. So it turns out when you
Speaker 4:  put a CD into certain CD players, I mean they, I guess they, they all
Speaker 4:  use infrared to read it, but it seems like some of them maybe also use
Speaker 4:  infrared to register that a CD is really going in and
Speaker 4:  they can't see it. And so they just eject the CD and they won't put it in.
Speaker 4:  Andrew Marino on our team went out and these things are
Speaker 4:  sold out, but he managed to find one and he tested about a CD players. So
Speaker 4:  you have like a clam shell one where you just like put it in and close it.
Speaker 4:  Or I guess maybe like a disc tray. Yeah. Yeah. That will work. But otherwise,
Speaker 4:  these Lord fans are really upset because
Speaker 6:  You know what fair they paid for this music and now they can't listen
Speaker 6:  to it on their car cd. Which, you know, like, that's one reason to buy a
Speaker 6:  cd Yeah. Is if you have a car that still has those things. So I totally get
Speaker 6:  what they're saying, but at the same time, it is kind of cool to have a transparent
Speaker 4:  CD. Looks okay, I'm moving on with this one because I don't wanna get crashed.
Speaker 4:  A federal appeals court struck down the FTCs click to cancel
Speaker 4:  rule this week. This is
Speaker 6:  Bullshit. That's what
Speaker 4:  This is. Yeah, this is, yeah, this is, this is the thing that was gonna let
Speaker 4:  you cancel your gym membership.
Speaker 6:  This was, this
Speaker 4:  Is, this should be a bipartisan issue. If there was ever a bipartisan
Speaker 4:  issue,
Speaker 6:  Why did they look, I I, does anyone like it when you're trying
Speaker 6:  to cancel a thing and they're like, actually you have to call an email. Nobody
Speaker 6:  likes this. Nobody wants this. This was a bipartisan, like
Speaker 4:  It's devastating. This is absolutely devastating.
Speaker 6:  This is absolutely,
Speaker 5:  We should have gotten this done. Who's responsible? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Who is responsible for this? I'm just, why would they like, I'm sorry. Like
Speaker 6:  even
Speaker 4:  It is they okay, they said, they said the FTC did a bad job making the rule.
Speaker 4:  So it's, it's not like they can still do it. It's just like, will
Speaker 4:  the new FTC do? It was like,
Speaker 6:  Oh great. No they won't because the, the, I don't know, maybe I'm being mean,
Speaker 6:  but I feel like it's capitalist to be just like, no, make
Speaker 6:  it hard for them to cancel. 'cause then we can get revenue. I tried. 'cause
Speaker 6:  these people can't remember. Just cancel their subscriptions.
Speaker 5:  I tried to cancel pet insurance once and it was the most ar i,
Speaker 5:  I just gave up and paid another year for pet insurance.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. No. That's a lot of, no,
Speaker 5:  You had to like write a handwritten note. Mail
Speaker 6:  It. That's insane.
Speaker 5:  Call their CEOI.
Speaker 4:  Sorry. It's good news for your pet, I suppose.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he was, he
Speaker 4:  Was alright. Oh. Oh,
Speaker 6:  That was my god. He was dead. Thunder crash. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Vik. He was moving.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So nothing's first true flagship phone plays it a
Speaker 6:  little safe. 'cause you know nothing. We know nothing for. Oh God, you gotta
Speaker 6:  stop me with the nothing ponds, but nothing Oh, no. Has something going for
Speaker 6:  it. Which is the, it's known for its forward design and this is not
Speaker 6:  cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it has. So instead of like all the lights on the back,
Speaker 5:  that was like the glyph thing, which looked cool,
Speaker 5:  wasn't super useful. I didn't find it super useful. It has a little tiny,
Speaker 5:  like,
Speaker 5:  programmable, like LED thing, sort of like the
Speaker 5:  asus like R phones where it
Speaker 5:  can be a little icon. It can be a, an emoji icon for a certain
Speaker 5:  app. It makes more sense to me because you could assign
Speaker 5:  different notifications to different glyph patterns. And I would
Speaker 5:  be looking at it like, I can't remember if that thing lights up. Do I have
Speaker 5:  a phone call or what? This is like a, a more clear, like
Speaker 5:  you could, you could put a little poop emoji when the phone rings or something.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. People were hating on it. I don't know. I think it's a good
Speaker 5:  idea
Speaker 4:  Because they, they demoed it with like a spin the bottle. Oh, that's dumb.
Speaker 4:  Which, okay, but hear me, hear me out. I'm actually super infa. It,
Speaker 4:  it's the carrot sensor. They're just like, they're like, no one is gonna
Speaker 4:  use this. Here's your carrot. Yeah. And I love it. I love
Speaker 6:  It. Maybe they should have just put a little more whimsy into it. I don't
Speaker 6:  know. I think people have expectations. So Yeah. This didn't meet their expectations
Speaker 6:  of what they wanted from nothing.
Speaker 5:  I guess they wanted something from nothing.
Speaker 6:  They wanted something from
Speaker 5:  Nothing. That doesn't work.
Speaker 4:  We deserve, we deserve this one. We
Speaker 6:  Deserve that. The crash probably to sell.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The government is still suing Apple for
Speaker 5:  antitrust.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Good. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No, I'm very pleased to see that's still happening.
Speaker 4:  Apple, apple tried to get it dismissed and the judge was
Speaker 4:  just like, yeah, seems like they've got a case. Like, And I, they
Speaker 4:  didn't, you know, they didn't like rule on it in any meaningful manner. They're
Speaker 4:  just like
Speaker 6:  So litigious, right? Like, they do this all the time with
Speaker 4:  Everything. I mean, this is, well, okay, so this is, The government was like,
Speaker 4:  Hey, apple, like your entire business model's anti-competitive and apple's.
Speaker 4:  Like, that's not true. And this judge is like, let us at least find out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So that's, that's it. That's good. That's good. That's good. I wanna
Speaker 4:  see this play out. I think like there are huge repercussions. Yeah. Potentially.
Speaker 4:  So it'll be, it'll at least be a fun time in court. Yeah. Yay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All right. My turn. So Adding calendar events
Speaker 6:  with a screenshot is AI at its finest hard agree. Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  Someone also testing the dev beta of iOS 26. Good.
Speaker 4:  It actually works
Speaker 6:  Now. Hard agree. Yeah. Yeah. For the mo it, it does the thing
Speaker 6:  that you want it to do. It's, it's kind of like, oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So on iOS 26, you take a screenshot of something
Speaker 5:  and you'll get a little prompt. It'll say add the calendar
Speaker 5:  and it'll use generative AI to, and it, it
Speaker 5:  already did a version of this, but it wasn't, it, it was pretty like,
Speaker 5:  find the date, use the email subject line as the
Speaker 5:  calendar thing. And that was kind of the end of it. I will say Gemini does
Speaker 5:  this a lot better. Like, we will add multiple events. We'll ask you
Speaker 5:  follow up questions like, did you wanna add this or this? And
Speaker 5:  it understood. Time zones.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's a big
Speaker 5:  One's. Very good. Really good. That's a big one. I, I think it's a win all
Speaker 5:  around. I'm like, free us from the tyranny of calendar apps.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Ugh.
Speaker 5:  That's what I say about that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Sold good. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. Sold on it.
Speaker 5:  Hey, we beat the clock. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wow. This
Speaker 4:  Don't
Speaker 5:  Push it. Now I'm braced for thunder. Should
Speaker 4:  I take next one? Oh
Speaker 6:  No, they just wanna keep us on our toes. Now there's,
Speaker 4:  We think we've made Eric too powerful. Powell's second Generation Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro might launch this year according to Bloomberg.
Speaker 4:  Supposedly they're just gonna do the pretty much exact same thing. Put an
Speaker 4:  M four chip in it to keep it, I mean, it is, the Vision Pro is, is
Speaker 4:  just, it is a Mac on your face and Yeah, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  heavy, rough when it's $3,500 and, and an M1 and
Speaker 6:  It's a heavy Mac
Speaker 4:  On your face. So this is the other thing. Supposedly they're gonna do some
Speaker 4:  sort of new strap, which like, I feel like everybody I've talked to about
Speaker 4:  the Vision Pro is like, you gotta get a different strap.
Speaker 6:  You gotta get a, like, first of, so there's two staff straps now. There's
Speaker 6:  the solo on it and there's the one that looks like a harness. I forget the
Speaker 6:  name of it right now, but I keep switching between both of them.
Speaker 6:  Neither of them help. It's just I can't, I, you know,
Speaker 6:  I, I'm not calling the people who believe that, like, you can wear it for
Speaker 6:  hours, liars. But I have never been able to do that.
Speaker 4:  So, okay. I'm gonna keep us quick on this next one too. As we, as we move
Speaker 4:  forward. Nvidia briefly became the first four
Speaker 4:  trillion company this week. The thing that's interesting here,
Speaker 4:  apple was the first 1 trillion. Apple was the first
Speaker 4:  American company to 2 trillion. Apple was the first company of 3 trillion.
Speaker 4:  Nvidia wins with 4 trillion. It's ai, it's right, it's, it's, it's the ai,
Speaker 4:  it's
Speaker 6:  Ai
Speaker 4:  Chip.
Speaker 6:  The chips need to,
Speaker 4:  The times have changed. Apple is merely a three trillion company.
Speaker 4:  Oh,
Speaker 5:  I'm Miss Machine.
Speaker 4:  Your our, our thoughts are with Tim on these trying times.
Speaker 6:  These trying times. He has his biceps to keep him company. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  True. Okay. Do you know Cameo still around?
Speaker 6:  I did not know it was still around
Speaker 4:  Cameo. Not only is still around, they launched a new app this week for tracking
Speaker 4:  your friend's birthdays. It's it calendar, but it only does birthdays. Do
Speaker 5:  We need,
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 4:  Dumb. And I don't And Cameo is doing it. Why?
Speaker 6:  I don't,
Speaker 4:  Oh, I guess is the idea that then you're like, oh, oh,
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's my friend's birthday. I should get them a, a cameo from that random
Speaker 6:  select. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  That's kind of genius. But also, no, no.
Speaker 4:  I will say and like, apologies to, I don't know all of my friends, everybody
Speaker 4:  I know, I only remember birthdays because they're in my calendar.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. It, if they're not in there, I don't know that you were born.
Speaker 6:  I'm an astrology nerd. Like I, it's how I cope with everything
Speaker 6:  now. So I just find out people's signs and then know the general
Speaker 6:  time of what their birthday is.
Speaker 5:  Oh, you just get a sense.
Speaker 6:  I just get a sense. They're like, oh, you're a Gemini. Oh, your birthday
Speaker 6:  passed. Like that kind of thing.
Speaker 5:  That was true. That was right. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There
Speaker 5:  You go. It's good. It's working. It's
Speaker 6:  Good. It's good stuff. So Apple just added more frost to its liquid
Speaker 6:  glass design. That's 'cause it's liquid s I'm not a fan. Oh,
Speaker 5:  She said it. I, wow. I'm not a fan. Okay. Here's my hot take.
Speaker 5:  I think it's kind of okay. Like I've kind of gotten used to it.
Speaker 6:  No, I have bad eyes. Like I have truly awful eyes and
Speaker 6:  anyone's ever read my Smart Glasses review or anything that has to do with
Speaker 6:  vision. Know that my eyes are garbage. These are garbage eyeballs that my
Speaker 6:  parents gave me. I, I
Speaker 6:  legitimately had a really hard time reading. Yeah. And like, and obviously
Speaker 6:  it's Deb bait. I'll be different when it comes out. I'm pro more
Speaker 6:  frost. But then it's not glass.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, it's frosted glass.
Speaker 6:  It's frosted glass. I had to put the little outlines on all the buttons,
Speaker 6:  which make the whole transparency thing not because like, if you go into
Speaker 6:  the messages, you can't see any of the buttons. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then you're just like a slap. It's terrible. I don't
Speaker 5:  Like it. You guys, you guys know what? I watched Minority Report for the
Speaker 5:  first time, literally for the first time this last week. Oh wow. And they're
Speaker 5:  putting all the glass in front of glass. I was like, there it
Speaker 4:  Is. We made it. We made it.
Speaker 6:  We did it.
Speaker 5:  The future's here
Speaker 4:  Now. And yeah, it seems like it was, everything worked out nicely. And Minority
Speaker 4:  Report.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. It was good. Good. Technology's really good.
Speaker 4:  Good to hear. It's fine. Alright, we've got two more. Two more.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna make this.
Speaker 5:  Oh, is it my turn? Yes. Yeah. Nintendo is ending. Its
Speaker 5:  cost saving Switch. Game vouchers. I didn't know there were Switch game vouchers.
Speaker 5:  How do I get one? And I can't, it's too late anymore.
Speaker 4:  So I guess ve did you ever use these? I did not. These were like, okay,
Speaker 4:  these were, people love these things. They were such a, a bargain.
Speaker 4:  It was this weird thing where n Nintendo was like, if you subscribe to Switch
Speaker 4:  online, so you have to be a member, but for a hundred bucks they'll sell
Speaker 4:  you a voucher and you can use it to get two full price
Speaker 4:  Nintendo games. And so you could lock in the price of a game at $50
Speaker 4:  basically. Which, if you're gonna buy two Nintendo games, it's like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  great. You're just like, you're saving like $20 or more. Particularly as
Speaker 4:  you're like, Hmm, these things are creeping up the price this is, this is,
Speaker 4:  they're like, cheers of the kingdom or whatever the next Zelda is, is
Speaker 4:  gonna be $90. Okay, last story. We made it, we're doing
Speaker 4:  it. HBO Max is officially h drum roll.
Speaker 4:  HBO Max. Again, thank,
Speaker 6:  Thank
Speaker 5:  God
Speaker 4:  The world is restored. We're safe.
Speaker 6:  I actually,
Speaker 4:  Not from Eric, not from Thunder. Not from Thunder, but we did it. Everyone,
Speaker 4:  we did it. We got 15 stories. All of the stories.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna declare this first version of The Thunder Round. Successful. Mostly
Speaker 4:  successful. I think it was successful. We, we've made it. We made it. We,
Speaker 4:  we, I feel set out
Speaker 6:  We accomplished what we set out
Speaker 5:  To do. Exactly. There you
Speaker 6:  Go. There
Speaker 5:  Was thunder
Speaker 4:  There. Was there, yes, there was Perhaps a lot of thunder.
Speaker 6:  There's some aggressive thunder happening. I feel like Eric, maybe, you
Speaker 6:  know, a little thunder. Happy.
Speaker 4:  That's it for the thunder round. And that's it for The Vergecast. We'd love
Speaker 4:  to hear your questions and feedback. Do you like the thunder round? I hope
Speaker 4:  so. Email us at vergecast at The Verge dot com or give us a call.
Speaker 4:  8 6 6 VERGE 11. The Vergecast is a production of The
Speaker 4:  Verge and Vox Media podcast network. Our show is produced by Eric Gomez,
Speaker 4:  Brandon Kiefer, Andrew Marino, and Travis. See
Speaker 4:  you next week.