# Transcript
ID: 32bdeb18-b91b-44c8-8a74-2cb7e0b8d231
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3233055384296376916/2643788504243560110/s93290-US-5287s-1736855475.mp3
Description: In five days, TikTok as we know it could be finished in the US. The Verge's Lauren Feiner joins the show to discuss last week's Supreme Court arguments over the ban, why things don't look good for TikTok, and what's likely to happen in the next five days. After that, Kickstarter CEO Everette Taylor talks about the state of the gadget inventor, and what it means to be part of the creator economy in 2025. Finally, we answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline about magic-link logins, and why passwords remain such a disaster.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Crowdfunded
Speaker 2:  Sox. I'm your friend David Pierce, and it is five 30 in the morning and I
Speaker 2:  am in the Charlotte, North Carolina airport on my way home from CES.
Speaker 2:  It was really fun, CES this year actually. It wasn't like the Newsiest or
Speaker 2:  Splashiest CES of all time, but AI was everywhere. Even though no
Speaker 2:  one knows what to do with ai, there were tons of wearables. The health
Speaker 2:  tech I actually thought was really interesting. Pool robots for some reason
Speaker 2:  were absolutely everywhere. I don't know how much interesting
Speaker 2:  technology there is in the pool robot space. If you're into that, let me
Speaker 2:  know. I'd love to hear it. But they were absolutely everywhere. Super fun
Speaker 2:  show. And by the way, thank you to everybody who came out to our live vergecast
Speaker 2:  at CES. It was super fun just to get to hang out with all of you and talk
Speaker 2:  about tech and CES and all of our feelings about everything. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  do more shows like that too. So If you miss this one, keep an eye out because
Speaker 2:  we're, we wanna do more live stuff. It's just fun getting to do this with
Speaker 2:  all of you guys. For now, we have some
Speaker 2:  CES adjacent stuff to talk about. I would say we're gonna do two things
Speaker 2:  on today's show. First, we're gonna talk to Lauren Finer about the TikTok
Speaker 2:  Band and the looming changes coming at meta
Speaker 2:  and basically the huge social landscape change that
Speaker 2:  feels like it's coming potentially like in the next few days
Speaker 2:  and weeks. It's gonna be a really interesting moment in this space, and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about it. Then I'm gonna talk to Everett Taylor, who's the CEO
Speaker 2:  of Kickstarter. Kickstarter was at CES last week, but I talked to Everett
Speaker 2:  right before CES about what it means to be
Speaker 2:  Kickstarter right now. We, I just spent the week talking to startups who
Speaker 2:  are desperately trying to figure out how to make and ship and get
Speaker 2:  products in front of people, and he had some really interesting thoughts
Speaker 2:  on what it means to be a tech creator right now and what it means to make
Speaker 2:  products in 2025 and how this landscape is
Speaker 2:  changing for people who just want to be out there making things and
Speaker 2:  selling them to people. Really interesting talking to him about it. I've
Speaker 2:  had sort of mixed feelings about Kickstarter for the whole time I've been
Speaker 2:  covering tech, and it was fun to process that with some of it. We also have
Speaker 2:  a really fun question from the first cast hotline. Lots to get to this week.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be a really fun show. All of that is coming up in just a second,
Speaker 2:  But first, I just, while I was doing this, walked completely the wrong direction
Speaker 2:  from my gate, and now I have to turn around and not miss my flight. This
Speaker 2:  is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Welcome back. All right, let's get into this. So today, if you're listening
Speaker 4:  to this on Tuesday is January 14th. On January 19th,
Speaker 4:  we will hit the deadline imposed by a bill that says either TikTok has to
Speaker 4:  be divested from by dance or will be banned in the United States.
Speaker 4:  It's actually not exactly that simple, and we're gonna talk about the ways
Speaker 4:  in which it's not exactly that simple, but it is kind of that simple.
Speaker 4:  TikTok as we know it, as the thing that you use now either
Speaker 4:  will or will not still be here In five days. And I think
Speaker 4:  we are getting an increasingly clear sense of which of those two things
Speaker 4:  might actually happen, especially after the bill that
Speaker 4:  originally banned TikTok and would do so on January 19th
Speaker 4:  was argued in front of the Supreme Court. We have new information, we have
Speaker 4:  a sense of what's gonna happen. I don't think it looks great for TikTok,
Speaker 4:  but let's get into all of what's to come. Lauren Finer has been
Speaker 4:  covering all of this for us and is having an extremely chill beginning to
Speaker 4:  2025, and she's here now to help us walk through all of it. Lauren Finer,
Speaker 4:  welcome back.
Speaker 5:  Thanks for having me. Just
Speaker 4:  A super chill way to start the year, I would
Speaker 5:  Say. Totally. Very, very normal.
Speaker 4:  It's just, and it's just gonna keep happening. We're, you're gonna be on
Speaker 4:  this show a lot in the next few months, so I'm really sorry in advance.
Speaker 5:  Looking forward to it.
Speaker 4:  So let's just rewind the TikTok story very slightly. I mostly wanna talk
Speaker 4:  about kind of where we are now and what's happening in the next week, but
Speaker 4:  like, give me the, the sort of CliffNotes version of how we ended
Speaker 4:  up in the Supreme Court last Friday.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so if we wanna start from like the very beginning, we gotta go back
Speaker 5:  a few years to when Donald Trump was president the first time
Speaker 5:  and he tried to do a TikTok ban through an executive order that
Speaker 5:  ends up getting shot down in the court because of some kinda legal reasons.
Speaker 5:  Then, you know, everyone kind of forgets about it. There's a committee
Speaker 5:  of in the federal government that's looking into a possible
Speaker 5:  sale or what could be done to mitigate the risks that they see of
Speaker 5:  TikTok being owned by a China-based parent company by dance.
Speaker 5:  But all things considered, everyone kind of forgets that this is
Speaker 5:  happening and we don't really hear that much about it. Then
Speaker 5:  go back to last year and all of a sudden
Speaker 5:  we see all of this momentum around a bill that could ban
Speaker 5:  TikTok and there'd been things like this before, but none of them have
Speaker 5:  really caught on. And all of a sudden this one is just like
Speaker 5:  rocketing with support and we end up seeing
Speaker 5:  a vote, an overwhelming vote in the house to pass this bill
Speaker 5:  after lawmakers got briefed on classified information.
Speaker 5:  And then we see it kind of quickly move through the Senate and
Speaker 5:  we see broad bipartisan support for this bill. And President Biden
Speaker 5:  quickly signs it into law. So that starts the clock on
Speaker 5:  this band deadline, which is now January 19th.
Speaker 5:  So that's where we were at. And then TikTok all along has
Speaker 5:  been fighting this. They've given by dance, their parent company has
Speaker 5:  given no indication that they actually would be interested in selling the
Speaker 5:  app. Meanwhile, we've seen a few kind of people
Speaker 5:  come outta the woodwork saying, we would love to buy the app,
Speaker 5:  but it's still not clear that it is for sale or that China would allow it
Speaker 5:  to be for sale, even if bike dance wanted it to be. And
Speaker 5:  that ends up landing us in the Supreme Court. You know, first
Speaker 5:  the case went to the DC Circuit Court, which had
Speaker 5:  exclusive jurisdiction per the text of the law to
Speaker 5:  see this. And they decided, a three judge panel
Speaker 5:  decided, all three judges said that this is a constitutional
Speaker 5:  law, it does not violate the First Amendment, even though it could result
Speaker 5:  in the ousting of a speech platform. Then
Speaker 5:  TikTok appeals the ruling we end up in the Supreme Court, and that's where
Speaker 5:  we were on Friday when the Supreme Court heard oral arguments in this case.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And it's, I I would say it had been barreling toward the Supreme Court
Speaker 4:  kind of from day one, right? Like we, we, I remember talking about this when
Speaker 4:  the law was first even being debated, that it was like this is gonna end
Speaker 4:  up in front of the Supreme Court in one way or another. So this is kind of,
Speaker 4:  this is the capstone we had been waiting for for months.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. This was a long time coming. This was always gonna be a fight between
Speaker 5:  two really fundamental interests of the US government, which are
Speaker 5:  national security and free expression. So this was always kind of barreling
Speaker 5:  to toward this place.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And it seems like one of the things that happened a lot
Speaker 4:  in the arguments on Friday was the question of is this
Speaker 4:  even a thing about free speech? Which surprised
Speaker 4:  me, and it seemed like surprised some people that that was even
Speaker 4:  up for debate about are we even having a conversation about free speech?
Speaker 4:  Walk me through that a little bit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think, I honestly wasn't surprised by that framing
Speaker 5:  that we saw by a lot of the justices, because If you just look
Speaker 5:  directly at the text of the law as it's written, it's
Speaker 5:  written to talk about the
Speaker 5:  foreign adversary control of a social media app.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, in the text of the law, it doesn't say anything about
Speaker 5:  speech, about like who says what or, you know, what kinds of
Speaker 5:  speech is allowed. It's purely about who is allowed to
Speaker 5:  own a social media app. And you know, we have like foreign
Speaker 5:  ownership rules over, you know, certain kinds of
Speaker 5:  other kinds of media. So it's not a wholly different
Speaker 5:  concept, but you know, obviously no law like this has ever
Speaker 5:  really gotten to this point before.
Speaker 4:  But then how do you, how do you square that with the fact that simultaneously
Speaker 4:  in Congress and elsewhere, we've been endlessly litigating
Speaker 4:  propaganda on TikTok and the kinds of things that people are seeing. And
Speaker 4:  there were, there were huge arguments and there's been some suggestion that
Speaker 4:  one of the things that people got in this infamous briefing
Speaker 4:  last year was about pro-Palestine posts on
Speaker 4:  TikTok and the way that the algorithm is shaping public opinion. Like
Speaker 4:  I understand that it's not in the law, but it, it feels like if you're looking
Speaker 4:  at this, we have to be talking about content a little bit, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, I think that's definitely all, all things that the court
Speaker 5:  will be thinking about. Okay. I think, you know,
Speaker 5:  part of what seems to mitigate that, at least in
Speaker 5:  during the arguments for some of the justices might be that
Speaker 5:  there's both, there's kind of these like two justifications that the government
Speaker 5:  has given for this law, which is both the fear that China
Speaker 5:  could somehow influence by dance to
Speaker 5:  alter the algorithm that TikTok relies on to push
Speaker 5:  a certain narrative to American users. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 5:  a lot of lawmakers saw the very
Speaker 5:  pro-Palestinian content on TikTok as an example of what could be
Speaker 5:  done, whether or not that was actually coming from China or not. And obviously,
Speaker 5:  you know, there's plenty of reasons why, you know, more content
Speaker 5:  might be skewed one way or another on a certain platform based on
Speaker 5:  who's there or whatever. But I think that was an example to them
Speaker 5:  of if China wanted to use this for nefarious reasons to say,
Speaker 5:  you know, to push like anti Taiwan
Speaker 5:  content or something like that. I think that was an example to them of how
Speaker 5:  it might be used. So I think there's that, and then there's also the second
Speaker 5:  reasoning that I think might be even more compelling to
Speaker 5:  the Supreme Court about data security. And that
Speaker 5:  is something that I think is less touches speech a little bit
Speaker 5:  less than, you know, talking about like propaganda
Speaker 5:  and you know, how an algorithm could be used to push that kind of content.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah, I, I do think it, it seemed interesting,
Speaker 4:  even just watching the live stream, this is the most closely I've ever paid
Speaker 4:  attention to a Supreme Court thing, and they
Speaker 4:  do a good job of just kind of calling bullshit on everybody, which is sort
Speaker 4:  of fun that it's like everybody comes up for their turn being told they're
Speaker 4:  liars by the nine justices, which is a dynamic, I actually really appreciate
Speaker 4:  it. But it was, it, there was a certain sense in which the, the
Speaker 4:  TikTok lawyers come up and they're like, okay, this is about free speech.
Speaker 4:  And they're like, Hmm, not really. And then the government lawyers come up
Speaker 4:  and they're like, this is about corporate ownership. And they're like, is
Speaker 4:  it? So it's just, it's kind of mind bending, but I guess the, the
Speaker 4:  idea here is they're, they're just poking at everybody trying to figure out
Speaker 4:  what makes the most sense to them.
Speaker 5:  Right, exactly. And I think you hear them kind of asking questions where
Speaker 5:  they're prodding, like, what are the outer bounds of this? If we were to
Speaker 5:  write something like this, what would that mean? Or how would we do this?
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 4:  That's a good, sorry, I don't mean to interrupt. Yeah, but you just brought
Speaker 4:  up the thing I wanna talk about that I was, was gonna forget about, which
Speaker 4:  is Jeff Bezos who kept coming up. Ian, I think
Speaker 4:  the way that you're describing what, how, why, why did poor Jeff Bezos
Speaker 4:  keep getting pulled into this whole thing?
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Okay. So
Speaker 5:  Bezos kept being brought up by, in these arguments as
Speaker 5:  kind of anal an analogy because obviously Bezos founder
Speaker 5:  of Amazon, who also now owns the Washington Post,
Speaker 5:  you know, I think what they were using him as kind of
Speaker 5:  a foil or of like what would happen if like,
Speaker 5:  you know, there was some kind of influence on, on
Speaker 5:  this owner of a US-based media company
Speaker 5:  by a foreign adversary. And h how is that any different from the
Speaker 5:  ownership structure that we see with TikTok? Like for example,
Speaker 5:  one at one point they talked about what if the Chinese government had
Speaker 5:  like kidnapped Bezos's children and held them hostage
Speaker 5:  so that he would print prop propaganda. Like how is that any different than,
Speaker 5:  you know, a media company that's owned by a foreign adversary versus
Speaker 5:  like one that's being, having a lot of influence by
Speaker 5:  foreign adversary through perhaps nefarious means?
Speaker 4:  What is the point of that analogy? Like what's, what's in the, the, I think
Speaker 4:  it was, was it Sonya Sotomayor who brought that up? I think it
Speaker 4:  was whoever, whichever justice it was. What is the point of that analogy
Speaker 4:  in this case, do you think?
Speaker 5:  I think the idea is that, you know, I think there's this question
Speaker 5:  of what's the kind of like the starting point of
Speaker 5:  the influence and the negative influence that Congress wants to root out.
Speaker 5:  Like is it this like foreign ownership
Speaker 5:  or is it, you know, this influence that could happen on even an
Speaker 5:  American company through some other means. So I
Speaker 5:  think it's kind of trying to find where is that line?
Speaker 4:  Okay, and then I guess as a result, what is the
Speaker 4:  government's role in that moment, right? Like, at what
Speaker 4:  point is the government supposed to get involved here? Seems to be one
Speaker 4:  of the open questions.
Speaker 5:  Right? Right. Okay. And, and like who is allowed to print propaganda
Speaker 5:  because of what influence? And you know, I think those are kind of the main
Speaker 5:  questions there.
Speaker 4:  Okay, that makes sense. So I, it seemed like coming out of these
Speaker 4:  arguments, the, the odds of TikTok
Speaker 4:  winning and, and we should talk about what winning means, but the odds of
Speaker 4:  TikTok winning seemed to go down in a lot of
Speaker 4:  people's minds. Was that your read too?
Speaker 5:  That was my read. I think, you know, I think the only
Speaker 5:  justice who stood out to me as potentially on TikTok side was
Speaker 5:  Justice Gorsuch, who seemed to have concerns about,
Speaker 5:  you know, the evidence in this case. And just,
Speaker 5:  you know, I think a lot of the, the big questions that TikTok has brought
Speaker 5:  up here, but I don't think we saw a clear, you know,
Speaker 5:  vote of support for TikTok for many of the other justices. I think it's
Speaker 5:  possible they get some more on their side, but I think it was, you
Speaker 5:  know, less clear there. And I think my feeling
Speaker 5:  was that the, the questioning was harder on
Speaker 5:  TikTok or seemed to be that they, their thinking was more in line with the
Speaker 5:  US government, but of course, you know, it, it can be hard to just say
Speaker 5:  because they're always talking in hypotheticals and aren't completely tipping
Speaker 5:  their hands.
Speaker 4:  Right. Yeah, I mean, I keep coming back to this question of
Speaker 4:  how real versus theoretical the threat actually
Speaker 4:  is. And it seems like we are still very much in this
Speaker 4:  place of China could do things and TikTok could do things
Speaker 4:  and the algorithm could be doing things. And the,
Speaker 4:  the most real piece of it, I think seems to be the data collection piece.
Speaker 4:  And I wonder if that's why the lawyers continue to focus on it,
Speaker 4:  because that is one thing that is definitely happening and, and is, is provably
Speaker 4:  happening, is that TikTok and by extension, by dance and by extension potentially
Speaker 4:  the Chinese government are collecting vast quantities of data about
Speaker 4:  whatever, it's like almost 200 million people in the United States. That
Speaker 4:  seems bad. Sure. But I, I still, I'm so hung
Speaker 4:  up on this thing that like, I think it was in the spring that a, a bunch
Speaker 4:  of, a bunch of people in Congress got a briefing that was classified
Speaker 4:  about something, some threat the TikTok posed, and then they
Speaker 4:  came out of that briefing and voted 50 to zero to ban it, right? So like
Speaker 4:  that seems bad. And then it, it passed through the house, it passed through
Speaker 4:  the, like, everybody who has seen something
Speaker 4:  appears to come out on the other side saying, this is a problem, we have
Speaker 4:  to get rid of TikTok. But we have never been told what that something is,
Speaker 4:  what was in the briefing, what we actually know. And at this point, even,
Speaker 4:  even the Supreme Court and these lawyers seem to be arguing
Speaker 4:  mostly in theory as opposed to about like
Speaker 4:  the the real stuff that is really happening on the ground right now.
Speaker 4:  Did I miss anything? Are there, are there concrete things going on that we're
Speaker 4:  talking about now that we haven't been in the past or are we still kind of
Speaker 4:  just talking about what TikTok might be?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think that's true as far as we're publicly aware. I
Speaker 5:  think, you know, we don't really know what was said behind
Speaker 5:  closed doors, what sort of classified information the government does
Speaker 5:  possess. So I don't think we can say for sure that there're
Speaker 5:  not aware of any actual ongoing or,
Speaker 5:  you know, past action that the Chinese government has taken with regards
Speaker 5:  to TikTok. But, you know, I, I think
Speaker 5:  the way that it's been discussed from people who've seen the information,
Speaker 5:  at least doesn't seem to me that there was necessarily
Speaker 5:  that kind of thing going on, although, you know, hard to say, you
Speaker 5:  know, maybe they just can't even allude to it. Right.
Speaker 5:  But I think it at least seems like there
Speaker 5:  us intelligence officials feel like there is enough possibility
Speaker 5:  there or access for the Chinese government to
Speaker 5:  potentially gain to bite dance and thereby to
Speaker 5:  TikTok and American users that they feel like it's a sufficient enough threat
Speaker 5:  to guard against. And I think maybe feel that, why
Speaker 5:  should we wait for an attack to happen to take actions against it,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah. And I I'm so conflicted on that line of thinking and
Speaker 4:  it, it does feel like it underpins a lot of this where it goes back to the
Speaker 4:  what are we even arguing about question, right? And I think there is either
Speaker 4:  something that we're arguing about that we the public don't
Speaker 4:  yet know about or we are arguing in theory
Speaker 4:  and, and it feels, it feels very different to me which one of those it turns
Speaker 4:  out to be. And I'm not sure we're ever gonna know. And that drives me insane.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But so the, the other thing that kept coming up is the question of
Speaker 4:  basically why hasn't TikTok just sold yet? Like why, why
Speaker 4:  even go through all of this hassle? Just let somebody write you a check for
Speaker 4:  many tens of billions of dollars and move on with your life. And I think
Speaker 4:  tiktoks argument seems to be that it's not actually that simple that actually
Speaker 4:  selling isn't really an option. Can you explain that a little bit? What,
Speaker 4:  what is, what is the argument that selling is not only not a good idea, but
Speaker 4:  sort of impossible?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, So I think even before that I would say, you know, any business
Speaker 5:  that's in active litigation, they're not going to
Speaker 5:  want to kind of give the court a sense that, you know,
Speaker 5:  a sale is possible. That you know what the, what the government wants them
Speaker 5:  to do, they're gonna be able to just do easily.
Speaker 4:  That's fair. If they could just go take the money, they, they have every
Speaker 4:  reason to not tell you they can do that. That is fair,
Speaker 5:  Right? I think it's in TikTok and by dance's interest to exhaust every legal
Speaker 5:  route before they really pursue a sale. At the
Speaker 5:  same time, I think tiktoks argument is that this is really
Speaker 5:  not super feasible to just separate from by dance.
Speaker 5:  You know, there's so much like code intermixed like that we're relying
Speaker 5:  on this algorithm, you know, just to extract
Speaker 5:  is like really an arduous task. It's not as simple as just like,
Speaker 5:  you know, cutting off at one point. So I think that's probably true. You
Speaker 5:  know, a a lot of this is like years of
Speaker 5:  technology being built and I don't think it's gonna be that simple
Speaker 5:  just to separate. At the same time, I think another
Speaker 5:  part of the argument is just that China won't sell the app.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's something that the DC circuit said, well that's not our
Speaker 5:  problem.
Speaker 5:  And you know, I think basically China's able to
Speaker 5:  block the sale if they want to. They are able to,
Speaker 5:  they consider the algorithm and export. So they could definitely clamp down
Speaker 5:  on that and say, by dance you cannot sell this algorithm
Speaker 5:  beyond that, you know, groups like Project Liberty
Speaker 5:  are interested in just buying the app without the algorithm, which would
Speaker 5:  mean like, you know, the the underlying platform, the user
Speaker 5:  base, the content, things like that. But even then
Speaker 5:  China could kind of exert its influence on ance and say, you can't
Speaker 5:  do that. And you know, an an expert in, you know,
Speaker 5:  kind of China business told me that
Speaker 5:  this is something that might be in the country's interest to hang on to
Speaker 5:  TikTok, both because they have markets in other parts of the
Speaker 5:  country where TikTok could still be active and they also
Speaker 5:  might be betting, hey, you know, someday maybe TikTok will be allowed back
Speaker 5:  in the US and then we wanna be the ones able to capitalize
Speaker 5:  on that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it's a really interesting sort of parallel universe.
Speaker 4:  I don't think it's gonna happen. It seems very unlikely to me that TikTok
Speaker 4:  changes hands in some meaningful way in the next five days. I could be wrong,
Speaker 4:  I sort of hope I'm wrong because I think it'll be fascinating to see what
Speaker 4:  that looks like. But one of the things that, that one of the lawyers is saying
Speaker 4:  in those arguments is that even If you allow TikTok to
Speaker 4:  be sold or or exchange hands in some way, it
Speaker 4:  completely changes what TikTok is. Which is the thing I find
Speaker 4:  absolutely true. That seems right to me. That right under new owners with
Speaker 4:  a new team, with a new code base, you have a thing that looks like TikTok
Speaker 4:  but is in every real practical way, not TikTok. And I think
Speaker 4:  the question of what that would look like is just as a person who is
Speaker 4:  interested in products and like how we interact with technology, I find that
Speaker 4:  so fascinating because it's never really happened before that. Like, what
Speaker 4:  If you took the thing everyone cared about and just like
Speaker 4:  ship a thesis it and just like changed all the parts, would it still be TikTok?
Speaker 4:  I think the answer is no, but it would be really, it, it would be really
Speaker 4:  interesting to find out. But I, I do find that argument that even If you,
Speaker 4:  If you sort of keep a thing called TikTok alive, but change everything about
Speaker 4:  it, it kills TikTok. I think, I kind of think that's right. That feels right
Speaker 4:  to me.
Speaker 5:  I I'm, yeah, I I think it's hard to say. I think there is
Speaker 5:  a huge benefit of having 170 million
Speaker 5:  American users on the app already that can't be discounted and for sure all
Speaker 5:  the content that already exists. I mean, that's a lot to work with.
Speaker 5:  Even If you don't have, you know, this like secret sauce
Speaker 5:  algorithm that fight dance has come up with, I think, you know,
Speaker 5:  I could see how it might be possible to overlay another algorithm in here
Speaker 5:  that is able to do something pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, I, I, again, I like this is sort of the future I'm hoping for because
Speaker 4:  I think it would just be fascinating. I would just love to see all of that
Speaker 4:  play out, but I don't think it's gonna happen. What do you think is gonna
Speaker 4:  happen here? Like the, we have five days from when this episode publishes
Speaker 4:  to the, the January 19th deadline of some kind.
Speaker 4:  It seems like to me the two most likely possibilities are
Speaker 4:  that either the Supreme Court issue, some kind of
Speaker 4:  stay, the, the, the ban is a day before the
Speaker 4:  Trump inauguration and it seems reasonably logical that the, the Supreme
Speaker 4:  Court might say we're just gonna let the next administration decide what
Speaker 4:  it wants to do with this, or
Speaker 4:  some kind of mix of those things will happen that
Speaker 4:  like, and and you raised this possibility in a story you wrote about it that
Speaker 4:  like the ban might happen, but then Trump might come in and decide not to
Speaker 4:  care. But then that has some weird implications. Like what, what is
Speaker 4:  your sense of fast forward seven days from now, what do you think's going
Speaker 4:  on?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, So I mean my best educated guess is
Speaker 5:  that the ban does go into effect on January 19th.
Speaker 5:  The Supreme Court lets it happen and then
Speaker 5:  Trump gets inaugurated the next day. Perhaps he instructs
Speaker 5:  his DOJ not to enforce it,
Speaker 5:  but probably Google and Apple still follow it because
Speaker 5:  as was pointed out in oral arguments, there's a
Speaker 5:  five-year statute of limitation on this law. So if those
Speaker 5:  companies break the law now, they could still be prosecuted for it
Speaker 5:  later on unless, you know, they're able to argue that we were
Speaker 5:  doing this under the, you know, promise that we wouldn't be
Speaker 5:  prosecuted and perhaps they'll win that argument. But it
Speaker 5:  is still risky for those companies. Right.
Speaker 4:  So and the, and the, the two sort of practical pieces of the ban, if I have
Speaker 4:  this right, are app stores can't host the app. So that,
Speaker 4:  that's like what you're saying where Google and App will come in and I think
Speaker 4:  they get fined for every person who downloads the app after the 19th
Speaker 4:  is the idea. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They get fined $5,000 per user that accesses the app.
Speaker 5:  Wow. So that really adds up. Oh
Speaker 4:  Wow. Yeah. So, okay. So the theory then is even If you make it through the
Speaker 4:  four years, some new president comes in in four
Speaker 4:  years and says, just kidding, I'm going to enforce all four
Speaker 4:  years of $5,000 per person fines. Right.
Speaker 5:  Or Trump gets mad at Tim Cook or Sunup Chai.
Speaker 4:  Oh sure. And then he just changes his mind, hold this over his Interesting,
Speaker 4:  okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Although, you know, I think again it, what came up during oral arguments
Speaker 5:  is perhaps they'd have some sort of due process claim to say,
Speaker 5:  you know, we were operating under this promise of non-enforcement and maybe
Speaker 5:  they would win that. But again, risky given how much they
Speaker 5:  have at stake in penalties.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. So best case scenario, that's a giant mess. And then the
Speaker 4:  other sort of practical side of it is US
Speaker 4:  providers are banned from hosting TikTok in any correct sort of meaningful
Speaker 4:  way, right? So it's not like illegal to use TikTok
Speaker 4:  after January 19th. It's just that essentially everyone who
Speaker 4:  provides TikTok to you is no longer allowed to, so it has the effect of a
Speaker 4:  ban, but like it's, it's not against the law to have TikTok on your phone
Speaker 4:  after January 19th. Right,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Okay. And the app isn't just gonna like poof and disappear from
Speaker 5:  your phone. It'll still be there just If you haven't downloaded it, you
Speaker 5:  won't be able to. And If you have downloaded it, it's probably
Speaker 5:  within a few weeks, months, we don't really know, we'll just
Speaker 5:  start to degrade to a point that it becomes basically unusable.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think anyone who has ever like had an old iPad and like app
Speaker 4:  by app, it just sort of stops working because they don't update anymore 'cause
Speaker 4:  they don't get the security updates or whatever. Like that's what'll happen
Speaker 4:  to TikTok. Right. And it'll be sometime yeah, in the, in the weeks or months
Speaker 4:  afterwards, like every individual feature will just start to break and then
Speaker 4:  there won't be any more videos and then, and then that'll just be the end.
Speaker 4:  So. Okay, so you think something, something this will happen on
Speaker 4:  January 19th. What do you, what do you think happens on
Speaker 4:  say January 21st, we'll, we'll stop for inauguration day 'cause you know,
Speaker 4:  there's a whole thing that's gotta happen. What, what's your
Speaker 4:  read on what might happen After that? What is kind of the, the betting favorite
Speaker 4:  for, you know, the week after?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think it's possible that Trump then does
Speaker 5:  instruct his DOJ not to enforce the law and then that just,
Speaker 5:  you know, because at least for him that would give him a chance
Speaker 5:  to say, look, I tried to save TikTok and if Apple and Google
Speaker 5:  don't want to let you have it, then that's on them. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  So I think it's possible we see something like that and then it's on those
Speaker 5:  companies to decide what risks they're willing to take. I don't know that
Speaker 5:  they're gonna be willing to stick their necks out for a, another company
Speaker 5:  one with which Google, for example, competes with directly
Speaker 5:  through YouTube shorts. So
Speaker 5:  I think we will see some form of a ban. I think After
Speaker 5:  that point, maybe we see some discussions about
Speaker 5:  a deal. I think maybe Trump, instead of trying to get
Speaker 5:  the DJ not to enforce the law, tries to use it as leverage to
Speaker 5:  extract some kind of deal to end up making
Speaker 5:  TikTok in compliance with the law. But like we were discussing earlier,
Speaker 5:  I think it seems unlikely that China would actually be willing to sell the
Speaker 5:  app. And that's really, that's really the bottom line is it's
Speaker 5:  up to China to decide to sell it. And I think that's a big part of why we
Speaker 5:  haven't seen a sale up to this point.
Speaker 4:  Right, right. And do you think, If you were to tell 12 months
Speaker 4:  ago you that this is the point that we've landed on
Speaker 4:  January 14th, 2025, would you have been surprised?
Speaker 4:  I would've been surprised,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I guess that would've been before this bill was even introduced.
Speaker 5:  I'm pretty sure I would've been surprised. Mostly because not
Speaker 5:  much happens to, you know, to the point of
Speaker 5:  being introduced into law and,
Speaker 5:  you know, going to the Supreme Court in tech policy, you know, we've tried
Speaker 5:  to get much more, you know, basic things passed
Speaker 5:  in tech policy, like privacy legislation, you know, basic privacy
Speaker 5:  protections. And that has been just held up
Speaker 5:  in Congress for years and years and years and somehow they were able to
Speaker 5:  get, you know, hundreds of lawmakers behind this law
Speaker 5:  in very short order. And we're now at the point that the Supreme
Speaker 5:  Court is about to give a thumbs up or a thumbs down on it,
Speaker 5:  basically.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If you've trained me on one thing in the time that I've known you,
Speaker 4:  it's that the speed of this is insane. Yeah. Like a, the fact
Speaker 4:  that it happened that it managed to go through this whole process in a
Speaker 4:  relatively bipartisan way is remarkable given what happens to the tech. But
Speaker 4:  also the fact that we did it in essentially like eight months is just
Speaker 4:  unheard of. Like it's, yeah, it's, and given the fact that we had tried
Speaker 4:  this before and it failed and everybody was mad for a long time, but kind
Speaker 4:  of nothing happened and then just all of a sudden like poof out of nowhere
Speaker 4:  and it just runs through this whole process in eight months and might actually
Speaker 4:  finish on January 19th, is, is just procedurally
Speaker 4:  wild.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean this is extremely unusual for tech policy
Speaker 5:  for Congress in general. It's very much unprecedented.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Alright, before I let you go, let's just talk for five minutes about
Speaker 4:  meta. Sure. We talked a little bit about this on the show last week in Vegas.
Speaker 4:  The, the moderation changes the company's been making. Mark Zuckerberg went
Speaker 4:  on Joe Rogan and had a lot of thoughts about masculinity.
Speaker 4:  We'll leave that to the site. I think there are a couple of stories we wrote
Speaker 4:  that are very good that I'll put in the show notes that you should go read.
Speaker 4:  But I'm particularly curious for you as a person covering like
Speaker 4:  politics and policy, what do you, what do you make of all of
Speaker 4:  these moves that are making, this is happening right before we inaugurate
Speaker 4:  a new president, a new, a new administration is about to come in.
Speaker 4:  What are you seeing in the, the politicking of all of this?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, So I think I kind of separat it into two buckets in
Speaker 5:  my mind, the first bucket is like what normally happens when there's
Speaker 5:  a change in administration and businesses realize, alright, we
Speaker 5:  gotta, we gotta figure out how we're gonna deal with this for the next four
Speaker 5:  years. So, you know, I think things like having Joel
Speaker 5:  Kaplan take over a lot of their policy operations
Speaker 5:  make sense. I think that's a very kind of standard move to kind of have
Speaker 5:  someone who's more in line with the current administration lead your policy
Speaker 5:  office. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I also put the, everybody donating to the inauguration fund in that same
Speaker 4:  bucket. Totally. That it's like totally, you could be cynical about that
Speaker 4:  all you want and you can be mad that companies don't live out their values,
Speaker 4:  whatever. But like that is the most straightforward transactional. We would
Speaker 4:  like to be in a room with the new president more often move and
Speaker 4:  every company is going to do it
Speaker 5:  Right. I think no one's gonna, none of these companies are going to
Speaker 5:  just say, you know what? On principle we're gonna sit this one
Speaker 5:  out. We're gonna like, I don't think that's really in any of their interests.
Speaker 5:  They want to have a seat at the table, they wanna have a good starting point.
Speaker 5:  And, you know, I don't think it's that big of a deal to them to
Speaker 5:  donate a million dollars to these like multi-billion dollar corporations.
Speaker 5:  So I think yeah, that's definitely in the same bucket to me. And
Speaker 5:  I think there's also the fact that Elon Musk is right in Trump's ear.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I think they realize if we're not at the table, then the only person
Speaker 5:  they're hearing from in tech is Elon Musk and Yep. Do we wanna go along
Speaker 5:  with all the policies that only he is representing to Trump? So
Speaker 5:  I think they all know like, we need to, we need to be in play here. And I
Speaker 5:  think a lot of the moves are about that. I think there's also, you know,
Speaker 5:  things like the end of fact checking at meta
Speaker 5:  seems like something that maybe Mark Zuckerberg wanted to do for a while,
Speaker 5:  and this is a, you know, a good way for him to do it while also
Speaker 5:  kind of gaining some points with Trump. Then I think there's like this other
Speaker 5:  bucket where it's, you know, things that are really geared at
Speaker 5:  Trump in particular at, you know, this full Republican
Speaker 5:  sweep across the government that we're going to see take over.
Speaker 5:  And I think, you know, it's a recognition that the times have changed. We
Speaker 5:  have to really change how we go about things. And also
Speaker 5:  maybe perhaps a sense from within Zuckerberg himself that
Speaker 5:  he's felt like we've gone too far or, you know, this
Speaker 5:  isn't the way that I want to run this company. I think we've always seen
Speaker 5:  him kind of say, he doesn't wanna be the speech police, he doesn't wanna
Speaker 5:  decide what's right and wrong. And I think we've seen that
Speaker 5:  impulse take different iterations, whether it's the oversight board
Speaker 5:  or something else. And now we're seeing it take shape with him trying
Speaker 5:  to not involve fact checkers and to really loosen
Speaker 5:  speech policies on his platforms. And I think
Speaker 5:  the, the fact checking again, I think seems like something he wanted
Speaker 5:  to do for a long time. I think the changes to,
Speaker 5:  you know, what sort of speech is allowed on meta platforms
Speaker 5:  is probably like the more overall impactful thing because there's
Speaker 5:  just gonna be a wider range of the kinds of
Speaker 5:  speech that you're going to see on those platforms that I think a lot
Speaker 5:  of users probably won't wanna see.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think one version of his
Speaker 4:  thinking, he being Mark Zuckerberg that I actually find
Speaker 4:  if not good then at least sort of reasonable, is that I think
Speaker 4:  he has spent a long time learning that
Speaker 4:  trying to be out front of speech policy is a total waste of time That
Speaker 4:  Yep. That caring about this stuff politically is
Speaker 4:  all downside. And, and it has, it has gained him nothing. And I think after
Speaker 4:  four years of fighting with the Biden administration about all the bad things
Speaker 4:  that are happening on meta platforms, he is now just like, you know what?
Speaker 4:  Screw it. Like, I, I don't care. There is now a president who doesn't care.
Speaker 4:  Why on earth would I continue to fight this fight? All it does is cause me
Speaker 4:  pain. And I think a, that is a
Speaker 4:  perfectly reasonable place for him to have landed. And BI think that sucks,
Speaker 4:  right? Like, that is a, that is a real problem for a lot of people on a lot
Speaker 4:  of platforms, but I also kind of understand how he got there and it, it,
Speaker 4:  like, it says a lot about our political environment that both of those things
Speaker 4:  can be true at the same time. But I do wonder, like, are we just at a point
Speaker 4:  now where we're just gonna stop talking about speech policy because it's
Speaker 4:  just a total waste of everybody's time and energy?
Speaker 5:  I think that's highly possible. I think it feels so bleak
Speaker 4:  To say out loud, but I honestly feel like that's where we are.
Speaker 5:  No, I think So I think, you know, we went from this world of like, you
Speaker 5:  know, oh, social media platforms are so new and you know, it's just the
Speaker 5:  wild West and everyone says whatever they want. And then
Speaker 5:  realizing, okay, well we can't get advertisers on here if we just have
Speaker 5:  actual Nazis here and people don't wanna see that stuff.
Speaker 5:  And I think, you know, we went through kind of a big reckoning where we went
Speaker 5:  a lot in the other direction, and then I think the
Speaker 5:  companies realized, oh, actually by actively doing
Speaker 5:  something around speech policies,
Speaker 5:  we're getting a lot of flack because we're both being told we're not going
Speaker 5:  far enough and we're being told we're going too far. Right? And so we can't
Speaker 5:  win. And So I think this is kind of, you know, mark Zuckerberg throwing up
Speaker 5:  his hand saying like, all right, you know, more than half the
Speaker 5:  country voted for Trump this time
Speaker 5:  and, you know, whatever. Like, let's like not do
Speaker 5:  something instead of doing something and we'll still get yelled at either
Speaker 5:  way.
Speaker 4:  Right. Yeah. How much do you think this is about
Speaker 4:  Mark Zuckerberg in particular? Because, you know, a lot has been made
Speaker 4:  of, of Trump's prognostications about throwing Zuckerberg in jail for the
Speaker 4:  rest of his life. And there has obviously been some tension here. But
Speaker 4:  then on the flip side, I I agree with you that watching him
Speaker 4:  sit there with Joe Rogan, it felt like he was unloading a bunch of stuff
Speaker 4:  that has been sitting on his chest for a very long time. So
Speaker 4:  I, I guess this is sort of an impossible question to answer, but like, to
Speaker 4:  what extent do you think this is him playing politics with a new president
Speaker 4:  versus like freed by a new president to just say the things he
Speaker 4:  already believed? And I'm sure it's some of both.
Speaker 5:  I, yeah, I definitely think it's both. I think, you know, if,
Speaker 5:  if you're threatened by Donald Trump with being thrown in jail, you know,
Speaker 5:  he, he says a lot of things and maybe he's not actually gonna try to do that,
Speaker 5:  but like maybe he will. And I think you would wanna get on his good side.
Speaker 5:  So I'm, I'd imagine that's a factor in his thinking. At
Speaker 5:  the same time, I think from a lot of recent interviews that Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 5:  has done, I think there's this sense that he is like sick of apologizing
Speaker 5:  and he's like sick of having always been the bad guy
Speaker 5:  and, you know, having to try to do the right thing and everyone
Speaker 5:  yells at him no matter what. So I think it, it seems like it is somewhat
Speaker 5:  a personal change in thinking of like, well, I can't please
Speaker 5:  everyone, so let me please the person who has the
Speaker 5:  most power here for the next four years. Right.
Speaker 4:  Just to be clear, we don't feel bad for Mark Zuckerberg No. Having, having
Speaker 4:  to have spent all this time apologizing for the thing that you built. I don't
Speaker 4:  feel that bad. Sorry, buddy. But, but yeah. And I, I,
Speaker 4:  what I wonder is how much
Speaker 4:  fallout that is going to have, right? Because he is like, we are in a moment
Speaker 4:  where it is now really easy to say the things that people
Speaker 4:  have been saying quietly for years loudly. And I think
Speaker 4:  the, the, we're starting to see those policies start to shift and we're starting
Speaker 4:  to see that the, like forced culture shift back to
Speaker 4:  some things that had started to change but now are being unwound
Speaker 4:  again. And the question of like, is this
Speaker 4:  just Mark, is this just meta or is
Speaker 4:  there a broader sort of Silicon Valley culture change coming in? All of
Speaker 4:  that to me is like one of the big questions of the next few months. And
Speaker 4:  I got the sense even just talking to folks After that Rogan podcast
Speaker 4:  that like, I think we're gonna look back at that as a moment where like,
Speaker 4:  it, it, somebody said the quiet parts really, really, really, really loud
Speaker 4:  and got away with it, and now here we are.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean I think we've definitely seen this culture shift in Silicon
Speaker 5:  Valley and I think there's always been maybe some underpinning of that
Speaker 5:  in kind of this more libertarian slant that, you know,
Speaker 5:  Silicon Valley tech people have tended to have for a long
Speaker 5:  time. At the same time, I think it, you always have to look
Speaker 5:  at like, what's gonna go on with the actual businesses. And If you look at
Speaker 5:  Meta's business, you know, to tie back to the TikTok thing, if TikTok is
Speaker 5:  banned, Meta's gonna be like almost the only game in town
Speaker 5:  for Yeah. Like these short form videos. Obviously there's also YouTube shorts,
Speaker 5:  but you know, that's a TikTok is a huge competitor and then you
Speaker 5:  think about their meta's also involved in a
Speaker 5:  anti-monopoly suit from the FTC.
Speaker 5:  And you know, part of the thinking behind that is that,
Speaker 5:  you know, meta has become so big and stayed so big because
Speaker 5:  they're one of the only places to go and they've made that,
Speaker 5:  they've made sure that's the case. Those are the allegations that the FTC
Speaker 5:  would have. So I think, you know, are
Speaker 5:  people really going to leave Facebook and Instagram if they
Speaker 5:  disagree with these policies? Some might, but probably not
Speaker 5:  enough to really warrant Zuckerberg, you know, doing another
Speaker 5:  180 on his thinking
Speaker 4:  Here. Yeah. Historically speaking the answer is no. Some people leave very
Speaker 4:  loudly and most people don't. Exactly. And, and I think more and
Speaker 4:  more people are getting more and more willing to make that small trade in
Speaker 4:  favor of some of these other things like hoping that Trump will not try and
Speaker 4:  break your company up, which is a real thing that's sitting in front of Mark
Speaker 4:  Zuckerberg.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna say that if the end of 2025 is I have to use
Speaker 4:  Instagram reels exclusively, then this sucks. I
Speaker 4:  will, I will, I want any outcome that does not end with me having to use
Speaker 4:  Instagram reels. That's all
Speaker 5:  I want. Yeah. I mean, if the end of 2025 is anything like the end
Speaker 5:  of 2024, I think we, we don't know what's gonna happen this year. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's, that's, that's very real. All right, Lauren, thank you as always.
Speaker 4:  I suspect we are going to do this Oh so many times and I suspect at some
Speaker 4:  point you and I are gonna be in a courtroom together this year and I'm very
Speaker 4:  much looking forward to it.
Speaker 5:  Can't wait.
Speaker 4:  Alright, see ya.
Speaker 5:  Bye.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna
Speaker 4:  talk Kickstarter. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we're back. So I was at CES last week and one of the
Speaker 4:  things that you see at CES is just an infinite supply
Speaker 4:  of new ideas about technology. You also see an infinite
Speaker 4:  supply of copycat ideas about new technology. One of the amazing things
Speaker 4:  about CES is how quickly you see ideas percolate. Somebody
Speaker 4:  invents a thing and then it just spreads like wildfire among every other
Speaker 4:  company because things are mostly easy to make now. And I think that's
Speaker 4:  fascinating, but to me it's the new stuff that I think is most interesting.
Speaker 4:  You see so many booze that are just one person standing there
Speaker 4:  with a thing that they made and they're there to show it to people, but
Speaker 4:  also to try to get funding and to try to make partnerships. And it is very
Speaker 4:  much a trade show in that sense. And so much of what
Speaker 4:  we see in the world comes from like a person standing in a booth with
Speaker 4:  a thing that they made. And those are the people. Kickstarter has always
Speaker 4:  tried to help. Kickstarter has been around for many years now and
Speaker 4:  has gotten lots of interesting products off the ground. There's a decent
Speaker 4:  chance that a lot of gadgets that you use start on Kickstarter.
Speaker 4:  The Aura Ring, I think was a Kickstarter, pebble was a Kickstarter. Lots
Speaker 4:  of things have grown really huge out of Kickstarter,
Speaker 6:  new into the world, then I go to Kickstarter. Kickstarter has evolved
Speaker 6:  to the point where now we still have tons of creators who
Speaker 6:  need to get, get the money to get things off the ground, but
Speaker 6:  as the company has evolved
Speaker 6:  now we have, you know, billion dollar multinational
Speaker 6:  corporations, big tech companies, big creators
Speaker 6:  that are well established, that values the community and the
Speaker 6:  millions of people within the Kickstarter community where it's like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  If you wanna launch anything new, no matter where you are in your career,
Speaker 6:  where you are in the life cycle as a creator or entrepreneur or as
Speaker 6:  a business, Kickstarter is a valuable community because we have
Speaker 6:  such incredible backers that want to just support new
Speaker 6:  things. And I think what's beautiful about Kickstarter, especially over the
Speaker 6:  past couple years, is that we've evolved past just a crowdfunding
Speaker 6:  platform. Mm. We're building new products and features, new
Speaker 6:  business lines to support creators throughout the
Speaker 6:  entire lifecycle of, you know, their creator journey or
Speaker 6:  their, their entrepreneurial journey. So it's not just about, hey, you know,
Speaker 6:  before it was like, Hey, I'm gonna raise some money on Kickstarter, and then
Speaker 6:  it was like, good luck. Now Kickstarter is building this ecosystem of
Speaker 6:  products, features, and services that help you throughout the entire lifecycle
Speaker 6:  as a creator.
Speaker 4:  So, okay, I was gonna get to this later, but you, you just brought up one
Speaker 4:  of the things that I most wanted to talk about, which is that shift
Speaker 4:  from like, I've made a thing and I need some money to make more of them
Speaker 4:  to big established companies launching stuff on
Speaker 4:  Kickstarter. And Yeah, candidly, I've always wondered if that's a thing Kickstarter
Speaker 4:  like secretly hates that it, it like, it, it like breaks the vibe of the
Speaker 4:  platform for like a multinational corporation to come show up and try to
Speaker 4:  crowdfund something. Yeah. But there is something about
Speaker 4:  that that continues to work for these companies. And I've never
Speaker 4:  been able to put my finger on exactly why. And even as we cover it, it's
Speaker 4:  a challenge because like, it is that whole gamut of things and it's like,
Speaker 4:  okay, here is a product that's being launched. It could be either
Speaker 4:  like a dude who made a thing with a 3D printer and now wants to figure
Speaker 4:  out how to go make millions of them. Yeah. But it could also be a company
Speaker 4:  that's done this 20 times and is perfectly reputable and this thing is gonna
Speaker 4:  launch no matter what happens. And I think trying to figure out how
Speaker 4:  Kickstarter sort of can be all of those things is,
Speaker 4:  has, has just always been tricky for me as somebody like covering these gadgets
Speaker 4:  and talking about them. Can, can Kickstarter be all those things
Speaker 4:  to all those people?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I think So. I mean, I think first of all, I will, I
Speaker 6:  will say this, when larger creators or larger companies with larger
Speaker 6:  audiences come onto the platform, like it just brings eyes
Speaker 6:  and attention to other things that's on the platform, it grows the
Speaker 6:  community. And so yes, is there always gonna be a subset of people
Speaker 6:  like, you know, vocal minority, that's like, Hey, I don't like that L'Oreal
Speaker 6:  just dropped something on Kickstarter or whatever, which
Speaker 6:  they drop something very awesome. But
Speaker 6:  yes, we're gonna continue to have that, right? But the numbers
Speaker 6:  don't lie, the data doesn't lie. Them coming to the platform
Speaker 6:  actually helps smaller creators tremendously because of the visibility
Speaker 6:  that it brings to the platform and to other projects that are
Speaker 6:  currently on the platform. So we see an uptick for other projects
Speaker 6:  when those big creators or those big companies come to the platform.
Speaker 6:  So it's actually helpful. And one thing that I think is beautiful
Speaker 6:  about our community, specifically for design and technology and
Speaker 6:  new innovation, they're less attached to,
Speaker 6:  or they, they tend to be less attached to who is doing it and more
Speaker 6:  about what it is. Like they just want the, the coolest,
Speaker 6:  newest in most innovative thing. They're not so
Speaker 6:  tied to who that person is, which is a little bit
Speaker 6:  different when you get to categories like film and music and more
Speaker 6:  creative categories, right? And so to me, I think we can, we can
Speaker 6:  serve both because we have an audience of people that just want
Speaker 6:  really, really cool products right? At the end of the day.
Speaker 4:  That's really interesting. Yeah, and I think one of the questions I
Speaker 4:  think Kickstarter has always tried to reckon with is do we treat these things
Speaker 4:  like sort of transactional businesses or do we treat them
Speaker 4:  like content creators, right? Because like, I think there, it's a really
Speaker 4:  complicated balance, right? Because on the one hand it's like, I buy,
Speaker 4:  I, I pre-order a cooler, I expect that cooler to ship to my house,
Speaker 4:  right? Yes. Like that's a pretty straightforward transaction that we're all
Speaker 4:  used to all the time. But if I back a creator that I like, the,
Speaker 4:  the thing that I ask for in return is more
Speaker 4:  squishy and nebulous. Like, if they don't make anything, that's probably
Speaker 4:  bad, but I don't expect like complete control and specificity over what they're
Speaker 4:  gonna make. So like that, that relationship is just really different. But,
Speaker 4:  but it also sounds like the way you're seeing it, maybe it's not that different
Speaker 4:  that maybe even if I'm buying the cooler and I expect the cooler to ship
Speaker 4:  to my house, there is still some of that like content
Speaker 4:  creator, personality, relationship stuff going on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think it depends on the person, David. I think you're a very rational,
Speaker 6:  sensible human being. And so you're looking at it that way
Speaker 6:  where there's other people that come, you know, we, we talk about this all
Speaker 6:  the time at Kickstarter. When you pledge on Kickstarter, it says right there
Speaker 6:  in bold, Kickstarter is not a store. Meaning that,
Speaker 6:  hey, this, we're not guarantee guarantee you're gonna get this
Speaker 6:  product. We're not guaranteeing you're gonna get something that you like,
Speaker 6:  you know, even close to maybe what you, what you thought you were gonna get.
Speaker 6:  This stuff is hard, especially for first time creators and things like that.
Speaker 6:  Over 90% of creators actually do fulfill. I'm very happy about that.
Speaker 6:  I'm very proud of that number. But it doesn't always happen,
Speaker 6:  right? There's unforeseen things that happen all the time with creators
Speaker 6:  and entrepreneurs. And So I think there
Speaker 6:  are some backers who are like very, just like, almost
Speaker 6:  like e-commerce shoppers. Like I see a thing, I see a product, I
Speaker 6:  want it, I don't care if it's John or Sue or whoever
Speaker 6:  doing it. I don't care about the backstory, I just want that product. And
Speaker 6:  then you have some backers who are like really emotionally
Speaker 6:  invested in that creator, their story, what they're trying to
Speaker 6:  do. I love those backers by the way, because that is, I think that's
Speaker 6:  what's special about Kickstarter, that that emotional connection
Speaker 6:  that you have to somebody, because doing something
Speaker 6:  new or putting something new out, new out into the world is a very brave
Speaker 6:  thing to do. And I think those people that emotionally connect to that, I
Speaker 6:  think that's a very beautiful thing. But we have some people like that and
Speaker 6:  then we also have some people who just want the product. Neither are wrong.
Speaker 6:  Right. But there's just two different experiences on the platform.
Speaker 4:  Well, I, I agree that neither are wrong, but it does seem like on
Speaker 4:  some level you have to pick one. Right? Because like you said, you know,
Speaker 4:  90% of creators ship is both a very high number and a very low number.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Kind of all at the same time, right? Yeah. Like if, if if
Speaker 4:  Samsung only shipped 90% of the stuff that they launched, like, that'd be,
Speaker 4:  that's a problem. Yeah. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. For
Speaker 4:  Sure. And so, and I, I do feel like, I think a thing that I,
Speaker 4:  I've noticed over the years is I think Kickstarter has gone out of
Speaker 4:  its way to act less and less like a shopping mall.
Speaker 4:  But is is that, has, has that been deliberate on your side? Like, If you
Speaker 4:  had to pick one of those two approaches, it seems like you, you're much happier
Speaker 4:  on the side of like, be part of a community working
Speaker 4:  on something together, rather than show up by a thing and don't check on
Speaker 4:  it until it appears at your house in some months.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but that's because I'm like an empath and I'm a pro empathy
Speaker 6:  person, you know? Sure. You know, like at the end of the day, I'm an
Speaker 6:  entrepreneur myself, I'm a creator myself, So I understand
Speaker 6:  everything that goes into it. All the unforeseen things that could
Speaker 6:  potentially happen that can derail you,
Speaker 6:  you know? And so for me, I just have that level of empathy
Speaker 6:  and understanding. There's some projects that don't deliver for a year,
Speaker 6:  sometimes two years, right? Like the, these things have, and then you
Speaker 6:  have some more experienced creators who are like, they're cranking
Speaker 6:  these things out like clockwork, right? Like they already have the manufacturing
Speaker 6:  down pat, they know what they're doing, et cetera, et cetera. They'll launch
Speaker 6:  a Kickstarter and we'll literally release the product that that next week,
Speaker 6:  right? Right. So there's different types of creators on the
Speaker 6:  platform. But I do think what makes Kickstarter fundamentally
Speaker 6:  different from, you know, an Amazon or someone else like that in e-commerce,
Speaker 6:  is that these are people who are, who are genuinely
Speaker 6:  trying to get an idea out there. And I do think that emotional connection
Speaker 6:  and that sense of community and coming together is
Speaker 6:  really special. And I think that's why also the bigger
Speaker 6:  corporations still like to launch on Kickstarter. 'cause
Speaker 6:  the people are so passionate, and they'll give you that feedback and they'll
Speaker 6:  be real with you. And they'll also, if they feel very happy with
Speaker 6:  what you, what you do, they will be advocates for that product and that brand,
Speaker 6:  I think it first starts with the creator. I know we just talked about the
Speaker 6:  whole thing about like, you know, there are people that treat it more like
Speaker 6:  e-commerce, but I think
Speaker 6:  it always starts with the creator man. Like the creator,
Speaker 6:  their story, their passion, their drive,
Speaker 6:  how people resonate with their story and whatever they're trying to produce,
Speaker 6:  but also who they are as a person. I tell people all the time,
Speaker 6:  Kickstarter is no cakewalk. Like people will come on the
Speaker 6:  platform and fail because they think, oh, I just put a project on Kickstarter
Speaker 6:  and then people are just going to give me money. No, you have to have a true
Speaker 6:  go to market strategy. You gotta have a plan, you gotta have great storytelling.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  So I, if you're thinking about it that way, right? If it, if you're sort
Speaker 4:  of putting the creator at the center of it,
Speaker 4:  you can, I can sort of imagine a world where very quickly you're like, okay,
Speaker 4:  well the thing we have to do is build like a content platform for those creators
Speaker 4:  to make things outside of being sort of specifically project based.
Speaker 4:  And then it's like two more very small steps. And now you're TikTok, right?
Speaker 4:  Like it's, it's like, because this is where everybody has landed, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Everybody, everybody else that is in this space has come at it from
Speaker 4:  the opposite direction, which is we have given creators a place to build
Speaker 4:  an audience, and then we've given those creators ways to sell stuff. And
Speaker 4:  I, I think in a lot of ways that path has sort of
Speaker 4:  ruined those platforms. Like the TikTok shop, at least in my own
Speaker 4:  experience, has made TikTok essentially unusable. It is. It is. It's, I mean,
Speaker 4:  it is. It's like, it's a shopping mall now. Yeah. And that's fine for what
Speaker 4:  it is, but it is that is, it is like unrecognizable from what TikTok was
Speaker 4:  before the shop existed. Yeah. But it works. And so
Speaker 4:  what I wonder for you as the CEO is like, you've built the
Speaker 4:  second half of that equation already, and I can imagine there's a lot
Speaker 4:  of like, pressure and good reasons potentially, but
Speaker 4:  also maybe psychotic reasons given the competitive landscape
Speaker 4:  to go the other way and basically be like, okay, how do we become a like
Speaker 4:  creator first platform and do vertical video and
Speaker 4:  like make a thing that gives us all of the power of a creator
Speaker 4:  audience on Kickstarter? Like, is that, yeah. Is that a path that
Speaker 4:  makes sense? Is that where you're headed?
Speaker 6:  I mean, well, a couple things that it makes Kickstarter unique.
Speaker 6:  Number one, we're not a publicly traded company, right?
Speaker 6:  We're a private and we're a public benefit corporation. And so
Speaker 6:  some of these things that these, you know, larger
Speaker 6:  tech companies, the pressure of them to make,
Speaker 6:  you know, billions and billions of more revenue, they're always under pressure.
Speaker 6:  We gotta get the stock price up. We gotta do this, we gotta do that.
Speaker 6:  Kickstarter doesn't have that, right? Like, you know, Kickstarter was
Speaker 6:  profitable in year two of its existence, and
Speaker 6:  we've continued to scale and become bigger and more successful.
Speaker 6:  But we've done things our way and we've done things without the
Speaker 6:  pressures of, of feeling like we needed to
Speaker 6:  monetize everything. I'm trying to do the things that are the most
Speaker 6:  genuinely impactful to our audience. And my first couple
Speaker 6:  years here, I've been hyper-focused on giving
Speaker 6:  creators the tools, the products, and the services that they've been asking
Speaker 6:  for Kickstarter for years. So even before even
Speaker 6:  getting to anything like that, like we still have a long
Speaker 6:  road. And also sometimes you gotta understand where your
Speaker 6:  bread is buttered man, like, you know, and, and, and be really, really great
Speaker 6:  at what you do. With that being said, one of the things that we're
Speaker 6:  hyperfocused on this year is also backer development, right? And, and, and,
Speaker 6:  and developing better products and features for our backers. We've been very
Speaker 6:  focused on creators, but now we're like, how can we create
Speaker 6:  a more engaging, sticky experience for
Speaker 6:  backers on the platform? So I'm more focused on that
Speaker 6:  than necessarily, you know, trying to turn
Speaker 6:  Kickstarter into a TikTok like, you know, vertical
Speaker 6:  platform or anything like that.
Speaker 4:  There, there's definitely a world in which Kickstarter could sort of
Speaker 4:  choose to be more actively involved in the, like, here's how to help you
Speaker 4:  make stuff, process percent and printing services for people wanting
Speaker 4:  to make content and like that kind of thing. Is that, is that interesting
Speaker 4:  to you? Like, is that a space you think Kickstarter has stuff to do
Speaker 6:  That's more interesting to me than Kickstarter becoming like TikTok
Speaker 6:  Okay. To me personally, I think platforms like TikTok
Speaker 6:  and Instagram and Twitter and all of that have always played a role
Speaker 6:  in Kickstarter, right? In terms of how people market.
Speaker 6:  We now have our own marketing services, performance
Speaker 6:  marketing services called Kickstarter performance, which is like killing
Speaker 6:  it. Where we're, we're utilizing those platforms. So those platforms are
Speaker 6:  always going to be more important, but what can we uniquely
Speaker 6:  do? Like we try to go out there and be better than TikTok, that's really,
Speaker 6:  really hard to do, right? Yes. But I think we could be
Speaker 6:  potentially the best at white glove service with manufacturing and stuff
Speaker 6:  like that. Like that could be something that we could do. I'm not saying
Speaker 6:  that's what we're gonna do, but that's something that we know
Speaker 6:  uniquely our creators need that they might not be able to
Speaker 6:  get elsewhere. Instead of focusing on
Speaker 6:  competing with people at what they absolutely do
Speaker 6:  best. I'd rather focus on what Kickstarter absolutely does, does best, and
Speaker 6:  then filling the gaps for our creators where they need it.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. What are those gaps? I mean, you, you see it a lot and I, I would
Speaker 4:  assume it, it varies pretty widely in terms of what folks need, but like,
Speaker 4:  you know, you mentioned wanting to do the stuff creators have been asking
Speaker 4:  for, for years. Like what's, what's your sense of what's at the top of that
Speaker 4:  list?
Speaker 6:  One of them we're doing or we're about to launch, and that's
Speaker 6:  a pledge manager and post-campaign tools, right? So, you know, before it
Speaker 6:  was like you raise money on Kickstarter, and then it was like, congrats,
Speaker 6:  here's your $50,000. Good luck. Sure. Go out into the world, you know?
Speaker 6:  And now, you know, we're launching these post-campaign tools. Last year we
Speaker 6:  launched late pledges, which now allows you to, If you raise
Speaker 6:  $50,000, but hey, you might have another few hundred people that you
Speaker 6:  might raise another 10, $20,000 over the last, over
Speaker 6:  another week If you had it. Right? And so now you have late pledges, now
Speaker 6:  you're gonna have pledge management, CRM, all of those things
Speaker 6:  to help you, you know, your taxes, shipping, et cetera,
Speaker 6:  et cetera. So helping people fill the gaps of that post
Speaker 6:  campaign process, which is gonna be extremely important. We're gonna
Speaker 6:  have, you know, add-ons and cross sells and all different types of things
Speaker 6:  after a Kickstarter is over that a lot of these entrepreneurs
Speaker 6:  and creators need that we've never been able to provide for them,
Speaker 6:  which I'm really, really excited about. And that's already, we have someone
Speaker 6:  in data right now, and that's gonna be rolling out early part of
Speaker 6:  this year, which we're really, really excited for. The other
Speaker 6:  thing on the, on the other side is pre-launch, right? So we revamped a lot
Speaker 6:  of our pre-launch this past year, but there's so many
Speaker 6:  more things that creators need before actually launching a
Speaker 6:  Kickstarter, to be honest. Like depending on what you do
Speaker 6:  before, a Kickstarter will determine how successful your
Speaker 6:  Kickstarter even will be. Right? Totally. And so what can we do
Speaker 6:  more in that pre-launch process of filling those
Speaker 6:  gaps, supporting creators, helping them set realistic goals.
Speaker 6:  Maybe it's some of the manufacturing stuff, you know, all of these things,
Speaker 6:  making sure that they have the right pricing, et cetera, et cetera. AB testing.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of things that we could be doing on the pre-launch side that
Speaker 6:  we're currently not doing that I think that we can provide for
Speaker 6:  creators. And So I think the first steps is pre-launch and
Speaker 6:  post campaign and continuing to build out a suite of tools and
Speaker 6:  services for creators on both sides. So then you have this
Speaker 6:  kind of loop where it's like pre-launch Kickstarter post-campaign,
Speaker 6:  and then come back to pre-launch and continue Mm. To launch products.
Speaker 4:  Okay. You're, you're kind of confirming a thing I've always suspected about
Speaker 4:  Kickstarter, which is that the, the people who aren't like, you know,
Speaker 4:  large companies using it as a, as a kind of marketing pre-sale platform,
Speaker 4:  many of these people are like just people who made a thing. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  don't know, haven't run businesses like this, don't know how
Speaker 4:  to manage large quantities of money like this.
Speaker 4:  They're just like, I made a thing and I think people might like it and
Speaker 4:  they get some money, right? And I think the idea of like needing money to
Speaker 4:  do that stuff is, is part of it. But it is, I think
Speaker 4:  maybe a smaller slice of the, like how to actually successfully
Speaker 4:  accomplish your goals pie than anyone would like it to be. And all
Speaker 4:  the rest of the stuff is like less sexy to talk about and less
Speaker 4:  sort of creative and beautiful and artsy, but is like, that's the stuff
Speaker 4:  that falls apart. And I found this with the tech folks. It's not because
Speaker 4:  the thing didn't work, it's because they couldn't figure out how to ship
Speaker 4:  it, like over and over. It's that kind of stuff that falls apart
Speaker 6:  Is that piece. And now you have these big content creators that have an audience
Speaker 6:  where they can go on Kickstarter today and raise four or five, 10 million
Speaker 6:  or whatever it is, but do they even have the tools and resources
Speaker 6:  to actually make the thing
Speaker 4:  Happen?
Speaker 6:  Right? Right. And do it successfully. And so those are the gaps that we
Speaker 6:  see that we're trying to fill. And I think we're doing a good job thus
Speaker 6:  far.
Speaker 4:  You mentioned AI and I, I wanna, I I was, I'm gonna forget to talk about
Speaker 4:  it if I don't bring it back up now. I think like I'm a
Speaker 4:  CES right now. You're gonna be at CES this week. Literally all anyone wants
Speaker 4:  to talk about is ai. Yeah. And, and what you're saying is right, that like
Speaker 4:  some companies are doing interesting things and other companies are just
Speaker 4:  doing old things and calling them ai and that just is what it is. And that's
Speaker 4:  fine. But I think the, the potential of AI
Speaker 4:  within a Kickstarter universe is super interesting, right? Like the, the,
Speaker 4:  if AI is everything it is cracked up to be, and like, spoiler alert, it isn't,
Speaker 4:  but if it is, it, it's going to make a lot of things
Speaker 4:  easier for people. It's gonna make it easier to design things, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  make it easier to build things, it's gonna make it easier to do your taxes,
Speaker 4:  it's gonna make it easier to like do all the legal paperwork around this
Speaker 4:  stuff. And So I can imagine a world in which you're, you're like
Speaker 4:  baking a lot of that stuff into Kickstarter itself to
Speaker 4:  say like, these are tools that can automate and simplify some of
Speaker 4:  this stuff. And, you know, everybody talks about democratizing everything.
Speaker 4:  Like AI could do some of that, right? Like if, if I don't have to write code
Speaker 4:  in order to be able to do a project, I wanna do like the, the gap between
Speaker 4:  I have an idea and I can sell that idea to, people might get much
Speaker 4:  smaller.
Speaker 4:  It also might just be a bunch of snake oil nonsense and
Speaker 4:  may not come to anything. But were, you're,
Speaker 4:  like you said, you're, you're a company that doesn't have to chase anything
Speaker 4:  that looks like growth just for the sake of something that looks like growth.
Speaker 4:  But where's your head with AI stuff right now?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I, first I wanna say is that, listen, I'm pro technology.
Speaker 6:  I'm pro the advancement of technology. I know that
Speaker 6:  you can't just sit there and be scared and fearful of, of, of
Speaker 6:  technology. With that being said, I think there's something powerful
Speaker 6:  and beautiful about human made work and creativity.
Speaker 6:  And Kickstarter wants to be at the forefront of supporting that,
Speaker 6:  right? Supporting creators first and foremost,
Speaker 6:  before we even touch ai. And we wanna make sure
Speaker 6:  that the creators on our platform feel supported by the work that they
Speaker 6:  do. I see some platforms that are completely just, I mean,
Speaker 6:  I just saw meta as like creating fake AI
Speaker 6:  influencers. Yep. And it's like, dude, do you realize that
Speaker 6:  this, this, this is taking away from the
Speaker 6:  hardworking influencers and creators on your platform and why they use it,
Speaker 6:  and you already know where they're going with it. It's like, if they can
Speaker 6:  build these creators and make money off of them themselves,
Speaker 6:  but that's hurting your audience, we will never do anything that's gonna
Speaker 6:  hurt our community. Right? And so we wanna make sure there's so many people,
Speaker 6:  so many comic book creators and artists and musicians
Speaker 6:  that are hard at work to create things without the use of ai. And so we wanna
Speaker 6:  make sure that we're protecting those people and protecting their hard work
Speaker 6:  first and foremost. If there are ways where we can incorporate
Speaker 6:  AI to help make their lives easier or make creators more
Speaker 6:  successful on a platform, I'm 100% open to
Speaker 6:  exploring that. But I don't want to go too
Speaker 6:  far where it's hurting our community.
Speaker 4:  That line's gonna get really blurry though. Like, you're, you're, if it's
Speaker 4:  not happening already, it's gonna happen soon that you're gonna get musicians
Speaker 4:  who wanna kickstart an album of AI generated music, or Oh,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And they can, right now, they just have to be honest that
Speaker 6:  they've used AI and what they're doing. We have an AI
Speaker 6:  policy and we just ask that, Hey, If you use ai,
Speaker 6:  just say that you used ai. Right? And then If you are using
Speaker 6:  other people's work through ai,
Speaker 6:  identify those people and compensate those people when you can.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yeah. But I, I like, does that, is there a risk in that for
Speaker 4:  Kickstarter? Like the, we talk about this all the time at The Verge, the
Speaker 4:  idea that like, the internet is just going to be flooded with
Speaker 4:  AI content, you open up, like, if, if I'm just wanting
Speaker 4:  to kickstart a new album of AI generated
Speaker 4:  music every day on Kickstarter, that's not gonna work,
Speaker 4:  but it's gonna make the platform worse, right? Like, and,
Speaker 4:  and So I wonder like If you get to a point where 80% of the stuff on Kickstarter
Speaker 4:  is not interesting to most people because it's AI generated Yeah.
Speaker 4:  How that changes Kickstarter.
Speaker 6:  I think at the end of the day, our community does a great job of like
Speaker 6:  kind of pointing out what is interesting and what's not. I think if
Speaker 6:  someone came on today and tried to do a bunch of music that was AI generated,
Speaker 6:  they wouldn't be that successful and they're not gonna continue to do that.
Speaker 6:  I think the good thing about Kickstarter is that it almost
Speaker 6:  polices itself in a sense, right? Like, if the community isn't
Speaker 6:  for or supports it, you'll know because you're not getting
Speaker 6:  anything for it. And so I'm very open to see
Speaker 6:  how things evolve. I'm not someone that lives in the black or
Speaker 6:  the white. I very much live in the gray. I just understand right now
Speaker 6:  that human made things and human made work and creativity is
Speaker 6:  at the core of what we do today. And I do understand
Speaker 6:  the power of AI and how that could be supportive to creators
Speaker 6:  implementing that and what they do. But we wanna make sure that we
Speaker 6:  don't lose sight of what really makes Kickstarter special at the end of the
Speaker 6:  day.
Speaker 4:  Okay. This might be a stupid realization to be having this far into this
Speaker 4:  conversation. Yeah. But it also strikes me that
Speaker 4:  starting the whole thing with an exchange of money changes
Speaker 4:  the dynamic in a really useful way. Like I think I think about the, the AI
Speaker 4:  music that's suddenly all over Spotify. Yeah. And nobody really
Speaker 4:  likes it. I wouldn't, like nobody's seeking it out. It's not no super popular,
Speaker 4:  but there's so much of it that at volume it still works, right? Like if,
Speaker 4:  if, if I can, I can put out so much music that hardly any of it has to
Speaker 4:  be successful in order for it to still be a, a, an
Speaker 4:  in aggregate success for me. But that's a totally different relationship
Speaker 4:  than you have paid me for a thing. Yes. And I feel like there's,
Speaker 4:  I can't imagine the path to get to that kind of success
Speaker 4:  when first you have to pay me for a thing.
Speaker 6:  And what I said before, yes, we do have people that are
Speaker 6:  very much like, Hey, I am just getting a thing. They're thinking they're,
Speaker 6:  we never use the words buy, right? We don't see ourselves as a marketplace
Speaker 6:  in that way Sure. That are are using that. But still at the core,
Speaker 6:  the majority of our audience is wanting to support creators, new
Speaker 6:  things, new products. There is this like emotional
Speaker 6:  component to it, to it. And So I I, I think
Speaker 6:  people who want to behave in that way on the platform are
Speaker 6:  not gonna find a lot of success.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. Okay. All right. Last thing and then I'll let you go. I've kept you
Speaker 4:  long time here. Yeah. What, what do you tell creators about
Speaker 4:  how to talk to their audience that way? Because I think every bad
Speaker 4:  experience I hear about that somebody has on Kickstarter is about being ghosted
Speaker 4:  in one way or another. Yeah. Yeah. Like the, the experience of
Speaker 4:  I backed a thing and it didn't work. Yep. Is is frustrating,
Speaker 4:  but I backed a thing and then they disappeared is worse and feels
Speaker 4:  bad. And like that's the thing that breaks the thing. And so yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I assume this is the thing you spend a lot of time thinking and talking
Speaker 4:  about, but I am curious, like as you talk to these folks who are wanting
Speaker 4:  to build that relationship, what do you tell them?
Speaker 6:  Well, first and foremost,
Speaker 6:  they know what they're doing. Right? Like, let's, like these are adults,
Speaker 6:  these are creators, these are entrepreneurs. And what I'm very excited
Speaker 6:  about, and we already started rolling it, rolling it out, is we're
Speaker 6:  going after these, these potentially fraudulent creators or these
Speaker 6:  ghosting creators. Hmm. Never in Kickstarter's history have we done that.
Speaker 6:  We've kind of had this like, Hey, Kickstarter's not a store.
Speaker 6:  There's no guarantee that you're gonna get the thing. Like
Speaker 4:  I always compare it to the chat GPT thing where it's like, chat GPT might
Speaker 4:  lie to you. And it's like a total abdication of responsibility to say that.
Speaker 6:  100%. Yeah. And to me, I just like,
Speaker 6:  listen David, I stand on business, man, and like I come from South
Speaker 6:  Side Richmond, I, I'm all about
Speaker 6:  holding people accountable and making sure that we do the right thing. So
Speaker 6:  this year we're rolling out new things where we're going to be
Speaker 6:  going after these creators. We're gonna be banning them from the platform.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna be communicating back to their, to their backers, letting them
Speaker 6:  know that we're holding them accountable. We're gonna be putting people in
Speaker 6:  collections, going after the money to get it back for our
Speaker 6:  backers. Like we're not playing any more games anymore. And so, yes,
Speaker 6:  we can go and go to every creator and be like, Hey, make sure you're
Speaker 6:  communicating with your audience. Do the right thing. But we both know
Speaker 6:  that people that aren't trying to do the right thing is going to ignore that.
Speaker 6:  The one place where I do find empathy and like where we need to help more
Speaker 6:  creators are those like first time creators that they failed
Speaker 6:  and they're like under the weight of failure.
Speaker 6:  Right. And I don't wanna go after them. I just wanna make sure they get to
Speaker 6:  the point where they can at least communicate that to
Speaker 6:  their audience. I think that's gonna be so important. 'cause there are some
Speaker 6:  creators that just under the weight of the pressure, they're not
Speaker 6:  trying to ghost, but they have that social anxiety of like, I, I don't know
Speaker 6:  what to do. And I really empathize with that, but they still have to go and
Speaker 6:  communicate with that audience. And so the balance of helping those
Speaker 6:  creators, but also actually going after the creators that are being
Speaker 6:  fraudulent.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think the, the folks who give it a real
Speaker 4:  try and then just kind of admit defeat, I think. Yeah, I think you're right
Speaker 4:  that Kickstarter is unusual as a place in that
Speaker 4:  it has a lot of space for those people. Yeah. Right? Like that is percent,
Speaker 4:  that is a thing that is part of the system. Yep. It's the people
Speaker 4:  who just take your money and run that.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 4:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 4:  We love all of your questions. We try to answer at least one on the show
Speaker 4:  every week, but I have some ideas about how to do even more than that
Speaker 4:  this year. We're also working on some big stuff that started as hotline questions.
Speaker 4:  Please keep hitting off the hotline with all of your weirdest questions.
Speaker 4:  It's my favorite thing. This week's question is about passwords, or
Speaker 4:  I guess more specifically not passwords. Listen to this.
Speaker 7:  Hi David slash Vergecast. My name is John
Speaker 7:  in New York, and I have a question about sort of
Speaker 7:  related to The Verge creating a subscription
Speaker 7:  and more about sign-ins on websites.
Speaker 7:  A lot of websites I feel like these days do prompt
Speaker 7:  you to sign in via a link and an email.
Speaker 7:  I sort of understand that, but what is the, what is the reason
Speaker 7:  websites are moving, it seems like in that direction more.
Speaker 7:  Is it because people can't do passwords properly? It seems like
Speaker 7:  a, a lot of websites are just removing the ability to do
Speaker 7:  passwords at all. Is that the way of the future? Just
Speaker 7:  wondering what the process there is.
Speaker 4:  Okay, so this question actually sent me down a really interesting rabbit
Speaker 4:  hole because I frankly hate Magic Links as
Speaker 4:  a login mechanism. Basically the way Magic Links work, If you don't know,
Speaker 4:  is you go to log into something, you type into your username and you hit
Speaker 4:  submit. And instead of popping up another field that's like, Hey, what's
Speaker 4:  your password? It says, you know, we've sent you an email, go click on the
Speaker 4:  link in your email. So you go, you open your email, you get an email from
Speaker 4:  whoever you're trying to log into that says, click this link to finish your
Speaker 4:  login or something like that. You click that link and then it opens up to
Speaker 4:  the thing that you were reading. This is in theory
Speaker 4:  fine, right? I think that that idea works, and I'll tell you the reason
Speaker 4:  people do it, just to directly answer the question. The reason for Magic
Speaker 4:  Links is because they're better than passwords. I think everything
Speaker 4:  is better than passwords. And one thing that we've seen over time is there
Speaker 4:  is a big push away from if I run a
Speaker 4:  website storing your passwords. I just don't want them anymore.
Speaker 4:  The folks at 4 0 4 Media wrote a really great post about this a couple of
Speaker 4:  weeks ago about why they use Magic Links. And the thrust of it is essentially,
Speaker 4:  we don't want your passwords because as soon as you store somebody's passwords,
Speaker 4:  you become a security risk. And because most people have
Speaker 4:  bad password hygiene, they reuse passwords, they use bad passwords.
Speaker 4:  If I leak your password to my website, there is a
Speaker 4:  surprisingly good chance that what actually happened is I just leaked the
Speaker 4:  password to your email and your bank account and everything else. So
Speaker 4:  essentially what a lot of companies are starting to say is
Speaker 4:  just, we do not want your password. We don't want your data at all. This
Speaker 4:  is a thing you hear from a lot of privacy based companies like DuckDuckGo
Speaker 4:  has been saying this for years, is their privacy policy is just to not have
Speaker 4:  any data at all. Because the less you collect, the fewer risks there are
Speaker 4:  for that data and passwords I think are the number one
Speaker 4:  security vector there. And so that is one big reason to use Magic Links.
Speaker 4:  It, it offloads all of the worry about security to
Speaker 4:  just, as long as my email address is secure, which is my job
Speaker 4:  as a person,
Speaker 4:  it will work. This system stays secure as long as my email stays secure.
Speaker 4:  And I think for us as people, that's a reasonable
Speaker 4:  trade, right? Like it is just true that if your email address gets compromised,
Speaker 4:  you're hosed. Like, I hate to put it in quite those terms, but
Speaker 4:  If you do one single thing on earth that is good for you on
Speaker 4:  the internet, it is have a complicated and two factor backed
Speaker 4:  and unique password for your email that's just, just
Speaker 4:  do it. Or else you are just on borrowed time until something truly terrible
Speaker 4:  happens. Okay? So anyway, the upside of
Speaker 4:  Magic links is that it offloads a lot of that process.
Speaker 4:  The downside of Magic Links is that it's kind of crappy
Speaker 4:  user experience, right? So in a, in a certain world, like if I'm sitting
Speaker 4:  at my computer for instance, and it's easy for me to switch
Speaker 4:  from the tab of the website to the tab of my email,
Speaker 4:  that's relatively simple, right? And then I click the link and it opens the
Speaker 4:  same thing in another tab and I'm back to where I was. That's
Speaker 4:  slightly annoying just because it's a bunch of tabs switching and clicking
Speaker 4:  and it opens in another tabs. And now I have two tabs of the same thing.
Speaker 4:  One where I'm not logged in and one where I am that's slightly messy,
Speaker 4:  but is, I would say broadly fine. Where this really breaks down
Speaker 4:  for me, at least as a user, is on mobile, right? Where I
Speaker 4:  log into something, I go to my email,
Speaker 4:  which involves usually, you know, closing and opening other app or opening
Speaker 4:  the multitasking thing and you swipe for a while. That takes a minute and
Speaker 4:  then clicking the link and then when I click that link,
Speaker 4:  God only knows where it goes. This is the problem, right? On mobile, especially
Speaker 4:  on iOS, which is just awful about this, you have in-app browsers,
Speaker 4:  you have Safari, which a lot of apps just wanna open by default. And then
Speaker 4:  you have whatever you've picked as your default browser. So when you
Speaker 4:  are in a place reading a, an article and you wanna log in and read that
Speaker 4:  article, you get the magic link and it may or may not open
Speaker 4:  in the place where you were originally reading that article. This is a platform
Speaker 4:  mess and it it, it is everyone's fault, especially Apple's for the way that
Speaker 4:  it handles web browsers. But what it means is that you are just not
Speaker 4:  in the place that you expect to be and logged in in the places you expect
Speaker 4:  to be logged in. I have a theory that lots of people
Speaker 4:  who hate subscriptions, one thing we've heard frankly on The Verge is that
Speaker 4:  saying logged in is a challenge. And a lot of that comes from the fact
Speaker 4:  that when you use a browser on iOS, again in particular,
Speaker 4:  you're actually using several different kinds of browsers that do not talk
Speaker 4:  to each other. You're not just using like the iPhone browser.
Speaker 4:  Sometimes you're in Safari, sometimes you might be in Chrome, sometimes you're
Speaker 4:  in an in-app browser, sometimes you're in a different in-app browser. It's
Speaker 4:  a mess. My my one thing by the way is
Speaker 4:  try your very best not to use in-app browsers. Set the browser you want as
Speaker 4:  the default and then get in the habit of like pressing the button and saying
Speaker 4:  open and default browser. It is annoying to do that extra step
Speaker 4:  every time you open a webpage, but it makes all the login and magic linky
Speaker 4:  stuff a little bit easier. So all of this is
Speaker 4:  to say, I've been asking around a little bit, and I don't think anyone
Speaker 4:  agrees that magic links are perfect. There's
Speaker 4:  no sort of magically great thing about them,
Speaker 4:  but they do work, right? You probably have access to your email just about
Speaker 4:  everywhere. There's a chance that you have access to email more places than
Speaker 4:  you have access to your passwords. Most people, again, have bad password
Speaker 4:  hygienes and have them like written down on a sticky note on their desk.
Speaker 4:  There's a good chance your email is more accessible to you than
Speaker 4:  the list of passwords that you have. It also means things like
Speaker 4:  when you're on a new device that you've never used before, you can
Speaker 4:  use the magic link and still be relatively secure without risks
Speaker 4:  of things like, you know, keyboard capture and all that stuff.
Speaker 4:  It's a better, simpler system with fewer problems
Speaker 4:  than just asking people to type in their password all the time. All of that
Speaker 4:  is true. But when I talk to people about this, they say
Speaker 4:  what we should have is something more like pass keys. Pass keys
Speaker 4:  are really interesting and we've talked about them a bunch
Speaker 4:  on the show, but Passkey basically intercept this whole system
Speaker 4:  and just let you declare yourself to a
Speaker 4:  website with yourself. You use the Byron Metric security
Speaker 4:  on your phone to log into websites. I would argue that is the correct answer
Speaker 4:  and that is absolutely how it should work. None of these systems are perfect,
Speaker 4:  but they're very good and I think they're great. You can also solve a lot
Speaker 4:  of these problems by just having good password hygiene, right? Like If you
Speaker 4:  have a password manager, you can solve some of this problem, particularly
Speaker 4:  the user experience part of the problem by just having these things
Speaker 4:  auto-filled themselves more easily. Then you don't have to know your passwords,
Speaker 4:  you can have your passwords everywhere. It doesn't solve the specific security
Speaker 4:  risks of just inputting passwords, which are an
Speaker 4:  inherent security risk. But If you have, you know, unique complicated passwords
Speaker 4:  across every website that you use, the worries about
Speaker 4:  a specific one being leaked, at least go down. There are,
Speaker 4:  I should also say trade-offs to the magic link thing
Speaker 4:  with security. One other thing you see is the, the
Speaker 4:  codes that people get sent in emails or the codes that you can
Speaker 4:  get sent by text message, like six digit code that you use to log into stuff.
Speaker 4:  Those are also better than asking people to input passwords, but they
Speaker 4:  take time too. SMS in particular has its own
Speaker 4:  security risks. It you run the risk of having issues If you
Speaker 4:  have service problems. Look, none of these systems are perfect. This
Speaker 4:  is the thing I keep hearing from people is like, oh, we really should have
Speaker 4:  solved passwords by now. And passkey are probably the closest thing we've
Speaker 4:  ever come up with to solving passwords. But for right now we have this
Speaker 4:  big kind of mealy mess of different ways
Speaker 4:  to do better than having you just type your password into a text field
Speaker 4:  and everybody agrees that that is the single worst thing you can possibly
Speaker 4:  do. So magic links, they're not great, they're not
Speaker 4:  anybody's favorite thing, but they are definitely unequivocally
Speaker 4:  better than making people type in their passwords. And for that reason alone,
Speaker 4:  I will, I will keep using them. I will get annoyed every time I have to use
Speaker 4:  them on 4 0 4 and other places, but I will keep using
Speaker 4:  them. I hope that helps. Passwords are a mess
Speaker 4:  is essentially where it lands. None of this is good. Use pass
Speaker 4:  keys when you can.
Speaker 4:  Alright, that is it for the first cast today. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 4:  came on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more
Speaker 4:  on everything we talked about at The Verge dot com. We're covering all of
Speaker 4:  the run up to the will. They won't they TikTok ban really aggressively.
Speaker 4:  So keep it locked on the website. I think there's a lot left to happen in
Speaker 4:  the next five days, so keep it locked. Let us know what you think.
Speaker 4:  I'd love to hear all of your thoughts on whether it should be banned, shouldn't
Speaker 4:  be banned. I know this is a thing we've been talking about for literally
Speaker 4:  years at this point, but I'd love to hear your thoughts and I'd love to hear
Speaker 4:  your thoughts and questions on everything. Email us Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 4:  dot com. Call the hotline, eight six six VERGE one one. We absolutely love
Speaker 4:  hearing from you. We are gonna do even more hotline stuff
Speaker 4:  in 2025 than we did last year, so please keep all of your questions coming.
Speaker 4:  This show is produced by Liam James, Wil Poor and Eric Gomez. Vergecast is
Speaker 4:  a VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neil, and I'll
Speaker 4:  be back on Friday to talk about presumably the TikTok Band, plus everything
Speaker 4:  going on at Meta, all of the open AI stuff and lots more.
Speaker 4:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll