# Transcript
ID: b0545acf-9f73-4678-bd38-9074f76caf63
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7100689804036787853/185987208244174302/s93290-US-3822s-1760435298.mp3
Description: Google is on a bit of a heater when it comes to gadgets. The Pixel 10 lineup is one of the best Android phone options; the Pixel Watch 4 is suddenly a winner; the Pixel Buds are an excellent accessory; even the Pixel Fold got some welcome upgrades this year! With the help of The Verge’s Victoria Song and Allison Johnson, we do the impossible: we rank all six of Google’s Pixel gadgets, from worst to best. Are headphones better than smartphones? Can you really compare a tablet to a smartwatch? Who knows, but we try. After that, Allison and David answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about whether the dumbphone movement is a real one.
Speaker 3:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Google Pixel book.
Speaker 3:  My maybe favorite computer of all time that is now long gone and
Speaker 3:  Google refuses to keep making new ones. We're not gonna talk at all about
Speaker 3:  the Pixel book on this episode, but I miss it dearly. And I just, I Pixel
Speaker 3:  book. If you're out there, just know that I loved you anyway. I'm your friend
Speaker 3:  David Pierce, and today on the podcast we're gonna do something a little
Speaker 3:  new. We have a bunch of Google reviews over the last few days and really
Speaker 3:  the last couple of months. And we've seen a theme among the Google reviews,
Speaker 3:  which is that they're all very good. Google made some good gadgets. So we're
Speaker 3:  gonna talk about Google's good gadgets and then
Speaker 3:  we're gonna play a little bit of a new game about them and see if we can
Speaker 3:  figure out which of Google's good new gadgets is the best of
Speaker 3:  Google's good. New gadgets. It's gonna be a good time. All that is coming
Speaker 3:  up in just a second. But first I just realized I have three pairs of
Speaker 3:  headphones connected to my computer right now and I need to go disconnect
Speaker 3:  those before something horrible happens. This is the first cast, we'll be
Speaker 3:  right back.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we're back. Let's talk Google. Allison Johnson's here. Hi Allison.
Speaker 3:  Hello V Song and many cats. Hello,
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 3:  V for the folks on YouTube teach us about the cats.
Speaker 3:  Who are the cats?
Speaker 6:  This is Petey. He is the, the younger baby cat and
Speaker 6:  he loves to disrupt my work, hence why I bought a cat bed
Speaker 6:  that attaches to my desk so he can feel like he's part
Speaker 6:  of my day while staying out of the way. I love
Speaker 6:  that. And then back here we have my big boy Pablo, who
Speaker 6:  is currently taking a nap.
Speaker 3:  It's the dream, this is the life. Alright, I have, I have brought you guys
Speaker 3:  here because I want to try a new thing that I've been wanting to do for a
Speaker 3:  while. But first all three of us reviewed Google products this week
Speaker 3:  and I just wanna, I want to quickly breeze through them because
Speaker 3:  they all have in common that they're all very good and they're all very good
Speaker 3:  in kind of the same way, which I think is really fun and really interesting.
Speaker 3:  So Alice, I'm gonna start with you. You reviewed the Google Pixel
Speaker 3:  10 pro fold, the worst name phone in phones
Speaker 3:  and really liked it, I would say for like the one big specific
Speaker 3:  reason you really liked it, right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  You can kind of boil down the changes to two major things. One
Speaker 7:  is the new hinge, which is hard to tell from the outside, but
Speaker 7:  you can appreciate it in certain ways. And they
Speaker 7:  added qi support with the magnets and everything.
Speaker 7:  So you have like MagSafe, which I loved. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But the main update here is that this is the first
Speaker 7:  folding phone with an IP 68 rating, meaning it is fully
Speaker 7:  dust resistant. This is not existed on any folding phone
Speaker 7:  in the past. And it's important for a folding phone because
Speaker 7:  dust getting into the hinge can, you know, it can move under the screen
Speaker 7:  and then the screen is toast. It's, it's ugly and
Speaker 7:  it's been kind of a thing that prohibits me from, or I don't
Speaker 7:  feel good recommending these phones to people. They're $2,000,
Speaker 7:  right? Single grain of dust can bring it down. But
Speaker 7:  I took Google at its word. I brought the phone
Speaker 7:  to the beach, like air quotes. We have a beach in
Speaker 7:  Seattle, it's manmade, but there's
Speaker 7:  plenty of sand. And I set the thing
Speaker 7:  down to take a photo of it on the sand thinking
Speaker 7:  it would just kind of like gracefully sit on top of the
Speaker 7:  sand, you know, propped up against a log and all this. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  VV is making the face for anyone not watching this V is making the face that
Speaker 3:  I feel in my bones. Yeah. Right now. Which is, this is true
Speaker 3:  psychopath behavior.
Speaker 7:  It was not, that's not how it works. Yeah. It
Speaker 3:  Just, let me, let me just put this new gadget down on the sand. It'll probably
Speaker 3:  be fine. Yeah, it is like the last words of reviewer ever since. And
Speaker 7:  I open, yeah, I had it unfolded, of course. 'cause you wanna do that,
Speaker 7:  set it down on the sand, just sank immediately, like half
Speaker 7:  an inch down sand.
Speaker 6:  That's how sand works.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Who would
Speaker 7:  Exactly. Yeah. Which all came back to me as
Speaker 7:  I watched the sand work its way, you know how it's like immediately
Speaker 7:  everywhere it was around the, the corners of the screen. It was up
Speaker 7:  in the hinge, it was in the back of the hinge. I was like, well, I'm committed
Speaker 7:  to this. And I just took my photos.
Speaker 7:  I, I picked it up and I was like opening and closing it. There was
Speaker 7:  a crunching sound coming from there. No,
Speaker 7:  it was crunching. And I was like, oh god. And
Speaker 7:  then I was like, why not? Then set it
Speaker 7:  next to the water and get a picture of the phone
Speaker 7:  with the waves gently, like, you know, coming
Speaker 7:  ashore and not touching the phone. So I
Speaker 7:  did, I set it down next to like a seashell in a little piece
Speaker 7:  of seaweed and I was like, I'll just be able to grab it outta the way if
Speaker 7:  a wave comes. That's not how it works. So
Speaker 7:  wave like came and got about halfway over
Speaker 7:  the unfolded folding phone and I snatched it
Speaker 7:  up and I was like, I have to call Google now and tell them
Speaker 7:  their phone is busted. Like this is it.
Speaker 7:  Boy, I killed it. But the, it, it's fine.
Speaker 7:  I, I did take it like, you know, I tried it off. I got any of the
Speaker 7:  sand I could, I could see out of it when I got home, I
Speaker 7:  used some of the compressed air to like get rid of the rest of
Speaker 7:  the sand. And it was fine after that. And I'm, it's still
Speaker 7:  going.
Speaker 3:  It was the best feeling in the world when you just pick it up and you like
Speaker 3:  touch the screen and you like, you jiggle some stuff around just to see if
Speaker 3:  it's also working. You're like, oh, oh, it's, it's, it's fine. Yeah. My phone
Speaker 3:  is fine. Yeah. That is like the, the relief that comes at that moment
Speaker 3:  is so spectacular. Yeah. I cannot even describe.
Speaker 7:  Yes, I, I felt that I felt $1,800 worth of
Speaker 7:  that worth, worth,
Speaker 3:  Worth. Well I'm thrilled for you. I also like imagining the call to Google
Speaker 3:  where you're like, hi, so I buried your phone in the sand
Speaker 3:  and then I essentially threw it in the ocean and now it's broken. I'm so
Speaker 3:  sorry.
Speaker 7:  You're like, oops, sorry guys. It turns out you're not supposed to do
Speaker 7:  that. But I
Speaker 3:  Did it for journalism, you know,
Speaker 7:  I, I did it for the blog, but you know, oh, it survived. I
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 6:  Were you wearing the Pixel Watch four at that point in time and did it give
Speaker 6:  you a har high heart rate alert? You,
Speaker 7:  You
Speaker 6:  Know what, that's what we need to know.
Speaker 7:  I have gotten so many of those frigging alerts over the past
Speaker 7:  week where in, but they come in late. It, it gives you
Speaker 7:  a little notification that's like, you seem stressed
Speaker 7:  about 22 minutes ago. And
Speaker 6:  I'm like, oh. Oh, okay. So is that different? Yes, there are the stress,
Speaker 6:  there are stress notifications which come in a little after after
Speaker 6:  it's noticed that you may have had feelings. Yeah, physiological
Speaker 6:  feelings. And then there's also abnormal heart
Speaker 6:  rate alerts, which are like, oh, you're at rest, but your heart rate is really
Speaker 6:  high. You go, oh, oh I de oh. So I was curious if the ladder
Speaker 6:  was coming, but if, if it did have the the, we have
Speaker 6:  detected a moment of emotional distress. That's also
Speaker 6:  amazing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it might've, I was honestly too distressed to
Speaker 7:  notice.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, I seem to get a lot of those notifications,
Speaker 6:  Honestly. Oh, I do too. Don't worry. We're in the, the, the thick of tech
Speaker 6:  tober and tech tober just ended. That's peak you are having. But
Speaker 6:  this,
Speaker 3:  This is the beauty of both of your products that you both reviewed.
Speaker 3:  V you reviewed the new Pixel watch and, and the, the, these things.
Speaker 3:  Google has spent a long time making good
Speaker 3:  gadgets with stupid mistakes and, and
Speaker 3:  some of those mistakes were like, if you look at it wrong, it will just fall
Speaker 3:  apart into a hundred pieces in front of you. Or like if the wind blows on
Speaker 3:  it, it will scratch. And in, in both
Speaker 3:  the watch and the phone, Google seems to be like rapidly
Speaker 3:  actually solving those problems and you're like, I can now wear this lovely
Speaker 3:  round smartwatch out and not have it scratch
Speaker 3:  every time I bump up against another person on the sidewalk. And it's
Speaker 3:  like, these are just the little things. And this is what I mean by, I think
Speaker 3:  we all kind of had the same experience. Like I reviewed the Pixel Buds headphones
Speaker 3:  and there is no single like Earth
Speaker 3:  shatteringly great thing about them. It just does all the things and does
Speaker 3:  it pretty well. And that is like kind of the ball game. It turns
Speaker 3:  out that it's like if it just does all the things and doesn't have glaring
Speaker 3:  weaknesses, I'm probably really gonna like this product. And I feel like
Speaker 3:  v you had that experience at the watch too. It was like, none of this is
Speaker 3:  like mind blowing new stuff. It's just like a really good smartwatch for
Speaker 3:  the first time ever.
Speaker 6:  I did have a moment where I was sitting here and I was just like, holy fuck.
Speaker 6:  Did, did Google Make is, is Google
Speaker 6:  the maker of the best Android smartwatch right now? Hold
Speaker 6:  on, wait, Google. 'cause like, you know, the, the,
Speaker 6:  the very short TLDR of Android smartwatch history is that
Speaker 6:  up until 2021, they were kind of dog shit because Google
Speaker 6:  had really neglected wear OS two and it wasn't until
Speaker 6:  they like joined forces with Samsung to create Wear
Speaker 6:  West three. That stuff started to get better in
Speaker 6:  the Android space. But I would say up until this year, Samsung
Speaker 6:  was still technically the best or the most all around
Speaker 6:  Android flagship smartwatch maker. And you know,
Speaker 6:  Samsung has kind of been ghosting for a while and their
Speaker 6:  big update this year, which, you know, I still have this watch right here
Speaker 6:  with me was Squirkle, let's do a Squirkle guys
Speaker 6:  and there's Gemini on there, but that's Google's thing. But like Squirkle.
Speaker 6:  And so, you know, I, I've been having this watch here and I've been staring
Speaker 6:  at it while also staring at the Pixel Watch four on my wrist and going like,
Speaker 6:  I, I think Google's done it. I think they're the
Speaker 6:  Android smartwatch to beat because not only did they implement
Speaker 6:  Gemini in a much smarter way, even though I think it's still very hit or
Speaker 6:  miss,
Speaker 6:  they just all around have been innovating and iterating
Speaker 6:  year after year making progress. And this year they made a
Speaker 6:  ton of progress. It was like, I think Allison uses this descriptor a lot,
Speaker 6:  but it, it was like a bunch of updates in a trench coat
Speaker 6:  and now you have a Pixel watch and it's a big adult now.
Speaker 6:  And I was genuinely just sitting here like, oh my god,
Speaker 6:  you know, it is really smart that they added a dome display because when
Speaker 6:  you look at it, you do have a lot more screen space. It is really smart that
Speaker 6:  they extended material three expressive over to the
Speaker 6:  smartwatch because now everything is more glanceable
Speaker 6:  raise to talk. I don't have to be a power ranger for that to activate.
Speaker 6:  It actually does not activate for me when I do that. You just have to do
Speaker 6:  it very gently. And there, there it goes. We have, we have
Speaker 6:  a race to talk for Gemini and you know, they made it repairable,
Speaker 6:  which, you know, I, I'm gonna credit the verge.com with some real
Speaker 6:  durability testing, much like Allison's Beach extravaganza,
Speaker 6:  you know, Chris Welch, RIP to, well you know,
Speaker 6:  not REP but our beloved former Chris Welch.
Speaker 3:  He cracked the first, he's not dead, but he's dead to us. That's the important
Speaker 3:  thing.
Speaker 6:  He cracked the first Pixel watch and he has no idea how, he had no idea how
Speaker 6:  he did that. Then for the Pixel Watch two, I woke
Speaker 6:  up one morning and it was scratched to Helen back. You can look at our Pixel
Speaker 6:  watch two review to see the damage that was done. It was so bad that when
Speaker 6:  I texted the picture to Google, they sent people to my house
Speaker 6:  to pick up the watch and they were like, we must investigate what happened
Speaker 6:  to this. We must study what happened to it. Like
Speaker 3:  What criminal came through your window and just scratched up your watch and
Speaker 3:  left?
Speaker 6:  No, they actually sent it to a lab to see what happened so that we could
Speaker 6:  investigate. And all they said was abrasions happened
Speaker 6:  and it was scratched up really badly. And internally,
Speaker 6:  I have been told by my various comms friends at Google that they
Speaker 6:  blamed this guy Pete because he was But look at him at that time.
Speaker 6:  He's so sweet. Look at him, he's innocent, he's sweet and he's innocent.
Speaker 6:  He has done nothing wrong in his life, but he is mischievous and likes to
Speaker 6:  put smart watches in his mouth and chew on them. Especially when he was
Speaker 6:  a kitten, which, you know, he was a, he was a little baby when, but Soul
Speaker 6:  Watch too was happening. So now they, they curse this cat
Speaker 6:  and I take credit for the fact that the Pixel watch four is repairable because
Speaker 6:  we have done fucked up two of the displays
Speaker 6:  over time and you know, other people have as well. And it was like a
Speaker 6:  big thing online that the Pixel watch was not at all repairable. And guess
Speaker 6:  what guys? Now, now there's a little screws and they're
Speaker 6:  not proprietary screws. iFixit is gonna send sell
Speaker 6:  manuals and a repair kit so you can do it yourself for battery
Speaker 6:  replacements and display replacements. So that's
Speaker 6:  Thank you PD for your service. He's innocent. He didn't do it.
Speaker 6:  I don't believe that he did it, but in case you did, thank you for your
Speaker 3:  Service. No, he did it, but he did it on purpose for the cause
Speaker 3:  that was somebo, somebody had to do, you know what I mean? Like he's not
Speaker 3:  that smart if rights repair doesn't just do itself. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  PD really believes in right to repair.
Speaker 3:  That's exactly right.
Speaker 6:  He he does, he does because he's always, you know, like a cat
Speaker 6:  knocking shit off just to see how repairable it is. Yeah. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  that, that's, that's what PD contributed. It's
Speaker 3:  Like I fix it in Cats are the ones really getting this done for us, I would
Speaker 3:  say in general, but, so, okay, so this, this is, this brings us to the game
Speaker 3:  I wanna play here, which is, I think basically between these
Speaker 3:  devices and the Pixel 10, Google has had a very
Speaker 3:  good year of gadgets and I think is that a place where it's
Speaker 3:  probably, it probably has the best lineup of gadgets it's ever
Speaker 3:  had. And so I wanna do a thing I've been wanting to do with a bunch of companies
Speaker 3:  and I was gonna do it with Apple first, but I wanna do it with Google first.
Speaker 3:  And it's, it's a, it's a game I call company gadgets comma
Speaker 3:  ranked. And so what we're gonna do is, I, I have, I have made a
Speaker 3:  list of six Google gadgets and we're gonna rank them in order
Speaker 3:  from best to worst. And thi this is taking all things
Speaker 3:  into account, right? Like each one is gonna have a different set of competitors.
Speaker 3:  So it's how it relates to its competitors, it's what it costs, it's how you
Speaker 3:  feel about the company, it's all these things all considered and like we've
Speaker 3:  never had a way to be like our, the Pixel
Speaker 3:  buds better than the pixel fold. And dammit, we're doing that today
Speaker 3:  and maybe we'll never do this again, but I hope we will again and I think
Speaker 3:  it's gonna be very fun to do it. Our producer Travis
Speaker 3:  Eck has invented an entire new thing for us to do. Travis,
Speaker 3:  welcome to the show.
Speaker 8:  Hi. Thank you. Yes. I have vibe coded and
Speaker 8:  interactive for David to control during this segment so
Speaker 8:  that we can see the six products that we're going to rank
Speaker 8:  and their relative rankings to each other.
Speaker 3:  I need to know just a little bit about the vibe coding process. As you
Speaker 3:  know, a bunch of you over the summer did a vibe coding experiment
Speaker 3:  and I think none of you did it properly and you all did a bad job. But
Speaker 3:  Travis I think did a good job. So I wanna know, I want to know what you did.
Speaker 3:  How'd you do
Speaker 8:  It? I'm gonna tell you how I did this and then you're going to, you're going
Speaker 8:  to concede that vibe coding is much more difficult than you're claiming
Speaker 8:  that it's Alright. So basically all I wanted to do
Speaker 8:  was create a thing where there were six boxes and you could put the
Speaker 8:  little pictures of the things and you could drag them into the box and the
Speaker 8:  boxes are numbered one through six and then you can rearrange them if you
Speaker 8:  want. And the issue I kept running into, which has happened
Speaker 8:  every time I've tried to vibe code something, is it'll give you something
Speaker 8:  that's almost all the way there, but something's wrong with it. And so then
Speaker 8:  you'll say, Hey, can you not have it so that the boxes
Speaker 8:  overlap each other? Or can you make the text be bigger or
Speaker 8:  the texts not cut off and it'll be like, yeah, yeah, yeah, I did that, I
Speaker 8:  did that already the last time that you asked. Yeah, it's, everything's great.
Speaker 8:  And then, and then you say, no, it's not, it's exactly the same as the last
Speaker 8:  time. And, and then it'll be like, mm, are you sure
Speaker 3:  I come up, I think I found the problem and it will change
Speaker 8:  Nothing. Yeah. It'll be like, oh yeah, I definitely found it, but it's like,
Speaker 8:  no, you didn't, you broke the whole thing. So I've come up,
Speaker 8:  I have Pit Gemini and chat PT against each other
Speaker 8:  or maybe in collaboration with each other. So I will take a thing
Speaker 8:  that one of them has stalled out on and I will give the
Speaker 8:  code to the other l lm oh that and say, can you fix this
Speaker 8:  thing? And it'll fix it. And so I just ping ponged back and forth
Speaker 8:  from Geminis to Chachi pt.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 8:  So like three or four times having one edit the work of the other one because,
Speaker 8:  because Chachi BT doesn't know that Gemini thinks that it
Speaker 8:  solved all the problems. So it's gonna go in. So anyway,
Speaker 8:  I I present to you.
Speaker 8:  Do you see what I mean though, David? Like
Speaker 3:  This is, this is fantastic. Is everything I ever wanted it to be. I actually,
Speaker 3:  I think the like make them check each other's work. It's just like a constant
Speaker 3:  fresh eyes solution. Yeah. I love this for you. So
Speaker 3:  Travis, thank you for explaining and with all that,
Speaker 3:  let's, let's, let's play this game. This is
Speaker 3:  let's, if you're on YouTube, you're gonna see this. If not, don't worry about
Speaker 3:  it. This is called the Matic. Bye Travis. Thank you. Bye. Okay,
Speaker 3:  so we have six gadgets that we're gonna do this with. The six
Speaker 3:  gadgets are, and this is like a, a slightly imperfect thing, but this is
Speaker 3:  the best way I could think to do this. We have the pixel tablet, we have
Speaker 3:  the Pixel, regular Pixel, we have the Pixel A series,
Speaker 3:  this one's the Pixel nine A, but I mean sort of the whole A series. We have
Speaker 3:  the pixel fold, we have the Pixel Buds and we have the Pixel watch
Speaker 3:  and we are going to rank these six devices slash they're kind of
Speaker 3:  categories ish from one to six. I almost included like
Speaker 3:  Fitbit and Nest, but that got too messy. So we're just, we're just doing
Speaker 3:  a pixel thing here. Do you guys wanna start at the top or the bottom? I kind
Speaker 3:  feel like the bottom is actually gonna be the easiest.
Speaker 6:  I wanna start at the bottom. I wanna start at the bottom. And I know what
Speaker 6:  it's at the bottom too. It is the fucking Pixel tablet. Sorry. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  we shoulda all set
Speaker 3:  It out once. This is easy. Yeah, we're all very much on the same page about
Speaker 3:  that. The annoying part of this is I don't even think the Pixel tablet is
Speaker 3:  like all that terrible. It's just that absolutely nobody should buy it because
Speaker 3:  Google has no interest in it. Android tablet apps are bad. And this
Speaker 3:  thing like, it's
Speaker 6:  So expensive.
Speaker 3:  Someday this thing will be $99 on amazon.com and I will buy it
Speaker 3:  that day. And until then it should not exist.
Speaker 6:  You know, it has one good idea that there's a doc that you constantly charge
Speaker 6:  your tablet on because my iPad, iPad, he's a speaker, speaker, doc idea and
Speaker 6:  has a speaker. Great idea. Yeah. But also the problem is, is because
Speaker 6:  it does that I never use it as a tablet. Mm. So
Speaker 6:  ing so wouldn't be, I have two don't mys
Speaker 6:  just lives
Speaker 3:  Like, it just lives on the dock.
Speaker 6:  It just lives on the dock in, in the two places. Like we never take it
Speaker 6:  down. It's our smart home. Like, you know, Jen had me,
Speaker 6:  well Jen walked me through building a smart home and after I told her all
Speaker 6:  of my woes and the structure of my house, she's like, I think Google's
Speaker 6:  system is for you. And so now I have two pixel tablets and I
Speaker 6:  hate them equally.
Speaker 3:  Fair enough. All right, well that one, that one was easy. I had a feeling
Speaker 3:  we were all gonna land on this place. I'm sorry to the Pixel tablet.
Speaker 3:  I think I, I feel like from here things immediately get difficult for Yeah,
Speaker 3:  but let, let's build up from nothing. Alison, what
Speaker 3:  do you have at number five?
Speaker 7:  Oh, this is tough.
Speaker 7:  Gosh. Well I know what I want to be number one, so I'm
Speaker 7:  kind of working backwards I think. Okay. If this is kind of
Speaker 7:  in terms of who should buy these things.
Speaker 3:  No, it's best products, just best what is, what is in in all
Speaker 3:  this? This is, this is the, the point of this exercise is that it is extremely
Speaker 3:  all encompassing. Right? Okay. And so it's like, are are
Speaker 3:  part of it is should you buy it obviously like part of this ranking is going
Speaker 3:  to be ranking in which they are good and thus you should buy them. But I
Speaker 3:  think like price is a part of it, but it's not the
Speaker 3:  only part of it. And so it's like, I I, yeah, I'm putting all of this together
Speaker 3:  on purpose. I would propose that number five should be the pixel fold.
Speaker 7:  That's what I was thinking. I'm like, I feel bad. It's good. It's
Speaker 3:  A, it is good. It's
Speaker 7:  A great phone. But as far as like mass appeal, you know,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's not something I would still recommend. Even though you can take
Speaker 7:  you to the beach and drown it.
Speaker 3:  So our, our former colleague and now Googler Dan Seaford is like
Speaker 3:  forever just running around on threads, telling people about all the cool
Speaker 3:  things you can do with a foldable phone. And I believe him, it's lovely.
Speaker 3:  I think he is earnest about it and I love him for this. I
Speaker 3:  don't think Google or anyone has done a good job of making the case for why
Speaker 3:  you should have a foldable phone other than like look big screen, you know?
Speaker 3:  And like I love big screen only
Speaker 6:  Allison at tech events whipping out her foldable phone.
Speaker 6:  The only time I have ever wanted foldable phones were at
Speaker 6:  two tech events where my peers Allison at one of them and
Speaker 6:  my friend Sam from End Gadget at the other were like, huh, I got a live blog
Speaker 6:  this wifi in Brooklyn Navy, art is crappy. Well lemme just pull out
Speaker 6:  my foldable phone that can handle any awful CMS
Speaker 6:  God. And they're just blogging machines and I've gone, do I wanna
Speaker 6:  foldable? That was the only time I ever
Speaker 7:  Fold. It was a triumphant triumphant moment for the fold. I think
Speaker 7:  the, I would put, I feel better about putting the pixel fold at five
Speaker 7:  because the Samsung galaxies Z fold seven
Speaker 7:  exists and it is so much thinner and lighter in
Speaker 7:  like more comfortable to hold and carry.
Speaker 7:  Don't bring it to the beach. But yeah,
Speaker 3:  This feels good. V any objections?
Speaker 6:  No, you know. Yeah, no, I, I agree Also, like
Speaker 6:  you're gonna go to the beach and at the beach you're gonna wanna read. And
Speaker 6:  as our good friend Dan Seaford always says, reading is one of
Speaker 6:  the primary uses for the foldable phone. So if you're gonna go to the beach
Speaker 6:  and you wanna read on your phone,
Speaker 6:  I mean come on, you can't be defeated by a tiny grain of sand. No,
Speaker 3:  This is true. All right. No, I think we're doing the fold. I feel good about
Speaker 3:  the fold in part because it's also still $1,800.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Like for all the ways it's getting better, it is still twice the price
Speaker 3:  of all the other phones and that's bad. And that's true of all foldable phones.
Speaker 3:  Okay, this might be dumb. I think I wanna put the pixel
Speaker 3:  buds forth despite the fact that I just gave them a nine. And I think
Speaker 3:  they're terrific.
Speaker 3:  But I wanna do this for one specific reason, which is that there are so,
Speaker 3:  so, so many good pairs of headphones out there. It's not that these are not
Speaker 3:  very good, it's just that like in the scheme of things,
Speaker 3:  I think the price on these is very good. But I also like there was just a
Speaker 3:  prime day sale that had the Pixel buds Pro two, which are even better,
Speaker 3:  but usually a hundred dollars more expensive, $60 off. So I'm like,
Speaker 3:  okay, if I have 130 to $150 to spend on headphones,
Speaker 3:  give it a minute and shop for sales. And you can buy a lot of really good
Speaker 3:  pairs of headphones. And I don't think the pixel buds are like so
Speaker 3:  spectacularly better than everything that they deserve
Speaker 3:  sort of massive ranking. Yeah. Even though I think they're great.
Speaker 7:  That seems fair. They're not like standouts in the way that some of these
Speaker 7:  other things are. I think,
Speaker 3:  And I kind of think I, if we put pixel buds forth, I think the top three
Speaker 3:  all qualify as like actual standouts in certain ways. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say though, like, look, these are purple and they're so cool and,
Speaker 3:  and I love them. And look, look at that. Come
Speaker 6:  On David, this was the line in your review and I commented this on the
Speaker 6:  review that I was like, yes, as the verges foremost senior purple
Speaker 6:  reviewer, I, I loved your love of purple
Speaker 6:  and the assertion that we should all have purple headphones and I think all
Speaker 6:  tech makers should get on that stat. But to
Speaker 6:  your point, you know, for four and five I was debating between the pixel
Speaker 6:  fold versus the pixel buds. Okay. And I think the
Speaker 6:  1800 does justify the number five. But
Speaker 6:  the thing that was kind of for me about the pixel
Speaker 6:  buds was when we went to see the ha the content capture and the hands-on
Speaker 6:  Google itself was just like, well look at our phones, look at
Speaker 6:  our watch. And in the corner over there is the pixel buds. So
Speaker 3:  Right. And that's the thing, they're like, they're, they're very good. But
Speaker 3:  you, I mean, and I said this in my review, like you, you, it's very hard
Speaker 3:  to find a bad pair of headphones these days, which is like a lovely thing
Speaker 3:  about the world that there are a lot of great headphones out there at all
Speaker 3:  price points. But like I was looking just to sort of test my
Speaker 3:  price tolerance against others. And like you go to the Wirecutter and their
Speaker 3:  favorite pair of under a hundred dollars headphones is like a brand you've
Speaker 3:  never heard of that people absolutely love. And so it's like, okay
Speaker 3:  headphones, you're spoiled for choice. We
Speaker 3:  can make the pixel buts forth even though they're very good. And the purple
Speaker 3:  is awesome and if you have one, I will give you a high five on the street.
Speaker 3:  Alright, that's three. So let's pause here and take a quick
Speaker 3:  break. Just to recap, at number six we have the Google Pixel tablet,
Speaker 3:  easiest decision of the day. At number five we have the pixel fold. And number
Speaker 3:  four we have the Pixel buds. We're gonna take a super quick break, come back
Speaker 3:  and rank the top three. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we're back. Just to reorient, we have three things left on
Speaker 3:  the board. We have the pixel, which is like encompassing of all the normal
Speaker 3:  Pixel line, the Pixel, the Pixel Pro, the Pro xl, that's the pixel. We
Speaker 3:  have the Pixel watch, which frankly already a coup to be just in the top
Speaker 3:  half of the list here. And we have the Pixel A series including the Pixel
Speaker 3:  nine A, that's our top three in some order. Let's get back into it.
Speaker 3:  I think we have to put a phone here.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I know which one I want.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, which one do you wanna put number three?
Speaker 7:  I will put the regular pixel number three even though it's very good.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I think we agree on what number one should be then. Do we?
Speaker 3:  We'll get to that. Do
Speaker 7:  We? Okay.
Speaker 3:  I think, I think we might,
Speaker 7:  No, the Pixel is great. I think it's like you want an
Speaker 7:  Android phone that just feels like
Speaker 7:  Uncluttered and Unbusy and does
Speaker 7:  it tastes good pictures and it has chi too and all that. Like
Speaker 7:  great, this is, this is the phone you should get but it's, I don't,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, like there it is. You can get that,
Speaker 7:  you know that it, that is a thing that exists. It doesn't feel as
Speaker 7:  special.
Speaker 3:  But let me just, let me, this is an open question. I might be completely
Speaker 3:  wrong in setting myself up for failure here. If I'm just like a regular person
Speaker 3:  and I'm like, Allison, what Android phone should I buy? And you are allowed
Speaker 3:  to ask me no follow up questions. Aren't you recommending the Pixel?
Speaker 7:  Okay. Yes. But my follow up question
Speaker 7:  is, what is your wireless carrier giving away for free?
Speaker 7:  Because probably fair that's what you're doing.
Speaker 7:  No, no, no. In, yeah, I'm like, are you paying out of pocket? And
Speaker 7:  then, alright, I have, I have two follow-up questions to your no
Speaker 7:  follow up question. Question.
Speaker 3:  Well, so this is the part where I'm torn is I think right now
Speaker 3:  the Pixel 10 is the best Android phone and
Speaker 3:  I actually don't think it's like super close. Yeah. And I think that that's
Speaker 3:  a like meaningful, powerful thing and I don't think that's been true for
Speaker 3:  a while. I think Samsung really like figured out a lot of stuff and
Speaker 3:  got way ahead and I think Google has just sort of slowly resolutely caught
Speaker 3:  up and just the like day-to-day experience of using a Pixel to me
Speaker 3:  is so much more pleasant than using Samsung software still.
Speaker 3:  That like I just, again, like I I all the people in my
Speaker 3:  life who use Android, who don't wanna spend a lot of time thinking about
Speaker 3:  their phone have pixels and are happier for it. And I think that is like,
Speaker 3:  that means something. But there are phones that
Speaker 3:  cost as much as the Pixel that are also terrific, which is
Speaker 3:  why I think the Pixel belongs Yeah. In, in spot three.
Speaker 6:  But, okay, so my question though is that we're also ranking these things
Speaker 6:  against each other and if we're going with a phone for number three, you
Speaker 6:  know, people don't upgrade their phones every year anymore. And if you are
Speaker 6:  making a long-term choice between an A
Speaker 6:  series Pixel phone and a pixel phone, are you actually
Speaker 6:  gonna say that the A is better than the Pixel? Because I
Speaker 6:  have been using the Pixel 10 Excel for
Speaker 6:  Pixel Pro, you know, like one of those things for testing
Speaker 6:  in the summer of Android watches. And I feel like, oh my God,
Speaker 6:  it's really good. I'm, I'm like a, I've been an iPhone girly for a really
Speaker 6:  long time and I'm like, oh, this is really nice. I enjoy this quite a bit
Speaker 6:  except that I'm always accidentally circling to search
Speaker 6:  unintentionally. But yeah,
Speaker 6:  it's a really great phone. It feels like I've been so delighted by it this
Speaker 6:  past summer that I'm just like, oh, well if I, if it were up to me,
Speaker 6:  would I, I would be pleasantly
Speaker 6:  chuffed to spend the extra money regardless of carrier deals
Speaker 6:  for, for the mainline phone versus the budget. Especially if I am,
Speaker 6:  you know, a normal person and not a reviewer with like 50 phones in, in,
Speaker 6:  in my bag.
Speaker 6:  I, I don't know, I kind of am just like, I,
Speaker 7:  So here's, here's where I'm landing with this. I feel
Speaker 7:  like a nice $800 phone solved
Speaker 7:  like that exists that right now I would recommend the
Speaker 7:  Pixel. Like that's the one you should get. But it doesn't feel like
Speaker 7:  a standout in the way that I think the
Speaker 7:  Aeries Pixel phone is. Like, it is the phone I recommend
Speaker 7:  to like, not phone people. I I made my parents buy
Speaker 7:  them 'cause I don't want them walking around with phones that are security
Speaker 7:  risks.
Speaker 7:  The, the amount of like software updates it gets and what you get
Speaker 7:  in the price point, I think makes it like far and above
Speaker 7:  like, yeah, you're not gonna find this somewhere else. Not in this country.
Speaker 7:  And so I don't, I'm, I'm tipping my hand, but I I
Speaker 7:  really like the Aeries Pixel.
Speaker 3:  We do agree on the, on the, on the order at this first. Oh yes. I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm with Allison. I think we're gonna put the pixel third because for, for
Speaker 3:  exactly that reason. I think when you, when you think about what is it
Speaker 3:  competing with, the Pixel has real one-to-one
Speaker 3:  competitors in the way that the Aeries just doesn't.
Speaker 3:  So that's VII appreciate your point, ed. I'm
Speaker 6:  Sorry. No, I, I defer to the phone expert.
Speaker 6:  I am the wearable lady so I de I defer to expertise here.
Speaker 6:  All right, so
Speaker 3:  This leaves us with in sixth place the Pixel tablet, fifth place, the pixel
Speaker 3:  fold, fourth place the Pixel Buds, third place the pixel.
Speaker 3:  We have two left. We have the Pixel, A series and the Pixel watch. I
Speaker 3:  believe Allison and I both wanna put the a series
Speaker 3:  number one
Speaker 3:  V Would you like to make the case for why the Pixel watch? Yes. Should be
Speaker 3:  number one.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Because you could,
Speaker 6:  I think it's how far it's come one and where it is
Speaker 6:  going. Again, you could make the argument
Speaker 6:  that,
Speaker 6:  you know, in the world of budget phones, there is massive innovation
Speaker 6:  coming.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if I fully believe that on my side of the, the
Speaker 6:  tech review sphere. But every conversation
Speaker 6:  I've had with the Pixel team, every conversation I've had with
Speaker 6:  tech companies about what's coming next, it leads me to believe
Speaker 6:  that we are going to be living in a wearable hell soon.
Speaker 6:  Which
Speaker 6:  is, is, and if you look at the scope of things,
Speaker 6:  the only real competitor that the Pixel Watch has now is the
Speaker 6:  Apple Watch. As far as flagship things go, and
Speaker 6:  I don't say this lightly, this was the most intriguing
Speaker 6:  and the most interesting and the most a plus
Speaker 6:  of the wearables smart watches that I have tested this year.
Speaker 3:  You think the Pixel watch right now is better than the Apple Watch?
Speaker 6:  It is more interesting. It is. That's
Speaker 3:  Not what I asked.
Speaker 6:  It's almost on par. Okay. In some ways it's not, but it almost
Speaker 6:  is the fact that it has Fitbit integration and Fitbit does health
Speaker 6:  in a way that is smarter. Okay,
Speaker 6:  workout buddy, it's fine. But they're coming out with an AI coach
Speaker 6:  where the, the look that I got beforehand truly left
Speaker 6:  me sitting there going like, if they can pull this off, this is major.
Speaker 6:  You know, they are starting to innovate on, on on
Speaker 6:  certain areas that Apple just has not,
Speaker 6:  these Apple watches is still not repairable. These are, that's major. Yep.
Speaker 3:  I think you, you also can't underestimate how much better Gemini is than
Speaker 3:  Siri. And like if, if you, if you are a believer that
Speaker 3:  AI interactions and AI input in particular is like a real reason to get a
Speaker 3:  smart watch. And I think that it is, that is such a giant advantage for the
Speaker 3:  Pixel Watch series sucks so bad.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. My husband has gotten used to me being able to ask
Speaker 7:  Gemini questions on the watch and he goes, ask your watch.
Speaker 7:  Can you ask your watch this thing? I'm like, hold up.
Speaker 7:  I decide what I ask my watch.
Speaker 3:  You should just start, just reach out your arm and be like, you ask Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I don't
Speaker 7:  Care. You talk to the robot.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's just such a massive leap to the point where it's like,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna have to talk and we're gonna have to refi configure our buying
Speaker 6:  guide because this is the best Android smart watch on the market right now.
Speaker 6:  Like one plus sure the battery life is better, but the fact that
Speaker 6:  this can go from 14% to 27, no,
Speaker 6:  14% to 97% in 34 minutes is massive.
Speaker 6:  I, I did a test where I had this Ultra and the
Speaker 6:  Pixel Watch four, and this is the ultra three. They were both at
Speaker 6:  14 per 14% and 15% respectively. I
Speaker 6:  charged them for the same amount of time. The Pixel watch went to 97%.
Speaker 6:  The Apple Watch Ultra went to 55. Wow. So it charges faster than the Apple
Speaker 6:  Watch Ultra battery lifewise. I
Speaker 6:  got, I got a pretty good amount on, on
Speaker 6:  the, on the larger watch, which is the 45 millimeter.
Speaker 6:  Allison got I think a day and a half on the smaller watch. I think I got,
Speaker 6:  I forget the exact number. It's in my review. My, my brain is Swiss cheese,
Speaker 6:  but it was a good amount on there. I think it was around 55
Speaker 6:  hours. 40, 40 at least 48 hours I got
Speaker 6:  comfortably. And the fact that you can just charge it in
Speaker 6:  15 to 30 minutes and it's gonna be most of the way charged you, you
Speaker 6:  kind of solve the battery problem. Yeah. Fitbit is much better at sleep
Speaker 6:  tracking than the Apple Watch is. You have a wider, robust thing. The only
Speaker 6:  thing that it's not better at is GPS tracking, which, eh, whatever
Speaker 6:  the maps are good enough, even though it has dual frequency
Speaker 6:  GPS right now, they've, they both have satellite
Speaker 6:  connectivity, but frankly, at least in my neck of the woods, I hooked up,
Speaker 6:  I hiked up three mountains in dense state forests
Speaker 6:  and at no point did I lose cellular coverage on either watch.
Speaker 6:  So I have to go travel down at Thanksgiving to t ask in Maryland
Speaker 6:  where my in-laws are from and there is a nut farm
Speaker 6:  where there's only one bar of service and you have to stand in a certain
Speaker 6:  way. So I have to go test satellite there because nowhere in
Speaker 6:  the tri-state area that I've been to in the last three weeks is without cell
Speaker 6:  coverage. So I'm just saying there, you
Speaker 6:  know, I I will a seed if you guys really wanna put the A series
Speaker 6:  first, but in terms of like cohesive vision where this thing is going,
Speaker 6:  the, the massive strides they've made in four years, it's just
Speaker 6:  blown me away. I think you both will say that I am am a
Speaker 6:  grumpy pants. It's very hard to impress me. We
Speaker 3:  Said a lot of mean things about pixel watches on the Verge
Speaker 6:  Over the years. We have said so many mean things. Yes. And look at me now,
Speaker 6:  I am saying this is the best Android smartwatch on the market. And I don't
Speaker 6:  say that lightly. I actually think
Speaker 3:  Debating there is a real case case to be made that this is just the best
Speaker 3:  smartwatch period. Like especially for like, if you're not like a
Speaker 3:  Capital F Fitness person and the thing you want is like all the
Speaker 3:  other stuff that they talk about for smartwatches, there's a
Speaker 3:  run of those things that the Pixel Watch does better than the Apple Watch.
Speaker 7:  I, my only complaint just coming from the Apple Watch to the
Speaker 7:  Pixel for now, it feels like a
Speaker 7:  tiny bit slower. It is like just a beat behind
Speaker 7:  where I'm like pressing a a thing and it
Speaker 7:  takes a second to like pop up. You know, I don't know, you,
Speaker 7:  you're the, the expert on this v maybe you can
Speaker 7:  tell me if I'm imagining things, but I
Speaker 6:  Literally just got a notification across all three of them at this point
Speaker 6:  in time. All the three watches that I have right now, that's too many notifications
Speaker 6:  and the Garmin was the slowest. It's, it's, my arms
Speaker 6:  are constantly buzzing and I've just gotten used to it. But
Speaker 7:  What a sentence.
Speaker 6:  I think you could make the argument that the Apple Watch has gestures and
Speaker 6:  that this is only kind of starting to catch up in the gesture space. So in
Speaker 6:  terms of hands free computing, this is
Speaker 6:  a little bit ahead, but again, Gemini on the wrist,
Speaker 6:  light years ahead of Siri on the wrist, it's great. So
Speaker 6:  in terms of like the series 11, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Okay. That wasn't a major upgrade year over, like I I
Speaker 6:  legitimately said that the Apple Watch se three look at me. I just ha I'm
Speaker 6:  just pulling smart watches out of thin air. The, the SE three
Speaker 6:  was the most compelling Apple Watch this year and I, I love the Apple Watch.
Speaker 6:  I think it's a great smart watch. It has been leading the industry
Speaker 6:  for close to 10 years now and this is a real competitor
Speaker 6:  for the first time. I'm just like one-to-one. The ideas are there,
Speaker 6:  the cohesive vision is there. I, you know, in this
Speaker 6:  mad blitz review period where I've been writing like
Speaker 6:  10,000 words a week or what whatever and thinking about all these wearable
Speaker 6:  devices because why are there so many wearables this year? I don't know they
Speaker 6:  want me to die. But
Speaker 6:  you know, it's the one that at least of the wrist based
Speaker 6:  things has really impressed me and
Speaker 6:  it's a surprise. It's why I, if we were
Speaker 6:  doing this with a pixel watch today, I would not be arguing this hard is
Speaker 6:  what I would say. Mm.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, I also would've, like I wouldn't ruthlessly started making fun
Speaker 3:  of you if you had started arguing that hard. No, I think you're right. And
Speaker 3:  I think the, like what is the best smartwatch question is a very complicated
Speaker 3:  and b, totally moot, right? Like no one I think buys a watch first and then
Speaker 3:  a phone. So you're just buying the one that connects to your phone and like,
Speaker 3:  it's sort of the end, but the fact that they're even meaningfully close
Speaker 3:  and you don't have to miss one if you have the other huge victory
Speaker 3:  for phone buyers everywhere. Allison
Speaker 3:  was that, are you convinced, did that change your mind at all?
Speaker 7:  This is tougher than I thought now because the, the
Speaker 7:  argument that there's more innovation and there's more coming
Speaker 7:  to get kind of excited about I I totally see that on the
Speaker 7:  watch. Okay,
Speaker 3:  So can I, let me just pour cold water on that really fast. One of the, one
Speaker 3:  of the core beliefs of the Verge is that we don't review products based on
Speaker 3:  future potential. And this is, we can redo this ranking at some point, but
Speaker 3:  this right now is, is the best, what is the best Google product
Speaker 3:  right now?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I think the, the the strides thing is real, right? And the, the the
Speaker 3:  like distance Google has come is amazing, but like
Speaker 3:  if we're gonna give, you know, I I I would have to sit here and be like,
Speaker 3:  well if Siri gets better and I don't wanna do that. So we can't do that with
Speaker 3:  generally.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, well it, there's also like a, phones
Speaker 7:  are such a known quantity and like a solved thing
Speaker 7:  where I talk to my hairstylist and I recommend, you know, I had her
Speaker 7:  buy a pixel, but then I'm like, have you thought about a watch?
Speaker 7:  And I kind of, I kind of have evangelize like smart watches
Speaker 7:  now 'cause I find them so useful. She got a smartwatch,
Speaker 7:  she got a Pixel watch and she loves it too. So you
Speaker 7:  I see
Speaker 6:  My side, Allison, come, come.
Speaker 3:  So the, the other thing is Allison, the, the point you made about whatever
Speaker 3:  phone you're getting for free from your carrier is also a knock against
Speaker 3:  the Pixel A series because the, the case I would make for the Pixel a series
Speaker 3:  is that for a very long time
Speaker 3:  you could not buy a good phone for less than about
Speaker 3:  $800. It just didn't exist. There were lots of phones at like
Speaker 3:  $200 that were fine and you could get like a perfectly
Speaker 3:  functional Android phone for not a lot of money. That's been true for a very
Speaker 3:  long time. But the, that sort of middle space where it
Speaker 3:  was good but not like feature complete but
Speaker 3:  was at a like meaningfully cheaper price point literally did not
Speaker 3:  exist. And then Google showed up and was like, well we're gonna do the A
Speaker 3:  series and has now gotten to the point where the a series
Speaker 3:  is meaningfully close to being as good as all of the
Speaker 3:  high-end competitors to the point where now I'm like, okay, well
Speaker 3:  you can have the $800 or $900 or
Speaker 3:  a thousand dollars phone or you can have this $400 phone that makes this
Speaker 3:  one compromise. What are your thoughts? And they, and like
Speaker 3:  I I've had the same experience you have where like a lot of people in my
Speaker 3:  life just very happily bought a series phones and, and
Speaker 3:  have never looked back. And it's like, sure, you don't get some of the like
Speaker 3:  high-end stuff. You don't always get the fastest processor. You don't always
Speaker 3:  get the best camera, but like you get a very good phone for literally half
Speaker 3:  the price and it, it reinvented the existence of that
Speaker 3:  thing. And I want to give the pixel a series of a lot of credit for that,
Speaker 3:  except particularly in the US there is a strong chance that you are trading
Speaker 3:  in a phone and thus getting whatever you get for almost no money.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. God, that is the ugly thing. I I think what I,
Speaker 7:  one of the things I appreciate about the a series is that it is with in
Speaker 7:  the realm of possibilities that you would pay out of pocket for this thing
Speaker 7:  and it's, you know, that that varies and there's
Speaker 7:  financing you can do if you're even doing that much.
Speaker 7:  But as far as like we're we are so in the grasp of these
Speaker 7:  carriers and the deals and the upgrades and
Speaker 7:  it feels so like kind of refreshing that the Pixel a
Speaker 7:  series is over here is like if you wanna break free of
Speaker 7:  that and you can like cobble together 500
Speaker 7:  bucks, you can still trade on your phone and probably get some
Speaker 7:  money off of that that exists and you can just own it and you can walk
Speaker 7:  away with it and it's your phone and you haven't made a
Speaker 7:  huge sacrifice as far as you know, performance or features. You
Speaker 7:  don't get a telephoto camera now, but you know, you can probably make do
Speaker 7:  that's my, that's my one thing to keep the
Speaker 7:  Pixel a series phone in the number one spot. It just feels
Speaker 7:  like it's the phone that can break the cycle
Speaker 7:  of carrier deal addiction.
Speaker 3:  All right Allison, I'm gonna make you do an incredibly unfair thing. I'm
Speaker 3:  sticking with the Pixel nine A as my number one V
Speaker 3:  has made a, I would say a surprisingly great case for
Speaker 3:  the Pixel watch. You have to break the tie.
Speaker 7:  Oh my gosh. Well I was gonna buddy just ran away
Speaker 7:  like I'm out
Speaker 6:  Is looking the door that's close right now and he's like, let me out because
Speaker 6:  the whatever. But I will concede that there
Speaker 6:  are times when I am using Gemini on the wrist and
Speaker 6:  I'm just like, I'm gonna just pull out my phone. So
Speaker 6:  if we're talking about that, I would not be mad for the Pixel
Speaker 6:  watch to be number two to me, I'm just
Speaker 6:  saying it's the best Android smartwatch out there. It is. And so if we're
Speaker 6:  talking about Google products as a whole and we're talking about like the
Speaker 6:  best thing that it does, you know, I
Speaker 6:  I'll be satisfied if it's in the top two.
Speaker 3:  I think on this list number two for the Pixel Watch is like there's going
Speaker 3:  to be rejoicing on the Pixel Watch team if if for this to even be number
Speaker 3:  two on here,
Speaker 6:  I'll be satisfied for it to be number two. So Alison, go with your heart.
Speaker 6:  I made my case.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna go with Pixel Watch number two as the like,
Speaker 7:  happy to be here. It's it's love in its life. And the number two
Speaker 7:  slot there, pixel nine a Reigns Supreme,
Speaker 7:  it's the phone you get your dad to buy.
Speaker 3:  Honestly, the Pixel watch was just happy to be nominated, you know what I
Speaker 3:  mean? Exactly. It's an honor just to be here at the award ceremony.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's it's getting best supporting actress even though it didn't even
Speaker 6:  think it would get nominated and yeah. You know, it's,
Speaker 3:  It just, it just came for the, for the free alcohol and instead it got
Speaker 3:  nominated and like that's, that's a huge victory.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'm, I'm quite satisfied. So
Speaker 3:  Just to recap at number six we have the Pixel tablet, which is the one team
Speaker 3:  at Google that should feel bad at the end of these rankings. I would say
Speaker 3:  at number five we have the pixel fold. Number four, we have pixel Buds number
Speaker 3:  three, we have the pixel, which I should say encompasses like just the pixel,
Speaker 3:  pixel Pro, all the, just the regular pixels. Number two,
Speaker 3:  we have the pixel watch and at number one the best product Google
Speaker 3:  makes. And I think we, I think we got this right, it's the pixel A series.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We nailed it.
Speaker 3:  I love this.
Speaker 6:  I really can't believe that Google is good at smartwatches now.
Speaker 6:  Like if you asked me this five years ago, I would've laughed at you. Google
Speaker 3:  Makes good gadgets consistently. This inevitably means in three months Google
Speaker 3:  will shut down the whole pixel line.
Speaker 6:  They'll all go into the, we're all gonna look like eighties. They'll all
Speaker 6:  go into the gravestone. God.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But until then, I'm very excited about this. Alright, thank you
Speaker 3:  both for doing this. Me, this was delightful. Travis, your tool works fabulously.
Speaker 3:  This was great. We're gonna have to do this again. I I I enjoy this exercise
Speaker 3:  very much and I think it's gonna be fun with some other companies too. Especially
Speaker 3:  ones that have like even weirder and more disparate product lineups to talk
Speaker 3:  about. Like, are the AirPods better than the iPad
Speaker 3:  is a question I'm going to say out loud to both of you at some point in the
Speaker 3:  near future and I'm very much looking forward to it.
Speaker 7:  Yes, I'll be thinking about that. I don't know, I
Speaker 7:  want the Dyson rankings.
Speaker 3:  Ooh, that's a good one too. The, yeah, let's
Speaker 7:  Do, let's do vacuum cleaners versus that weird hair dryer
Speaker 3:  Versus face
Speaker 6:  Masks. Which weird hair dryer.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This be, oh god, there's more than one. Okay. I
Speaker 3:  Dunno. I like it. We're gonna have to call in like $1.5 million worth of
Speaker 3:  DYS and gear and then we'll do this. It's gonna be awesome. Alright, well
Speaker 3:  until then we need to take a break. We're gonna come back, we're gonna talk
Speaker 3:  about AI and some studies about what AI is doing to our brains. But
Speaker 3:  until then, v Allison, thank you both. This was great. Thank you. We'll be
Speaker 3:  right back
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. Alison Johnson's still here. Hi Alison. Hello. Still,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna do a question for the Vergecast hotline. As always, you can call
Speaker 3:  8 6 6 Verge one one. You can email vergecast@theverge.com. You
Speaker 3:  can find Allison at the beach and yell at your questions at her as she's
Speaker 3:  dunking her phone into things. We love hearing all of your
Speaker 3:  questions and we're, we're gonna do lots more with them in the next several
Speaker 3:  weeks. We're talking about some fun stuff, so keep it locked for now. Allison,
Speaker 3:  we have a question about my favorite thing, the light
Speaker 3:  phone? Mm, here it's,
Speaker 16:  Hi, this is Lucas. I'm on my way to school right now campus.
Speaker 16:  I'm a student at Oregon State and I've been living with my light
Speaker 16:  phone since about May or so. And I love it.
Speaker 16:  It's absolutely fantastic. It's been my primary phone since then,
Speaker 16:  and every time I grab it out, lots of students end up asking about it
Speaker 16:  and it seems I, I'm not the only one who has switched to like a dumber phone.
Speaker 16:  I'm curious if more people, not just students are
Speaker 16:  switching finally. Okay. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so I, I bring this to you, Allison, because this is a thing I've been
Speaker 3:  grappling with a lot is I think the,
Speaker 3:  the stories you hear about people like wanting to get away
Speaker 3:  from their phones and wanting to reset their relationship with their phones
Speaker 3:  and understanding the ways that their phones are sort of problematic
Speaker 3:  influences in a lot of their lives. You and I have been hearing those stories
Speaker 3:  for forever, and I think my reaction to 'em for the longest time has been
Speaker 3:  like, o okay, that is like a statistically insignificant
Speaker 3:  but interesting story, right? That like, what actually turns out to be the
Speaker 3:  case is everybody pretty much just really likes their phones,
Speaker 3:  but it's somewhere in 2025. It has felt to me like
Speaker 3:  the tide is turning and there is not necessarily the light phone specifically,
Speaker 3:  but this idea of wanting less phone.
Speaker 3:  And I mean that in the broadest way possible seems to be real. And I,
Speaker 3:  I wanna know if that is how it feels to you, or if, if not,
Speaker 7:  I do think it's real and I, I hear it more,
Speaker 7:  I guess anecdotally from friends who are like, ah, I don't know. I've
Speaker 7:  been thinking about just going with a, a minimalist phone and getting a,
Speaker 7:  a compact camera and calling it a day.
Speaker 7:  And I always just, I hesitate a little
Speaker 7:  bit. I'm like, well, I'm gonna be the bummer here. But
Speaker 7:  like, you probably,
Speaker 7:  it's tougher than it seems and it sounds like Lucas has, is loving it
Speaker 7:  and is having a great time with it, and that's incredible
Speaker 7:  for him.
Speaker 7:  I have just struggled every time I've, I've tried one of these
Speaker 7:  sort of minimalist phones or it's a, a flip phone and you're kind of like,
Speaker 7:  it's a throwback
Speaker 7:  and my kind of go-to recommendations are,
Speaker 7:  you know, maybe a minimalist phone is for you. Here's some things to
Speaker 7:  try before you throw everything away.
Speaker 7:  Start your life over again without apps. Casey
Speaker 7:  Johnston actually has a really good guide to dumbing down
Speaker 7:  your smartphone. So kind of,
Speaker 7:  you basically do almost like a hard reset and you get rid of your apps and
Speaker 7:  you clean it up and you make it just less
Speaker 7:  enticing. I think that's a, you know, a lot of people could do that
Speaker 7:  and find themselves very happy with it.
Speaker 7:  And the other recommendation I go to is maybe
Speaker 7:  a cellular smartwatch. Hmm. Which was the little
Speaker 7:  experiment I ran recently. And I
Speaker 7:  found there are a lot of cases when I could leave my phone at home,
Speaker 7:  just go be out in the world, still have the ability to
Speaker 7:  text and make a call if I needed pay for stuff with
Speaker 7:  my, you know, tap to pay
Speaker 7:  that is well within, you know, you don't have to go buy a whole
Speaker 7:  new phone. You don't have to get into a whole new system. You can get the
Speaker 7:  smartwatch that exists for your phone
Speaker 7:  and, and try that. But those are my, those are my big
Speaker 7:  two things that I think a lot of people would be happy
Speaker 7:  with.
Speaker 3:  I agree. I've started recommending people buy the cellular
Speaker 3:  smartwatch, which was not a, a thing that I felt before. It was normally
Speaker 3:  like it's, there will be times where it's really useful, but unless you're
Speaker 3:  a person who goes on like really long runs and needs, that kind of thing,
Speaker 3:  I was always like, just get the wifi, it'll be fine. But I do think now the
Speaker 3:  opportunity to take that with you and have this sort of, if somebody
Speaker 3:  needs me, they can get me peace of mind, but still be mostly disconnected
Speaker 3:  is actually really powerful. I wonder as you're talking to,
Speaker 3:  you know, the companies that make phones or even the carriers or any of those
Speaker 3:  folks, do you have any sense that they're starting to reckon with some of
Speaker 3:  these changes? Like, are, are the folks building phones thinking about how
Speaker 3:  do we help the people who are trying to reset the way that they're
Speaker 3:  using their phones?
Speaker 7:  I think they do, and there's a real tension. You know,
Speaker 7:  I don't, I don't know how far we can hope that they will go
Speaker 7:  or expect them to go because they're kind of in
Speaker 7:  the business of keeping us on our phones, you know, and maybe that's more
Speaker 7:  down to the, the app makers than the, the people who make the hardware.
Speaker 7:  But I mean, there are really good tools on your phone for,
Speaker 7:  you know, monitoring your screen time. I don't find that super
Speaker 7:  useful, honestly, but focus modes, and
Speaker 7:  I kind of find it funny that Apple's latest idea
Speaker 7:  about how to reign in your notifications is to just like invent a new
Speaker 7:  focus mode that filters most of
Speaker 7:  the noise out.
Speaker 7:  So the, the tools exist. And I think there,
Speaker 7:  there is an understanding that people want this and we
Speaker 7:  want help
Speaker 7:  bringing some balance into how we use our phones. So poke at those
Speaker 7:  things. I think if you're kind of feeling this, but I don't, I don't know
Speaker 7:  if we can hope that the phone makers are gonna rescue us from our
Speaker 7:  addictions.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I tend to agree. And I think the thing that I've always wondered about
Speaker 3:  these companies is a, they obviously have tons of incentive to keep you on
Speaker 3:  your phone, but I've always wondered like, are they gonna get to the point
Speaker 3:  where the narrative against phones becomes so huge
Speaker 3:  that they have to make some of these changes or else they risk losing people?
Speaker 3:  Hmm. I don't think we're there yet. I mean, I know for sure we're not there
Speaker 3:  yet. Yeah. So we're definitely not at the point of like Apple and
Speaker 3:  Google and Samsung need to be worried about people abandoning their phones
Speaker 3:  in droves. I don't think that's coming, but I do think
Speaker 3:  the sort of human awareness that like my relationship with my phone
Speaker 3:  is not what I want it to be, and I'm not really in charge of it.
Speaker 3:  I think that is something people have come around to. Yeah. More
Speaker 3:  and more
Speaker 7:  All the time. Yeah, I think so. And there, it feels like
Speaker 7:  the big, you know, the apples the Googles and Samsung have are
Speaker 7:  very gently kind of prodding us. Like, Hey, here's a
Speaker 7:  focus mode, or maybe set up a bedtime routine if you want. You know,
Speaker 7:  don't worry, no worries if not. So I,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, maybe they will get a little more
Speaker 7:  robust, you know, as people ask for these things more. I hope so.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Agreed. I did, by the way, reach out to Kai Tang, who's one of the
Speaker 3:  co-founders of the light phone to ask about this specific question,
Speaker 3:  and he told me that the light phone is sold out of all of its inventory and
Speaker 3:  that the gap between
Speaker 3:  what they sell and how quickly they can build them means right now that the
Speaker 3:  wait time for a light phone three is two months. Oh, wow. And actually getting
Speaker 3:  worse, which is, he described a, a problem, but
Speaker 3:  a good problem to have. Yeah. So I think, again, I don't think the light
Speaker 3:  folks are producing phones in the quantities of, you know, the, the Apples
Speaker 3:  and Samsungs of the world, but this thing, they've been at this for like
Speaker 3:  a decade and I think that they, they have seen the, the, the sort of movement
Speaker 3:  towards it really build. And I think I'm starting
Speaker 3:  to talk to more and more startups who are building gadgets about this idea.
Speaker 3:  And, and there is, there's real energy in, in like, what else is there for
Speaker 3:  us to find out there? And I think everybody thinks, we just haven't figured
Speaker 3:  out the mainstream answer, which makes me worried that there isn't one.
Speaker 3:  But at least it's fun to see people continue to, to poke at this. And I think
Speaker 3:  for me personally, I stole a bunch of Casey's idiot, Casey was on the Vergecast
Speaker 3:  a while ago explaining some of this stuff, and I deleted a bunch of my apps.
Speaker 3:  I made my phone background black, and I offloaded
Speaker 3:  all of my fun apps onto a different device. I have this, I have
Speaker 3:  this last year's pixel fold, which I need to
Speaker 3:  return to Google at some point, but I keep around for testing reason.
Speaker 3:  I'm just lazy to ship. Thanks. Leave me alone. And this is now my fun phone.
Speaker 3:  This is where a TikTok is. This is where Instagram is. This is where all
Speaker 3:  the things that I want to just screw
Speaker 3:  around on a screen with Liv. And this phone is now mostly for
Speaker 3:  like talking to my family and attempting not to look at very often.
Speaker 3:  And that has been awesome. Love that. I, I love that. Obviously most people
Speaker 3:  should not buy two phones. That's insane. But if you have two phones lying
Speaker 3:  around, I highly recommend it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I, my job is to use my
Speaker 7:  phone as much as possible, so I'm, I'm pretty jealous right now.
Speaker 3:  That's the other way. Get a job that requires you to have tons of screen
Speaker 3:  time and then guilt is gone. Yeah. Problem solved.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I'm just, I am, I open up TikTok and I'm like, another day
Speaker 7:  at work. Another day in the, the content minds. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  This is what, this is what we do here. We do this for you people. Yes. Allison
Speaker 3:  looks at her phone all day for you only subscribes to the Verge, so she can
Speaker 3:  do it even more.
Speaker 7:  Please. My family is starving.
Speaker 3:  All right, Allison, thank you as always. I'll see you later. Thank
Speaker 7:  You. Alright,
Speaker 3:  That's it for the Verge cast. Thank you to V and Allison for playing
Speaker 3:  my silly game with me. Thank you to Travis for going through the true
Speaker 3:  rigors of vibe coding this insanity for us. And thank you as always
Speaker 3:  for watching and listening. If you have questions about any of it, if you
Speaker 3:  think we got the rankings wrong, if you too want to make a forceful argument
Speaker 3:  for the Pixel Watch, get at us.
Speaker 3:  vergecast@theverge.com. Is the email 8 6 6 version one one is the hotline.
Speaker 3:  If you, if you think the Pixel tablet should have been higher, if I'm being
Speaker 3:  honest, I don't really wanna hear it, send that to Allison, leave us out
Speaker 3:  of it. But anything else, I'm very curious what you think of the rankings
Speaker 3:  and even still who you would like to see us rank
Speaker 3:  next. This is a fun game. I had a good time. We're gonna do this again. What
Speaker 3:  company do you wanna see us rank next? Also, last housekeeping thing. Thank
Speaker 3:  you to everybody who has been watching and listening to and sending us feedback
Speaker 3:  on the version history episodes so far. We've done two, if you haven't caught
Speaker 3:  up, we did Hoverboards, we did BBM. Both have been very fun and very chaotic.
Speaker 3:  We have six more already lined up for you to do when we're already starting
Speaker 3:  to make the next batch of them too. But I wanna hear everything about what
Speaker 3:  you're thinking. What should we be making episodes about? What should the
Speaker 3:  version history questions be? I already have some ideas about how we're gonna
Speaker 3:  change those, but want to hear all of your feedback, all of your thoughts.
Speaker 3:  Again, vergecast@theverge.com. 8, 6, 6 version one, one. I'd love
Speaker 3:  to hear from you. Until then. The Vergecast is the Verge Production and part
Speaker 3:  of the Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon
Speaker 3:  Keefer, and Travis Uck. We will be back on Friday
Speaker 3:  with Neli Patel, presumably to talk about Brendan Carr. But
Speaker 3:  all of the other things going on this week because as ever, there is a lot
Speaker 3:  going on this week. The gadgets keep coming, the AI people keep spending
Speaker 3:  money and we'll be here until then. Rock Roll