# Transcript
ID: b9d9300b-a72e-4386-827f-b548429e2127
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2312140290969815838/-6244303874119430746/s93290-US-5968s-1757901438.mp3
Description: Fresh off a day filled with new Apple products, The Verge’s ground team reports back on everything they’ve seen — and touched. Allison Johnson walks us through the new iPhone Air, iPhone 17, and iPhone 17 Pro lineups, making sense of all the new camera features and wondering just how thin a phone really can be. After that, Victoria Song talks about why the AirPods Pro 3 may have been the big hit of the day, plus all the details on the three new models of Apple Watch. Finally, Jake Kastrenakes tells us about his first experience live at an Apple event, explains the appeal of a crossbody strap, and has a theory about why an orange phone is such a big deal.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Cross Body Straps. I'm
Speaker 1:  your friend David Pierce, and I'm back. I've been gone all summer. I have
Speaker 1:  a two month old baby who you will almost certainly hear at some point during
Speaker 1:  this episode. He's just right upstairs right now, and he has a lot of thoughts
Speaker 1:  about a lot of technology. I'm so, so happy to be back with all of you.
Speaker 1:  Thank you to Jen and v and Allison and Mia
Speaker 1:  and Jake and everybody who was on the show all summer, hanging out with you
Speaker 1:  guys and talking about tech. I had a lot of fun listening to the show. I
Speaker 1:  hope you did too. But I'm very glad to be back yelling all of my feelings
Speaker 1:  into a microphone because this is what I do and this is what I'm here for.
Speaker 1:  And today I have a lot of stuff to tell you about my summer and all of the
Speaker 1:  stuff that's been going on, but we're gonna get to that later. Today we're
Speaker 1:  talking about Apple as I'm recording this Apple's keynote just finished.
Speaker 1:  We got the new AirPods, we got some new watches, we got some new iPhones.
Speaker 1:  We got an iPhone air that I think is like kind of the secret to
Speaker 1:  the whole future of Apple as a company. We have a lot to talk about and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna talk about it with the folks who were actually on the ground. They
Speaker 1:  have some meetings to do. They have some hands ons to get. We're gonna let
Speaker 1:  them finish all of their stuff and then they're going to come on the show
Speaker 1:  and tell us about all of it. It's gonna be awesome. It's all coming up in
Speaker 1:  just a sec. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Allison Johnson is here in a hotel room somewhere
Speaker 1:  deep in Silicon Valley, I assume at this point. Yes. How you
Speaker 1:  holding up?
Speaker 3:  Great. I am coasting on fumes and little
Speaker 3:  appetizers that I ate for lunch, but that's, that's iPhone day baby.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, this is, this is what we do here. Yeah. You, you eat a bo you have
Speaker 1:  a bunch of coffee first thing in the morning, and then you don't eat anything
Speaker 1:  else for 11 hours. And that's, that's typically what the day is like. It's
Speaker 1:  good
Speaker 3:  To, and then I'm like, why do I have a headache? Yeah. You know why.
Speaker 3:  So
Speaker 1:  It's, it's a fun day and then you get to the end and you remember nothing
Speaker 1:  about any of it. And we all just move on with our lives.
Speaker 3:  It's true. So
Speaker 1:  This is why we do this podcast. This is to put in into the record that this
Speaker 1:  day actually happened for you. Yeah. And then you never have to think about
Speaker 1:  it ever again.
Speaker 3:  I appreciate that.
Speaker 1:  So obviously it was iPhone day,
Speaker 1:  I would say one of the less anticipated
Speaker 1:  iPhone days in a minute. It's possible. This is just 'cause I have been on
Speaker 1:  parental leave and not like paying attention to tech news for a while, but
Speaker 1:  I've been like loosely paying attention. And I feel like the summer there's
Speaker 1:  usually a, a big rumor mill and a lot of people thinking like big heady thoughts
Speaker 1:  about what does The iPhone mean and is this the end of The iPhone and what's
Speaker 1:  coming next? This didn't really feel like a super anticipated
Speaker 1:  iPhone season to me. Mm. Yeah. Did it feel like one to you?
Speaker 3:  I think there was, it's kind of shifted in a way to where we're,
Speaker 3:  our ears are kind of perking up for WWDC and the
Speaker 3:  sort of Apple intelligence and series stuff. 'cause that's just sort of a,
Speaker 3:  a story right now. I feel like the rumors kind of picked up
Speaker 3:  a little bit closer to the event. There were some
Speaker 3:  wild things flying around about like variable
Speaker 3:  zoom lenses and apertures that changed.
Speaker 3:  That stuff didn't happen. But it seems like we got
Speaker 3:  the, the kind of like
Speaker 3:  cosmetic stuff we were expecting. So if, if your
Speaker 3:  idea of a good time isn't, like The iPhone camera
Speaker 3:  bump goes sideways, then you probably weren't too
Speaker 3:  hyped for this one.
Speaker 1:  Fair. Yeah. Yeah. I think we, this was just, I guess this sort of year
Speaker 1:  where no one expected like real true fireworks, right? Like we,
Speaker 1:  we've been hearing a lot that there is kind of a three year plan
Speaker 1:  about foldable phones and flip phones and
Speaker 1:  this just seemed like maybe it was gonna be the, the, the year
Speaker 1:  before the year. And I think in, in a bunch of ways it was and is actually,
Speaker 1:  this is a, a good segue into the first phone I wanna talk about, which is,
Speaker 1:  it feels like we have to start with The iPhone Air, right? Which was, yeah,
Speaker 1:  it, it won't be the most successful phone that Apple launched today, but
Speaker 1:  it will certainly be the one most people talk about for the next week or
Speaker 1:  so, at the very least. So The iPhone Air, just to, just to run down the
Speaker 1:  specs very quickly, it is quite thin. I, I don't
Speaker 1:  know exactly how thin 5.6 millimeters is supposed to be,
Speaker 1:  but it's quite thin. They said the thinnest iPhone ever. It's, it's a thousand
Speaker 1:  dollars. It has 256 gigs of storage. They said it's very
Speaker 1:  durable. It has a bunch of new technology inside it.
Speaker 1:  Surprisingly good battery life, surprisingly, like solid
Speaker 1:  specs next to the rest of the, the, The iPhone
Speaker 1:  lineup. But the thing is, it's thin.
Speaker 1:  I I have, I have a cynical take about this And I have an optimistic take
Speaker 1:  about this, but mostly what I just wanna know is like, how does it feel to
Speaker 1:  hold this thing in your hand?
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be very irritating, but it feels re
Speaker 3:  you kind of have to pick it up to understand it. It does feel
Speaker 3:  really light. It is really thin. Like, you know, this going
Speaker 3:  in, I've used the Samsung Galaxy S 25 Edge had
Speaker 3:  the same experience of like, who cares? A thin phone. Like sure,
Speaker 3:  people want battery life. What's the big deal? And then you hold it and you
Speaker 3:  use it and you're like, oh, this, this really is kind of different.
Speaker 3:  Same experience picking up the, The iPhone Air.
Speaker 3:  It feels like, it's just, it's strange. We're so
Speaker 3:  attuned to how, like, how heavy a phone should be.
Speaker 3:  So you, you read the difference on a piece of paper and you're like, that's
Speaker 3:  not the, the weight especially, you're like, that's not much that much
Speaker 3:  lighter. You pick it up, you're like, oh my God, I feel like I'm gonna break
Speaker 3:  this thing. It's so tiny
Speaker 1:  In terms of what it feels like to pick it up, right? I think there's like,
Speaker 1:  there's like, whoa, this thing is thin and there's right next to
Speaker 1:  that feeling there is like, oh my God, am I gonna break this? And I think
Speaker 1:  that was one of the feelings I saw from a lot of people was like, is this
Speaker 1:  thing going to snap in my back pocket because it's so
Speaker 1:  thin? Is this thing going to just like fall apart if I
Speaker 1:  look at it wrong because it's so thin. And I was thinking a lot about the
Speaker 1:  M four iPad Pro that launched like last year in, in
Speaker 1:  2024, which is the closest thing I've had to, it
Speaker 1:  sounds like the experience you had today, which is I, I picked up the thing
Speaker 1:  and it was, it's this incredibly like impossibly thin iPad
Speaker 1:  and you know, we're we're reporters at a press event. I'm like trying to
Speaker 1:  play it cool. It's like, don't, don't be weird, don't clap in the event.
Speaker 1:  Like I picked it up in front of an Apple PR person and completely involuntarily
Speaker 1:  just went holy shit. Yeah. And I had this moment of being like, this thing
Speaker 1:  isn't supposed to feel like this. Yeah. And I don't know that it meaningfully
Speaker 1:  changed my experience of using it for the next year,
Speaker 1:  but I liked it more because of that and that counts for something.
Speaker 1:  And so it's like, is that the kind of experience you're talking about here
Speaker 1:  where it's like this isn't, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  maybe it is some incredible engineering marvel where you're like, I can't
Speaker 1:  even believe this is a smartphone anymore. Or maybe it's just like,
Speaker 1:  it feels cool and that counts for something.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think it's a little bit of both. It's like, maybe this exists
Speaker 3:  because Apple and Samsung are just like, well, we
Speaker 3:  ran out of things to do, so we're gonna make it thin. Now
Speaker 3:  maybe it exists because they're like, we need to sell more
Speaker 3:  phones. How about something that looks different and feels different?
Speaker 3:  I, for me it was little moments like using the
Speaker 3:  Galaxy Edge, especially where, especially
Speaker 3:  with a phone, you, you are taking it everywhere you go. I,
Speaker 3:  they have so many different pants. I put it in the pockets of and bags
Speaker 3:  and every time it kind of fits into a, a
Speaker 3:  bag that I'm used to shoving a bulky phone into, I was
Speaker 3:  like, oh, this is nice. It feel just like, just a little moment of,
Speaker 3:  oh, okay. You know? Yeah. I see the point of this.
Speaker 1:  Do you think it'll use differently? Like I, I I I, I think you're probably
Speaker 1:  right that it'll carry differently because it's thinner and lighter and
Speaker 1:  and smaller that way. But like, and you've only used it a little bit so
Speaker 1:  you can reserve judgment on this for now, but is your sense that like it'll,
Speaker 1:  it'll actually feel different to manipulate the thing because it's thinner
Speaker 1:  this way?
Speaker 3:  The thing I kind of wonder, especially
Speaker 3:  since like the pro iPhones have gotten so big
Speaker 3:  and heavy
Speaker 3:  and the thing that, that I get tired of is sitting
Speaker 3:  and reading kind of one handed
Speaker 3:  that might feel better over a length of time. You know, like
Speaker 3:  it's the kind of thing you, you notice if you're living with
Speaker 3:  a device and hard to say when you pick it up for, you know,
Speaker 3:  five minutes and there's 30 people behind you Right.
Speaker 3:  Wanting you to move out of the way.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it,
Speaker 1:  It's gonna save us from our pinky divots is what you're, is what you're saying,
Speaker 1:  like the thing where we all hold the phones like this? No, and you get the,
Speaker 1:  you get the hole in your
Speaker 3:  Like nothing can save us from the pinky divots.
Speaker 3:  It's here to stay. Yeah. No, but yeah, it could, it could
Speaker 3:  be meaningfully more comfortable to use,
Speaker 3:  but I think it, it might end up being a lot of, like, it
Speaker 3:  is just a little bit less of a pain in the butt to put into a bag and carry
Speaker 3:  around and, and looks kind of cool.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I, I will say I really do buy the theory that
Speaker 1:  it looks kind of cool means something, right? Like especially these things
Speaker 1:  are so like a commoditized in our life,
Speaker 1:  but also b like ever present things in our lives. And
Speaker 1:  I think making it nicer to look at and hold
Speaker 1:  for its own sake is actually fine. And I think with, with so much
Speaker 1:  technology, we've actually gotten away from that that everything is
Speaker 1:  just like slaby glass rectangles that are made for
Speaker 1:  ruthless efficiency and nothing else. So like, even if I don't buy it, which
Speaker 1:  I don't think I will, I, I appreciate the idea that there is one that
Speaker 1:  mostly exists just to be the nice one.
Speaker 1:  What is tough for me is it does feel like you are making one big
Speaker 1:  huge giant sacrifice, which is that there's only one damn camera
Speaker 1:  on the thing
Speaker 3:  That is the thing. Yeah. And it's, you can sort of
Speaker 3:  understand it on like a $600 phone. This
Speaker 3:  one is nine ninety nine, so, well this is
Speaker 1:  Like the folding phone problem where they're like, oh, well what if, what
Speaker 1:  if we had all this other cool stuff, but the most important feature kind
Speaker 1:  of sucked and it was more expensive. Do you want that? And people are like,
Speaker 1:  no.
Speaker 3:  Right. Yeah. I don't, it does feel like it goes in the opposite
Speaker 3:  direction and, and battery too. You know, same with the flip
Speaker 3:  phones. You know, they have smaller batteries and that's a
Speaker 3:  thing they've had to contend with year after year and they've caught up a
Speaker 3:  little bit, but it sort of feels like, yeah, why take a step
Speaker 3:  backwards potentially on battery life and camera
Speaker 3:  and still pay a thousand dollars for a phone? I think that
Speaker 3:  might be a non-starter for, for some people,
Speaker 3:  maybe some people really don't care that much about how
Speaker 3:  many cameras are on the back or how many of their photos
Speaker 3:  are
Speaker 3:  two x optical quality zoom
Speaker 3:  versus, you know, with the main standard
Speaker 3:  focal length. Yeah. There's, there are all kinds
Speaker 3:  of people in this world, I guess.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. This phone is a little bit like death by a thousand
Speaker 1:  cuts is too strong, but it is, there are just, it has a lot of little
Speaker 1:  dings against it in the service of being like really
Speaker 1:  beautiful and really thin. And again, that that's fine.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like they make other phones. I think if this was The iPhone
Speaker 1:  17, I think we'd have a big problem. Yeah. But the fact that this is
Speaker 1:  something different, I actually think is, is great. And I will be fascinated
Speaker 1:  to see how it does. And it's made me think a lot about like
Speaker 1:  the, the Tesla Roadster and even like the Vision Pro
Speaker 1:  and this thing that some companies do where they're like, we are just going
Speaker 1:  to make this thing because we can and it's going to be the
Speaker 1:  best it can be. And typically it's like wildly expensive.
Speaker 1:  I actually expected the air to be significantly more expensive than it is.
Speaker 1:  Like this thing would almost make more sense to me at like $1,500 than
Speaker 1:  it does at 9 99. But to say basically like we've built
Speaker 1:  some really interesting technology here, and this is, this is my optimistic
Speaker 1:  thesis about The iPhone error is that this thing is like a science project,
Speaker 1:  right? This is, this is tech that you have to develop if you're Apple in
Speaker 1:  order to do lots of things, right? A bunch of people have pointed out that
Speaker 1:  inside the camera bump on The iPhone error is essentially the
Speaker 1:  whole thing. So you, you've put a massive amount of compute
Speaker 1:  power and all this stuff into a very tiny sliver of the device,
Speaker 1:  which is the kind of thing that you have to continue to miniaturize if you
Speaker 1:  want to do all the other things that Apple presumably wants to do with
Speaker 1:  robots and glasses and wearables and everything else. Like you can sort of
Speaker 1:  pry this thing open and see where it wants to go with lots of different devices.
Speaker 1:  This is what you have to do to make a flip phone that really works. This
Speaker 1:  is what you have to do to make a foldable phone that really works a lot of
Speaker 1:  the work it did on the, the titanium frame and making this thing
Speaker 1:  durable and this is the stuff you have to do to do all of that stuff. So
Speaker 1:  it's like, if this is basically all the tech they had to build
Speaker 1:  anyway, that they just put into a nice looking phone that they'll, they'll
Speaker 1:  sell you in the meantime. That's cool. My
Speaker 1:  cynical take is basically what you already just said, which is that they've
Speaker 1:  completely run out of ideas and they're like, well we can make it kind of
Speaker 1:  thinner. Is that anything? And I, I would say I'm
Speaker 1:  in the, I'm fully in the 50 50 camp where I think it is, it is very
Speaker 1:  much both of those things simultaneously.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah, I think so too. And I, I think Apple's had a tough time
Speaker 3:  figuring out that kind of second
Speaker 3:  standard iPhone there. We had the mini, you know, rested soul
Speaker 3:  and then we had the plus models and it didn't sound like
Speaker 3:  those sold as well as Apple wanted them to.
Speaker 3:  So they're like, well what do we have to lose? And I think, I
Speaker 3:  think there really is something too, if you're developing a
Speaker 3:  thin phone for a folding phone, like
Speaker 3:  why not put it out there now? And this is
Speaker 3:  yeah. Kind of a good testing ground.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't hate it. Like I, I really hope we, we look at all of these
Speaker 1:  phones in like twenty, twenty seven, twenty twenty eight and you can, you
Speaker 1:  can point right back to The iPhone Air and see where all that stuff started.
Speaker 1:  Like, I, I hope that is where all of this lands. Let's talk about the phones
Speaker 1:  people are actually gonna buy because I, I think I, I'm like sincerely looking
Speaker 1:  forward to seeing how many people buy the air because I suspect a lot of
Speaker 1:  people are going to go to an Apple store and look at it and leave with a
Speaker 1:  different phone. That is 100% my plan and I'm very
Speaker 1:  excited about it. But let's start with The iPhone 17, which I actually think
Speaker 1:  this is an interesting play for Apple here to try and figure out
Speaker 1:  its normal phone. So last year I bought a 16, yeah. After
Speaker 1:  years of buying pros, I bought a regular 16 because I wanted, I
Speaker 1:  wanted it to be blue And I love this blue phone to death,
Speaker 1:  even though everything about it is worse than the pro
Speaker 1:  and, and it, it felt like a huge sacrifice to get a blue phone. And it was,
Speaker 1:  and this is the life that I have chosen for myself. The 17
Speaker 1:  feels closer to having the right
Speaker 1:  set of features for almost everybody than it has in a long time.
Speaker 1:  So lemme lemme just run down a bunch of them for you because
Speaker 1:  God only knows what numbers you are able to remember at this time of day.
Speaker 1:  So it's, it's just The iPhone 17, like you mentioned. No, plus our,
Speaker 1:  our whole theory about big cheap screens was evidently just dead wrong.
Speaker 1:  The iPhone plus is, is at least for now, no longer starts at
Speaker 1:  $799, starts with 256 kids of storage as an
Speaker 1:  a 19 chip. It has a 6.3 inch display, which is an
Speaker 1:  incorrect decision because you And I both agree that 6.1 inches is the correct
Speaker 1:  size for a smartphone screen. And Apple blew it on that one.
Speaker 1:  It has a promotion screen, which it seemed like they gendered a lot of
Speaker 1:  enthusiasm in the Steve Jobs theater today.
Speaker 3:  Actual cheering, there was real cheering. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's got the always on display stuff. It has better scratch resistance. It
Speaker 1:  has substantially longer battery life, which I think is really interesting.
Speaker 1:  Upgraded cameras,
Speaker 1:  slightly faster. Wireless charging, it's a little heavier, it has more
Speaker 1:  Bluetooth. It's just like, you know, bits and bobs have changed around the
Speaker 1:  edges, but like fundamentally the thing is like a, a better,
Speaker 1:  faster, more durable, longer lasting iPhone, which feels
Speaker 1:  like roughly the list of things I would've actually asked Apple to do.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Which is great.
Speaker 3:  I know it's, it feels like a good year. And I said this last year for the
Speaker 3:  16, which was catching up a little bit and
Speaker 3:  it felt like a good year. I think it really is a good year for the, for the
Speaker 3:  regular iPhone 17 getting the promotion
Speaker 3:  display. Like thank God our national nightmare is over.
Speaker 3:  There's, I think our, our colleague Dominic Preston pointed
Speaker 3:  out in some of our coverage that you can get a
Speaker 3:  120 heart display on like a $200
Speaker 3:  Android phone. Yeah. You know, it was time. So it's here.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 1:  I will say just a real quick PSA to anyone who is wondering what is a promotion
Speaker 1:  display, what is the difference? Don't find out if you don't
Speaker 1:  know the difference. Yeah. Don't ever find out
Speaker 1:  like you're gonna be like, oh, let me hold the phone that I have next to
Speaker 1:  a promotion display. Don't do that. No, because once you see the
Speaker 1:  difference, it ruins it for you. But if you don't see the difference, like
Speaker 1:  God bless your life is going to be better for not knowing the difference
Speaker 1:  between a 60 hertz and 120 hertz display. Yeah. But once you see it, you
Speaker 1:  can never unsee it. And I now see it every time I turn
Speaker 1:  on my iPhone 16
Speaker 3:  And yeah. Oh
Speaker 1:  True. I came on this podcast a year ago and said, I don't care. And boy was
Speaker 1:  I wrong.
Speaker 3:  No, you care. A year later. Oh, that was the great experiment. It's, it is
Speaker 3:  like a curse in a horror movie where once you are
Speaker 3:  burdened with the knowledge, it it just follows you. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So thank God promotion display is here. I
Speaker 3:  know you are not partial to the always on display. I love an
Speaker 3:  always on display. Every time I switch from an iPhone
Speaker 3:  that has an always on display to the one that doesn't, I've,
Speaker 3:  I keep thinking it shut itself off. I, I'm like, why is this
Speaker 3:  phone dead? Interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Wait, so I have the exact opposite experience. This is so funny. So I think
Speaker 1:  I'm not against an always on display. I think the way the Pixel doesn't always
Speaker 1:  on display right. Is exactly correct. Like show me the time
Speaker 1:  and like the, the barest bit of information from a notification that is,
Speaker 1:  that is what I want from an always on display. My problem with the iPhone's
Speaker 1:  version of the Always on display has been that I turn my screen off and it
Speaker 1:  still feels like it's on.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And, and try as I might, I have never been able to get used to the thing
Speaker 1:  where my screen, like granted it's called an always on
Speaker 1:  display, but it just feels like it's on And I find myself instinctively
Speaker 1:  going to turn the screen off over and over and over and over and over throughout
Speaker 1:  the day. Oh yeah. And I, I always end up turning it off before I get
Speaker 1:  used to the feature. Okay. But I will say I, I have come
Speaker 1:  to believe that I'm in the minority of that And I think most people
Speaker 1:  like the thing where they can look over and sort of get a
Speaker 1:  rough sense of their phone without picking up their phone. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 1:  that's probably a good thing for the world too. And so like yeah,
Speaker 1:  this feels like a good feature to have everywhere.
Speaker 3:  I think so. Yeah. And the wallpaper, if you're not used to
Speaker 3:  the, the dimmed wallpaper and it sort of depends on what you
Speaker 3:  have on some, some wallpapers you're like, yeah, this is not
Speaker 3:  off enough of an always on display.
Speaker 3:  So super glad that's here. I am always, I don't
Speaker 3:  know if I just get my hopes up when companies say that
Speaker 3:  their screens are more scratch resistant
Speaker 3:  every single year. I'm like, this is my year. I always get scratches
Speaker 3:  on the screen. I'm just a reckless, I put my
Speaker 3:  car keys next to the phone in a fanny pack and they're just
Speaker 3:  touching each other, but they're making, you know, big claims
Speaker 3:  about how scratch resistant the Tomic Shield is.
Speaker 3:  So yeah. Good things coming to the basic
Speaker 3:  iPhone. I'm gonna shout out the SAGE on the regular iPhone
Speaker 3:  looks great. Oh, And I really like it.
Speaker 1:  Is that the one they call natural, which is
Speaker 3:  Just the stupidest No, they call,
Speaker 1:  They call it s it was an actual sage,
Speaker 3:  Which I'm pretty sure they're, we've had a sage pixel, so
Speaker 3:  love
Speaker 1:  This. They're just come around, I come around. I do appreciate the push towards
Speaker 1:  the like slightly earthy colors. I, I have actually, I have come to enjoy
Speaker 1:  that very much. It's coming. Does the base iPhone 17
Speaker 1:  have the awesome new front camera?
Speaker 3:  Yes. They all, okay. Can we talk about
Speaker 1:  This for a second? This seems super cool. Can you explain like what this
Speaker 1:  new selfie camera is up to?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so it's a new 18 megapixel sensor
Speaker 3:  and it is a square format sensor.
Speaker 3:  So rather than having to turn the whole phone
Speaker 3:  to do switch between like portrait and landscape mode, it can
Speaker 3:  do it in sensor and it doesn't lose a bunch of
Speaker 3:  resolution in the process. So you can do this,
Speaker 3:  you know, you frame up a selfie and you can tap a couple of icons
Speaker 3:  on the screen to expand or rotate the picture.
Speaker 3:  Or you can have it, you know, its center stage where
Speaker 3:  it will kind of follow you around the frame automatically or it'll do the
Speaker 3:  rotating by itself. So if someone joins,
Speaker 3:  joins you in the photo, it'll just go boop and you'll both be in it.
Speaker 1:  This might sound like slight hyperbole, but I honestly think
Speaker 1:  the ability to take landscape selfies while holding your phone in
Speaker 1:  portrait is like the most exciting iPhone
Speaker 1:  upgrade in years.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It might change
Speaker 1:  Truly because it's, it's, it's the sort of thing,
Speaker 3:  Everything
Speaker 1:  All the time landscape selfies always look worse because the cameras suddenly
Speaker 1:  off to the side and half the people in the selfie are looking to this side
Speaker 1:  of the camera and half the people are looking to this side of the camera.
Speaker 1:  Nobody is correctly looking at the camera. Yeah. Everything just looks
Speaker 1:  wrong. You're not able to get as far away and hold it as naturally. So like
Speaker 1:  this thing where you can hold your phone the way your phone is meant to be
Speaker 1:  held and take whatever kind of photo you want, I think is
Speaker 1:  like amazing. Yes. I think center stage is like kind of a
Speaker 1:  wacky feature. It, it makes more sense to me on, on iPhone frankly, than
Speaker 1:  most because people tend to be sort of all over the place as they're
Speaker 1:  holding their iPhone. Like sometimes I FaceTime with my nephew and he's just
Speaker 1:  literally like holding it at his side and so I'm just looking sort of up
Speaker 1:  the side of his face. Yeah. And so the idea of like trying to solve some
Speaker 1:  of these problems makes a lot of sense. But truly just the square sensor
Speaker 1:  alone I think is just genius.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I am here for it. I, whenever I'm changing
Speaker 3:  between, you know, selfie camera orientations, I feel like I
Speaker 3:  always have something else in my hand. I have to put something down and I'm
Speaker 3:  like holding, like totally adjusting the, the way I am holding
Speaker 3:  the phone. So yeah, I think there was a lot of kind like oohs and
Speaker 3:  ah, from the crowd when they talked about this one. So
Speaker 1:  I'll say it means I will never ever use the camera control as a shutter button
Speaker 1:  ever again. True. The only time I ever use it is for landscape photos. Oh,
Speaker 1:  that's, and there is absolutely no reason I will ever touch it again.
Speaker 3:  Oh, RIP camera control
Speaker 1:  Right now. It's just only going to be by accident instead of mostly
Speaker 1:  by accident.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So let's, let's talk about the, the Pro and Pro Max, both of which still
Speaker 1:  exist. Only the plus got got the ax this time.
Speaker 1:  The, the story here I think is kind of the same usually as the Pro and
Speaker 1:  Pro Max Better camera
Speaker 1:  niftier, you know, hardware features. They talked a lot
Speaker 1:  about a vapor chamber and vapor cooled performance. None of
Speaker 1:  which means anything to a real person who just wants to use their phone,
Speaker 1:  but I'm sure is like neat and cool. The thing that is the most
Speaker 1:  interesting I think about the design is they have extended the camera bump
Speaker 1:  all the way across the back again. You've, you've seen it. This is new for
Speaker 1:  an iPhone. How does it look?
Speaker 3:  It looks All right. I was sort of unsure with, you
Speaker 3:  know, there, the rumors about this redesign have been coming
Speaker 3:  in for a while and it's hard to tell,
Speaker 3:  you know, from pictures, they, apple really did make a lot of
Speaker 3:  the,
Speaker 3:  they started from scratch. You know, when they in the presentation
Speaker 3:  you just see like a big chunk of aluminum. You're like, oh
Speaker 3:  yeah, we're gonna mill the shit outta that aluminum.
Speaker 1:  I bet this is gonna be smaller later. It was
Speaker 3:  Gonna be sick. Yeah. They made a phone out of it. But there is kind of a,
Speaker 3:  a, a cohesive element to the body and the, the
Speaker 3:  camera bump, they are calling it a camera plateau. I refuse to
Speaker 3:  acknowledge this. I will not look directly at it. And I'm gonna call a camera
Speaker 3:  bump. That's what it's,
Speaker 1:  It is a, it is a, it is a bump for a camera. That's
Speaker 3:  Exactly, don't, yes. Don't make it like geography. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It doesn't have to be a thing. It's fine. No. Although I said this about
Speaker 1:  the dynamic island for like a year and a half and now I just un ironically
Speaker 1:  say the dynamic island and every time I do, I know I hate myself a little
Speaker 1:  more. So I assume, yeah, this will happen with a plateau as well.
Speaker 3:  Probably. This
Speaker 1:  Is one of those things that I, I know a bunch of people were like having,
Speaker 1:  you know, thoughts about as an Apple design thing. And it is to
Speaker 1:  be clear, the last company to decide to do this.
Speaker 1:  Everybody else has been doing the full width camera bump for a while now.
Speaker 1:  I'm fine with it. I think I, I've been using the, the Pixel 10 Pro a bunch
Speaker 1:  for the last few days and a, it makes
Speaker 1:  cases make more sense. Like the, this just looks nicer to have a
Speaker 1:  case with the thing all the way across. And then also
Speaker 1:  it sits caseless better. Like, it, it is at that little tiny bit of
Speaker 1:  an angle instead of being the teeny tiny bit of wobbly that The iPhone has
Speaker 1:  always been. And it, it just, it, it just seems fine
Speaker 1:  to me. Like yeah, I am completely unbothered by this decision that Apple
Speaker 1:  made. And I think if anything it actually looks visually
Speaker 1:  less asymmetrical in a way that I really like.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. I'm into it. I think the, the thing that
Speaker 3:  I, in person, I was caught off guard more by,
Speaker 3:  so the, the body of the phone itself is aluminum. They went back to
Speaker 3:  the aluminum Yep. The chunk of aluminum. No titanium.
Speaker 3:  They kind of walked away from that. The air is titanium, but
Speaker 3:  so pros aluminum, but a big chunk of the back panel
Speaker 3:  is that ceramic shield,
Speaker 1:  Like the same stuff on the front.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's, so it's not glass and it's
Speaker 3:  colored like the phone, but it's sort of, they're
Speaker 3:  different materials. So they have kind of a different
Speaker 3:  interesting look to them. It almost looks like a, it's
Speaker 3:  like a two-tone thing where you're like, this is an orange
Speaker 3:  phone with a cool little orange thing in the middle of it.
Speaker 3:  The idea is that it won't crack and splinter into
Speaker 3:  a million pieces when your 4-year-old, which is good,
Speaker 3:  drops it on some concrete. I'm not pointing any fingers,
Speaker 3:  but I did walk around Apple Park with this phone in a
Speaker 3:  phone case because my review unit of 16 pro
Speaker 3:  is shattered. Oh no. Yeah. Not a great look.
Speaker 3:  It's tough. Yeah, it's tough out there for a phone.
Speaker 1:  I've only ever destroyed one review unit and it was, it was, it was an
Speaker 1:  iPhone that I was, I I will, this is like seared
Speaker 1:  into my brain. I was in the Safeway grocery store
Speaker 1:  And I took my phone out to look at my grocery list. Went, okay, cool,
Speaker 1:  I'm ready to go. I have everything I need. Went to put it in my pocket, missed
Speaker 1:  my pocket, and literally just threw the phone onto the ground and it
Speaker 1:  like, it essentially exploded into a thousand pieces in
Speaker 1:  on the floor of the Safeway. And so I took a picture And I sent it to the
Speaker 1:  Apple comms people And I was like, I don't know what you want me to do with
Speaker 1:  this. Right? But I'm happy to mail all of these pieces of
Speaker 3:  Glass to you. Oh God. Did, did they have to get the broom out where they
Speaker 3:  like clean up
Speaker 1:  Produce? No, but I did produce ask somebody for a paper towel so that I could,
Speaker 1:  I could bring
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 1:  Pieces together. It was tough. But anyway, just know that you're not alone
Speaker 1:  and this, this happens. Thank you. This this happens to all of us. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  yeah. But I agree in all of these cases, I think a, an actually
Speaker 1:  interesting through line of a lot of apple's announcements today was
Speaker 1:  things that are more durable. And I think that's great. Like that is, that
Speaker 1:  is a company that realizes that people keeps these things longer and
Speaker 1:  is okay with that and wants to make that work for them. And I think that
Speaker 1:  rules, like I'm, I'm very happy about this. Yeah. Can we talk about the pro
Speaker 1:  cameras for just a minute? Because good thing about the pro cameras,
Speaker 1:  there's three of them. They're all 48 megapixels. Now, bad thing about
Speaker 1:  the cameras, apple has used that fact to do a bunch of insane math about
Speaker 1:  cameras. That doesn't make any sense to me. And you're a person who understands
Speaker 1:  cameras better than I do. So what I don't understand is how are there three
Speaker 1:  cameras but also eight cameras and it all feels like lies.
Speaker 1:  Can you explain what's going on here to me?
Speaker 3:  I know. So yeah, how did we get here?
Speaker 3:  It started with, you know, the, the
Speaker 3:  48 megapixel sensor has enough resolution
Speaker 3:  that you can crop and use the middle of it and
Speaker 3:  not have to upscale it to zoom in. So you can get a
Speaker 3:  two times optical quality zoom
Speaker 3:  air quotes, this is Apple's term for it,
Speaker 1:  Which is not the same thing as optical zoom, as you have said before on this
Speaker 1:  podcast. It's just cropping. It is
Speaker 3:  Cropping.
Speaker 1:  It's just cropping. It can be good cropping, but it's still just cropping.
Speaker 3:  Good cropping. They will of course say they do, they have
Speaker 3:  a special pipeline for it and it's really wonderful and beautiful.
Speaker 3:  So it's been doing that in the one x camera and
Speaker 3:  you can get these other kind of like 35
Speaker 3:  millimeter equivalent focal links with sort of similar stuff going on.
Speaker 3:  They've been doing that. There's the wide angle camera of course.
Speaker 3:  And then upgrading the telephoto camera to 48
Speaker 3:  megapixels this year.
Speaker 3:  And out at the same time, downgrading the zoom from five
Speaker 3:  x to four x or the, the, oh yeah. Focal length. It's not
Speaker 3:  zooming, they just copy and pasted the same
Speaker 3:  concept over the telephoto where they're like, we can crop
Speaker 3:  in the middle and give you an eight times
Speaker 3:  optical quality zoom. We didn't do any digital
Speaker 3:  zoom upscaling. You won't see any
Speaker 3:  gross artifacts from that kind of thing. Although you can do
Speaker 3:  digital zoom to 40 times and it's not good.
Speaker 1:  And then it'll do weird AI shenanigans. Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  Oh boy. Yeah. It's a can of worms. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I mean on the one hand it's,
Speaker 1:  it's all marketing lies and we should say so. But on the other hand,
Speaker 1:  I I I think a lot about like the, just the regular people I see using their
Speaker 1:  phone and, and it is such a common behavior still
Speaker 1:  to pinch and zoom on your phone to 3.6 x
Speaker 1:  and then take the picture. Right. And it's like my heart dies
Speaker 1:  a little bit every time I see somebody do that because it's, I'm like, oh,
Speaker 1:  you've just made your picture worse when you could have just done that later.
Speaker 1:  But actually you, they don't understand that and nor should they have to.
Speaker 1:  And in some ways Apple is making that process cleaner,
Speaker 1:  right? Yeah. Like it's, it's saying we're gonna give you options that are
Speaker 1:  optimized and are going to make more sense so that you can do these things
Speaker 1:  that are destructive and they're going to make your image worse,
Speaker 1:  but in a, in a way that we are going to take slightly better care of you
Speaker 1:  for. And I think that's something I don't, yeah, I dunno how much that is,
Speaker 1:  but it feels like something
Speaker 3:  And, and it gives you the little buttons at the bottom of the screen that
Speaker 3:  makes it simple. It's like one x two x, you know,
Speaker 3:  four x we, we understand that I can push a button that says two x
Speaker 3:  rather than Yeah. Pinch and zoom to something between two and three
Speaker 3:  that's gonna look kind of crappy for no good reason. It just, it hurts
Speaker 3:  every time. I know I'd, I sit there and cringe when
Speaker 3:  they're like eight lenses in your pocket.
Speaker 3:  But the, the reality is like, it's,
Speaker 3:  it's better than just a a, a free for all of digital zoom,
Speaker 3:  I think. Sure.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And if you, if they would just call it like camera simulators, it would
Speaker 1:  be fine. Yeah. Right. Because that's essentially what it is, right? It's
Speaker 1:  it's, you're you're doing presets and those presets are designed
Speaker 1:  to simulate the experience of certain kinds of camera that I think is great.
Speaker 1:  I have no problem with that. Lots of camera apps do that and do it well and
Speaker 1:  are like, oh, we're gonna do x, y, Z filter to make it look like a film camera.
Speaker 1:  I have no problem with that. Just don't say your three lenses are eight lenses
Speaker 1:  because they're not like that's it, that's that's my only, that's my only
Speaker 1:  gripe. I can look at the phone and see how many lenses there are. Yeah. We
Speaker 1:  don't need to do any more work than that
Speaker 3:  As someone who carried around a big heavy actual
Speaker 3:  zoom lens with a lot of actual focal lengths.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I take issue with that. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That said, I do think there's a strong chance this camera is going to be
Speaker 1:  very good. It, it has a bunch of new, you know, it does, it does ProRes raw,
Speaker 1:  it does log two, it does genlock. It's got the simultaneous front and back
Speaker 1:  recording, which I think is very cool.
Speaker 1:  Like this continues to be a camera phone in a very real way for
Speaker 1:  Apple. And I think that makes a lot of sense. What
Speaker 1:  I wonder particularly about with the Pro and Pro Max
Speaker 1:  this year is
Speaker 1:  how sort of far that still goes, right? Like
Speaker 1:  it's, it's, it is better. There's no question it is better, but the biggest
Speaker 1:  problem that I think people have had with
Speaker 1:  Apple cameras, especially for the last one or
Speaker 1:  two revs of The iPhone, is like apple's ideas about what makes good
Speaker 1:  photos. And I think it, it's so much about the imaging pipeline that Apple
Speaker 1:  has decided and this thing where they're like, we are going to crush all
Speaker 1:  of the dynamic range and make sure there's no shadows and make sure every
Speaker 1:  photo is usable. That like this idea that people have, that their phone
Speaker 1:  photos are getting worse is not about the hardware, it's about apple's ideas
Speaker 1:  about what your photos are supposed to look like. And even just looking at
Speaker 1:  the sample photos and stuff here, it's like, are maybe we're just pointing
Speaker 1:  even better hardware at that exact same problem And I just don't know.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I have a lot of conflicting feelings about it because
Speaker 3:  yeah, we've all seen the, the over HDR look, the
Speaker 3:  crunchiness. I talked to Mark LaVoy a couple
Speaker 3:  weeks ago kind of about that problem
Speaker 3:  with, with phone cameras in general. And he
Speaker 3:  pointed out, you know, that their job is to make
Speaker 3:  the photo readable on screens of different sizes in
Speaker 3:  different lighting conditions. And you know, I think, I think we know
Speaker 3:  that. I'm like, yeah, that's why everything in the foreground
Speaker 3:  looks brightened and because Apple can't be in
Speaker 3:  trouble when your relative was like in
Speaker 3:  the shadows in this photo, does it make
Speaker 3:  for a camera that people actively like
Speaker 3:  is another thing. The Apple is still, they've got
Speaker 3:  the, the photographic styles and they've sort of gone here,
Speaker 3:  it's your problem now where you, you dial in kind
Speaker 3:  of how you like skin tones. You do like contrast you like,
Speaker 3:  you know, and actual HDR in your
Speaker 3:  photos And I don't think they've solved anything.
Speaker 3:  It's there if you know how to go change those things and what
Speaker 3:  they mean.
Speaker 1:  And there's a subset of users that will do that, right? Like you can buy
Speaker 1:  the Pro Max all the way up to, I think it's two grand with a, with two
Speaker 1:  terabytes of storage. The people who are gonna buy that phone are the people
Speaker 1:  who are going to go in and, and dial this stuff in in a
Speaker 1:  way that works. And I think I've long been a proponent that Apple should
Speaker 1:  give people more control of their devices. And so like, yay, that's great.
Speaker 1:  I'm into that. I really, really wonder in these particular cases,
Speaker 1:  if, if Apple is going to give people more
Speaker 1:  sort of front and center ways to make things look just better.
Speaker 1:  Right? Because I think like your point and Mark's about like
Speaker 1:  it is there to prevent you from taking bad photos is a good and
Speaker 1:  honorable goal, But that's not the same thing as taking good photos. And
Speaker 1:  I think these phones are designed and they cost like
Speaker 1:  they are for people who wanna take good photos and video. And I don't know,
Speaker 1:  like as, as you review these things, whenever you get to, I'm, I'm very
Speaker 1:  curious how you feel about the actual stuff that's coming
Speaker 1:  out of the camera. Yeah. 'cause that's ultimately, like, they're better cameras
Speaker 1:  than ever, but
Speaker 1:  Apple still has to make a lot of decisions about them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. Having feelings about phone cameras is,
Speaker 3:  is my jam. So this is what we do here. Yeah. I, yeah.
Speaker 1:  All right. Well, I, I should let you go here, but do you, do you have a bet
Speaker 1:  on, there's four models here. Do you think there's one that is
Speaker 1:  gonna be the like sneaky runaway success hit of the
Speaker 1:  line coming out?
Speaker 3:  I think there's gonna be a lot of orange iPhone 17
Speaker 3:  pros on the street. I think it's, I think I so too, yeah, it's a real
Speaker 3:  vibrant color. It's, it looks nice. I think it's, it's gonna
Speaker 3:  be a hit
Speaker 1:  And it screams I have the new one in a way that's very hard to do with an
Speaker 1:  iPhone
Speaker 3:  These days. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I like it. That's a good take. All right. We need to take a break,
Speaker 1:  Allison, you I'm sure have more stuff to do. Do so. Thank you for coming
Speaker 1:  in, doing this with us. Thank you. All right, we'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. V song is here. Hi, ve.
Speaker 5:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  How are you feeling? Let's just talk about like your mental state for a minute
Speaker 1:  here.
Speaker 5:  It's ah, that's my mental state. That's, that's
Speaker 5:  that's how it's, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1:  How so thi this is the first iPhone event I have not been at in a while.
Speaker 1:  How does this compare? You, you've been doing this for a while. What, what
Speaker 1:  were your vibes compared to recent ones?
Speaker 5:  It's a little weird to, to be honest, in, in some, in some
Speaker 5:  sense it's like, oh, business as usual. And in another sense,
Speaker 5:  I just felt like there was some tension in the air just of like,
Speaker 5:  what is on deck? What's happening? And like, I think we all had
Speaker 5:  a sense that the air was coming. We knew that watches were coming. I think
Speaker 5:  everyone was pretty clear that AirPods were coming. But like, when you walk
Speaker 5:  out of it, usually there's like one or two things that you're like, oh, this
Speaker 5:  is the, the stuff. And it's now it's like skinny phone and
Speaker 5:  orange, which I must say I'm an orange hater. I like,
Speaker 5:  I orange is on my shit list. And I looked at that orange phone And I went,
Speaker 5:  oh, that's a good orange. I'm tempted. Do I want an orange
Speaker 5:  phone? Am I gonna have an orange existential crisis? I mean, I have an existential
Speaker 5:  crisis every week, but this is my existential crisis. Do I want an orange
Speaker 5:  phone? I don't know. I don't know. I kind of want an orange phone.
Speaker 1:  I do feel like the internet has spent the entirety of today,
Speaker 1:  by and large coming around to the orange phone. I feel like the, the, we
Speaker 1:  first saw the orange phone and everybody went like, absolutely not. No, thank
Speaker 1:  you. And I, and, and one by one, everyone I saw in Blue Sky
Speaker 1:  was like, maybe I like the orange phone.
Speaker 5:  I will say like the leaks that came out, especially, I think I saw one earlier
Speaker 5:  today And I was like, is that orange or is that dooo brown? Like a dooo brown
Speaker 5:  orange? Because if it's a dooo brown orange, we are gonna have to
Speaker 5:  do do that over. But it is, I will say it's not a
Speaker 5:  sherbet orange. Like Charles Charles Palmore asked me this. He went,
Speaker 5:  is it spice or is it sherbets? It is spice. Oh, that's good. Spices. Okay.
Speaker 5:  It's like a pumpkin spice, autumn vibes, but
Speaker 5:  bright. And it's, it's just like a quintessential deep orange.
Speaker 5:  And like I said, I am an orange hater. I'm, I'm Miss Purple.
Speaker 5:  I'm the verges foremost expert on good shades of purple.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, do I want an orange
Speaker 5:  phone? Do do I want an orange? I this, that's something I'm gonna be asking
Speaker 5:  myself for the next few days.
Speaker 1:  It is the most important question facing us in America right now. Yeah, I
Speaker 1:  would say. Yeah. Yeah. But I wanna talk to you about AirPods And I wanna
Speaker 1:  talk to you about watches. And there we have four products to cover And I
Speaker 1:  have them in the order in which I find them interesting. Which is maybe
Speaker 1:  not the order that is going to make sense, but this is just the order we're
Speaker 1:  gonna do it, which I think means we need to start with the AirPods first.
Speaker 1:  Because I think to me, the AirPods Pro three were like the single
Speaker 1:  most straightforward, slam dunk, great new product
Speaker 1:  at this event. It's, they, they just, I agree with you. They just are good.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's just chef's kiss, like, you know,
Speaker 5:  optimizer issue one, which I'm just gonna plug here, subscribe.
Speaker 5:  But in, in that, I basically was like, I think Apple just needs to give the
Speaker 5:  people what they want in general. And I was speaking
Speaker 5:  specifically to the watches, but I think the
Speaker 5:  AirPods three is just what people want. It's, it's just, you
Speaker 5:  know, genuinely good. I've spent some time with the product. I got to
Speaker 5:  test out the A NCI gotta tell you, I was very impressed by
Speaker 5:  the A NC. Like I am wearing the AirPods two, so I'm not
Speaker 5:  wearing the three right now. Gross. But yesterday's news.
Speaker 5:  But I gotta say I was in the, that little room
Speaker 5:  where you have the hands on, you know, David, it, it echoes.
Speaker 5:  The music is playing, people are talking, it's
Speaker 5:  loud, you know, they were doing demos on that floor. I
Speaker 5:  put them in my, I put them in my ear holes and
Speaker 5:  everything's quiet And I can just hear the dulcet sounds of the F1
Speaker 5:  soundtrack, because that is the playlist that, that had us listen to. Sure,
Speaker 5:  of course.
Speaker 1:  Wait, but that's pretty impressive. 'cause I would actually, I would compare
Speaker 1:  an Apple hands-on room to like a pretty
Speaker 1:  busy train station. Yes. Right. It's like there's, there's a lot of
Speaker 1:  sort of hustle and bustle. There's no like specific loud noise, which
Speaker 1:  is actually in many cases easier to cancel. Yes. It's like the reason they're
Speaker 1:  good on planes is because it's just one noise the whole time. But this is
Speaker 1:  just kind of stuff happening. So to be able to do that
Speaker 1:  on a pair of a very small headphones and b
Speaker 1:  like in an environment like that is really impressive. And I think the pros
Speaker 1:  have been impressive for a while at that in part just because they have that
Speaker 1:  seal in your ears. Yeah. But like the, the a NC
Speaker 1:  here, they said like the world's best a NC over and over to the point where
Speaker 1:  it's like, I kind of think you're lying, right? But maybe there's something
Speaker 1:  to this.
Speaker 5:  I think there's something to it, especially in this particular form factor.
Speaker 5:  Like of course I think it's gonna be really hard to be over your
Speaker 5:  cans. And obviously I have some at home, I'm gonna see how they compare to
Speaker 5:  my Sony alphabet soup XM four. Sure. I just know the last three.
Speaker 5:  But I will would say that I did notice a different, 'cause I
Speaker 5:  use these AirPod pro twos quite frequently, And I did notice
Speaker 5:  a difference. And I think it really has to do with the, the fact that they've
Speaker 5:  improved the fit, which my conspiracy theory is, yeah. You know,
Speaker 5:  partly they talked a lot about design at this event, and you always know
Speaker 5:  that it's gonna be kind of like a hmm, interesting event when design is like
Speaker 5:  the thesis that they're, they're coming to it with it, but you know, they're
Speaker 5:  like, oh, it fits in your ear more ergonomically. And when you do hold the
Speaker 5:  three versus the two in your hand, you can see that there have been like,
Speaker 5:  changes to the shape. But my, my pet theory
Speaker 5:  is that when you add heart rate sensors to an
Speaker 5:  earbud, you need to nail the fit.
Speaker 5:  If the fit doesn't, if the fit isn't absolutely perfect,
Speaker 5:  that particular sensor is useless to you. So I think it's
Speaker 5:  like a confluence of things. You want to have the best A and C, but also
Speaker 5:  having a really secure fit in order to get heart
Speaker 5:  rate. That's just gonna make the seal better regardless. And then on top
Speaker 5:  of that, there's five sizes of tips. Now mine were
Speaker 5:  medium, so it was just fine straight out of the case. But you know,
Speaker 5:  I was, I was quite impressed.
Speaker 1:  It's actually the, the set of hardware things they did here
Speaker 1:  is pretty impressive, right? So in addition, right, there's the, there's
Speaker 1:  the heart rate sensor. It's I think a slightly
Speaker 1:  lighter whole thing when you include the, the headphones
Speaker 1:  and the case, the whole package is slightly lighter. It's IP
Speaker 1:  57 dust, sweat resistance, which is like, to be clear,
Speaker 1:  is not the same as my headphones are waterproof. Like, like please dear,
Speaker 1:  sweet Jesus, no, do not think your headphones are waterproof, but this is
Speaker 1:  better. And this is the first time Apple has given these things a real proper,
Speaker 1:  they will withstand this stuff rating. Yes. That,
Speaker 1:  that I feel comfortable and good with. So that's exciting. Better battery
Speaker 1:  life, more ear tips, like you said, the, the heart rate
Speaker 1:  sensor, it'll do live translation stuff like this. This is a lot of hardware
Speaker 1:  stuff to do in headphones. This is not just like we improved
Speaker 1:  the software and it'll connect more cleanly to your Mac so that it'll ring
Speaker 1:  every time you get a phone call on all of your computers. Now this is like
Speaker 1:  real genuine hardware stuff inside of these, which is awesome.
Speaker 5:  It's very substantial. And you know, I think like, like I was mentioning
Speaker 5:  with the fit kind of playing into the
Speaker 5:  A NC, some of it is also just kind of, I think there's
Speaker 5:  the most thesis in this device com across all of the ones that were
Speaker 5:  released today. Because on the one hand, you know, we are slowly like
Speaker 5:  giving baby baby sprinkles of AI in there with the translation.
Speaker 5:  And that is a thing that we've been seeing across the board from other companies.
Speaker 5:  But it's most natural. I think it's one thing to translate a phone call
Speaker 5:  on, on a phone and yay Gemini, yay all of the
Speaker 5:  whatever live translations for phone calls. But it's very natural to have
Speaker 5:  it in your AirPods when you're going about
Speaker 5:  it. Kind of just makes sense to have it built into the actual
Speaker 5:  buds themselves. Totally. And then just
Speaker 5:  I, as someone who works out, was kind of like, oh my god,
Speaker 5:  you're allowing standalone workouts with the AirPods
Speaker 5:  alone. Hmm. You don't need an Apple watch anymore. You can just do 50
Speaker 5:  types of workouts. And it's quite extensive. I did get a demo of this,
Speaker 5:  of the heart rate sensor and how the standalone workout
Speaker 5:  session is gonna go. And I was like, oh, this is huge
Speaker 5:  for people with wrist tattoos. Because I consistently hear from people
Speaker 5:  who are like, I don't wanna wear a chest strap, I don't wanna, my
Speaker 5:  Apple Watch doesn't really do heart rate. Well 'cause I have a whole
Speaker 5:  sleeve, there's just a tattoo there. Well, you don't need to worry about
Speaker 5:  it anymore. You can just have it in your ears and use that
Speaker 5:  to, to track. Or, you know, I have friends who do boxing, they can't wear
Speaker 5:  a watch while they box, right? But they want the heart rate stuff. So you
Speaker 5:  could just do it that way. It's kind of having
Speaker 5:  a new modality that's
Speaker 5:  open to you for heart rate tracking and you know, it's actually better
Speaker 5:  in my opinion, than the Powerbeats Pro two, which
Speaker 5:  introduced this. And so, you know, there was kind of a sense that the heart
Speaker 5:  rate tracking was coming, but it's better because
Speaker 5:  it's gonna work in tandem with your Apple Watch. So you can have
Speaker 5:  a multiple streams of data with the Powerbeats Pro two, it's always gonna
Speaker 5:  defer to your Apple Watch. This will go, hmm, so you have a stream of heart
Speaker 5:  rate data from your earbuds. Oh, you have a heart stream
Speaker 5:  of heart rate data from your wrist, which one is more accurate right now?
Speaker 5:  Which one is giving you the better signal? And it'll switch between
Speaker 5:  those,
Speaker 1:  Which is like an incredibly aply way of thinking about things,
Speaker 1:  right? Yeah. Like if you wanna describe the thing that Apple tends to be
Speaker 1:  better at than anybody else, it is precisely that thing. And half of that
Speaker 1:  thing is making you buy more devices that do largely redundant things, but
Speaker 1:  the other half is like actually making the sum greater or actually making
Speaker 1:  the whole greater than the sum of its parts. And that is yeah. Meaningful.
Speaker 1:  And I think that's very cool. So I think to me, yeah, the, the AirPods Pro
Speaker 1:  three are like, if, if you're in the market for AirPods, these sound like
Speaker 1:  they're gonna kick ass. I think I, it's probably overkill if you're not
Speaker 1:  really like an exercise person, but to me, honestly for the IP 57
Speaker 1:  alone, it, as someone who has had weather
Speaker 1:  and laundry ruin multiple pairs of AirPods over the years, like that
Speaker 1:  alone is a huge upgrade for me.
Speaker 5:  I mean, that's a huge thing for me too, as someone who has been caught in
Speaker 5:  downpours while running. So it's, I've, I've wrecked
Speaker 5:  earbuds that way. So it is a pretty, it's a pretty,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, I think it's surprisingly like the sleeper hit, in my opinion
Speaker 5:  as far as utility goes, as far as it like, should I upgrade? I,
Speaker 5:  I mean of course I'm gonna test 'em and I'm gonna live with them and tell
Speaker 5:  you everything that is great and not great about it. But if you're a day
Speaker 5:  one, I don't give a crap what reviewers think. This is the
Speaker 5:  thing that I think makes most sense on paper to upgrade to.
Speaker 1:  Totally. So, okay, let's talk about the watches, which I would argue are
Speaker 1:  substantially less straightforward. And I,
Speaker 1:  what I realized to me is I actually think the watches are most interesting,
Speaker 1:  like directly in order from cheapest to most expensive. Yes. Which is not
Speaker 1:  how I have felt about the Apple Watch before. Ordinarily I would've said
Speaker 1:  like the, the, the middle one, the, the sort of
Speaker 1:  vanilla Apple watch is the one, the se is the one if
Speaker 1:  and only if you just can't afford it. Like understand. But like
Speaker 1:  if you can, if there's any way at all to get the regular watch, get the watch,
Speaker 1:  and then the ultra is if you're like a lunatic in several ways. But
Speaker 1:  I don't feel that way anymore. Now I, the, the, I wanna start with the watch
Speaker 1:  se three, which I think might now be the
Speaker 1:  correct Apple watch for most people. Lemme just run you through
Speaker 1:  some of the specs here that I think are like big giant, huge upgrades,
Speaker 1:  $249, lovely price, faster processor, longer battery life,
Speaker 1:  stronger glass. It has an always on display, which is one of the like main
Speaker 1:  things a watch should do is tell you the time, all the time.
Speaker 1:  It has 5G, it has better battery, not great battery, but it has better battery.
Speaker 1:  It has more of the gesture stuff that the other watches have had. It's missing
Speaker 1:  some of the like really high end fitness health stuff.
Speaker 1:  But if you can do without that and what you want is just like a, a smartwatch
Speaker 1:  for other smartwatch things. This feels like a, the,
Speaker 1:  the biggest upgrade by a mile in this line.
Speaker 5:  100%. I was sitting there going like, am I most excited about the
Speaker 5:  SE three? Right. That was not on my bingo card. And to be quite
Speaker 5:  honest, I am most excited about the SE three because it is the most
Speaker 5:  substantial of the updates. And it's a confusing move
Speaker 5:  in some respects because now the gap between the SE
Speaker 5:  and the series,
Speaker 5:  it's razor thin. Yes. It's basically health. Health is the big
Speaker 5:  differentiator between the two. I I, I would say health and battery life,
Speaker 5:  but one of the things that's not coming to the SE three is the high blood
Speaker 5:  pressure feature that's currently going through FDA clearance.
Speaker 5:  I think they're, I think they're pretty confident that they will get that
Speaker 5:  clearance soon. But yeah,
Speaker 1:  There was a footnote I think that said by the end of this month, they expect
Speaker 1:  the hypertension stuff to be FDA
Speaker 5:  A approved. So like, yeah, so, you know, they, who knows,
Speaker 1:  But that's that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Who knows? But they, they seem pretty confident. And if we
Speaker 5:  look at Apple's track history, it's, or track record
Speaker 5:  is a lot better than Withings. It's
Speaker 1:  Real,
Speaker 5:  It's a lot better than that one. So, you know, it's kind of one of
Speaker 5:  those things where I sat there And I was like, okay, you know,
Speaker 5:  one, one of the things that the SE three is getting is also a speaker.
Speaker 5:  That was a thing that was get kept to the flagship last year.
Speaker 5:  It truly is, what are you missing? You're missing blood oxygen. Yep.
Speaker 5:  You're missing EKGs, you're missing
Speaker 5:  that high, high blood pressure thing, but you're getting sleep apnea. You're
Speaker 5:  getting the sleep score. And, and the reason why you're not getting
Speaker 5:  the high blood pressure thing is because it does not have the most up-to-date
Speaker 5:  optical heart rate sensor. Which, you know, it's, it's good enough.
Speaker 5:  You don't get the 24 hour battery life, which we have to talk about
Speaker 5:  the significance of it being 24 for the series 11, but
Speaker 5:  it is getting fast charging for the first time. And I have
Speaker 5:  talked to dozens, bazillions, I, I, many,
Speaker 5:  many Apple Watch users, I have talked to them and they either fall into the
Speaker 5:  category of like, well, it's no garment, it's not lasting forever.
Speaker 5:  Or the very like, well you just charge it when you shower. What's the big
Speaker 5:  deal, yo? And you know, 15 minutes on the charger is
Speaker 5:  supposedly gonna get you eight hours-ish of battery life. So
Speaker 1:  I'm be asking. So as long as you shower every eight hours, you should be
Speaker 1:  fine. You
Speaker 5:  Should be fine. This is, so
Speaker 1:  I, I actually, let's talk about battery life and, and this, this is a good
Speaker 1:  segue into the series 11 because I, I think that
Speaker 1:  the single most important spec of the Apple watch right now
Speaker 1:  is battery life. I, in terms of like a, your ongoing
Speaker 1:  enjoyment of the product B the set of things that you can do with it, especially
Speaker 1:  I think I'm more and more converted to cellular
Speaker 1:  apple watch all the time. I don't own a cellular watch right now, but I am,
Speaker 1:  I am confident the next one I buy will be a cellular one because it just,
Speaker 1:  there's just a set of things that suddenly become possible, But that also
Speaker 1:  is going to destroy battery life. So we're at this place now where like the
Speaker 1:  E three says 18 hours of battery and that just isn't enough. Because what
Speaker 1:  that means is it is going to die before I can charge it. It just, it just
Speaker 1:  does.
Speaker 5:  Here's the thing. Apple always says 18, but they're the opposite of Samsung
Speaker 5:  where I have like yelled at Samsung many years in
Speaker 5:  a row by them overestimating or overpromising on the battery life of their
Speaker 5:  watches and them fall. I admit I'm a power user, but
Speaker 5:  them falling short of the promises and
Speaker 5:  me being like, yo, that's, that's dumb. And Apple
Speaker 5:  has always under promised and over-delivered with battery life. That is true.
Speaker 5:  It depends year to year. So it's not always gonna be better
Speaker 5:  or whatever, depending on what features they're offering and what's running
Speaker 5:  in the background, what the software is. But I
Speaker 5:  have routinely gotten better than 18 hours of battery life for many,
Speaker 5:  many years now to the point where I'm like, they say 18. But that is such
Speaker 5:  a conservative estimate. I think
Speaker 1:  That's true. Now that I think about it. I, And I do think to your point,
Speaker 1:  I think, I think the fast charging thing is probably the bigger deal. 'cause
Speaker 1:  if it, if it was true that I could charge zero to a
Speaker 1:  hundred or close to it in the time that it takes me to like shower and get
Speaker 1:  ready in the morning, charging stops being a problem. Like now I have infinite
Speaker 1:  battery life, right? Like yeah, I, I take it off when I take my clothes off
Speaker 1:  And I put it on when I put my clothes on and that is the end. We've done
Speaker 1:  it.
Speaker 5:  And you should, you should be airing out your wrist. Right? I'm very, very
Speaker 5:  passionate about airing out your wrist because I've, I, again, I'm a crazy
Speaker 5:  wearable lady, so I
Speaker 1:  Was gonna say this feels like a you problem to, to some extent, but
Speaker 5:  To some extent. But you really do need to air out your wrists because the
Speaker 5:  skin gets weird if you don't.
Speaker 1:  My Apple watch, which is currently dead, I'm taking off right now just to
Speaker 1:  air out my wrists while we're doing this.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. Your skin will thank you for that. But to that
Speaker 5:  point, you know, for them this is 10 years of
Speaker 5:  them never budging beyond the 18 hour estimate. Even though I have
Speaker 5:  routinely gotten more than 18 hours for several years, especially
Speaker 5:  after they introduced the low, the improved low ba low battery power mode.
Speaker 5:  So for them to say it's 24, I'm sitting here just like, are we
Speaker 5:  getting 24 or are we getting 36? Right.
Speaker 5:  You know, it of course it always depends on your usage. It depends on how
Speaker 5:  much extra you can get out of a low power battery mode.
Speaker 5:  But I'm saying I think them
Speaker 5:  moving from 18 to 24, they do not do that unless
Speaker 5:  they're very confident and they are very conservative.
Speaker 5:  So for them to say 24 to me as
Speaker 5:  having tested everything since the, I don't, I don't even
Speaker 5:  remember, but it's like a small number like the Apple Watch series two,
Speaker 5:  at least having lived with every iteration of the Apple watch since then,
Speaker 5:  that is, that is big to me. Particularly me. I was just like
Speaker 6:  24 hours, oh my God,
Speaker 6:  they've moved the number up. Oh my god, that never happens.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, I was sitting there just like exclamation point, exclamation
Speaker 5:  point, exclamation point that that's actually a big thing and it's the number
Speaker 5:  one thing that readers are, are in my comments about just being like,
Speaker 5:  moderate life is my number one thing and it plays into sleep tracking
Speaker 5:  because you cannot have 18 hours and, and sleep track
Speaker 5:  effectively. And it, sleep tracking is something that people really want.
Speaker 5:  You know, apple has always been a little bit behind on sleep tracking compared
Speaker 5:  to the market because of the battery life issue. So for them to really
Speaker 5:  do that and on top of that go, we have a sleep score for you. Now
Speaker 5:  that is sort of,
Speaker 5:  I gotta say that, that those are just like how they air pods
Speaker 5:  and the heart rate sensor, you know, those things work synergistically,
Speaker 5:  having long battery life having a sleep score. These are things that enable
Speaker 5:  each other.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And you, you continue to convince me that sleep tracking is
Speaker 1:  a huge thing because I think, and this, this gets us to the ultra a little
Speaker 1:  bit. Like I, one of the things that puts all of these devices
Speaker 1:  that we're talking about here together is that Apple
Speaker 1:  is really like pretty aggressively pivoting into being a
Speaker 1:  health tech company in a way that I am perpetually surprised by like
Speaker 1:  all of the sort of everyday normal person features
Speaker 1:  stay the same year to year and then they give you more health stuff. Like
Speaker 1:  that's what's happening on these devices. And it, it's fascinating And I,
Speaker 1:  I continue to think like, I, I think I believed Tim Cook when he says
Speaker 1:  it is like a thing he cares about as a person.
Speaker 1:  I have a lot of thoughts about what Tim Cook cares about as a person right
Speaker 1:  now, but we'll come back to those another time. But I think I,
Speaker 1:  it is fascinating that that is a thing that Apple has identified as like
Speaker 1:  meaningful to its business also. And I think to your
Speaker 1:  point, I do think sleep track and especially the sleep score thing
Speaker 1:  strikes me as a, a, a huge opportunity there to like
Speaker 1:  get right and do in a like big mainstream way.
Speaker 5:  Listen, I come from a family of doctors and one of the things that
Speaker 5:  they always told me is that the number one possession you have, the thing
Speaker 5:  that will influence your life more is your health. If you have bad
Speaker 1:  Health, that's such a parent thing to say, I'd
Speaker 5:  Love this for you. It's, but also it's, it's a parent thing to say, but this
Speaker 5:  was mostly my grandpa who was like a big famous doctor in this one city in
Speaker 5:  Korea. And he was just like, if you do not have your health, you do not have
Speaker 5:  a good life. And I was very dramatic. That's like a very, you
Speaker 5:  have to think about it in a very old dramatic
Speaker 5:  Korean grandpa way where he's like, Victoria, if you do not have your health,
Speaker 5:  you do not have life. So, but he's true, he's
Speaker 5:  completely correct in the sense that this is the thing that Gale Apple
Speaker 5:  watch to be a thing. 'cause you know, if we,
Speaker 5:  we go back in Apple watch history, they thought it was gonna be fashion and
Speaker 5:  LLOL. Yeah. I'm too poor to ever have a Hermes Apple
Speaker 5:  watch even though they're very pretty, they're very nice but
Speaker 1:  Still exists. And it still exists. Which is a thing, thing I didn't realize
Speaker 1:  still exist until literally today when they said Hermes on stage. Yeah. Still.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But you know, it didn't really kick off until EKGs came out and then everyone's
Speaker 5:  like, oh my God, this is gonna save your grandma's life and now what do they
Speaker 5:  do every single year? And I think I said it in the live blog And I was like,
Speaker 5:  Q the annual, the Apple watch will save your life real. And they, and it's,
Speaker 5:  and it's very compelling because you have real life people and they find
Speaker 5:  different ones every year. It's not the same person every year. Different
Speaker 5:  people who are like, this thing saved my life because it pointed out a thing.
Speaker 5:  And you know, I think that's, we watch it and we go like, well
Speaker 5:  yeah, okay, you're giving me health anxiety. But at the same time it's a
Speaker 5:  very compelling marketing proposition. And the thing that
Speaker 5:  I get asked a lot by my friends, family, people I know is what do I
Speaker 5:  buy my mom or my dad? They recently had a health crisis
Speaker 5:  and so what do I, what do I do? And you know, they, what they are
Speaker 5:  doing is they're basically positioning the SE three as kind of like the
Speaker 5:  core smartwatch experience. It's something that gives you a taste
Speaker 5:  and it's very expansive, but we're gonna get, keep the
Speaker 5:  health to the series. So the series is now
Speaker 5:  your overall health watch. And then, you know, the ultra three is for as
Speaker 5:  lunatics out here doing fitness stuff
Speaker 5:  basically. So, you know, if you think about it from that lens, the updates
Speaker 5:  make sense. I kind of wish they made it clearer in their
Speaker 5:  messaging. 'cause you kind of have to just like sit there and turn into the,
Speaker 5:  the meme of the, the, the lady doing the, the math floating around her
Speaker 5:  and just going like, what, what is happening here with these updates?
Speaker 5:  But I think that's the key D differentiator going forward between
Speaker 5:  the series and the se is like, how much do you care about your health?
Speaker 5:  Right? How, how much do you, like nobody wants to
Speaker 5:  die, right? Like we all want health insurance because we want to live and
Speaker 5:  we want to live well and we want to live healthy. So I don't think Tim Cook
Speaker 5:  is wrong even though, you know, SW Tim Cook. So he obviously cares
Speaker 5:  about all of that. But
Speaker 5:  I genuinely think that people will do anything to live a healthy life
Speaker 5:  because it means they get to live longer. It means they get to spend more
Speaker 5:  time with the people they love. So tapping into that and saying this is an
Speaker 5:  essential device for you to live a long how Happy Life
Speaker 5:  Kain kaching baby, that's monetization for
Speaker 1:  You. It's true, it is, it is tough to argue with the theory there, but I
Speaker 1:  like that differentiation of like, there's the, there's the smart watch,
Speaker 1:  which is the, the SE three. There is the Health watch I guess,
Speaker 1:  which is the, the series 11. And then there's the Lunatic watch, which is
Speaker 1:  the, the ultra three. Yes. And I mean lunatic as a compliment to be clear.
Speaker 1:  Every ev all of you lunatics who are hearing this being like, I'm normal
Speaker 1:  And I wear like, please know that I hear you And I love you.
Speaker 1:  Nothing about the ultra three seemed super duper exciting to me.
Speaker 1:  It's got like a little bigger screen. The, the ed's a little better. Little
Speaker 1:  longer battery life, like the, the things you would like hope would get a
Speaker 1:  little better. Rev to rev, but nothing that feels like it's gonna sort of
Speaker 1:  meaningfully change your experience with this watch.
Speaker 5:  I think that is a hundred percent true for non lunatics
Speaker 5:  because Okay, you know, you know they speak the largest,
Speaker 1:  I speak the non lunatics. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  The largest display ever. Well I held the ultra two and the
Speaker 5:  three side by side And I think VERGE cast listeners know because I've been
Speaker 5:  screaming this all summer, I have garbage eyeballs. My, my eyes are not great.
Speaker 5:  So take that with a grain of salt knowing that my
Speaker 5:  eyeballs not the best eyeballs and and on earth held them side by
Speaker 5:  side. And I went I guess the bezels a little thinner.
Speaker 5:  I guess it's slightly. Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1:  I mean this is where we're at now. Yeah. This
Speaker 5:  Is where we're at. Yeah. But for the lunatics out there, the thing is
Speaker 5:  SOS satellite communication Sure. Fair. That's gonna be the thing. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because if you're a through hiker, if you're someone who has a Garmin in
Speaker 5:  reach or you wanna be able to, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  you've fallen down a ravine and your phone went flying and
Speaker 5:  you're just like, ah, crap, a moola, I don't wanna die
Speaker 5:  And I really save me someone. Well now you have
Speaker 5:  OS satellite, SOS and it includes texting,
Speaker 5:  includes location SA sharing and it also includes just
Speaker 5:  sending messages in areas where you have absolutely
Speaker 5:  no signal whatsoever.
Speaker 5:  For me, my initial thing was like, well they had that on The iPhone,
Speaker 5:  what's the benefit of having that on a watch? And so then I
Speaker 5:  was thinking of the scenario where I fell off a cliff And I'm like, oh God,
Speaker 5:  there goes my phone. I guess it's still on me
Speaker 5:  za Sure. But also, you know, one, one of the things I was
Speaker 5:  thinking about was like, well on the ultra, the battery life lasts a pretty
Speaker 5:  good dang long time. So you have options I
Speaker 5:  guess. Yeah. But you know, it, it is an important thing. It's the heart
Speaker 1:  Rate thing all over again, right? Like it's, it's, it's a case where there
Speaker 1:  just is no downside to having more versions of the feature
Speaker 1:  at your
Speaker 5:  Disposal. Yeah. And you know, a lot of through hikers, like our very
Speaker 5:  own good Mitchell Clark, may he hike in
Speaker 5:  perpetuity, but when he went on his absolutely lunatic
Speaker 5:  quest to go to the Pacific Crest Trail, I,
Speaker 5:  dude, I don't know how you did that Livia Mitchell, but couldn't be me.
Speaker 1:  That's lunatic stuff. It really
Speaker 5:  Is. That's lunatic. Yeah. It like, this is who that appeals to, right? Because
Speaker 5:  they, those people have Garmin and reaches, they have subscriptions for the
Speaker 5:  Garmin and reach, and that's basically there to go like, oh, I'm in
Speaker 5:  t Ask in Maryland where my, my spouse is in-laws are from, and there's only
Speaker 5:  one tree where if you stand a certain way you get a bar of signal.
Speaker 5:  You know, like for people who are in those areas who spend a lot of time
Speaker 5:  in those areas who maybe don't wanna have their phone on them, or even their
Speaker 5:  phone isn't really doing it for them, you know, you just have another
Speaker 5:  option. I think it's a good thing
Speaker 5:  in terms of if you're paranoid about that or if you just wanna check in on,
Speaker 5:  on these hiking trips or whatnot. But the other thing
Speaker 5:  is, you know, it's a watch that people
Speaker 5:  who love the ultras, love the ultras. When we were in the,
Speaker 5:  the arena, you know, when the ultra came out, I heard people
Speaker 5:  around me go, yes. Yeah. And I was, oh yeah, what is this? What is this
Speaker 5:  visceral love for the,
Speaker 1:  It does have its
Speaker 5:  People, the ultra for sure. Like it has its people. And for those people
Speaker 5:  I think that's who the satellite s os is for. And you don't pay a
Speaker 5:  subscription for two years with that. Yeah. And you know, that's
Speaker 5:  you, I mean, one should hope if one is buying a $800
Speaker 5:  watch for the satellite SOS and trying to
Speaker 5:  get rid of some of the other equipment and maybe like streamlining it into
Speaker 5:  like minimal devices. One would hope that you don't have to pay an extra
Speaker 5:  subscription for the SOS communication. Yeah. I think
Speaker 1:  Apple can spot you for that one. Yeah. I just wanna say by the way, that
Speaker 1:  ever since you said it's different people in every video when they talk about
Speaker 1:  the people whose lives are saved, I can't stop thinking about if there's
Speaker 1:  one person who's just like, you know, Richard just like
Speaker 1:  keeps falling down mountains and just like sends Tim Cook an email every
Speaker 1:  year and is like, buddy, you did it again. I'm still here.
Speaker 1:  I got, I got the SOS this time. We're cool. And he's like, my, my friends
Speaker 1:  found me 'cause of this new feature. And he's just like, Tim Cook is just
Speaker 1:  like, stop sending this guy Apple watches. Like he's out there. And if it
Speaker 1:  is you who keeps trying to die, but being saved by your Apple watch,
Speaker 1:  I, I would like to hear from you.
Speaker 5:  I also would love, I would love to interview you. We should do a, we would
Speaker 5:  love to do a special Tuesday episode. A hundred percent dissect your
Speaker 5:  life. But
Speaker 1:  Yeah, he And I will come fall off Cliffs with you anytime
Speaker 5:  I look forward to it. I'm, you can go fall off. I have no desire to fall
Speaker 5:  off. I've got training to do. I I I had a Charlie Hor horse
Speaker 5:  the other day from rolling over in my bed, so I'm aging And I can't take
Speaker 5:  these risks of falling off CL Cliffs, but I would love to
Speaker 5:  interview you about falling off a cliff. So there we go. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I love this for us. All right, we gotta take a break. ViiV, I'm sure got
Speaker 1:  more things to write about watches, but were we, we got more to talk about
Speaker 1:  this things. I, we have two
Speaker 5:  Wrists and there are three watches I don't want to
Speaker 1:  Do. Can you do one as like an ankle monitor situation? Oh,
Speaker 5:  At some point. Many people have suggested this to me, which I don't know
Speaker 5:  how that makes me feel, but
Speaker 1:  I think you string them all together and wear them like a choker around your
Speaker 1:  neck. V Thank you. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  As always
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  at warp dev slash vergecast.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. One more thing to talk about and Jake
Speaker 1:  Kakis, it's you. Hi, Jake. Hey, it's good to see
Speaker 7:  You. They let you back in. They did.
Speaker 1:  Miracle of Miracles. It's possible this is the last vergecast I
Speaker 1:  will ever get to do, But that they, let me do one more. I'm
Speaker 7:  Excited you're here.
Speaker 1:  You had a new experience for you. You've been at
Speaker 1:  The Verge for 650 years. You, you joined Yeah.
Speaker 1:  In in the, the Renaissance period, if I remember correctly. But this is
Speaker 1:  te
Speaker 7:  If Im not, technology is very different back then. It is very
Speaker 1:  Different. But if I'm not mistaken, this is the first time you have been
Speaker 1:  to Cupertino for an iPhone launch, right?
Speaker 7:  This is my first time at Apple Park. Yeah, certainly my first iPhone
Speaker 7:  hardware event. And it was, you know, a new experience for me. It's,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's very different watching it remotely, seeing all the
Speaker 7:  photos, reading the live blogs, and actually being here, seeing
Speaker 7:  the scenery being in the space. It's Apple really,
Speaker 7:  you know, you kind of look at it from afar and you go, oh, they really like
Speaker 7:  put a lot of polish on this place. And then you get there and you're like,
Speaker 7:  whew, that was a lot of work. Went into this thing. What
Speaker 1:  Stood out? Like it's been a long, crazy day. What, what are some of the like
Speaker 1:  wildest moments of the day for you? Well,
Speaker 7:  Okay, if I can just talk about the space because I think this is something
Speaker 7:  that obviously most people don't see. They, they sh shoot their videos
Speaker 7:  around campus and having now been on their campus for the first time, I,
Speaker 7:  I really understand why like, it is a sculpted,
Speaker 7:  carefully crafted park and the park in the name.
Speaker 7:  I think externally as an observer has always felt, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  a little pretentious. And now being there, I'm like, nope. There's like
Speaker 7:  Rolling Hills, there's a ton of, it's an actual park.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Trees. There's grass, like, it, it really does feel like a park and
Speaker 7:  there just happens to be a weird spaceship in the middle. So perhaps it is
Speaker 7:  a little bit pretentious to build that for yourself,
Speaker 7:  but it really is a, a, a very lovely, remarkable space. And you understand
Speaker 7:  why they're like, of course we're gonna show this thing off. Like of course
Speaker 7:  we're gonna dot ourselves around this campus for
Speaker 7:  these videos. And you know, the theater that they bring you into is just,
Speaker 7:  it, it it's gargantuan. It's like, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  brutalist isn't quite right because it has obviously soft edges everywhere,
Speaker 7:  but it's just, you know, towering walls,
Speaker 7:  you know, these Im immense views of the sky. It's very striking
Speaker 7:  And I, I think a lot of the
Speaker 7:  hyping up of the space that they did, you know,
Speaker 7:  it doesn't necessarily come across in the photos and videos. And then when
Speaker 7:  you're there in the space, you understand why they put
Speaker 7:  so much energy in into telling people about this place. It really,
Speaker 7:  it really is very impressive. And, and you know, the
Speaker 7:  iPhones,
Speaker 7:  that's what we're here for. But as somebody who hadn't seen
Speaker 7:  the location before, really, really fascinating to get to go there.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's one of the things I really like about going to WDC
Speaker 1:  every year is that it is full of people who have never been to
Speaker 1:  Apple Park before. And I think a, there is something about Apple as a
Speaker 1:  company that like people are attached to in a way that is very unusual.
Speaker 1:  But there is something about that place. Like you And I have been to a lot
Speaker 1:  of corporate offices. Yes. And most of them are corporate offices.
Speaker 1:  And I think the, the only two places I've ever been that felt sort
Speaker 1:  of meaningfully different were, when I lived in Oakland, my
Speaker 1:  landlord happened to be a Pixar animator and so he just
Speaker 1:  took my wife And I on a tour of the Pixar offices and that was
Speaker 1:  like, that's a place that is also sort of like famously special and people
Speaker 1:  do like super elaborate decorations of their offices so that they look like
Speaker 1:  movie sets. That was very cool. And then for me, the first
Speaker 1:  time I went down the stairs at the Steve Jobs theater and
Speaker 1:  you're up in this huge sort of open waiting room that's
Speaker 1:  like all glass all the way around. And then you start to go down the stairs
Speaker 1:  and the stairs are like basically carved out of marble Yeah.
Speaker 1:  As you go all the way. And it's just like, there's something
Speaker 1:  genuinely sort of special about it. And that is like, it, it
Speaker 1:  doesn't make me like the iPhones more, but it's like, God, they did a good
Speaker 1:  job.
Speaker 7:  I mean there's something like, religious isn't the right word, but when you're
Speaker 7:  looking up at that big staircase from down below,
Speaker 7:  it's just this thing that towers above you and you feel your
Speaker 7:  scale within it. And I, I don't even mean to say that it gave me these
Speaker 7:  feelings about Apple, but they clearly designed it to have an effect
Speaker 7:  on you. And I it's a remarkable piece of architecture when you're standing
Speaker 7:  inside of it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like shouts to the architects is really what it is. They spent
Speaker 1:  a lot of money and did a very good job. It also, from what I can tell, seems
Speaker 1:  like an awful place to work because you're like, I have a meeting over there
Speaker 1:  and it's a three quarter of a mile walk. That's a different problem.
Speaker 7:  There's lots of golf carts. I was scoping out whether they had apple
Speaker 7:  bikes. I think they do, they have pretty be single speed. So
Speaker 7:  there, there's a, tell me if I'm wrong, I might be mixing up single speed
Speaker 7:  and fixie, but there's a chain, but it's one
Speaker 7:  chain. I don't think there are gears. They're like this kind of soft
Speaker 7:  gray silver, they look, they look nice, they look nice.
Speaker 1:  Gears are are too much visible work. Do you know what I mean?
Speaker 7:  Apple can't do, there was no chance there were gonna be gears on those. No
Speaker 1:  Ab never, I honestly, it's surprising they're not fixie bikes now that
Speaker 7:  You mentioned. Yeah. I'm honestly, I'm stunned. These things aren't like,
Speaker 7:  there isn't like a hot market for these. Like if, if you're a
Speaker 7:  true Apple fan, you've got a lifted apple bike.
Speaker 1:  When I was living in Silicon Valley, you used to see the Google bikes all
Speaker 1:  over the place. People would steal them off of Google's campus and ride them
Speaker 1:  to Caltrain or whatever. I don't think I've ever seen an Apple bike in, in
Speaker 1:  the wild. So if, if you've seen one send us pictures Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com, I wanna see all of your Apple bike spottings. But I
Speaker 1:  suspect there are large security guards who will
Speaker 1:  do crimes to you if you do that,
Speaker 7:  Be careful. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So we've already talked about the phones, we've already talked about the
Speaker 1:  air pods, we've already talked to the watches. What I wanna do with you is
Speaker 1:  kind of cover off all the other stuff because it, at an event like this,
Speaker 1:  there's always a lot of other stuff. And the thing that jumped
Speaker 1:  out to me the most, and I'm curious just to get your thoughts on
Speaker 1:  this, this felt like a very accessory heavy iPhone
Speaker 1:  event in a way that they typically aren't. They talked a bunch about a case,
Speaker 1:  there was a lot of noise about and crossbody strap that everybody had a lot
Speaker 1:  of feelings about. Like there was just a thing where they're like, we're
Speaker 1:  gonna launch a bunch of devices, but then we're gonna do kind of a lifestyle
Speaker 1:  brandy thing around them. And I know you got to see some of the
Speaker 1:  devices, I don't know how many of the accessories were out there, but what
Speaker 1:  do you make of this push towards all
Speaker 1:  of this stuff that you can sort of attach to your devices right next
Speaker 1:  to the devices themselves?
Speaker 7:  Okay. People are so hyped for this crossbody strap really
Speaker 7:  are. And it is, it is not for me. I am not the demographic. I don't know
Speaker 7:  who the demographic is, but they're out there. I've seen them.
Speaker 1:  I just think the idea that you're gonna buy a phone and just proudly
Speaker 1:  display it like pretty loosely on your body
Speaker 1:  is just lunacy. Like, don't, don't do that.
Speaker 7:  I, I think it's, it, it's bizarre. You're just like, I don't wanna know
Speaker 7:  too much about this phone. It's just gonna be floating around
Speaker 7:  while I'm not using it. I might hear it vibrate, I might, I don't
Speaker 7:  know. I'll find it eventually. It it feels like you just
Speaker 7:  like let it float off. I, it's not for me,
Speaker 7:  but there's, people are very excited. I don't know why. I think maybe it's
Speaker 7:  'cause a a new category for Apple, even though there's a trillion of
Speaker 7:  these things in existence. I think all their new cases have little
Speaker 7:  lanyard straps now because they know that this is a thing. They know people
Speaker 7:  wanna wear them this way. Do they
Speaker 1:  Though, like, is is, is there actual evidence that this is a real thing that
Speaker 1:  exists? I've,
Speaker 7:  I've seen them around, I've seen them around New York. I, I can't quite tell
Speaker 7:  if it's a tourist thing or a Gen Z thing. I, I
Speaker 7:  like, I don't want to date myself here, but I suspect there is a
Speaker 7:  specific demographic and it's just like, it's not men in their
Speaker 7:  thirties. That's fair. Which like,
Speaker 7:  I don't know.
Speaker 7:  I, I like the pocket, the pocket still works for me. Yeah, sure.
Speaker 7:  I'm doing fine. But, you know, to to your point about like this being an
Speaker 7:  accessories heavy event, you know, I do think it's interesting
Speaker 7:  for us as phone reviewers And I think
Speaker 7:  for, for folks who are listening who are probably, you know, big fans of
Speaker 7:  technology, the accessories always feel like a little bit of an afterthought.
Speaker 7:  And I think it is probably worth realizing that
Speaker 7:  the, these purchases go hand in hand for everybody. And if
Speaker 7:  the accessories don't work, the, the, the device doesn't necessarily work
Speaker 7:  for you. And I don't think, like if you go out in public, you're, you're
Speaker 7:  rarely going to see an iPhone without a case on it. You're, you,
Speaker 7:  you don't see air tags without things wrapped around them. Right. That's
Speaker 7:  true. So like Apple I think is necessarily seeing, okay, we need to pair
Speaker 7:  these two things and yeah, they had a lot of different
Speaker 7:  options here. Obviously the big one was the return of
Speaker 7:  the, the woven cases. This comes two years after the disaster of fine
Speaker 7:  woven. They look very similar. This new one's called tech
Speaker 7:  woven, but they say it is much better.
Speaker 7:  They did not have them out in the demo area though, so I, I think
Speaker 7:  that was intentional. They probably knew people were going to immediately
Speaker 7:  try to rub some keys against them to see what happens. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I'm imagining every single reporter like ran out, grabbed the sharpest
Speaker 1:  thing that they had. Oh yeah. And I was like, I'm gonna, I'm gonna go find
Speaker 7:  That case. I mean, as soon as I got my hands on an iPhone air, I, I like
Speaker 7:  squeezed it a little. I'm like, I gotta see this Benz. Like I don't wanna
Speaker 7:  did it. There's, there's handlers there, you know, you can't too much.
Speaker 7:  But I, I was, you know, in my, in my limited testing, I
Speaker 7:  did not, you know, no flex yet. We'll, we'll we'll see why
Speaker 7:  that's good
Speaker 1:  Journalism. Usually that's what, that's when you gotta be like, oh no, look,
Speaker 1:  somebody's stealing a MacBook and then just like snap the phone and run
Speaker 1:  away.
Speaker 7:  I, you know, I thought maybe not on my first visit to, to their headquarters.
Speaker 7:  I, I didn't want to get escorted out by security. But you know, I, I
Speaker 7:  gave a little flex for, for journalism. I gave a little flex and,
Speaker 1:  And okay, what did you think? We, we, we spent a bunch of time with Allison
Speaker 1:  talking about the, The iPhone Air. But you, you're the only other person
Speaker 1:  I know who has touched the thing. What do you make, what do you make of
Speaker 7:  It? It's striking. It's striking how thin it is. It really is. It's, it's
Speaker 7:  a lovely piece of hardware. It is. I'm, I'm
Speaker 7:  a small phone guy as much as is possible these days, which is usually
Speaker 7:  like the 6.1 inch area. This is 6.3 inches,
Speaker 7:  definitely feels a little bit bigger. But I think because it's so thin,
Speaker 7:  it can get away with it a little bit more. It's not necessarily as big on
Speaker 7:  your person. They let me sneak into my pocket. It, it
Speaker 7:  like fits in the pocket. It feels light, it's
Speaker 7:  nice. It's, it's, it is a striking piece of hardware. And I suspect that
Speaker 7:  a lot of people, you see this in a showroom and you're like, hmm, that's
Speaker 7:  a pretty nice slogan. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Can I tell you the funniest picture that I saw on our website today? Oh yeah.
Speaker 1:  Which I believe is courtesy of you is the very
Speaker 1:  thin iPhone air with a big fat, old battery case
Speaker 1:  just stuck to the back.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I'm, I don't even necessarily like wanna talk about it as it
Speaker 7:  relates to The iPhone Air people freaking love
Speaker 7:  apple's battery packs. The old one was enormous
Speaker 7:  and chunky and the ugliest thing on earth. People love that
Speaker 7:  thing.
Speaker 1:  You see them everywhere. It's the, the battery packs and the the
Speaker 1:  MagSafe wallets that just are like, you know, the whatever. Yeah. You can
Speaker 1:  have two credit cards on it. I see those everywhere. So
Speaker 7:  I, it, it kind of surprises me that they're not bringing this
Speaker 7:  back for the other phones. Again, people really like this thing.
Speaker 7:  So it's just for The iPhone Air, which I have questions, I have questions.
Speaker 7:  If that means they have battery life concerns about the phone itself
Speaker 7:  or if they just know that people like these, and maybe this will help drive
Speaker 7:  iPhone air sales because people will go, I wanna pair these two things.
Speaker 7:  When you pair them together, it does sort of make you go, oh,
Speaker 7:  why did I get The iPhone Air? Right. Like, 'cause if you have battery problems
Speaker 7:  with The iPhone Air, maybe you should have just gotten a bigger iPhone in
Speaker 7:  the first place and Right. Because now you have a bigger thing altogether.
Speaker 7:  If
Speaker 1:  You're buying your phone for the battery life, don't buy The iPhone Air.
Speaker 7:  I I will say The iPhone Air plus the battery pack,
Speaker 7:  the battery pack is a lot, a lot thinner than the old one. Okay.
Speaker 7:  It is thicker than The iPhone Air still so ever so slightly
Speaker 7:  thicker. So you're basically doubling the thickness of The iPhone Air, which
Speaker 7:  I'll say still doesn't feel terrible. Right. It, it, that
Speaker 7:  together feels like a, a reasonably sized phone, but it's
Speaker 7:  bigger than other iPhones. So, so it's,
Speaker 1:  But it's in two pieces and more expensive.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's in two pieces. You can lose one of them. You have to charge both.
Speaker 1:  You've a deconstructed iPhone 17 pro with worse features.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. So, you know, if, if you're just going out to the store, you
Speaker 7:  leave your battery pack behind. If you're going for your entire day, you
Speaker 7:  know, you, you get a double iPhone.
Speaker 1:  Sure. I love this for you. This is, this is the optimism we come here for.
Speaker 1:  This
Speaker 7:  Is, this is what you're gonna see everywhere
Speaker 7:  starting 2026.
Speaker 1:  I mean, you're, you're, you're probably right about that. When you were
Speaker 1:  in the room, I assume it was like, so just for folks
Speaker 1:  who haven't been there, you, you leave the Steve Jobs theater and right behind
Speaker 1:  it is this like big open, airy, hands-on area And I
Speaker 1:  have to assume that it was like
Speaker 1:  75% people clamoring to get to The iPhone Air,
Speaker 1:  25%. Everything else,
Speaker 7:  It, it was, I, it felt to me like an even split between the,
Speaker 7:  The iPhone Air and the Orange
Speaker 7:  iPhone Pro. Oh,
Speaker 1:  Fascinating.
Speaker 7:  At, at The iPhone pro table, all the other colors. Who cares
Speaker 7:  White, what is this? Gotta get that orange one. There are lines
Speaker 7:  for the orange one. I had to elbow my way in to get the orange one.
Speaker 7:  That, that's what people wanna see. Which I think it could just be for
Speaker 7:  this crowd. It is the most new looking iPhone pro.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, people are, it, it's an interesting one for Apple. They don't usually
Speaker 7:  go that bold, that bright, but yeah, you get out there
Speaker 7:  and people are, are, it's packed. It's like a mad rush to get
Speaker 7:  out there. And Apple has, I dunno,
Speaker 7:  dozens and dozens of, of demo stations. It's sort of this weird freeform
Speaker 7:  thing where they've got representatives standing by to
Speaker 7:  demo the phones. Nobody really wants them to demo the phones.
Speaker 7:  And so everybody's grabbing the phones. There's, you know, I think
Speaker 7:  there's
Speaker 7:  written journalists who are trying to get photos really fast
Speaker 7:  and impressions really fast so that they can go back and, and write stuff
Speaker 7:  on their laptops. There's talkers who are recording video, there's people
Speaker 7:  with full camera setups on tripods. So it's, it's just
Speaker 7:  a complete rush, a complete madhouse in there.
Speaker 7:  And Apple is doing their best to, to keep order as everybody
Speaker 7:  kind of scrambles and bounces between the new devices.
Speaker 1:  Interesting that the orange one was such a big hit. And this, this is now
Speaker 1:  three for three of VERGE guests on this podcast who are into the orange iPhone,
Speaker 1:  which I would say was pretty controversial on the internet.
Speaker 7:  I wanna say I I said it was very popular. Oh, what
Speaker 1:  Are only two for three? Okay.
Speaker 7:  It's, I'm not an orange guy in general. It's,
Speaker 7:  there is like a, a little, not an autumn coppery something to it. It's a
Speaker 7:  little bold for me. I don't know if I would, if I would do the orange. It
Speaker 7:  is a weird color. It's like right in time for, for Halloween or pumpkin
Speaker 7:  spice season or something.
Speaker 1:  I I do appreciate the swing that it is, right. Like it is,
Speaker 1:  yeah. I think Apple has been guiltier than almost
Speaker 1:  anybody of doing incredibly boring colors where
Speaker 1:  it's like, it's like, look, we made a, we made a blue
Speaker 1:  iPad mini that is like essentially not blue.
Speaker 1:  Like this isn't even a color. What are we doing here? You can't
Speaker 7:  Tell. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  No. And so to actually come out and be like, and there was actually a bunch
Speaker 1:  of this, there's some of this with the, the tech woven cases. There's some
Speaker 1:  of this with the, the crossbody strap. There's some of this, there's just
Speaker 1:  real like showy energy in some of these devices in a
Speaker 1:  way that I actually really appreciate. Not all of it is for me, but like
Speaker 1:  I, I appreciate the loudness of it. There's not a lot of that in
Speaker 1:  tech right now.
Speaker 7:  I I think that's sort of the story here too, right?
Speaker 7:  Not everybody upgrades their phone on a regular cadence. They, they
Speaker 7:  wait until it dies. And this year in
Speaker 7:  a lot of ways was designed to say, Hey, in case you haven't been paying attention,
Speaker 7:  a lot has changed. Right? Year over year, maybe not
Speaker 7:  so much if you're going back a few years. Okay, now there's a
Speaker 7:  brand new design in the pro, right? There's a whole new airline.
Speaker 7:  Do you need two cameras? Who cares? No one camera is actually four cameras.
Speaker 7:  What? Like it's, everything is new and different. There's this new accessory
Speaker 7:  options, lots of new colors, everything has a new name. So yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think you're right. Like this is a year about being kind of flashy
Speaker 7:  And I think that's very much by design to show like, hey, there's been a
Speaker 7:  generational shift even if it wasn't necessarily these phones. And you can,
Speaker 7:  maybe you can make the argument that it's these phones. I think they're saying
Speaker 7:  cumulatively a lot has changed since the last time we changed up our
Speaker 7:  designs. And that's very true. 'cause it's been since I think 2019
Speaker 7:  when we got this basically same design on The iPhone 11 pro.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, and we have been hearing from a lot of folks. I think for our audience
Speaker 1:  in particular, at least the 13 seems to be the sweet spot where there
Speaker 1:  are, there were a lot of 13 owners
Speaker 1:  looking at this event being like, is am I finally gonna pull the trigger
Speaker 1:  here? Which feels about right, right. Like it's, it's now
Speaker 1:  four generations ago, which is I think a reasonable amount of
Speaker 1:  time for a phone to last now. And if you're coming from the 13,
Speaker 1:  like a lot of stuff is gonna be a lot better. And also it's gonna be
Speaker 1:  orange, right? Like yeah. Right. And that, that counts for something. And
Speaker 1:  I think you, you're like, and it's going to, you're gonna wear it, you know,
Speaker 1:  with a weird sash across your body. Like it's, your phone is gonna feel
Speaker 1:  like you bought a new thing. And I think, I think you're right. That's hard
Speaker 1:  to come by in a lot of ways right now. And, and finding even
Speaker 1:  simple ways to get that done is pretty interesting.
Speaker 1:  Speaking of things that are going to change everybody's phones a lot, not
Speaker 1:  a lot of software talk today. So we, we have all these other
Speaker 1:  companies that are basically just like getting on stage and saying, here
Speaker 1:  is our phone. It does ai. That is it's whole purpose. It's, it's a brick
Speaker 1:  for ai. I think Apple probably said AI a couple of
Speaker 1:  times, but these are not AI devices. They didn't talk about Siri, they
Speaker 1:  didn't talk about Apple Intelligence. It was just a completely different
Speaker 1:  way of talking about smartphones than we've seen recently.
Speaker 1:  Was that weird in the room?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's so funny. You're completely like the pixel tent. They held up
Speaker 7:  the same phone Yeah. Like the exact same thing and said now
Speaker 7:  with with more ai Yeah. The iPhones. Yeah. It, it's like
Speaker 7:  there's maybe some small software tricks to work with
Speaker 7:  what they've already got or some of the tweaks they're making. Right. You
Speaker 7:  know, I think if you look at the watches, okay, there's some where where
Speaker 7:  the, the AirPods Yeah. They have some, some software to, to work with
Speaker 1:  With That's fair. Yeah. The live translation and stuff that, that counts
Speaker 1:  as a I that's
Speaker 7:  True. But I, I do think you're right. Like there's not any
Speaker 7:  exclusive certainly AI features, which, which is what
Speaker 7:  you would expect to be the big deal. At least flagship ones beyond that,
Speaker 7:  that sort of, you know, live translate stuff. The one place I
Speaker 7:  did clock some changes is maybe in the front facing camera, right? There's
Speaker 7:  a whole bunch of software stuff going on
Speaker 7:  to work with that new center stage camera where it keeps changing shape around
Speaker 7:  you. It's fascinating as far as I can tell, there just isn't
Speaker 7:  an option to shoot with the entire sensor, right? Hmm. You can, you
Speaker 7:  have to shoot with it in its wide or portrait setup
Speaker 7:  or doing one of its wacky things. You can
Speaker 7:  control it manually, but it really is designed as a set it and forget it
Speaker 7:  thing, which is interesting right. That that's working
Speaker 7:  on how the hardware works. But other than that, I agree with you. I don't
Speaker 7:  think it's a big software year. And I think if you look at a lot of apple's
Speaker 7:  changes, not just to The iPhone line, but to the MacBooks, the
Speaker 7:  watches in recent years, their big advantage
Speaker 7:  is is hardware, right? It's silicon, it's sensors.
Speaker 7:  They're so far ahead of the game in most places. They're
Speaker 7:  able to, you know, they, they introduced a new
Speaker 7:  chip for several of their networking things. They
Speaker 7:  updated their modem six months after their last modem. That's true.
Speaker 7:  Right? No one else is doing this. I don't know, I don't know if they need
Speaker 7:  their own modem. Maybe they do. We'll find out. But
Speaker 7:  that's where their focus really seems to be. It's, it's getting these edges
Speaker 7:  with hardware And I suspect they'll have a
Speaker 7:  software story again soon. But, you know, I think they were
Speaker 7:  probably hoping it was gonna be AI stuff and, and we know how that went.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And then, then they thought it was gonna be liquid glass and
Speaker 1:  boy, have I been using those betas for a while? And boy do I still hate liquid
Speaker 1:  glass? It's
Speaker 7:  There.
Speaker 1:  It it sure is.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think that's about the best you can say for it. And I think, again, like
Speaker 1:  if I were to be
Speaker 1:  the most glass half empty about all of this that I could be,
Speaker 1:  you could paint a real story about a lot of what Apple is doing here
Speaker 1:  that is very like
Speaker 1:  lipstick on a pig, right? That they're like, well we don't have any actually
Speaker 1:  new product ideas, we're just gonna make it all look different.
Speaker 1:  And that is very unapply. Right? I think the, the
Speaker 1:  thing that Apple has done so successfully, so for so long is that it has
Speaker 1:  had better product vision than any of its
Speaker 1:  competitors. And so everybody was like, oh, here's a box for playing music
Speaker 1:  on. Right? Like Apple was the one that understood what that is supposed to
Speaker 1:  look like and how that's supposed to work. What's so fascinating about Apple
Speaker 1:  right now is that what it is really good at is exactly what you're saying.
Speaker 1:  It is able to just out execute at like a very
Speaker 1:  like, infrastructural level. All of its competitors
Speaker 1:  like it, it's, it's chips are just so much better than
Speaker 1:  everybody else's. It. The rest of it almost doesn't matter. Its products
Speaker 1:  are going to be better because it has that and now it's, it's
Speaker 1:  it's spreading that out into like you're talking about some of the, the neural
Speaker 1:  engine stuff and some of the networking chips and they're just like really
Speaker 1:  ready to take a knife to Qualcomm with all of the modem stuff as quickly
Speaker 1:  as possible. And it is like, that is now Apple's edge.
Speaker 1:  It's not like the people in the, the design studio with
Speaker 1:  the blonde wood tables that everybody talked about for forever in these like
Speaker 1:  hushed reverent tones. That's not their advantage anymore. Their advantage
Speaker 1:  is like the deeply unsexy computer stuff.
Speaker 1:  And it's fascinating.
Speaker 7:  I think you can look at this a as a good thing or a bad
Speaker 7:  thing. Right? Does Apple have a grand vision
Speaker 7:  for how to change smartphones to make them work better for us?
Speaker 7:  It does not seem that way. No. Right. I don't think they have been building
Speaker 7:  toward that over the past few years,
Speaker 1:  To be fair. I don't know that anybody does, but I certainly don't think there's
Speaker 1:  any evidence that Apple does.
Speaker 7:  No, no, I agree with you. It it, it might not be there. This may just
Speaker 7:  be what the product is. Are they able to
Speaker 7:  iterate every year through hardware to make it a little bit better and a
Speaker 7:  little bit better and a little bit better? And are they able to do that better
Speaker 7:  than most other companies because of their iron grip on their
Speaker 7:  hardware supply chain and you know, their their deep
Speaker 7:  engineering team? Absolutely. Right. And that's what, that's what we saw
Speaker 7:  again, right. It's like little tweaks everywhere. Right. We're gonna
Speaker 7:  upgrade some of the cameras. We're gonna add a bunch of
Speaker 7:  flashy if confusing new camera features. I think I
Speaker 1:  Agree with all of that. And it, it actually leads me to the last question
Speaker 1:  that I have for you, which is that you are kind of famously an Android
Speaker 1:  guy in a, in a world full of iPhone people. That's actually
Speaker 1:  statistically not true at all. But it, it, it often feels that
Speaker 1:  way, at least among
Speaker 7:  The Verge Yeah. In the
Speaker 1:  Group chats. Is is there anything here that tempts you back to the, The
Speaker 1:  iPhone side of things? It's a little bit, we've seen kind of the, the swings
Speaker 1:  from these companies now are you, are you tempted towards an iPhone?
Speaker 7:  I mean the, the big thing for me is cameras, right? I I, I'm going to
Speaker 7:  go more or less where the best camera system is. And I, I
Speaker 7:  honestly for the past few years, I feel like it's been a wash. Right.
Speaker 7:  Went to the pixels a while ago. That's right. And I think you,
Speaker 7:  you could, I think by the time that you're pixel peeping to be like, well,
Speaker 7:  white balance. Alright.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. It's been a matter of taste as much as anything for, for a while
Speaker 1:  now.
Speaker 7:  Absolutely. Yeah. The cameras are getting better, right? The the new
Speaker 7:  telephoto, you know, we've only seen demo shots.
Speaker 7:  Of course they look gorgeous. That's how it always is. Yeah. But I'm intrigued.
Speaker 7:  They say the sensor's a lot bigger.
Speaker 7:  They are doing a bunch of, you know,
Speaker 7:  normal zooming enhancement instead of AI
Speaker 7:  zoom enhancement and hopefully it looks
Speaker 7:  good and is real. So, you know, I I think
Speaker 7:  some of the others are, are maybe not moving as fast in that department.
Speaker 7:  The front facing camera thing is, is weird and trippy, but
Speaker 7:  I'm interested, you know, it's, it's a big new sensor,
Speaker 7:  you know, it's, it's a, the redesign is, is nice. It looks nice.
Speaker 7:  I don't think like that's necessarily the reason to buy it.
Speaker 7:  But if you've got an old phone, you know, that's, that's
Speaker 7:  certainly a telling point that things have changed. I think for somebody
Speaker 7:  on Android or somebody who's been on Pixel, you know, it's these
Speaker 7:  iterative upgrades, right? It's the same story. Do I love the camera
Speaker 7:  control button? Do I love how it works with the new camera features?
Speaker 7:  Maybe. Maybe. We'll see.
Speaker 1:  It doesn't sound like you're tempted towards an iPhone. That was like a very
Speaker 1:  nice way of saying, nah, I'm good. I,
Speaker 7:  Listen, I don't think we have enough time for this, but I, I've got like
Speaker 7:  an hour long thing about notification management on iPhones. Oh
Speaker 7:  boy. Oh boy. It's not All right. It's not good,
Speaker 1:  Jake. If it wasn't 11:03 PM where I am, I would sign up
Speaker 1:  for that right now. But luckily you And I have a lot of podcasts to hosts
Speaker 1:  for do this fall. We do. So we're, we're gonna have some time to do this.
Speaker 1:  All right, for now. You need to go. I need to go.
Speaker 1:  I'm very glad you got to go to Cupertino. This is like, this is a fun thing.
Speaker 1:  You And I have been on opposite sides of this where you've been like telling
Speaker 1:  me what to do as I run around Cupertino a million times. So it was, it was
Speaker 1:  fun to get to watch you do the chaos all on your own.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. I have so much more sympathy for you now. I'm
Speaker 7:  I've, it's a weird day. I'm sorry for everything I've ever said.
Speaker 1:  It's a weird day and, and you're always like, you're always like, what are
Speaker 1:  they doing? And the answer is they're just sort of wandering aimlessly around
Speaker 1:  Apple Park trying to figure out where they are.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, exactly. It's
Speaker 1:  A life. All right, Jake, thank you Zoe. Good to see you buddy. Later.
Speaker 1:  All right, that's it for the show today. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 1:  on with me. It's pure chaos being in Cupertino for one of these events. So
Speaker 1:  please know it's a heroic effort to be on The Vergecast on Apple Day. And
Speaker 1:  as always, thank you for listening and watching. We're gonna talk a lot more
Speaker 1:  about Apple in the next couple of weeks. We're gonna test these devices.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna see what happens when people start to buy these devices. Our
Speaker 1:  new and old devices are gonna get a bunch of new software. Liquid Glass,
Speaker 1:  I think is gonna like, kind of blow some people's minds both in good and
Speaker 1:  bad ways. So we, we have a lot of Apple stuff to talk about. And if you have
Speaker 1:  questions or thoughts or spectacular ways you want us to destroy iPhone
Speaker 1:  airs, please tell us. Call the hotline, eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 1:  Send us an email Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Send us everything. We're
Speaker 1:  gonna do a lot of Apple stuff for the next couple of weeks, so buckle up.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be fun. Until then, we should get outta here. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Travis ak, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. Vergecast is The Verge production
Speaker 1:  and part of the Fox Media Podcast network. Like I said, we'll be back on
Speaker 1:  Friday. Jake And I are gonna talk more. Apple. I have a bunch of
Speaker 1:  just thoroughly hot takes that I have been desperate to say out loud,
Speaker 1:  so I'm going to potentially get myself canceled live on The Vergecast on
Speaker 1:  Friday. We'll see you then. Rock and roll