# Transcript
ID: 45055ed4-da06-47d1-a47e-5e57648087b6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6259229236207102074/-1352064839180583531/s93290-US-6239s-1746784984.mp3
Description: Where will Meta, Apple, and Google be three years from now? It's starting to look like they might all be very different. Nilay, David, and The Verge's Richard Lawler start the show with Eddy Cue's testimony in the Google search trial, in which Cue argued that AI is taking over — and that Google should be allowed to keep paying Apple gobs of money. The hosts also chat about the latest in the Meta trials, and how the recent Apple ruling is already changing the App Store. Then, there are some gadgets to talk about: the panopticon-slash-killer-app coming for Meta's smart glasses, the new Surface Pro and Surface Laptop, and a lot of new iPhones. In the lightning round, we do another round of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, then talk about some new Netflix designs and the latest in our worldwide hunt for party speakers.
Speaker 5:  I had this week.
Speaker 6:  This is your new claim to fame.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna talk about it vaguely remembered.
Speaker 6:  Is it better to be like very remembered
Speaker 6:  or not remembered? Like if you had to choose between
Speaker 6:  slightly, vaguely, barely remembered and not remembered at all. If he was
Speaker 6:  like, I have no memory of doing that podcast with Eli four years ago, is
Speaker 6:  that better or worse? Well, if you'd said Nelly
Speaker 5:  Patel, he'd know who you're talking about. Yeah, exactly. Eli, who's
Speaker 5:  that guy? You know, as a podcast host, I think what you want is, I remember
Speaker 5:  every minute of that experience and changed. I send it to everyone that I've
Speaker 5:  ever met and I'm like, this is my org chart. We're gonna get to it, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna explain what we're talking about. But It is true that literally today,
Speaker 5:  just hours before we are speaking adversary under
Speaker 5:  oath in the United States Justice system said he
Speaker 5:  vaguely remembered talking to me.
Speaker 6:  Congratulations.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's a, it's a weird life. I live, I'm your friend Eli. That's
Speaker 5:  David Pierce.
Speaker 6:  Hello,
Speaker 5:  Richard Lawlers here. Hey, buddy, I'm back. He's back
Speaker 5:  A lot going on this week. A lot of, a lot of courthouse activity.
Speaker 5:  There's a rumor, by the way, from CBC's, David Faber, that Warner Brothers
Speaker 5:  in Discovery will split up again, which is just the, the circle of life.
Speaker 5:  Like we're gonna, we're gonna play the Lion King song here.
Speaker 6:  They should call the companies Warner Discovery and just, bro,
Speaker 6:  those should be the two companies
Speaker 5:  I would join, bros. Yeah. Obviously I work for Bros Bro is the one. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  there's there's some facial recognition news in the AR world.
Speaker 5:  Brendan talked a lot this week.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, he was back with a vengeance.
Speaker 5:  Our boy, Brendan just did not shut up this week. We got, he
Speaker 6:  Didn't like that the segment was short last week, so he, he had to do some
Speaker 6:  stuff.
Speaker 5:  He didn't, he was like, well, I gotta, I gotta start running my mouth. We
Speaker 5:  have Gen Tui battling robot lawnmowers to the death. And
Speaker 5:  then finally Netflix took my advice. Just be, let's be direct
Speaker 5:  about what happened here. I told 'em to do something and they finally did
Speaker 5:  it. So a lot, a lot going on. Let's start, let's start
Speaker 5:  in court. Where else? My hot prediction is that 36 months from now,
Speaker 5:  we will not recognize Apple and Google.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's just my hottest prediction I've got going right now. Whatever
Speaker 5:  you think of as Google now, and whatever you think of It is Apple. Now, 36
Speaker 5:  months from now, these companies will be radically different in some way.
Speaker 6:  Interesting that you're not lumping Meta into that. Do you not think it also
Speaker 6:  qualifies?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. Okay. We'll, we'll come to that meta's also in our trial, but
Speaker 5:  like, if you peel Instagram in WhatsApp off of
Speaker 5:  Meta, like I, I think the essential character of Meta remains,
Speaker 5:  whereas, you know, what we're talking about with Apple is you're gonna, in
Speaker 5:  one trial, they're gonna take $20 billion of search revenue away from Apple.
Speaker 5:  In the other case, they can't make money in the app store the way they were.
Speaker 5:  They've appealed that decision. That just changes the company. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. And then in the Google case, the, just in 50 different ways, the
Speaker 5:  government might break up Google fundamental changes of the company. So
Speaker 5:  those are my hot predictions. I maybe they'll come true, maybe they won't,
Speaker 5:  that's why they're they're hot. But you really see that pressure
Speaker 5:  that these companies are feeling right now in court where their
Speaker 5:  various executives are on the stand talking about how their businesses work.
Speaker 5:  In particular in the Google search remedies trial. Eddie
Speaker 5:  Q is on the stand this week and he, I mean literally he, with just
Speaker 5:  a sideways comment, he dropped Google stock price by
Speaker 5:  10% or almost 10%. David, you've been paying
Speaker 5:  a lot of attention to the Google search case. You were in that courtroom
Speaker 5:  during the, the other part of the trial. What's going on here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so Apple's been a really important part of this trial the whole time
Speaker 6:  because like, it, it, the, the simplest version of this trial was about
Speaker 6:  Google became too powerful because it could afford to be the default search
Speaker 6:  engine essentially everywhere. And the most important and most
Speaker 6:  expensive version of that is Safari on iOS. So Apple was,
Speaker 6:  I mean like all over the, the liabilities part of this
Speaker 6:  trial. And a huge piece of this was essentially Google is the only company
Speaker 6:  that was able to give Apple $20 billion a year to be
Speaker 6:  the Safari search engine. Thus we have a problem. Like you, you can kind
Speaker 6:  of boil it all the way down to that. And that is, that is where we are. So
Speaker 6:  it was meaningful again, to see Eddie Q come back at all to talk about this
Speaker 6:  stuff. He talked to, he testified in the first version of the trial and now
Speaker 6:  he's back doing it again. And he made a surprising amount of
Speaker 6:  news for somebody who is like, very well media trained.
Speaker 6:  And I think the thing I've come to believe is the people like this who come
Speaker 6:  to testify largely come to do it on purpose. Right? And I think
Speaker 6:  Nila, you're, you're a lawyer, so you, you know this better than I do, but
Speaker 6:  I, there's like two ways it goes. There's either somebody asked them a
Speaker 6:  relatively open-ended question and they get to say the thing that they've
Speaker 6:  been preparing to say. And there was a lot of that. Like I was there for
Speaker 6:  Sundar Phai last time and he really wanted to talk about not letting people
Speaker 6:  reverse engineer Google. And he said that over and over whenever he was able
Speaker 6:  to. And then there are just times where you ask them yes or no questions
Speaker 6:  to get them to actually reveal things that they don't wanna reveal because
Speaker 6:  they're, and they have to, those are the two sides of how
Speaker 6:  you learn information in these trials is essentially what I've discovered
Speaker 6:  sitting in them. Yeah, this one, Eddie Cube just unprompted starts dropping
Speaker 6:  bombs about what's going on with Google search. So he's like,
Speaker 6:  he says, the biggest news, the one you're referring to is that Eddie Q said
Speaker 6:  by way of sort of explaining how transformative AI is
Speaker 6:  and why AI is so important and why it's becoming competitive to search. And
Speaker 6:  it's very clear obviously, that he would like to continue making $20 billion
Speaker 6:  a year from Google. So all of this under the guise of like Apple would
Speaker 6:  really like Google to win this trial so that it can keep giving Apple lots
Speaker 6:  of money. He says that for the first time
Speaker 6:  in, I believe 22 years was the number he gave ever. But in 22 years
Speaker 6:  of having this deal, Google searches are going down in
Speaker 6:  Safari
Speaker 6:  by some meaningful amount. And that's
Speaker 6:  the thing that tanked Google stock
Speaker 5:  Like instantly, like yeah, the line went down CNBC
Speaker 5:  like broke into coverage. Like Google stock is down because Eddie Q
Speaker 5:  said search volume is going down because of ai. Right.
Speaker 6:  And again, this, this is a search surface that is worth $20 billion
Speaker 6:  a year to Google. That's like that. It is such a core part of what makes
Speaker 6:  search work that any meaningful downtick is, is
Speaker 6:  a huge deal for Google. Eddie Q's thesis is this has to
Speaker 6:  do with ai. People are turning to the, the built in
Speaker 6:  Syrian chat GPT stuff to replace it. People are using perplexity to replace
Speaker 6:  it. People are using chat GPT search to replace it. Like
Speaker 6:  his theory is that instead of going to Safari and typing in the search box,
Speaker 6:  people are doing lots of different things. Google even actually I think in
Speaker 6:  a really interesting way, confirmed that. So Google immediately
Speaker 6:  comes out with a statement, lemme just read you the statement from
Speaker 6:  Google. It says, we continue to see overall query growth in search. That
Speaker 6:  includes an increase in total queries coming from Apple's devices and platforms
Speaker 6:  more generally. As we enhance search with new features, people are seeing
Speaker 6:  that Google search is more useful for more of their queries and they're accessing
Speaker 6:  it for new things in, in new ways. Whether from browsers or the Google app
Speaker 6:  using their voice or Google lens, all none of that
Speaker 6:  is a refutation of anything that Eddie Q said. Right? Like both of these
Speaker 6:  things can be true at the same time. But what is, what this
Speaker 6:  implies is that a lot of people are leaving Safari and
Speaker 6:  doing Google stuff elsewhere. And
Speaker 6:  I certainly believe that like the Google app is hugely popular and Google
Speaker 6:  has started pushing really, really, really, really hard to get you
Speaker 6:  in part because it's desperately afraid it's gonna lose this trial and not
Speaker 6:  be able to be the default in Safari anymore. And one thing that Edq said
Speaker 6:  in the first version of this trial was that one of the things Apple was afraid
Speaker 6:  of was that if they stopped doing this deal with Google, Google would use
Speaker 6:  all the other surfaces that it has to get people to do
Speaker 6:  things like download Chrome and download the Google app. They were afraid
Speaker 6:  that like every time you open YouTube, which is like an unassailably powerful
Speaker 6:  app on iOS, there would just be a big ass bar at the top that's like, wanna
Speaker 6:  use Google download Chrome?
Speaker 5:  Why use Google?
Speaker 6:  Or like whatever. Right? And that's, that's stuff is really important. Those
Speaker 6:  are like Google can do that kind of work and move
Speaker 6:  a lot of people wherever it wants and it doesn't do that because of
Speaker 6:  this deal. And so Eddie Q is sitting here being like, maybe
Speaker 6:  this is already shifting away from me and he wants to do everything he can
Speaker 6:  to protect this thing that is hugely lucrative
Speaker 6:  for Apple. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's a thing here that you, you mentioned it briefly at
Speaker 5:  the top, a Apple and EQ want to protect the
Speaker 5:  $20 billion, maybe even $25 billion
Speaker 5:  worth of revenue that they get for doing nothing,
Speaker 6:  Right? It's free money,
Speaker 5:  Right? They do literally nothing except set
Speaker 5:  Google search to be the default in Safari, which is the thing that
Speaker 5:  everybody wants to be the default in Safari and for doing
Speaker 5:  nothing except what everyone wants them to do for
Speaker 5:  zero effort. They received 20 to $25 billion a year
Speaker 5:  in revenue. And a DQ
Speaker 6:  Even kind of alluded to that where he was like, even if they didn't pay us,
Speaker 6:  we'd probably still have to do it because it's the thing that everybody wants.
Speaker 5:  And so if you're, you're Apple, you're like, well, that would go away. That's
Speaker 5:  just the freest money that's ever existed. And then the other big pot of
Speaker 5:  free money is in-app purchases and the Apple tax and all that stuff.
Speaker 5:  And they're under a court order, which they're appealing, which has
Speaker 5:  allowed Spotify and Amazon and other companies to say, you can just buy your
Speaker 5:  stuff on the web and you don't have to pay the tax. This is a big deal. Like
Speaker 5:  Apple's looking at the free money going away. And so I, yeah, I, I,
Speaker 5:  I see what Eddie is doing on the stand. He's, he's trying to
Speaker 5:  make this thing seem like it's already dying so the government
Speaker 5:  doesn't take it away. Right? And he's doing it in a framework that,
Speaker 5:  you know, antitrust regulators like will roll their eyes and be like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah, we know the monopoly lifecycle, right? The companies get too big
Speaker 5:  and they get too lazy. And then the disruptors come up and then the companies
Speaker 5:  go away. And on the stand, Eddie Q was like, look, when we
Speaker 5:  started Apple, you know, IBM was the big dog and now look at them, right?
Speaker 5:  And he's like, maybe one day we'll go away. Just leave us alone so we can
Speaker 5:  collect the $25 billion in free money until like, there's just a thing
Speaker 5:  like he's, he's doing like, you know, it's like what? Like the
Speaker 5:  archetypes and storytelling, like the hero's journey. But it's the monopoly
Speaker 5:  lifecycle, right? Like, we're gonna learn your lesson and come back stronger.
Speaker 5:  It's like we're all gonna die one day, leave us alone,
Speaker 6:  Right? Just let us die in peace with our $25 billion.
Speaker 5:  Just let us die rich man. I, I beg of you judge,
Speaker 5:  let me die a rich man. That's all I've ever wanted. I'm on the board of
Speaker 5:  Ferrari, Eddie Q's on the board of Ferrari. Why do you think Ferrari got
Speaker 5:  CarPlay? You know what I mean? Like, it's just very obvious why Ferrari was
Speaker 5:  one of the first, what's like Ferrari portion, Aston Martin got CarPlay first.
Speaker 5:  Like, you know, where Apple executives are spending their time.
Speaker 5:  But there's just a piece here where you're like, the other
Speaker 5:  side of that Apple wants to preserve this money, they're gonna make this
Speaker 5:  argument that they're already seeing the change. Like, you don't, don't worry
Speaker 5:  about this. The market's taking care of it. The thing that's really interesting
Speaker 5:  to me is how fast and furiously the stock
Speaker 5:  dropped. And there's a part of me that says Google
Speaker 5:  stock dropped. And the thing that's really, the thing that's really interesting
Speaker 5:  to me is just how fast and furiously Google stock dropped on a
Speaker 5:  pretty innocuous statement, right? Like what q fundamentally said
Speaker 5:  was the market's already shifting and like all of these big
Speaker 5:  search remedies you wanna do, they, they're not gonna matter. 'cause the
Speaker 5:  markets already taking care of this monopoly that you're so worried about
Speaker 5:  government. It is pretty innocuous, but the market dropped.
Speaker 5:  But the but the stock dropped because I think everyone is waiting for that
Speaker 5:  first piece of evidence that Google search is under threat.
Speaker 6:  Yes, that's exactly what I was gonna say,
Speaker 5:  Right? The first sliver of evidence that AI
Speaker 5:  will actually take search is like a
Speaker 5:  kind of death nail for Google. And
Speaker 6:  Until now it really has been all vibes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, all vibes. Like at the launch of Bing, Sasha Nadela told me
Speaker 5:  he's like, every point of market share I can take from Google is billions
Speaker 5:  of dollars. Like, I don't have to win. I just to peel off like two points
Speaker 5:  of market share. And this is a huge business for us and everyone's just been
Speaker 5:  waiting and it's like, well, Bing didn't do it.
Speaker 5:  Sorry guys. But like everyone was waiting for like, oh well Google
Speaker 5:  get dethroned. And even if you believe
Speaker 5:  Google's statement here, which I think is reason reasonable interpretation
Speaker 5:  of this is search volumes are dropping in Safari. 'cause Google's getting
Speaker 5:  people to use the Google search app, right? That's more or less what they're
Speaker 5:  saying, but maybe search volumes are dropping in Sari. 'cause everyone's
Speaker 5:  using Chacha PT instead who like, who truly knows Apple knows, but they
Speaker 5:  said Safari. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean, and realistically I think the answer is, is pretty clearly some of
Speaker 6:  each,
Speaker 6:  but it It is, It is certainly true that we
Speaker 6:  are finally slowly getting
Speaker 6:  real information that suggests that Google is fragile, right? And I think
Speaker 6:  part of that is also as this trial goes on, the people I talk to who are
Speaker 6:  watching the trial seem to be like day by day becoming
Speaker 6:  more and more convinced that something catastrophic is gonna happen to Google
Speaker 6:  at the end of this. That I think like going in the, the, the sort of overwhelming
Speaker 6:  betting favorite for the outcome was Google is going to
Speaker 6:  stop having to do these deals exclusively and is just gonna win on its merits,
Speaker 6:  right? That either it was just gonna get what it wanted, which is to just
Speaker 6:  remove the word exclusive from all of its deals and nothing else changed.
Speaker 6:  Or Judge Meadow is gonna be like, you can't pay money or you can't pay
Speaker 6:  money above a certain amount to be part of these deals. And that would, that
Speaker 6:  would have real ramifications, but it would still leave Google with a giant
Speaker 6:  advantage because it's Google. But now more and more there is this
Speaker 6:  sense that like, okay, something, some Google is going
Speaker 6:  to get punched in the face in one, at least one like seriously
Speaker 6:  lasting way. And then you pair that with, oh, and maybe
Speaker 6:  it doesn't even matter because maybe this thing is already starting to crack
Speaker 6:  in front of our eyes and that there's like, you just set off this incredible
Speaker 6:  panic about Google.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And again, the, the market reacted to what is a pretty
Speaker 5:  fundamentally innocuous comment. Yeah. Right. Searches
Speaker 5:  in Safari are falling for the first time ever. Like Apple is
Speaker 5:  obviously trying to protect the free money. So of course
Speaker 5:  it's saying that this thing you think is a problem is not a problem. Here's
Speaker 5:  a a tiny slice of evidence, right?
Speaker 6:  This thing you think is good actually sucks. Don't even worry about it.
Speaker 5:  It's fine. Yeah. This is like, whenever, whenever regulators go to big cable
Speaker 5:  companies, they're like, but we compete with everyone. Like how can, how
Speaker 5:  we, you can't possibly regulate us. Like there's a guy down the street with
Speaker 5:  a tin can and a dream and he's obviously our biggest competitor. And it's
Speaker 5:  like, what are you talking about? Like, that's this again,
Speaker 5:  but, you know, app Eddie said some other stuff. He said, they're looking
Speaker 5:  at adding perplexity in other search engines, AI powered search engines to
Speaker 5:  Safari. He, he made a lot of noise about
Speaker 5:  AI being a new user interface paradigm that might replace the iPhone entirely
Speaker 5:  in 10 years. I, I think that was, you know, to your point David,
Speaker 5:  like that was one of his canned lines. Like, there's
Speaker 5:  so much change happening. Why would you bother the market? Like e 10 years
Speaker 5:  from now, we'll all be wearing AI glasses and you won't even need an iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Like, right. Just let, let me die rich. And you
Speaker 5:  just look at all that, you're like, oh, there, he's trying to protect it.
Speaker 5:  But I think inadvertently he
Speaker 5:  validated some of people's biggest ideas about the change to come.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think It is important to remember his
Speaker 6:  upside and his incentive for what he should believe. Like It is good for
Speaker 6:  Apple to convince everyone for lots of reasons that AI is about to change
Speaker 6:  everything. And that suddenly this is all hugely competitive. And actually
Speaker 6:  maybe you should be more afraid of open AI than anybody. But the the other
Speaker 6:  thing that I really liked is that Eddie Q said all this stuff. He's like,
Speaker 6:  we're we're building it all. And then pressed, he said, and I quote to date,
Speaker 6:  they're just not good enough, which is the answer to why they're not doing
Speaker 6:  more AI stuff. And so he is like, AI is gonna change everything, but also
Speaker 6:  AI sucks. And It is like, welcome to the discourse about ai,
Speaker 6:  right? And it's like, I, you know what I'm tired of, and Richard, you and
Speaker 6:  I have talked about this before, the people who were like, well, this is
Speaker 6:  the worst it's ever gonna be, so just wait and AI is
Speaker 6:  gonna change. Like maybe it's sucks now, but this is the worst it's ever
Speaker 6:  gonna be. And I'm like, but that it's still so we agree. It's bad
Speaker 7:  That it's, it's a weird thing that you can get people to say that at first.
Speaker 7:  They'll, they'll talk only about how great It is, but then once they can't
Speaker 7:  talk about that, suddenly it changes and it's, oh well, what it will be and
Speaker 7:  what it could be. Right? And it's just like, what is going on? What is the
Speaker 7:  real discussion here? What is it right now? What, what can you say? And I
Speaker 7:  think it's notable, particularly because Apple is at least perceived as being
Speaker 7:  so far behind in ai. So there's a lot of questions about like, what
Speaker 7:  they can do there. And I, I feel like if they were really that
Speaker 7:  worried about how fast AI is changing, they would, his reaction would be
Speaker 7:  different. The things he would say on the stand would be different than what
Speaker 7:  he actually said. Well,
Speaker 5:  He, wait, he did say that the Google money prevented
Speaker 5:  Apple from building its own search engine. Like he straightforward, he was
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, that's, that's, we probably didn't do it 'cause we were just
Speaker 5:  getting this free money. But then he was like, but it would've been hard.
Speaker 5:  And like they're good at it. And it's like, yeah dude, you just wanted 20,
Speaker 5:  20 billion, billion dollars. Like, you shut up my house. And you're like,
Speaker 5:  if you would just keep eating the peanut butter you're already eating, we'll
Speaker 5:  give you $20 billion. I'd be like, all right. Yeah. I'm super not gonna start
Speaker 5:  a peanut butter factory at this point in time. Like, yep.
Speaker 7:  How much money did they, did they spend on the car that they never made?
Speaker 6:  I think 10 billion was the number we heard, wasn't it? So
Speaker 5:  Half, half a year worth of free Google money.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 7:  Know, but that, that is the world of ai.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well the actually, the, the funny thing about the AI not being
Speaker 5:  good enough yet, sure this is as bad as
Speaker 5:  it will ever be. We can all fine. But like there was a study this
Speaker 5:  week from IBM, which is essentially a consulting company
Speaker 5:  now trying to sell AI services branded as Watson and other people's AI services.
Speaker 5:  And in their own study about how much AI you need and you should buy from
Speaker 5:  IBM. They're like, in our survey of CEOs, only
Speaker 5:  25% of AI projects had returned on the investment.
Speaker 5:  And so one out of four, and then the rest of the answer is like, and the
Speaker 5:  CEOs were like, we're using too much stuff and it's not all well grade. And
Speaker 5:  it's like, yeah, this kind of sucks. It's like if you just, if in
Speaker 5:  2004 you just walked up to everyone, you're like, Bluetooth, now
Speaker 5:  you're just gonna use Bluetooth. And everyone's like, but these are giant,
Speaker 5:  like not all of us are real estate agents. We can't wear these headsets all
Speaker 5:  day. You know, I, I leased a three series and I've got this headset, but
Speaker 5:  that doesn't make me a real estate agent. You understand what I'm like, this
Speaker 5:  isn't right yet and you gotta wait 10 years for AirPods and
Speaker 5:  like that's still where we are. It's like, it'll be great next year.
Speaker 6:  No, but there, but it's, it's not even like that's the best case scenario.
Speaker 6:  The worst case scenario is like, we go and we tore a house
Speaker 6:  and it's not as big as I want it to be, but I'm standing in the kitchen.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, but think about it. This is the smallest this kitchen will ever
Speaker 6:  be. Like that doesn't, that's nothing that, that
Speaker 6:  I have, I have implied that something is going to get bigger or better and
Speaker 6:  just, and it doesn't matter that there's no evidence that it's gonna,
Speaker 7:  And I I think the way, the place that it's the most obvious to me is in the
Speaker 7:  AI trends, the AI mees that develop, like we saw what the action figures
Speaker 7:  and other things like that. You have these people who are paying for access
Speaker 7:  to AI tools. They have no idea what to do with them. And so they're like,
Speaker 7:  I can make an action figure of myself. Would, would that be evidence that
Speaker 7:  I'm paying for something that's useful? Anything that will work, okay, I'll,
Speaker 7:  I'll turn myself into a cartoon. Whatever I, I need to do something to
Speaker 7:  prove that I this investment was worth it.
Speaker 5:  Well I wanna make a distinction here. 'cause there's an entire class of
Speaker 5:  professionals that are using AI in different ways. A Figma this week
Speaker 5:  launched Figma sites and you can just make like beautiful
Speaker 5:  designed websites with ai. It's basically a site builder. Like you just tell
Speaker 5:  her what you want. It just like makes you a website with all kinds of animations.
Speaker 5:  And so yes, it's, it's cool. They have an a co-generation tool that they're
Speaker 5:  gonna launch soon. Obviously Cursor exists. We see the AI
Speaker 5:  usage in, in apps like Photoshop, which is basically it like a hundred percent
Speaker 5:  like usage rate. It's the same as layers, which is essentially a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent Yes. So there's like, and we have like lots of listeners
Speaker 5:  who are software developers who are like using this stuff all day long. There's
Speaker 5:  some value there. I think what we are focused on in this
Speaker 5:  conversation is the idea that AI search is
Speaker 5:  already a useful great product that can do everything You want that ag
Speaker 5:  agentic AI where you just tell Siri to get you a sandwich and it
Speaker 5:  can do it, or you can tell Alexa plus to exist
Speaker 5:  and it will be in your house. None of that stuff is real yet. Like
Speaker 5:  that is all pipe dreams, like truly pipe dreams.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's the gap. I I I think that gap is getting bigger
Speaker 5:  between what people say it can do or will do or one day will do.
Speaker 5:  And then the real things people are using it for now. And
Speaker 5:  IIII think it's important to validate like, yes, people use cursor
Speaker 5:  every day to great effect. Yeah. I use
Speaker 5:  generative noise reduction in Lightroom almost every time I
Speaker 5:  take a photo now. It, it's not even it, I think it should just be built into
Speaker 5:  the import workflow for me. It's really good. Like I'm, I'm like, why am
Speaker 5:  I pressing a second button? Like just put it, just do it here. There's all
Speaker 5:  this stuff that is good and that works. There's this other
Speaker 5:  piece. And even some of the generative AI tech stuff, like if you
Speaker 5:  sell something in eBay and you're just like, make me an item description,
Speaker 5:  fine, right? Like, it doesn't matter. But then there's this other
Speaker 5:  piece where you're like, 10 years from now you won't need an iPhone
Speaker 5:  because AI will be so good that you're just gonna be talking to your glasses.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, well, a lot of stuff has to go. Right, right.
Speaker 6:  My, my new shortcut for that is to just, every time you
Speaker 6:  see ai, just auto replace it with machine learning. And, and
Speaker 6:  in some places that makes perfect sense, right? Like a lot of the stuff you
Speaker 6:  just described, like Figma is doing this stuff and it, it's using
Speaker 6:  machine learning to do all kinds of interesting stuff for you. And this stuff
Speaker 6:  is like useful and valuable and it's a feature of the software. But then
Speaker 6:  anytime I hear somebody be like, yeah, I asked my machine learning what I
Speaker 6:  should and I'm like, oh, right, we're out. Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we used, we used to just call this algorithms and I think we all
Speaker 7:  understood what they were and it's still really good for those things when
Speaker 7:  they were like, oh yeah, you'll use the algorithms and it'll figure it out
Speaker 7:  if you know how to program those AI coding tools are really useful because
Speaker 7:  you know what they're doing and you know how to work around it, you know
Speaker 7:  how to, to fix it and whatever it's not good at, you can fill in for me.
Speaker 7:  I don't know how to program, if I tried to use an AI coding tool, you will
Speaker 7:  get something that does not work and I do not know how to fix it.
Speaker 5:  We should do Richard Lawler hackathon. We should, where we just demand that
Speaker 5:  you vibe code different kinds of apps and see what,
Speaker 7:  And they will, that's
Speaker 5:  10 Richard bring down NORAD by himself. Like let's find out today.
Speaker 6:  But just to, just to bring this back to Eddie QI think a, a thing that I'm
Speaker 6:  just realizing now as we're talking is that Apple is actually massively
Speaker 6:  incentivized to bring all of these things to
Speaker 6:  iOS as fast as it possibly can. Like Apple's case four, we
Speaker 6:  should keep getting Google's money gets stronger and easier once it
Speaker 6:  integrates perplexity. Like it's because they can be like, look, this stuff
Speaker 6:  is already being cannibalized. The change is already happening. So the fact
Speaker 6:  that Apple is saying this stuff is not good enough and is actively not doing
Speaker 6:  it, strikes me as an even more damning critique of this whole
Speaker 6:  thing. Because it would be much easier for EQ to get up and be like, the
Speaker 6:  Google deal doesn't matter that much because we, we already have a perplexity
Speaker 6:  deal and people are using that too. Like it could introduce the competition
Speaker 6:  if it wanted to and it doesn't because I think at some, somewhere in that
Speaker 6:  company are people who continue to make like making good products. Well
Speaker 5:  There's also a, a very interesting sort of like business flywheel
Speaker 5:  that I don't think the AI search companies have really solved yet. So
Speaker 5:  Google can spend $20 billion a year on Apple
Speaker 5:  to get the default placement. Then they collect all of the searches.
Speaker 5:  They show ads on those search pages, which are very good at making money
Speaker 5:  to the point where like the search pages are getting more useless. 'cause
Speaker 5:  they're just ads now. Yeah. So they collect all the data from the searches,
Speaker 5:  they monetize each individual search at varying rates and with increasing
Speaker 5:  amounts of like revenue aggression.
Speaker 5:  And then they've got all the search data, which helps make the search product
Speaker 5:  better and feeds all their other training efforts. And so they've just got
Speaker 5:  a lot of different ways to collect value for the $20 billion they spent.
Speaker 5:  Right? Perplexity is like, you do a search on
Speaker 5:  perplexity, it costs them a bunch of money, right? Like there's just a
Speaker 5:  bunch of GPUs that have to do some work and use a bunch of power and then
Speaker 5:  they're like, they don't make any money. I'm
Speaker 6:  Now mentioning Perplexities,
Speaker 5:  Right? They have a subscription fee and they make some revenue, but it's
Speaker 5:  not a lot of revenue and they're certainly not profitable. And it's like
Speaker 5:  if they paid Apple money to collect a bunch of searches which
Speaker 5:  cost them money, that's just a, that's just a black hole of money.
Speaker 5:  Like it, you're just spending money to lose money. And I, I don't know that
Speaker 5:  any of these companies can actually make that deal yet in a way that doesn't
Speaker 5:  just accelerate their own doom loop. Right? They'll, they'll just lose
Speaker 5:  money.
Speaker 6:  Right. Except for open ai, which has an infinite capability to keep raising
Speaker 6:  money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Then Sam Altman just has to go tour the capitals of the world. Again,
Speaker 5:  he was literally the United States Senate today I be like, what I need is
Speaker 5:  infinite money for nuclear power. And you know, Ted Cruz is
Speaker 5:  like you or tell me more. And it's like, how do you do this?
Speaker 5:  Teach me your ways, Sam. Seriously, but I, but that's a real problem for
Speaker 5:  Apple and I don't think it can get those deals yet from these companies.
Speaker 6:  Certainly not in the way that it, it has from Google,
Speaker 6:  Google capable of making those deals for
Speaker 6:  Gemini. And we heard Sundar Phai say that that
Speaker 6:  talks for a deal like that are underway and they were hoping to get it done
Speaker 6:  by the middle of this year. So like that's, there's a deal there somewhere
Speaker 6:  that makes more sense for Google just because it's Google and like you,
Speaker 6:  you see Google on its own side working towards that, right? Like there's,
Speaker 6:  there's AI mode in search. Now Gemini is starting to do search that it's
Speaker 6:  like you can start to see how they just pull piece by piece out of search
Speaker 6:  and into ai, integrate Gemini, move on with your life.
Speaker 6:  But I think you're right that like perplexity just can't pull that off, I
Speaker 6:  don't think.
Speaker 5:  Not yet until they figure out how to make money doing this stuff. I don't
Speaker 5:  think they can. Okay, so my hot prediction is 36 months from now
Speaker 5:  these companies do not look recognizably with the companies they're today.
Speaker 5:  What do you think Google, especially Richard,
Speaker 6:  What do you think?
Speaker 7:  I mean, what is left of Google? If if they, what? So
Speaker 7:  are we thinking that they lose Chrome or that they lose Android? Or both?
Speaker 5:  Maybe both. If they, you know, they've lost the ad tech case,
Speaker 5:  now they're onto the remedies phase, which starts in September. So that'll
Speaker 5:  wrap up. And for all we know, they're gonna have to sell their ad exchange
Speaker 5:  or they're gonna have to split off DFP, like something is gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  There was news there this week. Yeah. The the, the government once again
Speaker 6:  going for it, like we, we talked about there are three parts of the Google
Speaker 6:  ad tech stack. The government would like them to get rid of two of them.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And Google's counter proposal by the way, is what if we do nothing? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like actually it's fine. I
Speaker 5:  Dunno, just kidding. I can go home just lit up.
Speaker 7:  I can't even imagine Google without the infinite money spout that is their
Speaker 7:  ad tech sec. Like,
Speaker 5:  This is what I mean, 36 months from now, they lose this trial. They'll find
Speaker 5:  they'll appeal. They have already lost that trial. They're gonna go to Remedy,
Speaker 5:  something will happen and won't be nothing, which is what Google has once
Speaker 5:  again asked for. It'll be something they'll appeal that
Speaker 5:  it'll go up and down the chain. Something will result. That's why I'm, that's
Speaker 5:  why I'm giving myself three years, right? It's not the end of next year.
Speaker 5:  It's at the end of three years,
Speaker 6:  10 days ago I would've said even three years feels too short. But then
Speaker 6:  watching what has happened to Apple and how quickly these
Speaker 6:  policies have changed and how quickly the app store has changed and how hard
Speaker 6:  it will be to wind this back. Even if Apple does appeal and win on appeal,
Speaker 6:  like maybe three years is not that long a time. Like once, once this stuff
Speaker 6:  shifts, it shifts.
Speaker 5:  And again, this is part of the monopoly lifestyle like story.
Speaker 5:  Like these things are big and they seem invincible and then tomorrow they're
Speaker 5:  over.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there's a lot to be said for that, but the pressure right now is from
Speaker 5:  the government and a underrated part of the monopoly lifecycle
Speaker 5:  is the monopoly gets himself in trouble with the government, gets all distracted
Speaker 5:  and the then the challenger comes along and it has like free space. This
Speaker 5:  is very much what happened to Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. This is why Google and Apple exists the way they do because Microsoft
Speaker 5:  got distracted. So you have opportunities for like OpenAI and Perplexity
Speaker 5:  and whoever else. I'm just saying three years in three years,
Speaker 5:  I don't think these companies look recognizably like the companies we have
Speaker 5:  today, particularly Google. I'm not sure what's gonna happen with Apple,
Speaker 5:  but particularly Google. It just feels to me like
Speaker 5:  it's gonna look a lot different.
Speaker 6:  See, I would actually put Apple at the top of the rankings as I'm thinking
Speaker 6:  about this. Yeah. Because I think there is an overwhelming chance that
Speaker 6:  $20 billion goes away one way or another. It's not gonna
Speaker 6:  get out of this trial still being $20 billion. I just, I just don't, I can't
Speaker 6:  see a way knowing what we know now that that deal
Speaker 6:  at that number gets preserved. And then like you said, stick that
Speaker 6:  next to all of the stuff that's happening with the app store. Like the,
Speaker 6:  the, my Victory lap this week was I absolutely called that Amazon had a version
Speaker 6:  of the Kindle app sitting around waiting with links in it to the web store.
Speaker 6:  So you could buy a book in the Kindle app that's already out the
Speaker 6:  Patreon change things and now you can subscribe to Patreons through the web.
Speaker 6:  Like every app that has another way to bill you is starting to
Speaker 6:  bill you quickly outside of the, and like all that is just money that
Speaker 6:  Apple used to get for free that now it doesn't get for free. Well,
Speaker 5:  Wait, no, hold on. So John Gruber will be on to code on Monday,
Speaker 5:  so look forward to that. But I I, I made a similar point to him in that conversation
Speaker 5:  and what he reminded me of was you couldn't buy a book in the
Speaker 5:  Kindle app before. So it was not, it was money that Apple wasn't getting
Speaker 5:  anyway. Right. And so that's fair. I guess the first players are seeing are
Speaker 5:  Amazon, Spotify, Patreon, which
Speaker 5:  weren't paying the taxes.
Speaker 6:  Sure. But there's a, there's a massively long, like Candy Crush is
Speaker 6:  coming if it hasn't yet, I don't Yeah. Pay terrible attention to Candy Crush,
Speaker 6:  but like this is the move and now everybody has it. And
Speaker 6:  like you said, apple has both appealed the overall ruling and
Speaker 6:  appealed having to make this policy change ahead of the
Speaker 6:  appeal. So it's like the, the way It is now, apple has to had to
Speaker 6:  comply immediately and then appeal. And it's saying, no,
Speaker 6:  this thing you're asking us to do is so horrible and unconscionable that
Speaker 6:  we can't be asked to do it until the appeal is over again,
Speaker 6:  not a lawyer seems like they're probably gonna lose that one based on
Speaker 6:  what we know of how everybody feels about this case. But
Speaker 6:  it, it's just happening so fast that at some point, like Apple
Speaker 6:  is going to have to decide to individually pick a fight with every important
Speaker 6:  developer on its store
Speaker 6:  or the toothpaste is just out of the tube here and,
Speaker 6:  and once it's out, it's out. Right? Like the people aren't gonna wind back
Speaker 6:  to happily paying Apple 30% if they don't have to.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There, there's a bill, it's a, it's a kind of a fake bill
Speaker 5:  in the way that some of these bills are just fake. Like they're opportunistic
Speaker 5:  bills from Congress, people who just wanna like be a part of the good fight.
Speaker 5:  But there's a bill this week in the Congress that would
Speaker 5:  require Apple to have alternative app stores require Google to have alternative
Speaker 5:  app stores on their platforms. And so you just see, oh, the pressure's mounting
Speaker 5:  the political will, especially once people can see it, oh, I was able to
Speaker 5:  buy a book in the Kindle app and then Apple took it away. It's a
Speaker 5:  very hard to convince people of something they can't see and feel. It is
Speaker 5:  very easy to convince people that taking something away is bad.
Speaker 6:  Speaking of John Gruber, he, he wrote a good piece about that this week that
Speaker 6:  you, It is one of those things that you open up the Kindle app, you tap the
Speaker 6:  link to go get a book and immediately your brain goes, oh my God, it's insane
Speaker 6:  that it was not like this the whole time. Like It is so unbelievably
Speaker 6:  user hostile that you, you couldn't even, there was no way
Speaker 6:  to even go get the book. You had to go to a different app and type the name
Speaker 6:  of the book it like insanity. And the minute you see how it's
Speaker 6:  supposed to work, the minute you realize this is just because Apple hates
Speaker 6:  you. That's the only like, and and I think you're right that there, it's,
Speaker 6:  there's no going back from that.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So answer my question, Richard, 36 months from now, do
Speaker 5:  you think it looks the same or do you think it looks unrecognizably different
Speaker 5:  or some, I guess somewhere in between.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna take the field. I think that it still looks the same,
Speaker 7:  but the e like the ecosystem has changed and now Apple and Google are throwing
Speaker 7:  haymakers at each other.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  That's a good take.
Speaker 5:  All right, David,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna sort of throw in with Richard, which is, I think, I
Speaker 6:  think these companies stay recognizable but
Speaker 6:  are so vastly less powerful that other stuff
Speaker 6:  bubbles up. Like I thing I'm starting to hear is everyone on Earth now is
Speaker 6:  building a browser because they understand the browser is very important
Speaker 6:  in new ways, in part because of this trial and ev and
Speaker 6:  like, they also see that maybe whatever's gonna happen to Chrome is going
Speaker 6:  to open up the browser market in a meaningful way. Again, we've been hearing
Speaker 6:  all these AI companies are building a browser like that
Speaker 6:  is going to march into every single one of these markets, right? Like the,
Speaker 6:  the market for being a payment processor on the internet is more interesting
Speaker 6:  than it's been in an extremely long time because now suddenly these things
Speaker 6:  are open to all of those things. So like, I think it's
Speaker 6:  less that like to some extent the big companies are gonna be like pulled
Speaker 6:  down a little bit, but also like the tide under them is gonna come up much
Speaker 6:  higher than it has been able to in a long time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know, there's other pieces of the search remedies case this week
Speaker 5:  beyond Eddie Q right? The, the head of search said
Speaker 5:  these proposed changes would totally undermine trust in Google and search
Speaker 5:  if you let everyone have access to the Google search graph, right? And basically
Speaker 5:  everyone can read all the searches that are happening, everyone can get access
Speaker 5:  to our search results and repackage them. Like maybe people will just stop
Speaker 5:  searching tru using search. And you know, the quote Google has used for years
Speaker 5:  is people ask Google questions that are so intimate they won't even say them
Speaker 5:  out loud. Right? And so you break that, you're gonna break search altogether.
Speaker 6:  And what the DOJ keeps saying to that, by the way, is do you think you're
Speaker 6:  the only company on earth that can protect user privacy? And Google
Speaker 6:  continues to say no. Like again, on its face, that's not a
Speaker 6:  crazy thing to say, right? Like we, we, we make a lot of fun of companies
Speaker 6:  who don't have a better defense who just scream privacy and security that,
Speaker 6:  that that's a shortcut for I don't actually have a good reason, but,
Speaker 6:  but in this case, like there, there is some truth to it, right? Like if you
Speaker 6:  think about the stuff you have put into the Google search box, you, you can,
Speaker 6:  you can tell everything about a person from what they Google in, in ways
Speaker 6:  that are potentially very scary. But It is also true that Google is not the
Speaker 6:  only company on earth capable of being a good steward of that information.
Speaker 5:  I also think It is now increasingly clear that people are
Speaker 5:  asking wildly intimate questions to chat GPT.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Right. Even more so,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Even more like incredible. I mean, it's trying to get Kevin Ru to break
Speaker 5:  up with his wife, man, and he's, he's talking about the front page of the
Speaker 5:  New York Times. People
Speaker 7:  Weren't just uploading their entire medical history into Google
Speaker 7:  in the little search box. Like that wasn't happening
Speaker 5:  Before you make this a podcast.
Speaker 5:  Like there's, it's obvious that something else is happening, but Right. But
Speaker 5:  that's, that would be something that really changes the dynamic of the web.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Firefox basically said we'd be doomed if Google didn't pay us the money.
Speaker 5:  Which our friend Casey Newton keeps pointing out like, that's your
Speaker 5:  fault, bro. Right? Like, you've built your entire business
Speaker 5:  is your competitor to Chrome on the back of a Google search deal. Like
Speaker 5:  have you thought about, okay, but that Firefox has,
Speaker 6:  Mozilla has been through like several CEOs and a decade knowing
Speaker 6:  this is the problem and utterly failing to figure out what to do about it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're like, we're gonna do NFTs.
Speaker 6:  It's hard to have that much sympathy at some point. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's it's tough. I I'm, I'm always rooting for them, you know, like they're
Speaker 5:  be open source champions. Yeah. But you know, they took the, the side
Speaker 5:  quest and the NFTs and it was like, oh, you, we are totally out of ideas.
Speaker 5:  And then right, then there's the ad tech stuff. So I just like, I look at
Speaker 5:  this and I'm like, part I, I would re-rank them, David, I would say Google.
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. 36 months from now, it's revenue looks different.
Speaker 5:  It it's gonna have to build other businesses.
Speaker 6:  Maybe it's gonna go up 'cause it doesn't have to give Apple $20 billion.
Speaker 5:  Maybe there's that, but maybe, maybe. But like right now, and you have
Speaker 5:  written about this many, many times, every business at Google
Speaker 5:  looks tiny next to search. Yes. So they don't invest in them.
Speaker 5:  Right. You're like, what? We'll move the needle at Google and you're like
Speaker 5:  a business as big as search and everyone's like, well, we don't
Speaker 5:  have any of those ideas. Right. It's just
Speaker 6:  Like, right. And then eventually if you get big enough, you build a business
Speaker 6:  that by accident runs into search and then you die. Yep. Because search will
Speaker 6:  kill you.
Speaker 5:  And the only things that have survived are things that like help search in
Speaker 5:  like meaningful ways. Android survives because It is a surface for search.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And that's why they did it YouTube, you did not want to concede that
Speaker 5:  user base to Microsoft at that time. Right. Okay. But it means that
Speaker 5:  like how many times have we talked about the pixel and are they gonna truly
Speaker 5:  invest in the Pixel and like the pixel is there to keep Samsung honest and
Speaker 5:  that is about it. Yeah. It's, it's not there to be a big winner of a product
Speaker 5:  because they don't care as long as people are searching Google on Samsung
Speaker 5:  phones. Right. Well, maybe if the search business starts to
Speaker 5:  wither, like those priorities shift and Google has to invest
Speaker 5:  in its other businesses and grow that maybe be more diversified. This is
Speaker 5:  what happened to Microsoft by the way. Windows came under significant pressure.
Speaker 5:  Sachi Nadel was like, all right, we're just gonna do Azure until I figure
Speaker 5:  something else out. And then he started rebuilding each of those businesses
Speaker 5:  in turn and he pulled it off. He's very, he was very good at what he did.
Speaker 5:  He pulled, he pulled it off at Microsoft. Vastly more boring now than it
Speaker 5:  was before. Sure. But like, he pulled it off. I
Speaker 5:  I think Google is gonna undergo that kind of transformation. I think Apple
Speaker 5:  looks different because the sense that something is gonna come
Speaker 5:  after the iPhone will continue to panic that company.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Right now they're saying it out loud. Something is gonna come after the iPhone
Speaker 5:  and they think the user interface will probably be voice in ai.
Speaker 5:  Well, that means we're just in, we're in for it. Right. Right. That is a,
Speaker 5:  that is a company in a defensive posture, not an offensive posture. And I,
Speaker 6:  Well, and a company that is for whatever reason,
Speaker 6:  completely unable to compete in a meaningful way on those
Speaker 6:  things. Like if you're, if you're sitting around being like, okay, if, if
Speaker 6:  we agree that AI is the thing, who's gonna win apple's? Not
Speaker 6:  in the first five companies, you would name It is the biggest company on
Speaker 6:  earth. And it wouldn't, you wouldn't bet on Apple as a, as a powerhouse
Speaker 6:  to solve ai. As AI gets really good, which is where I think Google has a
Speaker 6:  real shot. Right. And this is another thing that keeps coming up in the remedies
Speaker 6:  cases. Google is out there trying to do, again in AI what it
Speaker 6:  already did in search based on the premise that Google
Speaker 6:  has the resources to be a winner in ai. And I think that's true. I don't
Speaker 6:  think it'll be the only winner. I think there are going to be lots of winners.
Speaker 6:  As we saw Sam Waltman open AI acknowledged this week. They went, they like
Speaker 6:  bailed on the whole for-profit idea and are just back to being like, nevermind,
Speaker 6:  we thought we were gonna win so spectacularly, but now we're not. And just
Speaker 6:  kidding.
Speaker 6:  But you look at all of that and it's like, okay, Google has a real shot at
Speaker 6:  this, but Apple is gonna have to go undergo like a complete
Speaker 6:  culture and organizational shift in order to
Speaker 6:  be the kind of AI company that It is going to need to be if AI is going to
Speaker 6:  win.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I feel like I'm obligated by law right now to tell everyone
Speaker 5:  that the t in chat, BT stands for transformer, which is invented at Google
Speaker 5:  if you don't mention this every so often, a Google PR person like leaps out
Speaker 5:  of a bush. That's true. And brandishes that fact at you, right? They,
Speaker 5:  they invented a bunch of the core technology and they know how to deploy
Speaker 5:  it. Sundar has said many times, like, they know how to make it cheaper and
Speaker 5:  more energy efficient. He's like, that's what we're good at. So like
Speaker 5:  you can, you can believe that Google will just do its core competency. They've
Speaker 5:  also, to their credit, done the hard restructure. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. They, they got rid of Google Brain, they exited some
Speaker 5:  executives, they put Demis in charge of everything.
Speaker 5:  Okay. You can, you can see that they've undergone some changes to make the
Speaker 5:  move. But now the, the big thing is
Speaker 5:  under the pressure, and I don't know, apple hasn't undergone
Speaker 5:  any changes, right? They're like, this guy's gone, but here's another executive
Speaker 5:  who's been here for 40 years. You're in charge now. Right?
Speaker 6:  And for a company like Eddie DQ gets on stage and or gets on stage. Eddie
Speaker 6:  DQ gets on the stand and is talking about, like,
Speaker 5:  It really is a few good men. Like he just starts vamping, you know, like
Speaker 5:  Jack Nicholson, like just improving the lines in poor Tom Cruise,
Speaker 5:  just sitting there smiling, be like, I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 6:  Eddie, Eddie Q would really like that comparison. But Eddie Q gets on the
Speaker 6:  stand and talks about Apple's thing being cannibalizing its projects
Speaker 6:  before they're dead. Right? Like the iPhone exists because they cannibalize
Speaker 6:  the I or the iPod and everybody told them they were nuts to do so, but then
Speaker 6:  they got the iPhone. Apple's not doing that now. Like, there is none
Speaker 6:  of that left in what we see from Apple anymore. And it, it,
Speaker 6:  that posture just does not exist. It is kicking and screaming at
Speaker 6:  every one of these changes.
Speaker 5:  By the way, I just searched it on Google. I use Google for what it's intended
Speaker 5:  for. And It is in fact true that Jack Nicholson improvises the line. You
Speaker 5:  can't handle the truth in, if you go, Ben,
Speaker 6:  That's cool.
Speaker 5:  And, and Tom Cruise just had to, he just had to be like,
Speaker 5:  okay, nice. Let's keep this baby going. And I'm
Speaker 5:  Eddie, I dunno if you're listening, if you end up on the stand again
Speaker 5:  in this case, I encourage you to scream at the United States
Speaker 5:  Department of Justice. You can't handle the truth.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely, yes.
Speaker 5:  All right. We gotta take a break. Let's all breathe. You, you write
Speaker 5:  us, tell us what you think is gonna happen 36 months from now. Do these companies
Speaker 5:  look the same or different? I'm, I'm, you know, you know what I think, but
Speaker 5:  I'm curious what you all think.
Speaker 6:  May, 2028 predict what the world's gonna look like. Good luck everybody.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna come back and we're gonna spend a little more time in a courtroom
Speaker 5:  with Meta. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Look, I wanna leave the policy
Speaker 5:  talk and the legal talk by always doing a pallet conser with gadgets. And
Speaker 5:  we're gonna do that, I promise we're gonna do that. But we can't leave court
Speaker 5:  just yet because Richard Adam ary,
Speaker 5:  he was on fire today just, just chopping it up
Speaker 5:  in our nation's capitol. What, what, what happened in this case?
Speaker 7:  He had a lot to say when he came on the stand today. We've heard a lot about
Speaker 7:  Instagram. We've heard about reels, we've heard about threads. I mean,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, I don't know if he's explained why they haven't launched an
Speaker 7:  iPad app yet, but I'm sure he'll get to it at some point. You know, we're,
Speaker 7:  we're still recording this as, as he's talking, he
Speaker 5:  Said they're going to, like a couple weeks ago he said Instagram's gonna
Speaker 5:  do an iPad app. Yeah, I don't, I don't believe it until he says it under
Speaker 5:  oath.
Speaker 7:  Probably because he knew this testimony was coming and how he would be today.
Speaker 7:  That is what it was. 'cause I've been wondering why would, why now, why,
Speaker 7:  why is that happening? It's this because he talked about everything. He talked
Speaker 7:  about Facebook deciding to buy Instagram in 2012, which he called one of
Speaker 7:  the best acquisitions of all time. He said that Threads was originally supposed
Speaker 7:  to live within the Instagram app, which is kind of weird to think about.
Speaker 7:  But the way that they're linked, I can certainly see how they would've had
Speaker 7:  that idea. And also when you look at, for example, how YouTube
Speaker 7:  has done the posts in YouTube that these apps don't necessarily think about
Speaker 7:  bringing things out. But, but then they kind of realized that if you're gonna
Speaker 7:  take on Twitter, you need to have a dedicated app. So, so that makes a lot
Speaker 7:  of sense. I think also he, he said that one of the biggest mistakes he made
Speaker 7:  was the first version of reels that, that to me was just,
Speaker 7:  I'm not sure if the current version of reels is not still one of the big,
Speaker 7:  biggest mistakes. Yeah. But I did think it was interesting that he said
Speaker 6:  All the subsequent ones
Speaker 5:  Also. Well, the first version of Reels was built on stories, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so he was like, you're gonna open a story and you're gonna swipe through
Speaker 5:  stories the way that you're swiping through reels now. And he is like, no,
Speaker 5:  that's not what people wanna do. They just want TikTok. So they copied TikTok,
Speaker 7:  Copy Snapchat, copy TikTok, move on. And that is the metal way.
Speaker 7:  As, as we've seen, they said that they, Instagram has spent up to $700 million
Speaker 7:  a year to lure creators. So they're bringing in a lot of money. They're spending
Speaker 7:  a lot of money on Instagram.
Speaker 7:  Just, just so, so many different things. I I, I was
Speaker 7:  surprised that he said so much. But also the way that er has been lately
Speaker 7:  as It is open, as he is been as frequently posting, is constantly talking
Speaker 7:  to the people about algorithms and Instagram and, and what they think. I'm
Speaker 7:  not really that surprised to see that, that he just has so much to say.
Speaker 7:  Now,
Speaker 5:  You know, I've briefly talked to Adam about his
Speaker 5:  posts and like what he does, and he, he always, he, he makes two points in
Speaker 5:  general. He, I think he's even said this publicly, he's like, one,
Speaker 5:  my audience for this is so small. Like, I just want creators. Like they have
Speaker 5:  a lot of questions they should hear from me. And then his point is, I want
Speaker 5:  to use the tools, right? Like he, he's like, I wanna feel what it's like
Speaker 5:  on that side of the screen, not just as a consumer Instagram. So I, I always
Speaker 5:  think it's like people overread why he's doing it. Like
Speaker 5:  90% of Myer's Instagram posts are like, no, we're not listening
Speaker 5:  to you. You know, very basic stuff. Like the algorithm is not punishing you
Speaker 5:  if you use the letter Q in your caption. Like it's just him
Speaker 5:  debunking conspiracy theories and then almost all of them boil down to, and
Speaker 5:  you should post more, like the most basic stuff. But I, the part where he
Speaker 5:  is like, I wanna use the tools. I think It is really interesting, but he
Speaker 5:  doesn't get off. You can't knock. He's as good as it gets, right? You
Speaker 5:  can't knock him off his game. And it felt to me, I mean, this is
Speaker 5:  the case where the government is trying to prove that Meta bought
Speaker 5:  Instagram to foreclose a competitor. And Adam's point was
Speaker 5:  to push Meta's argument that Instagram would've never been
Speaker 5:  successful without Meta. Right. That all by itself, it would've
Speaker 5:  never developed the way it was. That Meta really turbocharged it.
Speaker 5:  I think he made some of those points. And then I
Speaker 5:  think, you know, as all these go, like I think he oversold the idea that
Speaker 5:  they're under existential threat from small competitors all the time. David,
Speaker 5:  what do you think? I,
Speaker 6:  I think that's right. He went way out of his way to talk about how
Speaker 6:  big a competitor TikTok is, which is, we, we've talked about this before,
Speaker 6:  but this has become meta's sort of hobby horse in this trial is
Speaker 6:  the very existence of TikTok suggests Meta cannot possibly be a
Speaker 6:  monopoly, which in a certain way is actually a very compelling argument.
Speaker 6:  But what it has done and did, again to Miss Air is just make a
Speaker 6:  bunch of Instagram executives admit that they're not doing a very good job,
Speaker 6:  which I really enjoy. And so like over and over and over again, they just
Speaker 6:  keep apologizing for all of the ways that they're losing to TikTok. And I
Speaker 6:  just find, I find that to be so very funny. And, and
Speaker 6:  again, like the all this money, like you're talking about Richard, the $700 million
Speaker 6:  to lure creators, like
Speaker 6:  how, how, where is that money going? Like YouTube
Speaker 6:  just pays ad revenue. There are creator funds
Speaker 6:  and there are this stuff, but like Instagram is spending a huge amount of
Speaker 6:  money in these sort of unknowable ways trying to get creators
Speaker 6:  off of those other platforms and onto Instagram. I find that really fascinating.
Speaker 6:  But
Speaker 6:  even just listening to Myer talk about it, like I, I find
Speaker 6:  myself wondering a lot if Instagram knows what Instagram
Speaker 6:  is, and this kind of goes back neli to your point about wanting
Speaker 6:  to use the tools. Like Adam Terry also made a video
Speaker 6:  I think today about, oh no, sorry, this was
Speaker 6:  months ago now that, but it came resurfaced today about how
Speaker 6:  he wanted Instagram to not be a lean back experience.
Speaker 6:  And it's like this thing is supposed to be an interactive and social and
Speaker 6:  like a place you hang out. And that was like, one of their big things with
Speaker 6:  threads was the reason they pulled it out into its own app was because they
Speaker 6:  wanted replies and posts to be on the same level with each other. And so,
Speaker 6:  like they have this idea that it's a social network and like, I don't know
Speaker 6:  anyone who experiences Instagram that way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean that's why they're spending the money in creators, right? Right.
Speaker 5:  Instagram sees creators as a good source of content after many rank and file
Speaker 5:  users began posting fewer of their own updates. That's why they spend the
Speaker 5:  money. That's from the, that's from the testimony today.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And just, just come out and be like, Hey, we're a, we're a streaming
Speaker 6:  service. Like, it's fine. It's, I I just, I don't know. We, I, we've gotten
Speaker 6:  to this point now where I think Meta as a company, it
Speaker 6:  continues to be obsessed with this idea that like, we can get back to friends,
Speaker 6:  sharing with friends. And it hasn't been that in a very, very, very
Speaker 6:  long time.
Speaker 5:  I, I think that's what they say. I think internally
Speaker 5:  they all know this is why they spend $700 million a year on me. I fair
Speaker 5:  creators from TikTok. Like, this is why they're fine with spaghetti Jesus
Speaker 5:  in the feeds. It just doesn't matter to them. Right. And I, I, I
Speaker 5:  think, you know, mark posting on Facebook or Adam posting on Instagram, like
Speaker 5:  they're using the tools. I actually really appreciate they use the tools.
Speaker 5:  I think not enough executives use the tools except for Tim Cook claiming,
Speaker 5:  I believe the GQ that he uses every single Apple product every day,
Speaker 5:  which I don't, there are not enough minutes in the day. But
Speaker 6:  Do you remember all those, all the times during like the, the Twitter years
Speaker 6:  where people would keep track of how many tweets the various like executives
Speaker 6:  and board members had? Yeah, I think, I think like, I think you're right.
Speaker 6:  I think it, it's, it's useful and correct to see
Speaker 6:  executives be part of this.
Speaker 5:  I think Mark and Adam are warped because they have, it doesn't matter,
Speaker 5:  right? There's just like millions of people will just respond to everything
Speaker 5:  they do. I Adam want really wanted to experience Instagram. He would start
Speaker 5:  a meme page from scratch po as a college student and try to go viral
Speaker 5:  every day because that is actually the experience the creators of Instagram
Speaker 5:  are having, right? This like desperate need for algorithmic validation,
Speaker 5:  right? If Adam really wanted to experience Instagram, he would
Speaker 5:  download a Netflix video, downloader speed everything up 15%, add
Speaker 5:  that weird vertical line and begin posting copies clips of a few Good men
Speaker 5:  to Instagram every day.
Speaker 6:  You just broke Richard A. Little.
Speaker 5:  Do you see what I'm saying? That's the real experience of Instagram, right?
Speaker 5:  Free booting memes from X and being like, here's the difference between
Speaker 5:  men and women. Like
Speaker 5:  that's the experience of Instagram and that's what
Speaker 5:  many, many creators experience like being an Instagram creator
Speaker 5:  is choosing between the dark path of
Speaker 5:  just free booting memes or doing those ai baby podcasts for like Theo v's
Speaker 5:  a baby that's all over the place, right? And it's outta control like every
Speaker 5:  other clip of my feed. And it's just like, can I just say I love this force
Speaker 5:  fed to me,
Speaker 6:  I am like I am, I am sort of constitutionally against AI generated
Speaker 6:  content in my feed and baby podcasts are very much for me.
Speaker 5:  That's very funny. Please don't do it to us or do it to us and don't share
Speaker 5:  with anyone but us. You see what I'm saying? That's like one path, which
Speaker 5:  is the dark, dark side. There's the slightly less dark path
Speaker 5:  of like be a Gary Vayner, Chuck Hussle bro, where he
Speaker 5:  just screams at you about your content not being good enough. And the algorithm
Speaker 5:  is just people and just make great shit. And like, that's the path I've chosen
Speaker 5:  personally. And then there's like everybody else being like, I just want
Speaker 5:  more views. And it's like, well, you're not, you're not hustling hard enough.
Speaker 5:  Right? And none of that is, I made a nice video update
Speaker 5:  about changes to the algorithm. We got a million views just 'cause I'm Madary,
Speaker 5:  Right? Like you're, you're you're still having a synthetic experience on
Speaker 5:  their own platforms. And I, I look at all this and it's like
Speaker 5:  the, the thesis of this case is they
Speaker 5:  saw a competitor and they bought it because they were afraid,
Speaker 5:  right? And you can argue at the markets and me we and all this stuff, but
Speaker 5:  like that's the real case is look at how bad these emails were.
Speaker 5:  They saw a competitor and they wanted to crush it. And I, I don't know if
Speaker 5:  they realize that what they're doing right now is making
Speaker 5:  the case very strongly that if they could have bought TikTok and crushed
Speaker 5:  it, they would've, 'cause they obviously saw this competitor and they
Speaker 5:  weren't allowed to buy it. So they had to compete and like, look at
Speaker 5:  all this evidence of all this stuff they're doing to compete with TikTok
Speaker 5:  that they didn't have to do 'cause they bought Instagram.
Speaker 5:  And like, would, wouldn't that have been better? Right? And I, I
Speaker 5:  don't know if that has been tied together correctly. I know the government
Speaker 5:  will get there, but it, it's just like we're kind of,
Speaker 5:  you're kind of proving the point a little bit. Like look at how hard we're
Speaker 5:  competing with TikTok. It is like, yeah, look at how hard Meta did not have
Speaker 5:  to compete. Look at how hard Facebook did not have to compete with Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Look at how hard Facebook didn't have to compete with WhatsApp. That's
Speaker 5:  the, that's the case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And the messaging stuff I think has been in some ways even more
Speaker 6:  damning. Like you talk about just what's in their emails.
Speaker 6:  Facebook was petrified of what was happening as people were moving to messaging
Speaker 6:  and understood that that was the next place people were gonna go to actually
Speaker 6:  talk to friends and family. And it has just come up over and over. Like they
Speaker 6:  just keep showing emails where one Facebook executive or another is like,
Speaker 6:  if we don't buy a messaging service, everyone will die because all
Speaker 6:  of our, everyone's friends are leaving. And then they're like, ah, we didn't
Speaker 6:  really think WhatsApp was gonna make any money. And it's like, well is that,
Speaker 6:  are those not the same thing?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's a weird thing. And it does, it really does feel like everyone is
Speaker 6:  actually kind of saying the same thing with really different words. And it's,
Speaker 6:  to your point, not super clear who is going to be the one to
Speaker 6:  try to like make something cogent out of all of this.
Speaker 5:  So there's another turn of this Harry's testimony today where he
Speaker 5:  talked about trying to integrate the teams and it eventually
Speaker 5:  got to the point where he was like, the Instagram team was too
Speaker 5:  spiky and too weird and I had to reel them in and I didn't do that first.
Speaker 5:  And then he, he just dunked on me a little bit, which was super great. The,
Speaker 5:  the Federal Trade Commission in court, their lawyers played
Speaker 5:  erry, his own interview on decoder. They played him a clip
Speaker 5:  from Decoder and they prefaced it by saying, do you remember this conversation
Speaker 5:  with Eli? And Adam said, I vaguely remember speaking to Eli.
Speaker 5:  Congrats. Super great. Yeah, I love you too Adam. I vaguely remember our
Speaker 5:  conversations as well, but the clip is really interesting. They,
Speaker 5:  they played in the, well should we run the clip? We don't have it, but let's
Speaker 5:  pretend I'll read it to you and we can actually run the clips.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we can play the clip.
Speaker 5:  So Clip is really interesting because, you know, decoder is an org chart
Speaker 5:  show, right? Where asked like, well how do you structure the company? And
Speaker 5:  so I asked him how Instagram was structured and how he'd integrated more
Speaker 5:  into Facebook over time. And this is, if you'll recall,
Speaker 5:  2021 is this conversation. It is, Facebook is trying to tie
Speaker 5:  everything more tightly together because it sees this antitrust stuff coming.
Speaker 5:  And if you'll recall, 2021, this is when Donald Trump had been
Speaker 5:  banned after from all the platforms after
Speaker 5:  January 6th, after all the elections. Like just bad, just
Speaker 5:  bad stuff all the way around.
Speaker 6:  Didn't this interview run with like a super spicy headline?
Speaker 5:  The, the headline of the interview on our site was Adversary says Banning
Speaker 5:  Donald Trump was the right thing to do. It's, and the Donald Trump FTC just
Speaker 5:  played a clip of that interview to Sary in the courthouse. But they
Speaker 5:  used, I think the Apple Podcast headline is like much softer.
Speaker 5:  So they showed that screenshot instead of the one on our site, which is
Speaker 5:  very funny. So he said,
Speaker 5:  I told every, when I took over Instagram, I told everyone I was gonna be
Speaker 5:  a sponge. I wouldn't change for any push, for any change, I would try to
Speaker 5:  understand Instagram, the product, the employee advice and the val values.
Speaker 5:  The one place where I almost immediately broke my promise was safety and
Speaker 5:  integrity. I was very interested in details 'cause I'd run blah blah blah.
Speaker 5:  I'm just skipping ahead 'cause we're gonna run the audio. And he said, I
Speaker 5:  found for the most part, Instagram was running around stuff and our team
Speaker 5:  was tiny and I made them integrate with the bigger Meta team so it could
Speaker 5:  grow. And this is the best argument that exists.
Speaker 5:  I'm actually really curious why the government played this to Adam, right?
Speaker 5:  Because the best argument is trust and safety is really hard.
Speaker 5:  The scale is really hard doing it on photography and video is even
Speaker 5:  harder, right? 'cause you just need more compute to scan all that content.
Speaker 5:  And you need unified rules and you need to manage contractors around the
Speaker 5:  world and multiple language, all this stuff. That is the best argument they
Speaker 5:  have that Instagram was able to scale because
Speaker 5:  Meta had that particular infrastructure. And maybe
Speaker 5:  you could argue that they had ad sales infrastructure all also, but it was
Speaker 5:  that particular infrastructure. I thought it was really interesting. And
Speaker 5:  then he gets to the Instagram team was chafing against
Speaker 5:  Meta, right? And he, he, he thinks a bunch of stuff was overblown. And eventually,
Speaker 5:  of course Kevin's system and Mike Krieger leave Meta.
Speaker 5:  They're, they were on the stand last week. They're very spiky. They said
Speaker 5:  they could have made it on their own. But I just think it's really interesting
Speaker 5:  that so much of the story is here are the capabilities
Speaker 5:  that Meta actually provide Instagram versus having compete with Instagram.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean, and over the years Meta has made the case for itself
Speaker 6:  as a trust and safety organization like many, many times. It is one of the
Speaker 6:  things that that company is invested in at a level beyond almost
Speaker 6:  anybody else, which is a wild given all the stuff that still happens on its
Speaker 6:  platforms. But yeah, It is kind of weird to basically play that.
Speaker 6:  'cause it, I mean both of those things I suppose can be true at the same
Speaker 6:  time where the Instagram team can be chafing against it, but also
Speaker 6:  really needed the trust and safety help. But I don't know that, like at best
Speaker 6:  that feels like a wash of an argument to me from
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Well I think that the two things that can be true at the same time are that
Speaker 7:  even if in in a world where Instagram had remained independent, that it still
Speaker 7:  could have been weird and bad in the ways that It is weird and bad now
Speaker 7:  and just a, a cluster of things that don't really work together, even if
Speaker 7:  Meta had never purchased it. We've seen what's happened with Twitter
Speaker 7:  like prior, prior to Elon Musk. And also that the reason
Speaker 7:  why Meta purchased it was to take out a competitor
Speaker 6:  Fair. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And also if you are the sort of person who believes all these companies censor
Speaker 5:  too much and you're worried about social big platform free
Speaker 5:  speech abuse, sure you can worry about that. The solution is you have
Speaker 5:  more big companies moderating different ways and competing to have the best
Speaker 5:  moderation policies. Not one ever bigger company imposing the same rules,
Speaker 5:  in the same processes, in the same Mark Zuckerberg whims
Speaker 5:  not, meta's not doing content moderation anymore. We're doing community ed.
Speaker 5:  So like that is the problem, right? Is the scale. I don't know
Speaker 5:  that the, the Trump administration, they were smart would be making this
Speaker 5:  argument. 'cause it's such a big argument they make all the time. But what
Speaker 5:  they actually want is control over Monopoly speech. So I don't think they're
Speaker 5:  gonna make this argument,
Speaker 5:  But it's really like that's a thing that you would want, you would want multiple
Speaker 5:  platform companies operating independently so that if you hated the moderation
Speaker 5:  on Facebook, you would leave and go to an independent Instagram Right. And
Speaker 5:  experience a different moderation system. And that just has never played
Speaker 5:  out. We've never really seen that play out. No. Or you would have an Instagram
Speaker 5:  that was better at protecting teens, right? Because you would,
Speaker 5:  they would feel pressure and people would leave their platform to go to some
Speaker 5:  other platform. And we certainly have not seen that play out.
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 5:  All right. So same question as before, 36 months from now, what does Meta
Speaker 5:  look like? Is it recognizable? Is it very different?
Speaker 6:  I think Meta gets out of this one. Yeah. Yeah, because
Speaker 5:  Mark Zuckerberg's just floating around the Oval Office
Speaker 6:  Kind of. Yeah. I think Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 6:  probably thinks he can convince Donald Trump to just throw out this case
Speaker 6:  in one way or another. And I think the, the,
Speaker 6:  like, again, the technicalities of this continue to be so complicated and
Speaker 6:  it's, the market definitions are weird and like friends and family
Speaker 6:  sharing services is a strange thing. And so I feel like it might
Speaker 6:  sort of lose this case in the court of public opinion and win it on
Speaker 6:  technicalities.
Speaker 5:  All right, Richard,
Speaker 7:  They get out of this, but they do some weird thing where Facebook becomes
Speaker 7:  a spin code that they spin off into its own thing and Mark just takes
Speaker 7:  Instagram and, and Meta and, and all the VR stuff
Speaker 7:  and turns into Horizon and goes and lives in the Metaverse.
Speaker 6:  Okay, that's an unbelievably good idea. Mark. Just fully,
Speaker 6:  he just zags on him, spin off Facebook.
Speaker 6:  He's like, the company's not even called that anymore. This is for old people.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna sell Facebook to the A A RP and I'm gonna go
Speaker 6:  do Instagram and WhatsApp. The metaverse unbelievable idea. I have no
Speaker 6:  notes.
Speaker 5:  I, my answer here all depends on what happens with TikTok.
Speaker 5:  I think if TikTok survives Meta does not look
Speaker 5:  recognized in three years, I, I actually think there's a, a better chance
Speaker 5:  they lose this case than anyone thinks. Okay. Because the market
Speaker 5:  definition of they're, they pinned a lot on that. The judge gets to pick,
Speaker 5:  the judge is allowed to just invent their own market, right? They're like
Speaker 5:  the market for Scrolly videos, like done and done, I'm calling it. Right?
Speaker 5:  So we'll see what happens there. But if there's no
Speaker 5:  TikTok, right, TikTok actually gets banned. I think Meta
Speaker 5:  just collects all those users and it can withstand whatever changes comes
Speaker 5:  its way if TikTok does not get banned, I think the competitive threat is
Speaker 5:  still so high. And the relevance of these, these things are
Speaker 5:  fading. Like TikTok is just vastly more culturally relevant than Instagram
Speaker 5:  is today. Oh yeah. It's vastly more culturally relevant than
Speaker 5:  Facebook is today. Aside from your child's little
Speaker 5:  league softball schedule. It is like posted in a, an uns scannable
Speaker 5:  PDF in a Facebook group. Like it's fine, but like
Speaker 5:  the cultural relevance of TikTok is so high and Meta doesn't have moves.
Speaker 5:  I I don't think they can figure it out. And so you get the pressure, the
Speaker 5:  court case and whatever remedies in a court case, all the distraction of
Speaker 5:  compliance, blah, blah, blah, blah. And then a, a continued ascendance of
Speaker 5:  TikTok 36 months from now. These companies look totally different. I dunno
Speaker 5:  it that's, that's my conditional
Speaker 6:  It is certainly true that there doesn't seem to be any way in the next
Speaker 6:  36 months for Meta to buy its way out of its problems, which is a thing he's
Speaker 5:  Done. I mean, they've been trying
Speaker 6:  That's Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How many meme coins has, has Zuck bought?
Speaker 5:  Zuck is like, here's what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna punch Ukraine. Like I'm
Speaker 5:  gonna do some MMA on in the Middle East. Like
Speaker 5:  I He's trying Yeah. Dana White's running it now. There you go.
Speaker 5:  All right. That's the baby podcast right there. If you want the clip, that's
Speaker 5:  the one. All right, let's, let's breathe. Let
Speaker 5:  one second and then actually p cleanse this with some gadget news and it's
Speaker 5:  Meta Gadget News, but it's still Gadget News. It's
Speaker 6:  Neli specific Meta Gadget. It is, It is
Speaker 6:  Eli's number one dream gadget.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So here the, the news is, there's a rumor that Meta will have new
Speaker 5:  AI glasses and they will have a quote, super sensing mode with facial recognition.
Speaker 5:  I've been saying for years now that the killer app
Speaker 5:  for glasses, for smart glasses is names and faces. I'm horrible at names
Speaker 5:  and faces. If I could just look at people and be told their name, I would
Speaker 5:  probably be the most po po powerful politician in America. I'm say I, I'm
Speaker 5:  not, you know,
Speaker 6:  You think that's what, that's the only thing that's stopping you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause I walk up to people, I'm like, who are you? And that you can't
Speaker 5:  get votes that way. That's not normal. Like Bill Clinton famously would
Speaker 5:  like go to a rope line in Vermont like five years after he'd last been there,
Speaker 5:  and he'd remember every single person and, and their children. And everyone's
Speaker 5:  like, well, we love that Billy Clinton. And then, you know, like, now he
Speaker 5:  became president. I show up at a rope line in Vermont, I'm like, I don't
Speaker 5:  all of you look exactly the same to me. Like total face blindness. If I could
Speaker 5:  just do names and faces.
Speaker 6:  Is it like a white people thing?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's another baby podcast moment right there. You're the theo.
Speaker 5:  I'm trying not to say you did it.
Speaker 5:  No, it's like literally everywhere. I just, I can't do it. If I could do
Speaker 5:  it, the problem is to do it, you need to build a worldwide facial
Speaker 5:  recognition database, which is deeply problematic. Like,
Speaker 5:  that is the panopticon surveillance state. And as
Speaker 5:  much as I want this product, I'm like, I think that trade off's pretty bad.
Speaker 5:  Facebook has a long been able to build this product because they have
Speaker 5:  everybody's names and faces.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There have been versions of this product hacked together using Meta AI
Speaker 5:  glasses, live streaming to Instagram live captured in a, in a web browser
Speaker 5:  and sent to Clearview. You've, we've run the demos, we've talked about it.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Like the proof of concept has been there. And so I think Meta knows
Speaker 5:  like, oh, this is the killer app. Like we should show people the killer app.
Speaker 5:  Like all bets are off right now with privacy law in the United States. All
Speaker 5:  bets are off with AI regulation in the United States. We're just doing it.
Speaker 5:  And I think people are gonna be so creeped out so fast that the backlash
Speaker 5:  will be intense. Oh,
Speaker 6:  I completely agree. I mean, I think it, it's, it's interesting to see
Speaker 6:  this start to percolate up next to real time
Speaker 6:  translation as like everyone's holy grail feature for this stuff, right?
Speaker 6:  Because it's, that's the thing everyone is working on. Anyone who has
Speaker 6:  ever done any AI anything would love to tell you how it's gonna help
Speaker 6:  facilitate real time translation so all the people in the world could talk
Speaker 6:  to each other. And this is like, it's, it's getting right up there with it.
Speaker 6:  And I think I would define it slightly broader than the way you're thinking
Speaker 6:  about it, which is just like sort of latent world awareness,
Speaker 6:  right? Because like, think about the, the Project Astra demo we saw from
Speaker 6:  Google last year where you can like ask it where you left your keys. Like
Speaker 6:  it's, it's relatively similar technology that makes my glasses
Speaker 6:  know your neli and my glasses know that my keys are over there, right? So
Speaker 6:  I think that is the thing now that everybody understands is
Speaker 6:  or at least believes is like a killer app for all of this stuff. And
Speaker 6:  it's like, where is the, you know, where are the groceries in the
Speaker 6:  car? And it'll like remind you that you left them in the car because it's
Speaker 6:  all, you put them in the car and all that kind of stuff is, is
Speaker 6:  starting to bubble up from all of these different companies. But It is, it's
Speaker 6:  the same thing like, oh, I have to give you 100%
Speaker 6:  constant access to everything happening around me all the time. And in exchange
Speaker 6:  you'll tell me where I left my keys and what Eli's name is,
Speaker 5:  You're gonna label stuff.
Speaker 6:  And I don't think most people wanna make that trade. I just don't. Look,
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook is heavily invested in air glasses as a rumor this week that Apple
Speaker 5:  is, is building chips for its own ar glasses. Now that
Speaker 5:  stuff all seems still p pretty pipe dream to me, right? Like Meta's Orion
Speaker 5:  glasses are too expensive to build because the, the,
Speaker 5:  the, the blocker is the optics, right? Right. You gotta make
Speaker 5:  a lens that can accept images. Meta insists on calling them holograms.
Speaker 5:  If you see a Meta executive refer to their glasses as doing projecting
Speaker 5:  holograms, like I literally want you to stop them in their tracks and be
Speaker 5:  like, use words correctly. They're not holograms, they're just image overlays.
Speaker 5:  They're just projecting onto wave guides and glasses like everyone else is
Speaker 5:  doing. Holograms are, you know, three dimensional the existence.
Speaker 5:  It, we we're Vergecast people. You understand what I'm saying? Use the words
Speaker 5:  right.
Speaker 5:  I mean it Okay. But like the optics are the problem.
Speaker 5:  Meta invested in one set of optical technologies that thought would scale.
Speaker 5:  They didn't, they didn't get cheaper. Apple hasn't solved this problem. That's
Speaker 5:  why they built the Vision pro the way they did. There's a lot of steps between
Speaker 5:  here and now. And then you look at what the promise is. And again, I would
Speaker 5:  buy names and faces, glasses in one RV given all, even with
Speaker 5:  all their problems, I would buy them tomorrow. I think it'd be great for
Speaker 5:  conferences where everyone opted in. Like there's a lot of places you could
Speaker 5:  make it work, right?
Speaker 5:  But at the end of the day, the is we're gonna label stuff.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna look at a painting and we're gonna be like, here's the name
Speaker 5:  of the painting. And it's like, you gotta do a little bit better than that,
Speaker 5:  right? You gotta make a better promise than everything will be labeled.
Speaker 7:  I think something interesting that happened here, when you talk about that
Speaker 7:  backlash and, and what might happen that they're not anticipating, remember
Speaker 7:  when Microsoft talked about bringing out out their recall
Speaker 7:  for, for Windows where it Yeah. Remember every single thing that has been
Speaker 7:  on your screen and then people said, wait, every single thing that has been
Speaker 7:  on my screen,
Speaker 5:  David wrote a piece where he was like, I love this. He's like, screenshots
Speaker 5:  are the future of ai. That was like your headline. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  For precisely the opposite reason of recall. Like it's, it's
Speaker 6:  because the thing a screenshot lets me do is say, I care about this, save
Speaker 6:  this for me and then make something out of it. Like the, I
Speaker 6:  I, we've talked about this v song was on the show just
Speaker 6:  recently talking about the, these ai recording wearables and there is, there's
Speaker 6:  this thing you realize where you're like, oh my God, I do so much stuff that
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna have any record of and everybody goes to like porn and
Speaker 6:  whatever. But like, I don't, it's weird that it has a, it
Speaker 6:  it has an audio record of every TikTok I watched today. Like that's weird.
Speaker 6:  Like,
Speaker 7:  Like it shouldn't have a recording of what someone was saying when I walked
Speaker 7:  past them in the store and like, it it's pulling that up when I search because
Speaker 7:  I don't even remember that I didn't even hear it at the time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's, it's not my information to have, and yet I have it. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, I, I think we should summarize this podcast immediately.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, like I'm exci if medic Meta of all companies
Speaker 5:  announces a facial, a set of facial recognition glasses, like
Speaker 5:  it's, they don't have a great privacy rep to begin with, right?
Speaker 5:  It is the killer app for these glasses. I I'm being a little snarky about
Speaker 5:  labels. Like that is the promise labeling people is the killer app for
Speaker 5:  these glasses, right? If again, if you're at a conference, just imagine a
Speaker 5:  conference and, and you know, there's big signs that say in this,
Speaker 5:  in this convention hall, everyone's gonna be wearing these glasses. Like
Speaker 5:  we, we were already name tags before we're enabling the glasses in in this
Speaker 5:  one place. Yeah. Okay. Still a little gray area. You should be able to opt
Speaker 5:  out. But like, let's say that exists, right? Everyone has agreed to
Speaker 5:  participate in this social experiment and you're walking around and you
Speaker 5:  see the person that, you saw the conference last year and you had a conversation
Speaker 5:  and you totally forgot their name and you gave them the card and it's like
Speaker 5:  got lost the backpack and that's gone. And what you get is here's
Speaker 5:  this person, here's their name, here's like the company
Speaker 5:  they work at, like the name tag, but you don't have to like look down at
Speaker 5:  the name tag. That is actually a, a trip. Like it would ease social
Speaker 5:  interaction in that environment in a very specific way that would be worth
Speaker 5:  wearing glasses
Speaker 5:  in almost every case. Like having to charge the glasses and put them on your
Speaker 5:  face is my theory of wearable bullshit. Like that's a lot of care for not
Speaker 5:  a lot of value,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  I don't think Meta can convincingly make the case,
Speaker 5:  but I also think they know that the only thing people are wearing the ray
Speaker 5:  bands for is to have a very convenient camera and no one is using
Speaker 5:  any of the AI features of the Meta glasses and they have to come up with
Speaker 5:  something else.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean, I, I agree, but I'm not, I'm just not convinced
Speaker 6:  this is that thing
Speaker 5:  We'll see. Yes. More gat news. Just to run through it quickly,
Speaker 5:  there's a rumor that Apple's gonna do the iPhone Air with a bigger screen
Speaker 5:  in 2027. There's also a rumor that Apple's gonna do a foldable next year
Speaker 5:  and they're gonna move the iPhone release date around.
Speaker 5:  What do you think the
Speaker 6:  Idea is that there are now going to be, I believe the end, I believe it would
Speaker 6:  be six different iPhones and that that's too many to
Speaker 6:  launch at one event. So there are going to be two
Speaker 6:  different iPhone launch events going forward because they're gonna do, I
Speaker 6:  think it would be Pro Air and foldable
Speaker 6:  at one and then base plus
Speaker 6:  se at another. And I would argue that Apple has learned
Speaker 6:  precisely the wrong lesson here. And the correct answer is don't have six
Speaker 6:  phones, but this is where we are. So that's apparently
Speaker 6:  like the, the eight, the iPhone 18 cycle
Speaker 6:  appears. It is going to be a huge one.
Speaker 5:  The iPhone, this iPhone 16 cycle is supposed be huge 'cause of Apple intelligence.
Speaker 6:  Well, right, I was just gonna say the, this is all based on like some
Speaker 6:  perennially sketchy supply chain stuff and we never
Speaker 6:  really know and it's all very messy, but I think
Speaker 6:  there has been some smoke about a foldable iPhone coming in around in
Speaker 6:  and around 2027. That leads me to believe that's probably still
Speaker 6:  relatively right. But I just, I don't know. I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm having so much hard, I'm having such a hard time caring about a
Speaker 6:  slim iPhone and it appears that is going to be the thing this year
Speaker 6:  and I, I don't care. I just don't care.
Speaker 5:  I think if they make a foldable iPhone, it, it folds out to like iPhone,
Speaker 5:  iPad mini size, and then the iPad gets like windowing, which they've rumored
Speaker 5:  it's gonna get real weird. It's gonna get real weird. And
Speaker 6:  Then they will still refuse to make a touchscreen MacBook for reasons that
Speaker 6:  continue to not make any sense forever
Speaker 7:  Or multi-user on the iPad.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Also
Speaker 5:  That it's the only thing anybody actually wants. Richard, there's a bunch
Speaker 5:  of new surface stuff. What's going on here?
Speaker 7:  This is what Tom, Tom Warren had had all of the information this week
Speaker 7:  about my Microsoft launching some. First of all, they have a smaller Surface
Speaker 7:  Pro laptop, so they've got a 12 inch. Finally, we, we'd heard
Speaker 7:  some rumors about this. It starts at $799. It has arm inside,
Speaker 7:  so it doesn't have a fan. I think you have the iPad competitor that
Speaker 7:  this smaller, that the Surface Pro is kind of always supposed to be. Now
Speaker 7:  the Windows on arm is pretty good with the Qualcomm chips
Speaker 7:  and with that, all the things that Windows have done to be able to run more
Speaker 7:  and more programs, it's the time the, the Surface Pro
Speaker 7:  that people were looking for that it was kind of supposed to always be
Speaker 7:  This is a lot more it, the the price Yeah. Is a lot lighter. It's, it's
Speaker 7:  a good size. It's, it seems like his first impressions of it. I think he
Speaker 7:  said that the 12 inch has the eight core chip, 16 gigs Ram
Speaker 7:  256 gigs of storage for 7 99.
Speaker 5:  This fully looks like my new airplane computer.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  One second. Perfect. Right?
Speaker 7:  It seems like that is the one that you could just take with you and you'll
Speaker 7:  have your computer in the kind of the sa the same size and shape of an iPad,
Speaker 7:  but you'll be able to have multiple accounts and computer stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This does seem like, at least in theory, Microsoft has
Speaker 6:  been sort of dancing around the right set of specs for a long time. Like
Speaker 6:  it was, it was too small and then, and then it was too big and then there
Speaker 6:  was the surface go, which was, and then some of it was too slow and some
Speaker 6:  of it, like it always had a couple of things right? And a couple of things
Speaker 6:  wrong. And at least on paper, I think you're right that this is the one that
Speaker 6:  is like, okay, you, you made the list correctly this time
Speaker 6:  it's still, it's a thousand bucks by the time you buy the keyboard, which
Speaker 6:  everybody's gonna do. So whatever. But still, like as a, as a
Speaker 6:  what is the sort of easy computer to recommend to most
Speaker 6:  people, this feels plausible to me in a way that I'm
Speaker 6:  very excited about.
Speaker 7:  And the idea, the keyboard case doesn't have tower on it anymore.
Speaker 5:  Oh, good. So look, get all matted and nasty. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  They don't have that. They also launched the Surface laptop 13 inch with,
Speaker 7:  with an arm processor in it. So,
Speaker 5:  And that one oddly covered in Berber carpet.
Speaker 5:  That'd be amazing. Microsoft made like a full seventies basement
Speaker 5:  laptop. No, that one's just made of, it's made of normal
Speaker 6:  Materials. This one has a fan though, which I think is weird. That's the
Speaker 6:  only thing about the Surface laptop, which is a machine I have loved for
Speaker 6:  many years. They, they went ahead and gave this thing a fan, which strikes
Speaker 6:  me as maybe a good idea, but not a great sign of confidence
Speaker 6:  in the whole Qualcomm situation at the moment.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, you know, the goal for these devices is to
Speaker 5:  set the tone for the Windows ecosystem. I think they're, they do that job
Speaker 5:  just fine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they're great looking. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They look good. Those videos are on YouTube. Go watch 'em.
Speaker 5:  They're great. Let us know what you think. Also
Speaker 7:  The testing, what's the smoke blowing around inside of the surface
Speaker 7:  laptop to show how the air air flows. I thought that was really cool. You
Speaker 7:  can see that on the social media and the article.
Speaker 6:  Dude, every time I watch one of these like stress testing gadgets, videos,
Speaker 6:  I'm always like, yeah, I've seen like a hundred of these before and then
Speaker 6:  11 minutes later I'm like, riveted. Yeah, just watching a thing, press the
Speaker 6:  button over and over and over again. I will watch an infinite number
Speaker 6:  of something beating up a gadget that
Speaker 5:  It turns out like four, five years into The Verge. I actually made a rule
Speaker 5:  that we were never gonna look at phone prototypes again. Like this. Just
Speaker 5:  like fundamentally stopped. We were like, I was like, great. Like, once again,
Speaker 5:  you've brought me to the quietest room in Northern California to look at
Speaker 5:  your headphones, like, we're just not doing this anymore. And then you're,
Speaker 5:  it's like kind of, can I go to the quiet room again?
Speaker 6:  You just have to acknowledge it for what It is like is this is, I'm, I'm
Speaker 6:  here once again
Speaker 5:  In the quietest room in California
Speaker 6:  To watch you punch a gadget in the face over and over again. I'm like, I'm
Speaker 6:  ready for it.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. Watch the video, it's great. All right, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 5:  We'll right back with lighting around unsponsored for flavor.
Speaker 5:  Alright, we're back to lightning round unsponsored
Speaker 5:  for extra flavor. See, the reason I keep saying that a joke,
Speaker 5:  which is I I agree with many of our audience is getting less funny over time,
Speaker 5:  although people do want the shirts. And so every time you hear someone say
Speaker 5:  who their sponsor is, you realize they have less flavor because we don't
Speaker 5:  take the money. You can't pay us to say anything. You can show up
Speaker 5:  suitcases full of money, they have Ford Fiesta's full of money, then
Speaker 5:  it's not a lot of money. You see? See what I'm getting? Well
Speaker 6:  That was good because if there's one thing that resuscitates a joke, it's
Speaker 6:  explaining it in great detail to the audience.
Speaker 5:  It's a small, it's a small car.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's the joke.
Speaker 5:  Frank's full of money.
Speaker 5:  You, we won't take it. Everyone else takes the money. If you wanna support
Speaker 5:  us, you, you can subscribe on The Verge dot com. You, you, you can pay us
Speaker 5:  money, but then you still can't tell us what to do. That's true. It's a great
Speaker 5:  deal.
Speaker 6:  But you get, you get a badge next to it when you yell at us about it.
Speaker 5:  That's true. That's good. And that's good. It's very good. All right, David,
Speaker 5:  it's time.
Speaker 6:  Oh, we're so back. Last week it was quiet.
Speaker 6:  Too quiet. And so this week, according to the notes that I'm seeing, we are
Speaker 6:  so, so, so very back on America's favorite podcast.
Speaker 6:  Within a podcast. Brendan Carr is a dummy neela, what do we have?
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr was a real dummy this week and
Speaker 5:  like a shotgun blast of Brendan Carr this week. He, he was all
Speaker 5:  over the place. He was at a Milken conference. Alex Heath is actually at
Speaker 5:  this conference, but at this conference he gave a bunch of interviews to
Speaker 5:  a bunch of media outlets. Not us, Brendan Rude,
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying if, if you had reel stones you'd show up on our show, but
Speaker 5:  he gave a bunch of, you know, interviews to your cable news outlets. And
Speaker 5:  boy did he say a lot of things. So I wanna start with some classic
Speaker 5:  Brendan, like classic Republican FCC chairman
Speaker 5:  stuff because, you know, for all of his, many, many faults,
Speaker 5:  he's still a deregulatory telecom friendly
Speaker 5:  FCC chairman. And so he just says the things now
Speaker 5:  that you would expect people to say, but after all this time, you
Speaker 5:  just know that there are industry plants and they're dumb. So Brendan
Speaker 5:  said, during the Biden administration, the United States fell behind
Speaker 5:  on opening the airwaves up to private sector. And China now has an edge,
Speaker 5:  if you'll recall,
Speaker 6:  In American airwaves. I don't know. Okay,
Speaker 5:  But we, we might be losing the race to 5G again, you guys. Oh no.
Speaker 5:  And then to put a gloss on it, a 2025
Speaker 5:  gloss, he said AI is gonna be the use case that will drive
Speaker 5:  some of these telecom networks. That's why we have to get more spectrum out
Speaker 5:  there. We have to make it easier to invest in these high speed networks.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, bro, they're chatbots
Speaker 6:  Also. The, that, that quote is going to stick in my head
Speaker 6:  for a long time as the moment AI officially lost all meaning as
Speaker 6:  a thing that anyone agrees on. Yeah. Like what, what does that even mean?
Speaker 6:  It's AI is going to drive some of these telecom. Does he just mean it uses
Speaker 6:  bandwidth?
Speaker 5:  But again, the, It is currently expressed as
Speaker 5:  chatbots.
Speaker 5:  Like we're we're pumping vast amounts of UTF text
Speaker 5:  around the internet. Like what are you talking about?
Speaker 5:  He's a dummy, but he wants to have more spectrum auctions and sell more spectrum
Speaker 5:  to the big companies and provide more government subsidies to the biggest
Speaker 5:  telecom companies on in the country because we
Speaker 5:  have to win a fake race.
Speaker 5:  I don't know, man, if you, Brendan, if you can explain yourself,
Speaker 5:  you can show up, but you tell like the race to six G is coming
Speaker 5:  where you sit today, think just be ready. Take a
Speaker 5:  beat, take a moment, pull your car over and get ready to
Speaker 5:  shout down the people who say there is a race to six G because of ai.
Speaker 5:  Steal yourself for this battle because it's coming. And it won't be robot
Speaker 5:  surgery on a grape, which never happened.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be ai. If we don't beat ai, China will win the race to six
Speaker 6:  G eight K, six G AI is a thing you're gonna start to hear, it's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be nuts. So that's just like, that's like your little amused boosh
Speaker 5:  of Brendan being a dummy. Right? Just saying the same dumb things.
Speaker 5:  Dumb that FCC chairman who want to give more spectrum and handouts to telecom
Speaker 5:  companies always say dumb, not
Speaker 5:  illegally dumb. Sure. Right. Not you're a traitor to America. Dumb.
Speaker 5:  Which
Speaker 6:  For Brendan is, you know, great job. Good job, Brendan.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He made, he made he whatever, you know, he yeah, he, he stayed in his
Speaker 5:  lane
Speaker 6:  Regular dumb.
Speaker 5:  Then he started to get, well, I think traitor dumb. He
Speaker 5:  talked about the fccs investigation into Disney's DEI
Speaker 5:  practices. And he said the preliminary data from our investigation
Speaker 5:  indicates they're doing intentional discrimination potentially among race
Speaker 5:  and gender. That's a really big deal. It's a good thing by the way. 'cause
Speaker 5:  you know, Disney's slightly caved here. They've gotten rid of some of their
Speaker 5:  rules. You know, they're, they're, they're trying to appease the Trump administration.
Speaker 5:  He said it's a good thing they're headed in the right direction, but we wanna
Speaker 5:  make sure that it's in substance and not in name only. We have to like
Speaker 5:  take a look at the conduct that took place in the past that is a
Speaker 5:  potential problem under the fccs own equal opportunity
Speaker 5:  employment rules. Which by the way, they got rid of because Brendan
Speaker 5:  and he got rid of all the DI rules, right? So he's basically saying, I'm
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna continue to try to punish Disney for nothing.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like
Speaker 5:  they, Ariel was black one time and now Bob Iger has to go to jail and
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr's gonna be the one to do it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're doing intentional discrimination potentially among race and gender
Speaker 6:  is the whole problem that existed forever that we tried to
Speaker 6:  solve with DEI like that's very good was the problem.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. You dous. So he's still right. He's still
Speaker 5:  trying to punish companies for their speech and how they run their
Speaker 5:  companies. He is very interested in punishing companies for their speech.
Speaker 5:  This is the thing he cares about the most. And so
Speaker 5:  pushed on this, he tried to claim, and this is the
Speaker 5:  one that just really, really got me. He tried to claim
Speaker 5:  that the fccs investigation into CCBs
Speaker 5:  and the Kamala Harris interview on 60 Minutes and the
Speaker 5:  Paramount merger with Skydance Paramount owned CBS was
Speaker 5:  totally unrelated to Donald Trump's own
Speaker 5:  $10 billion lawsuit against CBS for the Kamala Harris interview.
Speaker 5:  He said, I haven't even read the president's complaint. We're just doing
Speaker 5:  law enforcement. These aren't threats. That's just a penalty where I can
Speaker 5:  take away the broadcast licenses. Which by the way, no FCC has done for decades
Speaker 5:  upon decades. And even the last time they did it required multiple and multiple
Speaker 5:  court cases and they still didn't get to do it. He said, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 5:  no. There are three separate things that are going on. President Trump has
Speaker 5:  his lawsuit against CBS that's in state court. I haven't read that complaint.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what all the complaints are. There's the transaction before
Speaker 5:  US Paramount and Skydance, and then there's a 60 minutes complaint. Those
Speaker 5:  last two have to do with The FCC. The first one doesn't. We're staying in
Speaker 5:  our lie and we're just reviewing it. It's just the normal course of review
Speaker 5:  where we take a normal interview with a politician during an election
Speaker 5:  and we threaten to punish a company as hard as we can because they want get
Speaker 5:  a merger approved. And what we want from them is a settlement
Speaker 5:  saying that they will not do quote unquote news distortion, which means they
Speaker 5:  will tilt their coverage towards us. But that has nothing to do with Donald Trump,
Speaker 5:  even though no, of course not Two weeks ago, Brendan is proudly wearing
Speaker 5:  the literal gold bust of Donald Trump's head as a pin on his chest.
Speaker 5:  You have no credibility, Brendan, like none at all, because you love
Speaker 5:  to spout out on social media and be a MAGA warrior. And then when you're
Speaker 5:  pressed on it, you pretend that you are a normal gray suit
Speaker 5:  government bureaucrat just doing the normal process of review. And you can't
Speaker 5:  have both, you can't, you can't be a totally corrupt
Speaker 5:  like Censorious bureaucrat and then on the other
Speaker 5:  hand be like, I'm just a lawyer doing my job. By the way, you know who agrees
Speaker 5:  with me about this? It's not a bunch of weirdo progressive libs.
Speaker 5:  It's the American Enterprise Institute. One of the most conservative think
Speaker 5:  tanks in America. Published an article this week called Policing News.
Speaker 5:  Policing, DEI The FCC s Shifting Priorities Erode Its Credibility.
Speaker 5:  It's an entire article about Brendan destroying the credibility
Speaker 5:  of this agency by doing censorship from
Speaker 5:  a conservative think tank. Here's just a quote in short, the
Speaker 5:  fccs mission cre panders to the president eroding the commission's stability
Speaker 5:  because it's hard to predict the regulatory direction which it will head
Speaker 5:  next other than a pro-Trump one. That's not
Speaker 5:  me. It's not, you know, uncle woke over here
Speaker 5:  that's one of the most conservative think tanks in America, agreeing with
Speaker 5:  bipartisan groups of former FCC commissioners agreeing with
Speaker 5:  everybody who's ever looked at Stephen Levy wrote a piece in Wired about
Speaker 5:  this a couple weeks ago. Down the line, everyone looks at this and
Speaker 5:  says, this man who is in charge of our nation's communications infrastructure
Speaker 5:  keeps issuing threats about content to broadcasters, to cable
Speaker 5:  networks, to internet companies, has no power to regulate. And it's because
Speaker 5:  he wants to censor speech and these little claims that he's just doing the
Speaker 5:  normal review with a penalty that has essentially never
Speaker 5:  been used in the course of a merger review to take away broadcast
Speaker 5:  licenses for news distortion. You don't get to do that when you
Speaker 5:  also wear the gold head of Donald Trump on your chest. Where when you're
Speaker 5:  also a MAGA warrior, when you're also on Twitter all day every day,
Speaker 5:  responding to reply guy saying you're gonna punish companies for their speech.
Speaker 5:  As always, Brendan, you're welcome to come on this show, which is much harder
Speaker 5:  than the softball cable networks that you go on and try to answer some of
Speaker 5:  these questions and see if you can respond with rigor and care to the
Speaker 5:  accusations that your desire to censor speech
Speaker 5:  rises to the level of not just first Amendment violation, but
Speaker 5:  outright hostility to our constitution. Anytime you want this show decoder,
Speaker 5:  you can just hang out with David in a coffee shop and I'll film it from around
Speaker 5:  the corner with an iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Sounds great.
Speaker 5:  However you wanna do it, but I don't think you can. I think you're a coward
Speaker 5:  that has been Brendan Carr's dummy America's favorite podcast with our podcast.
Speaker 6:  Oh, we're so back. Felt good. I didn't like taking a weed. We
Speaker 6:  last week we were just like, yeah, Brendan kind of still seems like he sucks
Speaker 5:  Better. Don't worry, he'll talk again better. Yeah. He, he can't show, he
Speaker 5:  can't help himself. He's saying he's loving his job. So being America's chief
Speaker 5:  sensor, all right, we need a pallet cleanser. David, what you got for me?
Speaker 6:  Let's talk about Netflix just for a minute. Yeah. Because Netflix had
Speaker 6:  kind of a sneakily interesting week product wise. First
Speaker 6:  big new update for the, the TV app for Netflix, which I find
Speaker 6:  my like hobby horse of reporting is about streaming
Speaker 6:  recommendations, like how to tell you what you wanna watch. I think It is
Speaker 6:  just the most fascinating thing in the world. And what Netflix did in part
Speaker 6:  was that banner at the top of the Netflix app, it's now much bigger.
Speaker 6:  And the, the one thing that that communicates is that Netflix
Speaker 6:  believes more strongly than ever that it can just put something in
Speaker 6:  front of you and you'll probably click play. And so I think that's fascinating.
Speaker 6:  This is much less like a discovery thing that we're, we're
Speaker 6:  moving rapidly away from the like infinite, you know, side
Speaker 6:  scrolling tiles to just like a big ass thing that's
Speaker 6:  like, watch this you clown and Netflix is
Speaker 6:  betting that that's gonna work. And I find that really fascinating. But thing
Speaker 6:  number two, and Neli, I believe you are going to
Speaker 6:  maybe rightfully, maybe wrongfully take a victory lap on this one. Netflix
Speaker 6:  is just doing TikTok now. Yeah. Like imagine Netflix did TikTok. That's what
Speaker 6:  it's doing.
Speaker 5:  So it's interesting 'cause it, it's not TikTok it, it's in the mobile
Speaker 5:  app. They're gonna do a, a vertical swipey feed of stuff
Speaker 5:  you might wanna watch. We haven't seen it. Right. There's this quote
Speaker 5:  from Eunice Kim, the cheap product officer at Netflix. We know swiping through
Speaker 5:  vertical feed on social media apps is an easy way to browse video content.
Speaker 5:  We know our members love to browse clips and trailers by the next obsession.
Speaker 5:  Sort of w what people love to do is watch
Speaker 5:  pirated clips of movies from the middle on TikTok. And so
Speaker 5:  that's the experience you have to recreate, not you're gonna swipe
Speaker 5:  and then watch a trailer from the beginning.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like that's not it. Like what It is. I'll just keep using a few
Speaker 5:  Good men 'cause it's very funny and TikTok just insists that I keep watching
Speaker 5:  this movie maybe 'cause I watch every clip to the end and it's like, do you
Speaker 5:  want more of this? It's like I do.
Speaker 5:  It's, we're gonna drop you in the middle of some of the most impactful scenes
Speaker 5:  from the movie Ice Cold. And there's comments next to it, most of which
Speaker 5:  are what movie is this? And then people lying, which is very entertaining.
Speaker 5:  It's that. Yeah. So I'm curious how they actually execute this
Speaker 5:  idea. I it, I've asked everybody. I've asked the CEO Tuby, I've asked Netflix
Speaker 5:  itself, the their executives have been on the show. I've asked them and
Speaker 5:  they're all like, yeah, it's hard 'cause we don't have the rights to all
Speaker 5:  this content. Right. And you know, TikTok, there's people are stealing it,
Speaker 5:  so of course you just put the best part. But like the studio is gonna say
Speaker 5:  Netflix owns a bunch of its content so it could do it. Right.
Speaker 5:  We'll see. But I, I think in many ways this is the new discovery
Speaker 5:  method and you know, and David is just like, oh, the laziest TV
Speaker 5:  watcher in the world. He is like, just play me whatever. Like this is, this
Speaker 5:  is the modern, just, I wanna start watching something so I'm just gonna
Speaker 5:  flick channels. It's that mechanism. But for like the social media
Speaker 5:  social video age.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But it's, it's funny you mention the, the trailers thing. 'cause that,
Speaker 6:  that's been the thing I've been thinking about too. Like Spotify has
Speaker 6:  been desperately trying to do this with music and podcasts too. And
Speaker 6:  like you go to the podcasts page on Spotify and it just like
Speaker 6:  starts playing a podcast right there in line and it
Speaker 6:  starts at the beginning, which is a huge mistake. And, and like you're saying,
Speaker 6:  when you're in this browse thing, showing me the beginning of the movie
Speaker 6:  is the wrong thing to do, showing me like the, the
Speaker 6:  thing that is happening that is gonna catch my eye is the thing to do. And
Speaker 6:  we're already seeing this in trailers now. Like the, there's now the trailer
Speaker 6:  before the trailer where they, they show like eight seconds and then it's
Speaker 6:  like the trailer for Thunderbolts begins now. And it's like, I thought it
Speaker 6:  began when I clicked play on this YouTube video 19 seconds ago. So
Speaker 6:  already that has shifted to like grab you faster
Speaker 6:  and I think either a bunch of content makers are gonna
Speaker 6:  start to have to like be smarter about how they make these trailers for these
Speaker 6:  people or Netflix is gonna have to get really smart about saying, okay, this
Speaker 6:  is the grabs 30 seconds of this show, which is the thing Netflix
Speaker 6:  knows. Like, it it sees how people interact with this stuff. Oh, that's
Speaker 5:  Really interesting. I hadn't thought about that.
Speaker 6:  Netflix can theoretically figure out and it could just, it could play me
Speaker 6:  the thing that is likely to work for me in my own feed.
Speaker 5:  Does Netflix know that? I mean, Netflix watch data is like mostly linear,
Speaker 5:  right? What they know is when people stop watching, they don't know when
Speaker 5:  most people begin watching. 'cause for Netflix everybody begins
Speaker 5:  at the beginning,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 7:  Well they they know which ones you come back to. Sure. And obviously maybe
Speaker 7:  they, they maybe their, their, their producer here is actually the people
Speaker 7:  on TikTok who post the clips and they just go back and take those clips.
Speaker 5:  That would be amazing if Netflix was scraping TikTok to see which Netflix
Speaker 5:  shows got the most reactions as pirated TikTok videos.
Speaker 5:  There's something here that's really powerful. Yeah. It just, it all comes
Speaker 5:  down to the execution and the thing that they're competing against is infinity.
Speaker 5:  People trying infinity variations on infinity free content that
Speaker 5:  they're not paying for, which is like always the problem. But to me
Speaker 5:  this is, it's so the future of discovery, I'm, I'm kind of excited to try
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be fascinating. And to Richard's point, there, there is this source
Speaker 6:  of tons of good data on what people actually care about.
Speaker 6:  It just, it's just all illegal and doesn't belong to Netflix.
Speaker 7:  I, I wonder if, what if the, the use of it isn't even
Speaker 7:  as much. Okay. So you watch this and then you watch the video, but just,
Speaker 7:  it means that you're using the Netflix app more and that you're less willing
Speaker 7:  to let your Netflix subscription die. Whether or not you watch the show
Speaker 7:  anything, but it's just something you can use to eat time, which is what
Speaker 7:  a lot of these apps really are. You don't know what to watch, but you just
Speaker 7:  don't want to scroll past some men talking on a podcast
Speaker 5:  Or babies.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like a what if step two of this thing is, it just becomes another
Speaker 6:  set of things to watch on Netflix that they're just like, oh, you're, you're
Speaker 6:  watching, instead of watching Netflix shows, you're watching things 18 seconds
Speaker 6:  at a time.
Speaker 5:  That's fine. And Netflix is right. We compete with death or whatever
Speaker 5:  they say, yeah, sleep not death. Netflix
Speaker 5:  is like-and is like, I will defeat death.
Speaker 5:  But they're like, we compete with like, they're fully in the attention economy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They've known it for a long time. Their competitor is YouTube and video
Speaker 5:  games. And so if you are in the Netflix app watching short
Speaker 5:  clips of Bridger and all that, I don't think they care. 'cause they already
Speaker 5:  own the content. That's the thing that makes this harder for every other
Speaker 5:  service. Right? Like even Apple TV can't do it.
Speaker 5:  You, you think Apple's paying for all that stuff, but like many other big
Speaker 5:  production companies and studios actually make the majority of their content
Speaker 5:  still. So these, they're all licensing deals and they, they don't have all
Speaker 5:  these moves. Netflix just outright owns a bunch of its stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So, well, let's see. I'm excited for this one. It, there's something here
Speaker 5:  that I think is very powerful. The TV
Speaker 7:  UI is weird because it's like three different versions of interfaces. They
Speaker 7:  already did. But I don't know. Back to the future, I guess.
Speaker 6:  I mean this is like the Netflix story in a nutshell. They're like, what if
Speaker 6:  we just, what if we just stretched some boxes and condensed some boxes?
Speaker 6:  Does that help?
Speaker 5:  What if we made the thumbnails bigger and the text smaller?
Speaker 7:  I just want them to never show me a summary that is like a clip of a review
Speaker 7:  of the show. That doesn't tell me anything about what It is in the show.
Speaker 7:  I don't, I don't care if XY, Z website said it was cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. What is it about? Fascinating deadline. And you're like,
Speaker 6:  cool. Thanks Netflix. This is great. That's exactly what I needed to know.
Speaker 5:  You know, apple doesn't show you the Rotten Tomato scores of its own shows.
Speaker 5:  If you ever like, look and oh that's, you know, the Apple TV interface usually
Speaker 5:  has that little bit of metadata. But for Apple stuff it's like not there.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. All right. I wanna end on two more gadgets. Well,
Speaker 5:  one more gadget really, I just wanna call it the fact that gen two E reviewed
Speaker 5:  four robot lawnmowers and maybe the most gen two e
Speaker 5:  moment that can exist. You, you have to read it. It's very
Speaker 5:  good. It includes the line. They don't cut your lawn, they shave it.
Speaker 5:  Perfect. Per perfect.
Speaker 6:  Jen went through a lot to get that story done and it's very good. So everyone
Speaker 6:  should go read it and buy a lawnmower Just to support Jen, because this is
Speaker 6:  like a year of work to try and get these things to shave her lawn.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. You should buy the lawnmower. I think you should read the story
Speaker 5:  and subscribe to the Vich. You can wait, wait a couple years in the lawnmower.
Speaker 6:  That's fair. Read the story and subscribe to the Vich and then maybe don't
Speaker 6:  buy a lawnmower.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And then I wanna end with just a tiny we party speaker update.
Speaker 5:  It's very hard to top party speaker in front of a fighter jet, which is what
Speaker 5:  we had last week. Thank, thank you again for sending us that photo. We got
Speaker 5:  some more photos, many more photos of party
Speaker 5:  speakers in boxes, in stores. Again, I love you.
Speaker 5:  I'm happy that when you see a party speaker, you think of us. It's very validating.
Speaker 5:  I'm glad Where, I'm glad we're a community. That's not it. Like
Speaker 5:  you, it's in the wild Right Guys in
Speaker 5:  Europe on a scooter using it as a chair. We did get one photo
Speaker 5:  that I was really good. I don't wanna run it 'cause it was, it's an audible
Speaker 5:  marketing campaign, you know? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But Audible apparently puts people in marathons wearing
Speaker 5:  party speakers as backpacks playing audio books.
Speaker 5:  And so you can like run along in the race. That's good.
Speaker 5:  Listen, and that's like multiple different books. Like there's a rom-com
Speaker 5:  book, there's like another book and you can follow it. Very good. Audible
Speaker 5:  stunt.
Speaker 6:  We got one like up on a shelf in a gym. A lot of people seeing party speakers
Speaker 6:  at their gym. One at a, at a, I think it was a
Speaker 6:  butcher shop in India. I think the, the thing that we've done that I'm very
Speaker 6:  proud of is we have, we have taught people to see
Speaker 6:  the party speakers in the wild. Yeah. It turns out they're everywhere and
Speaker 6:  we were all just trained to not notice them. Yeah. It's like a real fish
Speaker 6:  noticing the water situation that's happening right now. And we are discovering
Speaker 6:  the extent to which the world has been infiltrated by party speakers. And
Speaker 6:  so people who were like, I've been to this place every day for five years
Speaker 6:  and they never noticed this giant fifth grader sized speaker
Speaker 6:  blowing audio at me all day. Now we're seeing it.
Speaker 6:  We've, we've changed the world.
Speaker 5:  And then we received one person who was like, how do you not know about this
Speaker 5:  phenomenon called sound clashes that apparently take place in Jamaica and
Speaker 5:  India where they just build giant speaker systems
Speaker 5:  and play them at each other? And I was like, first of all, that's I, how
Speaker 5:  did I not know
Speaker 6:  This? Like battle bots, but it's party speakers.
Speaker 5:  But those aren't party speakers. Those are giant custom audio rigs. So oh,
Speaker 5:  honorable mention to sound clashes. I encourage you to go watch the videos
Speaker 5:  on YouTube. They're wild, different, different, right?
Speaker 5:  That's like the people who, if you get in the car audio, they, people are
Speaker 5:  like, oh, I really care about SPL and what they're just talking about, how
Speaker 5:  loud their sub buffers are. I love you, you know, that's great.
Speaker 5:  Forward
Speaker 7:  Facing or rear facing neli, are you stealing your trunk or, or are you not
Speaker 7:  stealing your trunk? We gotta talk about it.
Speaker 5:  This is a, this is a big issue. You know, what's up? Like
Speaker 5:  that's a different, we're we'll do a whole other series on that someday.
Speaker 5:  And I appreciate that. People were like, oh, you wanna talk about party speaker?
Speaker 5:  But I get it. I understand the connection that was made in your mind.
Speaker 5:  Different. We're we're, we're still on party speakers.
Speaker 6:  We'll get to that. Alright,
Speaker 5:  We're way over. Just so over. We love you all. That's it.
Speaker 5:  That's The Vergecast. Bye.
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 9:  you. Give us a call at eight six six Verge one one.
Speaker 9:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 9:  Our show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 9:  that's it. We'll see you next week.