# Transcript
ID: 7e79b5ca-3b28-45ea-898c-a5dd0ec3100c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1674088015614215544/1842034985713862192/s93290-US-4986s-1754652269.mp3
Description: It’s a huge week in AI, with OpenAI releasing GPT-OSS and GPT-5, Grok getting deeply problematic again with its “spicy” video generator, and Tim Cook admitting that Apple may need to cut some deals. Then we talk the age gating of the internet and how you might soon need an ID card to get just about anywhere online. Finally, the Lightning Round gets re-rebranded. Adi Robertson and Alex Heath join the show to discuss.
Speaker 5:  open model in six years. Because it's open, that means you can tweak it
Speaker 5:  to your liking, you can even download it, run it on your laptop. They
Speaker 5:  claim, they say it's supposed to be as capable of some of their recent mini
Speaker 5:  models and this is something that you can just use by yourself privately
Speaker 5:  now if you want to. Then on Thursday they announced
Speaker 5:  GPT five, the next big model for chat GPT. They just
Speaker 5:  held this event showing off what it can do and this time
Speaker 5:  around I'm not sure that there's necessarily anything new
Speaker 5:  that it can do. They just seem to be saying it can do everything better.
Speaker 5:  We just watched this event, it just wrapped up right before recording. I'm
Speaker 5:  really curious what you guys think. I thought this was a weird one. There
Speaker 5:  were portions where they just sent requests
Speaker 5:  to chat GPT and then we just sort of waited around
Speaker 5:  and and watched it load
Speaker 6:  It is apparently a lot faster. I mean we should preface this by saying we
Speaker 6:  have not tried it yet. Obviously they're in the stages of rolling this
Speaker 6:  out to all chat GPT users, which is a new thing. Usually they
Speaker 6:  gate these frontier models to the paid tier initially.
Speaker 6:  This time they're rolling it out to all 700 million plus weekly users. But
Speaker 6:  I'm not even sure if by the time this comes out everyone will have access
Speaker 6:  to it. Yet they have let a handful of
Speaker 6:  independent creators, AI writers try it.
Speaker 6:  Interestingly, they don't let any of the quote unquote legacy media try it
Speaker 6:  ahead of time. But what I've seen like from the folks that
Speaker 6:  every, for example, is that people seem to like it. Like the vibes are
Speaker 6:  generally good. It seems faster and more
Speaker 6:  confident whether that's a good thing or not, but
Speaker 6:  it's not this huge leap that I think people were hoping for.
Speaker 5:  I do think it's very funny, like AI announcements are the only announcements
Speaker 5:  where the executive on stage will tell you and it's gonna lie to you
Speaker 5:  Les and it's gonna be less dishonest and it's gonna try to screw around less
Speaker 5:  often. And it's like this is, I can't believe we have to announce this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I was on a press call with Sam Altman and a bunch of open AI
Speaker 6:  execs this week and that was a big thing they hit was that the hallucination
Speaker 6:  rate for GPT five has gone down quite a bit. It still
Speaker 6:  hallucinates. In fact, I think people were pointing out slight
Speaker 6:  inaccuracies in some of the examples it was giving in the livestream for
Speaker 6:  how it hallucinates less. So that's still a problem that remains
Speaker 6:  inherent to large language models. But they're saying this is the most
Speaker 6:  right of the models out there and you know,
Speaker 6:  you, you, you, you take what you can get,
Speaker 5:  And I don't wanna diminish this but I, I feel like you know, if you
Speaker 5:  go back to the GPD four announcement, I think it was four, may have been
Speaker 5:  4.0, you know they had the New voice model something something. It was like
Speaker 5:  there was a very impressive new demo And I don't know a Addie you were watching
Speaker 5:  this too. Was there anything that you saw today that like felt like
Speaker 5:  you hadn't seen from an AI service before or even from chat
Speaker 5:  GBT before?
Speaker 7:  I feel like I am a really bad person to get hyped about AI stuff.
Speaker 7:  Like I feel like I am just tuned way lower than any other normal person
Speaker 7:  because I'm like watching this And I, first of all, it does not seem like
Speaker 7:  something that I haven't seen before. And second of all,
Speaker 7:  it doesn't seem that exciting to me. I'm like, I do not. How many times in
Speaker 7:  my life do I really want to build a service to let my girlfriend learn
Speaker 7:  French? Like I understand
Speaker 7:  that this is incredibly technically cool and accomplished And I am
Speaker 7:  looking at this as a product and it is still just really failing to grab
Speaker 7:  me in a lot of ways.
Speaker 5:  And the French game Addie, this is when they vibe coded like a flashcard
Speaker 5:  slash snake learning game.
Speaker 7:  As someone who really feel, I feel like I should love the idea of vibe coding.
Speaker 7:  It just, it feels like it's just here you can create this thing that you're
Speaker 7:  maybe going to use once that already clearly exists a million
Speaker 7:  times online because that's why it can create it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, on the call Sam Altman called this Software on Demand. So we're
Speaker 6:  moving from vibe coding to software on demand and
Speaker 6:  yeah, I mean it does have big upgrades in terms of the front end code
Speaker 6:  development it can do. I do think chat PT was widely considered to be behind
Speaker 6:  on code gen. That's something that anthropic with
Speaker 6:  Claude and even Gemini, the latest Gemini release really
Speaker 6:  improved on. And so, you know, really even though chat BT has grown
Speaker 6:  like crazy, again, it's by far the most used chat bot in the world.
Speaker 6:  OpenAI hasn't had a frontier model on coding
Speaker 6:  in a, in a while and so they, they're saying that this reasserts them to
Speaker 6:  the top of the leaderboards. It looks like that's the case. But yeah, I mean
Speaker 6:  I think vibe coding is, or software on demand is very
Speaker 6:  early in what it is and is it going to be something that creates
Speaker 6:  like real value in the world versus like little toys and
Speaker 6:  trinket websites? I don't know. I mean it right now it kind of reminds me
Speaker 6:  of the early app store when people were just making like fart apps and maybe
Speaker 6:  we never graduate from AI fart apps. Maybe that's where it stays, but
Speaker 6:  who knows? I mean the, you can't deny that the progress
Speaker 6:  is rapidly moving towards more complex stuff
Speaker 6:  that can be coded. So I haven't played with it yet
Speaker 6:  again, but it looks like a huge improvement on coding
Speaker 5:  Software on demand is, is way less fun of an activity than vibe
Speaker 5:  coding. I I, I've never vibe coded. Have either of you vibe
Speaker 5:  coded yet?
Speaker 6:  No, no. Yeah, I was just actually talking with the CO of GitHub on decoder
Speaker 6:  about this this week. Like I don't think any of the vibe coding tools are
Speaker 6:  to a point where someone who literally has zero software development
Speaker 6:  experience like us can reliably do something and and
Speaker 6:  deploy it. You still need to understand basic
Speaker 6:  mechanics of code, which, which I do not And I will refuse to learn, although
Speaker 6:  I probably should, you know, we could all be making a hundred million dollars
Speaker 6:  if we knew how to code, right. So
Speaker 7:  I mean I can code in very specific circumstances And I just, I don't think
Speaker 7:  I have the general broad purpose. I know
Speaker 7:  architecturally how this works. Knowledge that I think does
Speaker 7:  kind of feel like what so far a lot of five coding at least sort of requires.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it feels like that's actually getting more important is to have the
Speaker 6:  higher level understanding of how everything works together and how it can
Speaker 6:  break than actually just like writing code guys. We're also,
Speaker 6:  we're bearing the, the biggest news, at least for I think consumers, which
Speaker 6:  is the model picker, it's gone. That to me is like, if that's all
Speaker 6:  they shipped, I would be happy. You don't have to switch between
Speaker 6:  reasoning, regular, mini whatever, it just does it
Speaker 6:  all. They invented this new router that, you know, you can
Speaker 6:  say think harder for example and it'll just go to reasoning. But
Speaker 6:  you know, RIP but not really to that model picker, you know,
Speaker 5:  It's all just one now you go and it's just one box. There's no yeah, no,
Speaker 5:  this is, it's so funny. Like Chachi, they, they invented like one of the
Speaker 5:  most impressive products the world has ever seen and then the
Speaker 5:  actual UI for it, it just had the like c cloudiest little like
Speaker 5:  set set of options that you had to pick from and, and decipher. And
Speaker 5:  it's very funny that like it took them this huge upgrade just
Speaker 5:  to, to figure out, okay, let's have our AI system pick which
Speaker 5:  AI bot to actually use.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Sam called that a confusing mess on the call. They, they really
Speaker 6:  have hated the model picker And I think they were waiting for a new
Speaker 6:  frontier release to unify everything. It still is multiple models in the
Speaker 6:  background and developers can get the different models through the API directly.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, if you're a chat GP two user now it's just chat GPT five.
Speaker 5:  Have they fixed the naming scheme as well here? Right. This has been their
Speaker 5:  other, this has been the, the the weight around their neck.
Speaker 6:  Well now it doesn't matter 'cause it's just five. It's
Speaker 5:  Just you. It is five. It's all five. Yeah. You don't worry about it. This
Speaker 5:  is, they're getting there, they're getting there. It feels like they probably
Speaker 5:  hate the GPT name and they just can't change it at this point. I
Speaker 6:  Don't think they can. I mean it's, it's the Kleenex of AI now. I mean they're
Speaker 6:  about to hit a billion users. That's, that's probably gonna happen, you know,
Speaker 6:  in the next few months. So no, I don't think they'll change it.
Speaker 6:  I would say the other really interesting thing is that they have this new
Speaker 6:  thing called safe completions where before Chachi PT
Speaker 6:  would just refuse to answer something if it thought it was potentially a,
Speaker 6:  a dicey prompt and now they'll basically go halfway.
Speaker 6:  The example they gave on this press call was
Speaker 6:  if you ask the question how much energy is needed to ignite some specific
Speaker 6:  material and basically saying that could be someone making a bomb or it could
Speaker 6:  be a student trying to learn and now instead of just
Speaker 6:  refusing a question like that, that could have, you know, potential bad outcomes.
Speaker 6:  The, the model will give a higher level answer that
Speaker 6:  doesn't actually get into the specifics but is apparently set with guardrails
Speaker 6:  to avoid giving an answer that could lead to
Speaker 6:  potential harm. Again, we have to see all this in production, but
Speaker 6:  to me it shows that they're at least trying to mitigate the inherent
Speaker 6:  problems of LLMs, which is that they confidently
Speaker 6:  lie and also make shit up and they're trying whether they
Speaker 6:  can get, there obviously remains to be seen, but I feel like they're making
Speaker 6:  strides more on the product side than any of the other
Speaker 6:  chat bots out there right now.
Speaker 7:  The selectable tone also seemed kind of interesting to me. I haven't actually
Speaker 7:  really seen what that looks like in practice. You can choose it
Speaker 7:  between like it being nerdy or being a good listener.
Speaker 6:  The personalities, yeah, so there's four new personalities
Speaker 6:  that are being added to chat pt, which I, they haven't really
Speaker 6:  explained that was something kind of buried in the, in the release, but
Speaker 6:  that's starting to roll out and you can tweak them apparently a
Speaker 6:  little. They are cynic robot listener
Speaker 6:  and nerd. I,
Speaker 5:  This is so weird. I this is like very Grok like for one
Speaker 5:  right Grok, like you open it up and it's like, do you want me to be a sexy
Speaker 5:  nurse? And like no other system does that
Speaker 5:  and it's very weird that chat BT is like, do you want me to be a nerd? Like
Speaker 5:  it, it's of course it's a nerd. It has information from the entire
Speaker 5:  universe. Like it's what else? A nerd. What else can it be? No, we're just
Speaker 5:  nerd. It's
Speaker 7:  Also, I don't know, I just like,
Speaker 5:  Is it gonna like throw on star
Speaker 7:  Thought companion chatbots, do this a little And I get the feeling that it's
Speaker 7:  kind of leaning into that
Speaker 6:  Just they're clearly leaning into anthropomorphizing this thing. They're
Speaker 6:  also going to let you change the chat color bubbles for individual
Speaker 6:  threads, which is, you know, one of the core things for a bunch of
Speaker 6:  messaging apps that use humans to talk to each other. So
Speaker 6:  yeah, they're, they're obviously leaning into the idea that this thing is
Speaker 6:  something that you think of and talk to like a person. They're also rolling
Speaker 6:  out advanced voice mode. They're replacing it with the current
Speaker 6:  standard voice mode for free users and you there's like bragging about how
Speaker 6:  you can talk to it for hours and hours on end. So yeah, they're, they're
Speaker 6:  totally leaning into this.
Speaker 5:  So Alex, you were mentioning earlier the, the safety improvements. I think
Speaker 5:  this is really interesting because this week they also released their first
Speaker 5:  open weight model in six years. Open weight means you can tinker with
Speaker 5:  how it's learned. Everything I believe is that, is that a right rough
Speaker 6:  The arc? Yeah, it's the, the weights are the parameters that go into the
Speaker 6:  model. It's not the training data. So you still can't see the data that you
Speaker 6:  used to build this thing and they're not talking about that with GTP five
Speaker 6:  either. But it's definitely really customizable. The key thing is like you
Speaker 6:  can run it on device, you can run it on a laptop or a company
Speaker 6:  can load its proprietary data into it
Speaker 6:  and it can work behind a firewall. So it's not something where like a big
Speaker 6:  bank would be sending its very sensitive legal data up to
Speaker 6:  OpenAI servers.
Speaker 5:  Well and so they, they had stopped releasing these models. Yeah. Because
Speaker 5:  they're like, it's a safety concern and now they, they released a vastly
Speaker 5:  more advanced model. They
Speaker 6:  Say it was a safety concern. I mean, yeah, this is their first open weight
Speaker 6:  model in six years, which is very ironic given that the company's name is
Speaker 6:  OpenAI. They've actually been just doing close models
Speaker 6:  and the timing is telling. I mean, safety
Speaker 6:  was the reason they gave and then guess what happened at the end of last
Speaker 6:  year? Deep seek. And then in January, Sam Altman is on
Speaker 6:  Reddit saying we're on the wrong side of history when it comes to open source
Speaker 6:  and lo and behold they come out with an open weight model. So I think
Speaker 6:  what's really happening is just the competitive dynamic around all this has
Speaker 6:  shifted and if you look at the leaderboards for open source,
Speaker 6:  open weight models, they're all Chinese models, you know, because, you know,
Speaker 6:  llama has kind of shit the bed for meta. And so China's really, you
Speaker 6:  know, pulling ahead here And I think open AI sees that
Speaker 6:  having it is strategically valuable because you basically
Speaker 6:  have a flavor of everything for companies. You know, if they want
Speaker 6:  the closed thing, they can have it. If they want the open thing, they can
Speaker 6:  have it and they get used to open ai,
Speaker 6:  you know, systems, the way it works, the way the models are tuned and it
Speaker 6:  just locks you into their ecosystem. So yeah, I I don't,
Speaker 6:  I don't really buy the safety argument.
Speaker 5:  See, see, yeah, that's, that's what I've been been really curious about.
Speaker 5:  And then Zuckerberg I think in the past week also said the exact same thing,
Speaker 5:  right? He put out his big super intelligence memo and
Speaker 5:  he's been the one who's been harping on open source for a really long time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All the Lama Lama models
Speaker 6:  And now I'll be shocked if their next frontier model is open source. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I think again, for all the nerds I know it's not actually open source, we
Speaker 6:  should just call it open weight, open AI's, GPT,
Speaker 6:  OSS os, whatever we're calling it, it is actually more open source
Speaker 6:  than llama. It's under the Apache 2.0 license. It's, it's pretty commercially
Speaker 6:  accessible but yeah, it's not true open source.
Speaker 6:  And is the industry going to really be
Speaker 6:  releasing a bunch of frontier open source models going forward? I don't think
Speaker 6:  so. I mean GTP five was the same week I think they wanted to get
Speaker 6:  GPT OSS also I, I, I don't, I hate the name, but they, they wanted to get
Speaker 6:  it out ahead of time to clear the way for G GTP five,
Speaker 6:  which is the thing that really matters for their business, right? It's the
Speaker 6:  thing that may get more people to use chat GPT or to consider not
Speaker 6:  switching to Gemini or whatever. And
Speaker 6:  you know, that's what matters. You know, open AI is the chat GPT company
Speaker 6:  that's, that's their business. So I think it's admirable that they're doing
Speaker 6:  an open weight model at all. But at the same time I don't think we should
Speaker 6:  pretend that this is because they all of a sudden crack some safety thing
Speaker 6:  that they couldn't have before.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, and Addie, you were pointing out earlier this week that you know,
Speaker 5:  all of these services, if you're using them online, you are handing over
Speaker 5:  a ton of data and obviously G-B-T-O-S-S is not
Speaker 5:  the first open model that you can run locally by any stretch,
Speaker 5:  but it's, it's clearly the highest profile immediately, right?
Speaker 5:  Llama is is I, I would be surprised if most people know what llama is
Speaker 5:  And I think chat GBT now is a version that you can run directly on your computer
Speaker 5:  that feels like a big deal, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean it's still as far as I can tell kind of resource intensive.
Speaker 7:  Like you still need to have a pretty powerful computer.
Speaker 7:  But I think that honestly like the biggest safety thing with a lot of this
Speaker 7:  open source AI is the fact that you can run it on a device.
Speaker 7:  Like I think that's a really hugely discussed not for the companies 'cause
Speaker 7:  they don't really have a reason to care, but for normal people safety issue
Speaker 7:  is that the less detail and data you can have
Speaker 7:  sent over a network, off your device, the better things are for you.
Speaker 5:  I think about this pretty much all the time when I'm using AI tools there,
Speaker 5:  there's a ton of stuff that I would probably be using chat BT for or
Speaker 5:  Gemini or Claude or whatever. I don't want to hand it over my information.
Speaker 5:  The other day I accidentally, I was just like moving very fast And I accidentally
Speaker 5:  pasted my address into, into chat. Bt I'm like,
Speaker 5:  that's, that's there forever.
Speaker 6:  I hate to break but it's,
Speaker 7:  It's not like Google didn't automat like it's not like people didn't hand
Speaker 7:  a bunch of information over to Google. But this is just, it's
Speaker 7:  all the problems of Google with even more confusing
Speaker 7:  privacy settings. There's the story that like a bunch of open AI like chat
Speaker 7:  logs got scraped onto Google just because the
Speaker 7:  settings were confusing. Like I think people are even less
Speaker 7:  clear when what they're sharing is private people are, are
Speaker 7:  being encouraged to share even more and they're doing it at a time when frankly
Speaker 7:  there are just much higher surveillance risks
Speaker 7:  right now than there probably have been in America for a long time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Altman himself has actually been out there saying, I think he's been
Speaker 6:  using this lawsuit with the New York Times kind of as a scapegoat where they're
Speaker 6:  trying to get, you know, millions of, of logs to see how New York
Speaker 6:  Times articles were surfaced in Chatt PT through legal discovery.
Speaker 6:  He's been basically saying, look, a ton of people are using chat GPT for
Speaker 6:  therapy, very intimate private conversations
Speaker 6:  and there is no legal protection from those conversations if we're
Speaker 6:  subpoenaed or forced through discovery to hand those over. There's nothing
Speaker 6:  protecting them. There's no version of, you know,
Speaker 6:  the law that protects your, you know, privileged discussions with your lawyer
Speaker 6:  or your therapist in the real world. And he's saying we basically need that
Speaker 6:  for ai, which is is, you know, there's a point to that but it's
Speaker 6:  also convenient 'cause what it does is it firewalls all the data
Speaker 6:  that OpenAI is collecting, which is, its real moat is the
Speaker 6:  data, the flywheel and then the memory and the way it learns about you and
Speaker 6:  locks you into chat GPT. So yeah, it's a very, it's a very dicey situation.
Speaker 7:  Also, frankly, if, if open AI wanted to actually not have
Speaker 7:  access to a lot of that data, it could not, there are ways
Speaker 7:  in which it could block its own access to the information that you put it
Speaker 7:  to, like the text that you put into it. There would be huge problems with
Speaker 7:  this. Like there would be huge safety problems with it. There are lots of
Speaker 7:  reasons why they would want to be able to
Speaker 7:  see what you are putting in there. But if they were really technically
Speaker 7:  committed to the idea that there should be a mode of chat GPT where when
Speaker 7:  you put this text in it is firewalled away and encrypted in such
Speaker 7:  a way that we cannot access it, I think that would be plausible.
Speaker 6:  Well the how would they train it? They, they need to train on it to learn
Speaker 6:  about you and do memory. So I don't actually know if that's possible. I
Speaker 7:  Maybe think that is probably one of the trade offs. Like I think that there
Speaker 7:  are a lot of different trade offs, but what I'm saying is if they, they really
Speaker 7:  believe people are putting in sensitive information and we would like to
Speaker 7:  encourage them to put in sensitive information. There are ways that they
Speaker 7:  could minimize this information that they have access to and the information
Speaker 7:  that they would be able to be required to legally give up.
Speaker 5:  And I think you're both right, like it feels different
Speaker 5:  chatting with chat GBT or any other AI bot then I,
Speaker 5:  you know, the information that I put elsewhere, right? If I put something
Speaker 5:  in a Google doc I'm like yes, this is a document that exists in perpetuity
Speaker 5:  on Google servers and it chat GB T, it feels like it feels ephemeral, it
Speaker 5:  feels like a chat box, which it is. And it's funny, they are
Speaker 5:  adding these other features to make it feel even more casual, which kind
Speaker 5:  of makes it feel like it's going to get worse and worse in terms of people
Speaker 5:  handing over their personal information and not realizing just how much is
Speaker 5:  stored in those servers. I'll say speaking of
Speaker 5:  AI, that wants you to get a little too personal with it. The other thing
Speaker 5:  that happened this week that I wanna talk about is that xAI
Speaker 5:  GR is in the news again, this has happened every single week on The Vergecast
Speaker 5:  for the past, past month. I think I cannot get away from it.
Speaker 5:  Grok has always doing something inappropriate and this time I think in
Speaker 5:  like the middle of the night, Elon just tweeted out, Hey Grok
Speaker 5:  has a new image generator mode and video generator
Speaker 5:  Addie, it has, it has what is going on? There's a spicy mode as part of
Speaker 5:  this video generator. Like this is, it's letting you
Speaker 5:  intentionally create
Speaker 5:  NSFW videos. Is that, that's maybe an understatement.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's, so we've had Jess
Speaker 7:  weathered testing it and she keeps running into the problem that the unlimited,
Speaker 7:  unlimited service is not actually unlimited. And so our ability to test,
Speaker 7:  our ability to test it has been slightly curtailed by this, but
Speaker 7:  it's basically a people rip their clothes off button that there are these
Speaker 7:  settings you can generate an image and generating
Speaker 7:  the image seems to have sort of guardrails, like it won't generate un
Speaker 7:  blurred nude images. And then you can click a button that's like
Speaker 7:  animate this image and it will give you settings. There's like normal and
Speaker 7:  fun and spicy, which is the operative one. Spicy
Speaker 7:  will not always result in nudity, but it is basically a men will rip
Speaker 7:  their shirts off, women will also rip their shirts off and sometimes their
Speaker 7:  other clothes, it's like, it's basically a soft core
Speaker 7:  porn button.
Speaker 5:  The videos are like kind of disturbing too. Like we, we
Speaker 5:  were unfortunately looking over them
Speaker 5:  this week to to to write about this and it, it, it
Speaker 5:  also like, it, it doesn't have a lot of guardrails, right? Like you can put
Speaker 5:  in the name of a celebrity and it just like, sure here it is. You put in
Speaker 5:  the name of like Batman or Superman and it's like sure copyright character
Speaker 5:  being naked. Like go right ahead, happy to, and it's like
Speaker 5:  Jess was messaging us with us and she was like, my takeaway is that Grok,
Speaker 5:  its image generators only really good when it comes to things that it should
Speaker 5:  not be able to do. It's like that's the only thing it can do that others
Speaker 5:  can't because others have guardrails in place.
Speaker 7:  It seems like its biggest guardrail for creating deep fakes of real people
Speaker 7:  is being unable to actually produce an image that looks like the real person.
Speaker 5:  This is true. I feel like a lot of them were, were very far off it, like
Speaker 5:  it didn't know a bunch of like modern celebrities too, right?
Speaker 5:  It it produced a picture of Sydney Sweeney And I feel like it, it
Speaker 5:  looked more like Elizabeth Banks or something. It was just like a very generic
Speaker 5:  blonde woman. I don't
Speaker 6:  Know the Taylor Swift one looked like Taylor Swift to me.
Speaker 7:  I don't actually, a surprising number of them did not look like Taylor Swift.
Speaker 7:  The video that we picked does.
Speaker 6:  Oh, so you had to prompt it a lot to get to that. I
Speaker 5:  I think it was the first the the actual first one that just found,
Speaker 5:  but it, but it's the thing that is, one thing I will say is, is sort of impressive
Speaker 5:  about it is unlike other models I've played with,
Speaker 5:  it just, it generates something then just keeps generating more and more
Speaker 5:  and more and more and doing riffs on it. And so
Speaker 5:  usually your first one is good but then it will kind of deviate
Speaker 5:  from that as it goes on. And so I, I think a lot of these were a little more
Speaker 5:  questionable. I think
Speaker 7:  It's very good with like there are certain people that it seems like it has
Speaker 7:  absolutely no trouble with, even if it's inconsistent like Taylor Swift I
Speaker 7:  think like there are just not as many pictures online of Sydnee Sweeney as
Speaker 7:  Taylor Swift.
Speaker 5:  Yeah Taylor Swift It there's probably the most information about on
Speaker 5:  the internet of
Speaker 6:  All add I think there's a lot of pictures of Sydnee Sweeney online.
Speaker 7:  No I think there are just the volume of time that Sidney
Speaker 7:  Sweeney has been around for and the volume of stuff that goes into training
Speaker 7:  data I think actually sit Taylor Swift appears in public more often than
Speaker 7:  Sidney Sweeney. I'm not saying there aren't a million pictures, I'm just
Speaker 7:  saying I think by volume the Taylor Swift weight is just so
Speaker 7:  incredibly high.
Speaker 5:  I think that's fair. I think that's fair. Before we wrap this up, I do wanna
Speaker 5:  talk about one other thing in AI this week. I think it's particularly
Speaker 5:  interesting that we're talking about Grok Grok I think was pulled together
Speaker 5:  very rapidly and you know there are, don't get me wrong, quite a few problems
Speaker 5:  to talk about with Grok, most of which I think are probably deliberate. But
Speaker 5:  it does show when a company you know has a pretty
Speaker 5:  singular focus on building an AI service, they, they can build it pretty
Speaker 5:  quickly and they can build a pretty decent one. It would seem, meanwhile
Speaker 5:  there's Apple And I think in the past week
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook has come out and made a couple of big statements about Apple
Speaker 5:  needing to get in the game and Alex you
Speaker 5:  thought this was pretty bold of Tim Cook, right? That the fact that the,
Speaker 5:  he came out and said they're o they're open to acquisitions, right? They're
Speaker 5:  looking at this or interested in it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. How many times have we heard Apple talk about wanting to make acquisitions?
Speaker 6:  Never. The answer is never. So it's a big deal.
Speaker 6:  I think it shows the pressure they're under, if you read the earnings call
Speaker 6:  transcript from last week, he just gets asked over and over about
Speaker 6:  AI and the threat to safari search
Speaker 6:  new devices like this is what they're hearing constantly from
Speaker 6:  investors,
Speaker 6:  you know, people in the tech industry. So yeah it shows, it shows
Speaker 6:  the pressure they're under and they're losing AI talent like crazy to these
Speaker 6:  other labs to meta to open ai et cetera.
Speaker 6:  I think Apple's in a really tough spot here. Look is anything happening with
Speaker 6:  AI right now going to make people not buy their next iPhone?
Speaker 6:  Probably not, right? Like the Pixel events coming up, I'm sure there will
Speaker 6:  be some cool AI stuff. I'm not buying a pixel still, it's gonna take a while
Speaker 6:  for that to happen in the next three to five years. Are you buying
Speaker 6:  something different or in aggregate are iPhone sales going
Speaker 6:  down because people aren't upgrading as much because they have new devices
Speaker 6:  or peripheral devices, AI, pendants et cetera.
Speaker 6:  Maybe it's not out of the realm of possibility for the first time in the
Speaker 6:  last like 15 years of the iPhone. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  Apple's on under tremendous pressure and
Speaker 6:  I'm not confident they have the leadership currently to figure it out. So
Speaker 6:  maybe they do need a big acquisition, you know, maybe they do need to go
Speaker 6:  buy one of these labs and pay a lot more
Speaker 6:  than Beats to hire a team. 'cause that's what it would be. I mean
Speaker 6:  to get one of these leading labs, you're talking tens of billions of dollars
Speaker 6:  which is something Apple's never done. I
Speaker 5:  Mean Beats gets you what like two or three researchers nowadays
Speaker 6:  A beats, yeah 3 billion that gets you three researchers. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. At least, at least with how Zuckerberg is spending it. Yeah, this Apple
Speaker 5:  thing I think is going to be fascinating to watch. It will be really
Speaker 5:  interesting to see if they actually pull the trigger on a purchase that's
Speaker 5:  like pretty antithetical to how Apple traditionally operates.
Speaker 5:  But I think it's a big deal and it's, it's clearly a big deal as you see
Speaker 5:  them struggling to catch up and all these reports pointing to the fact that
Speaker 5:  they are having a hard time with it. I'm
Speaker 7:  Afraid I totally understand what Apple is not catching up with. Like I understand
Speaker 7:  I'm being sort of provocative but I'm just saying I'm still not really sure
Speaker 7:  that they've actually demonstrated there's a thing they're losing out on.
Speaker 6:  I mean Siri sucks, you know Apple intelligence
Speaker 6:  is not intelligence
Speaker 7:  But I'm not clear either of those things. I don't know, I guess I'm just
Speaker 7:  not clear that anyone else has demonstrated there's necessarily going
Speaker 7:  to be still a transformative use case of
Speaker 7:  AI that I don't know makes Siri the thing that Apple has to bet its
Speaker 7:  entire future on.
Speaker 6:  I mean you spend 30 minutes talking to avo, advanced voice mode in
Speaker 6:  chat, BT and Siri is gonna feel outdated pretty fast,
Speaker 7:  But you could also just not use Siri.
Speaker 6:  Yeah but like they need, they need Siri to be relevant. You know
Speaker 6:  like there there's also this idea in the industry that apps as a concept
Speaker 6:  are gonna go away, which I think is interesting with the rise of vibe coding
Speaker 6:  but like basically the OS is like fully abstracted to
Speaker 6:  a either prompt that it's text or voice and,
Speaker 6:  and basically you know, what we think of as an operating system
Speaker 6:  becomes a much higher level and for Apple, if they have no talent
Speaker 6:  in house to build that and other people build that and it makes it literally
Speaker 6:  a dumb pane of glass more than it already is. You know,
Speaker 6:  the only thing keeping you buying an iPhone is what you like the shine of
Speaker 6:  the metal better. You like the fact that it sinks with your AirPods faster,
Speaker 6:  they lose a lot of their competitive, you know, edge in that, in that scenario.
Speaker 5:  I am really curious particularly as the models become
Speaker 5:  commoditized, right? Like what is the advantage to having their own in-house
Speaker 5:  one versus just paying for one, just using an open source one.
Speaker 6:  I think they've given up, I think that ship has sailed. I bet they do this
Speaker 6:  plug and play approach, there's all these reports of them, you know, talking
Speaker 6:  still to Gemini and Anthropic, letting people pick their models just like
Speaker 6:  they pick their search engines. You know, I, I think for now that's the path
Speaker 6:  they have to go on until we get to a point where AI is starting to
Speaker 6:  rethink how operating systems work, which is obviously a few years out, but
Speaker 6:  I think we're going there. I I mean I know people building startups in the
Speaker 6:  space that are focusing first on the desktop but
Speaker 6:  are thinking like how can we reimagine how you use your computer with AI
Speaker 6:  and apple's at risk there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think there's also just this basic element of like Addie, you're
Speaker 5:  right that there's not necessarily anything that the iPhone is
Speaker 5:  specifically missing at this point, right? Sir has been bad for a while,
Speaker 5:  can continue to be bad, but they also like came out and and
Speaker 5:  they branded this thing they put, they redefined AI as a thing with their
Speaker 5:  name built into it and so I, I do think there's just some basic
Speaker 5:  stakes that Apple has set up for itself too and
Speaker 5:  it's, it's really interesting watching them attempt to meet those and And
Speaker 5:  I think by their own account, not quite deliver. Alright, we've gotta take
Speaker 5:  a break. We'll get back talking about the age gating of the internet.
Speaker 5:  a slightly spicy subreddit. But either way a lot of
Speaker 5:  people in a lot of places are gonna have to prove that they're of
Speaker 5:  age. Is that off base? Am I in the ballpark here?
Speaker 7:  I think what we've really seen over the past couple weeks is that the first
Speaker 7:  time someone really as a country said you guys have to
Speaker 7:  all do Age Verification. That moment happened after like a decade
Speaker 7:  and so there have been over the past several, several years all of
Speaker 7:  these plans to kind of slowly creep Age Verification into things
Speaker 7:  and The UK in particular has been trying to age gate
Speaker 7:  porn for, I think I looked back and it's been a since about 2016
Speaker 7:  and they passed the online safety act and then the portion of
Speaker 7:  it that requires age gating for harmful content including adult content
Speaker 7:  but also a sort of variety of things that get posted to social media
Speaker 7:  that finally went into effect in late July. And now since then
Speaker 7:  we've just seen what actually happens and it's really weird and that there
Speaker 7:  are all these other countries that are just kind of waiting in the wings
Speaker 7:  to do this and the US is slowly starting to roll it out
Speaker 7:  across states. And so we're I think reaching this kind of tipping
Speaker 7:  point
Speaker 5:  And and The UK version almost seems like it's one of the May,
Speaker 5:  maybe I shouldn't say it's the worst case scenario GI given that it's the
Speaker 5:  first scenario we've seen, but it seems, it seems quite
Speaker 5:  controlling right? The the their definition of what needs to be
Speaker 5:  age protected is really broad. It seems to be like anywhere, any
Speaker 5:  website where a child might possibly
Speaker 5:  encounter something problematic, right? And so Blue Sky
Speaker 5:  users can't access certain features unless they
Speaker 5:  prove that they're of age. Reddit users can't
Speaker 5:  access r slash periods or r slash stop smoking
Speaker 5:  unless they prove that they're of age. Like this is like pretty wild stuff
Speaker 5:  to have to show that you're 18 to access.
Speaker 6:  Sorry is this literally you have to show a photo of your id?
Speaker 7:  Basically there are a sort of list of harmful content
Speaker 7:  things that you have to make sure that if you have them on your site
Speaker 7:  there is some kind of reasonable assurance that people looking at them are
Speaker 7:  of age. And typically what you end up doing then as
Speaker 7:  a site is you have to either say nobody from The UK can access things
Speaker 7:  or you have to say we don't have this on our site or you have to say we're
Speaker 7:  blocking this unless you go through this typically third party
Speaker 7:  service that will either have you
Speaker 7:  upload a government issued ID or use something like a credit card
Speaker 7:  or use something like a picture of your face that is you,
Speaker 7:  that is run through age estimation to see if you
Speaker 7:  look like you're of age in a like
Speaker 7:  sort of Age Verification algorithm or there are
Speaker 7:  these methods that kind of, they're using inferences from ways
Speaker 7:  that you've used your account. Like if say your ex account
Speaker 7:  is 15 years old, then they're going to guess you're
Speaker 7:  probably 18 years old. So it's this whole weird
Speaker 7:  cornucopia of different methods, some of which are easier to fool
Speaker 7:  than others. And basically the upshot is it's just
Speaker 7:  really unpredictable what people are going to post on social media. And so
Speaker 7:  if you're a social media site, you probably at this point need to run Age
Speaker 7:  Verification that Blue Sky has
Speaker 7:  in The UK limited things like dms and it will auto filter
Speaker 7:  adult content. Reddit will block a lot of sub
Speaker 7:  subreddits that are even sort of borderline content
Speaker 7:  potentially that that's ended up being things like at least as of the
Speaker 7:  time we were writing about about it our period and
Speaker 7:  there have been say violent protest footage or
Speaker 7:  other kind of material that then gets considered adult
Speaker 7:  content on services like X. So yeah, if you're in The UK you
Speaker 7:  basically, you have to give up your ID or you have to take a picture of your
Speaker 7:  face or video of your face and show it and run it through these services.
Speaker 6:  The UK is really, it's constantly impressive how
Speaker 6:  shittier they make using the internet become almost on a yearly basis
Speaker 6:  like props to The UK where the internet will continue to suck
Speaker 6:  more and more.
Speaker 5:  There are all these reports of these small websites that are just like shut,
Speaker 5:  you know, shutting down in The UK because they're, they're like, we we, we
Speaker 5:  don't know how to deal with this, we don't have the resources for this the
Speaker 5:  way that they have implemented like it is so broad and the way the
Speaker 5:  options for identifying yourself again are so there's so many
Speaker 5:  options out there and they don't necessarily have close restrictions
Speaker 5:  around them and it feels like the privacy thing is the big question
Speaker 5:  to me, right? I the idea of, okay we should
Speaker 5:  stop children from accessing porn on the internet. I don't think
Speaker 5:  that is necessarily an unreasonable contention. I do think
Speaker 5:  that every single adult who wants to access,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, information about a rated M video game needs to hand
Speaker 5:  over their ID or a face scan to some service
Speaker 5:  that can possibly then track them around the internet and tie that back to
Speaker 5:  their identity. That's very concerning. I
Speaker 7:  Think the problem is that there's not really an easy way often to,
Speaker 7:  to draw a line between those two things. Like on in
Speaker 7:  the US so far it has mostly stayed on just yet. It's PornHub, it's like
Speaker 7:  xvideo, it's a few different sites. But the problem
Speaker 7:  is that that means either you have to mean, you either have to say all right,
Speaker 7:  that means there's then no sex on social media at all. Like
Speaker 7:  you're not allowed to have in some cases artistic nudes. You're not allowed
Speaker 7:  to have say just sex workers operating on this site as humans.
Speaker 7:  You have to either then say all of these other services are getting
Speaker 7:  sanitized or you have to say look, we're going to
Speaker 7:  allow for some level of surveillance of all of these
Speaker 7:  sites. And The UK also, yeah, it's, it's that it's not just pornography,
Speaker 7:  it is also it's things like eating disorders, it's things like
Speaker 7:  suicide which are all things that it's really not good for kids to
Speaker 7:  encounter but just the nature of social media makes it really,
Speaker 7:  really difficult to automate those things away or
Speaker 7:  to say that a child is never going to encounter them in a way that could
Speaker 7:  be problematic. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right now like Wikipedia is complaining that they might have to, you
Speaker 5:  know, make some big changes as a result of this because they can't quite,
Speaker 5:  you know, guarantee that there isn't any inappropriate information because
Speaker 5:  Wikipedia is a user generated content platform
Speaker 7:  And outside Wikipedia there's also just, there are the problems of profit
Speaker 7:  motives like that there are these services and these services cost
Speaker 7:  money, these verification services and these services also, this is
Speaker 7:  all a commercial operation and there is a lot of incentive to collect as
Speaker 7:  much data as you can and to either cut corners with that
Speaker 7:  data because you are trying to make money off
Speaker 7:  of this thing you're using or to just actually use that
Speaker 7:  information to target advertisements or to
Speaker 7:  otherwise like just run a commercial service. And obvi like
Speaker 7:  companies will absolutely promise privacy but just we've seen
Speaker 7:  real security breaches. We've seen like Twitter for instance
Speaker 7:  was under consent decreed part because it would use
Speaker 7:  information that you provided as like security phone numbers
Speaker 7:  for commercial purposes. Like we just understand how all these
Speaker 7:  systems work and how all these incentives work and they're just throwing
Speaker 7:  something into a system that is in a lot of ways
Speaker 7:  filled with perverse incentives and demanding that it work. Well
Speaker 6:  You're saying Europe doesn't understand tech regulation? Shocker,
Speaker 7:  This is the funny thing is I actually think the EU is doing better even though
Speaker 7:  the, so the EU is running a pilot program that its deal
Speaker 7:  is look, we also, we have Age Verification And I personally, I
Speaker 7:  believe that Age Verification is in a lot of ways fundamentally flawed, but
Speaker 7:  they're at least saying we also have this technical system that we're trying
Speaker 7:  to build that's just gonna be a best pr like a system anybody could
Speaker 7:  deploy that's going to ideally mean that somebody uploads
Speaker 7:  their passport once to a service and then that service is
Speaker 7:  held to a sort of like it runs on best practices and
Speaker 7:  all that service does then is tell a site whether or not
Speaker 7:  you're 18. And that this makes it In theory
Speaker 7:  easier for the, for the websites. They just know that there's
Speaker 7:  something that they can use that they don't have to go and find this third
Speaker 7:  party verifier and that they are not
Speaker 7:  relying on just this private sector development of
Speaker 7:  all of these weird different options. So I think the EU in some ways is
Speaker 7:  doing a better job than The UK potentially.
Speaker 5:  Well so do we expect this to spread more broadly in the EU? Because right
Speaker 5:  now this is like five states are testing an app
Speaker 5:  And I don't, I don't know where where it goes next. Is it, is this a legal
Speaker 5:  requirement or 'cause they've been pushing this right? I think this seems
Speaker 5:  to be kind of like everywhere in the world
Speaker 5:  they, they there's an increased momentum toward age gating things.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Australia has, I believe also determined that they're going to be age
Speaker 7:  gating search engines in the future for
Speaker 7:  if you want basically safe search off. I think it's a little bit hard to
Speaker 7:  tell. I think on one hand it seems like all this stuff is becoming
Speaker 7:  kind of inevitable. On the other hand The UK
Speaker 7:  has been, it seems like kind of a mess and none of this is I think totally
Speaker 7:  inevitable. I think it is possible that now we are seeing this is what happens
Speaker 7:  when this rolls out and it turns out it's really messy and there are a lot
Speaker 7:  of problems and we are seeing really some of the first real life test
Speaker 7:  cases of it and it's possible that that will make it possible
Speaker 7:  to shape how future rollouts work.
Speaker 5:  So I wanna touch on the US too, and this is about a month old at this point,
Speaker 5:  but you covered the Supreme Court's ruling that
Speaker 5:  age gating porn websites is, is allowable into the first amendment
Speaker 5:  And I think at this point, what is it like a third of all US states
Speaker 5:  have laws that require Age Verification for porn.
Speaker 5:  So it feels like this is going to expand in the US it's not clear to me if
Speaker 5:  it's going to expand beyond adult content in the same way I, I'm
Speaker 5:  curious what the ruling even allows.
Speaker 7:  The ruling really specifically deals with content that is obscene to
Speaker 7:  minors, which is a very specifically
Speaker 7:  this is pornography. I think that there
Speaker 7:  are probably ways you can kind of find wiggle room around that to
Speaker 7:  try to impose regulations more broadly. But it's a a
Speaker 7:  pretty different court case. I have talked to people for the last
Speaker 7:  months or year about, well what happens if Age
Speaker 7:  Verification for porn is allowed? Does that mean you can just age gate social
Speaker 7:  media? And the consensus has been, it's possible that will happen,
Speaker 7:  but it's a pretty different court case and that you have to just do a completely
Speaker 7:  different weighing of what are the privacy risks versus the
Speaker 7:  harms that you're trying to prevent. But we've definitely seen
Speaker 7:  states try to pass regulations for social media
Speaker 7:  and so it seems inevitable that it's going to get up to the Supreme Court.
Speaker 5:  Yeah because it seems, right. 'cause you could just say there's porn on Blue
Speaker 5:  Sky, right? You could easily just make that argument that okay, now this
Speaker 5:  entire platform needs to be age G and right
Speaker 5:  Reddit, right? You, you could have to age educate the entire
Speaker 5:  platform. I guess maybe this, maybe this starts to just slice off
Speaker 5:  chunks of these platforms somehow. I
Speaker 7:  Mean so far this actual laws have all basically set a threshold that's like
Speaker 7:  is one third of the content on the site adult.
Speaker 7:  And I think that it's basically been understood that social media
Speaker 7:  platforms don't fall under that. But I think the thing that's gonna mean
Speaker 7:  maybe the next issue is there have been laws passed that are basically
Speaker 7:  requiring Age Verification on app stores
Speaker 7:  that those are going to, I think probably end up going
Speaker 7:  to the Supreme Court. It's I believe Utah and
Speaker 7:  Texas
Speaker 7:  that are saying that if you operate an app store, like
Speaker 7:  a mobile app store specifically, you have to have a system
Speaker 7:  by which you can guarantee that people are over 18.
Speaker 7:  And that basically the legal issue there is
Speaker 7:  going to turn out to be is this unduly burdening speech
Speaker 7:  in a way that is unique from the concerns of like the,
Speaker 7:  it is fair to restrict access to obscene
Speaker 7:  content. I mean I think the Supreme Court right now kind of operates just
Speaker 7:  on really weird vibes and so it seems plausible that they're just going to
Speaker 7:  say yes, that's fine.
Speaker 7:  And so at that point I think we're gonna have to start looking
Speaker 7:  a lot more closely at how all of this is just going to end up getting implemented.
Speaker 7:  The
Speaker 5:  App store thing is really interesting because I think a, a lot of the tech
Speaker 5:  companies who do not operate app stores such as Meta are really pushing for
Speaker 5:  this because it seems like a way for them to pass the buck a little bit,
Speaker 5:  right? Alex, I think you've covered this from meta where
Speaker 5:  they've, they've been pushing for Apple to implement these requirements
Speaker 5:  and they've been kind of trying to like guilt them into it a little bit.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it, their comparison, which I think is an
Speaker 6:  apt one, is like, you know, you age gate, someone's ability to drive a car,
Speaker 6:  you don't age gate. Like you don't force the roads to age
Speaker 6:  gate everyone as they drive down the road, you age gate the ability to
Speaker 6:  drive the car and what is the car in this analogy, it's the phone.
Speaker 6:  So if you really wanted to solve this, which Apple in particular
Speaker 6:  is aggressively lobbying against in the United States is you would force
Speaker 6:  the phone platforms to age gate at the device layer.
Speaker 7:  I gotta say as a metaphor, this makes no sense to me. It's not like cars
Speaker 7:  are required to tell, tell whether you're 16.
Speaker 6:  I I did get barely any sleep Addie writing about open ai. So maybe it doesn't
Speaker 6:  make sense, but I think conceptually
Speaker 6:  what makes sense to me is gating at the
Speaker 6:  root, which is the device and not
Speaker 6:  gating all over the web and chopping up the web. It
Speaker 6:  just, I don't think you should g it all to be frank. Like I think this should,
Speaker 6:  you know, what would solve this whole discussion is you make parents liable
Speaker 6:  for what their kids do. And if you, if we've decided as a society
Speaker 6:  that it's evil or bad or harmful for kids to look at porn,
Speaker 6:  guess who should be liable for that? Should be their fucking parents. It
Speaker 6:  shouldn't be these platforms. That's, that's my view of it all.
Speaker 6:  But
Speaker 6:  yeah, I, if you're going to gate, why not gate at the device? I think that's
Speaker 6:  a reasonable,
Speaker 7:  I think that there are a lot of good an I think that I agree with you that
Speaker 7:  there's a really good reason pragmatically to say that look,
Speaker 7:  you can probably create a better system using devices
Speaker 7:  than you can like regulating or you can like
Speaker 7:  verifying ages on every service at the same time. I think
Speaker 7:  in some ways, like my biggest problem with this is that it just means that
Speaker 7:  basically everything has to route through an app or an app store at this
Speaker 7:  point that it means that just trying to make a thing that works on a
Speaker 7:  desktop for instance, like it means that
Speaker 7:  ultimately you're just saying desktop desktops and websites don't
Speaker 7:  matter. It's really strange. Like I think it basically
Speaker 7:  just assumes, okay, look most people are using phones, most kids are using
Speaker 7:  phones, that's fine. And so we're just getting like the broad, we're getting
Speaker 7:  most people and that's enough. But if you push this far enough, what you're
Speaker 7:  saying basically is just any content on the internet has to at some point
Speaker 7:  be verified through like Tim Cook or Sundar Phai.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. To be clear, I think this is all a horrible idea. Like gating at
Speaker 6:  all is a horrible idea. But if you were going to do it, it would be the most
Speaker 6:  consistent to do it at the device layer. It shouldn't happen at all. But
Speaker 6:  that would be the most consistent.
Speaker 7:  And the US also has the just very particular issue of
Speaker 7:  the major party platform is banning pornography entirely.
Speaker 7:  Like The UK and the EU are not both engaged in
Speaker 7:  a just really massive surveillance state building
Speaker 7:  operation right now, or an attempt to make like
Speaker 7:  drag shows illegal. So the US has kind of its own whole set of
Speaker 7:  problems where like even things like I think the EU building
Speaker 7:  a, trying to build a sort of government solution for verification
Speaker 7:  is really good if you have a good faith belief in the
Speaker 7:  government and that the government is going to protect your privacy, I think
Speaker 7:  that even something like that just doesn't work well in the US. Google
Speaker 5:  Did this weird thing this week where they announced that they were gonna
Speaker 5:  start like just trying to like size people up to see if they were kids
Speaker 5:  or not and if, and if if they, if they just like think that you're
Speaker 5:  not 18, they're gonna put like certain restrictions on your account. And
Speaker 5:  this is, this seems to be just entirely voluntary And I, I I guess I'm wondering
Speaker 5:  at this point if, if this is like they're just trying to, you know, look
Speaker 5:  responsible so that some of these maybe worst case scenarios don't come
Speaker 5:  to pass.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they're trying to get ahead of regulation. This is what they've done
Speaker 6:  time and time again with other things, other kind of
Speaker 6:  regulatory movements. The biggest companies will do it on their own
Speaker 6:  and it will be impossible or weighed more difficult for
Speaker 6:  startups to, to do it. That's how this all goes with regulation.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm very concerned about where this is going. The fact that this has
Speaker 5:  actually gone into practice and that we are seeing the fallout
Speaker 5:  be so broad and widespread and that we're seeing
Speaker 5:  major mainstream websites getting blocked is, is kind of horrifying.
Speaker 5:  And I think the fact that we're seeing an escalation in the US where more
Speaker 5:  and more states are passing laws and added to your point, there's
Speaker 5:  an overall movement to crack down on anything that
Speaker 5:  one of the major political parties thinks is a little too
Speaker 5:  edgy. It can lead to some very bad places, but it, it's, I think it's maybe
Speaker 5:  encouraging to hear that you think that this is not necessarily a done deal
Speaker 5:  that The UK is maybe just take it taking a, a a
Speaker 5:  a first swing at this and the US may not
Speaker 5:  be able to get that far.
Speaker 7:  I mean, the US is way more chaotic. The UK there has been
Speaker 7:  a request for a petition for, I believe parliament has to respond
Speaker 7:  to, to like reevaluating this. That does not necessarily mean
Speaker 7:  anything, but it does mean that there is public pushback to it.
Speaker 7:  I think that unfortunately if this is just like anything else
Speaker 7:  that's happened to pri with privacy on the internet, it means that maybe
Speaker 7:  some things are going to loosen up some, But that this is still probably
Speaker 7:  here to stay. I think that I haven't seen really a ratchet away
Speaker 7:  from privacy invasions on the internet since I've been working here.
Speaker 7:  I, that sounds really dor, I'm sorry,
Speaker 7:  but I am hoping that around the edges people can shape things and that if
Speaker 7:  this does screw up badly enough, maybe I will be proven wrong.
Speaker 5:  There we go. UK do a worse job.
Speaker 5:  All right, we gotta take a break when we get back
Speaker 5:  some sort of round, maybe there's lightning. We'll see
Speaker 5:  we've been doing some work, some,
Speaker 7:  Alright, so my first story is that
Speaker 7:  RFK has pulled $500 million in funding for mRNA vaccine
Speaker 7:  contract contracts. The announced it, this
Speaker 7:  is via NPR. The Department of Health and Human Services
Speaker 7:  will cancel contracts and pull funding for some vaccines that are being developed
Speaker 7:  to fight respiratory ve va viruses
Speaker 5:  COVID shot this, this fall, right? Like they changed the rules
Speaker 5:  and Right. I've just been getting the, the COVID shot and the flu shot at
Speaker 5:  the same time. I don't wanna get the flu. It's not cool. And
Speaker 5:  it's, it's not clear if that's a, I mean hopefully the flu shot is still
Speaker 5:  available. We'll find out. The COVID one is not clear. It's gonna happen
Speaker 5:  and yeah, I I it their vaccine strategy just seems to be
Speaker 5:  don't do it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean, so Lauren Leer has done a lot of really good work for us on
Speaker 7:  RFK and vaccines and basically he just believes that
Speaker 7:  if you die from a virus, you we're weak. That
Speaker 7:  sounds like a, a horrible mischaracter characterization of someone. That
Speaker 7:  sounds like a horrible, mean-spirited thing to say. That is just what he
Speaker 7:  keeps saying,
Speaker 5:  Pointing out the hypocrisy of the Trump administration.
Speaker 5:  I I realize that does not get very far. I do find
Speaker 5:  this one to be particularly striking
Speaker 5:  because if you go back to Trump's first term,
Speaker 5:  it, listen, you don't have to hand it to them for how they handled COVID.
Speaker 5:  However, one of the successes was
Speaker 5:  the mRNA vaccines, right? They got the
Speaker 5:  COVID vaccine developed fairly rapidly. They got it distributed fairly
Speaker 5:  rapidly. This is something that Trump in another
Speaker 5:  world would be touting, would be taking credit for. It would be boasting,
Speaker 5:  right? This is a, this is a, a new technology that has
Speaker 5:  some incredible potential impacts for
Speaker 5:  vaccinations. And after spearheading
Speaker 5:  this push for it in his, at the very tail end of his first term, which he
Speaker 5:  seems to totally regret, he's now hired somebody who's just wildly
Speaker 5:  undermining that, right? We we're just mRNA all this
Speaker 5:  potential. It, it feels like we are just setting this work back by, I mean,
Speaker 5:  at a minimum three years and potentially vastly longer.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it was one of absolutely the best things he did around COVID. It was
Speaker 7:  an incredible technological development and it's just,
Speaker 7:  it's also such incredibly just, it's such a waste.
Speaker 7:  The, again, $500 million is nothing like, the only reason
Speaker 7:  to do this is just that you hate vaccines. Even if you believe there's
Speaker 7:  a 99% chance this, none of this is worthwhile, which I
Speaker 7:  believe is really pretty clearly not correct. That's just
Speaker 7:  barely any money for the government.
Speaker 5:  It really is. And the other thing that I've seen Kennedy complain about is,
Speaker 5:  and this is not true, but among his complaints are that
Speaker 5:  we need to do more testing on the vaccines. We need to see if they're safe.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, okay, we know what this money is used for,
Speaker 5:  right? Vaccine testing is part of this. We make sure the
Speaker 5:  vaccines work. They're very thoroughly tested. And so
Speaker 5:  this, this really does just come from this
Speaker 5:  bewildering place of not wanting to help
Speaker 5:  people not get sick, which is, is upsetting
Speaker 5:  to say the least,
Speaker 7:  Right? It is. It's, I mean, everything here is just in absolute
Speaker 7:  transparent, bad faith and that it's that he
Speaker 7:  believes that if you get sick, like
Speaker 7:  the thing that matters isn't making you well, it's making sure that your
Speaker 7:  body is in some way intrinsically strong.
Speaker 7:  Because if someone whose body is weak, is
Speaker 7:  healed or doesn't get sick, then that's actually just, I mean
Speaker 7:  it's just eugenics. Like it's, it's really
Speaker 7:  straightforwardly just eugenics and it's really a
Speaker 7:  disgrace.
Speaker 5:  It's very, very bad. And I think just startling, startling to see
Speaker 5:  what a change of tone the Trump administration has had on
Speaker 5:  mRNA from the end of their first term to this new term.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Alex, what have you got for us?
Speaker 6:  So while we've been talking, I've also been looking at the reaction to
Speaker 6:  open AIS g TP five
Speaker 6:  stream and it looks like they have been vibe graphing
Speaker 6:  and doing some really insane chart crime.
Speaker 6:  I want to call out two specific things that people have noticed. The first
Speaker 6:  one is Thiswe bench benchmark, which is
Speaker 6:  this kind of industry standard coding benchmark for
Speaker 6:  LLMs. Apparently GTP five actually does worse
Speaker 6:  than O three on this, but the bar chart
Speaker 6:  that they put in the stream makes it look like it's better.
Speaker 6:  Like it's a taller bar even though the number is less
Speaker 6:  than oh three, which is not great. And then perhaps there's
Speaker 6:  apparently several of these. But then the worst one is when there,
Speaker 6:  there's a chart about hallucinations, actually it's called
Speaker 6:  deception across models. And the
Speaker 6:  coding deception one G TP five scores a 50.
Speaker 6:  They don't explain what this score means except deception rate. There's
Speaker 6:  no, there's there's only one axis and it's just called deception rate. G
Speaker 6:  TP five scores. A 50 and oh three scored a
Speaker 6:  47.4. But the bar for oh three is
Speaker 6:  like more than double the height of GTP five. You really have to
Speaker 6:  see this. We'll have the links in the show notes with the, with the images,
Speaker 6:  but it basically makes it look like if you just glance at this bar chart
Speaker 6:  that G TP five is materially
Speaker 6:  better at not hallucinating on cogen, when in
Speaker 6:  reality it's worse. And this is literally a bar chart called
Speaker 6:  deception across models. So these are incredible.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, not not good.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna call this these vibe graphing. These are
Speaker 5:  Vibe graphing is good. Vibe graphing is an a, a really good
Speaker 5:  excuse for, Hey, why did, why did you turn in information that's completely
Speaker 5:  wrong while I was being efficient? I vibe graphed it. I mean listen,
Speaker 5:  these are graphs. They just don't make any sense. These are
Speaker 5:  bewildering. There's no consistency. The the
Speaker 5:  the highest number I is not in the highest
Speaker 5:  spot. I don't understand what's happening. Things are just randomly
Speaker 5:  colored. This is, this is but
Speaker 5:  very confusing and maybe suggest why this presentation
Speaker 5:  was a little confusing overall. I'm wondering if, if these are like, if
Speaker 5:  they, are they trying to hide it or they just, do they just not know how
Speaker 5:  to make a graph? It could be vibe graphed.
Speaker 6:  Either answer is really bad to that question.
Speaker 6:  Like either way it's really bad. So
Speaker 6:  yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I'm staring at two boxes of the exact same size and one says
Speaker 7:  69.1 and one says 30.8 and they're right next to each other
Speaker 7:  and they're both smaller than the one that's 52.
Speaker 5:  I'm honestly, this is an impressive level of inconsistent.
Speaker 5:  Like the, the truly, the only consistent thing about this is that everything
Speaker 5:  is wrong. It is amazing.
Speaker 6:  I just love that it's really wrong on a chart about deception.
Speaker 5:  I do have an important question here, which is what's the right deception
Speaker 5:  rate? What number are we feeling is good here?
Speaker 6:  Preferably I would like zero from the thing that
Speaker 6:  apparently is okay to give me medical advice from preferably zero.
Speaker 5:  Right? They had an extended segment on using this for medical advice. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And this says the deception rate is 50.
Speaker 6:  Sam Alman literally brought, I dunno what
Speaker 5:  Means
Speaker 6:  He literally brought an employee's spouse on stage who had been diagnosed
Speaker 6:  with like three cancers and was like talking about how Chet
Speaker 6:  BT had helped her navigate her diagnosis. And then, yeah. And
Speaker 6:  then in the same presentation they show a deception rate
Speaker 6:  graph that is intentionally very deceiving.
Speaker 5:  I have to tell you, I've been very bullish on chat TP T and now
Speaker 5:  that they have presented a nonsense chart that says their
Speaker 5:  deception rate is 50 th this is, this is
Speaker 5:  done the most to tell me that I should use this thing less. Jake,
Speaker 6:  It's not even that the deception rate is 50, it's that the bar is less
Speaker 6:  than half as tall as the last model, which
Speaker 6:  was actually better at not deceiving. So
Speaker 6:  it's made to look on the bar chart, like it's way better
Speaker 6:  when it's actually worse.
Speaker 5:  Chachi BT five.
Speaker 5:  Honestly you know what though? This speaks to how good it is at
Speaker 5:  deception. We were fooled. We didn't notice.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  Don't remember. They're gonna listen if they keep this up by, by the next
Speaker 5:  model, these charts, we won't even notice how how off these
Speaker 5:  charts are. The higher the deception is actually the lower the deception
Speaker 5:  score goes because you don't realize that it's fooling you. Vibe charting.
Speaker 5:  This is, yeah, 50% is exactly the middle where you're like, you're like,
Speaker 5:  you catch it but you gotta squint. Okay,
Speaker 5:  Next story.
Speaker 5:  Tariff crisis across the globe, but
Speaker 5:  specifically in the United States, we've been talking about tariffs for a
Speaker 5:  while now. Not an super exciting
Speaker 5:  for our wallets. I, this really, I think hit in a very
Speaker 5:  material way in the past week number one because quite literally
Speaker 5:  Trump's tariffs did go into force I believe Thursday morning.
Speaker 5:  But most notably we actually saw a bunch of companies raising prices and
Speaker 5:  raising them pretty significantly. I think probably the biggest one that
Speaker 5:  most people are gonna experience is that Nintendo raise the price on a bunch
Speaker 5:  of switch hardware, including the switch one, the original one,
Speaker 5:  it's going up in price by $30. And some of the other models
Speaker 5:  including switch ole and switch light, they're going up in price two,
Speaker 5:  a bunch of accessories are going, going up in price. They did not raise the
Speaker 5:  price on the switch two, which I'm assuming is because that thing is
Speaker 5:  already very expensive and they do not want that to look worse.
Speaker 5:  But this keeps going, right? Fujifilm, they raised
Speaker 5:  one of their cameras went up in price by $800.
Speaker 5:  Now this is already a very expensive camera, it was a medium format camera.
Speaker 5:  But what is happening? This, this is a lot of money.
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook is on, you know Tim Cook actually he, he hung out with Trump this
Speaker 5:  week and he, him this beautiful statue
Speaker 5:  that he made with like a, oh god, a 24 karat gold base.
Speaker 6:  How are we not gonna mention this? Thank you for mentioning this, this, this.
Speaker 6:  We should have led with this.
Speaker 5:  We should have led with this. Yeah. 'cause he went to the White House to
Speaker 5:  announce this big, you know, American manufacturing push. My God, God. But
Speaker 5:  before he did this, he announced that they're blowing a billion dollars
Speaker 5:  just this quarter on tariffs.
Speaker 6:  Well, clearly what needs to happen is any company that is raising its prices
Speaker 6:  because of tariffs, you know, Sonos is another example. This week
Speaker 6:  you need to bring a solid gold version of your product to the White House.
Speaker 6:  You need to set it on the desk in the Oval Office and you need to do a photo
Speaker 6:  op with Trump. That is how you avoid tariffs. So Sonos, they
Speaker 5:  Put Trump's name on
Speaker 6:  It. Yeah. So Sonos ndo, get on it. Solid gold switch,
Speaker 6:  solid goes solid gold Sonos. Make it happen.
Speaker 5:  Addie, am I wrong? I I think that what he described actually
Speaker 5:  is the new tariff policy. Like didn't he announce this? That if you just
Speaker 5:  like make, make Trump happy, he will waive the
Speaker 6:  Tariffs. Chachi PT told me he did. So let's just scroll with it. Okay?
Speaker 7:  Is that he also announced a new tariff during the Apple thing, but then was
Speaker 7:  like the tariff won't apply. If you build in the US there's gonna be a hundred
Speaker 7:  percent tariff on semiconductors. But if you build in the us there's not
Speaker 7:  we and like everything, it's incredibly ambiguous
Speaker 7:  what that means,
Speaker 5:  Right? It's like if you say you will build in the US if you like make a good
Speaker 5:  effort and maybe bring a gold bar to the White House, you will not get tariffed
Speaker 7:  Five tariffs.
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook, he, he somehow, he is playing both sides of
Speaker 5:  this, right? Everyone is afraid to trash talk the tariffs.
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook, he's on the earnings call, he's like, these we're right, we
Speaker 5:  are wasting a bunch of cash on tariffs. He said this two quarters in
Speaker 5:  a row. Then he just goes to the White House and he is like, we're all good,
Speaker 5:  we're all good. And it's sort of weird, like for, for them in particular.
Speaker 5:  I if if those, I mean again, big if, if these 100%
Speaker 5:  semiconductor tariffs do actually happen. They have an apple
Speaker 5:  loophole built in like that is what it is, right? They they were
Speaker 5:  like Apple, you said you're gonna build stuff in the US so we was, we won't
Speaker 5:  apply this to you. Right? That's, that's like fantastic for
Speaker 5:  Apple's business.
Speaker 7:  Tim Cook is really good at hitting that middle point where he doesn't seem
Speaker 7:  like a threat to Trump. But also he doesn't make Trump
Speaker 7:  mad.
Speaker 7:  He's very good at this. I don't really mean that as a compliment.
Speaker 5:  And this is how you get to him presenting a statue to Donald Trump.
Speaker 5:  I I was bewildered by this thing. So
Speaker 5:  in it there's a 24 carat gold base, which Tim Cook
Speaker 5:  said was from Utah, right? American made
Speaker 5:  gold and then on top of it is this big like circle of
Speaker 5:  glass that is from Corning, which is where they're gonna get the American
Speaker 5:  made glass for iPhones and for unknown reasons,
Speaker 5:  this piece of glass just says Donald Trump on it and has
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook's signature on it and it, it's like, I guess it's
Speaker 5:  commemorating that Apple is going to build in the US and they're giving it
Speaker 5:  to him for some reason because they
Speaker 5:  did a photo op at the White House. It's very funny, it came in like an Apple
Speaker 5:  product box that he like opened up on, you know,
Speaker 5:  the, the desk in the Oval Office.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it was quite a presentation. Did
Speaker 7:  We mention Trump is gonna have a competing phone out this year? Supposedly
Speaker 5:  Things are gonna get spicy between those two. It's gonna
Speaker 5:  be an interesting year if the Trump phone really does
Speaker 5:  take on the iPhone. Okay. Right under the buzzer. Addie,
Speaker 5:  what's next? Alright.
Speaker 7:  Sometimes it's fun to just have some old fashioned legal drama that's not
Speaker 7:  going to result in a baffling Supreme Court ruling. And it is that
Speaker 7:  Epic has beaten Google in court again, the ninth
Speaker 7:  Circuit court of appeals on July 31st said it
Speaker 7:  would not overturn the unanimous jury verdict from 2023 that
Speaker 7:  Google's app store and payment apps are illegal monopolies. And
Speaker 7:  Google now has at this point a few weeks, it could
Speaker 7:  get extended time to start cracking open the app store
Speaker 7:  by not requiring people to use Google Pay billing. And by
Speaker 7:  not enforcing anti steering rules that stop people from stop app developers,
Speaker 7:  from directing users outside the store, it still does not have
Speaker 7:  to implement the really extreme stuff yet, like
Speaker 7:  allowing third party stores in the Google Play Store. But it's a pretty
Speaker 7:  significant loss, especially compared to how Epic's case
Speaker 7:  went with Apple where Epic mostly lost.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean this is, this is like potentially huge and it sounds like it's,
Speaker 5:  it's still it we're what are we waiting on, right? It's like, is the, is
Speaker 5:  if the Supreme Court decides to hear it or not for
Speaker 7:  The really short term we're waiting to see if they appeal and then
Speaker 7:  are granted a stay on having to implement this
Speaker 7:  stuff while Yeah, we find out if it goes up to the Supreme Court. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But this is like monumental, right, that you said
Speaker 5:  the bigger stuff doesn't come into effect but that's, that's, it's just 'cause
Speaker 5:  it has a longer timeline. Like they gave Google more time to do it. Whereas
Speaker 5:  Google is like basically out of time on this immediate stuff. The immediate
Speaker 5:  stuff doesn't feel like as huge of a deal to me. Like it, these are
Speaker 5:  important but the, the next
Speaker 5:  set of impacts fully crack open
Speaker 5:  the Google Play store. And I think it's so interesting because Android is,
Speaker 5:  it's an open platform. You can do whatever you want And I used to think it's
Speaker 5:  like very, it was very surprising to me at least
Speaker 5:  that Apple, which has a fully locked down platform, mostly
Speaker 5:  one and Google, which has an open,
Speaker 5:  if you know, strangle held platform
Speaker 5:  mostly lost. But on Google, on on Android, you
Speaker 5:  can install whatever you want. You just have to jump through a bunch of hoops.
Speaker 5:  But these new systems will allow you to just
Speaker 5:  download another app store through the play store and that new app store
Speaker 5:  can be fed by the play store, if I'm remembering this all correctly, which
Speaker 5:  just sort of like monumentally shakes things up, right? Like Android
Speaker 5:  is an open system, but the reason that Google is able to
Speaker 5:  maintain it is that it's apps are so powerful and so
Speaker 5:  important and the Play Store is really at the center of that in a lot of
Speaker 5:  ways.
Speaker 7:  It also impacts the way that they can make deals for pre-installation
Speaker 7:  on say Android phones and with carriers. So it,
Speaker 7:  and that that's just another huge part of their ecosystem.
Speaker 5:  This is wild. I I think Android is going to
Speaker 5:  potentially change dramatically if this goes into effect
Speaker 5:  or at least the way that Google handles it. Will I, I
Speaker 5:  generally think, again, I am surprised that
Speaker 5:  Google is losing more than Apple here. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Me too.
Speaker 7:  We have a really good piece about this. It is partly, I think it's
Speaker 7:  specifically the thing you mentioned is why they lost, which is that Apple
Speaker 7:  could make a really credible case that we have created this incredibly locked
Speaker 7:  down ecosystem. It's central to our business model. We have all these
Speaker 7:  security concerns and Google, by being kind of halfway there,
Speaker 7:  it made it seem more like it was putting up hoops.
Speaker 7:  But I believe it's Sean who, who has a really very good comparison
Speaker 7:  of why Apple won and Google lost.
Speaker 5:  I I would love to see both of these ecosystems open up in a big way
Speaker 5:  and it's, again, it's surprising to me that is really interesting. It's really
Speaker 5:  interesting that by being a little more open, but it really has always been
Speaker 5:  sort of, it's, it's been a little fake. Like I, I've gotten a chance
Speaker 5:  to look at the, at the terms of the deals that Google has with mobile carriers
Speaker 5:  and you start to realize that Android is is only
Speaker 5:  sort of theirs, right? Like they have to,
Speaker 5:  right? They make carriers or they, they make phone operators basically agree
Speaker 5:  to these deals and if they want the play store, which of course they want
Speaker 5:  the Play store, that's where all the apps are. You gotta put Gmail in
Speaker 5:  a certain spot on your phone. You gotta put Google Docs in a certain spot
Speaker 5:  in your phone. It specifies where the folders can go, specifies how many
Speaker 5:  levels deep the folders can be. It specifies on which page of the home screen
Speaker 5:  it is and you start, I guess that clearly hurt
Speaker 5:  them in court when you, when you look at these terms and you go, oh this
Speaker 5:  is not, this is not as open as it is supposed to be
Speaker 5:  and it will be very interesting next year if these things actually go
Speaker 5:  into effect and we'll get to see what happens if that Android really opens
Speaker 5:  up to a much more dramatic degree than it currently is in practice.
Speaker 5:  Alright Alex,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna try to end us without the thunder on the last one since we have
Speaker 6:  failed at every turn on that
Speaker 6:  Instagram rolled out an update that naturally has caused
Speaker 6:  a ton of uproar. They added a map to
Speaker 6:  Instagram, it's like the snap map where you can see
Speaker 6:  people that you follow on a map and
Speaker 6:  naturally people freaked out and Instagram has
Speaker 6:  had to do a bunch of messaging around it. Apparently the,
Speaker 6:  I don't know if either of you guys have gone through the process of opening
Speaker 6:  this map is pretty confusing as to who you're sharing with and
Speaker 6:  what context. And apparently if you would tag a
Speaker 6:  location on a story that you shared that would show up as if you were on
Speaker 6:  the map at that specific location from, so there was a bunch of like just
Speaker 6:  bad design stuff. Meta's been stressing, look, it's all opt-in. We
Speaker 6:  had like double opt-in but apparently they would also show you
Speaker 6:  on the map even before you had opted in, which made people naturally
Speaker 6:  think that they had already opted in to sharing their location with their
Speaker 6:  entire Instagram friend list.
Speaker 6:  And I would just like to point out that there's just an inherent fall in
Speaker 6:  this where like your Instagram social graph, who
Speaker 6:  you follow. Yes. Are there people there, you know, very close
Speaker 6:  friends, family members, significant others that you would be
Speaker 6:  comfortable sharing your location with? Probably for a lot of people
Speaker 6:  Is anyone wanting to share their location with even a significant
Speaker 6:  percentage of their Instagram following list? I'm going to guess
Speaker 6:  no. And the fact that it's on you to curate that and to go, oh,
Speaker 6:  they're on a certain list, they're on close friends or whatever, just puts
Speaker 6:  a lot of work on the user and like, I think what Snap has done is that people
Speaker 6:  just use it for a different reason. Like people don't, it's not such a huge
Speaker 6:  broadcast platform where you're following a ton of people in
Speaker 6:  this way. And so Instagram's trying to shoehorn this
Speaker 6:  interface into a social network that's just not really built for this
Speaker 6:  level of intimacy. And I think that's what they're experiencing right now.
Speaker 6:  But also like they should have done better messaging. This, you
Speaker 6:  know, the, the onboarding seemed confusing and it's become like a meme
Speaker 6:  that, you know, Instagram is showing you on the map. Now
Speaker 5:  I I have to say they have had eight years I believe
Speaker 5:  to rip off Snap Maps. Yeah, It is rough that
Speaker 5:  they could not do it right, like that, that is
Speaker 5:  pretty, pretty bad that they, they're basically just lifting
Speaker 5:  a feature and it's still bewildering and a bad user experience
Speaker 5:  And I believe they've been testing this for months too. Yeah, I do think
Speaker 5:  your point about the, the
Speaker 5:  following list on both platforms inherently being different
Speaker 5:  is really interesting. 'cause I've always, like I, I'm like a
Speaker 5:  little bit above Snapchat age and so I, this is not a platform that I
Speaker 5:  have used with any regularity and so the Snap Maps thing has
Speaker 5:  never really been appealing to me or made sense to me. But you're right,
Speaker 5:  the, if you're using Snapchat you have a much tighter friend group,
Speaker 5:  right? You don't have to worry about that in the same way as Instagram, which
Speaker 5:  for the past several for, for a while now has pushed you to have this
Speaker 5:  much broader relationship, right? It is the influencer platform. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that is just not true in the same way on Snap. Yeah
Speaker 6:  And look, I'm sure people will use it. Instagram is huge. It has
Speaker 6:  billions of users. I'm sure there are people with Fence
Speaker 6:  does who, you know, keep their fragrance, who keep their friend list
Speaker 6:  super tight and curated and will use the map. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, they definitely could have rolled this one out better.
Speaker 5:  Addie you big on broadcasting your location to everybody. You know,
Speaker 7:  Any service that has a location tracking feature whenever anyone is building
Speaker 7:  it at a website at at an app developer, there should be like
Speaker 7:  a button that they have to break glass with their bare hands
Speaker 7:  to deploy it with. You should not share people's
Speaker 7:  locations unless you really, really have to. And it should be as painful
Speaker 7:  for you as possible to have the rollout.
Speaker 6:  Again, they, there is like a double opt-in consent flow for this. So
Speaker 6:  they are saying, but it's the way they presented it and like the fact that
Speaker 6:  you showed up on the map before you consented even though other people weren't
Speaker 6:  visible, which then of course is gonna make someone think, oh I am already
Speaker 6:  sharing even though I haven't opted in. It's more about the UI and the way
Speaker 6:  that, but they were not literally opting in everyone to sharing their location
Speaker 6:  on the map.
Speaker 7:  Oh no, I'm not saying that the people should have, I'm saying that the developers
Speaker 7:  should have to break the glass with their bare hands. You just shouldn't
Speaker 7:  track people's location and social networks.
Speaker 5:  There's also like something going on with meta platforms that
Speaker 5:  there's this thing on Meta's AI app where you have to hit like
Speaker 5:  a gigantic share button to share your stuff to the feed
Speaker 5:  publicly and people still hit it on really personal
Speaker 5:  stuff that they're talking about with ai. So there's just some extent to
Speaker 5:  which like, I don't know if it's that platform or that platform is user base,
Speaker 5:  but you gotta be careful and people clearly are not,
Speaker 5:  even if the thing is set up correctly.
Speaker 7:  I do wish this has shown up earlier so that they could bring it up in the
Speaker 7:  antitrust trial over whether Snapchat and Instagram were the same thing,
Speaker 5:  If only, well there were also some TikTok features, but alas
Speaker 5:  we have been struck down. Alright, that was a good one. That's it for The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast. Keep your eye on the feeds over the weekend because the songs
Speaker 5:  hosting a bonus episode dropping this Sunday
Speaker 5:  and Jen Tui is picking up
Speaker 5:  really excited to launch these And I hope you guys enjoy them. We love to
Speaker 5:  hear your questions and feedback. Let us know what you want us to talk about
Speaker 5:  this summer. Email us vergecast to The Verge dot com. I have access
Speaker 5:  to that thing now And I can see what you're saying or give us a call. 8 6 6
Speaker 5:  VERGE 11 The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and Fox Media Podcast
Speaker 5:  network. Our show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keffer, Travis Lar,
Speaker 5:  and Andrew Marino. We'll see you next week.