# Transcript
ID: 4cd79023-c573-456c-8fa7-3afbd74ab5c2
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3697439391298700655/-2425336533296029076/s93290-US-6728s-1741347401.mp3
Description: Apple's new gadgets this week were pretty minor updates, so of course we talk about them for a long time. Nilay and David are joined by The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes, and the three hosts discuss the latest iPad, iPad Air, MacBook Air, and Mac Studio. All three have... a lot of thoughts. After that, they run through some more tech news, including the Digg reboot, the end of Skype, VW's cheap new EV, and more. Finally, in the lightning round, they talk about the latest from DOGE and the Trump administration, Brendan Carr's latest assaults on free speech, and a smartphone that is mostly (but not entirely) a camera.
Speaker 7:  Hello and welcome to our Chest, the flagship podcast with minor updates
Speaker 7:  that do not support Apple Intelligence.
Speaker 7:  If you think we can't make an hour and a half show about
Speaker 7:  the new iPad Air, I dunno what show you think you're listening to right now.
Speaker 7:  'cause we we're gonna do it. We're gonna find a way. I'm ready. It's gonna
Speaker 7:  be emotional. It's a winding road. Some of you'll cry, I
Speaker 7:  think some of you'll share. It's up to you to decide who you are, but
Speaker 8:  You have to choose right now before we start at
Speaker 7:  The top of the show. You gonna laugh or you gonna cry? What kind of, what
Speaker 7:  kind of person you gonna be? I'm your friend Neli David Pierce here. Hello,
Speaker 7:  Jake Castran is here.
Speaker 9:  Hey, good to be here in the actually very, very real control room
Speaker 9:  as all of our video viewers can tell.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. What did you pick this background? What?
Speaker 9:  I don't wanna give away the charade here, but this might be
Speaker 9:  a controllable screen behind. I
Speaker 8:  Love this.
Speaker 9:  This might not be real.
Speaker 8:  Can I tell you something? So one of the first times I ever did a a like cable
Speaker 8:  TV hit and you guys have both done this. So you know how they work, what
Speaker 8:  what what happens is they usher you into a teeny tiny room with a
Speaker 8:  screen behind you and a camera and a light in front of you. And it is either
Speaker 8:  zero or 700 degrees in that room. Yep. Depending on the day.
Speaker 8:  And then you sit there and you do your thing and you go home. To discover
Speaker 8:  that I was not sitting in front of a window with like the beautiful
Speaker 8:  New York City skyline behind me was like genuinely upsetting the first time
Speaker 8:  this ever happened to me. And I have, I have had angry feelings about virtual
Speaker 8:  backgrounds ever since.
Speaker 9:  Listen you guys, next week we're going to Times Square, we're recording this
Speaker 9:  thing live. All of the backgrounds will be real. This is what I'm saying.
Speaker 9:  Elmo will come and harass us.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna do TRL live like in the nineties. The first time I ever did came
Speaker 7:  when you said that you're kind of describing CNN I'm guessing. 'cause that
Speaker 7:  was,
Speaker 8:  It was CNN in fact.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That because the tiny hot room, that's very much CNN. Yes,
Speaker 7:  I was, I was surprised not by the fact there was a green screen, which David,
Speaker 7:  I I truly what I knew green
Speaker 8:  Screens existed.
Speaker 7:  You but that one, these are fancy
Speaker 8:  Studios. They should have windows.
Speaker 7:  You walk through the fancy studio, right? Where all the people are working.
Speaker 7:  'cause the anchors like, you know, their shows look over the fancy studio,
Speaker 7:  all the people working and you're like, oh my God, I'm, I'm, I did, I may,
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna be on cable news. Which over time fades in terms of
Speaker 7:  excitement. And then you are led into this like hot windowless room where
Speaker 7:  no one else is there and you can't see them. And that was the thing that
Speaker 7:  blew my mind.
Speaker 7:  Jake is sitting in some sort of, you know, wireless network
Speaker 7:  command center. That's what that looks like to me.
Speaker 9:  And, and Neli by the way, recorded all of this dialogue hours ago. I'm just
Speaker 9:  responding to it.
Speaker 7:  The first time I went and visited at and t's network operation center,
Speaker 7:  the Knock, which is here in New York. They have one in New York. I will never
Speaker 7:  forget this. It's just a room of charts and graphs. I don't know why they
Speaker 7:  need a command center. Like I, it, it was never actually made clear to
Speaker 7:  me why they needed to build like NASA mission control
Speaker 7:  for the wireless network. But they, they have it. It's cool. I think it's
Speaker 7:  there for like partners to like look at stuff like they need a place that's
Speaker 7:  like not a server rack, you know? But I will never forget
Speaker 7:  one of the engineers just pointed to this huge trunk of traffic on the graph
Speaker 7:  and was like, that's porn.
Speaker 7:  Anyway. Just like, oh yeah, that's, you're probably,
Speaker 7:  that's awesome. So Jake, If you could just wheel around and show us where
Speaker 7:  the porn is,
Speaker 9:  As you can see behind you there somewhere right here I think.
Speaker 7:  Alright. We got a lot of talk about today. Not just Jake's wall of porn.
Speaker 7:  There's new Apple products, there's a new iPad Air, there's a new MacBook
Speaker 7:  Air, there's a new Mac studio, which very
Speaker 7:  compelling. I I gotta say I have a lot to say about the New Mac studio.
Speaker 7:  Then we got like two lightning rounds. Dig is back. David
Speaker 7:  reported on the 15th return of dig. And then of course we're gonna end
Speaker 7:  by just talking shit about Brendan Carr. That's what we do here on the B
Speaker 7:  chest. I think it's gonna be a good one. I
Speaker 8:  Will say it is, it's a real bummer how popular that segment has become. And
Speaker 8:  I've gotten a bunch of people who are like, please never kill Brendan
Speaker 8:  Carr as a dummy because it's great. And I keep being like, look, I would
Speaker 8:  love to stop doing Brendan Carr as a dummy, but it requires a certain thing
Speaker 8:  that is not going to happen, which is pregnant easing to be a dummy.
Speaker 8:  So this, this segment will be alive and well for a very long time. I suspect
Speaker 7:  We we're at the point where we're getting fine grain criticism of the name
Speaker 7:  of the segment. We'll, we'll come to it. I'll explain. Can I start with the
Speaker 7:  gadget reveal though? One of the silliest gadgets I've ever purchased in
Speaker 7:  my entire life. So we were on vacation, which many people conspiratorially
Speaker 7:  believed meant that I was either cloning my body or dead
Speaker 7:  t knows. So we were on vacation, we go to the beach. I have a crap underwater
Speaker 7:  camera that I bought a million years ago that is now quite fun to take 'cause
Speaker 7:  I can just like give it to the 6-year-old and she can like have it at the
Speaker 7:  beach and don't worry about it breaking, it takes horrible photos. It's just
Speaker 7:  a real thing. And then you see all the people have like the iPhone cases,
Speaker 7:  you know, and like that's not great either 'cause they get foggy and cloudy
Speaker 7:  and whatever. So I was like, I'm gonna buy a new underwater camera. And I
Speaker 7:  went and I looked and the one that everybody buys is the Olympus TG six
Speaker 7:  or the TG seven now. Which is basically the same thing with the US PC port.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't matter, it's like orange. It looks cool.
Speaker 7:  And then you look at the photos, you're like, this is not actually better
Speaker 7:  than my iPhone. I've now come all the way back around to I'm gonna buy this
Speaker 7:  horrible case for an iPhone. And then I thought to myself, what if I order
Speaker 7:  from Japan, Sony's underwater case from an
Speaker 7:  RX 100
Speaker 9:  Oh oh wow.
Speaker 7:  Which is just one of the silliest goddamn things in the entire world.
Speaker 7:  If you buy it in the States, it's like $350. If you buy it on eBay from Japan,
Speaker 7:  it's like 200. I don't understand how that works at all. Wait, you're,
Speaker 8:  You're saying this is your RX 100?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, well it's the RX one. I don't have
Speaker 9:  Isn't it a tiny Pointin shoot?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, the RX 100 is a tiny pointin shoot. I'm sorry. Sorry. If you're listening
Speaker 7:  to this triple, basically
Speaker 8:  This is the size of your
Speaker 7:  Camera giant plastic bubble that goes, I can't even figure
Speaker 7:  out how to open it right now. It's basically a, you can hear all the slots.
Speaker 7:  It, the camera fits into this giant plastic bubble. Whoa. Here's the best
Speaker 7:  part about it. This
Speaker 9:  Looks legit. This looks like it would survive like, you
Speaker 9:  know,
Speaker 8:  Depths.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's for scuba divers. Yeah. So the RX 100 to control it,
Speaker 7:  you turn the ring around the lens. If you're familiar with your RX 100, like
Speaker 7:  that's how you change the aperture. So you gotta do that. So it came with
Speaker 7:  a gear, like a rubber gear that you slip around the front
Speaker 7:  of the RX 100
Speaker 7:  and then that rubber gear is geared to a big knob on the side.
Speaker 9:  Oh wow. Incredible.
Speaker 7:  Easily the best gadget I've bought in a hundred years, I've been taking pictures
Speaker 7:  in the house, which is not underwater.
Speaker 7:  And then this big silly white thing on the front is the flash diffuser. So
Speaker 7:  you can pop up the flash and RX 100 and make flash photos underwater. So
Speaker 7:  I've been taking flash photos.
Speaker 9:  Is flash useful underwater? Do you get the same like party
Speaker 7:  Effect once you like fall down the, the rabbit hole of like, I'm gonna take
Speaker 7:  photos underwater. You get into like, it, it is as gadgety and nerdy
Speaker 7:  and like supportive space as any hobby. You know,
Speaker 7:  I just wanted to have a camera that can get wet at the pool. So like, I
Speaker 7:  don't think, I don't think I'll need the flash, you know, but it is easily
Speaker 7:  one of the funniest gadgets I've ever purchased.
Speaker 8:  I feel like the thing that that reminds me of is like, like really,
Speaker 8:  really knock off James Bond gadgets. Yeah. Like if James Bond
Speaker 8:  had no budget because of tariffs, like all of a sudden
Speaker 8:  he's getting these like large plastic cameras. But that thing is secretly
Speaker 8:  like a gun and A, and a voice recorder in addition to being a way to
Speaker 8:  take underwater photos. I'm very into this thing.
Speaker 7:  The, I mean it just, the fact that it was, first of all, it, it showed up.
Speaker 7:  It's from Japan, so all the instructions are in Japanese.
Speaker 8:  Perfect.
Speaker 7:  And like it's, it's basically just like a series of rubber gaskets and then
Speaker 7:  affordances to turn the knobs and buttons on the RX 100.
Speaker 7:  So there's, there's a wheel on the back and then there's like a mode dial
Speaker 7:  on top. And so you have to like line everything up so
Speaker 7:  that this knob right here can gear itself to turn
Speaker 7:  the mode wheel on top of the camera. And I'm just like looking at these
Speaker 7:  like Ikea pictures and all of his Japanese text and I was like,
Speaker 7:  I'm a pretty smart guy. Like I'm gonna horsepower my way through this.
Speaker 7:  And eventually I gave up and I downloaded the manual in English from the
Speaker 7:  internet. So, but it's, I had a lot of fun with it and it was sitting
Speaker 7:  on the CES when I started recording and I was like, you know what, you know
Speaker 7:  what the show needs before we do Brendan Carr, this needs an
Speaker 7:  honest to goodness ridiculous gadget. And there's nothing I love more than
Speaker 7:  a ridiculous semi gadget. True. By the way, there are many third party cases
Speaker 7:  that are vastly cheaper. There are many third party cases vastly more expensive.
Speaker 7:  This one was just, I Googled it on eBay and I was like, I I kind of
Speaker 7:  wanna buy a, a silly gadget from Japan today. So I did
Speaker 8:  Anything that attaches to a button to move that button
Speaker 8:  somewhere else. Yes. And turn it into a wheel that presses the button like
Speaker 8:  you are The Verge now. Welcome. You've done it.
Speaker 7:  It's so good. This
Speaker 8:  Is what we do here.
Speaker 7:  It's funny because we don't have another beach vacation plan. It's like,
Speaker 7:  I don't even know what I'm gonna use. You need to find
Speaker 8:  Reasons to get underwater. It's just gonna be in the bathtub on like
Speaker 8:  a Wednesday thing.
Speaker 7:  It's like cold in New York. Like I'm, I'm not getting in the pool anytime
Speaker 7:  soon.
Speaker 7:  Anyhow, I encourage you to send in your silly gadget
Speaker 7:  purchases. 'cause I think we all need that to keep us grounded as a community
Speaker 7:  during these times. So speaking of silly gadgets, let's talk about all the
Speaker 7:  new Apple stuff. Tim Cook teased, you know, it was gonna be an air and
Speaker 7:  then they started with the iPad Air, which I both understand and
Speaker 7:  be, I think deflated everything that came after it. David, you you
Speaker 7:  wrote this story. Try.
Speaker 8:  So we kind of knew there were gonna be
Speaker 8:  iPads. I think my operating assumption was that we were gonna
Speaker 8:  get a base iPad refreshed because that thing
Speaker 8:  hasn't been updated since I think the fall of 2022. We did, we did. And
Speaker 8:  we'll get to that. But my, what my point is, my assumption was, okay, the,
Speaker 8:  there's like, there, there was a lot of smoke around there being an Apple
Speaker 8:  announcement this week. And I was like, I said to Jake, I was like, my, my
Speaker 8:  betting thesis is it's gonna be the base iPad feels like it's time
Speaker 8:  and then Tim Cook does this thing. And we're like, okay, maybe it's, maybe
Speaker 8:  it's the MacBook Air because again, the iPad Air got revved less than 12
Speaker 8:  months ago. Like the, the, this iPad Air that I have
Speaker 8:  right here on my desk is less than a year old. And so I was like, well why
Speaker 8:  on earth would there be a new iPad Air? And yet lo and behold there was a
Speaker 8:  new iPad Air. So Apple announced, I would say
Speaker 8:  with with interest and excitement on iPad Air
Speaker 8:  and then tried to absolutely bury out of existence that it was also updating
Speaker 8:  the base iPad. And we should talk about that. 'cause I think it's really
Speaker 8:  fascinating. But the, the, the story of this iPad
Speaker 8:  Air is precisely one thing. It's that it now has an
Speaker 8:  M three chip instead of an M two chip. That's it.
Speaker 7:  Actually, I think the story is ever so slightly different. I mean I, the
Speaker 7:  air this new era has Apple intelligence, right. They've added it to that.
Speaker 7:  It's not in the base model.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 9:  Which is funny 'cause before these were announced, David and I were messaging
Speaker 9:  each other on Slack and we're like, they've gotta just put Apple Intelligence
Speaker 9:  on this and call it today. It's the only thing, only thing to do here. And
Speaker 9:  it's the only thing they didn't do.
Speaker 8:  That's also the only thing Apple has been doing with its gadgets for the
Speaker 8:  last 12 months.
Speaker 7:  That's what I mean. And I think they know the, the base is like a huge volume
Speaker 7:  seller. Yeah. Like they're just selling base model iPads as
Speaker 8:  And so is the air. I think like, I think pretty clearly the air is a hit.
Speaker 8:  I keep telling people not to buy it, but it seems to still be Yes. One a
Speaker 8:  lot of people land on.
Speaker 7:  And I just think it's, I I think we're at the point with Apple intelligence
Speaker 7:  in particular where the, you know, the bloom is just
Speaker 7:  off that road. Like it just doesn't matter to people. And so like
Speaker 7:  adding Apple intelligence to any Apple gadget right now is really just a
Speaker 7:  conversation about how much RAM it has. And I think they just didn't wanna
Speaker 7:  put enough RAM in the, in the base model iPad.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think that's basically right. And there's, there's some weirdness
Speaker 8:  happening where like there has been a pretty clean cutoff in terms of
Speaker 8:  chips that can get Apple intelligence. But now Apple is starting to roll
Speaker 8:  some of those features, but not all of them back to like the iPhone 15
Speaker 8:  line. And so it's like this line is just getting blurry in a way that I find
Speaker 8:  very confusing. But also I, I think you're right that the
Speaker 8:  overwhelming fact is no one cares. Apple, apple cares a
Speaker 8:  great deal about you caring about Apple intelligence
Speaker 8:  and it just isn't working.
Speaker 9:  The top comment on our news story, which was, you know, apple and us
Speaker 9:  new iPad but doesn't have Apple intelligence. Top comment was no Apple Intelligence
Speaker 9:  sounds like an upgrade or something to that effect. It's like, yeah, like,
Speaker 9:  like this is not, it's a, it's an annoying little button that gets in the
Speaker 9:  way right now. The extra RAM seems great. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So you know, we, we talked about Alexa for ages last week.
Speaker 7:  My feeling is that Apple intelligence will not be a thing that anyone understands
Speaker 7:  until the new Siri comes out. Yeah. Expressed is a bunch of
Speaker 7:  weird text tools and Gen Moji who
Speaker 7:  cares, right? I can talk to Siri like it's actually intelligent.
Speaker 7:  That's the thing. And I think that's why they added the color and the animation
Speaker 7:  to the existing Siri. But it, it doesn't do it. I think they should have
Speaker 7:  held off on that actually.
Speaker 8:  I agree. I mean, and I think the, the response to the Alexa stuff
Speaker 8:  from last week has been really interesting because on the one hand
Speaker 8:  again, whether Amazon will actually deliver any of the
Speaker 8:  product it claims to have made TBD, all the signs are bad
Speaker 8:  for how that is going for Amazon. But they're saying
Speaker 8:  the right things about what they're trying to do. Right. And they've like
Speaker 8:  announced the thing and all, like all of the people in the Apple universe
Speaker 8:  that I know have spent this week being like, holy God is Siri far behind,
Speaker 8:  like further behind than anybody was. At least it was like, okay, this is
Speaker 8:  actually really hard and If you have like a mainstream product and use case,
Speaker 8:  just flipping that to LLM is tricky. And then Google
Speaker 8:  has done it. Amazon has done it. Siri sucks. And
Speaker 8:  there was some reporting this week from Mark Kerman at Bloomberg saying that
Speaker 8:  it's possible that the better Siri is actually like two years away.
Speaker 8:  Like we're, it's not close. And I think it this this thing Apple is
Speaker 8:  trying to do just gets uglier because of your exact point. Apple is like
Speaker 8:  hanging up billboards being like Apple intelligence and people are like,
Speaker 8:  what? That just means bad summaries of my text messages right now. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That everyone should turn off. Like it's, it's actually a problem
Speaker 9:  Every single one of their commercials there like aggressively saying like
Speaker 9:  it comes with Apple intelligence and it's a as though this is the thing that
Speaker 9:  people are excited about and it's funny that they're getting
Speaker 9:  excited about buzzwords, which is like not a very Apple-like thing to do
Speaker 9:  traditionally. Particularly when they haven't delivered. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And it's also when Chachi petit horrible name that no one can
Speaker 7:  pronounce if
Speaker 9:  Yeah, if they had just said like iPhone now with chat GBT, which it
Speaker 9:  is. I I think people've been like, Hmm,
Speaker 8:  That would've been way more compelling. Yeah. Yeah. We nuked Siri and now
Speaker 8:  it just goes straight to chat. GBT would've worked for people.
Speaker 7:  Apple one now includes, you know, two hours of advanced voice mode
Speaker 7:  and chat. GBT would've been fine. I, I like sure. But it's, it's a bad brand.
Speaker 7:  Like I, I know so many people who
Speaker 7:  call it chat GBT and it's like we're just like past the point of correcting
Speaker 7:  your friends, you know, like whatever. It's fine. You just kind of say it.
Speaker 7:  We all know what we're talking about here, right? Like yeah, you didn't buy
Speaker 7:  it on Canal Street. Like it's fine. It's like,
Speaker 8:  It's like singing a Michael Jackson song. You just like try to say the syllables
Speaker 8:  kind of right. Yeah. And really fast and you just get through it and it's
Speaker 7:  Fine. And then Rihanna samples it years later.
Speaker 7:  That's the real ones know exactly what I'm talking about. But the Apple intelligence
Speaker 7:  you have now, like you, you light up an iPhone and it's like, it's not in
Speaker 7:  your face. No. But ch Chibi is a bad brand that people are using 'cause it's
Speaker 7:  useful and like advanced voice mode is very
Speaker 7:  compelling no matter what. Like, you don't need to think about what's happening.
Speaker 7:  You're like, oh, I can just talk to this thing. And if they just given that
Speaker 7:  to Siri, I think it would've been fine. I think you would've ended up in
Speaker 7:  weird spots where people tried to jailbreak it or you had privacy issues
Speaker 7:  or Kevin Ru fell in love with it.
Speaker 7:  Siri tried to bang me again. Kevin, I I don't want to give the New York Times
Speaker 7:  headlines. It's right there for you. That should be a front page story. It's
Speaker 7:  true. But they haven't done any of that stuff anyway. I just think it's really
Speaker 7:  fascinating that the base model iPad, which is just the thing that sells
Speaker 7:  like forever and ever Sells, doesn't have this feature
Speaker 7:  'cause they don't need it. 'cause the thing is it like a Disney plus machine,
Speaker 7:  you know, like for so many people or it's deployed in enterprise and the
Speaker 7:  enterprises don't want Apple intelligence or it's in schools and they don't
Speaker 7:  want, like whatever that base model iPad represents
Speaker 7:  is not improved by Apple intelligence. And I think that says something very
Speaker 7:  important.
Speaker 8:  Well, and and what it super clearly communicates is
Speaker 8:  that however Apple wants to feel about Apple intelligence, it knows
Speaker 8:  for absolute certain that it is not a thing it can raise the price for
Speaker 8:  Right. Because if you're, if you're Apple, you, you, it's the, the base
Speaker 8:  iPad now has the A 16 chip, which is a two
Speaker 8:  chip bump from before, which is great, but is still
Speaker 8:  below the technical requirements to do
Speaker 8:  what you need with Apple intelligence. And they could have added
Speaker 8:  that chip, but then it would've made the thing more expensive. And
Speaker 8:  for a, for Apple, I think having a $349 iPad is actually really
Speaker 8:  important for a bunch of reasons. But also I think
Speaker 8:  this iPad now has Apple intelligence and is $50 more expensive is
Speaker 8:  not a winning sentence. And I think Apple knows that very, very clearly.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I threatened you with 90 minutes on inconsequential iPad bumps.
Speaker 7:  Do you feel it? Do you feel it? Is it coming?
Speaker 9:  Can I speak to some slightly also
Speaker 9:  inconsequential iPad Air things? Yeah. That, that, that went a little under
Speaker 9:  the radar. So they added the
Speaker 9:  function row keys that rules to the magic keyboard for the iPad
Speaker 8:  Air. Not inconsequential. That's the biggest upgrade here by a mile.
Speaker 9:  And they dropped the price on those by 30 bucks each. They're still crazy
Speaker 9:  expensive. It's still like 250 or 300 bucks or something insane. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  They went from most expensive keyboard ever. Two most expensive keyboard
Speaker 8:  ever. Minus $30.
Speaker 9:  You can still like buy another iPad for the price of a magic
Speaker 9:  keyboard, which actually would kind of rule. But
Speaker 9:  that's, I the function keys are, are great. Yes.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 9:  That's an important improvement. The iPad Air feels like it's getting ever
Speaker 9:  so slightly closer to being the tablet version of the MacBook Air.
Speaker 9:  Like you're supposed to spend roughly a thousand dollars on it. You buy the
Speaker 9:  13 inch version, you spend 300 bucks or whatever on the magic
Speaker 9:  keyboard and the stylus and you know, you don't get the fanciest stuff,
Speaker 9:  you don't get the high refresh rate display,
Speaker 9:  but you haven't spent all of your money on this thing. It
Speaker 9:  gets most of the stuff done that you needed to get done. It's,
Speaker 9:  it's, it's not exciting in that way. I think it's really interesting. I was
Speaker 9:  just looking over David's like recent iPad reviews. There is the only
Speaker 9:  iPad that David says not to get and
Speaker 7:  It's the one everybody buys.
Speaker 9:  It's right in the middle. It's, it's really tough.
Speaker 8:  The air has at times gotten it right. And I think
Speaker 8:  there, like the, the thing it's trying to do is the right thing,
Speaker 8:  right? Because like the iPad Pro is incredible and three times
Speaker 8:  what anybody needs both in price and in performance, right? Like
Speaker 8:  it's, it's massive, massive overkill. The thing the iPad
Speaker 8:  Air has to do is convince you that you need more than the base iPad. And
Speaker 8:  I think that case from Apple more for software reasons than for anything
Speaker 8:  else has gotten weaker over time. And I think what, what Apple will tell
Speaker 8:  you is that the thing that makes people step up is either the accessories,
Speaker 8:  which it clearly gates to this device because oh, I want a keyboard so I
Speaker 8:  can send an email. Now I have to get the air because that's how I get the
Speaker 8:  good keyboard attachment. Or same with the pencil, right? Like those things
Speaker 8:  are, are gated not for technical reasons, but because Apple is trying to
Speaker 8:  get you to upgrade. Like that's, that's just real. Or because people
Speaker 8:  want the extra performance because they're doing the, the kinds of creative
Speaker 8:  tasks that Apple always shows you on stage. Right? It's like if you're using
Speaker 8:  Final Cut Pro and Logic on your iPad, yes you should get
Speaker 8:  an error and not a base iPad. I cannot prove this,
Speaker 8:  but I'm willing to bet that that is a teeny
Speaker 8:  tiny sliver of iPad people. And, and to me, the, the
Speaker 8:  thing that I find myself saying a lot, and I, I wrote this, I recently updated
Speaker 8:  our iPad buying guide and was basically like, there are
Speaker 8:  two types of iPad users. There are people who want to just like send emails
Speaker 8:  and browse the web and do the crossword puzzle and
Speaker 8:  like look at photos, right? That is like, they're sort of the basic iPad
Speaker 8:  grandparents tasks you,
Speaker 7:  You've described grandparents. Sure.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. There are a lot of those out there. And a lot of them have iPads, I
Speaker 8:  can tell you constantly. And then there are the people who are like, I want
Speaker 8:  a creative machine, right? And that's where like the pencil is really useful,
Speaker 8:  whether you're drawing or you're editing videos or whatever. But it is like
Speaker 8:  you are doing hardcore creative tasks and that's when you show
Speaker 8:  up. And I think many, many, many people have convinced
Speaker 8:  themselves that they are the second kind of iPad user when in reality they
Speaker 8:  are actually the first kind of iPad user.
Speaker 7:  You're, you're just describing Apple as a community.
Speaker 7:  People who are like, what I do is 3D graphics and you're like, what you do
Speaker 7:  is CD emails, right? What
Speaker 8:  You do is watch Netflix and like that's fine. And the
Speaker 8:  $349 iPad is a kick ass Netflix machine and
Speaker 8:  it's gonna be an even better one.
Speaker 7:  Now, I don't mean to say that pejoratively 'cause we're gonna talk about
Speaker 7:  the Mac Studio in a minute and I'm basically convincing myself to buy a Mac
Speaker 7:  studio and my job is 1000% emails.
Speaker 7:  I don't Yeah. I'm just describing myself. Oh, same. We can all be that person
Speaker 7:  together. I'm just Yeah. Yeah. Every now and again, I look at the Photoshop
Speaker 7:  icon on my computer, right? Huh? Does that count? Think about it. Right.
Speaker 8:  And, and Apple,
Speaker 7:  I need, I need 30 GPUs.
Speaker 8:  And Jake, I think to your point about the MacBook Air, I think one of the
Speaker 8:  things that has worked really well for Apple is upselling on that with
Speaker 8:  your laptop or your desktop or whatever. Because that like by
Speaker 8:  definition needs to be your most powerful machine. So if you're ever gonna
Speaker 8:  overkill on something, it should be a Mac and on the iPad, I think
Speaker 8:  the thing to do is actually just be honest with yourself about like, what
Speaker 8:  is this thing really for in my life? And to me it's been a while since the
Speaker 8:  air has made a case above and beyond what
Speaker 8:  most people are actually going to do on their iPads. If
Speaker 9:  You could do high frame rate subway surfers, that would be a game
Speaker 9:  changer. But you gotta upgrade
Speaker 8:  To the pro for this.
Speaker 7:  All right? Right. I said we were gonna talk about the iPad Air for 90 minutes
Speaker 7:  as a joke. And it is just threatening to become real. We have to move on
Speaker 7:  to actual products that are worth talking about. Sorry to the iPad team,
Speaker 7:  you know, change the software maybe, you know, allow, allow real
Speaker 7:  multitasking. I'll, I'll give you, I'll give you three episodes of the show
Speaker 7:  If you allow real, can
Speaker 8:  I just throw a trivia question at both of you before we move on?
Speaker 7:  Let it run Maco West. The whole VERGE for a month will be about the new iPad.
Speaker 8:  Yes, a hundred percent. How long would you guys think
Speaker 8:  the, like average lifespan of an iPad is? Like if I, if I'm
Speaker 8:  shopping for this one, how old is my current iPad? It
Speaker 7:  It, it's gotta be over five. That's my, my heartfelt belief.
Speaker 8:  Jake, what do you think? Yeah, it's like seven years. Okay. Almost every
Speaker 8:  number I've seen it's, this is a hard thing to measure, but almost every
Speaker 8:  number I've seen says somewhere between five and seven years. Yeah. Which
Speaker 8:  is interesting, right? Because then it's like, okay, If you bought, If you
Speaker 8:  bought something in 2020, you bought the fourth
Speaker 8:  gen iPad Air in like a Covid haze,
Speaker 8:  which had an a 14 chip and it had touch id, that thing is still
Speaker 8:  getting software updates. I, I don't know that there's anything about these
Speaker 8:  new devices that is like so vastly better that you need to go
Speaker 8:  get it right now. Which is both the incredible success of the
Speaker 8:  iPad. And also a very weird thing about these devices, like, but
Speaker 7:  To Apple's credit, this has been their business for a long time, right? They
Speaker 7:  they are committed to their products.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Oh yeah.
Speaker 7:  So they're just like, we're just gonna make another one on, on a cadence
Speaker 7:  and they're gonna last a long time. And their money now is
Speaker 7:  not in selling the hardware, it's in taking a cut of every
Speaker 7:  button that you push in their operating systems. Right? It's in the app store
Speaker 7:  fees, it's in Apple one service fees. It's sending you to chat
Speaker 7:  GBT and Apple Intelligence and taking a cut of that subscription. If you
Speaker 7:  buy it. Like all of that is their money. It's giving Apple
Speaker 7:  TV plus away for free If you merely blink at a number of partners. Like
Speaker 7:  that's all their money. And so I think the hardware lasting a long time is
Speaker 7:  actually, you can complain a lot about that business model, the services
Speaker 7:  business model. 'cause it feels like using the devices is increasingly monetized.
Speaker 7:  But on the other end of it is the devices last a long time and they give
Speaker 7:  'em software updates for a long time. Yeah. Could they be, does that model
Speaker 7:  suggest the devices could be cheaper? It sure does,
Speaker 7:  but Apple's never gonna make the devices cheaper. No,
Speaker 8:  But it, but I, I do think you're right. And I think the more I look at these
Speaker 8:  announcements, and I think there's some truth to this with the max too. Like
Speaker 8:  Apple is a software company in a very real way. Like Apple is
Speaker 8:  more interested in just putting a thing in your hands that you will use software
Speaker 8:  on than it is on like reinventing
Speaker 8:  its hardware all the time. And that's fine.
Speaker 7:  Well that's been true. We, we, we should talk about the air. 'cause they
Speaker 7:  actually did lower presses in the air and that was intended once again to
Speaker 7:  be a segue away from these inconsequential. But Apple's a software
Speaker 7:  company has been true since the days of Steve Jobs. He was very fond. I think
Speaker 7:  it's Alan k. Famous computer scientist from back in the day. The,
Speaker 7:  his quote was, if people who are really serious about software
Speaker 7:  build their own hardware and that's like a motivating Steve Jobs quote. Totally.
Speaker 7:  Like he talked about from the beginning. So I think that's still there in
Speaker 7:  real for Apple. It's now expressed all the way into like they design their
Speaker 7:  own modems for the iPhone. Like they're very serious about building their
Speaker 7:  own hardware and in very different kind of way. Yes. But it's the
Speaker 7:  services component of that where they don't care If you have the device
Speaker 7:  for 10 years as long as you are paying that iCloud storage fee for
Speaker 7:  each and every one of those 10 years. And I, that has a lot of effects. Like
Speaker 7:  it changes your relationship to the device. It changes what Apple tries to
Speaker 7:  sell you. It changes what applications get built and deployed on those devices.
Speaker 7:  It changes, you know, like free to play games exist because of this model
Speaker 7:  and Apple has to not, apple has to studiously avoid
Speaker 7:  pointing out that a huge portion of its revenue comes from like five
Speaker 7:  candy crush whales. Like yeah. That's just it all, there's all
Speaker 7:  these weird outcomes there. But one of them that's very concrete is, oh,
Speaker 7:  iPads last for a hundred years. Like that's fine. Right.
Speaker 8:  Which in a vacuum is awesome. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Alright. MacBook Air, they did lower the price, which is shocking in
Speaker 7:  the context of tariffs 'cause we just assume prices will go up. But Apple
Speaker 7:  actually lowered price in the air. They added the sky blue color, which is
Speaker 7:  very pale. It's very beautiful, but it's very pale.
Speaker 8:  I'm kind of into it. I didn't like it. I have a, I have a blue
Speaker 8:  iPad mini from last year that I didn't really like, but there's something
Speaker 8:  about the like larger size of it and the sort of open screen on
Speaker 8:  a table that I'm actually kind of into in the blue.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It looks, it looks good. In the video we made and
Speaker 9:  Space gray's dead now
Speaker 7:  Space gray, which was not a color space gray was always a concept. It was
Speaker 7:  15, it was 15 different colors over the years. Is
Speaker 8:  That, I guess that is true.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It was never like a Pantone color. Like Apple would be like, I don't
Speaker 7:  know, this is like the gray we can make the aluminum today space gray. It
Speaker 7:  is, it's the
Speaker 8:  Dark
Speaker 7:  One. Yeah. Right. So it's gone. But hopefully we'll
Speaker 7:  come back or a black will come back. That would be tight.
Speaker 7:  The 13 inch to 9, 9 9, the 15 is 1199. So cheaper. And then
Speaker 7:  they rev webcam. So this is very much just a spec bump, but I think it's
Speaker 7:  a pretty good spec bump, especially at a lower price.
Speaker 9:  Well, especially they, they bumped the base ram last
Speaker 9:  year mid cycle. And so now that's,
Speaker 7:  That's your Apple intelligence.
Speaker 9:  Hey, you know what I, I've totally changed my tune. Apple Intelligence is
Speaker 9:  the greatest thing that's happened to mankind. Right? But for for
Speaker 9:  a grand, you now get a a, I think a very serviceable MacBook.
Speaker 9:  That's great. That, that's like a, a huge upgrade actually, even
Speaker 9:  though this is otherwise pretty quiet.
Speaker 8:  What if the legacy of the whole AI craze
Speaker 8:  is just that Chrome runs better on everybody's computers because we have,
Speaker 7:  I mean that has been the legacy of like virtually every major hardware revision
Speaker 7:  is like, oh, Chrome will now eat these resources as well. But yeah, no, you,
Speaker 7:  it's true. You buy a new MacBook, you turn off Apple Intelligence, you got
Speaker 7:  yourself a 16 gig RAM upgrade for no money. It's like amazing.
Speaker 7:  You turn it on and maybe that AI model starts to eat some of that ram, which
Speaker 7:  is, that's the trade off, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  We think we, nobody's actually sure what Apple Intelligence can do.
Speaker 9:  We, we, we have
Speaker 7:  Figured out it weird gigabytes of ran hold
Speaker 9:  That it is running on the computer, changing all of the things we write
Speaker 9:  to be smarter.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It, they've, they've RevB the webcam to match the MacBook
Speaker 7:  Pros webcam.
Speaker 7:  I'm, I dunno, but I feel like Apple keeps promising us
Speaker 7:  better webcams and they're all still kind of bad.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's a webcam. Like it's fine. I I I actually think
Speaker 8:  somewhat to Apple's credit, it has hit a point where it's webcams are fine.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, they're fine. They were not fine for a very long time, but they're
Speaker 8:  fine now.
Speaker 7:  So that's the rev of the air, which is interesting and I think a great computer.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think for 9 99 it's very hard to compete with I MacBook
Speaker 7:  Air as is currently configured and presented it. But it's
Speaker 7:  also true that we were like at MWC this week and like
Speaker 7:  we saw giant like tri-fold laptops.
Speaker 7:  We, the framework laptops were out. Like there's all kinds of, there's all
Speaker 7:  kinds of action in the laptop space and it, it's all still
Speaker 7:  revolving around a thousand dollars MacBook Air that is deeply hard to compete
Speaker 7:  with. Yeah. What do we think is going on there? Like, I see, what was
Speaker 7:  that Lenovo one? Like they demoed a giant calculator, like a huge portrait
Speaker 7:  screen. Oh, my screen
Speaker 9:  With
Speaker 7:  A calculator on it. I love this thing. Like I, I mean I'm, I'm here with
Speaker 7:  a giant underwater camera bubble, like give me a gadget, right?
Speaker 9:  Lenovo now has two different versions of basically this exact same
Speaker 9:  laptop where they're like, what if the screen was twice as much
Speaker 9:  screen and one the screen just like
Speaker 9:  rolls out from inside the laptop. Yeah. That was like a month ago.
Speaker 9:  And now they're like, wait a second. The screen's always out. It just
Speaker 9:  folds back. So one, it's always outside one, it's inside. Yeah. It
Speaker 9:  doesn't matter either way. It's still just a giant, super tall screen
Speaker 9:  and it looks just genuinely, utterly insane
Speaker 9:  to, to like have this little thing in front of you that you type on with
Speaker 9:  a enormous screen. But it also looks amazing and I want it more than anything.
Speaker 7:  So Lenovo I believe has been
Speaker 7:  the like foremost proponent of tent mode
Speaker 7:  for laptops Yes. For years now. Like a full decade. Yep.
Speaker 7:  Lenovo's like, look, the way you want to use the computer is intent mode.
Speaker 7:  Remember the yogas, the, the foldable, the two in one tablets, they were
Speaker 7:  making like the service competitors, If you will recall, like the, the thing
Speaker 7:  that they wanted you to do with a Lenovo yoga was tent mode. It
Speaker 8:  Was so flippy. I loved it.
Speaker 7:  It was so flippy. And so this new concept that Jake is talking about, you
Speaker 7:  can fold it back and put it in tent mode. So you have a, what looks like
Speaker 7:  a laptop, but then the screen is folded back over at an angle. So
Speaker 7:  it's a tent and someone sitting across screen on a table can see what's on
Speaker 7:  that screen. I love, I love the brain that
Speaker 7:  Yeah, whoever you are, like show yourself. I wanna hug you that
Speaker 7:  thought. Okay, here's how people should use laptops with other people.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Here's what I need you to do. I need you to sit across from me while
Speaker 7:  I look at my laptop, but then I'm gonna fold the screen back over in intent
Speaker 7:  mode. And then you'll look at this screen while I look at this screen and
Speaker 7:  we're gonna make eye contact.
Speaker 9:  The, I just tell you the, their product guy told Antonio
Speaker 9:  on our team, he said that the thing they compromised on was that they
Speaker 9:  wanted to put an entire smartphone screen to replace the
Speaker 9:  track pad. But that was too far.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Oh, that was too, yeah. That's just outlandish.
Speaker 9:  They, they couldn't make that happen a
Speaker 8:  Screen.
Speaker 7:  If you are out there regularly using tent mode, it it,
Speaker 7:  you know, maybe you've got a 10-year-old Lenovo yoga, like, well whoever
Speaker 7:  you are, If you are out there and you are either regularly using tent mode
Speaker 7:  or you've heard me describe this and you are like
Speaker 7:  thinking I gotta, I gotta get a laptop that can tent
Speaker 7:  let us know, you know, the, the email address is open. The, the phone lines
Speaker 7:  are, are always ringing.
Speaker 8:  This is the funny thing about this space to me, like I
Speaker 8:  don't want more innovation in laptops, which
Speaker 7:  Is kind of my question. Right. Maybe
Speaker 8:  An insane thing to say. But, but I think the thing I've come around to is
Speaker 8:  like, I think laptops are just a solved problem. Like I think we've, 'cause
Speaker 8:  we've been at this for a while and there had been a lot of ideas. There was
Speaker 8:  this time, I think it was, it was either Acer or Asus. I think it was Acer
Speaker 8:  flipped the track pad and the keyboard. Do you remember this when Oh yeah.
Speaker 8:  They had, they made a thing where
Speaker 7:  Yeah, keyboard in the front club. We used, we did, this was a recurring segment
Speaker 7:  on this show. Yeah. It was whole thing. Miller would be like, keyboard in
Speaker 7:  the front club. Here's another one of these. Yeah. It was like, there was,
Speaker 7:  that was the closest to success this concept has ever gotten.
Speaker 8:  And then everything got really flippy and then every, the razor was like,
Speaker 8:  what if they folded out? And Lenovo was like, what if it rises up out of
Speaker 8:  nowhere And, and everybody is like, no, actually what if the battery
Speaker 8:  lasted longer? Like, what if it was just laptop but
Speaker 8:  battery and then like, and I think that's fine. Like we're,
Speaker 8:  we're what, we're 30 years into laptops now. Like I think, I think we can
Speaker 8:  look at those and be like, okay, this is, we know what this thing is supposed
Speaker 8:  to be. Let's leave it alone and go do something else. And where I am with
Speaker 8:  tablets is like, I just don't think we're there yet. So I push harder on
Speaker 8:  that. 'cause I'm like, we can't, we have not finished what this thing is
Speaker 8:  supposed to be, but with laptops, I'm like, I think the MacBook Air is
Speaker 8:  probably my longest held like default recommendation
Speaker 8:  that is like, If you just want a laptop and I don't want to have any more
Speaker 8:  questions for you, I'm gonna tell you to buy a MacBook Air. And that's been
Speaker 8:  true for 10 years. I can't even, any
Speaker 7:  Other place, I can't say saying that with affection or disdain. Like If you
Speaker 7:  wanna get the fuck outta my face, buy a MacBook Air,
Speaker 8:  I have a MacBook Air that I love to pieces like
Speaker 7:  It's,
Speaker 8:  It's, it's affection. Like, and it has been, I think it's, it's frankly
Speaker 8:  kind of damning of the rest of the PC industry that nobody else has figured
Speaker 8:  out that what people actually want is a laptop that is like light and thin
Speaker 8:  and lasts a really long time.
Speaker 7:  No wait to be, to be fair, they have, they just have horrible branding
Speaker 7:  problems, right? Like what is the default Windows laptop that
Speaker 7:  competes with the microcare is a rich topic of discussion. Sure. And the
Speaker 7:  problem is it's the Dell
Speaker 8:  XPS 13, which they killed,
Speaker 7:  Which is gone. Right. They just won't like stick to a brand that makes sense
Speaker 7:  now they're like, here's what it's called. It's called the Double Dell Pro
Speaker 7:  and it comes with a side of fries. And you're like, I don't want that. Like,
Speaker 7:  I don't understand Sure what this is. You know, HP
Speaker 7:  had a line of computers that we thought would be the, they changed the logo
Speaker 7:  and they're like, now that's gone. And Apple to its credit radically changes
Speaker 7:  the product over time, but it does just slowly iterate the products in the
Speaker 7:  same names. And you can argue about whether there's too many products or
Speaker 7:  too whatever, but like they've just built brand equity in the name.
Speaker 7:  So much so that Johnny and I have tried to kill the MacBook Air and he couldn't.
Speaker 7:  Right. If you will recall, because, well, and
Speaker 8:  Again, they tried to make huge changes to how a laptop works and it
Speaker 8:  sucked. They're like, what if your laptop didn't have any ports and the keyboard
Speaker 8:  was bad so that we could make it thinner? And everybody said, no thank you.
Speaker 8:  Like we just figured it out. Yeah. We know what this thing is
Speaker 8:  supposed to be. Again,
Speaker 7:  This, this was kind of my question about all this. For a thousand dollars,
Speaker 7:  a 13 inch medical error, it, it seems
Speaker 7:  virtually impossible to compete with unless you need windows,
Speaker 7:  right? Unless, unless there's something driving you to use Windows and then
Speaker 7:  you have a huge menu of options. But there's not like all, even like,
Speaker 7:  should Apple put a touchscreen on this thing? Is like I, yes, I think, I
Speaker 7:  think they should merge iPad OS and Macs and they won't. They're just not
Speaker 7:  gonna, they're gonna sell you a weird iPad error and they're gonna sell you
Speaker 7:  a MacBook Air and that's fine. And I, there's something about this one in
Speaker 7:  particular where they, they revved it a little and they brought the price
Speaker 7:  down and they added some ram, which I think you should turn off Apple intelligence
Speaker 7:  and take advantage of that. It just makes this MacBook
Speaker 7:  Air like a particularly strong expression of it, of
Speaker 7:  Apple's dominance of this particular price point. I totally, I think it's
Speaker 7:  very hard to compete at this price point with, with this new error.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah. It's as a, as a thousand dollars computer, it's about
Speaker 8:  as compelling as I think is possible to do at this moment in time.
Speaker 7:  And that's why I think as a $2,200 computer, the new M three
Speaker 7:  max studio is the one I'm gonna buy for no reason whatsoever. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Okay. This, this thing is a deal.
Speaker 8:  I'm willing to have this conversation with you, but only If you can explain
Speaker 8:  to me what the hell is going on with the chips in the New Max Studios.
Speaker 7:  I don't think they can make an M four Ultra. I think that's what's going
Speaker 7:  on with the chips. The new the you, right? Like I think the way, the
Speaker 7:  way these chips work or, and I think their names are getting a little
Speaker 7:  confusing.
Speaker 8:  Just a little. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Right. Because I, what's, what's the difference between an M1 PRO and M1
Speaker 7:  Max and M M1 ultra like, or no, M four, M three, like
Speaker 7:  what they are really, what they really mean is we have fused
Speaker 7:  two or four chips together. And so there's something there that is too
Speaker 7:  confusing for people to understand because the way that's expressed is in
Speaker 7:  core counts. So you're like, I will configure an M three
Speaker 7:  Ultra max studio and your choices are 28 core
Speaker 7:  CPU 60 core GPU 32 core neural engine
Speaker 7:  or 32 core CPU 80 core GPU 32 core
Speaker 7:  neural engine. And you're just like, I don't know what any of that means.
Speaker 7:  That it's just, just like a meaningless set of numbers. Obviously
Speaker 7:  one is more than the other. But then you step back and
Speaker 7:  you're like, the cheaper model is the M four max, which has a 14 core CPU
Speaker 7:  and a 32 core GPU and a 16 quarter lunch. And you're like, oh, is this just
Speaker 7:  half? But it's a totally different chip family.
Speaker 7:  So like,
Speaker 8:  I stopped listening so long, I'm really sorry. It
Speaker 7:  Just none out hard. None of this makes sense anymore. They should change
Speaker 7:  these names because what you have is a chip family and
Speaker 7:  you're taking the core chip and then you're literally fusing another one
Speaker 7:  onto it or then, or you're fusing two three more onto it. And
Speaker 7:  I don't think that that tracks, that's not how people think of anything.
Speaker 7:  No. Like what are the core capabilities of a single chip in the
Speaker 7:  new M line versus three of the old one. You know, like I,
Speaker 7:  that's literally no one outside of Apple's chip team thinks this way. It
Speaker 7:  also,
Speaker 8:  Like we've, we've spent a lot of time trying to figure out the sort of internal
Speaker 8:  math of Apple's naming system and the fact that the fact that Ultra is more
Speaker 8:  than Max Got it good on that. But the fact that Ultra is so much
Speaker 8:  more than Max, that ultra on the last gen outweighs max on this gen.
Speaker 8:  So that a M three ultra is more than an M four max complicated.
Speaker 8:  I don't
Speaker 7:  Know. I I just tuned you out too. Okay. Here's what I, here's what I'm saying
Speaker 7:  to you. As, as, as everyone knows, everyone
Speaker 7:  in America is aware, I am thinking about buying a new computer
Speaker 7:  as,
Speaker 8:  As many was announced to you, cores. Are you in the
Speaker 7:  Market for breaking news across every cable news station?
Speaker 7:  I have often considered buying a new computer. I
Speaker 8:  Think that was on 60 Minutes this weekend, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, they did. They did that great John Oliver segment. And then I sat down
Speaker 7:  and was like, I dunno, you guys, it's a 2017 iMac. The fan
Speaker 7:  runs all the time. What do you guys think?
Speaker 7:  So I've been, I've been thinking about it. I I've solved a monitor problem,
Speaker 7:  which is I'm gonna buy a cheap monitor while I wait for the new studio display.
Speaker 7:  And in the meantime I might break one or more IMAX trying to convert it into
Speaker 7:  a monitor.
Speaker 8:  We got a couple of emails from people with non-car sounding solutions to
Speaker 8:  that. By the way. We're gonna have to, we have some stuff to try.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Well, well, that, that's a whole other show. So I'm like, I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  buy this new Mac mini. So you open the configurator and what's the first
Speaker 7:  thing you're gonna do? You're gonna, you're gonna upgrade to the M four Pro
Speaker 7:  because obviously my Photoshop needs are
Speaker 7:  intense.
Speaker 8:  Sure.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 8:  There's a lot of filters.
Speaker 7:  I, I I,
Speaker 8:  Photoshop and Patel they
Speaker 7:  Call it. I take screenshots of David and I draw mustaches on his face every
Speaker 7:  night and I need 20 GPU
Speaker 7:  cores to do that.
Speaker 7:  Sure. So then you're like, I'm, I'll stick with a base M four pro, I'm not
Speaker 7:  gonna upgrade for $200 to the next step up. That's too much.
Speaker 7:  But you're like, I can't sit here with 24 gigs of ram, so I'm gonna spend
Speaker 7:  $400 on 48 gigs of ram because 36 is not offered for some
Speaker 7:  bananas reason. And then you can't, five 12 gigs of storage
Speaker 7:  is not acceptable. So you have to go to at least a terabyte. And then
Speaker 7:  I'm not gonna sit here with a gigabit ethernet port. I'm gonna get 10 gigs
Speaker 7:  of ethernet. My home network is 2.5. Right. So like, at the very
Speaker 7:  least, I need that. And then one day I'm gonna get one of those crazy fiber
Speaker 7:  connections. I gotta be ready for the future. I am at $2,100,
Speaker 7:  2090 $9.
Speaker 7:  I've configured a Mac to $2,100. Like
Speaker 7:  instantly
Speaker 8:  Checking really quick. What was your starting budget?
Speaker 7:  The starting budget of MAC is 5 99. So you can like blink
Speaker 7:  at the MAC mini configurator and get it to be very expensive. Or you can
Speaker 7:  open the Mac Studio page and the base model Mac Studio is
Speaker 7:  $2,000. You're like, it already has 36 gigs of ram.
Speaker 7:  I'll upgrade to a terabyte of storage. It already has a 10
Speaker 7:  10 gigabit ethernet card. I don't need to upgrade this processor because
Speaker 7:  I don't know what any of these numbers mean. 2200
Speaker 7:  I, I think this is an obvious choice. I, and I think America needs to know
Speaker 7:  if the, I don't know. I look CVEs in a lot of trouble with Brennan
Speaker 7:  Carr already, so I don't think they're gonna allow me to come on and configure
Speaker 7:  a Mac, but I'm open to it.
Speaker 8:  There's like a whole BizOps team at Apple that just got a raise listening
Speaker 8:  to this podcast. Like just that thing that you just said. They're like, well
Speaker 8:  we did it. We have, we have one. I
Speaker 7:  Do, I do tend to keep computers for a long time. Like I,
Speaker 7:  they, they sit on the deck. I mean this is why I'm thinking about, I mean
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna find a way to justify this Mac Studio, but I
Speaker 7:  think this is a staggering deal for the Mac Studio. Which version was the
Speaker 7:  staggering deal? The M four max with 10 gigabit. Yeah, the M four max is
Speaker 7:  basically already configured. The only upgrade you really should do is to
Speaker 7:  a terabyte of storage. 'cause five 12 is like, it's almost like
Speaker 7:  we're getting to the point where If you do enough stuff on a computer, just
Speaker 7:  the system and then like swap the internal drive in a bunch of applications.
Speaker 7:  We'll eat up five 12. Yeah. So you should go to a terabyte. Yeah. By the
Speaker 7:  way, I mostly do emails in Slack. I'm just saying
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna convince myself to buy this computer. I think it's like truly,
Speaker 7:  I think like compared to specking up
Speaker 7:  a Mac Mini, which a lot of people love to do, or
Speaker 7:  I mean the Mac Pro at this point is just like completely off. Like I don't,
Speaker 7:  I don't, I know what the point of that thing is right now. They need to update
Speaker 7:  that. Seriously. I'm impressed with this studio.
Speaker 8:  The approval rating on the studio in general seems to be like through the
Speaker 8:  roof. Like I don't, I don't know. I've never heard of anyone who bought a
Speaker 8:  studio and is like bummed with the experience that they got from it. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Apple appears to have like really gotten this thing right.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I I should just buy one here on the show.
Speaker 8:  I think you can expense it If you buy it live. I buy on The Vergecast. Right.
Speaker 8:  And
Speaker 7:  None how that works. It is strange. They rev the Mac studio so deeply and
Speaker 7:  they haven't touched the Mac Pro, which is now just running an M two Ultra.
Speaker 7:  But I guess it's, If you need PCI slots,
Speaker 8:  That thing is eventually it's just, it's gonna be a studio with more slots.
Speaker 8:  Like it kind of already is a studio with more slots. That's, that's basically
Speaker 8:  what works. And that's fine. There will be a few people who need that.
Speaker 7:  A cooling system designed for Intel chips that required nuclear power, like
Speaker 7:  Yeah, sure. It is very funny. And by the way, in all of this
Speaker 7:  that, you know, we've talked about Apple intelligence so much like the entire
Speaker 7:  AI revolution is running on giant Nvidia cards and Apple and
Speaker 7:  Nvidia hate each other. And there's a very obvious thing for the
Speaker 7:  Mac Pro to be able to do and they will never do it. Like
Speaker 7:  there's just a personality conflict that will prevent the one Mac that can
Speaker 7:  accept PCI cards from plugging an NVIDIA card into it.
Speaker 7:  And they will, it will never happen. Like they will add touchscreens
Speaker 7:  to Mac and put Mac OS on an iPad two decades before they
Speaker 7:  allow Nvidia hardware to run their computer. Like it's just never gonna,
Speaker 7:  everyone has to be dead. Like generations of people have to be dead
Speaker 7:  before Apple and Nvidia can bend their fences. I
Speaker 8:  Kind of think you're right. I like, I want to find some like would
Speaker 8:  DraftKings take that bet on which one happens first? Because I would, I would
Speaker 8:  very much enjoy being involved in that wager. But I think
Speaker 7:  You're right. It it's not small. There's a long version. Short version. The
Speaker 7:  short version is, there were some aqui pros that Nvidia chips ages ago and
Speaker 7:  Nvidia screwed up the thermals so that they would basically come
Speaker 7:  unglued, un soldered inside the computers. Oh boy. And I think Nvidia wanted
Speaker 7:  Apple to pay for it. And Apple obviously. And now never generations of people
Speaker 7:  have to be dead. That's what I'm saying. Like your children's children may
Speaker 7:  see an Apple computer Nvidia trip.
Speaker 8:  Fair enough.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I should just find one right now. By the way, the maxed out Mac Studio
Speaker 7:  is $14,000.
Speaker 8:  That feels low. Like I'm That seems fine.
Speaker 7:  You're like, let's do it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That, that and the new MacBook Air, they're deals. They're
Speaker 7:  Deals, nothing but a deal.
Speaker 8:  512 gigs of unified memory on the Max
Speaker 8:  Studio.
Speaker 8:  I think on a, on a tablet, 64 Ks is actually basically
Speaker 8:  fine. Like, what are you downloading under your fucking iPad movies?
Speaker 7:  No, no, you're wrong. Wait until your kid needs to take a plane
Speaker 7:  with an iPad. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  She doesn't need 4K. Yeah, that's Bluey Is is AO K at four 80?
Speaker 8:  Do you know
Speaker 7:  How many episodes of Bluey there are? Do you know how many episodes Ofaw
Speaker 7:  patrol? They are. Have you ever sat with a 6-year-old and argued about which
Speaker 7:  episodes Ofaw patrol to put on their iPad before a 90 minute flight?
Speaker 7:  You're just like, all of 'em, just all of just give the library and that's
Speaker 8:  I'm I'm done with this conversation. That's why. Yeah, all the kids, they,
Speaker 8:  they're supposed to get the $350 iPad. They end up getting one terabyte of
Speaker 8:  storage. It's real preloaded Paw Patrol.
Speaker 7:  We're back, everybody. We're back. We're just, it just rolled right in. That's,
Speaker 7:  people wonder what happens between the segments while someone else reads
Speaker 7:  the ads. That's what happens.
Speaker 7:  All right. We got a tech lightning round. There's actually quite a lot of
Speaker 7:  small tech news. I I wanna start with this one because
Speaker 7:  David, I feel like we've run the Dig is back story 50 times.
Speaker 8:  It's probably right. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's been back several times. If you recall, dig was one of the early sort
Speaker 7:  of news aggregators when I worked at Eng Gadget a million years ago.
Speaker 7:  We would argue about what stories should get a dig badge. So if we saw that
Speaker 7:  like traffic was like going up on a story, we'd put the dig badge on it.
Speaker 7:  And the reason we'd argue about it was, I, I believe the dig badge at the
Speaker 7:  time was a flash object, so it would slow down the entire
Speaker 7:  website.
Speaker 8:  Oh wow. But we'd be like,
Speaker 7:  We're getting a lot of dig traffic. Like it's worth
Speaker 8:  Dig did send a lot of traffic. Like it was a real, it had a a pretty long
Speaker 8:  run there of If you were at the top of the Dig homepage, like it,
Speaker 8:  it crashed websites
Speaker 7:  And you'd want to game it. So If you saw that you're getting some traction,
Speaker 7:  you'd be like, we should put the dig badge on this story so people can click.
Speaker 7:  I, you know, I dig it. There are some of you listening have no idea
Speaker 7:  what we're talking about, but like, it was like Reddit, it was a meaningful
Speaker 7:  competitor Reddit at one point in time, and then it went away,
Speaker 7:  and now Alexis Ohanian, founder of Reddit, maybe gonna bring it back
Speaker 7:  with founder Kevin Rose and David, you talk to them.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So the, the one difference between the many comebacks
Speaker 8:  of Dig and this comeback of Dig is that this is the first one that Kevin Rose
Speaker 8:  who created Dig is actually doing. So there's something meaningful
Speaker 8:  there, and he is doing it with Alexis Ohanian, who's the co-founder of Reddit.
Speaker 8:  And
Speaker 8:  it's really interesting because talking to them about it, it's basically
Speaker 8:  like Kevin in particular has been, has had many opportunities to do
Speaker 8:  Dig Again, and I think for a variety of reasons, chose not
Speaker 8:  to, but they are all all in on AI and,
Speaker 8:  and the idea that it can be a, a tool for helping
Speaker 8:  moderators do stuff and helping sort content and helping like
Speaker 8:  summarize stuff and help people build stuff within these communities. Like
Speaker 8:  the, the next turn for social networking is
Speaker 8:  basically like, what if we were nice to our users, which is a surprisingly
Speaker 8:  rare thing in the social world right now, and what if we were able
Speaker 8:  to build the tools that moderators in particular actually need?
Speaker 8:  I think the theory is super interesting and there are definitely a lot of
Speaker 8:  people out there who have fond memories of digs, so they're gonna get to
Speaker 8:  trade on that for a minute.
Speaker 8:  But they're also, like, the thing they're trying to build is pretty unformed
Speaker 8:  at the moment. It's very new. They're very early in trying to figure out
Speaker 8:  what it is. But I like, I don't know, I'm curious about this in a way.
Speaker 8:  I didn't expect to be, I
Speaker 9:  Was a huge dig user back in the day. Loved it. It was, it was a, a really
Speaker 9:  important website and I think really early to those sort of
Speaker 9:  social news aggregation ideas, I I, I think one of the big
Speaker 9:  reasons that it failed was that it wasn't Reddit. It didn't figure
Speaker 9:  out the community element. Yep. And Reddit did.
Speaker 9:  And I think the problem that they're about to encounter is that what they're
Speaker 9:  basically describing doing now is making it Reddit, but with some
Speaker 9:  ai and the cool, maybe like, I
Speaker 9:  love, I I, I have very, very fond memories of Dig,
Speaker 9:  but it, it definitely sends a little, like you're saying unformed right now
Speaker 9:  in terms of exactly how that pans out. But it is true, like Reddit
Speaker 9:  moderators have a lot of challenges and it is a lot of work to keep those
Speaker 9:  communities together and not breaking rules and happy. And I think If you
Speaker 9:  are able to take some of the friction away from that,
Speaker 9:  maybe there is something they can do that makes it a little bit better and
Speaker 9:  smarter. And obviously Alexis's involvement here,
Speaker 9:  you know, gives a little bit of sheen to it.
Speaker 8:  Do we think Reddit's good? This is the thing I think a lot about be, and
Speaker 8:  I'm sort of serious. I like, I think a, a real thing Reddit has going for
Speaker 8:  it is that it is the only game in town in a, in a pretty meaningful way.
Speaker 8:  If you want to do things like you can do on Reddit, there's really nowhere
Speaker 8:  else to go. Wait,
Speaker 7:  I disagree. Really? There's still a giant ecosystem of like old school
Speaker 7:  forums that exists and there are like weird companies that run the
Speaker 7:  underlying software. So like every car in the world has a forum.
Speaker 8:  That's fair. But but like, If you want to, If you want to do
Speaker 8:  a bunch of that in one place, I suppose, yeah, like If you wanna talk about
Speaker 8:  cars, there are other places to go. But I think part of the appeal of Reddit
Speaker 8:  is that it is both a bunch of individual communities, but it kind of puts
Speaker 8:  them together in a meaningful way. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Though I do wonder, like I I, I'm not, listen, there was a, a dig
Speaker 9:  Reddit rivalry back in the day and I chose my side and my side lost. And
Speaker 9:  so I've, I've still got a grudge there. I do wonder like
Speaker 9:  how much Reddit users are using the Reddit homepage, the r slash
Speaker 9:  all feed,
Speaker 9:  whereas Dig, dig was a homepage. You visited the homepage, you know, if
Speaker 9:  they lean into the, that again, that is a different type of product than
Speaker 9:  Reddit where you were going to specific communities or curating a very
Speaker 9:  specific subset of communities that speak to you. And I do think, you
Speaker 9:  know, they have proven, you know, phenomenally strong at that. I, I, I think
Speaker 9:  Reddit has like kind of come and gone time and again over the past like
Speaker 9:  decade and I feel like it's, you know, maybe stronger than ever right now.
Speaker 9:  So I, I, I don't know. I would say that Reddit is good, is very good at what
Speaker 9:  it is doing. And I think it's kind of hard to beat, like Neli is, right?
Speaker 9:  There are these super nerdy forums for specific niches, but a
Speaker 9:  lot of those forums now just take place on Reddit. And I, I think
Speaker 9:  for a mainstream audience, like there is nowhere else you can go.
Speaker 7:  Right? So here's the company I'm obsessed with, it's called Vertical Scope.
Speaker 7:  They're in Canada. They seem very sweet, I should get them onto Coder in
Speaker 7:  some way. They own AAV s forum, which is why I think about them
Speaker 7:  all the time. Oh yeah. Because AAVs Forum is the real thing. It, Reddit has
Speaker 7:  not even bit into one ounce of what AAV s Forum represents. If you're like
Speaker 7:  a home theater nerd, you're listening to the show, you know what a BS warm
Speaker 7:  is, they also own toyota nation.com, ben's
Speaker 7:  world.org, guitars 1 0 1 and something called i fish.net,
Speaker 7:  which is internet's hard fish,
Speaker 8:  Especially like a two Truths and a lie kind of situation. Like one of these
Speaker 8:  is not real.
Speaker 7:  Also something called dog forums. It's real, they
Speaker 7:  have 101 million monthly active users across the thing. They're not
Speaker 7:  right. Like they're big. Yeah. It's 1200 sites that they run on their forums.
Speaker 7:  But you're right, If you go to AVS form, there's not some connectivity
Speaker 7:  to i fish.net, right? There's not this like overarching,
Speaker 7:  I'm on a social platform that has subreddits. There's just this big software
Speaker 7:  and then obviously what they do is they wanna ads across all that stuff.
Speaker 7:  I think that's really fascinating. And I think that really interesting thing
Speaker 7:  about Dig and Jake, you, you were a dig user, so
Speaker 7:  I, I want to like dig was about sending you away, right? It
Speaker 7:  was about curating the internet and there's a quote in David's piece where
Speaker 7:  they're like, we don't want to be just like an RSS reader with a like button.
Speaker 7:  Reddit is about the content on Reddit. Like yes, there are links on Reddit,
Speaker 7:  yes, they embed YouTube videos, all this stuff. But Reddit is really about
Speaker 7:  the stuff that is happening on Reddit. Totally. And a, a big problem
Speaker 7:  for almost every sort of like curator of links in the internet now including
Speaker 7:  us, is that all of the action is on social platforms.
Speaker 7:  There are not as many cool things on the web to link to as there used to
Speaker 7:  be.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Which
Speaker 7:  Is just a weird thing that is currently happening. And so like I wonder
Speaker 7:  is the new dig, Jake, as you think about why you picked Dig in
Speaker 7:  the first place, was it because it was aggregating the web and it was like
Speaker 7:  showing all this stuff? Or is it 'cause there was a community on there?
Speaker 9:  No, it was because it was aggregating the web, right? Like If you were a
Speaker 9:  tech nerd, If you went to dig.com, you would get everything you needed
Speaker 9:  to know. It was the place to be. And you know,
Speaker 9:  it, it was, it was a light touch website, super fun to be on there, but it
Speaker 9:  was not about community. Not at all. And I think again, like ultimately I
Speaker 9:  think that was one of the reasons that they lost, right? Like, like AMAs
Speaker 9:  could not have evolved on Dig in the way that
Speaker 9:  they did on Reddit. And I think Reddit's ability to create those communities
Speaker 9:  and to have homegrown content is what empowered it to, you know,
Speaker 9:  become so valuable and become such a special place. And so
Speaker 9:  this new dig is, you know, we should say we have not seen it, right? Right
Speaker 9:  now they just have like a landing page that says coming soon, there's supposed
Speaker 9:  to be invites going out in the next few weeks or something like that. But
Speaker 9:  you know, we fundamentally dunno exactly where it's going to land
Speaker 9:  on that spectrum between just being a news aggregator and
Speaker 9:  being a more community centric, you know, Reddit type of thing.
Speaker 9:  And I, I think just looking at the internet that exists
Speaker 9:  today, it seems very unlikely that they would create something that is
Speaker 9:  just, you know, the original version of Dig where it is just collecting a
Speaker 9:  bunch of links and sending you out. Right? You sort of need that community
Speaker 9:  element. And at that point it's like, okay, well where's the daylight between
Speaker 9:  this and Reddit?
Speaker 7:  It's AI tools for moderators. Yeah. David, did they tell you anything about
Speaker 7:  Federation or Social web or anything like that?
Speaker 8:  I asked about that and the response was basically
Speaker 8:  it's a thing that they're interested in, but it's so unsettled
Speaker 8:  that it didn't make sense to buy into any particular
Speaker 8:  system right now. Which I actually think is a pretty reasonable argument.
Speaker 8:  Like, should you at some point want to be part of this
Speaker 8:  federated system If you are dig and want to like build tools for
Speaker 8:  communities? Yes.
Speaker 8:  If you're a tiny team trying to get a product off the ground, should you
Speaker 8:  be making giant bets on Activity Pub or at Proto right now? Probably not.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Did you see that? Tap Bots, which made Tweetbot, which was great,
Speaker 7:  and they made Ivory from Ason. They have a new one for Blue Sky called Phoenix
Speaker 7:  that they just announced. Oh yeah. And it's fascinating and they should,
Speaker 7:  but they're a small team and basically our entire announcement for their
Speaker 7:  Blue Sky app is like an apology. They're
Speaker 7:  like, we know you want us to keep doing ivory, but they were small so we're
Speaker 7:  gonna just like try this one and we don't know which one's gonna win, but
Speaker 7:  we promise we're not abandoning this one. And I, I was reading, I felt really
Speaker 7:  bad for them. I was like, you don't have to apologize. Like, yeah, no one
Speaker 7:  knows what's gonna win. There's even a line in their post that's like,
Speaker 7:  we think Activity Pub is probably gonna win like over the long term, but
Speaker 7:  Right. All the actions on Blue Sky right now, so we should probably make
Speaker 7:  an app for that. And like, it's like guys, everybody gets it. Every,
Speaker 7:  no one knows how this is gonna shake out. Like right. It, it
Speaker 7:  seems like it's, it will be the future in some way,
Speaker 7:  but it is true that all the users are using App Protocol
Speaker 7:  and all of the engineers like Activity Pub to win then that,
Speaker 7:  that's just gonna take a while for it to play out.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's tough. And I think it's the, the thing I'm hearing from a lot
Speaker 8:  of developers right now is, is that same kind of thing where it's like, okay,
Speaker 8:  I don't wanna build myself out of the possibility of doing
Speaker 8:  either of these things, but I also don't wanna spend a lot of resources
Speaker 8:  supporting them. Which I think right now is probably like the prudent way
Speaker 8:  to think about the internet.
Speaker 7:  Sorry, I'm just investigating what's on live phish.com,
Speaker 7:  just closing tabs and is fish.com It's the, the I fish forms. Like
Speaker 7:  if
Speaker 8:  Apple made a fish, it would be called the I Fish. That's, this is what we're
Speaker 8:  talking
Speaker 7:  About here. No, it's i fish.net. I'm sorry. I
Speaker 7:  fish.net is the world's biggest fishing form.
Speaker 8:  Fantastic.
Speaker 7:  I thought it was about keeping fish as as pets, but
Speaker 8:  That's a completely different community. It's not allowed on I Fish s a
Speaker 7:  Wildly different community.
Speaker 7:  That's my fish fish net. Some, some of, there's a there on the i phish.net
Speaker 7:  forums, there's, there's a sub forum called Life in General.
Speaker 7:  It has 1.3 million posts
Speaker 7:  just saying
Speaker 8:  People just wanna hang out. Like it turns out people just wanna hang out.
Speaker 7:  They didn't need any AI to do that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. One more piece of news on this before we leave the, the social stuff
Speaker 8:  behind. There was some news this week that Discord is potentially
Speaker 8:  starting to think about an IPO, which is kind of fascinating. Discord has
Speaker 8:  been through some weird ups and downs as a company over the years,
Speaker 8:  almost got a, was like kind of maybe sort of getting acquired by
Speaker 8:  Microsoft at one point that didn't happen. Has been, has
Speaker 8:  had lots of ups and downs for content reasons. It's a weird time to go public.
Speaker 9:  Strange. I feel like end result for Discord, given that like If you just
Speaker 9:  look at the trajectory of Slack, slack went public, it was public for like
Speaker 9:  30 seconds, didn't really go great and now they're owned by Salesforce
Speaker 9:  and it's like, it's fine. So I don't know, like
Speaker 9:  Discord is fundamentally the same thing, but like for gamers
Speaker 7:  They dis wait, neither Discord nor Slack enjoy that comparison.
Speaker 7:  No, they hate it. And you're like, guys, If you opened your apps,
Speaker 7:  so what Slack will tell you is yes, we yes, but we enterprise
Speaker 7:  authentication is right.
Speaker 9:  And so is is is the the gamer market bigger than the enterprise market? Like
Speaker 9:  I
Speaker 7:  Well it's, I think there's, as a meme, stocks a consumer market, so like
Speaker 7:  Discord If you, you know, it's just a big consumer market that might pay
Speaker 7:  them directly.
Speaker 9:  Right. That's true.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, I, I think we're, we're in the age of all of these social platforms
Speaker 7:  being like, we're companies or there's space here. Like
Speaker 7:  everyone is pretty frustrated with the four billionaires who run all communications
Speaker 7:  in America. What if, what if we tried? Right. And it
Speaker 7:  helps If you have a billionaire of your own like Alexis.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, a couple of them in fact. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And I think that one of
Speaker 8:  the things that Kevin said about Dig, which I thought was really interesting
Speaker 8:  is like, I kept pressing on like, how big do you want this thing to be?
Speaker 8:  And they seem really interested in not trying to like,
Speaker 8:  deliberately not trying to go out and build another, you know, many billion
Speaker 8:  dollar gigantic company, which is like a thing you can say when you're already
Speaker 8:  fabulously wealthy from other means. Like this is the kind of thing that
Speaker 8:  they're like, maybe without the pressures of being a public company to go,
Speaker 8:  you know, screw over our users to please our shareholders, we can actually
Speaker 8:  do more interesting stuff. And so I think there is a real like boutiquey
Speaker 8:  nature to a lot of these projects that I think are really exciting.
Speaker 8:  And I think if, if the, if this dig thing goes well, it'll look like that
Speaker 8:  too. Would be my guess.
Speaker 7:  Once you go IPO then you have shareholders who want money. Right. And I,
Speaker 7:  I wonder how Discord will respond to that other stuff. Nothing has new phones
Speaker 7:  that phone three A and three a pro.
Speaker 9:  I've seen the AI button on the side.
Speaker 7:  Oh, of course. Yeah, that's necessary.
Speaker 9:  That's, that's the big new feature is I think it's called the essential button.
Speaker 7:  That's not confusing at all. I feel like I, we put the nothing phone on the
Speaker 7:  list, but actually the phone I wanna talk about is this weird Korean prototype
Speaker 7:  that Alison saw at Mobile World Congress. Well, that's right. Like nothing
Speaker 7:  made another phone, you know, they, it
Speaker 8:  Does AI things. No, that's fair. I do think I, I left it off the list
Speaker 8:  for today because Allison and Don Preston, who are at MWC are gonna come
Speaker 8:  on the show on Tuesday to talk about all of this stuff. But I do agree the
Speaker 8:  AI phone is maybe the single most interesting gadget of the entire week.
Speaker 7:  Well I just, I mean it's nuts. Like it makes a
Speaker 7:  3D avatar of you and watches everything you do and then it fills out forms
Speaker 7:  in the internet for you, which is whatever apparently wants. Like people
Speaker 7:  look at forms of the internet and they freak out apparently just every day
Speaker 7:  panic in the streets, just throwing their hands in the air. I don't know
Speaker 7:  how to fill out these forms. We have to collect all of society's information
Speaker 7:  to make an avatar of myself that can do this. But it's wild 'cause the, the
Speaker 7:  screen on the front is bifurcated and on top of the screen is an avatar of
Speaker 7:  yourself.
Speaker 8:  I don't understand it. I'm looking at this picture now and the
Speaker 8:  more I look at it, the less it makes sense to me. Actually
Speaker 9:  Does this, yo, is is that a second screen?
Speaker 7:  I'm just gonna read you this paragraph.
Speaker 8:  Like what is happening?
Speaker 7:  The idea is that you go around downloading your personal data history from
Speaker 7:  websites like Meta and Google also your medical records and financial data.
Speaker 7:  This is encrypted into a quote personal knowledge graph that is broken up
Speaker 7:  and stored across multiple third party cloud servers that theoretically only
Speaker 7:  the owner of data can access. And then all of this
Speaker 7:  is used to make an AI avatar that acts as a virtual assistant.
Speaker 9:  It also looks like it's running Android six.
Speaker 7:  I mean
Speaker 7:  it really does. Part of the charm of MWC is like what version of Android
Speaker 7:  is this really?
Speaker 9:  I'm so excited for this.
Speaker 7:  We, you should talk to Alison about all this on the show when she's on, but
Speaker 7:  they, the company claims that in order to do the demo where they had the
Speaker 7:  phone buy car insurance, they actually bought a car.
Speaker 7:  I guess they keep buying the car insurance.
Speaker 8:  Okay. I actually respect the hell outta that. Yeah. That is like the most
Speaker 8:  insured car in the world now.
Speaker 7:  It all looks very silly. And then, you know, as with everything, there's
Speaker 7:  too good to be true element. They say this phone will be sold globally on
Speaker 7:  May 1st for $375. Sure. Man, I
Speaker 7:  I'm dying to hear what Allison, and don't have to say it when they're on
Speaker 7:  the show, but it truly may be the most interesting gadget of the week.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I I I agree. I guarantee we will never see it again. But
Speaker 8:  I'm glad we saw it once. And that comes for something, the
Speaker 7:  Best part of the whole thing is that I guess in Korea they did
Speaker 7:  a blockchain based vaccine record system, but
Speaker 7:  crypto is so toxic that they apologized for it in the briefing.
Speaker 8:  Good lord.
Speaker 7:  And they're like, it's not a cryptocurrency, it's just a database.
Speaker 7:  It's really slow.
Speaker 7:  Very good. Volkswagen Id dot everyone, which is
Speaker 7:  one of the worst names ever. Volkswagen's new ev it's
Speaker 7:  super cheap. And Sean Kain, former VERGE Transportation reporter
Speaker 7:  says it's gonna be the first Volkswagen to run Rivian software. If you remember,
Speaker 7:  Volkswagen invested a ton of money in Rivian. They spun off some weird middle
Speaker 7:  company that makes software for both companies. And here we are the first
Speaker 7:  it's 20,000 euros or $2,100.
Speaker 7:  It's cute. And I think the idea that it's running Rivian software is super
Speaker 7:  fascinating.
Speaker 9:  You've used it How is Rivian software?
Speaker 7:  It wasn't enough to get me to buy Rivian. Yeah. You know, like, I'm
Speaker 7:  like a fancy car person. I, I like, you know, I'm older now. What about
Speaker 8:  A rivian for a fifth of the price though? Yeah. Like that to me is the whole
Speaker 8:  story of this thing. Right? It's it's, it's the $20,000 of it all that makes
Speaker 8:  this thing interesting.
Speaker 7:  That's true. Like a rivian. Right now you buy an R one, it's like a hundred
Speaker 7:  thousand dollars and it's like there's no software that will get me to spend
Speaker 7:  that much money in a car. Right. But on a much cheaper car, like the R three
Speaker 7:  X like I, I basically have convinced myself that I'll buy an R three X when
Speaker 7:  it comes out 'cause it's cute and it'll be cheaper. Yeah. This is very much
Speaker 7:  in the same mode. You know, Vivian's whole thing is the same as Tesla's whole
Speaker 7:  thing or whatever. Instead of having tons and tons of subsystems in the car,
Speaker 7:  they just have one or I think it's now they're down to some small single
Speaker 7:  digit number of compute units. So they basically have built a computer in
Speaker 7:  the car. They've rearchitected how the cars work, which is the point of all
Speaker 7:  that software. So that's what Volkswagen is really investing in. 'cause their
Speaker 7:  attempts to this were a disaster. Like famous in
Speaker 7:  corporate history level disaster. Volkswagen trying to do its own software.
Speaker 7:  What
Speaker 8:  I can't figure out about the, the id everyone, which again, like you undersold
Speaker 8:  how stupid a name that is for a
Speaker 7:  Car, it's so bad. It's in all caps and one is a number.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's awful. What, what is the thing that, by
Speaker 7:  The way, there's another one called the ID two all but
Speaker 7:  all is in lowercase
Speaker 8:  Something. So
Speaker 7:  ID is an uppercase dot two number lowercase all
Speaker 8:  Something about EVs has made everyone at auto companies
Speaker 8:  lose their minds. They're like, what if all the designs were insane
Speaker 8:  as if they were from thousands of years from now and they were named
Speaker 8:  completely incomprehensible things.
Speaker 7:  So I understand it on the design front. I I really do because
Speaker 7:  If you are building an ev you really want a low coefficient of drag. So you
Speaker 7:  get all these weird Tylenol capsules just floating down the highways
Speaker 7:  and then you don't have to build a engine or you, you don't need an engine
Speaker 7:  bay the way you need it to before. You don't need a transmission tunnel down
Speaker 7:  the center of the car. Like, you just get to, you have a skateboard and you're
Speaker 7:  like, what crazy stuff can we do? And the designers at Hyundai were like
Speaker 7:  a lot of crazy stuff. Yeah. Actually
Speaker 7:  the names are, I don't, there's no logical reason for the names to be this
Speaker 7:  bad across the board and they're, they are very bad.
Speaker 8:  But is the, is there something magical and repeatable about this? That it
Speaker 8:  is $20,000? Like, it, it feels to me like it should be a bigger deal
Speaker 8:  that somebody is actually able to make this thing at this price.
Speaker 7:  I think the real story here, and I'm just, I'm just taking a shot,
Speaker 7:  is Rivian already built the software and
Speaker 7:  Volkswagen,
Speaker 7:  like they have a big business in China, and the Chinese EV market is super
Speaker 7:  mature. And I think that has allowed them to build a car some lower costs.
Speaker 7:  And I think there's a reason we're talking about this car coming to Europe
Speaker 7:  and not to the United States right now. So like a lot of the investment has
Speaker 7:  been paid for, which is really what, why so many first generation EVs are
Speaker 7:  so expensive, right? You're, you're paying off a huge initial investment.
Speaker 7:  But If you Volkswagen, you know, you paid a bunch of money for your Rivian
Speaker 7:  investment, they're like, here it is. Like here's our CD rom make the car
Speaker 7:  good. And then there's huge investments across the entire Chinese
Speaker 7:  ecosystem. Actually, one of the, we should do a story on this somehow. I
Speaker 7:  will assign a story on this off this forecast. One of the most fascinating
Speaker 7:  things that is happening right now is that car YouTubers are discovering
Speaker 7:  that Chinese EVs are sick.
Speaker 8:  I've been noticing this. There's, there's like a run of these videos
Speaker 7:  Is like one of the best tiktoks around like one of my favorite TikTok channels.
Speaker 7:  He just did a bunch on Chinese cars. Like he opens one, I think it's
Speaker 7:  the L one. And he is like, if this car was in America, Tesla would be cooked.
Speaker 7:  Like that's the opening to the video. Wow. And then you, he goes through
Speaker 7:  it and the car is sick and it's $53,000 and like
Speaker 7:  yes. Is there a massive Chinese government subsidy
Speaker 7:  to develop those cars, produce those cars to do the ev Yes, there is the
Speaker 7:  economic system that develop that car is vastly different than the economic
Speaker 7:  system in the United States. But the car's done right, like it exists and
Speaker 7:  that the market is huge and Chinese automakers are,
Speaker 7:  they're, they're, they're like branching down a different evolutionary path.
Speaker 7:  Now, like here in the United States, we have a lot of hybrids. Like I have
Speaker 7:  a very cranky Jeep hybrid in China. They're all doing range
Speaker 7:  extenders. So they have gas engines that run at fixed RPMs that just charge
Speaker 7:  the batteries. We need more range. Mm. Which is like, that's how like diesel
Speaker 7:  electric locomotive works, right? Like they're just like headed off down
Speaker 7:  different roads. 'cause the core ev power train is like done.
Speaker 7:  And like we we're not, we're nowhere close. We have Tesla. And it's like,
Speaker 7:  well someone will throw an egg at your car. Like it's not a choice.
Speaker 7:  But I think it's like one of the most interesting stories is,
Speaker 7:  you know, like for a car and driver to do a big package
Speaker 7:  on Chinese cars, you know, they,
Speaker 7:  it would just be different. Like a traditional magazine like that just has
Speaker 7:  to like attack that problem differently. Car YouTubers just need content,
Speaker 7:  right? And they're kind of like out, like, here it is. Like
Speaker 7:  here's a, here's another weird Cadillac, it's
Speaker 7:  50,000 pounds. Like whatever. They're like, look at these other cars. Look
Speaker 7:  at, look at, these are weird. And there's an entire universe of cars that
Speaker 7:  are weird, like have like buttons that American cars don't have in them also.
Speaker 7:  And they're kinda like drawn to them. The, the
Speaker 8:  Chinese companies have done a good job of making cars that look like the
Speaker 8:  future in a cool way and not, like you said Tylenol
Speaker 8:  capsules. Like Yeah. Some lessons to be learned
Speaker 7:  From that. Look, I, I don't know, the economics of social platforms are weird.
Speaker 7:  The economics of the creator economy are weird. I don't know if the Chinese
Speaker 7:  car companies are paying all the car YouTubers suit. Like, I don't know.
Speaker 7:  Like I, I don't know what junkets they're taking. I just know that you
Speaker 7:  watch the reaction to these videos and it is astounding,
Speaker 7:  right? Like the, the one I'm describing from Fort went viral. Like Kara Swisher
Speaker 7:  shared a car video. Like what are we doing here? Like, is this weird? My,
Speaker 7:  my cousin and my uncle sent it to me like it went viral in a different way.
Speaker 7:  Right? Because the car inside of that video is compelling. And his point
Speaker 7:  is, we can't have this car. Like we don't have access to Chinese
Speaker 7:  cars this way and everyone because of tariffs, 'cause all this stuff.
Speaker 7:  They're like, oh, American manufacturers can't compete. That's not
Speaker 7:  what you want to, that's not what you want the comment section to be filled
Speaker 7:  with. Right? Like, you want the comment section to be filled with
Speaker 7:  like, fuck you GM forever or whatever. Like just, it was just not
Speaker 7:  present there. Right. And the part where it's like what you normally see
Speaker 7:  in an ev comment section, it's like, I, I'll never buy an ev The range extender
Speaker 7:  solved that problem. Kids are like, oh, you can just fill this thing. You
Speaker 7:  like gas, just put gas in this part of the car, it'll be fine.
Speaker 7:  We're far away from the Volkswagen. We, we started now,
Speaker 7:  now I'm just ranting about tariffs. A preview of what's to come my friend.
Speaker 7:  All right. Last item in the lightning round. And then I, I promise you, 90
Speaker 7:  more minutes of iPad Air conversation Microsoft shut down Skype.
Speaker 7:  I'm sad.
Speaker 8:  Jake, are you surprised by this?
Speaker 9:  No, no. I mean, I, I, I would love to know in the last time people used
Speaker 9:  Skype was I, I was looking back at some of the
Speaker 9:  retrospectives. There were like five Skype redesigns I didn't even know
Speaker 9:  happened there. There was one that was like so experimental. It like didn't
Speaker 9:  even have an interface. Like I, it was like some weird like
Speaker 9:  neo Snapchat thing. It was cra nobody even knew this happened
Speaker 9:  'cause nobody was opening up Skype. And you know, it's really sad. Skype
Speaker 9:  was,
Speaker 9:  you know, a very foundational pioneer in,
Speaker 9:  you know, voice calling in the VoIP space.
Speaker 9:  I, I remember like using it very early on and you would pay like, you know,
Speaker 9:  cents and be able to make a phone call Ooh, like crazy from
Speaker 9:  your computer to a real phone. And it felt incredible.
Speaker 9:  It was like the coolest thing ever. People used to call real phones back
Speaker 9:  then. This was, don't worry about that. Yeah, it's not important. You know,
Speaker 9:  Skype, Skype was, was kind of mind blowing and it really had this incredible
Speaker 9:  life as, you know, a chat app too and a a,
Speaker 9:  you know, a voice calling app of its own.
Speaker 9:  And you know, Tom Warren has a piece up on our site right now looking back
Speaker 9:  at sort of what went wrong.
Speaker 9:  It was sold to eBay for a while. eBay sold it to Microsoft. Microsoft paid
Speaker 9:  eight and a half billion, I think it was in 2011. And that was
Speaker 9:  right around the time things started going wrong. Which is not to say
Speaker 9:  it was Microsoft's fault so much as mobile was
Speaker 9:  exploding and Skype was a desktop service. And
Speaker 9:  this sort of ultimately, and I'm just stealing Tom's remarks here,
Speaker 9:  led to this situation where, okay, the pandemic comes around and everybody
Speaker 9:  needs to do voice calling and video chatting and nobody
Speaker 9:  went to Skype and everybody went to enterprise software
Speaker 9:  because it just, like, it never quite made that leap.
Speaker 8:  Okay. So I think, I think the, all the facts you just said are correct and
Speaker 8:  I think the story you just told is dead wrong. Hmm. I I, I
Speaker 8:  honestly believe I've spent a lot of time the last few days thinking about
Speaker 8:  this. I think Skype might be one of the most
Speaker 8:  bottled botched acquisitions in the history of the tech
Speaker 8:  industry. Like, I, I think you could make a case right now that Skype is
Speaker 8:  still the best loved brand name in its space.
Speaker 8:  Like, people I think still have better feelings about Skype right now
Speaker 8:  than they do about just about anything else in space. 'cause they
Speaker 7:  Stopped using it.
Speaker 8:  Sure. But like,
Speaker 7:  Like looking back, I, I, I mean, yeah, like I, I stopped using my creative
Speaker 7:  Rio MP three player and now I love it. But
Speaker 8:  No you don't.
Speaker 7:  I I love the memories associated with it. But
Speaker 8:  That's the thing. Skype was a decade ahead of its
Speaker 8:  competition on almost everything and had a bunch of like complicated tech
Speaker 8:  debt and foundational stuff in, I'm
Speaker 7:  Sorry it was a Diamond Rio. I apologize.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, there you go. Go ahead. Which is, yeah, you're not, you're,
Speaker 8:  you're not not helping my point here. This is great for me. Okay. I think
Speaker 8:  Microsoft bought a thing that, to your point, Jake had some tech debt,
Speaker 8:  had some problems had, was, was behind. But also
Speaker 8:  like the mobile revolution was the VoIP revolution, right? Like
Speaker 8:  mobile made WhatsApp happen. There's nothing that WhatsApp has that
Speaker 8:  Skype didn't sit on for a long time. Skype had a bunch
Speaker 8:  of like technical problems. It did peer-to-peer stuff because of the way
Speaker 8:  that it was architected early on. And it would've had to, but
Speaker 7:  Microsoft done did that,
Speaker 8:  Right? This is
Speaker 7:  The thing,
Speaker 8:  Right? It's all just, there's no reason this didn't work except that
Speaker 8:  Microsoft screwed it up. And Skype had a bunch of correct
Speaker 8:  ideas about not only what Zoom and
Speaker 8:  Teams and Meet would eventually do, but what, like the whole
Speaker 8:  messaging ecosystem was going to become that. It could have been
Speaker 8:  Skype, could have been Zoom and WhatsApp simultaneously.
Speaker 8:  It was just sitting right there for it. And it just
Speaker 8:  absolutely threw it away because of, as far as I can understand,
Speaker 8:  just total corporate disasters. I am also determined to get to the bottom
Speaker 8:  of what actually happened here inside of Microsoft. If you know and wanna
Speaker 8:  talk to me about it, David, at The Verge dot com. I have, I have until
Speaker 8:  May 5th to actually figure out the answer to this story before no one will
Speaker 8:  ever care anymore. And I am desperate to figure out what actually happened
Speaker 8:  here because like, something stupid
Speaker 8:  happened inside of Microsoft that made all of this fall apart and I cannot
Speaker 8:  figure out what it's, and also just the fact
Speaker 7:  Satcha Nadella was like, we own Skype.
Speaker 8:  I honestly, that might've been part of it, right? There's like a big leadership
Speaker 8:  change and like, we're gonna do something else. But even at the beginning
Speaker 8:  of the pandemic, the fact that Microsoft decided to build a thing called
Speaker 8:  Teams and turn that into its product instead
Speaker 8:  of just doubling down on Skype.
Speaker 7:  Weird,
Speaker 8:  Like, you know, it's a crappy brand for talking to your friends teams.
Speaker 8:  I feel the same way about Google Meet. It's like I, I get on for like
Speaker 8:  my fantasy football draft and they're like, oh, should we jump on meet? And
Speaker 8:  I'm like, no, I don't wanna go to work. Like this sucks. We just ruined
Speaker 8:  this. And like, I don't know, Skype, Skype had all the ingredients of
Speaker 8:  being like an actually central thing to the internet for a
Speaker 8:  really long time. And Microsoft just let it die.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This reminds me that in the middle of the pandemic, Verizon bought
Speaker 7:  BlueJeans and they tried to make everyone think blue jeans would be a thing
Speaker 8:  For so
Speaker 7:  Much money. For so much money. I, I think Skype had some
Speaker 7:  technical problems that made it easier to start with teams or
Speaker 7:  to start again with teams. And I'll never forget, you know, teams basically
Speaker 7:  killed Slack, right? They, the introduction of teams and the bundling of
Speaker 7:  teams in office is what drove Slack into the arms of Salesforce.
Speaker 7:  And I'll never forget someone at Microsoft was like, you have to understand,
Speaker 7:  everyone thinks we're making some like work chat product
Speaker 7:  teams is a video conferencing product. Like, that's what it is. And that's
Speaker 7:  why people are using it. That's why. And you're like, but that's Skype. You
Speaker 7:  Skype. You
Speaker 8:  Did that already. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And they were just very convinced that fundamentally
Speaker 7:  they were, they were initiating people to use Microsoft video chatting services
Speaker 7:  with teams. 'cause people thought it was Slack and Slack was all rage,
Speaker 7:  but they were actually competing with Zoom the entire time. I don't know
Speaker 7:  man, I, I'm sad. I, we made a lot of podcasts on Skype over the years. I
Speaker 7:  still think, by the way, Skype has the best To this day, the best audio and
Speaker 7:  video quality of all the services.
Speaker 7:  But I haven't touched it in forever. Like yeah
Speaker 8:  'cause why, why would you? Yeah, there's nothing,
Speaker 7:  Whenever, whenever I appear on CNBC for cable news hits, I would always tell
Speaker 7:  them to use Skype. 'cause they supported Skype and their engineers would
Speaker 7:  be like, what?
Speaker 7:  Like, you don't wanna love that. You don't wanna be on Zoom? And I be, zoom
Speaker 7:  looks bad. And I'm like, oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. And they would later they'd
Speaker 7:  all be like, you're right. We can't get anyone else to
Speaker 8:  circled on the tariff calendar. They were
Speaker 7:  Already, by the way, delayed for a month. I just wanna make that out, right?
Speaker 7:  TikTok is illegal.
Speaker 8:  Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That deadline is coming up in one month.
Speaker 8:  That's also gonna be that week. Oh man, the first week of April's gonna suck.
Speaker 7:  Rubber's hitting the road for the Trump administration, right? Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  you, they have all these ideas. They
Speaker 9:  Can't possibly delay these. Again,
Speaker 7:  Laws are just a concept. Concepts of a law.
Speaker 7:  The tariff lawsuits have to be coming. So tariffs are a big deal.
Speaker 7:  You know, you might be wondering why is the first guy sign my terrorist,
Speaker 7:  the CEO of Best Buy is like the prices are gonna go up and everything we
Speaker 7:  sell because everything is manufactured abroad or you know, the
Speaker 7:  Apple loves to say this is what the iPhone, like the Corning makes the glass
Speaker 7:  in America and they ship it over here and the chips are made over here. And
Speaker 7:  that, that all comes to China to, for final assembly and it's shipped back
Speaker 7:  to America. And by the way, we're hiring 500 billion people in Houston to
Speaker 7:  build Apple intelligence servers because everyone loves Apple intelligence.
Speaker 7:  And you're like, oh, they're trying to point out that their supply chain
Speaker 7:  is global.
Speaker 7:  And so every product we cover has is just
Speaker 7:  deeply and meaningfully implicated by tariffs to the point where we've been
Speaker 7:  asking these companies now for over a month, like, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 7:  And they're starting. I think the chaos is starting to, I think for it
Speaker 7:  initially they didn't wanna say anything like, Jake, I mean you've even running
Speaker 7:  the story basically initially they were just like, no, nothing. Like,
Speaker 9:  Yeah, just nobody would respond to us at all. And, and we, we just kept sending
Speaker 9:  emails and then yeah, finally people have been
Speaker 9:  starting to just be like, well, yeah, the prices are going up. My favorite,
Speaker 9:  and we talked about this a couple weeks ago, but like a a, I think it was
Speaker 9:  Acer's, CEO was just like, well, yeah, it's, there's like a 10% tariff. The
Speaker 9:  price will go up 10%. Like, there's just, just math and it's, yeah.
Speaker 9:  It's, it's sort of unavoidable. If they actually do, if, if
Speaker 9:  they go into effect, which I think like the big question is knowing whether
Speaker 9:  or not they're in effect at any given time. Right?
Speaker 8:  I think what's been really interesting the last few days even has been that
Speaker 8:  I think this time those folks thought it was real.
Speaker 8:  And so, 'cause like if, If you rewind to like the campaign,
Speaker 8:  nobody believed Trump about tariffs, right? Like, this is the thing
Speaker 8:  all the banks have been saying since is like, oh, we didn't think he'd actually
Speaker 8:  do it. And then he was like, oh, I'm actually gonna do it. And everybody's
Speaker 8:  like, well, we'll see what happens. And then it, it, then it got
Speaker 8:  paused and it was like, ha ha, we told you this is never gonna happen. It's
Speaker 8:  gonna be fine. And 'cause everybody was like, well why isn't the stock market
Speaker 8:  tanking? Tariffs are gonna be a disaster. And then it
Speaker 8:  didn't because nobody thought it was gonna happen. But then this time it
Speaker 8:  started, it, it felt real enough to people that A, they started talking to
Speaker 8:  us and b things started to change like the, the best by
Speaker 8:  CEO. One of the most interesting things I thought he said was not just our
Speaker 8:  prices are gonna go up, he said they're gonna go up in the next couple of
Speaker 8:  days. Like they were, they were, they were ready for it. Like they were going
Speaker 8:  to start making these changes quickly because this stuff happens quickly.
Speaker 8:  And I then you get this pause again
Speaker 8:  based on as far as I can tell, nothing. Like it's, it's just the same.
Speaker 8:  We had a perfect phone call and now I'm pausing tariffs for a month thing
Speaker 8:  every time. And
Speaker 8:  it, it's just, now I wonder what all of these companies and people
Speaker 8:  think again is like, okay, is this now just what we're gonna do? This,
Speaker 8:  this threat is gonna loom for four years but never actually become real in
Speaker 8:  a meaningful way? Or does it get more real and more scary
Speaker 8:  each time and they are continuing to like batten
Speaker 8:  down the hatches even more. Right?
Speaker 7:  And then there's other ancillary components of this, like the di minimis
Speaker 7:  rule that allows Shein and Temu and a bunch of other companies
Speaker 7:  to ship packages from China under a certain dollar amount with no
Speaker 7:  customs or tariffs. And that already off the
Speaker 7:  books but delayed again because there was no infrastructure to actually check
Speaker 7:  those packages and make people pay for anything. Like
Speaker 7:  look, you can argue with the policy of any of this, right? Like sure,
Speaker 7:  maybe we shouldn't have a diminish rule. Maybe we shouldn't undercut American
Speaker 7:  retailers by allowing she to ex, I dunno, there's a lot you could say
Speaker 7:  about that. You need an infrastructure, you need to execute, right? Like
Speaker 7:  plans are great, it's all in the execution and they are not ready to execute
Speaker 7:  any of this over and over again. We see that. And then, you know, the
Speaker 7:  various leaders of Canada and and Mexico are like, we made a graph
Speaker 7:  that says criminals down and Trump is like, pause for a month and like I
Speaker 7:  just don't, what are we doing? Yeah. Car prices
Speaker 7:  are supposed to go up by as much as $12,000. I have no idea what's gonna
Speaker 7:  happen to the EV market. That thing about the Chinese EVs, that's a tariff
Speaker 7:  story, right? Yep. They, they don't, they don't exist here. 'cause like we've
Speaker 7:  just made it impossible to trade in those vehicles here you start taring
Speaker 7:  regular cars at these rates. Like maybe you
Speaker 7:  actually do end up with a bunch of Chinese car makers being like, yeah, we
Speaker 7:  can compete now. Yeah, by accident.
Speaker 8:  Cheap Chinese cars plus tariffs end up being cheaper than
Speaker 8:  expensive Canadian cars plus tariffs. It's like, I had not realized until
Speaker 8:  I read a story Andy Hawkins wrote about this, that cars are already at record
Speaker 8:  high prices. Like however this shakes out
Speaker 8:  on, on this front. It seems like we might be due for some weird upheaval
Speaker 8:  in the car market here.
Speaker 7:  Look, if not for the other baggage, the only car anyone should buy is a
Speaker 7:  2-year-old model three, like the most appreciated,
Speaker 7:  cheapest car in the world that like won't break down. 'cause
Speaker 8:  There is a, there is a sign in my neighbor's yard, two doors
Speaker 8:  down that just says sell your Tesla. Yeah. And I'm starting to see those
Speaker 8:  pop up all over my neighborhood. They're
Speaker 7:  All, they're all
Speaker 8:  Over the place. And the bumper stickers that say, I bought this before Elon
Speaker 8:  was crazy. Like, it's a real, it's a really fascinating thing happening in
Speaker 8:  the Tesla universe right now.
Speaker 7:  If you, there's the great 4 0 4 media story this week about the cyber truck
Speaker 7:  owners club forum, just like breaking down over
Speaker 7:  how many, how many pe, how much people hate their cyber trucks
Speaker 7:  because you don't get to put the, I bought this before he was crazy on a
Speaker 7:  cyber truck, right? You're like, no, he was
Speaker 7:  right. He was doing a lot of this stuff. Like
Speaker 7:  speaking of Trump and Musk,
Speaker 7:  some, just some weirdness around Doge
Speaker 7:  the reality of what Doge is and the lawsuits are all kind of
Speaker 7:  colliding. So I think last time we talked about this, they officially
Speaker 7:  named an administrator of Doge, this woman named Amy Gleason. No one has
Speaker 7:  ever heard from
Speaker 8:  Who was, I think wasn't the story that she was on vacation in Mexico when
Speaker 7:  She was on vacation when she was
Speaker 8:  Named, yeah. When she was named. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Good stuff. And then Trump gave the State of the Union and he pointed at
Speaker 7:  Elon who didn't know what to do with his hands. Like he didn't do a
Speaker 7:  Nazi salute, so that's a win, you know, low bar. We hit it. He
Speaker 8:  Just sort of was weird with a water bottle for a while. He was just
Speaker 7:  Like, what should I do it?
Speaker 7:  Sweet, weird dude. And he said, Elon is in
Speaker 7:  charge of Doge, Elon is the head of Doge, it's being run by Elon. The
Speaker 7:  amount of seconds between that statement and it appearing in court
Speaker 7:  filings about Doge being illegal, zero seconds,
Speaker 7:  like literally in real time filings were updated and submissions
Speaker 7:  were made being like the government is lying to the court about who? The
Speaker 7:  administrator of Doja, it's Elon Musk. Look at t Trump telling Congress that
Speaker 7:  Elon Rons do. So then today Trump had a cabinet meeting
Speaker 7:  with Elon president reporting in Politico where he told the
Speaker 7:  cabinet that they were in charge of their agencies and Elon had no authority
Speaker 7:  to fire anyone. And it's like, guys, the judges
Speaker 7:  aren't stupid.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like they, they are getting the letters. I don't know if people really
Speaker 7:  recognize this, the letters, the emails he's sending out being like, what'd
Speaker 7:  you do this week? They're hitting the judicial branch.
Speaker 8:  Oh sure.
Speaker 7:  Like federal judges are getting the, what did you do this week? Emails.
Speaker 7:  They're not dumb. Like,
Speaker 7:  so I dunno if this is gonna work, but I I, the, the sort of like
Speaker 7:  legal reality, well the lawsuits are starting to catch up is basically what
Speaker 7:  I'm saying. And now we're at the point where, you know, Musk had a meeting
Speaker 7:  with the, like, Republican senators we're like, let us pass some laws to
Speaker 7:  do this for real.
Speaker 7:  And Trump has to like do this charade where he is like, Elon doesn't have
Speaker 7:  a job and everyone knows that he's in charge of Doge. I I think, I think
Speaker 7:  some of these lawsuits are gonna break against Elon and Trump in a big way
Speaker 7:  soon.
Speaker 8:  It, it's, it sure seems like it. And I think the, the, the bet they've been
Speaker 8:  making all along is that they can just be
Speaker 8:  2, 3, 12 steps ahead and it won't matter right. That
Speaker 8:  that what they've done will be hard to undo and they'll be onto the next
Speaker 8:  thing anyway. And
Speaker 8:  that one kind of seems to still be working. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like if, if the, if the judicial system is gonna remain
Speaker 8:  four crises behind Doge, doge is gonna keep getting what it wants
Speaker 8:  and that, that continues to be the playbook as far as I can tell. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  On that same playbook, you know, there's all this reporting about the FAA
Speaker 7:  being ordered to cancel this Verizon contract for connectivity and
Speaker 7:  work with Starlink instead because SpaceX is gonna fix everything. We just
Speaker 7:  did a long decoder with Andy Hawkins about what's going on with the FAA.
Speaker 7:  So SpaceX denied this study. They posted on x quote, recent
Speaker 7:  media reports about SpaceX and the F AA are false. SpaceX is working in
Speaker 7:  coordination with L three Harris Tech. That's the main contractor. That's
Speaker 7:  the one that Elon said was single digit months away from catastrophic failure.
Speaker 7:  And the FAA to test the use of Starlink is one piece of the infrastructure
Speaker 7:  upgrades so badly needed along with Fiber wireless and other technologies.
Speaker 7:  Starlink is a possible partial fix to an aging system. There is no
Speaker 7:  effort or intent for Starlink to take over any existing contract. That's
Speaker 7:  just fear uncertainty. They've signed a loan agreement with L three Harris,
Speaker 7:  they've provided Starlink. So basically they've gone all the way from
Speaker 7:  Trump saying, I've asked Elon to fix air traffic control after a plane crash.
Speaker 7:  And Elon be like, I'll do it. They're single digit months away from catastrophic
Speaker 7:  failure. Here's some Starlink to fix it. Verizon being like, that
Speaker 7:  was our job.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, we're already fixing it.
Speaker 7:  And now SpaceX being like, we didn't, we didn't do anything. We, we gave
Speaker 7:  them, we bought some starlings at Best Buy.
Speaker 7:  Deeply confusing stuff. Again, you need a plan. These are all
Speaker 7:  great ideas you need to execute. And they, they have not laid out how to
Speaker 7:  execute.
Speaker 9:  I'm clear. Is L three Harris's system actually like months away from
Speaker 9:  failure or is that just something that Elon is telling us?
Speaker 7:  Andy has been asking Pete Buttigieg this question because
Speaker 7:  if they're single digit months away from failure today,
Speaker 7:  that means they were only a little over a year away from failure
Speaker 7:  when he was the Secretary of Transportation. And he has not yet answered
Speaker 7:  our questions. But you would think we would know if the entire United States
Speaker 7:  air traffic control system was a year away from catastrophic failure,
Speaker 7:  you, you'd think we would know it.
Speaker 8:  It does seem worth saying that the only evidence we have in either direction
Speaker 8:  so far is wood. Elon Musk says, and
Speaker 8:  that should be taken with the requisite grains of salt.
Speaker 7:  I I honestly wonder why, why SpaceX put out this statement. I
Speaker 7:  I think maybe a lot of people assume that they were gonna fix air traffic
Speaker 7:  control and they don't want that responsibility.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I don't think that's a super fun job.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  SpaceX also has like quite a bit going on at this particular moment in time.
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  There's more here. Trump wants to screen everybody applying
Speaker 7:  for citizenship. He wants to screen all their social media.
Speaker 7:  Sure. I mean it just, it's more incursion into
Speaker 7:  speech. Like that just is a thing that Trump administration is very fond
Speaker 7:  of doing is like saying some speech is good and some speech is bad and then
Speaker 7:  saying they support free speech. And then the Senate has stripped
Speaker 7:  the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. It's enforcement powers over
Speaker 7:  what it's general enforcement powers that would've covered x turning
Speaker 7:  into a payment service, which well, you know,
Speaker 7:  a little light corruption is like, you know, it's the, the stuff that life
Speaker 7:  is made of, you know, a
Speaker 8:  Little light corruption. It's my favorite Broadway musical. That's
Speaker 7:  What keeps it exciting out here. These United States. Speaking of speech,
Speaker 7:  it's, I think it's time, David, is it on time? Oh
Speaker 8:  My God. America's favorite podcast within a podcast. Brendan
Speaker 8:  Carr is a dummy.
Speaker 7:  I will say, I got some notes last week saying it
Speaker 7:  we're minimizing Brendan Carr by calling him a dummy. 'cause he's not stupid,
Speaker 7:  he's evil. And my point was that he's too dumb
Speaker 7:  to make his evil seem fun.
Speaker 8:  I also think being a dummy and being stupid are not the same thing. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I, I feel very strongly that Brendan Carr is not stupid, but I do feel very
Speaker 8:  strongly that he's a dummy.
Speaker 7:  Let me make a comparison for you, Ted Cruz. Very smart man.
Speaker 7:  Some very bad ideas. You listen to Ted Cruz talk, he's like, he
Speaker 7:  makes it sound compelling. Like no one likes type,
Speaker 7:  you know what I mean? Like, he, he's like, let me weave you a story about
Speaker 7:  Supreme Court precedent. And at the end of it, you're like, huh, that's right.
Speaker 7:  And then you're like, wait, I thought about it that all that was lies. You
Speaker 7:  know, Brendan can't do it.
Speaker 7:  Like he's not smart enough to do it. He just says whatever
Speaker 7:  nonsensical censorship idea that he has, and I'll give you this
Speaker 7:  example. He was on stage last week after we taped,
Speaker 7:  he was on stage with Ben Smith, who's the editor in chief of S four, an event.
Speaker 7:  I know Ben Ben's a smart journalist. In the middle of this interview, Ben
Speaker 7:  Smith looked at Brendan Carr and said, I think, I think I'm being trolled
Speaker 7:  here because Brendan talks in such stupid circles,
Speaker 7:  right? Like, no matter what the question is, his idea is that he's so smart
Speaker 7:  that he can just like weave his way through it. And Ben was like, you're
Speaker 7:  just trolling me because you're, nothing you say makes sense. Like all of
Speaker 7:  it is in inherently contradictory and kind of like, you're just
Speaker 7:  justifying government censorship. And specifically what
Speaker 7:  he was responding to was Ben was saying, it aren't, aren't you just
Speaker 7:  attacking these broadcast stations for speech you don't like by holding
Speaker 7:  back their licenses or threatening these investigations? And Brendan's response
Speaker 7:  to this, this is one of the most value free, like,
Speaker 7:  like principles free, just naked. Like I'm a corrupt
Speaker 7:  piece of shit comments you can make. He said the FCC is built on
Speaker 7:  precedent and, you know, legal principles. And If you look
Speaker 7:  at what the Democrats did, I now have the, you know, they did bad stuff too.
Speaker 7:  So now I have the precedent to do bad stuff. And you're like,
Speaker 7:  no, you should not do bad stuff, right? If, if
Speaker 7:  your big worry is that under the Biden administration, the FCC
Speaker 7:  was doing all kinds of weird censorship, and you're a free speech warrior,
Speaker 7:  the answer is not for you to show up and do more censorship because they
Speaker 7:  set a bad precedent, right? Like, that makes you a
Speaker 7:  bad person, just straightforwardly If you're like, they
Speaker 7:  abuse the law. So now I am the Punisher.
Speaker 7:  You should not be in charge of speech in America. And that that is Brendan's
Speaker 7:  worldview. I promise you that is his worldview, is that he has been given
Speaker 7:  a permission slip to censor speech across the board
Speaker 7:  because the power he perceives to have, and when I say across the board,
Speaker 7:  I also mean across the ocean.
Speaker 7:  Because this week the, you know, his big thing this week, he, he said
Speaker 7:  the United States will defend the interest of our tech giants
Speaker 7:  against the uni, against the eus Digital Services Act. We've covered the
Speaker 7:  Digital Services Act a bunch on the show. I've made Jake write about it,
Speaker 7:  like every, like the entire VERGE team had to like write about the D S A
Speaker 7:  D S A is a big deal. It covers the big platforms. It says some platforms
Speaker 7:  are gatekeepers. There's Digital Markets Act, which right next to it. Then
Speaker 7:  the speech platforms have certain rules. What they can keep up and take down
Speaker 7:  the EU is like, we're, we're gonna have some laws around platforms. We have
Speaker 7:  a different, we don't, they don't have the First Amendment. They
Speaker 7:  have different speech laws in the eu, famously Elon Musk, I mean Mr.
Speaker 7:  Free speech absolutist lie, but he says it all the time. He is like, If you
Speaker 7:  don't like what's on our platform, pass a law and then we'll comply with
Speaker 7:  the law. Like, that's his vision. The EU passed some laws, they made some
Speaker 7:  laws, but JD Vance is like, your laws are incompatible to First Amendment.
Speaker 7:  And the EU is like, yeah, we don't, we don't have one of those. Like
Speaker 7:  we have, they have a different speech tradition. They're, I think they're
Speaker 7:  very proud of some of their free speech traditions. I get notes from our
Speaker 7:  European listeners all the time. They're like, we have free speech. This
Speaker 7:  is different than yours. And their criticism of our First Amendment is that
Speaker 7:  our First amendment is, is so absolute. Like we,
Speaker 7:  and I believe this, like I, I think this is a good thing, but the criticism
Speaker 7:  of it is it doesn't allow us to do common sense things
Speaker 7:  right there. We should not just allow hate speech the way that we allow it,
Speaker 7:  but our First Amendment jurisprudence allows it. We should
Speaker 7:  like deep fakes, we, we'll get to it, but like the EU can just like make
Speaker 7:  some speech laws in a way that I, I think is inappropriate. But they, their
Speaker 7:  criticism of our first amendment is you don't have to be this crazy about
Speaker 7:  it. Like you can just make some policies and see if they worked. And you
Speaker 7:  can change the policies. Brendan Carr is like, I will defend Facebook
Speaker 7:  against EU regulation. Dude, you run the FCC
Speaker 7:  like you are powerless against the European Union you have, there's
Speaker 7:  nothing for you to say that has anything to do with them. You can just
Speaker 7:  wield some enforcement authority corruptly, which you now said that you want
Speaker 7:  to do, and punish European companies that operate here or
Speaker 7:  issue statements of law that make no sense and basically just interfere with
Speaker 7:  business because you're on a power trip and everything
Speaker 7:  he does and says indicates that he's on a power trip. Even the
Speaker 7:  stuff that I think is intended to be like mysterious and fun is like, oh,
Speaker 7:  you're just on a power trip, for example, this is the last piece of
Speaker 7:  Brennan Carr. The SCC has these open meetings, right? And the open meetings
Speaker 7:  are supposed to be like, here's all the stuff on our agenda. They're usually
Speaker 7:  pretty unanimous. Like they don't argue at the open meetings. So they've
Speaker 7:  got one coming up and they're gonna explore at the march open meeting.
Speaker 7:  They're gonna explore alternatives to GPS to, you know, provide some redundancy
Speaker 7:  of system and also improvements to the 9 1 1 system. They're gonna next
Speaker 7:  generation 9 1 1. Great. This is like normal FCC stuff. Sure. This is what
Speaker 7:  you want the FCC doing. They're like, should 9 1 1 work better? Like Yeah,
Speaker 7:  you don't have to pay attention to this. I
Speaker 8:  Didn't know GPS was a problem, but we can come back to that some other time.
Speaker 7:  Well there's just like in a bipartisan way, you're like, we all depend on
Speaker 7:  this one system that could be disrupted. Sure. We should have, we should
Speaker 7:  have other,
Speaker 8:  Let's have more systems. Yeah. Right. Sure. I buy that.
Speaker 7:  This is some like basic stuff. Yeah. Final paragraph this. He says, wait,
Speaker 7:  there's more. Finally we'll consider an adjudicatory
Speaker 7:  item from the media bureau. I can't preview the details of an item like
Speaker 7:  this one in advance. I'm sure inquiring minds will wanna know, does it fit
Speaker 7:  with public safety? Our theme, unfortunately, the answer to that question
Speaker 7:  is no. But that's just how life and open meetings go. Sometimes this vote
Speaker 7:  will be part of our broader efforts to clean house and clear up some backlog.
Speaker 7:  So we'll be closing out with a good government win. What's an adjudicatory
Speaker 7:  item from the media bureau?
Speaker 8:  What
Speaker 7:  Right. He that, that means adjudicatory means he's gonna issue a judgment,
Speaker 7:  right? The media bureaus recovers all the broadcasters.
Speaker 7:  He's gonna do some goofy shit and he's like
Speaker 7:  hyping himself for it.
Speaker 8:  Could this be like the 60 miny kind of stuff that we've been talking about?
Speaker 8:  Like yet another, you were mean to Donald Trump on your news
Speaker 8:  show kind of things.
Speaker 7:  I I have no idea. I'm just saying like, he is drunk with power
Speaker 7:  and Yeah. And sitting in a chair that should not afford him any power whatsoever.
Speaker 8:  And he is having the time of his damn life. And we know that because he keeps
Speaker 8:  saying it out loud.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, he keeps, I mean, and I'm just saying we should not have government
Speaker 7:  sensors. I I know that's controversial here in America in 2025.
Speaker 7:  We should have government sensors. We should have government sensors who
Speaker 7:  think they can just make law any, any way they want, which is what Brendan
Speaker 7:  is doing. We should have government sensors who go to events and tell journalists
Speaker 7:  that they're empowered to be corrupt because they think their predecessors
Speaker 7:  were corrupt. That is exactly the opposite of how you clean up a
Speaker 7:  corrupt government. And you should not have government censors who think
Speaker 7:  that doing censorship is worth
Speaker 7:  like a hype reel in a press release. Like all this is wrong.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 8:  Real like, bad guy with a gun, good guy with a gun energy.
Speaker 8:  Like the only way to stop the bad stuff is for me to do it. And
Speaker 8:  then it's not bad because I'm doing it. Yeah. It's like, it's kind of a,
Speaker 8:  like, I, there's like a, I'm a little tiny part of me that admires
Speaker 8:  that way of like thinking about your life, but it also just seems insane
Speaker 8:  to me.
Speaker 7:  When Trump was elected, our European reporters,
Speaker 7:  Thomas Ricker, tum War and all those folks, they were like, oh, we're in
Speaker 7:  for it. Because the EU is all about regulating the tech giants. And
Speaker 7:  there's a reason that all of the tech CEOs were the
Speaker 7:  inauguration. They want Trump to fight a war over the D s a in particular
Speaker 7:  d s a Digital Service act. And you can see that the war is starting.
Speaker 7:  It's not that Brendan Carr loves the tech giants, right? He wants to reopen
Speaker 7:  Section two 30 because he's just gonna write a law to reinterpret
Speaker 7:  a law that exists, not something an agency can do
Speaker 7:  very specifically, not something an agency can do anymore because it was
Speaker 7:  supreme recent Supreme Court ruling.
Speaker 7:  But it's like, you see that there's no logical coherency
Speaker 7:  to this man except the abuse of power. On
Speaker 7:  the one hand, he's gonna protect the check giants against Europe. On the
Speaker 7:  other hand, he's gonna beat them over the head with his interpretation of
Speaker 7:  two 30 so that they censor the way he wants them to. And it's like, just,
Speaker 7:  anyway, Brendan, as always, I know you listen, I know you get readouts. I,
Speaker 7:  I I, I honestly, I know you do. You're, you're welcome to come under
Speaker 7:  coder and face some real questions. I I'm gonna invite you every week I,
Speaker 7:  if people wanna tweet at Brendan, you can. He's, he's available. He loves
Speaker 7:  to tweet. He doesn't do anything except he know tweet at people and think
Speaker 7:  about how to abuse his power. So's up Brendan. He bren's and welcome on decoder.
Speaker 8:  What if, what if the adjudicatory item from the media bureau is Brendan Carr
Speaker 8:  coming on decoder?
Speaker 7:  That would be amazing. Brendan Carr is putting the eye Patel in jail.
Speaker 7:  I think he's a coward. I don't think he'll ever show up. So there's that.
Speaker 7:  But he's welcome. Anytime he wants,
Speaker 8:  We go. All
Speaker 7:  Right. We gotta wrap up with like a gadget just to clear the air. Jake, what
Speaker 7:  he got. Did
Speaker 9:  You see the phones that you can just attach an entire camera lens on the
Speaker 9:  back of
Speaker 7:  I did. And I got a note from Dieter being like, how do these, you think these
Speaker 7:  pogo pins work? Which is just very
Speaker 8:  Good. Wait
Speaker 9:  On, on this. They don't, they don't have to work. This is, I'm sure you should
Speaker 9:  ask Dom Mor because this is at MWC, so when you talk to 'em on Tuesday,
Speaker 9:  but it's, they're concepts, so I don't like do they work?
Speaker 9:  Like that's a very big question mark. Do they look insane and
Speaker 9:  ridiculous? Yeah. And do I like absolutely want this? A hundred percent.
Speaker 9:  It's just like, you know, and you could put a pancake, like pancake lenses
Speaker 9:  exist, right? There are small camera lenses. No, no, no, no. These are full
Speaker 9:  on telephoto lenses strapped to the back of, of what is essentially an
Speaker 9:  iPhone. So they just like
Speaker 8:  Made a phone with a mount on it and you can,
Speaker 9:  It rules, there's just,
Speaker 7:  It's an m mount, a full
Speaker 9:  Sensor just in the center, like open and exposed on the back
Speaker 9:  of this camera. It
Speaker 8:  Rules. It's great. Do you have to put a body cap on your phone when you're
Speaker 8:  not using it?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's not a bad idea. I mean,
Speaker 8:  I love, I I unironically love that idea.
Speaker 9:  This is great.
Speaker 8:  It's fabulous. Like we're, we're doing weird camera bump
Speaker 8:  things all over the place anyway. Like, just go after it.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, exactly. The, the cameras ha have sort of peaked. We've just
Speaker 9:  been doing multiple cameras. The ultimate trajectory
Speaker 9:  of smartphones is just to turn them back into DSLRs that can make
Speaker 9:  phone calls.
Speaker 8:  All I'm hearing is the lumia had this, right, like 12 years ago. The lumas
Speaker 8:  were correct.
Speaker 7:  What if, because there's two approaches here. The one is the what if the
Speaker 7:  main sensor was just a full on sensor, right?
Speaker 7:  Sure. And then there's what Jami is doing, I think, which is
Speaker 7:  what if we made a whole ass camera and just like mag safety it to
Speaker 7:  the back of the phone?
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's the one where it's like there's pogo pins. They're saying that it
Speaker 7:  communicates with like a, a laser communication system. Think
Speaker 9:  About how convenient it would be if in order to have the quality of
Speaker 9:  A-D-S-L-R on you at all times, all you had to do is carry an entire additional
Speaker 9:  lens that you could strap to your phone.
Speaker 9:  I, I want this to be great and this doesn't make any sense. So like,
Speaker 7:  It's a whole camera. It's got the sensor, the optics all in a
Speaker 7:  lens module and you just kinda like snap it on the back of a phone.
Speaker 9:  Oh, I didn't realize the, the sensor is in, in Xiaomi's lens.
Speaker 9:  Okay. That's pretty good actually. Right?
Speaker 7:  So the, the one, there's two of them. One of them is like, one
Speaker 9:  Of them is the exposed sensor.
Speaker 7:  One of 'em is the exposed sensor and then the lens is just go on it with
Speaker 7:  a regular mount. And that's like one idea, you know,
Speaker 7:  like
Speaker 9:  Idea
Speaker 7:  That's, If you just had the idea, that's the idea you would have. And then
Speaker 7:  there's x being like, ah, it's not quite ludicrous enough.
Speaker 7:  What if the sensor was in the lens and then every time you changed lenses,
Speaker 7:  you were also changing sensors.
Speaker 8:  My, my worst tech take has always been that
Speaker 8:  there is some very good idea in all of this. Like, do you remember the Samsung
Speaker 8:  Galaxy camera that was literally just a, a Samsung phone
Speaker 8:  strapped to a camera? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  That
Speaker 8:  Was a good idea. I remain 100% certain that a
Speaker 8:  point and shoot that runs full Android is a thing that should exist.
Speaker 9:  If you could watch Netflix on that thing, I I really think it would find
Speaker 9:  an audience.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's just like the, the creator economy is huge. Everybody is just
Speaker 8:  out here doing, like, you're telling me the people who like buy a second
Speaker 8:  phone just to make tiktoks, wouldn't buy a second phone with a kickass
Speaker 8:  lens on it.
Speaker 7:  So David, the funniest part of this story is that deep, deep in the
Speaker 7:  story, there is a link to Sony having this idea in 2013
Speaker 7:  with something called the Cyber Shot, QX 10 and QX 100. Yep. That story
Speaker 7:  was written by David Pierce for The Verge dot com,
Speaker 8:  10 outta 10.
Speaker 7:  And so you have a review of the QX 10 and your, your conclusion
Speaker 7:  was that the QX 10 was bad and the QX 100 was great.
Speaker 8:  I don't think any of that held up at all. I was right. No, no.
Speaker 8:  Can I get a readout on what the review scores were here?
Speaker 7:  I don't know. Oh
Speaker 8:  Yeah. This was the review I wrote about seeing Paul wrote on the Streets
Speaker 8:  of
Speaker 7:  New York City. The, the layouts are so broken after over a
Speaker 7:  decade, like 12 years later, these layouts are broken. So funny, one of the
Speaker 7:  pictures is just captioned with the word fire twice.
Speaker 8:  Fun fact. I don't know why. I literally, I have a picture of Paul Rudd in
Speaker 8:  cargo shorts that I took on this camera when I ran into
Speaker 7:  Him. Yeah. The, in downtown, the specific broken pole quote in this story
Speaker 7:  is the QX 10 is slightly better than your phone. The QX 100 blows it away.
Speaker 8:  Hell yeah. And
Speaker 7:  I think we all know what a huge hit the Sony Cyber shot QX one. All,
Speaker 8:  All I'm
Speaker 7:  Hearing is history also, by the way, the score, I got to the score, the score
Speaker 7:  is 6.3.
Speaker 8:  Sure. Seven. I dunno
Speaker 8:  the Yeah, I, I remember debating between the 0.2 and the 0.3 for a really
Speaker 8:  long time. All I'm hearing is history is proving David Wright and this
Speaker 8:  makes me really happy.
Speaker 7:  It's it is very good. It was $500. Anyway, this idea is back with
Speaker 7:  by Jam and I'm very excited for it. Love it. All right, good. We've cleared
Speaker 7:  the air. Gadgets are back. Everybody here's my waterproof.
Speaker 8:  Jake has to go like direct the Super Bowl from his control room now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Alright. That's it. That's the Vergecast. Thank you Jake.
Speaker 8:  Thanks for having me.
Speaker 10:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 10:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The
Speaker 10:  Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 10:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 10:  that's it. We'll see you next week.