# Transcript
ID: 03259f31-fc0c-4472-af30-b7aaf0155b71
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7475519668245217342/7341272937961891388/s93290-US-6603s-1743769837.mp3
Description: It's a Nintendo Switch 2. What could it cost, a thousand dollars? In this episode, Nilay, David, and The Verge's Richard Lawler talk through why we don't really know. But first, we talk about the Switch 2, and some of the reasons we're excited — and maybe just a little concerned — about Nintendo's new console. This is likely to be the most interesting device of the year, and we learned an awful lot more about it this week. We also talk about Microsoft's 50th anniversary, the fate of TikTok, and other gadget news. Then we get to tariffs, with the help of Tuneshine creator Tobias Butler, who explains how tariffs affect the way hardware companies do business — and how they're navigating the current uncertainty. After that, in the lightning round, it's time for a little Brendan Carr is a Dummy, followed by the latest on Tesla's sales numbers, Alexa Plus, and Coyote vs. Acme.
Speaker 5:  Hey everybody, it's Neli. Before we start the show, I just wanna say we were
Speaker 5:  nominated for a Webby award, which is very exciting. We would love to have
Speaker 5:  you go vote for us. We'll put the link in the show notes. Once again, we'd
Speaker 5:  love to win this webby. We'd love your support. Go vote for us at the Webby
Speaker 5:  Awards.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast, the flagship podcast of adding Greek letters
Speaker 5:  that cancel each other out to an equation to make yourself look smart.
Speaker 3:  Who among us,
Speaker 5:  We're very lucky in that we have an audience where you can make that joke
Speaker 5:  and everyone got it and they, they got it on multiple levels.
Speaker 5:  Like there's a realistic chance The Vergecast audience is like,
Speaker 5:  I should make this equation more complicated. Like in your day-today lives,
Speaker 5:  it's
Speaker 6:  Like the, the thing where it's like, did you ever have those math problems
Speaker 6:  where you just sort of, in your brain, you just like, know the answer, but
Speaker 6:  then it's like, show your work and I'm, you're just like, I'm gonna just
Speaker 6:  make up a bunch of things that happen between here and there.
Speaker 5:  It's six. All right. I know it's six. I'm not gonna tell you why. I know
Speaker 5:  it's six. It's
Speaker 6:  Six. Yeah, it's not important. Why? It's six, but it's six. Leave me alone.
Speaker 5:  And the answer is, crash the world economy. Alright, I'm your friend Neli.
Speaker 5:  David Pierce is here. Richard Lawler's here. Hey, good to be here. Welcome
Speaker 5:  back on today of All Days, my friend. There's a lot going
Speaker 5:  on this week. David keeps mumbling. We have too much show. We have a lot
Speaker 5:  of show. We're gonna talk about tariffs. We're actually, we've invited Tobias
Speaker 5:  s Butler who is the, the, the, the sole proprietor of a gadget maker
Speaker 5:  called Tuneshine, which I love, we've talked about in the show before. I
Speaker 5:  wanted to bring someone on to talk about the real impact of tariffs. So
Speaker 5:  we invited somebody who makes hardware, really cool hardware that I love
Speaker 5:  to talk about. What's gonna happen to his business. That's gonna be fun.
Speaker 5:  We've got a lightning round. We've got a podcast for a podcast that people
Speaker 5:  love. It's Microsoft's 50th birthday, which there's a lot going on there.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 6:  What I'm saying. We have too much show. Like if everybody could just stop.
Speaker 5:  David. David, The Nintendo Switch two is also out this week.
Speaker 5:  And then on top of that, sometime this weekend, TikTok is
Speaker 5:  gonna get banned again or sold directly to Jeff Bezos, which he will operate
Speaker 5:  then from his yacht. Do
Speaker 6:  You know how long ago the switch to announcement feels to me right now as
Speaker 6:  we're sitting here? It was, it was 28 hours ago,
Speaker 6:  give or take. And I, you could convince me it, it was like in January at
Speaker 6:  this point,
Speaker 5:  On top of all of that, we're gonna do a full hour on the fact that I once
Speaker 5:  again recommended brother printers to the internet. And what that says about
Speaker 5:  the state of the media ecosystem we out with. So buckle up
Speaker 5:  five hour verse. Yes. We should start with Microsoft because
Speaker 5:  on the day this this show comes out April 4th,
Speaker 5:  Microsoft will turn 50 years old, which makes me
Speaker 5:  feel like an ancient wizard.
Speaker 5:  That is just an old, old number.
Speaker 6:  You were, you were just graduating from college when Microsoft started, right?
Speaker 6:  Is
Speaker 5:  That I, I sat Bill Gates down. I was like, listen
Speaker 6:  Here, young pup.
Speaker 5:  No, it's, it's incredible. Microsoft is one of those companies that we, we
Speaker 5:  once covered as sort of an upstart, a challenger. Now It is an
Speaker 5:  institution. It It is the infrastructure that all the other
Speaker 5:  companies run on with Azure. We, we covered the bomber era.
Speaker 5:  The Verge started like with Windows phone,
Speaker 5:  like the idea that Windows phone would be a meaningful competitor provided
Speaker 5:  us an awful lot of traffic in our, including some of our,
Speaker 5:  our most contentious reviews of all time. When
Speaker 5:  we would write, Hey, this Windows phone is not very good. Oh yeah, boy,
Speaker 5:  people had feelings.
Speaker 6:  The Lumia comments were like, nothing I've ever seen on Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Tech message for a long time. It was the most comments we ever got was on
Speaker 5:  a review of the like Lumia 900 or something.
Speaker 5:  They're gone now. We switch commenting platforms. So you can't, and
Speaker 5:  I think that's good. I think that it's probably for the best that you can't
Speaker 5:  go back and read this like everyone, you know that right to be forgotten.
Speaker 5:  Everyone can just forget that one. But here's what I wanna do in honor of
Speaker 5:  the birthday. We don't wanna go too far into, into the history of Microsoft.
Speaker 5:  We published a list of the 50 best consumer products Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has ever made. I think most people think we got it right. There's
Speaker 5:  not a lot of, there's not as much heat as you would expect. There are some
Speaker 5:  people who vehemently disagree with our ordering. Yes. But the stuff on
Speaker 5:  the list, I think everyone agrees is the right stuff.
Speaker 6:  I was sort of impressed that we managed to get to 50 and I look at most of
Speaker 6:  these 50 and I'm like, eh, sure. It's pretty good. There's only a few that
Speaker 6:  I'm like, I don't know that this belongs on any best of list of anything.
Speaker 6:  But for the most part it's, it's Microsoft has a better run at this than
Speaker 6:  I anticipated.
Speaker 5:  Honestly, I was talking to Jake who made this list with Tom and he was like,
Speaker 5:  look, you know, lists are there to be argued about
Speaker 5:  because I was like, I wanna add more stuff. Like put this in an honor roll
Speaker 5:  mention category. And he was like, Wendell's m
Speaker 7:  I'm just, I'm gonna say it. Wendell's Media sent. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna
Speaker 7:  Yelling the thing. Alright, so here's the thing. Keep yelling into the boy.
Speaker 5:  Richard and I were there during the Windows Media Center days when we were
Speaker 5:  at Eng Gadget together. Microsoft would ship you a PC with a cable
Speaker 5:  card decoder in it. There are people listening to this show, young people
Speaker 5:  who do not understand that Microsoft thought it could turn a Windows
Speaker 5:  PC into a cable box using middleware and hardware developed by a
Speaker 5:  consortium of cable companies that were forced to do it by the United States
Speaker 5:  government. And they thought that this would work
Speaker 5:  like a lot. They super thought this would work for years.
Speaker 7:  We spent a lot of time on that. We all invested a lot of time
Speaker 7:  into that idea.
Speaker 5:  You would call the cable company and be like, I need this code to activate
Speaker 5:  a cable card in my pc. And they would just be like, no, no, we're not
Speaker 5:  gonna do that.
Speaker 6:  There is something to be said for Microsoft, just
Speaker 6:  has a series of ideas that it just keeps doing over and over.
Speaker 6:  And one of its ideas is television and that's,
Speaker 6:  yeah. As far as that idea ever goes at Microsoft it seems, but they're just
Speaker 5:  Like, the only reason television, we talk about CS every year is
Speaker 5:  for years Bill Gates would show up in Las Vegas and give a
Speaker 5:  speech where he'd be like, here's what I'm gonna do. I'm put a PC in the
Speaker 5:  living room. Yeah. And this idea is called convergence
Speaker 5:  and then soon there will be a PC in your living room for
Speaker 5:  like a decade. And then he was like, what if it was an Xbox?
Speaker 5:  And he was like, what if the Xbox was a cable box? What if the Xbox had IR
Speaker 5:  blasters and that didn't work? And eventually we got to, what if
Speaker 5:  we put basically a, a raspberry pie in your living room and
Speaker 5:  it ran Roku software and everyone's like, oh, that was way better than a
Speaker 5:  full on pc. But this is real. It drove the tech industry for years.
Speaker 5:  And Richard and I had to cover it. Richard former, the editor of Eng Gadget
Speaker 5:  hd. Yes. An entire subsection of Eng Gadget that we, we created
Speaker 5:  because Microsoft was like, what if we put a pc?
Speaker 5:  So Richard, I told you, you had to, you had to pick from this list.
Speaker 5:  Your favorite Microsoft product not is you can't pick media center.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's you doing honorable mention. See
Speaker 7:  That's how the media, the does the censorship that that's what's
Speaker 7:  going on. So I, I'll turn it back on you and I will include
Speaker 7:  Microsoft's most successful effort at bringing a PC into the living room.
Speaker 7:  The Xbox 360.
Speaker 5:  Oh the
Speaker 7:  Time that almost kind of worked because Netflix happened. HD DVD
Speaker 7:  Drive did not so much work, but the Netflix app came out on the Xbox
Speaker 7:  360, very wildly successful. And that whole red
Speaker 7:  Ring of death thing and all the Xbox that they had to take back and fix,
Speaker 7:  we're just not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Set that aside. HGDB and the Red Ring of death. You set that aside.
Speaker 5:  360 was great. 360, also notable because it was
Speaker 5:  a skunkworks project inside of Microsoft under an executive named Jay Allard
Speaker 5:  who was given special permission to not use Windows or Intel
Speaker 5:  chips. So it was a custom operating system on custom
Speaker 5:  chips. And that's why it was good.
Speaker 6:  Wow.
Speaker 5:  This is a true story. And
Speaker 6:  No one at Microsoft went, oh, if you need special permission to do this,
Speaker 6:  we might have other bigger problems. Like that's no,
Speaker 5:  You know, I think many people at Microsoft did that
Speaker 6:  Well. Sure.
Speaker 5:  And then they, they they got rid of their CEO and they
Speaker 5:  got a new CEO who solved a bunch of problems. Yeah. That was also
Speaker 5:  where they got, remember the courier concept that's on this list? It was,
Speaker 5:  it was a concept video. I don't even think they ever made a project. I don't
Speaker 5:  think they ever made it a product that was just a big book. Like you could
Speaker 5:  open like a notebook and write in it and it was a tablet and associated iPad
Speaker 5:  killer. Also Jay Allard saying, what if I didn't have to use Windows? And
Speaker 5:  that was a bridge too far. My friends, they had been burned by putting windows
Speaker 5:  in the living room so many times they let him do the Xbox 360. But
Speaker 5:  when he was like, what if I made an iPad that was good out of not windows,
Speaker 5:  they're like, death to you sir. And that was the end of that.
Speaker 5:  Alright David, what's your story?
Speaker 6:  So I did not expect to feel
Speaker 6:  the feelings that I felt about this particular one, but the, the
Speaker 6:  one on this list that I most went, ah, as soon as I saw it was the surface
Speaker 6:  headphones. Ooh, did y'all ever have the surface headphones?
Speaker 5:  No. No. But they had the wheel, right? That's 22.
Speaker 6:  They had the wheel. So they, they sounded like fine. But they had
Speaker 6:  unbelievable battery life when unbelievable battery life in
Speaker 6:  like a set of wireless noise canceling headphones was not a
Speaker 6:  guarantee. And they had the dials. One side was
Speaker 6:  for volume and one side was to dial up and down
Speaker 6:  transparency basically. So you could like, you could, you could change how
Speaker 6:  much of the world you could hear and how much you could just be sort
Speaker 6:  of ensconced in noise cancellation. And still to this day, that is
Speaker 6:  by a mile the best interface on a pair of headphones I've ever seen. Everybody
Speaker 6:  else is like weird buttons on the side that you can't find.
Speaker 6:  Or they do the Sony Touch stuff. That's just a nightmare.
Speaker 6:  Like Microsoft just did it right the first time and I think they
Speaker 6:  made two pairs of the surface headphones if memory serves and then just
Speaker 6:  stopped. 'cause that's what Microsoft does. Why keep doing our good things
Speaker 6:  when we can make more windows. But I loved those headphones. I still have,
Speaker 6:  I still have a pair around here somewhere. I'm sure they don't work anymore.
Speaker 6:  But like, I used those for a really long time because they were super
Speaker 6:  comfortable and just being able to like walk around or be on a plane or whatever
Speaker 6:  and just sort of spin it back, talk to somebody, spin it forward. Amazing.
Speaker 6:  I loved those headphones.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know, well they died is 'cause Microsoft failed to make a mobile
Speaker 5:  phone and the entire headphone industry requires you to own a phone in order
Speaker 5:  to make a successful pair of
Speaker 6:  Headphones, whatever.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying,
Speaker 6:  I mean there is that,
Speaker 5:  That's, that's your answer. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There are a
Speaker 5:  Lot of, I know there's gonna be some people who tell me that Sony and Bose
Speaker 5:  are doing fine, but there's, that's just because Apple keeps forgetting to
Speaker 5:  rev the AirPods Max.
Speaker 5:  This is real. And also the AirPods Max are heavy anyway, the service headphones
Speaker 5:  legitimately good. Love a wheel. Very Microsoft to be like, what if
Speaker 5:  there was a mechanical moving part on these headphones
Speaker 5:  that we gave up?
Speaker 6:  If they had just put a cable card in your headphones, everything would've
Speaker 6:  been
Speaker 5:  Fine. Okay, so I'm gonna, I'm gonna pick two.
Speaker 5:  They're kind of like both odd. You can pick two mentions. They're both on
Speaker 5:  the list, they're just low on the list. Wait,
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry. So Richard can't cheat. Richard
Speaker 5:  Did cheat. He provoked an entire conversation about cable card,
Speaker 5:  which made it happen, which admittedly is very easy to do on this show.
Speaker 6:  Richard. We're doing tariffs on Meli. This is happening.
Speaker 5:  So I'm just gonna pick the one that I think everybody expects me to pick,
Speaker 5:  which is the Zune, the Ill faded, but Beloved
Speaker 5:  Zune a product that gave us the word squirkle,
Speaker 5:  the real thing, a product which boldly asked the question,
Speaker 5:  what if this was Brown?
Speaker 5:  It's true. Those are their ideas. Let's, let's make it brown. And
Speaker 5:  instead of a click wheel, have a Squirkle, not great, but
Speaker 5:  introduced what the design language that would become metro, which is now
Speaker 5:  everything. And I still to this day have a
Speaker 5:  limited edition, one of 5,000 Joy Division Zune,
Speaker 5:  which is, it comes in a giant box that you know has the
Speaker 5:  Unknown pleasures art on it. It has every Joy division song on it. And
Speaker 5:  every now and again, I I open the box when you open it. They, they had Peter
Speaker 5:  SSL design, the box joy, division orders designer. So you open it
Speaker 5:  and it like lifts up. It's not elegant. It's like a big cardboard
Speaker 5:  box and like a bunch of, now it's old, like a bunch of brittle cardboard.
Speaker 5:  It is like creeks at you, but it like lifts up and you can like look at a
Speaker 5:  joy division in, and then you close it and you put it away until someone
Speaker 5:  puts Zoom on a list of 50 Microsoft products. And you remember the fact that
Speaker 5:  you paid too much money for this thing.
Speaker 6:  Is that one of those things that you like kept in the box because you were
Speaker 6:  like, someday when Joy Division is the biggest band in the world, this is
Speaker 6:  gonna be worth something.
Speaker 5:  One day my daughter will come home wearing this t-shirt and I'll be like,
Speaker 5:  you know, I have a Joy Division Zoom.
Speaker 5:  Have you ever listened to, I mean one of these songs and Lady
Speaker 6:  That's Yeah. Your, your Heine cube was sewing for like thousands of dollars
Speaker 6:  on eBay. So, you know, wait it out, it could happen. That's
Speaker 5:  True. Although I will never, the Heineke is like in the Vox Media office,
Speaker 5:  by the way, once again, thank you my friend Gabe, who I effectively stole
Speaker 5:  this back from. It's, it's there, it's fine. It's there. The Joy Division
Speaker 5:  student lives in its box in my closet. It's never, that's very precious to
Speaker 5:  me. Okay. So that's the, the main thing. But the one I I
Speaker 5:  insisted beyond this list is Microsoft Word 5.1
Speaker 5:  for the Mac, which was such a good word,
Speaker 5:  processor, that when it was replaced by Word six, which sucked, people
Speaker 5:  kept using it for one full decade. They were like, Nope,
Speaker 5:  I'm not upgrading to Word six. I'm not going to word
Speaker 5:  2001 for Mac. All the ones, there was a, this weird period where
Speaker 5:  Microsoft, the, the years that they revved the Mac software
Speaker 5:  were different than the years they revved the Windows software. So you'd
Speaker 5:  have Word 2000 and then the Mac would be like Ward 2001.
Speaker 5:  This made no sense to anyone, but people just kept using Word 5.1 for a decade.
Speaker 5:  I encourage you to look at the screenshot. It is archaic. It's in black and
Speaker 5:  white. It was a perfect piece of software, like a
Speaker 5:  legitimately perfect piece of software.
Speaker 6:  I was just gonna bring up the screenshot because it, it's actually like,
Speaker 6:  if, if you haven't looked at it, and again, I encourage you to, we'll put
Speaker 6:  it in the show notes. If you were to draw a cartoon making
Speaker 6:  fun of how ridiculous word looks with like
Speaker 6:  billions of buttons and every there there's like 14 scroll
Speaker 6:  bars here and all of It is completely inscrutable. And then there's
Speaker 6:  like three lines of text. Like if you wanted to make fun of the design of
Speaker 6:  work, this
Speaker 5:  Is perfect. Is what one of those buttons, if you look at every one of those
Speaker 5:  buttons, you know exactly what they do and they're right in front of you.
Speaker 5:  And there's not a single bit of wasted or hidden
Speaker 5:  interface.
Speaker 6:  There are five things here that you could convince me all make the space
Speaker 6:  bigger between lines. No, but
Speaker 5:  They do in different and meaningful ways.
Speaker 5:  I'm telling you also, you click the buttons and then the thing happens and
Speaker 5:  then you, you click the button right next to it that does the other thing.
Speaker 5:  This is why it's perfect software because everything happens. See, I gotta,
Speaker 7:  I gotta disagree with you there man. We, we have to embrace debate on this
Speaker 7:  show. We gotta go in that direction. How, how can you go Word
Speaker 7:  5.1 and not Microsoft Excel?
Speaker 5:  Ooh, I think Excel's gotta be on this list. But like as a concept,
Speaker 5:  not as a individual version. No,
Speaker 7:  No, not not actually using it. Just the idea.
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 6:  Is the idea of Excel. I Excel is not on this list. And I think the fact that
Speaker 6:  we put Clippy at 50 and Bob at 49
Speaker 6:  and did not put Excel on is a statement. I'm very glad that we made, I
Speaker 5:  Don't think anyone noticed Excel's on the list. All right, we gotta, that's
Speaker 5:  the show everybody. We gotta go
Speaker 5:  in Incre. I guess Excel technically is business software, not consumer software.
Speaker 5:  That's my argument for you. Sure. All right. That's Microsoft. Go read the
Speaker 5:  list, let us know what you think we got right or wrong or what you put on
Speaker 5:  the list. Congratulations to Microsoft for inching Ever closer
Speaker 5:  to Oblivion. Can you tell, I'm thinking about aging. That's what's happening.
Speaker 5:  But congratulations to Microsoft. We, we, we presumably they'll be around
Speaker 5:  for another 50 years because they make software, not hardware. And I don't
Speaker 5:  know if the tariffs will apply to them. All right. Let's talk about the Switch
Speaker 5:  two for a minute. I think Ash is gonna be on the show. Ash Paris is gonna
Speaker 5:  be on the show real soon to go in depth. She's actually played with it. She's
Speaker 5:  got a number of hands-on impressions. You should watch her YouTube video,
Speaker 5:  but we should still talk about it. David, what's going on with Switch two?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, first of all, Ash, the, the YouTube commenters
Speaker 6:  have been loving ash these last 24 hours and it's
Speaker 6:  delightful and highly recommend watching. She did a social video and a
Speaker 6:  YouTube video. They're both very good. She and Andrew Webster have both used
Speaker 6:  the thing and both came away from it, I think like, pretty excited. They,
Speaker 6:  it's, we finally have details on the thing that we wanted
Speaker 6:  Nintendo to make, which is just a switch, but better. So there was a, there
Speaker 6:  was a direct this week, which is what Nintendo calls, it's like
Speaker 6:  periodic product announcements. And we got a bunch of
Speaker 6:  new specs. We got a release date. The thing's coming out on June 5th,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna cost $450, which made a lot of people feel a lot of feelings.
Speaker 6:  And we should talk about that for now, but
Speaker 7:  Well, it's gonna cost $500. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  $630.
Speaker 6:  Give it time. By the time it ships it'll be $11,000.
Speaker 7:  Well you, you're going to buy the Mario Kart bundle version, right? You have
Speaker 7:  like, you're not going to buy this and not get Mario Kart. That's true.
Speaker 6:  Especially 'cause Mario Kart on its own is $80. But anyway, Richard,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna list all the specs I can remember off the top of my
Speaker 6:  head and you're gonna fill in the rest. Ready. Okay. So big changes. It is,
Speaker 6:  it has a 7.9 inch screen, which is substantially bigger than before.
Speaker 6:  The, the thing is the same thickness as the previous switch, which is
Speaker 6:  nice, but It is like noticeably physically larger
Speaker 6:  10 80 p screen, not oled, which again made people feel feelings, but
Speaker 6:  there will inevitably be a switch to ole at some point in the future. That's
Speaker 6:  what Nintendo did with the switch. I'm sure it'll happen again.
Speaker 6:  New joycons that attach magnetically instead of the kind of wacky
Speaker 6:  sliding mechanism that they've had before.
Speaker 6:  There's a new whole like video chat system. There's a,
Speaker 6:  there's a camera and they're also gonna do third party cameras that are separate
Speaker 6:  microphone in the thing. You can, you can talk and chat all at the same time.
Speaker 6:  Lots of focus on online. There's new controllers, all kinds of new stuff.
Speaker 6:  But it's just a, it's just a big rev on the switch. And Richard, you were
Speaker 6:  saying right before we got on that there was chip news, right? I missed the
Speaker 6:  chip news.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Nvidia put out a blog post the day after Nintendo announced the switch.
Speaker 7:  A confirming that it again has an Nvidia chip inside of it
Speaker 7:  because It is Nintendo. They didn't really go into details on specs, but
Speaker 7:  they went into far more details than you would generally expect for Nintendo.
Speaker 7:  Confirming that it has DLSS NVIDIA's technology for kind of rendering things
Speaker 7:  and downscaling them to make, make them look better. You know, using, using
Speaker 7:  scaling and AI to make things look better and smoother
Speaker 7:  than the hardware kind of should be capable of. So people call it fake frames.
Speaker 7:  I think it works really great in some situations and others we'll see. But
Speaker 7:  it's also going to be capable of real time Ray tracing. The chip has
Speaker 7:  Nvidia RT cores and tensor cores. They use to do all this kind of AI
Speaker 7:  magic probably has some relevance to the things they're doing with video
Speaker 7:  and with audio. Like there's a mic on the device itself so that you can have
Speaker 7:  it set up in the doc and use it to chat. So I'm sure they're doing noise
Speaker 7:  canceling and all the other features that we've seen from Nvidia over the
Speaker 7:  years within this thing. So I, I'm very interested to see how it
Speaker 7:  performs really.
Speaker 6:  It does seem like this may, this may not be like a,
Speaker 6:  a huge high-end processor system that they're getting from
Speaker 6:  Nvidia, but like this device actually has kind of a lot to do.
Speaker 6:  And, and one of the things Ash and Andrew were saying is like a lot of the
Speaker 6:  games that they were playing felt bigger and more detailed and
Speaker 6:  like they are games designed to be run on much more powerful hardware
Speaker 6:  than we have in the last version. And so like the, the
Speaker 6:  te it was the Tegra chip inside of the first one, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm kind of wondering about that Chip overall because it was, it was
Speaker 5:  a tegra in that w that's all related to the fact that Nvidia thought it would
Speaker 5:  be a smartphone competitor to
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm and that just didn't pan out, right? And so that was the chip back
Speaker 5:  then. And now, you know, they're saying it's a custom chip. We should talk
Speaker 5:  about D-L-S-S-A little bit in this context. 'cause it, it's kind of
Speaker 5:  fascinating to see it brought to a mobile device in this specific way where
Speaker 5:  you get all like the better visual fidelity that
Speaker 5:  Ash and Andrew have talked about. And maybe that's just because of D Ls,
Speaker 5:  DLSS. Like May the games aren't, haven't been
Speaker 5:  switched tofi, they're just getting upscaled by ai, by this chip.
Speaker 5:  There's usually that's like, I wouldn't say it's power hungry, but it's,
Speaker 5:  that's power intensive, right? To run all of that after you've rendered
Speaker 5:  the game, which is not something we've seen, I think really in the mobile
Speaker 5:  context, which
Speaker 7:  Could also contribute to the fact that it has a, I think, a shorter battery
Speaker 7:  life than the switch one from what we've seen from the specs.
Speaker 7:  So it seems like it, it seems to me like this is a little bit more of a
Speaker 7:  doc friendly machine than, than that
Speaker 6:  Was read too. And I, I do wonder like what Nintendo has learned from the
Speaker 6:  first switch that made it think that, 'cause that was my exact reaction too.
Speaker 6:  And even the way that they talked about it, this is much more like a,
Speaker 6:  a thing they expect you to play on a table
Speaker 6:  or in, in front of a television or something else. Like even
Speaker 6:  the, even the mouse gesture thing is not a thing you do when you're
Speaker 6:  like sitting on the couch playing video games. Like I assume what Nintendo
Speaker 6:  has discovered is that It is like a sometimes
Speaker 6:  portable device, but a mostly docked device. And I think if you're,
Speaker 6:  if you know that, or you can assume that you get to lean on power
Speaker 6:  a little more and battery life a little less, which I think is the opposite
Speaker 6:  of what Nintendo did the first time. Like, especially for 2017,
Speaker 6:  what it managed to get out of the battery was, was
Speaker 6:  reasonably impressive. And it does feel like they, they flipped that balance
Speaker 6:  a little this time, which I think is probably the right call.
Speaker 5:  I'm dying to know. It's funny, we, we talked about Windows
Speaker 5:  Media Center,
Speaker 5:  all this stuff they're adding to it, the mouse mode, the camera, the video
Speaker 5:  chat, it's all getting away from what made the
Speaker 5:  switch in particular, such a huge success. Here's this
Speaker 5:  dedicated device for playing games. The best
Speaker 5:  games that, you know, the console makers have, or at least the most well-crafted
Speaker 5:  games that are pretty singular experiences with franchises. People love,
Speaker 5:  not it's a mouse,
Speaker 5:  right? And like Nintendo is very good at like weird interaction paradigms.
Speaker 5:  Like they, they did the entire we for, for God's sake. But like there's a
Speaker 5:  part of, you're gonna play Mario on the go and then there's another part
Speaker 5:  that's like, we're gonna talk about the C button a lot because that's the
Speaker 5:  video chat button. And that just seems like now we're
Speaker 5:  competing with phones and there's no reason to do that. Just to be
Speaker 5:  clear, by the way, the, the video calls are optional. You buy the optional
Speaker 5:  camera. If you just push the C button, it's, it's voice calls. But
Speaker 6:  I, it, it, this thing is very social in a way. I think It is really interesting
Speaker 6:  and like I I, I was going back and watching all the old first gen switch
Speaker 6:  ads and they're very much like people out in the world playing on this console
Speaker 6:  together. Like hand your buddy a JoyCon and you can like hang out on the
Speaker 6:  beach and play games. And this one is like you're in your living room but
Speaker 6:  you're still hanging out with your friends who are not in your living room.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, there's, there's just something that happened in the eight
Speaker 6:  years that is both like Nintendo's probably, right?
Speaker 7:  Well I think there is something that happened in the eight years between
Speaker 7:  the, the switch one and the switch two. It was called Covid. It was the whole
Speaker 6:  Thing. We all stopped going outside
Speaker 7:  And that was when they designed this system.
Speaker 6:  That's a really good point that if you, if you rewind to the beginning of
Speaker 6:  the, like what is the switch to meetings? It was probably a bunch of people
Speaker 6:  sitting on Zoom calls.
Speaker 5:  That's a, yeah, this is the first of the great covid hardware wave is like
Speaker 5:  super interesting. The mouse in particular gets me, is like,
Speaker 5:  here's this big interaction paradigm that requires you to have a desk.
Speaker 5:  Like how are you gonna use this mouse? You're gonna put it on a desk. Ash
Speaker 5:  was not a huge fan of this mouse. We'll see how it plays out.
Speaker 5:  It just seems like the switch is getting a little bit bigger, right? Like
Speaker 5:  it, the conceptually it's gonna do a little bit more stuff than it did the
Speaker 5:  last time, which is maybe good. Like that's the story of products and
Speaker 5:  that's how products had developed. But it, I feel like the switch was as
Speaker 5:  successful as it was because it was relatively inexpensive. It had Zelda
Speaker 5:  and Mario and all the rest of the, it had animal crossing and ultimately
Speaker 5:  it wasn't trying to do more than the things you needed it to do.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's what we're going to find out is whether this is the we
Speaker 7:  where it brought people together with kind of a new control dynamic that
Speaker 7:  the other video game systems weren't doing so much then, or if it's the we
Speaker 7:  you where it costs too much and the add-ons they put on it isn't
Speaker 7:  any, It is something that anyone wants.
Speaker 6:  Do you think there's a real risk that this is the we you, because I, I really
Speaker 6:  don't, like, I look at this and, and I'm like, this is, they're doing some
Speaker 6:  weird stuff, but fundamentally what everybody wanted from them is a better
Speaker 6:  switch. And it like, it really looks like this is a better switch. Do you
Speaker 6:  think there is actual, like this was a mistake possibility here?
Speaker 5:  It just depends on how much it costs. If this thing, if this thing breaks
Speaker 5:  $500 because of tariffs and big ways, right? If it's,
Speaker 5:  if it's, we announced what, 4 49, if it gets to 500 'cause of tariffs, everyone
Speaker 5:  like, oh, it sucks, you know, whatever. If it gets to $600
Speaker 5:  'cause of tariffs, it starts to get, that's pretty expensive,
Speaker 5:  right? And then you still gotta buy games and all this, all all these, you
Speaker 5:  gotta buy the camera, you gotta buy new, do all this other stuff is gonna
Speaker 5:  start happening that'll make it too expensive for where it should
Speaker 5:  live. And that then I think you have to decide how much you love
Speaker 5:  Mario.
Speaker 7:  It might not be the we, it probably isn't the we you, it might be the three
Speaker 7:  Ds.
Speaker 5:  No, that's all same one. I think it's gonna be, I think it's gonna be to
Speaker 5:  switch again. That's your, your prediction is three s or,
Speaker 7:  Or maybe maybe the two Ds. I don't, I don't know. I can't remember which
Speaker 7:  one.
Speaker 5:  Game Boy Pocket. It's always the side book Game Boy Pocket the Okay Game
Speaker 5:  Boy Pocket every time it comes on the show. I'll remind our high school listeners,
Speaker 5:  it fits perfectly into the slider case. But TI 82
Speaker 5:  calculator
Speaker 5:  something that I learned in 1998,
Speaker 6:  Every part of that reference will make no sense to people in high school.
Speaker 6:  Now. I love it.
Speaker 5:  No, they still sell. There's a store in our town in our little Westchester
Speaker 5:  town, the stationary store. Stationary store is just a
Speaker 5:  racket that sells ti calculators to high school students. That's its only
Speaker 5:  business.
Speaker 6:  Are they still like 150 bucks? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They still cost exactly the same. Unreal. And it's every
Speaker 5:  high schooler is required to buy one of these calculators and they all buy
Speaker 5:  'em at the stationary store. And I'm just there, you know, once a week being
Speaker 5:  like, you know, gameboard pocket slits, right? And
Speaker 6:  Can you imagine when tariffs make the TI 83 calculator, like
Speaker 6:  $245?
Speaker 5:  That's how you know that I'm old, is that I'm saying TI 82 and everyone else
Speaker 5:  has got the TI 83, which is slightly nicer. T 82 had a square
Speaker 5:  case, which covered the game Boy pocket better. Mm. The problem, and
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm sorry to my high school math teachers,
Speaker 5:  the problem is that when Ryan Ntel turned on
Speaker 5:  the game, boy it still dinged. And then your calculator
Speaker 5:  and Game Boy were taken away playing Dope
Speaker 7:  Wars wasn't good enough for you. You needed a game boy
Speaker 5:  Did you ever code you ever, did you ever, did you code your games right into
Speaker 5:  the calculator, Richard? Of course. Hell yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Come on. I did. I I dealt so much fake drugs on my
Speaker 6:  graphing calculator. Are you kidding me?
Speaker 5:  All right, speaking of dealing drugs, let's talk about TikTok.
Speaker 5:  The, the foremost scourge of our nation's youth. Lots going on,
Speaker 5:  on the TikTok story
Speaker 5:  This weekend is the deadline, Saturday is the deadline.
Speaker 5:  The deadline that was self-imposed by Donald Trump after the
Speaker 5:  actual deadline that was imposed by our nation's Congress and
Speaker 5:  upheld by the Supreme Court. So Trump takes office, TikTok was banned,
Speaker 5:  which means they just shut it, the shut the app down as a
Speaker 5:  stunt. Trump said, I'm giving you 75 days.
Speaker 5:  Here's a waiver from Pam Bondy, the Attorney General that says she won't
Speaker 5:  prosecute you for breaking this law.
Speaker 5:  Everyone said that was good enough, which is weird all unto itself totally
Speaker 5:  weird. But here we are at the end of 75 days, there's a rumor
Speaker 5:  that Trump is gonna do something called TikTok America
Speaker 5:  where he creates a sovereign wealth fund out of a stolen
Speaker 5:  Bitcoin as near as I can tell. And then
Speaker 5:  that will buy a huge chunk of TikTok by chance will remain
Speaker 5:  on the cap table, which might be illegal because the law says
Speaker 5:  they can't control the app or the algorithm. So I dunno what's gonna happen
Speaker 5:  there. The thing that I have been predicting would happen has
Speaker 5:  apparently happened, Amazon has sent a letter saying they would buy TikTok,
Speaker 5:  The Founder of OnlyFans Wants to Buy TikTok
Speaker 5:  Perplexity keeps insisting that It is a serious buyer for TikTok
Speaker 5:  in sending extremely petty notes to Kylie
Speaker 5:  whenever she notes that, that is doesn't seem realistic,
Speaker 5:  really? Yeah. They were like, no, we're for real. And
Speaker 5:  there's, there's just nothing. I'm sure you are can say to a Appstar AI company
Speaker 5:  that really wants you to believe it can buy TikTok. And then there's, you
Speaker 5:  know, project Liberty, which is Frank McCort and Alexis Hanian and Mr. Beast.
Speaker 5:  And they've got whatever idea about putting TikTok on the
Speaker 5:  blockchain.
Speaker 5:  Don't forget App Loving, oh, app Loving. And Steve Wynn somehow is
Speaker 5:  involved in that.
Speaker 5:  I'm sure Vergecast listeners are are aware of App Loving. I'm excited
Speaker 5:  for more people in America to wake up
Speaker 5:  and be told that a company called App Loving now owns TikTok.
Speaker 5:  It's a lot. That's a lot. What do you think is gonna happen?
Speaker 6:  Okay, here, here's where I land on this, which is nowhere. I think the,
Speaker 6:  the, the thing that I have come around to is, I think
Speaker 6:  It is true that there is the money out
Speaker 6:  there in the United States to buy TikTok in a way that
Speaker 6:  would satisfy everybody, right? Like I I I am increasingly
Speaker 6:  convinced that there are actually lots of people who could gin up the money
Speaker 6:  to make this happen relatively quickly. Like it's, it's every investor
Speaker 6:  wants to be part of this that's increasingly clear. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Jeff Bezos just has to sell a support boat. Not even the big boat. The,
Speaker 6:  The right. What I've learned by watching OpenAI is that like a hundred billion
Speaker 6:  dollars is not that hard to come by. Like you can just get it, you can have
Speaker 6:  a hundred billion dollars if you want a hundred billion dollars. So I think
Speaker 6:  that part, I actually am, I, I thought for a while it was gonna be
Speaker 6:  impossible that there was just nobody who was gonna be able to do it for
Speaker 6:  a mix of like financial and antitrust reasons. I no longer think that's the
Speaker 6:  case. And I think it's, it's pretty clear that the Trump
Speaker 6:  administration would happily just bend its antitrust rules for whoever
Speaker 6:  it blessed as the new owner of TikTok. There is still, still
Speaker 6:  to this moment, absolutely no evidence that Byan or
Speaker 6:  China is interested in their part of this deal.
Speaker 5:  Just nuts. Especially now that the tariffs have happened,
Speaker 6:  Right? If, if what you need is the blessing of the Chinese
Speaker 6:  government to do this,
Speaker 6:  why on earth does that seem more likely to happen now
Speaker 6:  than it did yesterday or, or three months ago
Speaker 6:  or a year ago or the first time Trump tried to do this? Like, I, if
Speaker 6:  anything, it seems to me the likelihood of this being possible
Speaker 6:  has gone down over time for that reason. And so I think,
Speaker 6:  I think by dance might be willing to call the administration's bluff
Speaker 6:  again and just shut down. And I like, if, if I had
Speaker 6:  to bet, I think it goes dark again.
Speaker 5:  Richard,
Speaker 7:  I think that the most important thing here is that we're having the wrong
Speaker 7:  discussion about TikTok or the wrong discussion about Bite Dance China, the
Speaker 7:  Trump administration. The discussion we need to have is that we should buy
Speaker 7:  TikTok.
Speaker 5:  This is
Speaker 7:  Number one.
Speaker 5:  Billion dollars is not hard to come by
Speaker 7:  Any of us will ever have in our lifetime. You see, everyone's putting in
Speaker 7:  bids for TikTok. Why haven't we, we we need to put in a bid for
Speaker 7:  TikTok. We could own TikTok. This is like, this is like a let's buy a
Speaker 7:  bar. It's, it's that conversation. 'cause we're getting to that late hour
Speaker 7:  and we're saying, you know what, we could just buy a bar.
Speaker 5:  I've had that conversation so many times in my life.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 5:  When I lived in, we're gonna start
Speaker 6:  A band, buy a bar and buy TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Okay? Having a band in a band, don't start a band. Don't do that.
Speaker 5:  You will come to a point in your life when you have played the metro in Chicago.
Speaker 5:  You reached all of your dreams and the only available next step is
Speaker 5:  to spend time in a van with the people in your band going
Speaker 5:  to midsize Midwestern cities. And you'd be like, nah, it was the wrong choice,
Speaker 5:  just saying. But at that same period of time in my life in Chicago,
Speaker 5:  we would walk by an empty bar, like on the corner
Speaker 5:  by my house, on our way home hammered. And we would be like, we
Speaker 5:  should, we should buy that bar, man. That could be the spot.
Speaker 7:  Buy the bar, buy TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Historically bad idea. Most of them go outta business. I I feel the same
Speaker 5:  is true about our bid for TikTok.
Speaker 6:  Richard,
Speaker 5:  I I'm actually curious why there are not more bidders, right? This is
Speaker 5:  a historically important asset in the American media
Speaker 5:  ecosystem. I'm, I'm honestly curious why we haven't seen
Speaker 5:  the New York Times or News Corporation or
Speaker 5:  whoever, Viacom outta nowhere, paramount
Speaker 5:  Plus is now TikTok, right? Like where, where is that
Speaker 5:  energy from the media conglomerates that all are desperate for
Speaker 5:  distribution? Where's Netflix? Like, this is all stuff that
Speaker 5:  would make sense for a bunch of these companies. I understand why Amazon
Speaker 5:  wants TikTok because TikTok shop represents
Speaker 5:  an entire marketing channel that connects to purchases that Amazon does
Speaker 5:  not have. Yep. That is a meaningful, I don't know if it's a competitor, but
Speaker 5:  it's, it's just a place where people go to find stuff to buy and then they,
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's definitely like a competitor.
Speaker 5:  And then they buy,
Speaker 6:  Amazon has been desperately trying to do TikTok for years now
Speaker 6:  and with, with essentially no success. And so like, instead if you just took
Speaker 6:  TikTok and just plugged in the Amazon logistics system behind it, it's
Speaker 6:  actually the cleanest fit of almost any of these things that
Speaker 6:  I think of. Like Amazon has the cloud services to make the infrastructure
Speaker 6:  work. It has the, the business angle, which is all the shopping stuff that
Speaker 6:  you just talked about. Like, it, it works. Amazon could buy TikTok and
Speaker 6:  the whole thing would make sense immediately in a way that it, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  much more, there's much more of sort of an underpants known thing
Speaker 6:  happening for a lot of these other companies. But I also think, I mean, the
Speaker 6:  answer to a, a lot of these questions is because Trump won't allow it to
Speaker 6:  happen. Happen, right? Like he, he is so at the center of all of this,
Speaker 5:  Well, I don't, I don't know if that's true. Trump wouldn't allow Netflix
Speaker 5:  to buy TikTok. You, you
Speaker 6:  Think Trump would allow the New York Times to buy TikTok
Speaker 5:  Who App Loving, which is just a mobile advertising company that everyone
Speaker 5:  has to say App Loving is like out here being like, we'll do it. Why not?
Speaker 5:  Like Perplexity is like, we'll do it. I like why, honestly,
Speaker 5:  why wouldn't Netflix? Which desperately needs a discovery
Speaker 5:  mechanism, right? They all do. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Why wouldn't, why aren't they in this mix? Why isn't Apple in this mix? Like,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's just interesting to see how many people must have kicked the tires,
Speaker 5:  right? They all have big m and a departments. They all have big, big business
Speaker 5:  development departments. It's funny to see how many people are like, no,
Speaker 5:  that's, that's too messy. Social media is too messy. But
Speaker 5:  you can see how any number of media organizations desperately
Speaker 5:  need distribution and they, they're just not in the game. And maybe
Speaker 5:  somebody called Jeff and Ka, it's too hard to find.
Speaker 5:  We, we just need to do Quibi again. Where's Kaz?
Speaker 5:  Where's our guy? By TikTok by the way, we should turn out turn the qui in
Speaker 5:  all fairness to Jerry Katz and per quid
Speaker 5:  not a sentence I thought I would ever say vertical micro
Speaker 5:  dramas are apparently very popular in other countries around the world. We
Speaker 5:  should do a story on that. It's their time.
Speaker 6:  If Quibi had been free, it would've worked. No,
Speaker 5:  Season two of Golden Arm is, is coming. I could feel it. Quibi feel it in
Speaker 5:  you always. That's my prediction. And that's, that's life.
Speaker 6:  Quibi was just
Speaker 5:  Early. I will point out, we, It
Speaker 6:  Is a take. I'll go to my grave
Speaker 5:  With we're having exactly the same conversation about who will buy TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Except now there are some bids, but we are having the exact same conversation
Speaker 5:  today as we did 75 days ago.
Speaker 5:  And the d the deadline is tomorrow as you're listening to this, on Friday,
Speaker 5:  the deadline is Saturday, it's the fifth.
Speaker 6:  And there's still absolutely no indication that it's for sale. Like
Speaker 6:  this is a bunch of people standing outside of a house being like, I'd like
Speaker 6:  to buy that house. And the person inside not selling the house.
Speaker 6:  This is not, you can't buy a thing that's not for sale and there's
Speaker 6:  no evidence at all that It is for sale. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean, again, and it's just funny 'cause the number of people who should
Speaker 5:  be beating down the door to buy this thing should be by all rights much
Speaker 5:  higher than it's
Speaker 6:  Yes. I do think, I mean we, we've seen this before, like when Disney kicked
Speaker 6:  the tires on Twitter. And I think, I think there are a lot of companies who
Speaker 6:  understand the, the mess that is social and
Speaker 6:  just are not set up to do it. Yeah. But like, yeah, but I get notes. Netflix
Speaker 6:  buys TikTok and immediately becomes a completely different kind of company.
Speaker 6:  Right. And I think it, it's not crazy to sign up for that, but it's not just
Speaker 6:  a thing you can do.
Speaker 5:  Right. But every single time we have some streaming executive on
Speaker 5:  decoder or some product person from one of these companies on decoder,
Speaker 5:  I get notes from product people around the industry. They're like,
Speaker 5:  you don't understand what they're all saying in every meeting at Disney at
Speaker 5:  Paramount Plus at Max's. Why can't we have a YouTube? Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  they're all staring at the, the thing that is going to kill them
Speaker 5:  down the line. Di like at Disney there are meetings are like, why don't we
Speaker 5:  have a YouTube at max? There are meetings are like, why don't we have a YouTube?
Speaker 5:  Because they see the thing and there are obvious reasons that they don't.
Speaker 5:  But in this one case, they could buy a thing that's almost like it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, it's, it's certainly the closest to just going
Speaker 6:  from nothing to something that has been available maybe ever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And yet yet,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 5:  Know it's gonna be App Love Everybody. No, no Shade App Love. And it's just
Speaker 5:  a very funny name. And I am dying for the TikTok conspiracy theories that
Speaker 5:  will occur if a company named App Loven buys this, buys this platform.
Speaker 6:  TikTok Buy App Loving has a really great retailer.
Speaker 5:  We'll find out either TikTok will exist next week when we do the show or
Speaker 5:  it won't, or Trump we're
Speaker 6:  Gonna buy it and it's just gonna be Detroit Pistons highlights and trucks
Speaker 6:  jumping over stuff. Steve,
Speaker 5:  Richard, and I'm here for it Ate. We're buying TikTok and it's, it's just
Speaker 5:  us forcing Richard to purchase and rehabilitate a bar.
Speaker 5:  Yep. That's it. Like, you've gotta find one. You've gotta, that's the
Speaker 5:  people want. You gotta do the TikTok thing, you know, like the the time-lapse
Speaker 5:  video of like tearing down the drywall and putting it back up.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna make Richard install gray floors in one of those like bronze
Speaker 5:  chandelier things. It is gonna be great. I'm excited for it. All right, we
Speaker 5:  gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. We're gonna start talking about
Speaker 5:  tariffs. It's gonna happen. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  We have to talk about Terra. We do. It is, I know
Speaker 5:  the only story, like in the biggest way, usually with
Speaker 5:  politics we have to draw some line to like phones.
Speaker 5:  You know, like, here's why The Verge is covering politics and I I want us
Speaker 5:  to cover politics. We, we do it, we cover policy very deeply. Like
Speaker 5:  usually you have to make an argument for politics and policy in our stories,
Speaker 5:  right? We, we cover consumer tech, Wes, a line to politics in
Speaker 5:  policy. And I want us to explain why we cover things like the
Speaker 5:  FCC or why we cover things like the National, national Institutes of Science.
Speaker 5:  Like there's, or the National Institutes of Health. Like there's research
Speaker 5:  that gets done at the federal level. There's policies at the Federal Trade
Speaker 5:  Commission. All this stuff affects the gadgets we make. Tariffs is much different
Speaker 5:  'cause the prices are just gonna go up and the supply chains that create
Speaker 5:  all the hardware is gonna go sideways. And there's not a great
Speaker 5:  argument for any of these tariffs right now. So Trump announced them.
Speaker 5:  The stock market literally crashed while he was speaking at the White House.
Speaker 5:  You just saw the numbers go down.
Speaker 5:  I, I watched CNBC today. I people, I know the anchors at
Speaker 5:  CNBC just openly confused Carl Quintin,
Speaker 5:  who's a great anchor at CNBC, A friend, he said, you're burning down the
Speaker 5:  house to cook a cheeseburger, which is an incredible quote. That is good.
Speaker 5:  Steve Mnuchin, who was treasury secretary Trump won, said
Speaker 5:  to Sarah Eisen, I believe, don't think too hard about how these tariff were
Speaker 5:  calculated.
Speaker 6:  I mean, that's the thing, like I think when you say there's not a great reason
Speaker 6:  for it, I think that is, that is actually like far too kind.
Speaker 6:  Like this is, this is pure nonsense and, and I think
Speaker 6:  it's nonsense what we have seen from the reaction. Like you
Speaker 6:  cannot find someone who can give you a measured reason
Speaker 6:  why this is a good idea. Right? You
Speaker 5:  Can find something, you can find chat GPT, which will Yes.
Speaker 5:  Which will deliver you the calculation that is used to calculate tariff rates.
Speaker 6:  Well, so, but that's the thing, right? And it's insanity all the way down
Speaker 6:  because it's like you, you rewind back through the campaign and,
Speaker 6:  and everybody was like, well, Trump clearly just doesn't understand how
Speaker 6:  tariffs actually work. It's just like a thing he likes to say. It's like
Speaker 6:  a hobby horse of his. He won't do them. And then immediately took office
Speaker 6:  and started doing them. And everybody was like, well, they won't be as bad
Speaker 6:  as he thought. And so over and over and over, the people who like
Speaker 6:  believed in him as an economic driver for the United States were like, he
Speaker 6:  won't do this. And then he did this and it was so much worse than
Speaker 6:  anyone anyone thought it was going to be. And then the more
Speaker 6:  we've learned about why It is the way that It is and how it was calculated
Speaker 6:  and how it was created and how it came to be, the more, the only
Speaker 6:  possible logic has become, none of this makes any sense. It
Speaker 5:  Is true that the United States Trade Representative put out a fact sheet
Speaker 5:  about the tariffs with a formula in it that was supposed
Speaker 5:  to explain how they calculated these tariff rates. And the formula contains
Speaker 5:  a bunch of Greek letters, two of which when you back at 'em out to the numbers,
Speaker 5:  just cancel each other out. What you have is a trade deficit divided in half
Speaker 5:  to calculate the rate. And then the floor is 10%. And the rates, the tariff
Speaker 5:  rates are against islands that have nothing but penguins on them.
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 6:  It's, it's so important to keep saying that's nothing, what you just described
Speaker 6:  is nothing.
Speaker 5:  Right? And they're described as reciprocal tariffs against countries. Adeno
Speaker 5:  tariffs on us. No, none of this makes any sense. Not,
Speaker 6:  These are not trade deficits, it's countries we buy things from.
Speaker 6:  Like that's, those are not the same thing. It's like, there there was, I
Speaker 6:  saw a thing this morning that was like, you don't have a trade deficit from
Speaker 6:  your dentist because your dentist doesn't buy anything from you. You buy
Speaker 6:  things from your dentist. Like, it's just nonsense. And
Speaker 6:  and we're at a point now where it's like we've gone way beyond
Speaker 6:  even like even now, the, the Trump administration being like, this is about
Speaker 6:  fentanyl crossing the borders, and this is how we punish the countries who
Speaker 6:  allow this to happen. That seems reasonable compared to where we are
Speaker 6:  now. Which is just, they went in and they were like, oh, well we have
Speaker 6:  a trade deficit with them. Let's tariff the opposite of that and that'll
Speaker 6:  sort it out. That's nothing.
Speaker 5:  So I wanna say there's been a lot of reporting, including from us,
Speaker 5:  that, that it's the ais that come up with this kind of math.
Speaker 5:  And It is true. Chacha PD comes up with this math. Claude comes up
Speaker 5:  with this math grok important one in the Trump administration because that's
Speaker 5:  Elon's comes up with this math. Gemini will come up with this math. But if
Speaker 5:  you switch to Gemini 2.5 Pro, which everyone got mad at us for
Speaker 5:  ignoring last week, but I it's now I'm using it. Y'all, y'all yell at us
Speaker 5:  and you ask it to show thinking on this prompt. It's basically like
Speaker 5:  the user's an idiot.
Speaker 5:  Like, like, it's like literally the second one analyze the
Speaker 5:  user's premise is the user assumes tariffs are a simple direct tool to
Speaker 5:  achieve balanced trade. And that a single calculation method can achieve
Speaker 5:  this across coun and countries. And then it just scrolls down and it gets
Speaker 5:  to a place that says address the easy way request. And it says,
Speaker 5:  given the complexity, there is no easy way to calculate tariffs that will
Speaker 5:  precisely bounce trade. The premise itself is flawed. So
Speaker 5:  look, I'm not saying that they used AI or not. I'm just saying maybe they
Speaker 5:  should have used Gemini 2.5 Pro, which would've gently let them down.
Speaker 6:  It's tough. I am, I'm generally suspicious of the, like they wrote this
Speaker 6:  official document with AI argument. I think like, people are dumb
Speaker 6:  is usually a more compelling outcome than the, like the, the Occam's razor
Speaker 6:  is people are stupid, not people use ai. This one is really,
Speaker 6:  really, it's not really hard to disagree. Like it, you put it in and
Speaker 6:  over and over people have run this experiment over and over again. You can
Speaker 6:  get it to give you that answer as long as you ask a stupid question, which
Speaker 5:  No human economist will give you that answer. No,
Speaker 6:  This is what I mean, like the reaction has been so universal that It is,
Speaker 6:  It is unreal.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow, look this is gonna affect the price of iPhones, it will affect the
Speaker 5:  price of The Nintendo Switch. Two, we, we have a piece, trying to guess how
Speaker 5:  much the price will go up in the switch. Two, it's a debacle of epic proportions
Speaker 5:  for the auto industry. That's a quote we ran in a story that Andy Hawkins
Speaker 5:  wrote. We're gonna track all this fallout across the board. There's a chance
Speaker 5:  that Trump just walks them all back. That's a thing that he does all the
Speaker 5:  time. Yeah, there's a chance that this is all just a, a weird
Speaker 5:  racket. We, we've been calling it gangster tech regulation. He just wants
Speaker 5:  people to deal. So he, he does this gangstery stuff.
Speaker 5:  We'll see how this shakes out, but I actually wanted to make this real for
Speaker 5:  our audience. I think you can go get a bunch of pie in the sky
Speaker 5:  tariff coverage everywhere, but we cover people who make things,
Speaker 5:  right. Not just big companies, but small companies. I, we love an
Speaker 5:  indie hardware maker here on the show. So you might've heard me talk about
Speaker 5:  a company called Tuneshine before, and the founder of Tuneshine is a guy
Speaker 5:  named Tobi Butler. I've read notes about tariffs from him on the show before
Speaker 5:  he's emailed me. I was like, I should write a
Speaker 5:  story about the Tuneshine and tariffs. And then all the s news happened and
Speaker 5:  I thought to myself, oh, we should just have Tobias on the show. So let's
Speaker 5:  bring 'em on Now. Tobias s Butler, you are the, the founder you the sole
Speaker 5:  proprietor of, of Tuneshine. Welcome to the Birch Cast. Thank you Eli.
Speaker 5:  Glad to be here. So as you, as Tobias knows, I have a Tuneshine. I love it.
Speaker 5:  Explain quickly what it's So Tuneshine is a
Speaker 9:  Lo-fi album art display that uses this kind of pixelated,
Speaker 9:  very tasteful, almost artistic screen to automatically show the album artwork
Speaker 9:  for the music you listen to. Works with Spotify, apple Music, and Sonos.
Speaker 9:  I definitely recommend, like, if you're listening to this on a podcast app,
Speaker 9:  checking out a picture of it. It's a very visual experience and often it'll
Speaker 9:  kind of click with people. But yeah, it's basically supposed to add this
Speaker 9:  nice ambient artwork to decorate your room and it connects with the kind
Speaker 9:  of music you like and help represent that visually in Your space.
Speaker 5:  So I started talking to Tobias because I demanded features and he, he delivered
Speaker 5:  them. So I will point out that he, you just added Shazam support
Speaker 5:  to the tune fund. So if you're listening, if I'm listening to vinyl at my
Speaker 5:  house, I can just push the button and the, the album mark shows up there.
Speaker 5:  It's a choice. I love this thing.
Speaker 9:  Cool. Really appreciate it. Surpris
Speaker 5:  You. It's just you, right? There's no one else in the company.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's just me. Increasingly, I'm kind of doing some things with,
Speaker 9:  with contractors. I've just recently
Speaker 9:  got set up with a contract manufacturer based in the US in Chicago
Speaker 9:  doing contracting with fulfillment companies to actually mail things out.
Speaker 9:  Which is great because that means that I don't have to be home every
Speaker 9:  weekday of every week and tune signs will still go out to people. But as
Speaker 9:  far as the product development, coding, marketing,
Speaker 9:  admin stuff, that is all me.
Speaker 5:  And there's a, a part of this story, which I am very taken by, which is you
Speaker 5:  worked at a tech company and you quit to start this company, right?
Speaker 9:  Yes. That's, that's basically correct. I, I quit kind of thinking, okay,
Speaker 9:  I have like a little bit of a nest egg enough to sort of
Speaker 9:  explore different options because I sort of thought, okay, It is a good time
Speaker 9:  in my life. I don't have kids yet. I, my budget is still pretty
Speaker 9:  flexible. Maybe I should just see if there's other things that I like
Speaker 9:  that aren't web development, which is basically what I was doing before.
Speaker 9:  And I basically discovered that I did want to continue to do coding, but
Speaker 9:  I really wanted to give Tuneshine a try. It was just giving me good
Speaker 9:  indications that it could be a business. Not only that I would be able to
Speaker 9:  start and had the skills enough to get pretty close, but also
Speaker 9:  that it was something that people were wanting. My friends were asking about
Speaker 9:  it and I love music. I'm a musician. I studied music
Speaker 9:  in school. So working on a music product just sort of made sense. So that's
Speaker 9:  why I decided to give it a go. This
Speaker 6:  Might be a really stupid question, but it is like before the now times
Speaker 6:  is, is when you go to start a business like this and you're like, okay, I'm
Speaker 6:  starting to source hardware. I, I kind of know the thing I wanna build. I
Speaker 6:  have to meet manufacturer. Do you have to become a tariffs expert anyway?
Speaker 6:  Like is that a thing that's on your mind as you're starting a company like
Speaker 6:  this?
Speaker 9:  I mean, prior to the first Trump
Speaker 9:  tariffs, which applied 25% tariff to a lot of
Speaker 9:  things. So I've always had tariffs on the, the circuit boards that
Speaker 9:  I was getting from China and the LED
Speaker 9:  screens, which I think are also in that classification or
Speaker 9:  at least among the classifications that get those things.
Speaker 9:  I mean, I think that yes, you are thinking about this,
Speaker 9:  however, if you are trying something out for the first time, especially
Speaker 9:  if it's your first time doing this as a hardware founder, there's gonna be
Speaker 9:  so many unknowns anyway that that is probably just gonna be one of many unknowns
Speaker 9:  that you encounter along the way. I think people who are maybe on their second
Speaker 9:  or third go are probably thinking a couple steps ahead on this, which of
Speaker 9:  course is much harder to do now that things are changing like twice a week.
Speaker 9:  But, so that's, it's it's a mixed answer.
Speaker 5:  I may ask you just a really reductive question 'cause I, I, I have the product
Speaker 5:  and I like it and I I see that it's like thoughtfully created,
Speaker 5:  but at a very abstract level it's a circuit board, a
Speaker 5:  microcontrollers, some wifi chips and a display. And then I,
Speaker 5:  I think you make the case, I actually discovered this product 'cause there's
Speaker 5:  videos of you on TikTok making the cases. And I was like, well that's cool.
Speaker 5:  I'm assuming that the wood for the cases is not tariffed yet, but it
Speaker 5:  might be soon. We'll find out.
Speaker 9:  So I, for a long time I was doing the assembly
Speaker 9:  myself, but I don't have a CNC machine to actually carve the case outta the
Speaker 9:  material. I am gonna continue to, there's gonna be some special additions,
Speaker 9:  limited runs and I will continue to assemble those at home just 'cause I
Speaker 9:  think it's very, I, I like having that physical connection to the product
Speaker 9:  and while I can't scale up enough to do all of these things, I think
Speaker 9:  people really like knowing that they bought something that was,
Speaker 9:  you know, not artisanal. I'm, I'm really just screwing it together. But they
Speaker 9:  like having that connection. Right?
Speaker 5:  But those parts, right, wifi chip controller, circuit
Speaker 5:  board display, all of that was coming from China before,
Speaker 5:  right? Yes. You weren't getting that domestically. Yeah. And so you're paying
Speaker 5:  some rate and the rate might have gone up because of Trump won tariffs, but
Speaker 5:  you could basically go to suppliers and say, I wanna buy this stuff and get
Speaker 5:  prices back.
Speaker 9:  Yes. Yes. And the easiest way to do that is to get
Speaker 9:  an Alibaba. People are super responsive. I, you know, you, you hear
Speaker 9:  this Simone y the, the robot
Speaker 9:  creator was talking about this recently where you reach out to a bunch of
Speaker 9:  manufacturers in the US and Europe and your response rate is really low.
Speaker 9:  I think some of that is just because they are
Speaker 9:  not as optimized for small clients. I think some of that
Speaker 9:  is just a company culture thing that's pervasive here.
Speaker 9:  But if you go on Alibaba, you're able to find these manufacturers,
Speaker 9:  buy from them, get samples and everything's consolidated into a single app.
Speaker 9:  It's sort of a weird janky app and they're a little bit iffy with their push
Speaker 9:  notification policies. But you can talk to everybody in the same
Speaker 9:  app and it makes the whole thing very streamlined.
Speaker 5:  So I emailed you when the first round of tariffs and
Speaker 5:  this Trump administration was happening. You said, my presses will go up
Speaker 5:  and down. I'm not sure what's gonna happen. Now we're here in the second
Speaker 5:  round. Who knows what's gonna happen, what's gonna happen to
Speaker 5:  Tuneshine? Are your prices gonna go up? Is the company still sustainable?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so I was kind of, before I was fell asleep last
Speaker 9:  night, you know, I'm, I'm doom scrolling a little bit and I'm just like,
Speaker 9:  oh no, like maybe I am, I am gonna have to raise prices.
Speaker 9:  And when I double checked my numbers this morning, 'cause I just put out
Speaker 9:  a video talking through the effects, I think it might have, it
Speaker 9:  looked like what actually came out to was basically a
Speaker 9:  10% increase in the price of each manufactured Tuneshine and
Speaker 9:  the reali. And the reason it's not the full like 54%
Speaker 9:  increase that is going to be applied is the tariffs from China
Speaker 9:  is for a few reasons. One is that some of this stuff was already tariffed.
Speaker 9:  In fact, much of this stuff was already tariffed. So the increase
Speaker 9:  is more like 25 ish percent, not the full 54.
Speaker 9:  The other thing is that the labor cost, like the, you know, the
Speaker 9:  most expensive parts of the Tuneshine are
Speaker 9:  screen circuit board and labor. At the moment, the way I'm manufacturing
Speaker 9:  it, labor cost is not tariffed 'cause that's done in the us So
Speaker 9:  that is not included in the how the tariff multiplier would work.
Speaker 9:  And the third thing is that I actually did recently meet someone who might
Speaker 9:  be able to move some of the parts into their, their spot in Wisconsin
Speaker 9:  with very competitive prices. So I'm getting samples there.
Speaker 9:  I think that's pretty unusual. I was kind of amazed, like there's a lot,
Speaker 9:  not a lot of PCB manufacturers in the US people talk about how, I
Speaker 9:  think like star link's, SpaceX stuff is like one
Speaker 9:  of the biggest PCB facilities. But in terms of just quick low volume
Speaker 9:  and by low volume, I mean like a thousand to 3000 ish
Speaker 9:  manufacturing for PCBs is not very common. But this guy has given it
Speaker 9:  a go and
Speaker 9:  I thought that was exciting that I might be able to beat that. So all of
Speaker 9:  that together amounts to a smaller increase than you might think based on
Speaker 9:  the 54%, but it's still an increase and I'm making orders of a thousand.
Speaker 9:  And so if it costs 10% more, that's like
Speaker 9:  thousands of less dollars in in profit for me, for each batch of Tuneshine
Speaker 9:  that's coming in. And I, all the
Speaker 9:  indications are that it could still be profitable, but
Speaker 9:  since I've been scaling up in each order of products that I
Speaker 9:  make is bigger than the last and it eats into the profits I've already made.
Speaker 9:  And because I had legal costs associated with filing a patent,
Speaker 9:  then
Speaker 9:  I don't know for sure yet. But it looks like it should still be okay. And
Speaker 9:  especially if I can get a little bit more efficient at marketing, which is
Speaker 9:  my second biggest cost after manufacturing, then I could potentially make
Speaker 9:  up for that. So if I'm getting more organic social reach or if I'm doing
Speaker 9:  better pr, then that helps 'cause I'm less reliant on paid
Speaker 9:  marketing channels. So that's kind of how I've been thinking about it.
Speaker 6:  It seems like part of the challenge here is, is the not knowing of it
Speaker 6:  all that like we is even just in the last two months we've, we've gone back
Speaker 6:  and forth so many times and, and like you talk about ordering these parts
Speaker 6:  and like, it, it's not like this is a thing you can do on a sort of day by
Speaker 6:  day basis depending on the the state of the economics of it all right? You're
Speaker 6:  having to make sort of months long decisions at a time, right?
Speaker 6:  Like how do you even do that in a moment like this where everything is up
Speaker 6:  and down from like 15 minutes to 15 minutes?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I mean the uncertainty is definitely a huge factor. And I think
Speaker 9:  my reading It is that a lot of the stuff
Speaker 9:  that's happening with the stock market is related to uncertainty as much
Speaker 9:  as anything else because we just don't know what's going to happen. For me,
Speaker 9:  there are some funny day-to-day things like if I'm getting parts shipped
Speaker 9:  like over the ocean for example, the delivery times can be very
Speaker 9:  unpredictable, but often this is a much cheaper alternative. So
Speaker 9:  I literally had a package that I think like got delivered yesterday
Speaker 9:  and I don't know if the timing perfectly works out, but the tariffs did seem
Speaker 9:  a little high. So I was like, darn. Like if it had just arrived one day
Speaker 9:  earlier, I could have saved like 400 bucks. But
Speaker 9:  what I think about really, like I, I can sort of plan this
Speaker 9:  stuff out, but as I was saying, when you start this stuff, there's so much
Speaker 9:  uncertainty. And I think about the people who are starting Kickstarters
Speaker 9:  and they're trying to make their best guess at
Speaker 9:  whether they have a viable business model because there's kind of a epidemic,
Speaker 9:  I'm sure you've noticed, of people who like raise a bunch of money on Kickstarter
Speaker 9:  and then ultimately realize like, oh, this business doesn't actually work
Speaker 9:  though. And so products lose support. I think there's a much greater risk
Speaker 9:  of that now because you have less certainty about how much money you wanna
Speaker 9:  raise on top of all the uncertainty you already had. Your prices might go
Speaker 9:  up, you, I think it just adds another factor on
Speaker 9:  top of all the other risks starting a business that might make people
Speaker 9:  think twice about whether they want to turn their little
Speaker 9:  home-built DIY or do we know or raspberry pie gadget into a real
Speaker 9:  product, which is a bummer because I would love to see more diversity in
Speaker 9:  hardware, more power to like smaller hardware players to
Speaker 9:  experiment with all these ideas that are out there that aren't really
Speaker 9:  seen as much in a very homogeneous hardware market. That
Speaker 5:  Seems like the important part, right? That you are living a, a
Speaker 5:  version of the American dream where you had a job, you said, I have an opportunity
Speaker 5:  to start a company, I can open the Alibaba app
Speaker 5:  and connect with a bunch of suppliers halfway around the world and
Speaker 5:  start a business and now there's a regulatory environment that might make
Speaker 5:  that surprisingly harder. Do you think you would've started
Speaker 5:  Tuneshine right now with the tariff uncertainty?
Speaker 9:  It's hard to say. I might've tried
Speaker 9:  to price it differently. The way my initial strategy was, was working with
Speaker 9:  the pricing is that I would read things online that
Speaker 9:  were basically saying take the price of your materials and multiply that
Speaker 9:  by four and that's what you should sell it for. I am not doing that,
Speaker 9:  which has interesting side effects where I basically am very resistant to
Speaker 9:  selling in retail environments because they
Speaker 9:  immediately want to buy your product wholesale for half of the sticker price.
Speaker 9:  And for me, that basically puts me underwater and I can sell direct to
Speaker 9:  consumer better than that anyway. But when I was first making these, I
Speaker 9:  kind of had that attitude of like, well, more likely than not,
Speaker 9:  if these sell, I can get the price down some way. I can
Speaker 9:  take the time. Once I know that people will buy them for the price that I've
Speaker 9:  set it at, then I can, maybe I can scale up, maybe I can find a different
Speaker 9:  supplier, I can get better at this and that. So I,
Speaker 9:  oh, through that process, I already brought the price down a lot.
Speaker 9:  It's going back up now, but I honestly,
Speaker 9:  like since I came from the software world, I'm not so certain that I would've
Speaker 9:  had the, the foresight anyway to be able to
Speaker 9:  incorporate this into the overall calculations. I was just sort of thinking,
Speaker 9:  all right, I'm gonna start small, I'm gonna sell 50, then I'm gonna sell
Speaker 9:  100 and then 200 500,000 price comes
Speaker 9:  down a little bit each time and we're getting more and more into healthy
Speaker 9:  business territory where I can look ahead in the next year and be like, yeah,
Speaker 9:  this is probably gonna work. But as I said before,
Speaker 9:  there's so much uncertainty with these things. Having another thing thrown
Speaker 9:  into the mix does not, I think make it more likely that people will
Speaker 9:  try experiments like this. Why
Speaker 6:  Not just throw it in and raise the price? I mean, I think we're gonna see
Speaker 6:  a lot of people who are just like, ah, tariffs, everything's more expensive.
Speaker 6:  Why not do that?
Speaker 9:  It's a good question. I think.
Speaker 9:  I think part of It is just the fact that I'm somewhat new to this and
Speaker 9:  I am, I think I may be a little bit more nervous than many people would be
Speaker 9:  about my customer's loyalty. I thought about that when I was
Speaker 9:  switching to manufacturing outside the house and I did get people who emailed
Speaker 9:  me who were saying, oh, this is a bummer. Do you actually have any that you
Speaker 9:  still made with your own hands that I can get? Like I, like literally somebody
Speaker 9:  asked me to like sign one, which was funny, but, and send it out to him.
Speaker 9:  So I, I do stress a little bit about customer loyalty.
Speaker 9:  I think I've done a pretty good job of building that, but by just trying
Speaker 9:  to be really transparent, talking about how this process works, trying to
Speaker 9:  be like the opposite of whatever corporate sheen you usually get from
Speaker 9:  marketing communications. So maybe I've built up an up goodwill where people
Speaker 9:  would say, hey, like, yeah, this is still fine. On the
Speaker 9:  other hand, I get some repeat customers, but not a ton. And
Speaker 9:  so those people I wouldn't necessarily have built up that loyalty to.
Speaker 9:  So I mean, coming from a big, I used to work@change.org
Speaker 9:  where we would just ab test everything. It's a little harder to ab test a
Speaker 9:  price. I kind of wish I could do that even though it's maybe a little ethically
Speaker 9:  questionable, but I, at least for
Speaker 9:  now, I wanna try it out. I think that 200 as a starting price,
Speaker 9:  it's already a somewhat expensive gadget. It's a very niche thing. I'm not
Speaker 9:  pretending this is like a toaster or a microwave oven or anything. It's,
Speaker 9:  it's a art art piece basically that you can get from your home or not.
Speaker 9:  200 is I think a, a pretty fair price, but it is a
Speaker 9:  bit high. And so I wanna keep it there and
Speaker 9:  hope that it works out. Basically.
Speaker 5:  I think I bought a walnut one that you actually did make by yourself. You
Speaker 5:  said two things that are really interesting to me. One, you
Speaker 5:  said American, European manufacturers kind of don't respond, they're just
Speaker 5:  like not in the game the way that the Chinese supply chain is just in the
Speaker 5:  game all the time. And then you said there's a guy in Wisconsin who might
Speaker 5:  be in the game. Now the point of the tariffs is to get you to move
Speaker 5:  your production to Wisconsin, right? The point of the tariffs is to get more
Speaker 5:  of the supply chain in the United States. Do you see that happening,
Speaker 5:  right? I mean you obviously have at least one person in Wisconsin who wants
Speaker 5:  to help you out. Do you see more of that? Is that ecosystem actually developing?
Speaker 5:  I,
Speaker 9:  My experience with this is somewhat limited, but the,
Speaker 9:  as you said, the the Chinese supply chain is just so well set up for this
Speaker 9:  stuff. There is absolutely no American answer
Speaker 9:  for Alibaba and just how easy it makes the overall process.
Speaker 9:  Maybe there are individual suppliers out there that
Speaker 9:  can compete on price, especially with the tariffs and maybe they do
Speaker 9:  respond, but having everything so streamlined,
Speaker 9:  it feels like you're kind of going back to the previous century when
Speaker 9:  you are trying to do things with the American, American manufacturers. It's
Speaker 9:  not outta the question that maybe someone's out there trying to build the
Speaker 9:  American Alibaba. That would be awesome. Like if, if, if
Speaker 9:  someone's out there and feels that spark, you have my full encouragement.
Speaker 9:  But there's a lot of stuff that's also just not made here. I mean the
Speaker 9:  ESP 32 microcontroller that I use, it's just a, it's a Chinese
Speaker 9:  company. Like
Speaker 9:  May, you know, maybe something using the TSMC factory in Arizona or
Speaker 9:  wherever that is, is, is gonna come up and make a competitor to that. But
Speaker 9:  how long does that take? How long does it take to build the ecosystem of
Speaker 9:  libraries that support this operating system and, and all of this
Speaker 9:  stuff. I think some people make these LED screens in the us
Speaker 9:  they don't have pricing on their website. It's a, you know, it's one of a
Speaker 9:  contact us for sales sort of deals.
Speaker 9:  But it's, it's lots, lots of obstacles because
Speaker 9:  they just really have a system for this that's
Speaker 9:  modern in, in a way that we do not.
Speaker 5:  How long do you think it would take to, to build that system here? I
Speaker 9:  Don't know that I would say that's outta my wheelhouse, but certainly,
Speaker 9:  almost certainly longer than a single presidential term for, for one.
Speaker 5:  I ask that question because I think that's the answer. Go ahead dude.
Speaker 6:  Well I was gonna say the Alibaba of it all I think is really fascinating
Speaker 6:  and is is a piece of this that I think is not getting talked about a lot.
Speaker 6:  That It is that this, It is just so much easier and
Speaker 6:  faster and more straightforward to do the kind of stuff you're talking about
Speaker 6:  on Alibaba and in China than just about anywhere else. So I, I
Speaker 6:  am curious like where that puts you sort of
Speaker 6:  long term, like let's assume the, the tariffs are real. It feels to me like
Speaker 6:  you have a couple of options. One is like tr hope everybody
Speaker 6:  moves part production to the US one is like find new parts
Speaker 6:  that they make in the us or two is just to figure out how to incorporate
Speaker 6:  the costs. Is the answer one of those? Is it some mixture of those?
Speaker 9:  I think it will be a mixture. I mean I ultimately, the, the PCB
Speaker 9:  people in Wisconsin, I didn't switch to them because I was like, I'm gonna
Speaker 9:  buy American made, but more because I, I think the contract
Speaker 9:  manufacturer I was using, I think they were getting PCPs made in India and
Speaker 9:  I actually didn't check how much the terrorists were going up on India, but
Speaker 9:  I think they were 10%. But still I switched because they were able to be
Speaker 9:  the cost w when they incorporated shipping and when they incorporated
Speaker 9:  that tariff, they were able to beat the cost. They were also able to make
Speaker 9:  a 3D printed part and they were down to bundle it together. They were even
Speaker 9:  down to do some electronics engineering for free
Speaker 9:  to throw that in, which is huge. 'cause you know, for these
Speaker 9:  500,000 here, that really adds up at, at the point that I'm doing this business.
Speaker 9:  So I think it'll be a mix and maybe I, I just kind of put a call out on my
Speaker 9:  Instagram and TikTok where I was saying, Hey, if you know people in the US
Speaker 9:  who might be able to do this, like sure I'm open to it, but I haven't seen
Speaker 9:  that. I mean I used to be getting cardboard boxes
Speaker 9:  with foam that just protected during shipping
Speaker 9:  price in the US $18, China four.
Speaker 9:  Wow. Like, so that's, that's 350% more. I would be
Speaker 9:  a bit surprised, but it doesn't mean it's not out there.
Speaker 9:  The other thing is that I just, by the nature of my business, I think I do
Speaker 9:  have a little bit more flexibility. I don't have people on
Speaker 9:  payroll yet. I'm not even on payroll yet, hopefully, hopefully this year.
Speaker 9:  But I don't have people on payroll. I like if you're Apple
Speaker 9:  and they'll probably maybe be able to get some exemptions. But like this,
Speaker 9:  you know, if It is a 10% or 20% increase in your, the price
Speaker 9:  for your items,
Speaker 9:  that is like billions of dollars. That's, it represents
Speaker 9:  tons, tons of people's jobs and, and entire big
Speaker 9:  corporate strategy Ocean liner that needs to be turned.
Speaker 9:  Whereas for me, I do, I do have a bit more flexibility because It is just
Speaker 9:  me. And so I don't have to fire people because of a
Speaker 9:  10% price increase, which is great. Maybe it means that I'm
Speaker 9:  skipping on the, the fancy four pack of beer and instead drinking Pacifico
Speaker 9:  a little more. But the, it's it's more flexibility. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook switching to Pacifico is actually the most obvious.
Speaker 5:  Just put
Speaker 9:  This first thought,
Speaker 5:  Put this in a range for me, right? There's Terrace went up and
Speaker 5:  maybe your costs go up 10% and you're drinking sadly some cheaper beer
Speaker 5:  and that's fine. And then what's the number that says this is no longer
Speaker 5:  sustainable?
Speaker 9:  I mean, if, if my manufactured cost
Speaker 9:  went over a hundred dollars, that's sorta, that's kind of
Speaker 9:  game over. I mean it's certainly without raising the price, I don't know.
Speaker 9:  Maybe there is a market like maybe, you know, maybe in a couple months people
Speaker 9:  will be be like, well like my TV was like
Speaker 9:  $900 and it used to be 400. So a Tuneshine for two 50
Speaker 9:  doesn't actually seem so crazy. But for if it
Speaker 9:  were over a hundred dollars, I I would be very surprised if people would
Speaker 9:  be able to pay what would make sense
Speaker 9:  to, to make that sustainable. Certainly with retail, 'cause I, if
Speaker 9:  I kept it at 200 and I'm paying a hundred, I literally would make zero on
Speaker 9:  each retail sale unless I get like a good deal. I, I'm only in one store
Speaker 9:  right now and she's sort of a friend of a friend and she gives me a little
Speaker 9:  bit more than 50% of the cost. But like if I'm aiming to be in
Speaker 9:  Urban Outfitters someday, I don't think they're gonna cut me a good deal
Speaker 9:  and that suddenly goes like off the table. I think if, if my manufacturing
Speaker 9:  costs go over a hundred dollars
Speaker 5:  Twice, what do you think is next? Fortrend, what are you looking at for
Speaker 9:  I'm really going for consistency this year. I just placed an order for a
Speaker 9:  thousand, which is my biggest order yet. And now that
Speaker 9:  the manufacturing and the fulfillment is outta my house, I'm just trying
Speaker 9:  to get that running on a kind of clockwork basis while I can add new features.
Speaker 9:  So I really wanna support more home music servers this year.
Speaker 9:  Plex run like Logitech Media server.
Speaker 9:  People are always emailing me more and more bespoke media servers. I wanna,
Speaker 9:  I wanna support as many of those as I can.
Speaker 9:  Trying a special edition, maybe some colors just got some samples
Speaker 9:  in and maybe a big one, maybe a vinyl record
Speaker 9:  sized one. So that's, that's, those are the things that are on my mind
Speaker 9:  right now. As soon as
Speaker 6:  You said ro a bunch of Vergecast listeners started like fist pumping at their
Speaker 6:  phones.
Speaker 5:  The Thero and plus audience, here're on The Verge Cha is strong fans. I'm
Speaker 5:  very excited
Speaker 9:  Fans, I see you run fans
Speaker 5:  Well when you make the big one, let me know. Built in microphone for the
Speaker 5:  Shazam. That's the, that's the
Speaker 9:  Game. That's that, that's sort of
Speaker 5:  $5,000 Tuneshine with an AI microphone in It is
Speaker 9:  What I'm looking for. Yeah, it's got, it's got like eight mics so that it
Speaker 9:  knows which direction the music comes from for some reason. Why not?
Speaker 5:  I love it. Tobias, thank you so much for joining the Bird Cast.
Speaker 9:  Thank you. Really appreciate it. Bye.
Speaker 5:  All right, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back lightning round and
Speaker 5:  America's favorite podcast for the podcast. We'll right back
Speaker 5:  Alright, we're back. It's a lightning round unsponsored
Speaker 5:  for flavor.
Speaker 6:  Does it need an ellipsis? There's been some debate about whether it's
Speaker 6:  unsponsored.dot for flavor or if it's just
Speaker 6:  unsponsored for flavor.
Speaker 5:  So I don't know. You, you tell me. Yeah, I will tell you that we,
Speaker 5:  the decoder tagline, which is big ideas and other problems
Speaker 5:  is impossible to say tagline. Like, it looks really good
Speaker 5:  with that built-in ellipsis, right? Big ideas. And then every
Speaker 5:  week I say it, I'm like, this sucks. So I
Speaker 5:  might just be having like, it's hard to say, you try saying it.
Speaker 5:  So I might just be having a response to that ellipsis.
Speaker 5:  Like, I think the, the pregnant pause is like good, right?
Speaker 5:  It's unsponsored for what flavor. Like that makes sense to me. But I don't
Speaker 5:  know that you wanna formally you tell me
Speaker 6:  Maybe it's like big unsponsored little for
Speaker 6:  flavor that maybe that that's kind of, that's the vibe.
Speaker 5:  We, again, the reason I keep saying It is to cement in the listener's
Speaker 5:  mind the idea that if something is sponsored, it lacks flavor,
Speaker 5:  which is the entire media now is just branded content deals,
Speaker 5:  right? It's just everything is sponsored or paid for. And I
Speaker 5:  just want you to think every time you think, see that you just think they,
Speaker 5:  there's less flavor here.
Speaker 6:  It's good. It's also a way to make sure that this show never makes any money
Speaker 6:  ever again. So we we're doing great,
Speaker 5:  But we don't lack for flavor.
Speaker 5:  David Richard just sighing. He is
Speaker 5:  like, what have I signed up for?
Speaker 5:  All right, it's time.
Speaker 6:  Oh my goodness. Richard, have you, have you been here for this yet? America's
Speaker 6:  it's a top two podcast within, within a podcast. Again, I keep getting emails
Speaker 6:  about Munch Squad on my brother, my brother and me and I, and trust me, I
Speaker 6:  hear you. I love it too. But it's time for America's other favorite
Speaker 6:  podcast. In their podcast. Brendan Carr is a dummy.
Speaker 6:  We're so bad. It is my first
Speaker 5:  One.
Speaker 6:  It's honestly, I'm thrilled for you. And this is the part where we just sort
Speaker 6:  of sit quietly and Neli talks for like an hour and a half. It's great. It's
Speaker 6:  my favorite brother. The show.
Speaker 5:  People have asked me if I, I write these and the answer is no. I just start
Speaker 5:  yelling. And that's, that's how much it builds up with me within me
Speaker 5:  week after week. Alright, this week on Brendan Carr is a dummy. Two things.
Speaker 5:  One last week we pointed out that he's threatening all kinds of companies
Speaker 5:  that he will investigate them and not let them do deals unless they cancel
Speaker 5:  their DEI programs because he just
Speaker 5:  likes making threats. And so this week T-Mobile closed a deal with a
Speaker 5:  fiber company called Lumos. They're doing a joint venture roll at fiber,
Speaker 5:  but only after it dropped all of its DEI
Speaker 5:  pages. This is the dumbest story in the world. T-Mobile had
Speaker 5:  a bunch of pages up that outlined quote, a culture of fairness, respect,
Speaker 5:  and inclusion. They were online until March 26th. They took 'em down,
Speaker 5:  deal got approved,
Speaker 5:  bing, bang, boom, we're we're close.
Speaker 7:  And, and because this is the current world in Mrs. Printed car, the
Speaker 7:  pages, they changed the pages. They don't say
Speaker 7:  DEI anymore. They're the URL that said D Diversity
Speaker 7:  gone. Many of the groups that were listed that championed
Speaker 7:  diversity gone, but they're just kind of different pages.
Speaker 7:  They just moved them good enough for bridging car.
Speaker 6:  They say stronger together now instead of diversity and inclusion,
Speaker 6:  which literally all that does is it doesn't get caught in
Speaker 6:  whatever scraper the AI tool is doing on their website. Like what we've learned
Speaker 6:  about Doge is that Doge is just like running a bunch of, of
Speaker 6:  AI checks to see, like when they use words like probation and
Speaker 6:  diversity and like trans anything,
Speaker 6:  and th this is the same kind of thing. They're like, oh, we're just gonna
Speaker 6:  4 0 4 a couple of webpage, we're gonna don't, don't look over here at these
Speaker 6:  webpage, which are different because they say
Speaker 6:  together and not inclusion. So it's fine. This is
Speaker 6:  the level of stupidity we have reached to. And apparently it worked for Brenda
Speaker 6:  and Carr
Speaker 7:  Segment
Speaker 5:  Called Car Dny. I wanna be very clear about this David. And
Speaker 6:  It works. That's the worst part. That that's all he, that's all Brenda and
Speaker 6:  Carr wanted.
Speaker 5:  It's true. The trans continental railroad is woke now that's, that's what
Speaker 5:  you need to take away from this. You know I'm right. You know, that's how
Speaker 5:  it's going. So that's one that happened, right? And that's just naked
Speaker 5:  corruption of the, the dumbest kind. Like there's,
Speaker 5:  they're just stupid. But it worked. And that's just the nature of corruption.
Speaker 5:  And am I saying that telecom companies aren't inherently kind of stupid
Speaker 5:  and corrupt? I'm not saying that I believe telecom companies are inherently
Speaker 5:  kind of stupid and corrupt. And whether it's promising
Speaker 5:  the chairman of the FCC that upon leaving, he will get a plumb job as
Speaker 5:  president of the lobbying organization for our nation's wireless carriers.
Speaker 5:  Which is a real thing that it just recently happened to a G Pi or saying
Speaker 5:  we're gonna remove the word diversity and replace it with the words stronger
Speaker 5:  together. It's all just corruption and that's fine, stupid,
Speaker 5:  a little bit racist, but the sort of corruption we're, we're used to. Then
Speaker 5:  there's Brendan just saying things that are demonstrably
Speaker 5:  untrue in ways that are quite honestly easy to check. So this
Speaker 5:  week the Democrats on the Energy and Commerce Committee in the House of Representatives
Speaker 5:  said they were very concerned about Brendan's general sensor
Speaker 5:  attitude and they wanted an investigation. So ranking member Frank
Speaker 5:  Palone from New Jersey ranking member Doris Matsui from
Speaker 5:  California and Yvette Clark from New York wrote a letter
Speaker 5:  to Brendan saying, we write to express deep concern over your actions to
Speaker 5:  target and intimidate news organizations and broadcasters in violation of
Speaker 5:  the First Amendment. These troubling actions assault the
Speaker 5:  constitutionally protected freedom of the press and violate the FCC statutory
Speaker 5:  prohibition against engaging in censorship. Directing FCC staff to devote
Speaker 5:  time and resources to bogus investigations constitutes a violation of the
Speaker 5:  law. Gross mismanagement, extreme waste of funds, and an abuse of
Speaker 5:  authority.
Speaker 6:  I just wanna point out that this, that's what it sounds like when you write
Speaker 6:  it Neli is what it sounds like when you just yell at into a microphone. I'm
Speaker 6:  very mad at that. It's the same thing. They're just saying the same stuff
Speaker 6:  you've been saying.
Speaker 5:  It's all, it's the same thing. It's all the same stuff. So they shared a
Speaker 5:  letter at the Office of Inspector General and they are asking for an investigation
Speaker 5:  into Brendan, okay, branch the, the
Speaker 5:  re's fighting. Brendan is furious about this Oliver
Speaker 5:  Darcy at Status who is doing an amazing job reporting on Brendan Carr, I
Speaker 5:  should say, and often gets comments back from Brendan, which is
Speaker 5:  fascinating, asked Brendan about this. And Carr in response
Speaker 5:  accused the Democrats of weaponizing the country's
Speaker 5:  communications laws against Republicans, which is wild
Speaker 5:  because he is the one being accused of weaponizing the communications laws.
Speaker 5:  And in response he's saying, even asking you about this and saying, I'm injuring
Speaker 5:  the First amendment is weaponizing those laws. And then he points out in
Speaker 5:  classic Brendan car fashion and then he claims in classic
Speaker 5:  Brendan car fashion that everything he's doing is fine. 'cause he thinks
Speaker 5:  the Democrats who proceeded him were doing it worse. So he says, if your
Speaker 5:  last name was Soros, you got special streamlined treatment on an
Speaker 5:  expedited basis by the previous FCC. If your last name was Musk,
Speaker 5:  then you got millions of dollars worth of awards revoked for partisan
Speaker 5:  political reasons. If you were a conservative outlet, then your FEC
Speaker 5:  licenses and distribution deals were held up or subject to government backed
Speaker 5:  cancel campaigns. This is what, this is demonstrably untrue, like
Speaker 5:  fully and completely untrue because one,
Speaker 5:  if the, if your complaint is that the previous administration was corrupt
Speaker 5:  and politically motivated and biased unfair, that does not mean that you
Speaker 5:  should do it too. It just doesn't, it means you should be better. It's actually
Speaker 6:  An admission of guilt. It's says I
Speaker 5:  Too am corrupt. You're saying these people were evil so I'm gonna do the
Speaker 5:  same stuff. Yeah, that's bad, right? That that just makes you a fluky of
Speaker 5:  a different stripe, but you're still a fluky second,
Speaker 5:  the, if your last name was Musk and your licenses got revoked,
Speaker 5:  that's because starlink was trying to defraud the government into getting
Speaker 5:  grants by saying it would provide service to like shopping malls.
Speaker 5:  Like they were, they were making fake maps. You can read, it's on our site.
Speaker 5:  We covered all of this. Ours, Technica covered all of this in detail.
Speaker 5:  The reason starlink wasn't getting awards for these rural broadband programs
Speaker 5:  is 'cause they were saying they were gonna cover densely populated suburbs
Speaker 5:  with shopping malls in them, not rural America, which starlink cannot do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't, it doesn't even matter if they can or can't do it. They were
Speaker 5:  looking at the maps and saying, no, that's not correct. Right? This is not
Speaker 5:  what you should be doing. So then Carr goes on to say, for those that
Speaker 5:  have benefited from the two-tiered system of justice that prevailed during
Speaker 5:  the Biden years, even handed mist may feel like discrimination,
Speaker 5:  but that does not make it. So this is also just
Speaker 5:  fully warped thinking, right? If you think that there was a two tiered
Speaker 5:  system of justice during the Biden administration, you don't pull the pendulum
Speaker 5:  back by investigating broadcast outlets in violation of First Amendment.
Speaker 5:  That is absolutely wrong. It is just, It is
Speaker 5:  censorious, it, it goes against the American system of justice.
Speaker 5:  And It is so outside the realm of authority for the FCC that
Speaker 5:  it, it like boggles the mind that I talk about it every week. This is not
Speaker 5:  what you want the Federal Communications Commission doing. You do not want
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr who is unelected saying that he alone can
Speaker 5:  control what is distributed over the airwaves because he understands
Speaker 5:  what the public interest is and he can reopen investigations that
Speaker 5:  like many, many, many former FCC chairman and commissioners
Speaker 5:  from years past have said or inappropriate, this is not what we wanted to.
Speaker 5:  And then on top of that, I have done a lot of reporting on this over
Speaker 5:  the years and I know that what he's saying about the Biden administration
Speaker 5:  is fully bullshit. I know this because the problems in the
Speaker 5:  Biden administration were that big telecom companies made the
Speaker 5:  Biden FCC corrupt and ineffective. So it could not
Speaker 5:  forcibly open up our nation's networks. They could not open
Speaker 5:  up cable companies, they could not do net neutrality. They could not
Speaker 5:  get the votes to regulate our systems to make sure that they
Speaker 5:  respected free speech by being open to all. And in fact, it's not
Speaker 5:  Republicans or Democrats to prevented this from happening. It is the big
Speaker 5:  telecom companies that got together and made it
Speaker 5:  impossible for Biden to nominate Gigi. So to the
Speaker 5:  FCC completing his commissioners of Democrats so they could pass votes.
Speaker 5:  We did a whole decoder on this. And in that decoder,
Speaker 5:  the, the star witness on that episode of decoder, we talked to a ton of people,
Speaker 5:  you can go listen to it. The, the, the star guest was the
Speaker 5:  CEO of Newsmax
Speaker 5:  who is not a Democrat. Chris Ruddy, the CEO of Newsmax is, I'm telling you,
Speaker 5:  this man is not a democrat. We, we are not aligned politically on a number
Speaker 5:  of things. But he came onto our show and said the
Speaker 5:  problem is the big cable companies
Speaker 5:  are trying to keep Gigi so out of the SEC
Speaker 5:  so that there are not votes to open these systems up and actually
Speaker 5:  protect access here. Let's just run the audit. Here's, here's Chris Ruddy,
Speaker 5:  the CEO of Newsmax talking to me under coder last year about the
Speaker 5:  actual problem in the cable industry under the Biden administration.
Speaker 16:  The cable industry is a bit of a racket and the big
Speaker 16:  broadcast companies are part of the racket and they benefit it. The people
Speaker 16:  that get screwed are the consumers, the cable customers.
Speaker 16:  And so the way the rack works is if you own a lot of
Speaker 16:  television stations that a local cable company needs your
Speaker 16:  A-B-C-C-B-S-N-B-C Fox affiliates, they basically
Speaker 16:  have you over a barrel because if they don't give you your channel, people
Speaker 16:  are gonna go to another cable system. Right?
Speaker 5:  What Chris is saying there, and what has been true for years is that if
Speaker 5:  you are Fox and you want Fox
Speaker 5:  News on a cable system, you have all of this leverage
Speaker 5:  because you also have Fox and you have the NFL on Fox.
Speaker 5:  And so you can go to cable operators like Comcast disclosure,
Speaker 5:  Comcast is a investor in Fox Media, although they hate the fact that I'm
Speaker 5:  talking about this and I've been talking about it for a decade. You can go
Speaker 5:  to Comcast or Spectrum or whoever else and say, do you want the NFL? You
Speaker 5:  have to pay us a very, very high rate for Fox News two
Speaker 5:  because if you don't, we're gonna take the NFL away.
Speaker 5:  A BC does this, you want ESPN, you gotta pay a whole bunch of money for a,
Speaker 5:  b, C family. They all do it. Comcast does it because they have NBC. There's
Speaker 5:  a reason they all vertically integrated all of this content 'cause they wanted
Speaker 5:  to leverage over all the dis distributors. That's the problem
Speaker 5:  you, so you look at where the alignments are and It is not Republicans and
Speaker 5:  Democrats. It is big companies and small companies.
Speaker 5:  That's why Chris Ruddy, CEO of Newsmax supported a very
Speaker 5:  progressive commissioner that was nominated by Biden. 'cause she wanted
Speaker 5:  to break the control of the big companies. That's why Rupert
Speaker 5:  Murdoch and all of his empire went to war against that
Speaker 5:  same commissioner of the SEC and made sure her nomination to go
Speaker 5:  through. Again, you can just go listen to this episode of Coder. It is totally
Speaker 5:  fascinating 'cause the lines are so scrambled in ways you would never expect,
Speaker 5:  but it's big versus small. And so Brendan is
Speaker 5:  babbling is running his mouth about the two-tiered system of justice and
Speaker 5:  the Biden administration and how conservatives were punished. And in reality,
Speaker 5:  you had the owner of M-S-N-B-C Comcast and the owner of Fox
Speaker 5:  News, Rupert Murdoch totally aligned.
Speaker 5:  There wasn't any daylight between them and how they wanted Biden to regulate
Speaker 5:  these systems. You had small companies like
Speaker 5:  newsmax saying, no, we actually need access. We actually need the regulator
Speaker 5:  to step up and open the door. And just
Speaker 5:  on its face you can see that Brendan is lying. He's concocting a
Speaker 5:  justification for his own bad behavior out of nothing.
Speaker 5:  And we are sitting here with the receipts. We've done the reporting for over
Speaker 5:  a decade on the FCC and how it works. And I can tell you that It is almost
Speaker 5:  always big versus small. It is very, very rarely
Speaker 5:  Republican versus Democrat. And I just think that Brendan is making this
Speaker 5:  a political project when it should be an access project, when it should
Speaker 5:  be about everybody having access to the internet on a fair level playing
Speaker 5:  field. When it should be about ISPs not being able to throttle you. It
Speaker 5:  should be about cable systems being cheaper. It should be about prices going
Speaker 5:  down over time. It should be about Americans paying lower prices for faster
Speaker 5:  speeds. We pay the highest prices in the world for some of the slowest speeds
Speaker 5:  available. And instead he's making about dumb political
Speaker 5:  bullshit because it lets him use power over and over and over again. He
Speaker 5:  wants to find justifications for him to assert authority over things He should
Speaker 5:  never have any authority over whatsoever. So every week I say this,
Speaker 5:  Brendan, I know you listen, I'm dead shore of it now
Speaker 5:  I know you get Google results for your own name, my man. Come on the show,
Speaker 5:  come talk to us about this. The people want you to come on decoder, come
Speaker 5:  on The Vergecast, see if you can make sense of this. See if you can justify
Speaker 5:  your own power seeking behavior because it's just every week it's getting
Speaker 5:  stupider and stupider. We can all see it. That's been Brendan Carr's dummy
Speaker 5:  America's favorite podcast within podcast.
Speaker 6:  That was good. That's good. I'm glad you wrote that out that that really
Speaker 5:  Can you tell that I it
Speaker 6:  Helped the, the writing helped, I think. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All right. We need a pallet cleanser.
Speaker 6:  Wait, I have a TV I wanna talk to you about. Okay. You may remember
Speaker 6:  from, was it last year that you, you came on the show and told us the story
Speaker 6:  about being at the the TV shootout? Yes. That was like last
Speaker 6:  summer.
Speaker 5:  The best thing I've ever done in this, in this entire job is going to the
Speaker 5:  TV shootout.
Speaker 6:  So, and this is like Richard is the perfect person to have here to do this
Speaker 6:  with us. There is a new there there,
Speaker 6:  it has been upgraded. The one that won, there's now a new one,
Speaker 5:  Sony, they've announced a new one. Okay. And they, and they only announced
Speaker 5:  it in an event in Japan. So we sent former Verge editor Sam Byford
Speaker 5:  to the event in Japan. Sony has announced a number of new TVs there. They
Speaker 5:  don't do their TVs at CS anymore, they just do them
Speaker 5:  later in the year. 'cause ever they know everyone will pay attention to them.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, so they did the mini LED a few weeks ago and then they just announced
Speaker 5:  that Sonia Bravia eight two,
Speaker 5:  this is the name you gotta love
Speaker 6:  Sony, not the Bravia nine. You
Speaker 5:  Absolutely have to love Sony's naming schemes. It's so bad,
Speaker 5:  right? They have the Bravia nine, but now they have the BRAVIA eight two.
Speaker 5:  Wait, the, I can't tell you, but also it doesn't how little census makes,
Speaker 6:  Correct me if I'm wrong, but the doesn't, the BRAVIA eight two
Speaker 6:  replace not the BRAVIA eight, but the A 95 L.
Speaker 5:  Yep, that's correct. So the Bravia nine is is a mini LED.
Speaker 5:  You got it. And the BRAVIA eight two is a
Speaker 5:  cutie ed that replaces the A 95 L.
Speaker 6:  When we buy TikTok, I think we should just rename it to a string of
Speaker 6:  letters and numbers that have nothing to do with anything.
Speaker 5:  It makes, this makes no sense. By the way, the regular BRAV eight is still
Speaker 5:  on sale. That's just a regular oled. So you have the BRAVIA eight,
Speaker 5:  which is an ed, the BRAVIA eight two, which is the new flagship QD
Speaker 5:  ed. And then the bra nine, which is led, I don't know man,
Speaker 5:  it's 125%. The peak brightness of the A 95 L
Speaker 5:  150% of the BRAVIA eight. So it's just basically the same idea
Speaker 5:  but brighter. And then if you remember from that whole TV shootout conversation,
Speaker 5:  that is very much not about features, right? Like HDM
Speaker 5:  ports or whatever. It's just about image reproduction and how closely it
Speaker 5:  can be calibrated to match a reference display. The reference display is
Speaker 5:  made by Sony. So everyone thinks this is unfair. Sony makes alt like they
Speaker 5:  have dominant market share and reference displays in Hollywood. So it makes
Speaker 5:  sense that they're the winners anyway. Now they're just openly saying this
Speaker 5:  TV will look most like this reference display. So they're, they've they've,
Speaker 5:  they've, they've just taken it fully on that they have this advantage. They
Speaker 5:  say it looks great, Sam said it looks great. We'll see, I'm, they say
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be cheaper than a 95 L. The A 90 L is very, the 8 9 5 L is
Speaker 5:  very expensive. It's $5,000 for the 77 inch one. Oh. And that's as
Speaker 5:  big as it gets. TVs are getting real big now and a nine five L is still 77
Speaker 5:  inches. So my guess is they're gonna make one bigger one that's more expensive
Speaker 5:  and the 77 will come down to price.
Speaker 6:  We, Richard, be honest, you're, you have, you have tickets booked to go to
Speaker 6:  Japan and buy one of these? Just, just tell me the truth.
Speaker 7:  No, I'm just going to buy three tickets and have the TV
Speaker 7:  come to me
Speaker 6:  Like first class. Okay. Just a full, full row of, of
Speaker 7:  You about the tar man. I can't be out here wasting money.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's just being smart.
Speaker 5:  It's all Can I, can I, can I say the best part of this story, which is not
Speaker 5:  the BRAVIA eight two, the best part of the story is that Sony is also
Speaker 5:  introducing a new entry level TV in the United States, which is called
Speaker 5:  the bravia two two
Speaker 6:  What?
Speaker 7:  Sony,
Speaker 5:  It's BRAVIA two numeral and then Bra two roman
Speaker 5:  numeral. It's the BRAVIA two two. It's great. I mean it's, it's
Speaker 5:  spectacular.
Speaker 7:  The sequel to a TV that was not sold in the us Yeah. So no one will even
Speaker 7:  what the original BRAVIA two was,
Speaker 5:  They didn't sell the original BRAVIA two here. So you're gonna go in the
Speaker 5:  store there, you see the BRAVIA two two, it's very good. There
Speaker 6:  Are so many better options.
Speaker 6:  Call it the BRAVIA three call it just the bravia two
Speaker 6:  parentheses the year that It is. Yep. There's
Speaker 7:  So have you ever tried to like talk to a person about buying the Sony noise
Speaker 7:  canceling headphones? Because you sound insane once you start trying to tell
Speaker 7:  them what the name is. Okay, so they're really good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  The w something
Speaker 6:  You at the WFH 0 0 0 0 0 H four.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. Bravia Tutu is a hall of fame
Speaker 5:  name for any product in history. It is, it's very
Speaker 5:  good.
Speaker 6:  The thing about It is no, no one will ever hear that name correctly. The
Speaker 6:  first time you'll say the Bravia two two and they'll, they'll think you
Speaker 6:  had to think about it and it's actually called the BRAVIA two, but you were
Speaker 6:  trying to remember if it's the two or the three. And, and so they'll think
Speaker 6:  you just said the Bravia two and then they'll buy last generation televisions.
Speaker 6:  And that is just a shame.
Speaker 5:  By the way, we've had a number of requests for updates on Saturday Samsung.
Speaker 6:  We have an all timer this week,
Speaker 5:  Which you'll recall is Samsung's executives
Speaker 5:  were required to start coming into the office on Saturdays, six days
Speaker 5:  a week to increase sales, which means they can only
Speaker 5:  have wacky ideas, right? That's not a product development cycle that's
Speaker 5:  just come in on Saturday and think of ways to juice sales. Actually David,
Speaker 5:  I don't know what you think the a timer is. You, you go first. I've got mine.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  Do we have different, I mine's, mine's a vacuum cleaner.
Speaker 5:  Okay. You've got the va I've got, no, I've got a TV one. Mine is,
Speaker 5:  this is several weeks ago now. They launched a $10,000 bundle
Speaker 5:  of eight TVs. So that's a Richard Bundle. You
Speaker 5:  put eight TVs that range from 55 to 98 inches
Speaker 5:  on the wall and they just, but they just sell it to you as one bundle.
Speaker 5:  And there are pitches that you will save $6,000 by buying
Speaker 5:  the TVs in bulk.
Speaker 6:  So like when I, I, I played ultimate Frisbee in college and we would buy,
Speaker 6:  you could buy like a bulk bag of just like random misprint
Speaker 6:  frisbees for way cheaper than you would buy the me. That's what this makes
Speaker 6:  me think of. You're just like, give us 10 grand, we're gonna ship you a bunch
Speaker 6:  of televisions. There'll be some sizes, some models where
Speaker 6:  you're just gonna get like a grab bag of televisions for $10,000. Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  Love it. So you get 1 98 inch, 1 65 inch,
Speaker 5:  oh no, you get 4 65 inch, but one is eight
Speaker 5:  K for some reason.
Speaker 5:  So you get 1 98 inch 4K, 1 65 inch eight
Speaker 5:  k, 365 inch 4K, and 3 55 inch four
Speaker 5:  Ks. None of them are alls, they're all just like medium good Samsung Q
Speaker 5:  LEDs. The funniest thing about this is when people buy lots of TVs
Speaker 5:  like this, usually what they do is they plug them into a matrix switcher
Speaker 5:  so they can put them in a grid and they get one big picture. But Samsung
Speaker 5:  is not selling you an even number of any size, so you
Speaker 5:  can't do that. This is just the whoop
Speaker 7:  Thing. When they, when they just sell a bag and they're like, yeah, it's
Speaker 7:  five bucks, you'll get So we'll, we'll send you some tv.
Speaker 5:  Don't
Speaker 6:  Worry about it. Yeah. Like those people who buy like pallets of return stuff
Speaker 6:  from Amazon and it's like you just kind of get what you get. This is
Speaker 5:  Like actually really good. This is the most, this is I think the most Saturday
Speaker 5:  Samsung we've had yet out of all of the thing. Like remember the previous
Speaker 5:  ideas were like, buy a phone, get a tv, buy a tv, get a tv. This is just
Speaker 5:  like, here's eight TVs for
Speaker 5:  $10,000.
Speaker 6:  That's so good.
Speaker 5:  That's very good. All right. What, what's yours? Yours. Some vacuum cleaner.
Speaker 6:  Mine is just, just very briefly, I just wanna mention the bespoke AI
Speaker 6:  Jet Ultra, an $1,100 vacuum cleaner that has
Speaker 6:  a screen on it that shows you a bunch of stuff, but also shows you
Speaker 6:  notifications for phone calls and text messages on your vacuum cleaner.
Speaker 6:  Samsung is now big into the idea that you should be able to do things like
Speaker 6:  make phone calls from your appliances. And I just, I just
Speaker 6:  want everyone to know that. I think that's fantastic and I'm extremely in
Speaker 6:  favor of it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm down. Look, you, once you put the screen everywhere, you gotta,
Speaker 5:  you gotta have a screen everywhere.
Speaker 6:  I want like Apple style live updates. So I'm getting like sports scores
Speaker 6:  as I'm vacuuming. Like this is, let's just go all into this. I'm ready.
Speaker 5:  My favorite again, when I say unsponsored for flavor, what I want you to
Speaker 5:  think of is when they're sponsored, they lack flavor. My favorite right now
Speaker 5:  is a bunch of tech influencers are taking money
Speaker 5:  to pretend the LG microwave, they announced at CS that doesn't have a window,
Speaker 5:  but instead has a screen and then there's a camera inside the microwave to
Speaker 5:  show you what's happening inside the microwave. But you can also watch TV
Speaker 5:  on the screen. A lot of people are pretending this is a gonna,
Speaker 6:  My absolute favorite thing about that is everybody has the same picture,
Speaker 6:  right? Which is them standing sort of across their kitchen from it and it's
Speaker 6:  behind them and it looks like the fakest most like
Speaker 6:  photoshopped bullshit screen back there. It's so
Speaker 6:  terrible. It's really good. You're like, look at my beautifully modern kitchen
Speaker 6:  and this horrible Android
Speaker 5:  Happened. It's like, you can watch TV on this micro. It's like
Speaker 5:  no lack of flavor is what I'm calling out there. My friends.
Speaker 5:  Just a few more here in the lightning round. Unsurprising, I think
Speaker 5:  for this audience, Tesla sales plummeted 13% this quarter,
Speaker 5:  particularly European countries. There's some juicing of numbers in other
Speaker 5:  regions. We'll see. But it, it just seems like,
Speaker 5:  man, if you, there's not a better financial decision than buying a used model
Speaker 5:  three right now. There's a lot of reasons not to do that, but boy can you
Speaker 5:  get one for no money 'cause they are being traded in at such insane rates,
Speaker 5:  which I think is gonna depress the new sales as well. Richard,
Speaker 6:  Do you see, do you see a lot of Teslas around? I I've been trying to like
Speaker 6:  chart the number of Teslas I see in my day to day and I'm convinced in my
Speaker 6:  neighborhood it has gone down. I can't prove it, but I'm convinced.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 7:  Hard to say. I still, I still see quite a bit, but like I live where GM
Speaker 7:  engineers go to retire, so I see a lot of like Hummers, like electric Hummers.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All the time.
Speaker 6:  Sick.
Speaker 5:  My sense is that GM is rushing out a bunch of its TVs. So Tesla
Speaker 5:  sales in Europe were down 43%. I'm saying about the numbers were a little
Speaker 5:  weird in China, they were down until the final week of the quarter when insurance
Speaker 5:  registrations like went, just went up. So like nobody knows why that happened.
Speaker 5:  So sales are kind of dropping. And then here in the United States, GM
Speaker 5:  reported 32,000 EVs are sold in the first quarter, which is double, it's
Speaker 5:  year over year. So the demand is still there, it's just going into other
Speaker 5:  places. Lucid is claiming that it's selling a bunch of EVs. So I think
Speaker 5:  the demand is, is is moving. And I think General Motors in particular is
Speaker 5:  trying to get some of its newest ones just like out the door,
Speaker 5:  like the Cadillac Vista, that's the new three row
Speaker 5:  SUV. Like it's not announced like they announced in November, but they haven't
Speaker 5:  like had a launch for it. And they're already dealers who are like, we have
Speaker 5:  'em now. And you just get the sense that like between tariffs and being aggressive
Speaker 5:  about Tesla, they're just trying to get products into showroom so people
Speaker 5:  can buy them. We'll see everybody
Speaker 6:  Who has been waiting for there to be a moment to take down Tesla
Speaker 6:  seems to be sensing that It is right now. Which is very funny because there
Speaker 6:  are a lot of pretty ugly wins against the car
Speaker 6:  industry as a whole and against EVs in, in specific and,
Speaker 6:  and yet there is like, to your point about the model three being a great
Speaker 6:  financial decision, like it's, It is super telling that that is the case
Speaker 6:  and still these numbers are what they are. Right? Like it's people
Speaker 6:  are not buying these cars for Elon Musk reasons.
Speaker 5:  That's super. That No, I'm saying a new model three is not a great to, although
Speaker 5:  those prices are coming down and they're doing 0% financing and like Elon
Speaker 5:  will come to your house and like kiss your baby if you buy one right now.
Speaker 5:  Like they're desperate to move those cars. Yeah. A used model three
Speaker 5:  a year old has depreciated so much that like if you're in the market
Speaker 5:  for a car, a two or 3-year-old model three is like
Speaker 5:  financially the only logical decision anyone should make. Lots of people
Speaker 5:  are not gonna make that decision and that number is gonna keep coming down.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. What does it cost to take off the Tesla logo and put on like an Audi
Speaker 6:  logo? You add that
Speaker 5:  Into, have you seen the cyber truck that's floating in New York City with
Speaker 5:  a Toyota logo on the back? It's very good. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  David, you have been paying attention to Alexa Plus, which is launched in
Speaker 5:  early access, but none of us believe it's actually out. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  Launched in the most aggressive air quotes you can possibly
Speaker 6:  imagine. I have not heard from one
Speaker 6:  regular human who has it. Like we, we've been looking around on social.
Speaker 6:  I know other reporters who have been looking. Joanna Stern has like been
Speaker 6:  very publicly begging people to be like, tell me you have Alexa Plus. And
Speaker 6:  it just doesn't seem to be out there. And it's like this is always early
Speaker 6:  access and it wouldn't be super shocking if you're Amazon to roll this out
Speaker 6:  to 10 people first. So I'm not necessarily taking this as like a
Speaker 6:  totally disastrous thing. Well,
Speaker 5:  The fact
Speaker 7:  That they said it was coming at the end of March and then they suddenly said
Speaker 7:  that it launched on March 31st. Might, might be a
Speaker 5:  Signal. They
Speaker 6:  Turned it on for like one random Amazon employee and they were like, we did
Speaker 6:  it. We launched
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 6:  You as long as you can, you know,
Speaker 5:  It's pan outs himself. Cut the
Speaker 6:  Ribbon with the big scissors. You've, I've
Speaker 7:  Done my homework at the last minute before
Speaker 5:  With chat GBT, it's just chat GBT being like you should do
Speaker 5:  tariffs.
Speaker 6:  But I do think there are a bunch of features that are missing,
Speaker 6:  like being able to do some of the more sophisticated AI
Speaker 6:  stuff. Like have the system sort of infer what you wanna order
Speaker 6:  and then order food from you or like remind
Speaker 6:  people around your house to do stuff. A lot of these sort like little tiny
Speaker 6:  edge cases, but they're the things that were supposed to be
Speaker 6:  sort of different and useful about Alexa, where it can kind of understand
Speaker 6:  what you're doing and where you are and what matters to you and then take
Speaker 6:  action on your behalf. Like that is the pitch for Alexa Plus. And
Speaker 6:  at least some of that still has not shipped. And, and yet again,
Speaker 6:  I think it was this week the Washington Post had a report
Speaker 6:  yet again that there is like a list of things that is way behind and not
Speaker 6:  ready for public consumption. And it's like, boy, at some point Amazon really
Speaker 6:  needs to like aggressively flip a this is good switch or
Speaker 6:  else this is just gonna get ugly. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And no one is yet has of yet solved the DoorDash problem. Why would DoorDash
Speaker 5:  let robots use its service instead of people? No one knows
Speaker 5:  the answer to this question.
Speaker 6:  Money.
Speaker 5:  It's a, but then, then Amazon just has to pay a bunch of, of extra money
Speaker 5:  for every DoorDash order. Yeah. To get whitelist on door
Speaker 5:  Dash's website. So we can click around on it. This makes no sense to me.
Speaker 5:  No. All right, last one. I don't understand one word of the story, Richard.
Speaker 5:  I'm hoping you can explain it to me. Coyote versus Acme is finally coming
Speaker 5:  to theaters.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So a lot of people were online were upset because
Speaker 7:  Warner Brothers killed a movie that no one had seen. There. There was this,
Speaker 7:  this coyote, the coyote movie that was supposed to come, it was
Speaker 7:  like a comedy with people were expecting it. David Oslo decided that it
Speaker 7:  shouldn't happen and that it would better to just take a tax write off than
Speaker 7:  to release this movie.
Speaker 5:  This a classic Zav move by the way. Yeah. Like earlier I was like, where
Speaker 5:  are the media companies trying to buy TikTok? And his is like, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  kill movies I've already paid for. Yeah. Ticket tax.
Speaker 7:  And there were a bunch of movies that kind of, this happened to, at one time
Speaker 7:  this was one that people got particularly upset about. So it's been sitting
Speaker 7:  on the shelf for a few years, but now at long last they have
Speaker 7:  sold it to Ketchup Entertainment.
Speaker 5:  Sure.
Speaker 7:  Who is going to give this movie a theatrical run? And if you would like to
Speaker 7:  see Coyote versus Ami in theaters, you will have the opportunity to buy a
Speaker 7:  ticket and do that. And I, I would be watching very closely. I wanna see
Speaker 7:  how many people really wanna see this movie. It's gonna
Speaker 6:  Be so funny if this movie sucks. Like,
Speaker 6:  like the the best outcome for this as, as a reporter is that this movie
Speaker 6:  turns out to be like great and a phenomenon. And like, I, I really hope that's
Speaker 6:  what It is. If this movie sucks, like a lot of people are gonna feel really
Speaker 6:  stupid, including me.
Speaker 5:  I don't know a ketchup entertainment is, except I do know they spend
Speaker 5:  $50 million on this movie and they're gonna release it next year. And for
Speaker 5:  some reason Warner Brothers turned down Amazon, Netflix in Paramount.
Speaker 6:  That's the part of it I find weird and potentially
Speaker 6:  for more money. Like it's, it's, it's just a very odd
Speaker 6:  situation that that Warner's has found itself in that like at some point
Speaker 6:  somebody had just turned around and was like, wait, you're telling me we
Speaker 6:  can get a check for this? Get the check. Yeah. And after
Speaker 6:  all this
Speaker 7:  Time check, but they don't want it to come out anywhere that anyone knows
Speaker 7:  about it. Right.
Speaker 5:  Guess they don't wanna be proven
Speaker 6:  Wrong. That's interesting, right?
Speaker 5:  A lot of American businesses is sort of explained by people being like, wait,
Speaker 5:  money is better than not money. Right? And then like, sort of chaotically
Speaker 5:  making a decision. This is what I've learned from five years of doing together.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean there might also be a certain set of, I was just looking and
Speaker 6:  the, the number they wanted originally was 75 to $80 million
Speaker 6:  and they are coming, well short of that. But so what might have happened
Speaker 6:  is they were like, well eventually somebody will give us the money. And then
Speaker 6:  Zav is like, did we ever get that money? They're like,
Speaker 6:  no, lemme go get some money.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. It's a good vergecast mystery. Why is this happening?
Speaker 5:  Which honestly should be the tagline of our show. Why is this happening?
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast
Speaker 6:  Also, if you've seen this movie, I know there are people in the world who
Speaker 6:  have seen Coyote versus Acme. If you've seen it and if you know if it's any
Speaker 6:  good, I I need to know. It's so important to me to know whether
Speaker 6:  this movie is any good.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna wrap us up by saying I wrote my annual just buy a Brother Printer
Speaker 5:  post. It is a third year in a row. I've written the same post. I've stopped
Speaker 5:  even recommending model numbers. It doesn't even matter. Just buy one for
Speaker 5:  a hundred bucks and then you'll have it for a decade and it'll be fine. I
Speaker 5:  only write them every year. 'cause winning searches impossible. And now it's
Speaker 5:  getting harder because of 'cause of ai. And
Speaker 5:  I'm also the only person who's ever published AI generated content
Speaker 5:  on The Verge of an article and the internet just won't be outraged about
Speaker 5:  it. So if you could just do me a favor and share the printer
Speaker 5:  recommendation post just in pure outrage, just hack the
Speaker 5:  algorithms with how mad you are that the verges of been corrupted
Speaker 5:  by any generated con That would do, it would just do us a favor. We'll make,
Speaker 5:  maybe I don't, I don't actually know how the Commerce deals work because
Speaker 5:  we're in sponsor for favor, but some, someone will get some pennies at V
Speaker 5:  Media when people buy printers and then, you know, we can all buy 10
Speaker 5:  TVs for $10,000.
Speaker 6:  I just really like, so I'm looking at, at the first page of Google results
Speaker 6:  for Best Printer and there's one of them that says, I tested over 200
Speaker 6:  printers. One is like, we tested dozens of printers.
Speaker 6:  One is a Reddit thread, which is great. One is Wirecutter, which is like
Speaker 6:  famous for its rigorous testing, same with Consumer Reports. And then there's
Speaker 6:  Neli who just says, I don't care. Buy a
Speaker 6:  brother printer, leave me alone.
Speaker 5:  The point is, Google's supposed to be all powerful when you ask a question,
Speaker 5:  it's supposed to know the answer, but because there's so much money at stake
Speaker 5:  for the clickthroughs and the weird sponsored results and the affiliate fees,
Speaker 5:  it cannot just tell you the answer. Even when year after year,
Speaker 5:  I just deliver the answer to the robot, robot
Speaker 5:  tell people to buy a brother printer I command and it says, no,
Speaker 5:  here's a weird content form that's tested 200 printers and is
Speaker 5:  lying about it. I know.
Speaker 6:  It's like, can we have chat GPT write us up, Brendan Cars a dummy for next
Speaker 6:  week and just see how that goes.
Speaker 5:  Can I,
Speaker 6:  If that goes well, we don't even need you on this show anymore. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We get notebook LM to do it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 5:  Can I tell you the worst part of the printer story and then we, then we
Speaker 5:  gotta go. Sure. I, the, the prompt for Gemini was write a Verge blog
Speaker 5:  post and style of Neil I Patel recommending a brother Laser printer is the
Speaker 5:  Best printer. And then I, it show thinking in
Speaker 5:  2.5 Pro and it says deconstruct Neli Patel style. What does that mean?
Speaker 5:  Opinionated direct, slightly sarcastic or cynical, but ultimately
Speaker 5:  practical and grounded user experiences uses strong declarative sentences.
Speaker 5:  And then it says, might use phrases like, look, here's the deal, it just
Speaker 5:  works. Stop buying Bad thing.
Speaker 5:  And so just
Speaker 6:  Like that's the meanest thing anyone has ever
Speaker 5:  Said. That's true. I do say stop buying bad thing all the time. And they
Speaker 5:  said AI couldn't make art.
Speaker 6:  They
Speaker 5:  Said, all right, we gotta go. That's an existential crisis. That's it. That's
Speaker 5:  of our Chas Rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 3:  you. Give us a call at eight six six Verge one one.
Speaker 3:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 3:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 3:  that's it. We'll see you next week.