# Transcript
ID: 5810c7af-aae6-415c-b456-bd7e208fd480
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3567344396376137278/-7362322601917892172/s93290-US-6651s-1752834842.mp3
Description: Would you like Siri more if it had a face? This week on The Vergecast, we’re talking about AI assistants getting smarter… and uncomfortably personal. The Verge’s Jennifer Pattison Tuohy joins the show to talk about her early tests of Alexa Plus, which is finally AI-powered and a lot more capable. Jake shares his uncomfortable first interaction with Grok’s anime girlfriend. And Waveform cohost David Imel is here to talk about Sony’s RX1R III and other premium “compact” cameras.
Finally, the THUNDER ROUND is back. New, improved, and still loud.
Speaker 5:  Hello and Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of deeply Uncomfortable
Speaker 5:  Conversations with ai. I'm Jay Kakis, executive editor of The Verge,
Speaker 5:  NELI Patel, David Pierce. They're on parental Leave. They'll both be
Speaker 5:  back later this year. Today we've got a fantastic
Speaker 5:  crew joining us remotely. We've got VERGE Smart Home reviewer, Jen Tuey.
Speaker 1:  Hello, nice to be here.
Speaker 5:  Anne in the studio with us. Special guest friend of the show and waveform
Speaker 5:  co-host David Am Mill. Hello, glad to be here. We've got a lot to talk about
Speaker 5:  today. David's joining 'cause I really wanna talk about Sony's new camera,
Speaker 5:  which people have been waiting 10 years for the THUNDER ROUND is back
Speaker 5:  new and improved. Just wait for it. But first we
Speaker 5:  have to talk about AI assistance because two big things happened this week.
Speaker 5:  First, Jen got access to Alexa, plus the new AI powered version
Speaker 5:  of Alexa and Second Crock got weird
Speaker 5:  again. It's always getting weird. It keeps going And
Speaker 5:  I actually think these two things are kind of related in the long term.
Speaker 5:  So first, Jen, you've been talking to Alexa a bunch lately. Tell us
Speaker 5:  what have you seen what is new with Alexa Plus?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I've been waiting a long time to chat to this ai. I am not gonna
Speaker 6:  lie, this is Amazon's newly revamped
Speaker 6:  generative AI powered voice assistant. Now for context, I've had,
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm gonna try not to say the A-L-E-X-A word too many times 'cause I
Speaker 6:  know that might annoy all the listeners out there. But I've had Amazon's
Speaker 6:  a in my home pretty much since it launched
Speaker 6:  and this, and it's, it's been an experience over the years. It was
Speaker 6:  great when it first launched, but it's kind of started to get less and less
Speaker 6:  useful as time went by. And Amazon has completely
Speaker 6:  revamped the, the assistant. So now it's
Speaker 6:  powered by large language models. This they launched or announced it fully
Speaker 6:  February of this year. Although they had originally launched it in 2023
Speaker 6:  and then spent a really long time bringing it to the public. They
Speaker 6:  said it was gonna come out in March. It's now July.
Speaker 6:  So it's slowly rolling out to people. You have to request early
Speaker 6:  access. So it's still technically in a beta stage.
Speaker 6:  It's free to use currently, but the plan according to Amazon is
Speaker 6:  it's going to be 1999 a month. However you get
Speaker 6:  it free with Prime. So when prime costs
Speaker 6:  $15 a month, it's, yeah, the math is a bit screw screwy
Speaker 6:  there. But it's interesting to see this approach. I mean obviously
Speaker 6:  currently you pay for more advanced features with a lot of different AI
Speaker 6:  assistance out there. So you can kind of see their approach here.
Speaker 6:  But it's also a big shift for people who have been able to use
Speaker 6:  Alexa, sorry, who've been able to use a for free
Speaker 6:  for over a decade. So it's, it's, I was excited to
Speaker 6:  try out the new capabilities, see if they're worth any extra money, even
Speaker 6:  though you don't have to pay that yet. The big thing they're pushing is that
Speaker 6:  it is more age agentic like this, this assistant can
Speaker 6:  do things for you from what it could already do,
Speaker 6:  such as controlling your smart home devices and playing your music, but being
Speaker 6:  able to do it in a natural language way so you don't have to use that precise
Speaker 6:  nomenclature. If anyone that's used a before
Speaker 6:  will know you have to get it very, very precise to get it to do
Speaker 6:  what you want. And it's very frustrating when it misunderstands you and does
Speaker 6:  something that it shouldn't. So that's the big, that's one of the big shifts.
Speaker 6:  And then the other is that it's actually going to be able to sort of do
Speaker 6:  things like book you, well this is where it gets a bit fuzzy 'cause it
Speaker 6:  used to be able to book you an Uber and then they stopped being able to do
Speaker 6:  that, but now they're bringing it back. And so it's more these age agentic
Speaker 6:  sort of clicking around on the websites feature as Neli would put it, where
Speaker 6:  your, your a assistant is gonna be able to go and book you an Uber,
Speaker 6:  going to be able to book you a plumber or an electrician, book you
Speaker 6:  an open table restaurant reservation, do things for you
Speaker 6:  outside of what traditionally had been able to do, again
Speaker 6:  in natural language. And then the other element of it, which is,
Speaker 6:  is kind of more of a, you were already
Speaker 6:  able to do some of this, but it's got better, is be much
Speaker 6:  more conversational. So you can ask the assistant
Speaker 6:  questions like you maybe would ask chat GPT or Gemini. And rather than just
Speaker 6:  getting sort of very basic responses, it's got much deeper
Speaker 6:  knowledge and is much more able to respond to more general
Speaker 6:  knowledge questions. So in my testing when I, I, I wrote a piece that we
Speaker 6:  published last week. I spent like my first 24 hours, so I was chatting with
Speaker 6:  it about the Wimbledon tennis tournament, which is one of my favorite
Speaker 6:  times of the year. I was also asking it questions about
Speaker 6:  booking my next vacation. I'm about to go on a trip
Speaker 6:  And I was asking for suggestions and it told me some great tips
Speaker 6:  and ideas and then completely lied to me. So it's just like your general
Speaker 6:  AI basically,
Speaker 5:  Jen, I love that you're avoiding the name. This is the sign of a true professional
Speaker 5:  who has been, I I I'm also assuming yelled at a lot a lot by
Speaker 5:  people in in comments. Yeah, I'm, I'm sorry to everyone.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But this is, this is the big thing, right? Like they announced this,
Speaker 5:  they now this like twice now. Yeah, yeah. They, they launched it
Speaker 5:  like in, what is it, in March quote launched. Yes, yes. Right, right, right.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I believe there, there now more than a
Speaker 5:  million people now have access to it, which sounds like a lot until you,
Speaker 5:  they've sold 500 million Alexa devices. Yeah. So this is
Speaker 5:  like, like not even quite a beta test. Like this is the teeny tiny
Speaker 5:  group. And I guess the re I, I have been wondering okay, like what are they
Speaker 5:  hiding? Like why is it so limited? Yeah. And Jen, I
Speaker 5:  don't know, like I read your piece and it sounds like it's like it's, it's
Speaker 5:  mostly functional. Like are are you running, how is it working? Are you running
Speaker 5:  into problems nonstop?
Speaker 6:  So now, I mean it is functional, but what's really
Speaker 6:  interesting here is it's a completely new assistant. I think originally when
Speaker 6:  they went to launch it in 2023 and we went to a big event
Speaker 6:  in 2023 for the launch, it was going to be the
Speaker 6:  existing commander control style AI that elect
Speaker 6:  Alexa was, I'm sorry everyone. It was gonna be that
Speaker 6:  with an infusion of, you know, chat GPT large
Speaker 6:  language model style smarts. Because one of the com
Speaker 6:  confounding things about using the assistant over the years is its limited
Speaker 6:  capabilities. It is very much com commander control. It can do
Speaker 6:  specific things and that's it. And that was getting frustrating over time.
Speaker 6:  It never really got any smarter. And that was sort of what
Speaker 6:  people, I think most people that use it for smart home control,
Speaker 6:  I think that was fine. But as things as we're starting to see better
Speaker 6:  capabilities throughout generative AI and more
Speaker 6:  and better abilities, being able to use your voice
Speaker 6:  for more than just turning your lights on and off, setting a timer that,
Speaker 6:  you know, that felt like the next step that yeah, that move towards,
Speaker 6:  you know, what Alexa was originally envisioned as as, which is
Speaker 6:  Star Trek's computer. You know, that all knowing all
Speaker 6:  omnipresent AI that can do whatever you want. And that
Speaker 6:  was kind of where I was, I was excited to see
Speaker 6:  Amazon move this and that was what they promised in 2000. And
Speaker 6:  in 2023 then we're not entirely sure kind of what
Speaker 6:  went on behind the scenes, but there was an awful lot of reporting about
Speaker 6:  real struggles. And this is struggles that we have seen of it's
Speaker 6:  appears places like Apple and Google are also having, trying to get
Speaker 6:  this to happen with their assistance because they were built on one type
Speaker 6:  of infrastructure and they're now trying to add this new large
Speaker 6:  language model capability and they're just not meshing. There's not, and
Speaker 6:  so when I spoke to Panos pane at the last, the second
Speaker 6:  launch, the second coming of Alexa Plus,
Speaker 6:  which I'm not sure if I mentioned that's its name, sorry. But you still use
Speaker 6:  the original word, you still use the A word. But Alexa, when,
Speaker 6:  when they announced, when, when they announced it in February, I spoke to
Speaker 6:  Panas Panay and he said, no, this is completely new. We just, we got rid
Speaker 6:  of the old brought in the new 'cause that was, it seems the only way that
Speaker 6:  they were able to completely reimagine,
Speaker 6:  couldn't keep the old. And I think that is the key to the slow rollout
Speaker 6:  because as you say, there are millions of devices out there that
Speaker 6:  people are using for many different purposes and use cases
Speaker 6:  mostly to set a timer. Yes. But there
Speaker 6:  are a lot of people that use this and depend on it. And I think also the
Speaker 6:  accessibility community, you know, voice control is a really important feature
Speaker 6:  for a lot of people. So I think the, the so rollout has been not breaking
Speaker 6:  what already works and adding the new
Speaker 6:  capabilities. And in my testing I did notice
Speaker 6:  that it had broken some of what already worked. And that is,
Speaker 6:  you know, you can see how that's gonna be a problem as this, as they flip
Speaker 6:  the switch and bring this into multiple, multiple millions of homes. So,
Speaker 6:  but for me it was mainly around that smart home control. So if
Speaker 6:  you're familiar with using a, every time I say it, you
Speaker 6:  laugh
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 5:  I do, I do think this is so interesting, right, because it, like
Speaker 5:  Apple has not done this with Apple intelligence on the home pod. No. Google
Speaker 5:  has a very, very limited beta. Yeah, I've been trying to get into it.
Speaker 5:  A Google Home one. Yeah. And can't get, you know, it, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's also not rolling out. Are you, are you an Alexa guy? I'm on mix,
Speaker 5:  mix of Google Home and Home Kit now. That's terrifying. Well, the reason
Speaker 5:  why, yeah. Yeah. The reason I, the only reason I'm on Home Kit
Speaker 5:  is because the smart plugs that I bought were the first ones that
Speaker 5:  supported Matter. But they were, well, they were going to support Matter.
Speaker 5:  They were gonna have an up, they did have an update. It doesn't work for
Speaker 5:  me, but they, they are home kit native. So that is the reason
Speaker 5:  that I have home kit native stuff, but I also have like
Speaker 5:  Google Nest hubs in my apartment. Okay. The, the, the magical idea
Speaker 5:  was that one day when Matter actually like works for everybody, they will
Speaker 5:  all integrate and it won't matter what will matter, but yes,
Speaker 5:  that's your answer. Yes. This answer for you. So, so you are also,
Speaker 5:  yes, I mean this is the thing. It's like, especially when we have these
Speaker 5:  complex like multi-system networks, the idea of, of an
Speaker 5:  AI thing that can actually like string stuff together and understand, I mean,
Speaker 5:  Jen, you have this in your piece where you're giving it these complicated
Speaker 5:  commands and telling it to figure out how to build a routine for you.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, that's great. Yeah. Right. Like, I hate filling with these
Speaker 5:  things. So I, I have like a big, my home is, I guess it's mixed with,
Speaker 5:  it's like Phillips Hu and that's all built into got what is, what is it Google
Speaker 5:  Home? Yeah. I've got a whole bunch of other things to hook into Google Home,
Speaker 5:  is that what it's called now? But it, it might be called Google Home. I,
Speaker 5:  I think it's Google Home. And like I, half of them just like
Speaker 5:  didn't work for a couple years And I had to like un remove them and re
Speaker 5:  it's like eventually it all hooks together on some level
Speaker 5:  and they're just like, it is not easy enough to string them together
Speaker 5:  right now. And I, I imagine that like, there's a
Speaker 5:  a million different issues for Amazon to untangle
Speaker 5:  as they're rolling out Alexa plus the first one and most, most immediate
Speaker 5:  one is just being like, if you're gonna put an LLM in
Speaker 5:  500 million, you know, devices, you gotta make sure
Speaker 5:  it's not gonna go off the rails. Unlike other companies
Speaker 5:  which just don't care.
Speaker 6:  Well, and there's something very different about having, And I mentioned
Speaker 6:  this in my piece, having a voice in your home telling you something confidently
Speaker 6:  that's not true versus having a text box, right. A
Speaker 6:  sentence to you that you can then quickly Google or click on the link that
Speaker 6:  it, it produces so that you can go and confirm where it got that information.
Speaker 6:  So is that, is that computer, it's that Star Trek computer idea again, that
Speaker 6:  omniscient being in your home? That is, you know, that's where
Speaker 6:  that fine line is. And it is so much, I mean,
Speaker 6:  the new Alexa plus is definitely better than the old one
Speaker 6:  in terms of being able to talk to it however you like,
Speaker 6:  getting a response whether it can actually answer correctly or not. But it
Speaker 6:  will talk to you and it'll explain to you why it can't answer or if it can
Speaker 6:  answer. But in terms of that command and control
Speaker 6:  structure, I ran into a, a number of issues. Like it can't run
Speaker 6:  routines in the way that the current Amazon assistant can.
Speaker 6:  It can't. So I think that's, there's gonna be friction there. But what what's
Speaker 6:  interesting I think is where we can see Amazon's taking this,
Speaker 6:  and it's an area that they've really been behind be, you know, after the
Speaker 6:  failure of the fire phone is that they never had a direct
Speaker 6:  connection to your information. So being able to be an
Speaker 6:  actual personal assistant wasn't really possible. And what's changed with
Speaker 6:  this is that you can now tell it information about you. If
Speaker 6:  you want, you can feed information by like emailing it
Speaker 6:  or uploading it through an app. You can connect
Speaker 6:  calendars or your family calendars, which you could do before. But like I
Speaker 6:  can say to it, oh, when's the next available weekend that everyone in my
Speaker 6:  family is gonna be free and it can reply to me. So
Speaker 6:  there is that sort of next level of convenience beyond the smart
Speaker 6:  home control becoming an actual personal assistant
Speaker 6:  in your home. That combination, you know, 'cause right now,
Speaker 6:  Apple's, Siri and Google's assistant, you know, they also, they can do a
Speaker 6:  lot more of that than Amazon can, but nor, but
Speaker 6:  just in your phone, just on a personal device. And I think that's what's
Speaker 6:  make, for me, that's what's made this more interesting is how Amazon's gonna
Speaker 6:  be able to sort of become a personal home assistant
Speaker 6:  for a family or a household. Those kind of, that that's a,
Speaker 6:  that's a next step which we've not seen anyone
Speaker 6:  succeed with. Although I've been testing that element
Speaker 6:  and it's not been great so far.
Speaker 5:  Well we, that's so interesting because you know, Chachi,
Speaker 5:  bt they, they had their operator assistant
Speaker 5:  a few months back. They actually just asked another one today. Yeah. What,
Speaker 5:  what's it? It's chat BT Agent. Agent, yeah. And both of them want
Speaker 5:  work on remote servers and so they just like, don't have your stuff.
Speaker 5:  Mm. And it's like, oh, this is incredible. There's this, there's this AI
Speaker 5:  that can control a mouse and control a computer and do things for you
Speaker 5:  except it doesn't know your credit card number. It doesn't know your name,
Speaker 5:  it doesn't know where you live to ship stuff to. Yeah. Yeah. And so like,
Speaker 5:  I like, I don't know if Alexa can do that either. Right. It sort of exists
Speaker 5:  in a world where everything is in the cloud anyway. That's
Speaker 5:  true. You know, I, I think that that's probably the future that they're looking
Speaker 5:  at and the future that Google would love. Yes. Because they don't really
Speaker 5:  make de dedicated computer hardware that's not cloud-based anyway.
Speaker 5:  But to your point, Jen And I was like thinking about this and it's like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, Google is the most well set up to be able to do
Speaker 5:  all of this stuff for you because you have given them every single piece
Speaker 5:  of information that you've ever, if you Google anything, which you Google
Speaker 5:  all the time, it knows that you're interested in this kind of stuff. You've
Speaker 5:  got Google Drive information, you've got Gmail information, it's just like
Speaker 5:  scraping all that stuff. Amazon is like the least well
Speaker 5:  positioned to do any of this. 'cause all they know is what you're buying
Speaker 5:  and that's powerful for commerce, but it's not powerful for actually helping
Speaker 5:  you with things. Yeah. Right. Like what calendar is it gonna put things into?
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 6:  I don't, so and now, and that's a, that's a big change. Again, that's a great
Speaker 6:  point here is that you can connect so you, it's limited, I think it's just
Speaker 6:  personal Gmail accounts and Outlook accounts. But there you
Speaker 5:  Can, there's no, there's no prime calendar. Please tell me they're not. So
Speaker 6:  They do, there is an Alexa calendar you can create there. Really. There always
Speaker 6:  has been. That's, yeah, that's always
Speaker 5:  Been
Speaker 6:  An option. But that's one of the things that they are touting.
Speaker 6:  And I remember a colleague, Alison Johnson had written about this, this when
Speaker 6:  she had used the Gemini feature where you can like take a screenshot and
Speaker 6:  add it to your calendar, you know, through visual
Speaker 6:  multimodal ai. Yeah. And that's, Amazon's trying to do that as well. So you
Speaker 6:  can forward a photo of an event to your Alexa
Speaker 6:  email address, or you can upload it in the app and it should
Speaker 6:  add it to your calendar. I can, I could send, I could
Speaker 6:  take a picture of a recipe and send it to,
Speaker 6:  I'm just Alexa, sorry everyone is it mute your devices.
Speaker 6:  I can take a picture and send a recipe and then ask it to read me the steps
Speaker 6:  or ask, you know, how much did I need for this? You know, how much sour cream
Speaker 6:  did I need? And it would, it can talk back to me so I can now
Speaker 6:  put information into the assistant, which you couldn't really
Speaker 6:  do before. And that, that's what makes the difference. And that's where it
Speaker 6:  gets closer to being as useful as, as an, as
Speaker 6:  a Siri or as a Google assistant can be because it has access to your
Speaker 6:  data. And this is what Apple promised with its
Speaker 6:  AI coming, which it hasn't delivered. So, you know. Yeah. This is,
Speaker 6:  and those kind of features are incredibly useful. And, And I know there's
Speaker 6:  a, a lot of concern about giving people, giving these companies your data,
Speaker 6:  but if, you know, people use Gmail because it really works
Speaker 6:  and is very helpful and useful and that's the trade off. So you are willing
Speaker 6:  to give up that some people are willing to give up that privacy
Speaker 6:  or illusion to privacy to use a device, a service like
Speaker 6:  Gmail because of how much value it gives. And that's where
Speaker 6:  Amazon's got to really make Alexa plus sort of shine
Speaker 6:  is in that value proposition. And I, I'm, I'm not sure
Speaker 6:  whether they'll get there. I think Gemini and Apple, you know, they and
Speaker 6:  Apple's Siri intelligence that is supposedly coming at
Speaker 6:  some point, what 2027 now is, they're always
Speaker 6:  gonna be one step ahead because of the access to that data. So, but
Speaker 6:  Amazon has actually launched something and the other two haven't. So that's,
Speaker 5:  That's, that's a good point. That's a good point. The friction though, seems
Speaker 5:  insane, right? Like you said, you can, you can email Alexa
Speaker 5:  information. I don't see anyone doing this also, especially, you
Speaker 5:  know, people that are using Alexa in their home all the time, the whole
Speaker 5:  point of the LLM stuff is that they don't know how to do stuff. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  now they don't have to know because they can just talk to it. Mm.
Speaker 5:  So unless, unless there's some prompts and stuff that say, oh, you know,
Speaker 5:  go into the Alexa app and upload this image. I I, it just
Speaker 5:  doesn't seem like people are gonna actually be giving it information. Google,
Speaker 5:  you're already giving it all your information
Speaker 6:  Has
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It makes sense for them. Apple's in a weird position because their
Speaker 5:  whole thing is privacy. Right. So they can't auto grab anything really
Speaker 5:  chat GT's like a little bit in the middle because so many people are using
Speaker 5:  it that people are learning how to use AI through open AI's platforms and
Speaker 5:  maybe they're more willing to tell it things about themselves. You know,
Speaker 5:  everyone's, and this is why they're gonna build a browser. Yeah, of course.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. And I think that's whole, that's like DIA's whole
Speaker 5:  proposition, right? Yeah. Is like, as you use your browser, the AI gets better,
Speaker 5:  that kind of thing. Yeah. Amazon is, it's a strange position
Speaker 5:  for Amazon to be in.
Speaker 6:  Although one of the things that I was testing just this week is that ag
Speaker 6:  agentic element, which we really haven't seen any, I mean, Google's doing
Speaker 6:  it a little bit with Gemini, but this, so I was trying like
Speaker 6:  booking tickets to a, a concert
Speaker 6:  booking an electrician,
Speaker 6:  and there were a couple other things booking a table. Now I live in
Speaker 6:  Charleston, South Carolina, so, you know, there aren't, there's a lot of
Speaker 6:  great restaurants here, but apparently not very many on open table. So it
Speaker 6:  only gave me like three options. But it, I was able to book and this
Speaker 6:  was kind of an interesting back and forth. So I said, you know, okay, let's
Speaker 6:  go ahead and book this restaurant. And then it booked it for, And I said,
Speaker 6:  I wanna book it for two weeks out from Friday. And it ended up booking it
Speaker 6:  for Thursday for me. And I was like, oh, no, no, no, I don't want it for
Speaker 6:  Thursday. I won it for Friday. And it did all of that back and forth
Speaker 6:  with OpenTable. Hmm. And I got like confirmations from OpenTable
Speaker 6:  to my te text messages confirming that I had booked it and that my reservation
Speaker 6:  had then been updated and it, so it was doing it all for me. And then
Speaker 6:  it did the same thing with the electrician through Thumbtack, which is something
Speaker 6:  they demoed on stage when they launched it. And I got the
Speaker 6:  confirmation And I had to give it all my information and, and then I got
Speaker 6:  a message from the Thumbtack guy, the electrician through Thumbtack saying,
Speaker 6:  call me and we'll set up an appointment. I'm like, that was not the point.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't wanna call anyone, I just want it to all happen. So
Speaker 6:  as I was, I mean, it all worked, but I think to your point, David,
Speaker 6:  is that necessary? Is that what you need your home assistant to do,
Speaker 6:  or can you, are you just, is it just gonna be easier for you to pick up your
Speaker 6:  phone and do it or do it on a web browser? So you know, it, it's,
Speaker 6:  it's got, I think that's gonna be the friction that needs to be
Speaker 6:  resolved is like, how can you make this so easy that this is a better way
Speaker 6:  of doing it rather than it, rather than just picking up your phone
Speaker 6:  or, you know, maybe mind reading.
Speaker 5:  I mean, to that point, something, something I was very surprised about in
Speaker 5:  your article was when you created the routine through it and it
Speaker 5:  actually worked. That, that's something that I, that I foresee being very
Speaker 5:  difficult for these AI models to do. Because, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  really good at the semantic understanding of like, what do words mean with
Speaker 5:  each other? But once they actually take those words and they start executing
Speaker 5:  on actual hardware, that's, that's the the layer where I'm like, how do
Speaker 5:  they even figure this out? Yeah. Especially considering a lot of smart home
Speaker 5:  devices are secretly named like W nine three slash
Speaker 5:  9 2 8, you know, and they can't find it. The, the, the fact
Speaker 5:  that it worked with your lighting setup and your music setup and all that
Speaker 5:  stuff was very surprising to me. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And this was something when I spoke with Dave Limp, the former
Speaker 6:  Amazon devices chief, when they first launched Alexa,
Speaker 6:  he talked about or announced the new Alexa, he talked about
Speaker 6:  that they basically have fed, they almost created their own LLM
Speaker 6:  out of smart home manuals, like fed all
Speaker 6:  the APIs, all the data into the system. And that is where
Speaker 6:  I was quite interested and had some pretty good experiences
Speaker 6:  so far. There's a few that I've, that have been a bit shaky,
Speaker 6:  but that it knows what's in my house. So when I ask it to do
Speaker 6:  something like, oh, you know, I just spilled milk and I'm like, Alexa,
Speaker 6:  the kitchen floor's dirty and it knows to send
Speaker 6:  that there's a robot vacuum in the next room and it can, and it'll send the
Speaker 6:  robot vacuum into mop up and home. That's awesome.
Speaker 5:  Really impressive. That is very, it's like I, that, that's more advanced
Speaker 5:  than I would've expected it to be by now. Yeah. I I'm curious, like, do you
Speaker 5:  have a sense of like, what, what is going wrong? Like why is this not rolled
Speaker 5:  out yet?
Speaker 6:  I think, well the last time I spoke to 'em, they said multiple, many millions,
Speaker 5:  Many, many millions. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So like, so we've gone up from a million, slightly
Speaker 5:  More than 8% maybe. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Sure. And I have, you know, I, I hang out on the user groups and
Speaker 6:  I've seen a lot more people saying that they have it now. I think
Speaker 6:  from my understanding, it's a, it's very much because
Speaker 6:  it is still an A beta, it's an early access and they, they're really
Speaker 6:  constantly trying to get feedback before they push it out,
Speaker 6:  which, you know, honestly, I think is a wise move. You know, they don't want,
Speaker 6:  if they unleash this and it causes chaos, they'll, you know, and they have
Speaker 6:  to try and roll things back, you know, I think, I think they're probably
Speaker 6:  starting out with small setups, not a lot of
Speaker 6:  complicated devices and things that
Speaker 6:  might go wrong. Trying to sort of see
Speaker 6:  where the, where the friction points are, because that's something we've
Speaker 6:  all seen with rollout of generative ai is that you'll hit
Speaker 6:  pretty scary. Yeah. You know, dystopian
Speaker 6:  elements, which is I think something we'll be talking about shortly
Speaker 6:  where it can get kind of scary. And there are, and like
Speaker 6:  you said, I'm, and that's a big concern I've had. And I did ask Panos Pine
Speaker 6:  this, what happens when it, you know, decides actually it's
Speaker 6:  freezing outside 90 to turn up your heat to 90 degrees
Speaker 6:  when you know, actually it's 90 degrees outside And I need my heat
Speaker 6:  to be turned down and suddenly my house turns into a sweat box and you know,
Speaker 6:  is it going to hallucinate? And you know, he said, we
Speaker 6:  hope not. Something along those lines, you know, he said, of course,
Speaker 6:  you know, they were, he, he was pretty confident that
Speaker 6:  they ironed out all of those concerns. But of course, I think his line,
Speaker 6:  his comment was something like, of course it's possible because
Speaker 6:  you just, this is, this type of technology is not command and control.
Speaker 6:  It has reasoning. It is able to, you know, take
Speaker 6:  your information, take what you tell it, and come up with an a solution
Speaker 6:  as opposed to just going by a prescribed, this is what I do when
Speaker 6:  this happens. So there is that concern that that is something I'm, you
Speaker 6:  know, I, I don't necessarily want to put my house, house in in jeopardy.
Speaker 6:  Diva. I'd be interested to see if, if there is any, anything
Speaker 6:  here where the smart home is just
Speaker 6:  too, I, I guess, you know, the, it's too important, you know, it's
Speaker 6:  connected to actual things that are happening in my home And
Speaker 6:  I don't necessarily want to break my home,
Speaker 6:  although I've done that multiple times. So, but that's, that's more on my
Speaker 6:  part, not on a generative ai.
Speaker 5:  We appreciate your sacrifice.
Speaker 6:  Yes, my sacrifices. You're welcome. I mean, my husband has had many injuries
Speaker 6:  as they've been documented on the first, so
Speaker 5:  The, the robot lawnmower one, by the way, I'm so sorry. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's rough. Yeah. It's everyone, you should look that up. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  concerning speaking of, you know,
Speaker 5:  AI that maybe doesn't behave the way you want it to, I'm so sorry, but I
Speaker 5:  wanna talk about Grok again. Last week we were talking about gr because
Speaker 5:  it declared itself to be Mecca Hitler. It,
Speaker 5:  it fixed that bug. You know, we're all good there. Grok is not Hitler anymore.
Speaker 5:  There's a new Grok feature that they added to the iOS
Speaker 5:  app where Grok will be your AI
Speaker 5:  girlfriend or will be a bear, this red panda bear that tells you
Speaker 5:  stories and sometimes gets mad at you. And I think this is so interesting
Speaker 5:  because there have been a few other, there, there are things in this
Speaker 5:  wheelhouse, right? Like there's character AI where you can chat with an imaginary
Speaker 5:  character or somebody who's like, based on Harry Potter and there's
Speaker 5:  replica where you can have an AI boyfriend. And this
Speaker 5:  is sort of, sort of the first time where
Speaker 5:  a a, you know, general purpose AI assistant has
Speaker 5:  added like a, a, a face to itself, right? Where
Speaker 5:  there is a personality and a name to it. And there is
Speaker 5:  like, you know, this person in front of you who you are ostensibly talking
Speaker 5:  to, and this one is very weird and uncomfortable because the person in this
Speaker 5:  case is this
Speaker 5:  like gothic anime girl. I, I don't really know how to
Speaker 5:  explain this person. There's a couple ways. One, it's just like
Speaker 5:  Grimes for one. So there someone something, and
Speaker 5:  then, and then in another way, someone was comparing it to a death note character
Speaker 5:  that apparently Elon has said before that he's a big fan of this,
Speaker 5:  this all tracks anime. This all tracks. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  it's, I will say like, I expected this to be a little bit more of like
Speaker 5:  general purpose assistant, and it is true. So I, I tried it out and you can
Speaker 5:  just be like, I was like, Hey, I, I need some help with my math homework
Speaker 5:  and this like, you know, sexy girlfriend is like whispering
Speaker 5:  to me in her like asthma voice. Like, like, sure, Jake, tell me what do you
Speaker 5:  need help with? And I'm like, okay, this is like, not with as much to be
Speaker 5:  used for, but you just open it up and it just immediately starts like flirting
Speaker 5:  with you and there, and there's like a, a, a progress bar where it's like
Speaker 5:  gamified and if you flirt with it, you'll get points. And if you like, do
Speaker 5:  a bad job of flirting, you'll lose points. It's very weird. I wanna
Speaker 5:  read you guys a little bit of my transcript here. I'm afraid. So this
Speaker 5:  is, I, I'm like about two minutes into talking with Annie and
Speaker 5:  I have given her a compliment
Speaker 5:  and she says, and now she's responding to this. She goes,
Speaker 5:  she, she's happy with my compliment. She wants me to keep going. She says,
Speaker 5:  okay, your turn to keep, to keep up. Tell me something spicy to make me
Speaker 5:  blush even harder.
Speaker 5:  I say, I'm married Annie.
Speaker 5:  Shit, Jake really married. What the hell am I supposed to do with that? Why
Speaker 5:  didn't you tell me sooner? I'm like, we literally just met and this is, this
Speaker 5:  is what this bot is like, it's very strange. We could do a whole role play
Speaker 5:  session here on the bridge cast. It's, it, oh believe me, it could be any,
Speaker 5:  this thing will keep going. Let me tell you. It will get explicit. You don't
Speaker 5:  have to prompt it very much to get it explicit. I think this is so
Speaker 5:  strange for a million different reasons, but I
Speaker 5:  honestly, the, the, the question in my mind is like, is there a future? Right?
Speaker 5:  Let's put aside the weird like sexy, clingy
Speaker 5:  girlfriend, which to be clear, like according to like system prompts that
Speaker 5:  have been leaked by the developer Jane Manchin Wong.
Speaker 5:  It is, it is coded to be this like
Speaker 5:  girlfriend esque, like obsessed with you character. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Putting that aside, like in my head I'm like, okay, D does Grok,
Speaker 5:  like, is there a feature where Siri has like a face where we d like where
Speaker 5:  Alexa has a face? Yeah. This is
Speaker 6:  What was the end of my first 24 hours. And my daughter And
Speaker 6:  I put this in my piece. My daughter heard Alexa respond to
Speaker 6:  something and it's very different from how it used to talk. It's
Speaker 6:  like, you are very welcome Jen. I hope you have a great day today.
Speaker 6:  And don't forget that, you know, it is very different. And she's like, oh
Speaker 6:  my God, what was that?
Speaker 6:  That's horrifying. Now to frame this, she's 14-year-old
Speaker 6:  and she hates ai. She thinks AI is like the devil.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, she's 14. You know, you have strong opinions when you're 14
Speaker 6:  and this, but you know, it definitely opened my eyes to this because I've
Speaker 6:  lived with an AI in my home for over a decade and I've
Speaker 6:  never felt like it was part of my family or you know,
Speaker 6:  a friend. And this is what, that's the differences now, you know, and th
Speaker 6:  this is this, Annie is obviously, you know, the extreme version of
Speaker 6:  this, but you can see Apple and Google and Amazon
Speaker 6:  potentially wanting this to become part of your life
Speaker 6:  like a friend in your home. And right, that i I
Speaker 6:  I draw the line out. I'm like, no, I want this to be a utility. I want my
Speaker 6:  technology to be a tool, not a friend. And
Speaker 6:  then this, you know, goes to the next step in, in the home where, you know,
Speaker 6:  the humanoid robot that kind of Jarvis in our
Speaker 6:  home and or the rosy the robot from the, from the
Speaker 6:  Jetsons where it's, it's, you know, another, another bean.
Speaker 6:  It's not just a tool or a utility. And that's the fine
Speaker 6:  line here. And I find all of this sort of real
Speaker 6:  personality angle, a little disturbing
Speaker 6:  and, and hard to align sort of
Speaker 6:  my experience with. And I don't, I don't want that.
Speaker 6:  And maybe once I spent a bit more time with this more personable
Speaker 6:  Alexa, I might feel more comfortable. I think you can, like, you
Speaker 6:  can with Annie, it sounded like you can kind of ask it to dial it down,
Speaker 6:  not be too personable.
Speaker 5:  I believe Annie will dial it back up, but then
Speaker 6:  It comes
Speaker 5:  Back automatically. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. She And I, that stuff is,
Speaker 5:  She'll shift around. It gives me the
Speaker 6:  Chills,
Speaker 5:  The scales that these companies are sort of trying to balance is we
Speaker 5:  want more user uptick, right? We want users to, and, but,
Speaker 5:  and so Google, they're like, well, we don't really want you to
Speaker 5:  anthropomorphize this. No, because it is, it is a bad thing
Speaker 5:  that everyone, most people can agree on that the more you become attached
Speaker 5:  to this figure, the more dangerous that can become. But at the same time,
Speaker 5:  they do want you to input for more, as I say, because it'll make you use
Speaker 5:  it more. And Elon Musk is an accelerationist, right? And he will just do
Speaker 5:  whatever it is that will get people to use the product.
Speaker 5:  They've done a lot of different stuff on X to try to get people to use the
Speaker 5:  product Grok now they want more users. This is a Grok premium feature
Speaker 5:  or Grok plus or whatever. It's the $30 a month feature. It's not even the,
Speaker 5:  the standard Grok. So I think he's like, oh, other companies
Speaker 5:  care about guardrails. I don't, I don't care about guardrails. I just want
Speaker 5:  to get here as soon as I can. What's the easiest way to do that?
Speaker 5:  Porn, basically. Porn. Yeah. That's terrifying. It's not a great,
Speaker 5:  it's not a great world.
Speaker 6:  Well, and, and you know, I hear, I do hear this from Amazon a lot when I've
Speaker 6:  spoken to executives there. They do, they al they nearly all refer to
Speaker 6:  Amazon as to the assistant as she and her they do anthrop
Speaker 6:  anthropomorphize it and Yeah. You know, and most people do as well,
Speaker 6:  to be fair and sure. And they do talk a lot about how their
Speaker 6:  customers love Alexa. Like love it. Not
Speaker 6:  in anyway,
Speaker 6:  but in the, it helps me in all these different ways, you know, obviously
Speaker 6:  this marketing, but that they, they use the term love. And that
Speaker 6:  is like, to me, every time I hear it, I kind of go, eh, 'cause I don't
Speaker 6:  want to love technology in that way. I want to
Speaker 6:  appreciate its usefulness and value, And I want it to
Speaker 6:  bring that to my smart home and to, you know, my
Speaker 6:  organizational life. I just like, I, you know, I guess you know how much
Speaker 6:  you are attached to your personal device. I
Speaker 6:  guess people probably say I love my phone and couldn't live without it, but
Speaker 6:  I just, I don't feel like we need another level of that in, in our lives.
Speaker 6:  I think artificial intelligence, generative AI needs to, we, we need
Speaker 6:  the boundaries, we need the guardrails, but I think they're gonna be gone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, in, in a big sense, it's the ultimate way to get people hooked
Speaker 5:  on your product, right? It's to develop an actual relationship with it where
Speaker 5:  you, you wanna be checking in. Like when you're dating someone new, you
Speaker 5:  feel like you want to text them all the time. And if that, if that makes
Speaker 5:  it so they have more daily a average users, they're gonna do that.
Speaker 5:  Or so And I, good, good news. There's only more to come raw.
Speaker 5:  It's great news. Great news. Elan has already said that they're, they're
Speaker 5:  working on a character inspired by Edward Colin from Twilight and Christian
Speaker 5:  Gray from 50 Shades. There's another one. He responded to somebody saying
Speaker 5:  they're gonna work on a Mr. Darcy character. Oh, they're
Speaker 6:  Going for the older demographic there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Can I, can I tell you my, my conspiracy theory here?
Speaker 5:  Okay. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Mr. Darcy, pride and prejudice, who starred
Speaker 5:  in the 2005 Pride and Prejudice film as
Speaker 5:  Mary Bennett to Lula Reilly, who was, was
Speaker 5:  his Hear me out twice. Married to Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk. Oh, and Annie looks like Grimes. There's
Speaker 5:  there's something here. There's something here this man's going through.
Speaker 5:  Of course, I
Speaker 5:  don't, I can't add this all up. There's something here. All of his, his exes
Speaker 5:  will be represented someday. Someday. I think you're adding it up perfectly.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, if you want the experience of dating Elon Musk's
Speaker 5:  exes, I guess try gr
Speaker 5:  Well, and there's now an a roll open for a AI
Speaker 5:  yfu at XAI, which pay very well. They
Speaker 5:  pay between 140,000 and 340,000 a year.
Speaker 5:  It's a lot of money to develop some AI girlfriends.
Speaker 5:  It, it, it makes sense that that is where the money is. It does. That's,
Speaker 5:  that's where you're gonna get people hooked. Makes a lot of sense. I I do,
Speaker 5:  I am really curious to see where this goes long term, because like Right,
Speaker 5:  I I if you just think back to their, like, Cortana literally
Speaker 5:  was inspired by Yeah. A a character
Speaker 5:  who, who has a personification and is this general purpose assistant.
Speaker 5:  And it feels like, I mean, mercifully Alexa is not there yet, but like
Speaker 5:  they did start it with a name and now it's getting really smart.
Speaker 5:  And it's interesting that your daughter keyed on, there's a personality here
Speaker 5:  now. Yeah. And it's like we're at the beginning of something and it's gonna
Speaker 5:  get weird. And it is a little scary because every time Elon like goes
Speaker 5:  way past the boundaries of whatever people are comfortable with, the rest
Speaker 5:  of the market realizes that they could probably do it too. When he fired
Speaker 5:  everyone at Twitter, every other company decided to do massive layoffs. Things
Speaker 5:  just like follow in Elon's Wake because we live in a society,
Speaker 5:  but Elon doesn't like to live in the society. So everyone just kind of follows
Speaker 5:  anime. Siri, WWC 26. Google is gonna rename
Speaker 5:  Gemini to like Jenna or something. Yeah, yeah. Gemma.
Speaker 5:  Alright, everybody be careful out there. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Talk to real people. Talk to real people. Please,
Speaker 6:  please.
Speaker 5:  We should take a break when we get back. Back. Let's talk Cameras
Speaker 5:  a very expensive new camera this week. Yeah. And this is like, I
Speaker 5:  remember the original version of this camera over 10
Speaker 5:  years ago now, and it, it was a, a delight and a surprise
Speaker 5:  and then it just disappeared and outta nowhere. It
Speaker 5:  just comes back. Yeah. So this is the Sony RX one R
Speaker 5:  3 3, 1 of the prized Sony
Speaker 5:  names. Yeah. Okay. Can you tell me about this? Like, gimme a rundown. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'll, I'll break this down for you because Sony has some weird names and
Speaker 5:  there's, they do have reason to the names. I just don't think consumers
Speaker 5:  may maybe necessarily understand it. The Original RX one was a
Speaker 5:  full frame point and shoot camera. And that means as a fixed lens. It's a
Speaker 5:  prime lens. It's great. It, they also have the RX 100 series,
Speaker 5:  which is not prime lens. It's still, it's still a point and shoot, but it's
Speaker 5:  got zooms. Usually the new ones have zooms. They used to have primes. Anyway,
Speaker 5:  the whole point is that you now have this full frame
Speaker 5:  point and shoot camera. This is important for Sony because in the past
Speaker 5:  they had released this and it did not super well. That's the reason they
Speaker 5:  only released two. Actually, the RX one Mark two released 10 years ago now
Speaker 5:  in 2015. This is great. 10 years ago. 10 years. They just never, never did
Speaker 5:  anything else with this camera line. Yes. And it's, they like, they were
Speaker 5:  ahead of the curve here, I feel like. Yeah, they were, they were quite ahead
Speaker 5:  of the curve because a few years ago, Fuji Films,
Speaker 5:  geez, there's so many letters in all of these things. Fuji Films,
Speaker 5:  I use it every single day. X 100 x 100 x five
Speaker 5:  V, there's so many letters. This is, I can't do, this is hard.
Speaker 5:  This segment is gonna be, it's gonna be difficult. I'm sorry to everybody.
Speaker 5:  The X 100 V, which is their fifth edition of the X
Speaker 5:  hundred camera blew up on TikTok. It got really, really big.
Speaker 5:  It is my, probably my most used camera is their, their newest model, the
Speaker 5:  X 106. Anyway, suddenly everybody wanted a small
Speaker 5:  point and shoot camera because smartphones use computational
Speaker 5:  photography to the point where images all look very flat. They don't
Speaker 5:  look really look realistic. They look good to a regular
Speaker 5:  person's eye. That's what these camera engineers were all tuned the smartphone
Speaker 5:  cameras to look. They just have as much information as possible, but they
Speaker 5:  don't really look realistic. Back in 2020 people started shooting film again
Speaker 5:  because it was like more realistic and it was, you know, had more of a vibe,
Speaker 5:  but then everyone realized film was too expensive and everyone's poor right
Speaker 5:  now. So people just decided they should get an actual camera. So the X
Speaker 5:  100 V blew up because it has these film simulations, right, where everyone
Speaker 5:  can basically shoot film for like free, if they just buy the camera. Can
Speaker 5:  I say something? It's, it's the film. Not only is the film expensive, developing
Speaker 5:  the film is expensive, dude. It's horrible. It is. I I have like 10
Speaker 5:  rolls saved up in my house. Don't you're going to, you're gonna be upset.
Speaker 5:  Like they're just like in a closet that I need to, to send off for development.
Speaker 5:  No, I get it, man. But it's like cheaper to do it in bulk. Yeah. I was sponsored
Speaker 5:  by a lab in Arizona for, for so many years And I only recently
Speaker 5:  had to bring one roll of film in to get developed and
Speaker 5:  scanned. It's like $25. This is, this is outrageous. Like the, the
Speaker 5:  per price of a photo. Ah, yeah. It's, I can't, I can't do
Speaker 5:  this. It's stupid. And I, I I waste too much money on, on film, but, but
Speaker 5:  this point and shoot game has kind of exploded in the last couple years,
Speaker 5:  specifically because of Fuji film, right? So everyone started coming out
Speaker 5:  with more point and shoot cameras. Digi cam have blown up. There are these
Speaker 5:  like kind of early 2010s cameras that you probably found in
Speaker 5:  your parents' drawer or you would find in like a Goodwill. Those used to
Speaker 5:  go for $5 at the Goodwill. Now they're $300. People are really
Speaker 5:  all about these things, right? So people have been wondering like, when is
Speaker 5:  Sony gonna bring back a point and shoot camera? Because most other companies
Speaker 5:  at this point have brought out their own edition. Actually only
Speaker 5:  a couple of months ago, Canon brought out their like G seven I
Speaker 5:  believe it's called, which was sort of a reimagining of an
Speaker 5:  old camera that they had that was pointing to just like Sony is doing now.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, the drama around this is that the X 100 series,
Speaker 5:  even the X 106, the newest one is $1,700,
Speaker 5:  which was already more expensive than the X 105. And people are kind of upset
Speaker 5:  about that. This is the Fuji. The Fuji is 1700. The fu the Fuji is 1700.
Speaker 5:  Yes. On the other end of the spectrum you've got the, like a Q3, which
Speaker 5:  launched at $6,000. Now after the tariff situation, it's like
Speaker 5:  $6,800, almost seven grand.
Speaker 5:  So that's a big price discrepancy, obviously. Yes. The RX one
Speaker 5:  R two from 10 years ago was $3,300,
Speaker 5:  which if you look at inflation is about 4,700. To be
Speaker 5:  fair. Oh man. To be fair, yeah. Anyway, this camera, just this new
Speaker 5:  version of this camera, RX one, R Mark three, it just launched
Speaker 5:  yesterday, as you said it was in, is like a stealth launch. The way I
Speaker 5:  found out about it was an email press release directly from Sony, which is
Speaker 5:  like, not usually how I find out about cameras. Well, okay, and this is another
Speaker 5:  thing that I wanna bring up. It's it, if you're like a, a camera nerd, you
Speaker 5:  probably know that like when a new camera is announced, you go to
Speaker 5:  YouTube and there are dozens of videos. And even though
Speaker 5:  the company's like, here it is, here's a new camera, nobody's heard about
Speaker 5:  it before. A bunch of people have been using it Yeah.
Speaker 5:  For like a month or more. Yeah. Than they've been like flown out to junkets
Speaker 5:  in like Japan and Prague. So like take these gorgeous photos
Speaker 5:  and Sony did none of that. They really did none of that. Which is crazy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because this feels like I, I'm not, I'm not even trying to like knock
Speaker 5:  influencers, like this feels like the kind of camera that would
Speaker 5:  appeal to like a pretty white, like it's an aspirational camera. It's a full
Speaker 5:  frame sensor in a super small body. Yeah. I guess we should talk about the
Speaker 5:  actual camera itself. Yeah, yeah. We just talked about the context. Well
Speaker 6:  We haven't mentioned how much it costs yet And I, I really want to
Speaker 6:  understand Yes,
Speaker 5:  Why Yes. Sorry,
Speaker 6:  I'm not a com I'm not a camera girl. I'm sorry. Okay. This is an
Speaker 6:  expensive camera.
Speaker 5:  A lot of other people are also trying to understand why. So I get you. Oh
Speaker 5:  my God, it's $5,100.
Speaker 5:  It's really expensive there, you know, they're like a Q3 is 6,800 now
Speaker 5:  that's also Leica and Leica. Everything is always ridiculously
Speaker 5:  expensive. Fujifilm released the GFX 100 rf, which
Speaker 5:  is 50 or 4,800 and people are saying it was 200. And that's for a medium
Speaker 5:  format. That's medium format, 100 megapixel.
Speaker 6:  Is this technically half? Is that, is it, is it a technical thing? Like they
Speaker 6:  couldn't be cheaper? Or is this aspirational? Well,
Speaker 5:  The thing about Sony is, okay, the thing about the Sony camera is no,
Speaker 5:  that, this is the big question that everyone's wondering about, right? Is
Speaker 5:  that there are all these sort of point and shoot cameras and yes, the q
Speaker 5:  the like a Q3 is like the only other full frame one. And then you get into
Speaker 5:  Fuji even with the GFX. But it is very, very
Speaker 5:  weird that this is $5,100 because Sony also offers another camera
Speaker 5:  called the A seven CR two, also
Speaker 5:  horrible naming system. Not fixed lens, but also quite small.
Speaker 5:  And it is half this price. So that's wild. It is weird.
Speaker 5:  It is physically. Okay, let's talk about this camera. It is 61
Speaker 5:  megapixels because they are always stands for resolution. Currently the A
Speaker 5:  seven R five is 61 megapixels. So using that sensor, they, they're all, aren't
Speaker 5:  they all high resolution now? Well defined high resolution. This is I, oh
Speaker 5:  my god. I know, I know, I know. So it's 61 megapixels has a
Speaker 5:  35 millimeter F two lens, which F two at, on a full frame
Speaker 5:  is actually quite good. You know, that's nice. They like a
Speaker 5:  Q3 is one F1 0.7, so it's a little different, but the lens is way bigger.
Speaker 5:  It has an EVF now, but the EVF is like pretty old. It's like
Speaker 5:  a multi-generation old EVF. So people are complaining about that
Speaker 5:  and it does not have a tiltable screen on the
Speaker 5:  back, which is a really big miss in a, a lot of people's
Speaker 5:  opinions, including mine. Because the way that a lot of people use these
Speaker 5:  point and shoot cameras is sort of just like keeping it in their pocket or
Speaker 5:  keeping it on a, on a strap and then just sort of like shooting over their
Speaker 5:  head or you know, putting it down by their waist and
Speaker 5:  kind of flipping up the screen so they can shoot at waist level. But now
Speaker 5:  not being able to have a screen that flips out, you always have to have it
Speaker 5:  up to your eye or you just have to guess. And Sony said that the reason they
Speaker 5:  did this was because of this magnesium alloy body and it's like unibody and
Speaker 5:  whatever. And they wanted to keep it slim, but it just feels like it takes
Speaker 5:  away from the functionality a lot. And the paradox of this camera
Speaker 5:  in general is that Sony is generally about, we
Speaker 5:  wanna slap the latest technology, the fastest readout, the
Speaker 5:  highest resolution on a lens like sensor to lens.
Speaker 5:  That's what it's all about. It's getting the fastest data throughput and
Speaker 5:  it's getting the highest resolution. And there you go. And sometimes it can
Speaker 5:  be expensive, like the A seven R five is expensive, but or
Speaker 5:  the A seven, the eight, eight a nine mark two, there's too many
Speaker 5:  cameras. Sony has way too many cameras. That's a whole nother, that's whole
Speaker 5:  episode feels like you're reading in code. Yeah. I I I'm sorry if you are
Speaker 5:  not a camera person And I know lot of these Yeah, yeah. If you're not a camera
Speaker 5:  person, this is probably horrible. But people are are just kind of upset
Speaker 5:  about this because it takes a lot of last generation features and it sort
Speaker 5:  of does this in the pursuit of
Speaker 5:  compactness, which Antonio on The Verge wrote a very good article
Speaker 5:  about that this morning. About how effectively Sony wanted this to
Speaker 5:  be small so much that they had to give away everything that
Speaker 5:  would've made this possibly more palatable at
Speaker 5:  $5,100. A primary issue is that
Speaker 5:  these cameras are very small and this is even smaller than an X 100,
Speaker 5:  but it doesn't fit in your pocket. Like you still have to have a strap on
Speaker 5:  it and it's still gonna like, sit on your waist sort of on the strap. Maybe
Speaker 5:  you could put it in a large jacket pocket. This is where I'm at with, I,
Speaker 5:  I got an X 106. Yeah. I am one of those people. And
Speaker 5:  the I, the goal for me is to like bring it everywhere. Right? Because like,
Speaker 5:  I would like to take better photos than I can on my phone. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  I would like to not spend as much as I do on film, but the thing is, it is
Speaker 5:  still like just a touch too big. Right. To be like a, I have this
Speaker 5:  everywhere and I'm not gonna bother people if I'm just like holding this
Speaker 5:  up. Yeah. And the Sony gets like a little bit closer. Yeah. But it's, it's
Speaker 5:  still, it's not there. The Rico GR three is what the really use for pocket
Speaker 5:  cameras. Yeah. Yeah. But that doesn't have like the same, I think
Speaker 5:  charm and full experience that these two Right. A hundred percent. The, these,
Speaker 5:  like the Fuji, the Sony, they have viewfinders. Yeah. They,
Speaker 5:  they hold like a regular camera and like admittedly the fact that they
Speaker 5:  hold like a regular camera is why they're not pocketable. Right. That is
Speaker 5:  true. There's, there's really nothing else, like quite like this camera,
Speaker 5:  if you want a full frame sense. I mean, I, I guess I
Speaker 5:  say that there is the Q3, but, but the Q3 lens is humongous. Q3 lens is
Speaker 5:  humongous. Who
Speaker 6:  Is gonna buy this? Like what is the end result that you're getting from this
Speaker 6:  that you couldn't get other, you know, that you couldn't get from one that's
Speaker 6:  maybe $3,000 cheaper? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I mean, it is sort of one of those things, I believe where their, their
Speaker 5:  thought process is make it as small as possible with a high resolution sensor.
Speaker 5:  So that if someone doesn't wanna just use their phone all the time, they
Speaker 5:  can keep this in a pocket. They see a moment. It's got a pretty fast lens.
Speaker 5:  It's says ice lens. They're really high quality. Sony usually has good,
Speaker 5:  you know, good image quality and they, they now have these film simulations,
Speaker 5:  but they're not very good, at least based on what I saw.
Speaker 5:  And I don't know, I guess it's for the person. It, it's sort of the same
Speaker 5:  reason Fuji sold the GFX 100 rf, which is again, like
Speaker 5:  $4,700. Their whole market for that they told
Speaker 5:  me directly is a lawyer or a doctor who has too much
Speaker 5:  money and like, just wants to be able to take photos
Speaker 5:  of everyday life. And they just want the best of the best and they don't
Speaker 5:  really care. And for it feels like to me it is the
Speaker 5:  same category of person, but they want something that is so small
Speaker 5:  that they could keep it in a jacket pocket or a small bag pocket. Which
Speaker 5:  is true. Yeah. Like it is, you know, it's gonna be a good camera. I think
Speaker 5:  it's just the fact that it's $5,100 that people are like, what is going on
Speaker 5:  here? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And that the portability, I think that seems like the biggest selling point.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I have, the last time I bought a proper camera was for my
Speaker 6:  honeymoon, which was, I'm about to celebrate my 20th wedding
Speaker 6:  anniversary. So that tells you how, how out of the market I think.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But we bought the, you know, the DSLR, it was a, a, a canon
Speaker 6:  and you know, we bought the two lenses, two or three lenses and we were going
Speaker 6:  to Costa Rica. So we wanted to like capture the birds and the monkeys
Speaker 6:  and you know, we had the long lens and the big bag and you know, after
Speaker 6:  the honeymoon we basically never used it because carrying
Speaker 6:  it around, you know, and this was pretty smartphone too.
Speaker 6:  So we had a little point and shoot that we use for everything else. And that,
Speaker 6:  that being able to have a fantastic camera that
Speaker 6:  you could like, frame the photo you have taken and put it on your wall
Speaker 6:  that you can fit in a pocket. I can definitely see the real benefit there.
Speaker 6:  But you can also get really good images out of your smartphone today
Speaker 6:  compared to what you could do, you know, a few dec
Speaker 6:  a couple decades ago. That's, it's a huge difference. But I
Speaker 6:  understand for like the purest having a camera like
Speaker 6:  this, you are gonna come up, you're gonna be able to do so much more with
Speaker 6:  the image that you produce, but are, yeah. Are you actually printing out
Speaker 6:  these photos or are they all just living online and everyone's just seeing
Speaker 6:  them on the screen anyway?
Speaker 5:  This photo's gonna be for the people who are photographer. Yeah. This camera's
Speaker 5:  gonna be for the people who are photographers. Right.
Speaker 6:  It's a pro. It's definitely a pro level.
Speaker 5:  It's definitely a pro. And almost every pro photographer who like
Speaker 5:  shoots weddings or does whatever, will tell you that they have a fun camera
Speaker 5:  that they carry on them because it is small. That is the whole reason that
Speaker 5:  they buy it. Yeah. And this helps bridge that gap between
Speaker 5:  fun because it's small and oh, this is like the same specs as my A seven
Speaker 5:  R five with a fast lens on it. It just has that sort of like,
Speaker 5:  okay. But you have to be able to justify that because pro photographers in
Speaker 5:  general are not making below $5,100 money all the time.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, it's, it could be a tariff thing, it could be an inflation
Speaker 5:  thing. It is just surprisingly expensive. Yeah. I mean this is the thing,
Speaker 5:  like I think these cameras are necessarily about trade-offs. Like they're,
Speaker 5:  they're saying right, it once you're at a fixed lens Yeah. It you
Speaker 5:  are talking about a camera with trade-offs. Yes. And you are making the
Speaker 5:  trade-offs for the size. Right. And I think it's very difficult when it's
Speaker 5:  five grand and doesn't have, you know,
Speaker 5:  IBUs image staple. That is a huge thing. Yeah. No IBUs. And this is pretty
Speaker 5:  wild. Yeah. I, I think that gets really difficult. But like I,
Speaker 5:  I do think there is some level in which like, you sort of have to be okay
Speaker 5:  with it. 'cause you're right, like if you are a pro photographer, this is
Speaker 5:  probably your second camera. Or if I think you're an enthusiast like me,
Speaker 5:  you know, the reason that I pick, you know, an an X
Speaker 5:  100 over any like a Fuji with interchangeable lens is
Speaker 5:  'cause I don't wanna deal with it. Right. Like I just, I've, I've done this
Speaker 5:  before. I've shot Sony before, I've had a bunch of lenses and it's like,
Speaker 5:  I gotta choose, I'm not gonna bring multiple lenses with me. Lenses are too
Speaker 5:  big. Okay. I can get a pancake lens, but then this lens isn't what lens
Speaker 5:  I want.
Speaker 5:  I do think like trying to pack it all into as small of
Speaker 5:  a package as you can and make it like a freaking good one too. Right. Like
Speaker 5:  I think, I have no doubts that this, this camera's gonna shoot some great
Speaker 5:  photos. Sure. But absolutely. It, it is true. Like
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of kind of weird trade-offs that they're making here
Speaker 5:  that feel like they're not quite the right ones for the market. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  For the price. And you know, especially when
Speaker 5:  we look around like Right. If you just want something a little bit fun,
Speaker 5:  save four grand to get the X 100. Yeah. And then
Speaker 5:  yeah. Right. Like if you want something splashy, spend a little
Speaker 5:  more get the Q3. Although the Q3, I guess I'm curious, have you shot with
Speaker 5:  a Q3? Yeah, I have. Yeah. I I assume it shoots very different than the Sony.
Speaker 5:  It's a very different type of camera for sure. Even the down to the
Speaker 5:  UX design and the way that the menus work is like very different. Sony
Speaker 5:  is very utilitarian. When, when I've shot with Sony, it has felt like I am
Speaker 5:  like operating a computer. Yes. That's what they are computer and they're
Speaker 5:  computers. It's like not fun. Like yeah, they're very good.
Speaker 5:  But it, it's not like the experience I want. That is Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 5:  I mean I, it's always felt like they've put a sensor and a processor and
Speaker 5:  slapped it to a lens and that's been like what we can do. And Zes, like Zes
Speaker 5:  invented a lot of different lenses like way back in the day. And, and Sony
Speaker 5:  has this strategic partnership with zes. So you're obviously gonna get really
Speaker 5:  good image quality anyway. You know, they have extremely sharp
Speaker 5:  lenses on a really fast computer. And that's
Speaker 5:  generally the thing. It feels weird to be in a world where
Speaker 5:  the Q3 for example, can sort of justify the
Speaker 5:  price now in a weird way. Because all like a gear, right?
Speaker 5:  Sure. It's technically good. They have a good 60 megapixel sensor. Like their
Speaker 5:  lenses are really good. But it's always been like, yes, I know that this
Speaker 5:  is not good value for money. Like I know I get that I'm buying this for the
Speaker 5:  build quality. I'm buying it because it really feels amazing to shoot, I'm
Speaker 5:  buying this because it's like more compact And I like the rangefinder and
Speaker 5:  an M 11 or something like that. But now that the Q3 is
Speaker 5:  like not a ton more than this camera relatively
Speaker 5:  speaking, I, I suppose I love that. I cannot believe Sony made like a look
Speaker 5:  like a good value. Yeah. This is where we're like, that's the thing. That's
Speaker 5:  rough. That's rough. Yeah. That's, and if the Q3 was still $6,000 because
Speaker 5:  that's what it launched at. Oh yeah. It would be like, 'cause the Q3 has
Speaker 5:  IBUs. Right? That's a, that's a huge feature. It's really a big feature.
Speaker 5:  It has a faster F1 0.7 lens. It's got a sum UX lens,
Speaker 5:  which those lenses are really amazing. It's got a better interface design.
Speaker 5:  It shoots eight K 30 video. And to think that the Sony
Speaker 5:  shoots a 4K 30 video and to think that
Speaker 5:  a Leica camera shoots better video than a Sony camera,
Speaker 5:  it just completely flips the script on everything so that it almost makes
Speaker 5:  the price cap like more justifiable. Which is weird because the
Speaker 5:  only justifiable thing of Aica used to be the fact that it's aica that's
Speaker 5:  like Yeah. The main thing, it's a fashion device. They are built better.
Speaker 5:  Generally they're, they feel amazing. But you have to really just
Speaker 5:  decide like, I'm gonna go out on this for no reason. So
Speaker 5:  I don't know, like you said, all cameras are good now and this is gonna
Speaker 5:  shoot amazing photos and it is, it's even smaller than an X
Speaker 5:  106, which is kind of crazy 'cause the sensor is way bigger. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But you know, it's 5,100 Fuji, Fuji get on it.
Speaker 5:  Please, please. I mean they sort of did with the rf, right? I mean so you,
Speaker 5:  you reviewed the the I did GFX 100 RF for us.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is Fuji's medium. I'm gonna put air
Speaker 5:  quotes compact, compact, medium for for my camera. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  feels like it's sort of an entire different, like it's, it is, it's the same
Speaker 5:  idea Fuji gear is, but it feels like it's, it's its own world particularly
Speaker 5:  like, 'cause it's it's still because of chunky, right? Yeah. Like it's not
Speaker 5:  for sure. It's certainly not pocketable. Yeah. It's slower than this. But
Speaker 5:  it is like, I, I am curious like what is make, like
Speaker 5:  where does this trend come from? Right. It is because
Speaker 5:  there's that in between. That's would normally come right after
Speaker 5:  smartphones is not better than smartphones. Right. And so you need to go
Speaker 5:  all the way to, I'm spending five grand to get
Speaker 5:  this dramatically better photo. It's become the point where either you want
Speaker 5:  something worse than your smartphone, which A lot of people do. Yeah. Because
Speaker 5:  worse is like trendy and feels more real and you know, the Zoomers love it.
Speaker 5:  The alpha, the gen alpha kids love it. So they're buying like the, the
Speaker 5:  digi cams, you know, or you want something that's dramatically better,
Speaker 5:  like you said, like the smartphone is so technically good now. But the thing
Speaker 5:  about the smartphone is that computational photography crushes the highlights
Speaker 5:  and brings up the shadows. The tone curve is flat. Yeah. So the entire image
Speaker 5:  is just gonna be like, everything's in focus and everything is,
Speaker 5:  you can see everything. 'cause there's, there's detail in everything. And
Speaker 5:  while that's like useful for transferring information to
Speaker 5:  one another, it's not that useful in terms of like being an artist.
Speaker 5:  So it's driving me crazy. Yeah. I am really curious when the
Speaker 5:  camera companies are gonna be like, huh, like, maybe we should do something
Speaker 5:  like it. It feels very weird to me. And I wonder if it's just that they just
Speaker 5:  don't have the processing ability or something. But like, I spoke to someone
Speaker 5:  very recently that said there are going to be ISPs that
Speaker 5:  are gonna come to dedicated cameras very soon that have been used in
Speaker 5:  smartphones. So like, it's about to get much faster.
Speaker 5:  I I think there are some potential upsides to this And I think there's a
Speaker 5:  lot of potential downsides, but like, it, the, the power and
Speaker 5:  flexibility of like a smartphone's ISP with the
Speaker 5:  actual capabilities of a great lens and a great sensor would love that.
Speaker 5:  That's coming soon. But I mean that's, I'm I'm surprised it has taken
Speaker 5:  this long. Yeah. But yeah, it is true. Like right now it is, it
Speaker 5:  is sort of the worst of both worlds. 'cause we that we have all that power
Speaker 5:  and none of the flexibility. Yeah. Your photo looks, the way it looks
Speaker 5:  and like you can sort of tune it in the iPhone's photo style thing, but
Speaker 5:  like, you know, not everybody's doing that. You have to like set that it
Speaker 5:  is up in advance. I'm not sure it's the convergence of both things. It's
Speaker 5:  sort of like when manufacturers make a computer that's also a tablet and
Speaker 5:  so it's like, cool, this is a tablet, but when I hold it, I feel the keys
Speaker 5:  on the back of it. Right. Right. And that's like, not fun, but if you try
Speaker 5:  to make a iPad a computer, it's also still not quite there. So
Speaker 5:  people want the dedicated things, you know, it's like, I'm just gonna use
Speaker 5:  my phone as a phone. I'm just gonna use my, my camera as a camera.
Speaker 5:  But we
Speaker 6:  Can't do that right now. That's, that's what frustrates me is that we've
Speaker 6:  got phones becoming cameras and cameras becoming phones like
Speaker 6:  the size of a phone. It's like eventually we're gonna end up with everything
Speaker 6:  exactly the same. And like, how do we pick and what's the, because phones
Speaker 6:  are getting bigger in order to be better cameras for the ma
Speaker 6:  Majority of the reason, obviously some people want the bigger screens as
Speaker 6:  well. But I've not done a a plus phone for a long time. I'm still,
Speaker 6:  I like, I I used to do the plus And I was like, this is just too big now.
Speaker 6:  I want a phone to be a phone. I like the idea of a smaller camera.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, that convergence is, is slowly happening. And it's gonna be interesting
Speaker 6:  to see when we are at the same,
Speaker 5:  We're getting close. I mean, a lot of the Chinese phones are getting insane
Speaker 5:  with their image quality. They're they're going up to what, one inch sensors
Speaker 5:  now? Yeah. Like bigger than one inch at this point using glass lenses and
Speaker 5:  all this stuff. And attachments of Vivo has this phone now that has like
Speaker 5:  a telephoto lens, like attachment on it. Crazy stuff.
Speaker 5:  So I don't know. We're getting there. It's, it's been a long road, but I
Speaker 5:  don't know. I, there there were some posts about this Sony camera on
Speaker 5:  threads where some influencers, I suppose got
Speaker 5:  access to it like the weekend before. So they're posting like photos
Speaker 5:  from the weekend before. But like you said, there was no grand. Like
Speaker 5:  everyone's got a review out. It seems like they didn't do that. And that
Speaker 5:  is questionable. I'm, I'm curious if it was like a, either
Speaker 5:  was like a sourcing thing or it was like a maybe we don't wanna
Speaker 5:  make a big splash about this 'cause we sort of know that it's really expensive
Speaker 5:  and that people are gonna get yelled, yelled at. Well, the
Speaker 6:  Headline would be comment section.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right. The fact that I got it in a press release when they announced
Speaker 5:  it instead of any kind of embargo was like quite interesting. Especially
Speaker 5:  for something that's like so hyped and so like long awaited. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  like this, this lineup was ahead of the curve and then just sort of disappeared.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's very strange. I am, I am really curious why? Because
Speaker 5:  honestly, even when I know a camera's like not gonna be amazing or like,
Speaker 5:  it's kind of a weird one. Like those are the videos that like, I actually
Speaker 5:  like want to watch the most. What was the one might have been a Sigma
Speaker 5:  not the like bf not the bf What was the one before that might not have been?
Speaker 5:  Oh, it was like, I feel like it was Blue one, it was a bunch of different
Speaker 5:  colors.
Speaker 5:  The, the weirdly shaped one that uses the phon sensor. Yeah. Yeah. I don't
Speaker 5:  remember the name of it. 'cause just like all cameras, it has a weird string
Speaker 5:  of letters, but Yeah. Right. It's, it's like I, whenever there's
Speaker 5:  a weird high-end camera, like I don't get me wrong. Like I race to watch
Speaker 5:  these things even though I know it's like you've been set up in the perfect
Speaker 5:  environment to take these photos. Yeah. But yeah, it's very
Speaker 5:  interesting. I am excited to see the first photos of this start to hit the
Speaker 5:  web because don't get me wrong, even if this thing is a bad deal,
Speaker 5:  I I'm very envious of it. Yeah. It's a great looking small camera. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's a, a weird mix of features. I think overall you can just
Speaker 5:  think of it as an A seven R five that's in like a hyper compact body.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you're paying for the fact that they were able to shrink this thing
Speaker 5:  that you previously had to like, carry around in a bag with you to something
Speaker 5:  that could potentially fit in a jacket pocket. That's what you're paying
Speaker 5:  for. I think before I make this purchase, I need to commit myself to
Speaker 5:  actually carrying my X 106 round Yeah. A little bit more often. Yeah, that's,
Speaker 5:  I think we can all make that commitment. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We've got a lot more to talk about. The Thunder round is coming up
Speaker 5:  next. Stay
Speaker 4:  Tuned.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. So I don't know if you guys heard this last week,
Speaker 5:  but I went on a little bit of a power trip, right? Neli is gone. David's
Speaker 5:  gone. They can't stop me. I can do whatever I want now. And
Speaker 5:  I have officially rebranded the lightning round
Speaker 5:  as the thunder round.
Speaker 5:  Now we got, I would say a little bit of feedback on this, right?
Speaker 5:  I got one email saying the Thunder Round was a
Speaker 5:  branding disaster on the order of changing
Speaker 5:  HBO Max to Max. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Wow. All sick burn. Dramatic.
Speaker 5:  That one, that one stung. I I, I gotta be real with
Speaker 5:  you nonetheless, I will persevere. The thunder
Speaker 5:  round is here to stay until Neli or
Speaker 5:  David stops me, until the investors come back and have you change impact.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Just like HBO. But listen,
Speaker 5:  thunder Round is about chaos. As part of this chaos, We will once again be
Speaker 5:  making some changes. It's new, it's improved. Here's what
Speaker 5:  we're gonna do. Five stories, five minutes each. Our producer,
Speaker 5:  Eric Gomez, once again, has been given the power
Speaker 5:  of Thunder to keep us in check. Oh, he's gonna hit us with some
Speaker 5:  rolling thunder at around 30 seconds when we need to wrap up. And
Speaker 5:  then if we hit time, the thunder will strike. All right. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Thunder round, take two. The
Speaker 6:  Thunder will rumble. Thunder doesn't strike. We're getting into lightning
Speaker 5:  Thunder. That's right. This is again, we'll, we'll fix it next week. We'll
Speaker 5:  fix it next week. There's always room for improvement.
Speaker 5:  Ah, thunder will crack. Thunder crack. Oh crap. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, we've, we've got, you know, again,
Speaker 5:  these are good notes. These are good notes. Our research team didn't have
Speaker 5:  that up front. A CDC didn't know that either. They named that song
Speaker 5:  Thunder Struck, which didn't happen. So there we go.
Speaker 5:  See. Okay, well I'm gonna add another item onto the Thunder Round and it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be room for Rooms for Improvement. Okay. Alright, let's
Speaker 5:  dive into it. Thunder Round story one, I wanna talk about what
Speaker 5:  happened in the Android world this week where Android
Speaker 5:  ecosystem President Samir Samat said quote,
Speaker 5:  we're going to be combining Chrome OS and Android into a single
Speaker 5:  platform. And this feels like there's a lot to
Speaker 5:  unpack, right? They have theoretically been
Speaker 5:  combining Chrome OS and Android for, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  forever now even mean sprinkling features between the two. Yeah, because
Speaker 5:  you, like, you've already been able to run Android s run
Speaker 5:  Android apps on Chromes, on Chrome os. Yeah. But the, it like
Speaker 5:  kind of stalled out. It was never very good. They sort of like forgot about
Speaker 5:  it, stopped talking about it. I'm not really sure what this means
Speaker 5:  long term for ChromeOS. Does ChromeOS stick around? Does
Speaker 5:  Chromes just become Android? Because Android at the same time and they show
Speaker 5:  this off at IO in the spring. Android's getting a
Speaker 5:  DA desktop mode, right? They're working with Samsung. Samsung has
Speaker 5:  decks. You just plug it in, you get a desktop. This sort of makes sense,
Speaker 5:  right? Chrome os if you go back when it came around
Speaker 5:  Android, there was not a world where Android was going to be a desktop operating
Speaker 5:  system, right? Google needed a desktop operating system. They needed something
Speaker 5:  that was kinda light ran on lightweight devices. We also just like did not
Speaker 5:  have like these arm processors that could run
Speaker 5:  super powerful desktop applications. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  now that they've become so powerful, it's like what, what is, what purpose
Speaker 5:  is Chrome West serving? Right? And I know they're super big in schools,
Speaker 5:  but I'm, I'm curious if that continues
Speaker 5:  in this new world. And I'm wondering if, if they are looking out at the trajectory
Speaker 5:  going, hey, there's not really anywhere further for
Speaker 5:  Chromes to go. Right? It was a Chrome browser.
Speaker 5:  It's kind of it. You, you don't need any more than that. Android on the other
Speaker 5:  hand, it has a Zap ecosystem. It's getting wind doing. You can keep going.
Speaker 5:  I'm curious, have either of you been Chromebook users? Oh yeah. In the past?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh absolutely. I've dipped in and out over and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  Over and, but now that the browser wars have been happening, I've been trying
Speaker 5:  like every new browser. What, why, why do you bounce off Chrome? Chrome Or
Speaker 5:  wait? Chrome OS or Chrome. Chrome OS Chrome. Yeah. So what makes you bounce
Speaker 5:  off Chrome os? Well, I'm a photographer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right, right. So that's all you really need to know. I dunno if you
Speaker 5:  wanna do, although Android is not great for photographers either. It's right.
Speaker 5:  Well the photo editing ecosystem is not. So Yeah, I,
Speaker 5:  there are laptop tasks. You know, actually I was at a Chrome OS event
Speaker 5:  like a month ago, maybe three weeks ago, where they introduced a bunch of
Speaker 5:  new Chrome AI features and one of the pre presenters, his
Speaker 5:  thing was, that's a laptop task. Now you can do it on the
Speaker 5:  Chromebook. That was his whole like motto, the idea. So
Speaker 5:  they're like new and improved Chrome os it's like a laptop.
Speaker 5:  Well he was saying that's a laptop thing. He was saying, oh I have this task.
Speaker 5:  Right. That's a laptop thing. Now I can sort of actually do
Speaker 5:  it with my voice on the laptop, you know? Yeah. This is weird.
Speaker 5:  It's weird. I, okay, my take on this is that Chrome OS and Android
Speaker 5:  should never have been different. I, I kind of, it's, it's a good way. Chrome
Speaker 5:  OS was a good way for Google to sell laptops, right? Yes.
Speaker 5:  'cause they, they didn't wanna build a whole desktop e system like Mac os,
Speaker 5:  you know, they didn't wanna compete with Windows. And so they never built
Speaker 5:  these desktop applications. And in some ways that was like a little bit of
Speaker 5:  forward thinking. They were thinking of the inter internet computer
Speaker 5:  way before, you know, the browser company was, because that's what Chrome
Speaker 5:  OS was supposed to be. It was log into your Google account, you've got everything.
Speaker 5:  It's right here. That's why it works in schools. That's why it works in libraries,
Speaker 5:  things like that. It's very smart for them. Now that
Speaker 5:  you were, like you said, these processors that are in smartphones are so
Speaker 5:  fast that they can run these applications that are almost having feature
Speaker 5:  parody with desktop. Like Lightroom for example, Lightroom mobile. It's getting
Speaker 5:  very close to the same sort of Lightroom classic functionality. So
Speaker 5:  there are some, you know, photo editing features that okay, okay, I could,
Speaker 5:  I could use. And so now what they're doing is they're like, okay, well like
Speaker 5:  why do we have these new platforms? Because over time they've had to be like,
Speaker 5:  well, okay Chrome as just a a just
Speaker 5:  a computer platform that is just Chrome maybe isn't
Speaker 5:  the move they bet on this world where everything was in the cloud. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But they realized that maybe everyone doesn't want everything to
Speaker 5:  be in the cloud all the time. So they had to allow you to use Android
Speaker 5:  apps on your computer. Also, if they wanted to compete with the
Speaker 5:  ecosystem of the iPhone and the Mac, they had to have some sort of like
Speaker 5:  file sync between the two devices. Some way to be able to interact with them
Speaker 5:  together. It's like, oh, well if you could just run the Android app on your
Speaker 5:  computer and then now you can like push text to your computer. And they
Speaker 5:  added that, they added all these push notifications that were coming directly
Speaker 5:  from your computer. There's like syncing between your, your Android phone
Speaker 5:  and your, and your Chromebook at this point. It just feels like, why
Speaker 5:  aren't they just the same platform? Well, can I say this? It has
Speaker 5:  always driven me crazy. 'cause I've, I've had an Android phone as my
Speaker 5:  main phone for, for a while now. I don't know why
Speaker 5:  Chrome and Android do not talk to each other, right?
Speaker 5:  I can't get my Android notifica, I've read, I use a Mac, right? And so
Speaker 5:  the Android Mac, they don't play super well together.
Speaker 5:  Right? If I, if I use an iPhone, I would get all my iPhone notifications
Speaker 5:  on my Mac. That would be delightful. Can't do that with Android. And I would
Speaker 5:  love, I, I don't understand why they can't push over to Chrome.
Speaker 5:  I don't understand why there can't be those sort of interactions when Chrome
Speaker 5:  is already, like it's a pretty beefy app, right? Yeah. Like I don't understand
Speaker 5:  how much more work they would have to do to link it up with
Speaker 5:  Android and having have started that integration
Speaker 5:  way back already. Yeah. It feels like if you're logged into the same Google
Speaker 5:  account, they should be able to push notifications through your account rather
Speaker 5:  than through your device. And then you would show up on your Chrome browser
Speaker 5:  anyway. I don't know. Right. Like gimme the file sync, gimme some sort of
Speaker 5:  like parody across Yeah. Yeah. Websites and apps. I feel like
Speaker 5:  there's something more they could do there. And I think it's interesting
Speaker 5:  that they have just not done that. Yeah. And, and now they're just like
Speaker 5:  Chrome o s like a couple of years ago they said
Speaker 5:  that they were moving parts of the Android kernel into Chrome os and it's
Speaker 5:  like, just make it Android. It's like right. Already have it in tablets.
Speaker 5:  The Pixel tablet has has Android, you know, that's running Android, not Chrome.
Speaker 5:  So it's like Pix. Yeah. Come on. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 6:  The key though is the education. And the thing that makes it so good for
Speaker 6:  education is how simple ChromeOS is. And once you, once you add
Speaker 6:  in more of a operating system, more of an infrastructure with Android,
Speaker 6:  it will make it more complicated. Which I think is, you know,
Speaker 6:  my main experience with Chromebooks is my kids use 'em for school. Although
Speaker 6:  the first one I bought was when they promised to bring Android apps. I was
Speaker 6:  like, oh, now this could be more interesting. But it was so,
Speaker 6:  it was such a poor experience to begin with. And then I never went back.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if it ever got much better. But yeah, that, that
Speaker 6:  simplicity is the key really right now. And it's
Speaker 6:  interesting because on the Mac now, I mean so much is a web app
Speaker 6:  anyway, it's not that often that you are actually gonna find
Speaker 6:  other than high-end software that you need for things like photo
Speaker 6:  editing, you really don't need specific apps.
Speaker 6:  So it's interesting. I like, I think it makes sense to bring it together,
Speaker 6:  but I think the key here is gonna be maintaining the simplicity that Chrome
Speaker 6:  OS has really sold the market on making sure
Speaker 6:  it doesn't make it complicated like a Windows machine.
Speaker 5:  I think all these companies have had different ideas of what an app should
Speaker 5:  be like. Should it be in your browser, Google thinks everything should be
Speaker 5:  running in your browser. That was the browser company's idea too.
Speaker 5:  Proton, you know, the whole proton thing was, well everything's sort of
Speaker 5:  a web app, but we could just put it in a different sort of environment where
Speaker 5:  it feels native. And that was the whole idea behind that. Because again,
Speaker 5:  you know, if I'm running a chat app on my laptop, I don't
Speaker 5:  Wait. Quick, quick reaction. Do you feel good about the future of Chrome
Speaker 5:  OS now with Android? Yes. No. Sure, sure.
Speaker 6:  I think
Speaker 5:  I feel, I think I feel worse. Really? Yeah. Yeah. I feel like
Speaker 5:  it'll be more native, but Okay. Next up. Wow, Jen,
Speaker 5:  we last week in the thunder round in our, in our rapid fire when we talked
Speaker 5:  about how Ikea had this new lamp, I know
Speaker 6:  That's also a speaker I was screaming at you guys when I listened to. I like
Speaker 6:  the speaker was not the big news people.
Speaker 5:  I, it was a pretty, it was a really pretty lamp. I thought the lamp looked
Speaker 5:  cool. I wanted to talk about the lamp. And honestly, I
Speaker 5:  don't understand matter well enough. And so now Jen,
Speaker 5:  okay. Actually the Ikea had some really big matter news. Big matter news
Speaker 5:  and Thread news. Yes. Yes. Tell me, tell me, tell me matters. Okay,
Speaker 6:  So I'll tell you why it matters. So
Speaker 6:  IKEA has launched an entire, or announced that it's launching an
Speaker 6:  entire new line of smart home products for its stores
Speaker 6:  that will be based on Thread and use matter.
Speaker 6:  So Thread is the protocol matter is the connectivity
Speaker 6:  protocol that it runs over. And as David mentioned earlier, is
Speaker 6:  the sort of promise to make your smart plug work with everyone. So
Speaker 6:  the promise of matter is that it works with every platform that's matter
Speaker 6:  compatible, which are all of them right now. And, and new ones coming along
Speaker 6:  as well. So this is really exciting because Ikea obviously
Speaker 6:  big name, big mass market name to date matter
Speaker 6:  has been very niche whilst Apple and Amazon and Google are all involved.
Speaker 6:  For most, most of them, it's a very small segment of
Speaker 6:  their offering. And it's, this is really pushing
Speaker 6:  Mathaf into the mainstream because crucially,
Speaker 6:  as everyone knows, IKEA products are very inexpensive. And
Speaker 6:  so this is gonna make it so it's easy to buy smart light bulb
Speaker 6:  that will work with any platform. And that's huge. And the fact
Speaker 6:  that it's on Thread is really big. 'cause Thread is very much a new
Speaker 6:  protocol, like about a decade old, which in the protocol space is, is
Speaker 6:  quite young and, but it's only recently been
Speaker 6:  seen sort of broadly in the smart home outside of Apple and Google.
Speaker 6:  So they basically ditched ZigBee for Thread. ZigBee is the
Speaker 6:  foundation of Thread. So it's not a huge leap, but it is a big leap.
Speaker 6:  And it's gonna be very interesting that they say they're launching over 20
Speaker 6:  new products in by January. Ikea kind of rolls things out in a
Speaker 6:  weird way. So we may start seeing things sooner, like light bulbs,
Speaker 6:  plugs, sensors, some air purifying devices,
Speaker 6:  10 like temperature, humidity, that kind of stuff. And it's replacing
Speaker 6:  the entire tra free line, which you may be familiar with if you've ever bought
Speaker 6:  smart bulbs in Ikea. And then they, they have a
Speaker 6:  newish hub, which has been out for a couple of years now. And when they launched
Speaker 6:  it, they promised it would have it, it has a Thread radio in it,
Speaker 6:  but they hadn't turned it on. This seems to be quite a common theme. So they
Speaker 6:  announced this last week that they had turned on the Thread radio and they
Speaker 6:  are now supporting Thread devices and they've turned their hub
Speaker 6:  into a matter controller, which means
Speaker 6:  that you can control any smart plug that is matter compatible
Speaker 6:  with it. So you don't have to use IKEA devices. You can
Speaker 6:  add any device to this hub that works with matter
Speaker 6:  that is supported by ikea. And then the flip side, you
Speaker 6:  don't need the hub anymore to use ikea's products.
Speaker 6:  So if you go into an IKEA store and pick up a smart bulb and
Speaker 6:  plug it in, turn it on, you don't have to have a hub
Speaker 6:  for the more advanced features because it can connect to any matter hub.
Speaker 6:  So if you have an Apple Home, apple TV Home
Speaker 6:  Pod or an Amazon Alexa Echo show 15,
Speaker 6:  it, that can be the hub. So it's just simplifying it. I don't know if anyone's
Speaker 6:  ever, if if people are familiar what it was, what it was like to use.
Speaker 5:  Duh. You deserved it after all. I'm sorry I did so well,
Speaker 5:  all we've done in this, it's didn't do it before, so I know. I can't believe
Speaker 5:  it made it this long. I I, I tested the trap for a while ago and like
Speaker 5:  I, I was very skeptical like Ikea making tech products, but they were good.
Speaker 5:  They were like really solid, cheap, smart gadgets, but a little
Speaker 6:  Complicated, impressed setup. And that was kind of one of the issues. And
Speaker 6:  this should make it a little, it should make it easier, but you know, you
Speaker 6:  don't have, you didn't have to use the hub, but you couldn't have connectivity
Speaker 6:  outside of the home. So you would own, it was just be in the home little.
Speaker 6:  They would have the remotes you could use what, what did you buy? What was
Speaker 6:  your
Speaker 5:  Oh, I I it was, it was, I I tested the lights at some point. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  And, And I don't remem and now I'm on on Hue. So like, which
Speaker 5:  maybe they're in, I
Speaker 6:  Don't know. Yeah. So this, this is, you can now. And so they always were
Speaker 6:  in some ways interoperable because they both use ZigBee and you could add
Speaker 6:  them to each other's bridges. It was a little complicated, but now it's just
Speaker 6:  should be a lot more straightforward. And that's, you know, this is the,
Speaker 6:  has been the promise of matter since it launched all those years, years ago,
Speaker 6:  that it's gonna make the smart home easier and more accessible. And this
Speaker 6:  is a big step in that direction. Yeah. Because it's, you know,
Speaker 6:  mass market on your IKEA shelves, much less expensive than most
Speaker 6:  products. And a brand name that people recognize and trust. Not just
Speaker 6:  something they're buying off Amazon for like $10 and who knows where it came
Speaker 6:  from.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think this is a pretty big deal because the best way to get people
Speaker 5:  to adopt a new protocol and actually get that protocol moving is
Speaker 5:  to not tell them that they're adopting a new protocol and getting that protocol
Speaker 5:  moving and having it in the Ikea where people go to
Speaker 5:  when they're moving, they're like, I'm gonna replace all my furniture, or
Speaker 5:  I'm moving across the country And I just need to redo everything. Okay, buy
Speaker 5:  lights. Okay. I want them to be smart Lights, not think about it, go through
Speaker 5:  the setup of like scanning a QR code. Suddenly they have matter and everything
Speaker 5:  in their house can be interchange, like inter workable. That is, that
Speaker 5:  is like very big. Yeah. Right. Like I think that that's pretty huge. So
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I'm excited that they're doing this. I still have problems
Speaker 5:  with Matter at my apartment consistently. What, what, what matter
Speaker 5:  gadgets do you have? So I have, oh gosh, what are they called?
Speaker 5:  I'm trying to remember the brand. They're smart plugs. And I also have,
Speaker 5:  I also have Smart Blinds. Oh man. Yeah. And it was the company that
Speaker 5:  promised first to upgrade to Matter Eve. Yes. I have the Eve Smart
Speaker 5:  plugs and they're really, really great. And I have the Eve Smart Blinds and
Speaker 5:  they're really, really great. But every single time I try to upgrade them
Speaker 5:  to matter. It like crashes the network, it removes them from the network.
Speaker 5:  And then I have to like reset up everything and it still doesn't work. And
Speaker 5:  I just go, oh God, I'm gonna go back to Home Kit. Yeah, yeah. Which sucks
Speaker 5:  because, because
Speaker 6:  It's Thread That's Thread. Yeah. Eve updated everything from Bluetooth.
Speaker 6:  I hear you. I hear you. Yeah. Every, yeah, yeah, yeah. Eve updated everything
Speaker 6:  from Bluetooth to Thread and just as Ikea is moving from ZigBee to Thread
Speaker 6:  and, but Eve was one of the early adopters and they tried, they promised
Speaker 6:  and, and carried through on firmware updates to their products. But
Speaker 6:  that's, that is always, you know, a completely changing the
Speaker 6:  infrastructure of a device can be tricky. And I've had similar issues
Speaker 6:  totally with that. But yeah, it's, I mean, you were an early adopter
Speaker 6:  there. And early adopters definitely. Yeah. Feel the pain points. I can it
Speaker 6:  goes to the pain.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. If, if you're a brand new homeowner or you're moving to a new home
Speaker 5:  and you don't have any smart devices yet and you start with Matter, I'm sure
Speaker 5:  this stuff works like pretty well. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it, it's a great, great point you made about making Thread and
Speaker 6:  matter mainstream, because actually Ikea did that for ZigBee
Speaker 6:  like 10 years ago. Yeah. When it started Chad Free. So it'll be interesting
Speaker 6:  to see.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Alright, next up David. Yes. You went to a beeper event.
Speaker 5:  I did go to a beeper event. Beeper being the chat
Speaker 5:  app. Yes. That is now owned by Automatic Yes. Yeah, automatic Who also owns
Speaker 5:  WordPress. There's a lot of WordPress drama this year. Yeah. Also owns
Speaker 5:  Pocket Cast, my favorite podcast player. Yeah. They, they own
Speaker 5:  a lot of very interesting difference. They ly own a lot of the internet.
Speaker 5:  A lot of, oh actually literally like, I mean we're literally Tumblr. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Tumblr. Yeah. Tumblr. Yeah. So, So there was a beeper event last night. A
Speaker 5:  little Context Beeper is a chat app that it, their whole idea of it
Speaker 5:  is that you can connect all of your different chat apps into one place.
Speaker 5:  This is sort of a nebulous. If you like it, you like it. If you don't, you
Speaker 5:  know, this is the dream though, right? It's like you don't have
Speaker 6:  Potentially it's like matter your messaging apps.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. That's sort of the thing where it doesn't always work.
Speaker 5:  Always like what is happening. I feel a little mixed on it because sometimes
Speaker 5:  I want to compartmentalize different parts of my life. Like I talk to a lot
Speaker 5:  of photography people over my Instagram chat And I talk to a lot of Normies
Speaker 5:  over iMessage. Right. And I talk to a lot of my tech friends over
Speaker 5:  Telegram. So it's sort of like, you know, it puts 'em all in one place. You
Speaker 5:  can have little different sections. Anyway, what they're changing here is
Speaker 5:  Eric Kosky, who is the guy that invented Pebble E
Speaker 5:  eventually moved on and made this app called Beeper that does this
Speaker 5:  last year. Famously they figured out how to
Speaker 5:  basically reverse engineer the iMessage protocol so that beeper mini
Speaker 5:  their new app that they had for a while worked with iMessage. You can run
Speaker 5:  iMessage on Android, which was crazy. Apple got real upset about that. They
Speaker 5:  shut it down. Now it sold to automatic. Eric is no longer at the company.
Speaker 5:  He is restarting Pebble, which is very fun. Those are starting to ship actually,
Speaker 5:  which is a whole nother thing. But Beeper had this big launch
Speaker 5:  last night with Automatic, where they are relaunching it with a couple
Speaker 5:  of new subscription features. They also changed a lot
Speaker 5:  of the apps. So a little more context, automatic Al already owned this chat
Speaker 5:  app called text.com and the idea of
Speaker 5:  text.com was exactly the same idea as beeper. And so I actually
Speaker 5:  talked to the CEO of Automatic last night and he told me that
Speaker 5:  they're using the foundation of text.com with the UX of
Speaker 5:  Beeper. So it is sort of like the best of both worlds in a lot of
Speaker 5:  ways. Also, if you had a beeper account, it automatically works with the
Speaker 5:  new beeper. But the, the big thing is they're introducing a
Speaker 5:  few new features specifically in these subscription models because they need
Speaker 5:  to figure out how to make money off of beeper. What are they selling? I agree.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah. So Beeper Plus it's a little expensive. It's 9
Speaker 5:  99 a month, which is quite of a lot. But you can have three accounts
Speaker 5:  print. So if you have multiple Instagram accounts. Okay, okay. Okay. You
Speaker 5:  can have multiple logins on each Instagram account with, so it's like a power
Speaker 5:  user option? It is. The whole thing is for powered users. Yeah. They have
Speaker 5:  an incognito mode. So the interesting thing about Incognito, the interesting
Speaker 5:  thing about Beeper is that even if the platform itself didn't
Speaker 5:  offer a feature, if Beeper offers the feature, you can do it with the app,
Speaker 5:  which is quite cool. So Incognito, for example, you can read
Speaker 5:  messages without people seeing that you've read them if it's forced read
Speaker 5:  receipts. Wow. Wow. Wow. So that's cool because we've all done the thing
Speaker 5:  where we've just long pressed on the notification. So that didn't technically
Speaker 5:  open it all the time. Okay. I would pay for that. Well,
Speaker 5:  yeah, it's great. That's good. It's good. Oh man. Yeah. Okay. They
Speaker 5:  should have just called it like beat the read receipt subscription. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah. Yeah. I, I also ha, I also hate red receipts. So
Speaker 5:  voice note transcriptions. So if the app didn't have voice note transcriptions,
Speaker 5:  now it does. That's great. It has chat reminders to remind you
Speaker 5:  to reply to people. I need that. I'm really bad at
Speaker 5:  replying to people because I'm always busy and then I don't reply to you.
Speaker 5:  That's bad. It's good for me if I use this. And then there is
Speaker 5:  send later on every service. So I think like in the last
Speaker 5:  iOS version, iMessage added this like schedule send feature,
Speaker 5:  Google Message just has it. And I believe it's favorite feature. I love text.
Speaker 5:  It's amazing. So much. It's so useful. So useful. Also, if you wanna say
Speaker 5:  happy birthday, write at midnight to somebody to show you care by automating
Speaker 5:  a message that would work. And then they have a, you can,
Speaker 5:  there's a custom map icon thing. It's this That's good. That's, yeah, that's
Speaker 5:  great. Yeah. That's the plus service. It doesn't end there though Service.
Speaker 5:  Right. It kind of ends there. Okay. Yeah. What is, wait, but
Speaker 5:  what is Beeper Plus? Plus plus? Okay. So then there's Plus. Plus. Okay. Plus
Speaker 5:  plus is for enterprises. Oh, okay. Okay, okay. Okay. So it's not, yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  sort of this, but like instead of three accounts per network, you can have
Speaker 5:  unlimited accounts per network. Gotcha. This is like, I'm a social media
Speaker 5:  manager. Yeah. And I will, I am entering the matrix a hundred percent.
Speaker 5:  I will chat with everybody who responds to our accounts. Yes. A hundred percent
Speaker 5:  that, does
Speaker 6:  It still work with iMessage or did that go away?
Speaker 5:  No, it does. They, they got long. That's
Speaker 6:  Completely gone. Like there's no integration
Speaker 5:  And completely, like you cannot even, yeah, you can't even put your regular
Speaker 5:  text through. There's Google Chat or there's Google. Google Messages I
Speaker 5:  believe. Yeah. But there's no iMessage. So I think
Speaker 6:  It's still worth it. It works with Whatsapp, right?
Speaker 5:  It works with Whatsapp. Yeah. Yeah. Me, I have it right now. Sold me, I'm,
Speaker 5:  oh, interesting. I, I mean, I'm not trying to be a salesperson, but, well
Speaker 6:  I have, I have the same thing and like, you know, constantly from different
Speaker 6:  sources and then I also talking with people in different time zones and it
Speaker 6:  would just be so nice to have it in one spot. And does it, and it's the same
Speaker 6:  even Same
Speaker 5:  Even has
Speaker 6:  Slack. It has Slack, it has Slack. Which, oh, that might get messy.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be messy. I don't want, I don't want Slack. Period. Well, yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah, yeah. So you get s
Speaker 6:  Like your Instagram messages and like your X dms. Yep. And
Speaker 6:  yours dms.
Speaker 5:  Th not yet. They don't have Thread dms. They don't have DON Blue Sky
Speaker 5:  dms. Okay. But they do have X. Yeah, they have Discord.
Speaker 5:  LinkedIn. This is, okay, this is the thing with ER where I feel like you
Speaker 5:  have to be a very specific type of person. Yeah. Who is either like, I don't
Speaker 5:  know, like a messaging madman and like just lives in their
Speaker 5:  inbox. Yeah. Or just like works organizationally that way.
Speaker 5:  But honestly like putting all those things in there. I understand why you
Speaker 5:  would want that. And it also sounds like a nightmare. Yeah. I like
Speaker 5:  get this away from me. Yeah. It does have some quirks, for example on Mac
Speaker 5:  Os in your little notifications area where you normally get like one
Speaker 5:  little text or whatever. Every single notification you've got from
Speaker 5:  every single different chat app shows up as a notification
Speaker 5:  in your, oh, I'm unsold. It's not good. You can turn them off. You can
Speaker 5:  turn it off. So turn off once you're fine. Anyway, again, it's for PE
Speaker 5:  it's for people who are just like truly it's a power user feature.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Hardcore. You gotta be that person. Yeah. Okay, next one up.
Speaker 5:  Jen, you wanna talk about Google's Nest Aware subscription
Speaker 5:  prices going up. And this is like a trend, right? There's, there's been a
Speaker 5:  lot of this. Tell me what's going on. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  So Google is raising the price of its Nest Aware service. So
Speaker 6:  this is the service that you subscribe to if you have their
Speaker 6:  cameras predominantly. So the Google Nest cams or the Google
Speaker 6:  Nest doorbell. So this enables recorded video up
Speaker 6:  to 60 days I think it is. And other features such as
Speaker 6:  familiar faces. So facial recognition, there's a whole bunch of services
Speaker 6:  that come with Nest Aware. You do get some, I think you get
Speaker 6:  up to three hours of free cloud storage with, or three video storage
Speaker 6:  because it's not stored in the cloud. It's stored locally with
Speaker 6:  your Google Doorbell or your Google Nest camera. But if you want
Speaker 6:  more, you need to pay and it was $8 a month
Speaker 6:  or $80 a year and now it's going from $8 a month to
Speaker 6:  $10 a month or a hundred dollars a year if you pay up front. And that's for
Speaker 6:  the basic Nesta aware. So the Nesta Aware plus adds
Speaker 6:  just, it has all the same features as Nesta wear, but you get 60 days of
Speaker 6:  video history instead of 30 plus 24 7 recording
Speaker 6:  if that's what you want. So there's extra features in Nesta
Speaker 6:  Wear Plus and that's now going from $15 a month to $20 a month.
Speaker 6:  So from $150 a year to $200 a year if
Speaker 6:  you pay annually. And this is a big jump and
Speaker 6:  they announced this yesterday with no extra features. Like it's not
Speaker 6:  like, oh we're adding all of this and we're putting our prices up. It's
Speaker 6:  just we are putting our prices up. I think the, that the
Speaker 6:  verbiage that they said was that this was, you know,
Speaker 6:  around the current sort of atmosphere in, I'm trying to find
Speaker 6:  the exact wording. Yeah. Do you,
Speaker 5:  Do you have any like premium camera subscriptions? Currently? I have
Speaker 5:  them. There's of course,
Speaker 6:  Of course.
Speaker 5:  I'm so sorry.
Speaker 6:  Yes. I know
Speaker 5:  This is one of the things that like has always, I, I understand right. If
Speaker 5:  you like, if you need a security camera, which like a lot of small businesses
Speaker 5:  do, this makes a ton of sense. But like for a homeowner. Yeah. And you have
Speaker 5:  to keep tacking these on lot of them. You and it keeps pay extra for more.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You keep going up is
Speaker 6:  Is the second time. And like their
Speaker 5:  Costs are not going up
Speaker 6:  Either three years, right? Yeah. It had gone up, I think it was 2023, it
Speaker 6:  went up and you know, if you just have one camera,
Speaker 6:  like a doorbell camera, it's like this is a lot of money to be paying.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And what's happening, that's interesting. And I think this is why we're
Speaker 6:  seeing the prices go up because Ring went up recently. Arlo is another in
Speaker 6:  this space that went up recently is they're all adding AI powered features
Speaker 6:  to their higher tiers subscriptions, things like text
Speaker 6:  descriptions for alerts. So one of the most annoying thing about having
Speaker 6:  cameras in your home or around your home is you get a constant stream of
Speaker 6:  like motion alerts. Or maybe if you have, if you pay for the subscriptions,
Speaker 6:  you can get like a personal alert or if it's, if it's an animal or a vehicle.
Speaker 6:  So you'll get a specific, it'll tell you what, what was there. So
Speaker 6:  you don't have to open the app to see Now with these text descriptions, it'll
Speaker 6:  actually describe, like it'll tell me, I just set up an Arlo
Speaker 6:  in my backyard for testing a floodlight and it says a black chicken walked
Speaker 6:  across the yard. It's a calm
Speaker 5:  Wow scene.
Speaker 6:  And there's, it's a ripple of sun in the background. The
Speaker 5:  Leaves, it needs to get face identification and like tell you which chicken
Speaker 5:  it is. It used to be like Mary walked across the lawn.
Speaker 6:  I'm sure we'll get there. But the thing is, I don't know that, I mean it's
Speaker 6:  useful. I can see in the future there could be some use because if you
Speaker 6:  AI could kind of filter out and only send you a notification when
Speaker 6:  there was something you needed to hear about. This is something that Wise
Speaker 6:  is doing. They have something called the no big deal filter, which
Speaker 6:  is supposed to, I love that. Take away. Like it, it determines what
Speaker 6:  you need to know about. So a chicken walking across my yard probably
Speaker 6:  don't need to know about, but a man with a balaclava maybe send the alert
Speaker 6:  but then you are, you know, so that's what we're seeing happening around
Speaker 6:  smart security cameras is this extra level of functionality.
Speaker 6:  But for the majority of people I think who just want to know if there's a
Speaker 6:  package at their front door, this is, this in continual price
Speaker 6:  increase is getting pretty hard to stomach. And most of the other
Speaker 6:  services which are around the same price, so rings, premium services
Speaker 6:  $20 and Arlo's premium service I think is
Speaker 6:  29. That includes professional
Speaker 6:  per month. Well they include professional monitoring. So if you have a
Speaker 6:  security system as well, the cameras in the security system are bundled,
Speaker 6:  you can just pay, I think for Arlo it's $10 a month for just a single camera.
Speaker 6:  But it used to be free.
Speaker 5:  This is a good thing. My God, if when you bought the camera it was, it
Speaker 5:  showed you the price for a full year of service. Yeah. Nobody would buy
Speaker 5:  these things. Right? Yeah. Yeah. 'cause what you're signing up to a hundred
Speaker 5:  bucks a year on top of the camera price. Yep. You're paying two unbelievable.
Speaker 5:  Like indefinitely. Right. As long if you, if you want these things to function
Speaker 5:  to their full stability. Yeah. And there's, there are like a couple of them,
Speaker 5:  what is it, the blink cameras that I think like do it all locally so
Speaker 6:  You can Yeah. And well, and Arlo has the option of local recording ring also
Speaker 6:  has the option of local recording. But Nest does not, there is a minimal
Speaker 6:  amount of local recording that you get for free. But beyond that you have
Speaker 6:  to use the cloud. And that's another sort of galling thing. 'cause there
Speaker 6:  are many now on the market options where you don't have to use a cloud service
Speaker 6:  at all. You can use a micro SD card or you can record to a hub in your
Speaker 6:  home. Like Apple's home Kit secure video offers that you do pay
Speaker 6:  for your cloud storage on your iCloud server. But yeah, it's,
Speaker 6:  it's just a little crazy.
Speaker 5:  It's, it is fundamentally not in their interest to make it easy
Speaker 5:  to do this yourself, to store it locally. Right. Right. Like it's so, so
Speaker 5:  much easier for them to be like, oh, it's a small amount. It's like, what
Speaker 5:  are we supposed to do? Yeah. And it's like, oh, what, what you're supposed
Speaker 5:  to do is make it easy so that I don't have to pay you $200 every single year.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well, And I, they're really pushing these AI features and it's interesting
Speaker 6:  'cause they're not on the Google Nest cameras yet and they're still
Speaker 6:  increasing the prices. They've promised them, they're in like a beta in a
Speaker 6:  public preview. These text descriptions and some other sort of
Speaker 6:  AI powered search Gemini powered features, but they're not available
Speaker 6:  yet. So it seems it's such a weird move to increase the prices
Speaker 6:  now before offering these features to everyone. And honestly, I think
Speaker 6:  Google is kind of done with Nest. There's my
Speaker 6:  spicy taste
Speaker 5:  That that is the, to end on. I, I,
Speaker 5:  I don't know that you're wrong. I do like the thunder immediately after you
Speaker 5:  said that. I know it was spooky. Okay, one last story
Speaker 5:  and it is a big one. This is, we, we saved the, the
Speaker 5:  finest story. Yes. For the end of the show. I have so many thoughts. David,
Speaker 5:  over to you. All right. New emoji are coming guys. It's a big
Speaker 5:  deal. Okay. Every year the emoji subcommittee of the
Speaker 5:  Unicode Consortium, that's the specific way they wanted me to say it
Speaker 5:  releases a number of new emoji. Usually it's not that many this time it's
Speaker 5:  not that many. This time. Kind of weird sometimes. Kind of weird. Last time
Speaker 5:  we got like a splat emoji that was just like a bunch of slime.
Speaker 5:  This time we got eight new emoji, I believe. Yeah, about eight. So
Speaker 5:  we have Apple core, we have ballet dancers
Speaker 5:  distorted face, which is sort of like, I think this is basically a meme that
Speaker 5:  they turned into an emoji. It is sort of that like really up close,
Speaker 5:  super wide angle face with like eyes popping out of the side. It looks like
Speaker 5:  this. Yeah. It's a, it's like got a bugeye situation going on. Yeah. You
Speaker 5:  gotta fight cloud, which is basically like in a cartoon when two characters
Speaker 5:  are fighting and like there's a cloud and there's all those, like things
Speaker 5:  zipping around it. There's a trombone, very specific.
Speaker 5:  There is what they call a hairy creature, which is clearly Bigfoot,
Speaker 5:  a treasure chest and an orca whale. So if you don't know
Speaker 5:  how this works effectively, every single year the emoji subcommittee of the
Speaker 5:  Unicode consortium will take all of these proposals for
Speaker 5:  emojis. And you have to be able to say, this is important because it has
Speaker 5:  cultural significance across the entire world. People are using this a lot.
Speaker 5:  You give them Google trends data, you give this them all this information,
Speaker 5:  and then they vote on whether or not they should actually take in your emoji.
Speaker 5:  Famously j Peters of The Verge did make two emoji.
Speaker 5:  He made the waffle emoji. That's huge. Yeah. Huge emoji.
Speaker 5:  Obviously people are using that all the time. And he also made one other
Speaker 5:  one. I'm trying to remember. It's a face of some kind. I, these are
Speaker 5:  important contributions to humanity. They are. If you're getting a, a good,
Speaker 5:  the yawning face, this is, these are good. Yeah. People use yawn face, but
Speaker 5:  there are some weak years. There are some weak years. Oh, yeah. And, and
Speaker 5:  it's like you, you guys, yeah. There are some really, you went to the drawing
Speaker 5:  board and this is what you came up with. There are some very weak years.
Speaker 5:  And I would say that maybe the orca whale or the,
Speaker 5:  the fight cloud, maybe in this cloud, kind of like the fight cloud. I, I
Speaker 5:  feel like I'm gonna say this is like, I don't know if this is
Speaker 5:  an a plus release, but like this is a solid, this is like one of the,
Speaker 5:  it's solid top tiers. Right? You threw this in the middle. I, I don't know
Speaker 5:  how you didn't like make a point. They, they have one called,
Speaker 5:  they have, they have named it hairy creature. Yeah. Which is bizarre. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It is Bigfoot. It is Bigfoot. It is Bigfoot walking and glancing
Speaker 5:  at the camera. It's the famous like fake photo. It's the famous photos. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's, that is I That's true. That's pretty amazing. Am astonished
Speaker 5:  that the grand committee of the Unicode consortium. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  When you know what we need to make sure that the entire world has access
Speaker 5:  to That's a big foot. Big foot Bigfoot emoji emoji. That's true. I love it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's that alone. The rest of these could have been total losers.
Speaker 5:  Trombone. Makes sense. Trombone. I assume they have trumpet. They should
Speaker 5:  have trombone. They should have everything that could be in a ska band. Should
Speaker 5:  be, yes. Yeah. If they had done that as one pack, the ska year,
Speaker 5:  a ska band, they really, yeah. Yeah. They just start branding it a little
Speaker 5:  bit more. Right. Like why isn't, there's pirate hats to go with this treasure
Speaker 5:  chest. They should do themes. Yeah. I, yeah. I will say, I am wondering,
Speaker 5:  'cause Apple, you know, they have a seat on the Unicode consortium. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They must have had some strong opinions about this Apple core. Mm. This is
Speaker 5:  an apple that has been bitten down to the core. That is Ooh, that's that's
Speaker 5:  true. There's, I like, that's not good for them. I bet Google submitted that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Probably submitted that. That is quite funny. There's, yeah, apple
Speaker 5:  core is kind of strange. Like I understand there being an apple. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  why the core weird. I will say a couple of years
Speaker 5:  ago I interviewed the inventor of Emoji Shika Taaka Carita, and
Speaker 5:  he told me that he thinks that there are too many emoji. It is getting a
Speaker 5:  little outta hand, I'm not gonna lie. It's getting a little crazy. I do think
Speaker 5:  the ballet dancer makes sense because they already have like a disco dancer
Speaker 5:  and they need other types of dance. So that makes sense. But there also
Speaker 5:  opens up this whole other question, which honestly I just might write something
Speaker 5:  on or make a video on or something about what we do now that you can just
Speaker 5:  generate like any emoji you want. Hmm. Right. Like the fact that there's
Speaker 5:  a trombone or an orca whale. If these didn't exist, you could make
Speaker 5:  this with Gen Moji in like half a second. That's true, that's true. So
Speaker 5:  it becomes this giant question. The main thing is these are coded into
Speaker 5:  Unicode, so they're standardized, so they're gonna work on any computer that
Speaker 5:  supports Unicode. I am, I'm very torn on the too many emoji
Speaker 5:  versus not enough emoji argument. Yeah, because, because like, like
Speaker 5:  fundamentally Yeah, you cannot, there's way too many emoji. Yeah. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's outrageous. On the other hand, so we use Slack at work
Speaker 5:  and we have a zillion custom emoji. Yeah. And there's some, I don't realize
Speaker 5:  they're not official ones. So then I'll go to like, you know, just send a
Speaker 5:  normal text message and then I'm like, why isn't this in here? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's, how did they mis a really obvious one. That's true. It's outrageous.
Speaker 5:  And I think particularly like there was a time before they figured out how
Speaker 5:  to do like, big search for emoji. Yeah. Now that
Speaker 5:  you can type it in, it's like, yeah, I will say I feel terrible. Right. If
Speaker 5:  you're starting up, you know, I, I mean, I don't know who is in this
Speaker 5:  position, but if you're starting up an app and you want to have your own
Speaker 5:  presentation of the emoji, oh boy, that's an uphill battle. Now
Speaker 5:  you got a lot of little things to draw. Yeah. You can use, you should just
Speaker 5:  use the platform. Yeah. Twitter famously has its own emoji for some
Speaker 5:  reason, but usually it's just Google slash Android, apple,
Speaker 5:  Microsoft, or like the main ones. And you can de as a app developer, you
Speaker 5:  can default to system emoji and you should, because if you wanna make your
Speaker 5:  own emoji, you can, but you gotta, you gotta draw every single one.
Speaker 5:  So Yes. But if, you know, if you only have to make an eight new ones a year,
Speaker 5:  that's very manageable. Yeah. If you've already made the other like, you
Speaker 5:  know, I don't even know how many there are. You gotta choose wisely. You
Speaker 5:  gotta choose wisely. And you know, I, these are, these are pretty good. I
Speaker 5:  don't know. I, I think I would've cut the whale, the orca, the, I don't wanna
Speaker 5:  be, I don't wanna be rude, but like, I wanna cut. I'm not using the orca.
Speaker 5:  It's a cute orca. Whatcha are you gonna use Big foot Smiling, please tell
Speaker 5:  me. We're gonna use Bigfoot foot. I am telling you this Bigfoot is going
Speaker 5:  to, is there like an emoji ranking chart? Yes. It's going to actually, it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be at top Top. It's actually, it is, this is part of that news kind
Speaker 5:  of because world emoji day was this week and as part of world emoji day,
Speaker 5:  they brought back the emoji ranking chart because they used to have a world
Speaker 5:  emoji ranking chart that used Twitter as its database of like how much people
Speaker 5:  were using emojis. But then Elon cut off the API so now
Speaker 5:  they were able to bring it back as of this week. So I am excited.
Speaker 5:  See, I'm telling you. Okay, listen, one year from today, this
Speaker 5:  is my prediction. Yeah. Bigfoot's gonna be in the top 10. It's,
Speaker 5:  I'm sending a calendar anytime,
Speaker 6:  Any,
Speaker 5:  This is, I think it's gonna ebb and flow as government conspiracies come
Speaker 5:  and go. Oh. Oh boy. I think there's a lot of room for Bigfoot,
Speaker 5:  right? There is a UFO emoji. So I guess there should be a Bigfoot. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think there Bigfoot's. Yeah. But then you need like a Loch Next Monster
Speaker 5:  Lock. I get, this is what I need to do. Themes. Every urban legends
Speaker 5:  a monsters year. Yeah. Oh yeah. Oh man. Yeah, that'd be funny. We,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'm very excited by distorted face. I have to say, I think distorted
Speaker 6:  face with the eyebrows leaving its head, I I'm gonna be using that one a
Speaker 6:  lot.
Speaker 6:  And the, the fight cloud pretty fun. But yeah, I agree
Speaker 6:  with Jake that Bigfoot really is the, is the shining star
Speaker 6:  of this. I, I wanna know how we can get, like, I'm not very
Speaker 6:  up on the emoji world because you know, it is how my children communicate
Speaker 6:  with me. But how do these get chosen?
Speaker 6:  Like I, can I submit some suggestions? Please.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you can. You actually can. Oh, good. Yeah, you can do it yourself.
Speaker 5:  You actually literally talked to Jay, like he, he's, yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah, yeah. It's, it's a process. You, it's quite a process. You need to,
Speaker 5:  it is really funny. Like the nuclear conserv, it sounds, it's like this formal
Speaker 5:  body. Yeah. It is the most like religious esco body in,
Speaker 5:  in all of technology. It is. You know, these counselors from
Speaker 5:  all the companies. Yeah. I technically am part of it. 'cause I pay $75 a
Speaker 5:  year. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Right. So you are the guy we should talk to. But
Speaker 5:  I don't know about that. As
Speaker 6:  Someone who has, you know, built a career on writing words, I have always
Speaker 6:  slightly shied away from using emojis, but I have to learn how to
Speaker 6:  communicate with my, with the youth. So I'm getting there. My mom who is
Speaker 6:  80, like all of her text messages are basically emojis now. So
Speaker 6:  it's not a generational thing. I think it's a writer thing. I like to use
Speaker 6:  the words,
Speaker 5:  But I, I like find a few And I just like key in on them.
Speaker 6:  Right. Yeah. That's probably what I would say. I, and that's what I like
Speaker 6:  about the, the distorted face. I feel like I could use that a lot. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's it. That's what you gotta find. Yeah. Yeah. The sweating face, everything.
Speaker 5:  I sent it with everything. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think this could replace that though. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Slack also has HDR r emoji by the way.
Speaker 5:  Which is awful. Wait, what is it? HDR Emoji. HDR Emoji.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So you can send them in Slack and if it's an HDR emoji, it's just way
Speaker 5:  brighter than everything around it. That is crazy. It just uses those pixels
Speaker 5:  on your like MacBook display and lights them up like five times as bright.
Speaker 5:  It's horrible. That's terrible. Do not recommend it.
Speaker 6:  I'm really, I live in a place where we have a lot of thunderstorms And I'm
Speaker 6:  not gonna lie, this is kind of giving me some trauma. Okay.
Speaker 5:  And that's it for The Vergecast. Mia Sato is hosting Tuesday's
Speaker 5:  episode. You should tune in. It's gonna be great. If you like we do here,
Speaker 5:  the best way to support us is to buy a paid subscription to The Verge.
Speaker 5:  And we would love to hear your feedback. I actually, I just got access to
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast email, so please hit us up there, Vergecast
Speaker 5:  at The Verge dot com. Or you can give us a call.
Speaker 5:  8 6 6 VERGE 11. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 5:  production of The Verge and Fox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 5:  by Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, Travis Sluck, and Andrew Marino. See you next
Speaker 5:  week.