# Transcript
ID: fe248e95-441d-4f75-ae26-0c26903eed10
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2406043097771064795/-1906897654865086249/s93290-US-4313s-1739877431.mp3
Description: This episode is all about companies in flux. First, we chat with The Verge's Alex Heath about all things Meta — whether the company is still serious about the metaverse, why its AI plans seem to be going so well, what "OG Facebook" really means, and what headsets to expect this year. After that, The Verge's Chris Welch takes us through the last year at Sonos, from the disastrous app launch to the pretty good headphones that were totally derailed by the disastrous app launch. Can the company get it together in order to launch its next big swing, a set-top box codenamed Pinewood? Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline all about business cards. Because, yes, it's 2025, but sometimes you still need a place to put a business card.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of completely
Speaker 2:  unnecessary corporate pivots. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I have a
Speaker 2:  new webcam. This will not be interesting to anyone who is just listening
Speaker 2:  to this show, which is most of you, but if you're watching this on YouTube,
Speaker 2:  you'll notice frankly that I look both hopefully better
Speaker 2:  and probably slightly worse. So I've had this Sony
Speaker 2:  Zv one lying around for a while. I got it with the intention of
Speaker 2:  upgrading my video conferencing and podcast video setup.
Speaker 2:  But it turns out that whenever you introduce like an actual camera to your
Speaker 2:  system, it makes everything more annoying. There are more things you have
Speaker 2:  to turn on and off. There are more systems you have to figure out. There's
Speaker 2:  more really awful Sony software that you have to download. And so
Speaker 2:  most of the time I just end up using a webcam like this one, just a normal
Speaker 2:  Insta 360 webcam. But then recently I was like, okay,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna try and upgrade and see if I can make myself look a little better.
Speaker 2:  So in a certain way, this camera is a huge improvement, but it also only
Speaker 2:  does seven 20 P when you're using it as a webcam, which it's 2025.
Speaker 2:  That's ridiculous. So we're trying this out. We'll see how it goes. And if
Speaker 2:  you're wondering why it's nighttime behind me, that's because it's nighttime
Speaker 2:  behind me. And this at this point is the only time I
Speaker 2:  have to endlessly mess with my desktop setup. 'cause during the day, I have
Speaker 2:  to like, you know, work like a real person. It's awful. I don't recommend
Speaker 2:  it. Anyway, that is not what we're here to talk about today. On the show,
Speaker 2:  we are going to do two things. First, we're gonna talk about Meta,
Speaker 2:  which is a company very much in transition. This is
Speaker 2:  a company called Meta who seems to be interested in lots of other
Speaker 2:  things and not the Metaverse. So we're gonna talk about that. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about how the company has changed internally and externally, and
Speaker 2:  what 2025 holds for the company as well. Then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about Sonos, which is actually a company in a similar
Speaker 2:  spot after a year full of a huge number of
Speaker 2:  self-inflicted wounds around the app and the ACE
Speaker 2:  headphones and the way that it responded to the app and to the launch of
Speaker 2:  the Ace headphones. Sonos is just in a weird place, but I
Speaker 2:  think the company is actually kind of unusual and interesting,
Speaker 2:  and we've talked about it a ton on this show, but I thought it might be good
Speaker 2:  to just try and tell the whole story all at once and see
Speaker 2:  if we can figure out what it means. We also have a hotline on a sort of unusual
Speaker 2:  topic, which is a thing I have not thought about in a while, which is fun.
Speaker 2:  And we're gonna get to all of that in just a second. But
Speaker 2:  first, I feel like I'm like zoomed in a little too far. And now
Speaker 2:  I'm going to spend just an outrageous amount of time mucking around in the
Speaker 2:  camera settings, trying to make all this work. This is The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Let's talk about Meta first because I think
Speaker 2:  If you look at the sweep of the tech industry right now, whether
Speaker 2:  you wanna talk about technology in general or AI
Speaker 2:  specifically or how tech and politics or interacting,
Speaker 2:  I think you could argue that Meta is the single most central company
Speaker 2:  in all of that right now. Whether you wanna talk about the future of social
Speaker 2:  and what it means for us to be people online in this information ecosystem,
Speaker 2:  or you just wanna talk about like AI glasses and the metaverse and
Speaker 2:  whatever. But at the same time, this company seems to be changing.
Speaker 2:  They've changed a lot of content policies recently. Mark Zuckerberg went
Speaker 2:  on Joe Rogan's podcast and talked about needing more masculine energy at
Speaker 2:  Meta. This company just feels like it is not going to be
Speaker 2:  the company we've known it to be for a very long time. And frankly, even
Speaker 2:  as Meta has changed a lot, I feel like we've been able to
Speaker 2:  sort of chart its path, but this feels like an inflection point and I just
Speaker 2:  wanna see if I can make sense of that. So I asked Alex Heath, who
Speaker 2:  Chronicles Meta and many others in his newsletter for The Verge called Command
Speaker 2:  Line. It's very good. You should subscribe. He is inside of Meta
Speaker 2:  in a way that very few people are and I figured could help us out. So let's
Speaker 2:  just dig into this. Alex Heath, welcome back to the show. Hey, it's
Speaker 2:  been a minute. Yeah, it has. We haven't done this in a little while. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  it's nice to see you again. Good to be back. I wanna talk about Meta
Speaker 2:  because there's been a lot going on with this company the last few months
Speaker 2:  and I've been thinking a lot in particular about a memo
Speaker 2:  that Andrew Bosworth sent about the Metaverse that I wanna talk about. That's
Speaker 2:  really fascinating. But it feels like you've been inside of a lot of these
Speaker 2:  meetings that the company's having, you've been reporting on a lot of the
Speaker 2:  goings on, they're very mad at you specifically about some of the leakers
Speaker 2:  that are going on. And I feel like Meta is in the middle of becoming
Speaker 2:  a very different kind of company than frankly, than it was
Speaker 2:  six months ago or three years ago, or like when it changed its name
Speaker 2:  to Meta. And I'm curious, like does it, does it feel
Speaker 2:  like this company is becoming something else right in front of our eyes right
Speaker 2:  now?
Speaker 8:  I'm not sure. I mean, I see what you're saying about becoming a different
Speaker 8:  company. I feel like Meta changes more than any of the other
Speaker 8:  big tech companies. Like it's definitely more chaotic. I think that's just
Speaker 8:  a function of Zuckerberg controlling the company and
Speaker 8:  it really being a, I would say,
Speaker 8:  imprint of his psyche at any given moment.
Speaker 2:  Fair. Yeah. He can get away with being chaotic because there's no one to
Speaker 2:  stop him really.
Speaker 8:  Right. And so, you know, it was interesting, I reported on this all
Speaker 8:  hands meeting that Zuckerberg had with employees a couple
Speaker 8:  weeks ago now, and I did a little word check
Speaker 8:  and he said the word metaverse once in an hour. Mm.
Speaker 8:  He said AI a lot and I think that's a pretty good
Speaker 8:  indicator of where things are at. But I don't actually
Speaker 8:  buy the external analysis that's out there
Speaker 8:  that this means they're giving up on the Metaverse stuff.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. Okay. Well so let me, lemme just read the bit of Bosworth's
Speaker 2:  memo that that has stuck in my brain and then I want you
Speaker 2:  to explain what you mean by that. So he, he
Speaker 2:  basically said it's going to be either quote the work of visionaries or a
Speaker 2:  legendary misadventure and then he said we had the best portfolio of products
Speaker 2:  we've ever had in market and are pushing our advantage by launching a half
Speaker 2:  dozen more AI powered wearables. We need to drive sales retention and engagement
Speaker 2:  across the board, but especially in Mr Fixed reality and Horizon World on
Speaker 2:  Mobile absolutely has to break out for our long-term plans to have a chance.
Speaker 2:  It was like literally like thi this is either, either we're geniuses or idiots
Speaker 2:  is like in his words the thing that they're using. And I, and I think you're
Speaker 2:  right that a lot of people took that to mean and obviously it's not gonna
Speaker 2:  work this year, so Meta's gonna be out on the metaverse and this is just
Speaker 2:  him setting the scene for that. Why do you think that's not what's going
Speaker 2:  on here?
Speaker 8:  Oh I think that's right. My point was more just that the AI
Speaker 8:  focus or pivot as some would say does not mean that
Speaker 8:  the Metaverse stuff is going away. I think Zuckerberg
Speaker 8:  actually used the phrase like Walk and chew gum at the same time in this
Speaker 8:  all hands meeting and they are still spending an
Speaker 8:  absurd amount of money on reality labs, which is the division
Speaker 8:  Bosworth who you just mentioned runs that bills all the metaverse stuff.
Speaker 8:  I think maybe it would be helpful to just like put that in context before
Speaker 8:  we talk about all the devices. Like please, I was looking through Meta's
Speaker 8:  filings with the SEC, their annual report.
Speaker 8:  They spent, well actually more specifically reality
Speaker 8:  Labs reduced their profit by nearly $18 billion last
Speaker 8:  year. Wow. That's a lot of money. And that keeps going up year after year.
Speaker 8:  That's more than Amazon paid for Whole Foods. It's more than three
Speaker 8:  x what OpenAI spent to run its entire company last year. Wow. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's the total market value of Snap the company is what they
Speaker 8:  spent on Reality Labs last year. They
Speaker 2:  Just lose a snap every year.
Speaker 8:  So to say that they're giving up on the metaverse, it doesn't bear out in
Speaker 8:  the numbers that they report to the SEC. And I thought another interesting
Speaker 8:  thing, I'm, I'm a, I'm a nerd about this stuff is
Speaker 8:  that they said in this report that this year they
Speaker 8:  expect to spend half of reality Labs is
Speaker 8:  spending on wearables, which is everything not Quest
Speaker 8:  and not Horizon. And historically they were spending
Speaker 8:  most on Quest. But what has happened in the last year or
Speaker 8:  two and something we reported out of that meeting that Zuckerberg had that
Speaker 8:  he disclosed for the first time is that the Met Ray Band glasses
Speaker 8:  are growing a lot faster than they anticipated. They've sold over 1 million
Speaker 8:  units of them, which isn't a lot in the grand scheme of the Quest, you know,
Speaker 8:  the Quest sells millions of units a year, right? It's already at like what
Speaker 8:  a solid gaming console, you know, annual sales would be.
Speaker 8:  But they see a lot more potential and what the Raybans represent
Speaker 8:  because they see it as a much more mass consumer device
Speaker 8:  than the Quest which even despite their best attempts over the years
Speaker 8:  still remains a gadget for
Speaker 8:  teen boys and gamers. I would say mostly.
Speaker 2:  Do you think Meta's right to think that there's more mainstream potential
Speaker 2:  in the RayBan glasses?
Speaker 8:  I don't know. I think
Speaker 8:  they're easier to wear. You know, Meta knows internally that one of the
Speaker 8:  biggest barriers to adoption for the Quest has been that it's just not comfortable
Speaker 8:  and it doesn't look good when you wear it. It's not a thing you wear out.
Speaker 8:  Right. Right. Whereas Raybans are things that are, and the other glasses
Speaker 8:  are gonna do or designed to be worn out. They're designed to be used more
Speaker 8:  like you would use a phone. Whereas the quest and mixed reality, even with
Speaker 8:  the mixed stuff they're doing, it really is more of an isolating experience.
Speaker 8:  Something that you would use in your house. And I don't think
Speaker 8:  that's gonna change. I think if anything those two product lines will further
Speaker 8:  separate from each other before coming back together. I do think they will
Speaker 8:  come back together, but it may take like 10 years when the tech gets really
Speaker 8:  good enough. So yeah, that's kind of the state of where things are. And just
Speaker 8:  back to your original point, like are they changing? I think the change
Speaker 8:  is that the Ray Bands and Zuckerberg's
Speaker 8:  excitement about them and also his kind of obsession with everything
Speaker 8:  AI that they're doing and how that intersects with the Ray band specifically
Speaker 8:  has really shifted a lot of the attention and a lot of the spending into
Speaker 8:  the wearable segment.
Speaker 2:  Right. I do think though I, if I were to
Speaker 2:  Galaxy Brain all of this for a second, it seems like Meta has
Speaker 2:  been desperately trying to invent its own more or
Speaker 2:  less solely controlled platform for a very long time.
Speaker 2:  Right. It got, it got hosed by mobile in so, so many ways. And
Speaker 2:  well Apple's. Yeah, Apple's control. Well Mobile made Facebook but also like
Speaker 2:  Right. Kept it from making a lot more money than it could have. And Apple
Speaker 2:  has made Meta's life very hard in a number of ways over the years.
Speaker 8:  Poor Meta. They're only worth $2 trillion.
Speaker 2:  I know. It's gotta be awful honestly. Yeah. Like I feel bad for Mark and
Speaker 2:  his gold chains. But
Speaker 2:  so I think a, a real impetus for trying to make the Metaverse happen was
Speaker 2:  based on the assumption that okay, this is going to be the next platform
Speaker 2:  and we have to be the ones who make it. Like I think that's been very important
Speaker 2:  to this company. And I think If you squint a little at
Speaker 2:  the combination of Meta AI and the RayBan Smart
Speaker 2:  Glasses, there's a platform in there and that that maybe
Speaker 2:  what is happening is Mark Zuckerberg is looking and saying, okay, I can bet
Speaker 2:  many, many, many billions of dollars on this really expensive, really complicated
Speaker 2:  virtual world thing that is at best a ways away
Speaker 2:  and at worst just not interesting to most people. Or I can
Speaker 2:  invent this other platform that I sort of accidentally discovered
Speaker 2:  just by partnering with a cool company in Italy. And so like
Speaker 2:  that's where I'm like maybe, maybe the big thing that Meta needs
Speaker 2:  it thinks it can get out of this combination of AI and smart glasses is much
Speaker 2:  more quickly than it can get it out of the metaverse.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I think the Metaverse is more of a grind. I think
Speaker 8:  if antitrust did not exist, if scrutiny of Meta did not exist, they
Speaker 8:  would've probably just like bought Roblox for an absurd amount of money right
Speaker 8:  now and made it horizon worlds. That's really what they want it to be.
Speaker 2:  That's such an interesting parallel universe in which that was allowed to
Speaker 2:  happen, right?
Speaker 8:  Like I think it would And the reason that Bosworth says in that
Speaker 8:  memo that Horizon has to work is that they can't just
Speaker 8:  have dumb hardware that doesn't have software. Right. The Ray
Speaker 8:  bands have the ai, the voice stuff, the camera, they have
Speaker 8:  utility. The Quest is a content device, it's an entertainment device,
Speaker 8:  an immersion device. And for Meta's business model,
Speaker 8:  which is ads, right? To really extend into the metaverse and eventually pay
Speaker 8:  for all this, they really need a social platform that is
Speaker 8:  embodied avatars that works in that kind of a context. And horizon is still
Speaker 8:  way behind, you know, it's still way behind where Roblox is way
Speaker 8:  behind where Epic is with its Fortnite kind of world building
Speaker 8:  experiment that it's earlier in than Roblox but making progress in.
Speaker 8:  So I mean he's right in that sense. Horizon needs to work, they need to have
Speaker 8:  their own social experience on this. They're just not there yet. Right.
Speaker 8:  I mean look, would a lot of companies,
Speaker 8:  you know much smaller than Medicare for having
Speaker 8:  something like the Quest? I don't know. I mean it sells millions of units
Speaker 8:  a year. They don't really make money on the hardware, but they are
Speaker 8:  seeding the world with millions of these devices. You
Speaker 8:  know, they're not very retentive devices. That's been a big problem though,
Speaker 8:  is that like, unless you're a gamer or like a young boy
Speaker 8:  who likes to troll people on in virtual reality, it's,
Speaker 8:  they're just really not something that people come back to. I'm also like
Speaker 8:  speaking from experience there, it's just not something that
Speaker 2:  Is Yeah. Mine's sitting right over there and I haven't picked it up in a
Speaker 2:  frustratingly long period of time.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. 'cause you don't have a really good reason to unless there's like a
Speaker 8:  game or something that you really wanna play. Whereas the Raybans are like,
Speaker 8:  these could actually just be your glasses. Right. And they actually just
Speaker 8:  upgrade what your glasses can do. Yeah. And you know, that's where
Speaker 8:  things get really interesting And you know, something that
Speaker 8:  Zuckerberg said in this recent all hands about that is that, you know,
Speaker 8:  this is going to be the year where basically they know
Speaker 8:  whether AI glasses as they now call them, instead of
Speaker 8:  AR glasses are going to be this next mass market
Speaker 8:  iPhone level thing based on the sales trajectory or whether it's going to
Speaker 8:  be in his own words, a grind. Interesting. And If you had
Speaker 8:  to describe Meta's entire hardware adventure over the last
Speaker 8:  10 years, it would definitely be a grind. So yes, they're prepared to keep
Speaker 8:  grinding, but I think, you know, this year it's a matter of whether,
Speaker 8:  look do the Ray Bands end the year it's 5 million sales, 10 million sales,
Speaker 8:  do the devices they're planning to ship, you know, later this year
Speaker 8:  really, you know, get people excited or do they flop? You know, that's the
Speaker 8:  stakes and I think he feels the stakes of that.
Speaker 8:  But you know, we have yet to see those devices. They're coming very soon.
Speaker 2:  What are those devices? You've scooped the roadmap so many times I've lost
Speaker 2:  track of what's coming and there's the Orion ones, which you saw Yeah
Speaker 2:  last year we talked about on the show. And those are not coming
Speaker 2:  this year. But something on the journey to that is coming this year. We think
Speaker 2:  that
Speaker 8:  Right? That's right. Yeah. Orion is not and Orion
Speaker 8:  itself what, and it was very clear on the writeup for us that it is not the
Speaker 8:  thing they're gonna ship a version that is like it will ship but it will
Speaker 8:  not ship until at least 2027 and it's gonna be very expensive. It's gonna
Speaker 8:  cost like what a decked out MacBook Pro costs.
Speaker 8:  What what is happening later this year is the first pair of
Speaker 8:  Meta designed glasses. So what they've done with
Speaker 8:  Ray Band and Luxottica to date, I think they've really rode the coattails
Speaker 8:  of that brand. And you know, Wayfairs are just this like super
Speaker 8:  classic cool classes design that everyone,
Speaker 2:  It does sort of feel like If you have access to Wayfairs, why would you,
Speaker 2:  why reinvent the wheel? Sure. Like, I don't know.
Speaker 8:  Well because they had already been building this device that
Speaker 8:  that the hardware takes a long time and this device was starting in the works
Speaker 8:  way before the, the Ray bands took off. It's called it's
Speaker 8:  Hyper Nova, it's gonna have a heads up display, it's basically their version
Speaker 8:  of Google Glass. It's going to be much better than what Glass was 10 years
Speaker 8:  ago. But it's gonna have the heads up display for things like showing
Speaker 8:  the photos you take incoming notifications, your interactions with Meta
Speaker 8:  ai getting some more visual feedback. They're gonna be pricey. I
Speaker 8:  wouldn't have be surprised if they're at least a thousand dollars. And the
Speaker 8:  stakes are that again, these are not designed as
Speaker 8:  raybans, they're Meta glasses and I think Luxotica will obviously play
Speaker 8:  a role in how they are distributed and maybe we'll do things like prescriptions
Speaker 8:  for them. But this is Meta's first real like shot at
Speaker 8:  can we do glasses ourselves from a societal
Speaker 8:  acceptance perspective? Right? Sure. And they're gonna be
Speaker 8:  pricey and they're gonna be an early adopter thing and if it ends up being
Speaker 8:  just a bad product, that's really not good for what Meta
Speaker 8:  is trying to do over the long run. And then they're also going to be doing
Speaker 8:  a lot more with Luxotica that I that I think while there's still risk there,
Speaker 8:  it's way less risky again because of the fact that Luxottica is
Speaker 8:  designing these things and Meta is basically just like the tech supplier.
Speaker 8:  So they're gonna do glasses with Oakley for athletes. I wouldn't
Speaker 8:  be surprised if we see, you know, Luxotica owns Supreme now would be surprised
Speaker 8:  if we see Supreme Glasses down the road. They're gonna do all kinds of these
Speaker 8:  glasses with Luxotica. But those are gonna be, you know, few hundred bucks
Speaker 8:  not ar at least to start. And then Hyper
Speaker 8:  Nova. And the reason Bosworth says in that memo, you know we're
Speaker 8:  gonna have half a dozen wearables this year is they're gonna have variants
Speaker 8:  of Hyper Nova but they're also gonna be finally shipping this thing that
Speaker 8:  I wrote about with Orion, which is their wristband. Which Oh right. Is
Speaker 8:  really one of the coolest pieces of technology I've used in a long time.
Speaker 8:  And I'm really interested to see how the world at large receives this
Speaker 8:  thing. It's how you controlled Orion and it's how you'll control
Speaker 8:  Hyper Nova these glasses later this year. And
Speaker 8:  it's uses EMG technology to basically
Speaker 8:  read your mind. They don't say that and that's not what's happening but it
Speaker 8:  feels that way. Yeah. Where you can, you know, do a very subtle
Speaker 8:  pinch gesture to click drag, that sort of stuff. Interact
Speaker 8:  like minority report style listing things. And it's the first time I've used
Speaker 8:  like a new input method and a really long time
Speaker 8:  that felt supernatural. I would put it on par with like,
Speaker 8:  you remember the first time you did eye tracking with the Vision Pro?
Speaker 2:  Sure, yeah.
Speaker 8:  Something like that where it's like wow, this is just a way more natural
Speaker 8:  way to interact with something. So that's gonna be really interesting
Speaker 8:  to see how that works with the glasses later this year. And it
Speaker 8:  will get people a taste of what's coming with the full fledged air glasses
Speaker 8:  in a few years. But the Ray bands for now are very much what
Speaker 8:  they're putting a lot of, you know, marketing and investment
Speaker 8:  into, we just saw the Super Bowl ad and I think they're gonna be riding
Speaker 8:  that hype wave for a
Speaker 2:  While. Yeah, I mean it, it seems like Meta in a really interesting way is
Speaker 2:  both trying to do the opposite of Apple, which we've been talking about for
Speaker 2:  a while, right? Apple is like we're going to build the best thing humanity
Speaker 2:  can possibly create and it's gonna cost $700,000 and no one's gonna
Speaker 2:  like it, but, and then, and then we'll figure out what to do from there.
Speaker 2:  That hasn't gone so great. Meta, I think
Speaker 2:  sort of by accident frankly seems to have found the exact opposite approach
Speaker 2:  where they're like, we're gonna take a thing that you already, like we're
Speaker 2:  going to make it a little bit better and then we're just gonna kind, kind
Speaker 2:  of keep adding stuff from there. And so it feels like, the question for
Speaker 2:  me is I think the, the Meta Ray band thing is is like that's,
Speaker 2:  that works like that I think is going to be a thing that will show up in
Speaker 2:  mainstream glasses everywhere, right? The like your glasses are now also
Speaker 2:  headphones and a little AI chat bot and there's a camera in the temple
Speaker 2:  like done. I think that is absolutely a mainstream use case.
Speaker 2:  Not very long from now. The question is how far up you can go from
Speaker 2:  there before you start losing people. Yeah. And to me that's the big question
Speaker 2:  of this year. 'cause we're gonna see a lot of people try, right? There were
Speaker 2:  all those companies that CES that were doing the little like green
Speaker 2:  heads up display right in front of the eyes. Some people will like that,
Speaker 2:  some people are gonna hate that it's, and so Meta seems like it's, it's
Speaker 2:  trying to like pull up on the the like how much
Speaker 2:  can this thing be chain? And I, I think
Speaker 2:  this is going to be an interesting year to see whether any of that actually
Speaker 2:  matters to most people or if everybody starts to be like, oh you've just
Speaker 2:  made a thing I wanna wear less. Which defeats the purpose of the whole thing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And that's the real stress for them with Hyper Nova. The
Speaker 8:  glasses that they're putting out with the display is, and the band is like
Speaker 8:  we're taking we Ray bands that have tech in them and giving you like a
Speaker 8:  roughly a thousand dollars Google Glass redux device, but
Speaker 8:  it's Meta, you know, all the brand concerns there. And by the way
Speaker 8:  there's like a mind reading band that you have to like relearn how to interact
Speaker 8:  with a computer and like maybe early adopters will love it if they
Speaker 8:  don't. That's pretty tough for you know, something that Meta is spending
Speaker 8:  billions a year on and has yet to really see any meaningful, you know, profit
Speaker 8:  from. But do not discount Zuckerberg's
Speaker 8:  willingness to grind this out. It's really interesting to me that like in
Speaker 8:  the 10 years that Reality Labs has been going now roughly
Speaker 8:  I this it's been like eight is that, you know, there's been so much
Speaker 8:  written about how this is a, you know, waste and how Meta it's gonna
Speaker 8:  tank Meta. And Meta has literally added like a trillion dollars in
Speaker 8:  market cap since it started Reality Labs. So they
Speaker 8:  can afford to walk in chew gum as Zuckerberg says. It's just a matter of
Speaker 8:  how long and like if the products don't actually
Speaker 8:  get used or received well in the next year or two, it's
Speaker 8:  gonna really set them back. And you know, he said in this meeting, like we
Speaker 8:  have a wide open, you know, field right now because Apple's dialed back,
Speaker 8:  you know, Google's still trying to get its, you know, whatever the 15th version
Speaker 8:  of its AR strategy off the ground. Yeah. No
Speaker 2:  One's afraid of Google's hardware division. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And so they have the early start and it's a matter of whether they can capitalize
Speaker 8:  on that and whether these products will really hit or not. And they've gotta,
Speaker 8:  you know, the quest is like we, we don't talk about it as much 'cause it's
Speaker 8:  just not as exciting anymore. But like they have to make that work, they
Speaker 8:  have to make it retentive. They have to find a way to make money from that
Speaker 8:  multi-year investment and horizon. They
Speaker 8:  really needed to be a thing that is like a creator platform as well
Speaker 8:  that people wanna build worlds in. And that's where the AI stuff starts to
Speaker 8:  intersect. It's like AI and PC's, generative
Speaker 8:  world building where it could kind of accelerate that stuff. But they're
Speaker 8:  still so behind Roblox and Epic on just the tooling and
Speaker 8:  the ease of use. So I don't even think Horizon is even in the App store still.
Speaker 8:  I think it's just a web app. Maybe that's changed recently. But I mean
Speaker 2:  It's, it's one thing to look at Horizon as like a
Speaker 2:  sort of primitive version of a technology to come. Yeah. And it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  well clearly they were too early, this thing isn't very good yet. Maybe there's
Speaker 2:  a roadmap to it but you put it next to Roblox and Fortnite which people are
Speaker 2:  functionally using for the exact things that Meta is looking for and it
Speaker 2:  just, it just looks like a disaster. Yeah. So let's talk about the
Speaker 2:  social thing on the other side of this because I think if I were to give
Speaker 2:  Meta credit for one thing in particular, it's that it has figured out how
Speaker 2:  to make AI in a way that makes sense for literally
Speaker 2:  everything it's doing. Like what you just described is like Meta has built
Speaker 2:  all this AI so that it works for reality labs. It
Speaker 2:  also has made these glasses a hit. In part it's also powering the ads business,
Speaker 2:  which is really like that trillion dollars is like in large part because
Speaker 2:  Meta has made its ads better thanks to ai. Like yeah we don't talk about
Speaker 2:  that 'cause it's really boring, but like that's what happened. Yeah, Google
Speaker 2:  is like, you can write emails and Meta metas like our ads are better now
Speaker 2:  and everybody gives them money. But then on the other
Speaker 2:  side there is like Facebook and Instagram
Speaker 2:  and Threads, which I feel like we don't talk about anymore because they're
Speaker 2:  just like, they're like furniture. They just sort of exist and we don't worry
Speaker 2:  about them. But then like in in on earnings calls
Speaker 2:  and in meetings and stuff, Zuckerberg is talking about bringing back the
Speaker 2:  OG Facebook. Yeah. And they're talking about bringing AI to more of Facebook.
Speaker 2:  Like what, what is coming on the social side of Meta that
Speaker 2:  you're hearing about
Speaker 8:  The OG Facebook stuff is something I'm still digging into and very interested
Speaker 8:  by. They've been trying to position Facebook as a
Speaker 8:  Gen Z app for the last few years. They're
Speaker 8:  keenly aware and we saw this actually in the stuff we saw through the Haugen
Speaker 8:  leakers that if they start to lose younger
Speaker 8:  users over time, it's really bad for a social network company.
Speaker 8:  So they have to make Facebook something that like, you know,
Speaker 8:  it's not just something you check once a year to see why
Speaker 8:  your parents are saying what they're saying to their friends on social media.
Speaker 8:  Right. It needs to be a thing that is like relevant beyond marketplace or
Speaker 8:  whatever and groups is working for them a little bit there. But I thought
Speaker 8:  it was interesting on the last earnings call he said he wants it to be a
Speaker 8:  lot more culturally influential.
Speaker 2:  I mean, don't we? All right. Like
Speaker 8:  Yeah, don't we all Sure. This I think has to do with ego
Speaker 8:  a bit. I mean this is what started the company. It is one of the
Speaker 8:  biggest products of all time that has had the most longevity, but it has
Speaker 8:  lost its influence. No question
Speaker 8:  that's gonna be really tough. And I'm not sure how they make it cool. Again,
Speaker 8:  they've been trying, like I said, for years, but Instagram, you know, is
Speaker 8:  staying strong for them. It's not growing quite as fast still as they had
Speaker 8:  hoped, but it's just like really saturated in culture and that's really good
Speaker 8:  for them.
Speaker 2:  Instagram actually strikes me as the most sticky thing. Like
Speaker 2:  if, If you were to say like I've come from the future
Speaker 2:  it's, it's 2029 and there's only one Meta service left,
Speaker 2:  I would, I would guess it's Instagram at this point. I really would. Which
Speaker 2:  I would not have said a few years ago.
Speaker 8:  You might be right there. It's definitely got staying power and
Speaker 8:  relevance and it's more, you know, used by, by younger people.
Speaker 8:  Obviously Threads is earlier, but like it's still
Speaker 8:  writing a lot of Instagram's engagement loops. Yeah. They really
Speaker 8:  haven't made it a standalone growth entity and they really haven't
Speaker 8:  figured out like how it relates to X and blue sky. I think
Speaker 8:  the next year or so, especially on the political front will be really interesting
Speaker 8:  for that.
Speaker 8:  But yeah man bringing Facebook back, who would've thought 20 years later
Speaker 2:  It will be purely from a like
Speaker 2:  reporting and person on the internet perspective. It's gonna be fascinating
Speaker 2:  because that would be a, a truly
Speaker 2:  unique moment on the internet to bring something like that all the way
Speaker 2:  back around to the point that it became like a must visit
Speaker 2:  destination for young people. Which it was
Speaker 2:  like, yeah, Facebook was the most, like when I was in college, it was the
Speaker 2:  most important thing on the internet. Yeah. And, and it is, it is no longer
Speaker 2:  that to, I think anybody getting that back would be really something.
Speaker 8:  It would. And you know, I've done a lot of actually reporting and
Speaker 8:  analysis of that like over the last 10 years. Facebook itself
Speaker 8:  has done actually a lot to fragment the internet and fragment the social
Speaker 8:  internet specifically by cramming video in there for ads by
Speaker 8:  cramming AI into their stuff from people you don't follow.
Speaker 8:  Instead of trying to actually address the core thing that Facebook was, which
Speaker 8:  was a place you could reliably see interesting stuff from the people you
Speaker 8:  actually know. They basically just slowly mutated the product
Speaker 8:  over a decade to be something that is like unrecognizable and not
Speaker 8:  personal at all for people that are under 45
Speaker 8:  and undoing. That seems really tough.
Speaker 8:  I'm sure there's a lot of people who haven't deleted their accounts but like
Speaker 8:  getting them back in and I think the internet actually could use what Facebook
Speaker 8:  originally was though, doesn't it? It feels super fragmented with x and blue
Speaker 8:  sky and all and group chats and a lot of the group chat activity is because
Speaker 8:  Facebook pushed people out of feeds that were strangely starting to feel
Speaker 8:  foreign and and bad and like they were killing democracy into group
Speaker 8:  chats. Can you get them back out of group chats into a feed of your friends?
Speaker 8:  That's gonna be really interesting to see. I'm, I'm very skeptical of that,
Speaker 8:  but it's something we're gonna be paying close attention to.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it is one of the, one of those things that if he's serious about it,
Speaker 2:  there are a few CEOs other than Mark Zuckerberg who could make the hard decisions
Speaker 2:  required to do that. Yeah. Because it would, it would cost you a lot of money.
Speaker 2:  Like just pretty straightforwardly,
Speaker 8:  You know, he actually, people didn't catch that. He actually hinted at that
Speaker 8:  in the last earnings call. He said something, I'm paraphrasing, but it was
Speaker 8:  a almost throwaway line where he was like, and we're gonna do things that
Speaker 8:  like will impact near term results but it's gonna be good for the
Speaker 8:  future. So I think the Facebook app, what you see when you open it is
Speaker 8:  going to change pretty dramatically in the next year.
Speaker 2:  Fascinating. Listen, if, if Mark Zuckerberg can get me using Facebook again
Speaker 2:  every day, that will be the, the tech CEO coup of the century
Speaker 2:  and I, and there are a lot of those going on right now. Last thing
Speaker 2:  before we go, there's been a lot of fallout internally that you've been tracking
Speaker 2:  and reporting on after Zuckerberg goes on Joe Rogan and talks about masculine
Speaker 2:  energy, they've done some layoffs. Part of what I'm thinking about when I
Speaker 2:  mention like this feels like a different kind of company I is just
Speaker 2:  like they've changed the way they talk to staff in these all hands. Like
Speaker 2:  Mark is yelling about leakers and posting your stories about the leakers,
Speaker 2:  about the leakers. Like what is your read on kind of the vibe
Speaker 2:  inside of Meta as those things shift? Well,
Speaker 8:  I mean it's tough. Meta is a huge company. I think when you talk about the
Speaker 8:  vibe of a 77,000 person company, you have to obviously
Speaker 8:  acknowledge that it's not a monolith. And there are a lot of lifers still.
Speaker 8:  There's people who try to tune out the drama.
Speaker 8:  There is a strong growing faction of
Speaker 8:  disillusioned, you know, pissed off people at, you
Speaker 8:  know, what has happened in the last couple of months with all the MAGA fueled
Speaker 8:  content changes, the Joe Rogan stuff,
Speaker 8:  taking tampons outta the men's room, all this culture war,
Speaker 8:  anti woke stuff and then how
Speaker 8:  these layoffs have been handled. You know, he basically copied Elon with
Speaker 8:  that and said they were gonna be targeting low performers, which
Speaker 8:  is rough. It's, it's a rough way to go out to, to have the CEO saying, you
Speaker 8:  know, this person's a low performer and have it be
Speaker 8:  SEOed to death for forever. So that's not
Speaker 8:  endeared a lot of goodwill. I think there's gonna be a lot more to come on.
Speaker 8:  The employee versus management tension there kind of reminds
Speaker 8:  me of where Google was, I don't know, six or seven years ago
Speaker 8:  when they were really going through all that employee upheaval and
Speaker 8:  Google still has it, but they've largely stamped it out or at least like
Speaker 8:  tamed it to such a degree that it doesn't feel, I don't know as dramatic
Speaker 8:  as it does at Meta right now. But Meta is very much going through a cultural
Speaker 8:  shift, which is what I've been writing about, where it was probably the most
Speaker 8:  open internally big tech company. And they're realizing they can no longer
Speaker 8:  do that with how big it is. And also just how
Speaker 8:  pissed off some people are at how things are going right. And so they're
Speaker 8:  clamping down on that stuff and we saw some of that with the Francis Haugen
Speaker 8:  leakers and how they reacted to that. But this feels like the next turn there.
Speaker 8:  And I do think metal will look a lot different, not just externally but internally
Speaker 8:  in the next year or so.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. We've talked a lot about Sonos on this show
Speaker 2:  over the last year. I think more than most companies its size
Speaker 2:  actually it is just a weird, interesting important company
Speaker 2:  in this space. I think if you're a listener to the show, I would say there's
Speaker 2:  a higher than average chance that you own some Sonos stuff.
Speaker 2:  This company has just kind of been around in our lives as things that people
Speaker 2:  who like technology like for a long time. But then Sonos kind of
Speaker 2:  spent last year setting all of that goodwill on fire
Speaker 2:  and we've talked about a lot of the news moments here. Sonos released an
Speaker 2:  app, Sonos released headphones, the app went terribly, the headphones were
Speaker 2:  fine. Patrick Spence, the CEO ended up being ousted. We've
Speaker 2:  talked about a lot of that, but I think I wanna go back and understand
Speaker 2:  the full story and see what happened inside of that company
Speaker 2:  and what we can learn. So again, it helps that I have access to
Speaker 2:  one of the people who knows this story the best. Chris Welch who has been
Speaker 2:  chronicling this story for us since the beginning and has gotten lots of
Speaker 2:  scoops and has some big scoops on what's to come from Sonos. So
Speaker 2:  let's get Chris and just dive into this. Chris Welch, welcome back to the
Speaker 2:  show. Hello David. It's good to be back. There's been a lot that's happened
Speaker 2:  in the last few months. There really is. And for once, I have not brought
Speaker 2:  you here to test terrible microphones, but, but what I
Speaker 2:  wanna do is I wanna talk about like the last 12
Speaker 2:  months of Sonos, which is a thing we've covered, covered a lot on the show,
Speaker 2:  but we've covered it kind of in newsy moments and
Speaker 2:  I have found myself, the further we get into the Sonos story, I
Speaker 2:  feel like the less I understand what actually happened here and what is
Speaker 2:  going on inside of this company and what is gonna happen next for
Speaker 2:  Sonos. And you, you had this big scoop last week about Pinewood, the set
Speaker 2:  top box that Sonos is working on, which I think is gonna be another moment
Speaker 2:  in time, but I just wanna sort of, as best we can tell the story
Speaker 2:  of really 2024 for Sonos. Yeah. And kind of
Speaker 2:  what that means going forward. Does that, does that sound all right to you?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 13:  Absolutely. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So I wanna start, I think it was in March of last year
Speaker 2:  when you had a scoop that Sonos was
Speaker 2:  releasing a new app.
Speaker 2:  What do you remember what you knew about this app at the time
Speaker 2:  that was like what we thought was coming back in March?
Speaker 13:  So the word back then is they were working on a new app for their headphones,
Speaker 13:  the Ace. And at the time we didn't realize it was gonna be like the whole
Speaker 13:  new Sonos app, but that's what it came to be like a whole
Speaker 13:  huge overhaul of the Sonos app, like a whole do over essentially of like
Speaker 13:  all the core technology in there and stuff like that. And so it was a huge
Speaker 13:  project and there were good reasons for doing so because like the,
Speaker 13:  so much of the Sonos like foundation is ancient, like the Sonos APIs held
Speaker 13:  together with like duct tape and bubble gum, like it's been around forever
Speaker 13:  and they've like barely worked on it. And so it's like kind of amazing that
Speaker 13:  Sonos whole platform still works as well as it does all these years later.
Speaker 13:  So they had good reasons to like redo the app and start from scratch and,
Speaker 13:  and do a big overhaul, but the way they went about it was just the
Speaker 13:  worst way imaginable.
Speaker 2:  Right. And I, in in retrospect we've, we've definitely
Speaker 2:  connected all of this change to Sonos is about to launch a pair of headphones
Speaker 2:  and needed this big sort of infrastructural upgrade. Like you're
Speaker 2:  talking about what do we know about what actually needed to happen there?
Speaker 2:  Like was this a thing Sonos actually had to do together that it
Speaker 2:  was like the, these headphones are coming out, we have to do this new technical
Speaker 2:  upgrade to make this possible. Did they just sort of decide to do it all
Speaker 2:  at once for big, you know, launchy branding energy? Like what was
Speaker 2:  actually necessary here to get the headphones out the door?
Speaker 13:  I think the leadership thought the whole process was gonna be a lot easier
Speaker 13:  than it was because from the start the ACE were like built only to
Speaker 13:  support the new app. Like they didn't, they never worked with the old one
Speaker 13:  at all. It's like from the jump they were like designed for the new app
Speaker 13:  and so they, they had planned all this like coincide at the same time.
Speaker 13:  And so I think they were very, very optimistic and like why
Speaker 13:  they like decided to like put the app out and not do a
Speaker 13:  beta or anything like that is still kind of a mystery. That's
Speaker 13:  something I'm sure that Patrick Spence is very
Speaker 13:  mad about these days. Yeah. His choices back then. And so
Speaker 13:  yeah, so the plan was to like do it all at once, put the headphones out,
Speaker 13:  make a big splashy introduction for the ace. This whole situation
Speaker 13:  has now caused those, caused those headphones to fall on their face and
Speaker 13:  I don't think they're ever gonna recover unfortunately. So it was
Speaker 13:  all for Naugh unfortunately.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. So I'm, I'm getting ahead of myself in this story here, but I
Speaker 2:  I that you just brought up, one of the things I had been thinking about the
Speaker 2:  most with the Sonos story is obviously by now
Speaker 2:  everybody knows the Bones app ships in May total disaster
Speaker 2:  kind of ruins Sonos in a very real way. The headphones are
Speaker 2:  very good, right? Yeah. Do you, is there a parallel universe
Speaker 2:  in which Sonos does like the
Speaker 2:  least with the headphones, like ships the,
Speaker 2:  the app with like whatever tiny upgrades they needed but didn't try to sort
Speaker 2:  of reinvent everything about the entire Sonos system to make the Ace work
Speaker 2:  the ace ships and it's a huge hit. Like is that, could that have happened?
Speaker 13:  I think it was always gonna be a pretty uphill climb for the Ace just 'cause
Speaker 13:  there's so much competition. Like Sonos saw this as a huge market opportunity
Speaker 13:  and it is a huge market, but you've got long time
Speaker 13:  heavyweights like Apple Beats, Bose, Sony brands that have
Speaker 13:  been around forever have their reputation. And so they were coming in with
Speaker 13:  these headphones that are very good, like you said, they're super comfortable,
Speaker 13:  they sound great. The TV audio swap feature is very neat.
Speaker 13:  And so yeah, they had like good aspects, but
Speaker 13:  trying to like top, you know, face off against Apple and
Speaker 13:  and and Bose is just a pretty daunting task.
Speaker 2:  Fair. But it does seem like even in that case, I think there's
Speaker 2:  an interesting thing that I think was happening at Sonos and has been happening
Speaker 2:  for a while where like this company is desperate to be a mainstream
Speaker 2:  brand. They're desperate
Speaker 13:  For growth. Sure, that's fair. One key question about this whole situation
Speaker 13:  is like, should Sonos should ever have gone public in the first place? Because
Speaker 13:  now they're a company that is like after growth above all else, finding
Speaker 13:  new customers trying to expand their customer base. And it's like how does
Speaker 13:  an audio speaker company really do that? You know, how much growth is there
Speaker 13:  really? And so that's a big, like should they have stayed private like
Speaker 13:  Bose and just like done their own thing forever and just like put out nice
Speaker 13:  new products every few years and just made a decent amount of income and
Speaker 13:  revenue and just been happy with that. But they are public now and
Speaker 13:  I think their biggest stock shareholder is BlackRock. And so these
Speaker 13:  like giant corporations that are gonna like push them to like grow and
Speaker 13:  grow and grow and so, right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean it, it is a thing I've always wondered is, is
Speaker 2:  what was it that caused Sonos to stop wanting to be
Speaker 2:  kind of a niche high-end audio company? And there are lots of those out there,
Speaker 2:  right? Like I think about like Bowers and Wilkins a lot, which is like a
Speaker 2:  company that a lot of people really care about. But if you're not like an
Speaker 2:  audio person, you've probably never heard of it. And one of the things that
Speaker 2:  Sonos did for so long that was so impressive was it had this kind
Speaker 2:  of high-end technology. Its stuff was very good, but it was like known
Speaker 2:  to humans. Like regular people bought Sonos stuff in a way that most people
Speaker 2:  were not running around buying Bowers and Wilkins stuff, right? And that's
Speaker 2:  so shade to Bowers and Wilkins, it's just like a different kind of brand.
Speaker 2:  But Sonos had found this thing where it was, it was like a
Speaker 2:  luxury audio company without being
Speaker 2:  sort of snobby about it. Yeah. In a way that was actually really powerful
Speaker 2:  for Sonos. And it feels like if it had just stayed there, it could have
Speaker 2:  done that thing for a very long time. And instead it was like, okay, what
Speaker 2:  can we do that will make us, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  relevant to people who don't otherwise care. And I, what I've
Speaker 2:  always wondered is like, is that Patrick Spence being like, how do I be cooler
Speaker 2:  and fancier and more famous? Or is it investors being like, where
Speaker 2:  is the quarterly growth? And it sounds like maybe it's a little of both,
Speaker 2:  but mostly the second thing. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  I think Patrick Spence is a quite a story because I think like for the most
Speaker 13:  part he was a pretty good CEO. Like Sonos had a lot of good products under
Speaker 13:  him. You know, the arc, the Rome and the move,
Speaker 13:  you know, quite a few string of hits. They were good products at least.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. But like this, this whole app debacle was like really his undoing
Speaker 13:  and like he should have, you know, played it much safer than he did.
Speaker 13:  And like part of that shift was like all the marketing they brought in this
Speaker 13:  guy from Dyson Jordan, sax Mar who got fired last week or
Speaker 13:  this week rather. And his whole thing was like, he wanted to make Sonos
Speaker 13:  more fashionable and like more mainstream. And like that was his world.
Speaker 13:  Like he came from Dyson, like high fashion. Right. You know, fancy tech.
Speaker 13:  And so like, and so he didn't hold the Sonos core customer base in high
Speaker 13:  regard. Like you saw them as kind of like niche and wanted to like expand
Speaker 13:  and grow and grow and grow. And the Ace was the whole big fixture
Speaker 13:  of this whole plan and didn't, didn't quite pan out. And like the marketing
Speaker 13:  around the ace was strange. Like they spent a lot of money. Like if it's
Speaker 13:  like last fall you couldn't miss the Sonos Ace subway campaigns in York.
Speaker 13:  They were
Speaker 2:  Everywhere,
Speaker 13:  But they didn't really say anything about the headphones. It just like photos,
Speaker 13:  pretty photos and like showed the headphones, but they didn't say like what
Speaker 13:  they did, why they were different from like your standard Bose headphones.
Speaker 13:  And so like they spend a lot of money but like for what gain not much. So
Speaker 13:  like that was his whole idea is just to like, make Sonos more fashionable,
Speaker 13:  more beautiful and like bring in like that crowd and
Speaker 13:  not sure it was the play.
Speaker 2:  Well that's, I mean this is the thing I find so fascinating is like there's
Speaker 2:  a version of that strategy that I think could have worked right?
Speaker 2:  Like Sonos, Sonos as a sort of lifestyle brand kind of tracks
Speaker 2:  for me, right? Like I think in the way that people recognize Bose as more
Speaker 2:  than just a set of headphones, like people, people know Bose
Speaker 2:  for like the science of sound stuff and Beats is a lifestyle
Speaker 2:  brand, but in like a very different direction. I think like I can see why
Speaker 2:  Sonos would make that decision, but then like you have to keep shipping things
Speaker 2:  that are good, which brings us back to the app. And so this, this is kind
Speaker 2:  of the, the moment that you've chronicled a lot at
Speaker 2:  Sonos over the last whatever, 10 months since this happened. But the app
Speaker 2:  ships in May, the response is horrific. Like immediately off the jump,
Speaker 2:  everybody hates the app, it becomes a, it, it starts to snowball and
Speaker 2:  become a huge problem. Like what, what is your sense having reported this
Speaker 2:  out months later of kind of what the summer was like inside
Speaker 2:  of Sonos as all of this is roiling and going on?
Speaker 13:  I think they knew what they were in for quite honestly. 'cause like there
Speaker 13:  were people inside Sonos who knew from the jump that like it was buggy not
Speaker 13:  where it needed to be to like stay on target After that launch. And they
Speaker 13:  had people, like, they had a small group of beta testers who, who like
Speaker 13:  definitely were complaining but like felt like they weren't getting any
Speaker 13:  feedback for those complaints. They were just like filing bug reports and
Speaker 13:  getting nothing back. And so yeah, it was just a slow,
Speaker 13:  slow roll of a very big disaster coming and like, they should
Speaker 13:  have seen it coming. They should have, you know, paused or at least like
Speaker 13:  delayed the ace until the fall. Like I've always wondered like why not just,
Speaker 13:  you know, punt the ace to like the holidays and put 'em out. Then the app
Speaker 13:  would've been in a slightly better state than it was then. And so, but
Speaker 13:  no, they just went full steam ahead. Yeah. People were like crunched,
Speaker 13:  they were like working overtime, like hours and hours and hours. Their chief
Speaker 13:  software guy and Nick Millington was sending out video messages to like
Speaker 13:  all the staff saying, you know, please everybody work a little bit harder,
Speaker 13:  put in a few more hours and people were just burned out and yeah. And like,
Speaker 13:  yeah and people, people at Sonos really care about Sonos. Like that's what
Speaker 13:  I've learned covering them so much. Like they've got a great staff, very
Speaker 13:  passionate about the brand, but they were pushed to their limits and like
Speaker 13:  then, you know, so the AF happens and since that they've laid off 300
Speaker 13:  people and like they've all lost their jobs because of like bad decisions
Speaker 13:  by Spence and, and his cohorts. So yeah, it's been tough to see,
Speaker 2:  Draw that line for me a little bit actually. 'cause I think this is, there
Speaker 2:  was an interesting thing that happened where I think the perception of the
Speaker 2:  app debacle became so bad and I think to
Speaker 2:  some extent we can talk about this, but like, I actually think we will
Speaker 2:  remember the app as being worse than it actually was.
Speaker 2:  It, it made a huge mistake of pissing off the people who like Sonos the most.
Speaker 2:  Which is, which is a stupid thing to do, but as a, as a like it's not like
Speaker 2:  it broke every Sonos speaker in existence, right? Yeah. And I think the way
Speaker 2:  we remember it is like it completely destroyed everything and it's like,
Speaker 2:  no, they, they just didn't ship a sleep timers, right? Which is like, yeah,
Speaker 2:  there, there was a bunch of stuff missing and that stuff is real, but I think
Speaker 2:  it was not the like five alarm fire of a disaster that it could have been,
Speaker 2:  but it became that over time for some people
Speaker 13:  It was like, honestly like, I think and like sometimes it would work and
Speaker 13:  then it would just stop working like out of nowhere. Like all your speakers
Speaker 13:  would like vanish from the app and like If you were having a party or hosting
Speaker 13:  like a big event and like that's when the app went on the fritz. I could
Speaker 13:  see how that would be infuriating. Yeah. So like yeah,
Speaker 2:  Especially for a company whose whole thing was that, that never ever happened,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah. Like for years that never ever happened to people.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Yeah. So there plays some issues with like, just like products just
Speaker 13:  like vanishing from the app for no reason and stuff like that. But like
Speaker 13:  on the whole, like for me it's been fairly solid since May. Like I
Speaker 13:  haven't had that many problems. I've had like the occasional, you know,
Speaker 13:  issue or bug, but on the whole it's just like, yeah, things are missing
Speaker 13:  a feature were of absent for months that took way too long to bring back.
Speaker 13:  And so like this all just tells you like there should have been a beta from
Speaker 13:  the, from the very beginning they should have had two apps like out at the
Speaker 13:  same time during this transition. And so yeah, it's just kind of,
Speaker 13:  I don't know, it just boggles the mind that like no one there like made
Speaker 13:  that decision so it was too late.
Speaker 2:  It reminds me a little of the, the stories we've heard about the, the humane
Speaker 2:  pin from last year that there were groups of those early
Speaker 2:  testers who were basically screaming as though they were blue in the face
Speaker 2:  about like, this thing doesn't work, you can't ship it. And and eventually
Speaker 2:  I, and I think it's, I'm I'm actually sort of sympathetic to tech companies
Speaker 2:  in this spot because you hit a point where it's like, okay, we have, we have
Speaker 2:  booked ad campaigns, we have, we have giant inventory sitting in a warehouse
Speaker 2:  that costs us money every day. We don't sell it. This stuff is, it is hard
Speaker 2:  to pull back once you have already committed, right? Right. And so I
Speaker 2:  think what you see over and over these companies do is just, just keep charging
Speaker 2:  through. And I think it's usually a mistake, but I also completely understand
Speaker 2:  why these companies keep making that mistake. It is just a, it's a hard moment,
Speaker 2:  but like when, when the people who make these products are
Speaker 2:  screaming at you about how they don't work, you should probably listen to
Speaker 2:  them. It's just a good rule of thumb I would say.
Speaker 13:  I agree. Like they saw the ace as like this like huge moment where they
Speaker 13:  would like have this new revenue driver and a big new product. And so I
Speaker 13:  think their mindset was like, let's just get it out and like,
Speaker 13:  let's see how it goes. We'll fix it afterwards. They didn't realize like
Speaker 13:  how bad the bugs would be for so many people all at once. And so,
Speaker 13:  yeah.
Speaker 2:  So is that, is that the kind of like I I, I mentioned sort of drawing the
Speaker 2:  line from bad app launch to sort of corporate
Speaker 2:  chaos. Lots of people get laid off, huge changes. Patrick Spence is out.
Speaker 2:  Sort of walk me through that spiral, I guess, like how do we get from that
Speaker 2:  launch to Sonos becoming sort of internally a very different
Speaker 2:  company?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, so the app came out, there were months and months of like just
Speaker 13:  bad vibes in the Sonos subreddit. Just complaints everywhere, every day.
Speaker 13:  And so it's been a pretty sad place for a few months. Did
Speaker 2:  You have a lot of people constantly telling you to keep yelling about how
Speaker 2:  bad the app is?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, yeah, of course.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I remember there were times where you were getting emails like all
Speaker 2:  day every day from people being like, you're not being mean enough to the
Speaker 2:  app.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. And it's like Sonos didn't help itself. Like there was one interview,
Speaker 13:  one statement they sent me where the now ex chief product officer said that
Speaker 13:  it took courage to put out the app, which it's never a word you want to
Speaker 13:  use in this industry. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Again, while we're giving free advice to tech founders, don't say that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Just it didn't, it didn't work for Apple when they talked about courage.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It didn't work for Sonos. Like, don't talk about your courage in putting
Speaker 2:  out products people don't like. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  So that, that didn't help. And it took like just way too long for Patrick
Speaker 13:  to come out and like make an apology. Like it took several weeks. Like he
Speaker 13:  had said, oh, we're working on it. And then finally he was like, we apologize.
Speaker 13:  I think back in November they put up this like multi-step plan, like, we're
Speaker 13:  gonna be much more careful with our software now we're gonna bring in a,
Speaker 13:  a quality ombudsperson was the role I think they had planned. And,
Speaker 13:  and just to like have like much more steps to make sure this would never
Speaker 13:  happen again. And more transparency for like people inside the company.
Speaker 13:  Like if they're saying, like trying to sound alarms, saying like, Hey, this
Speaker 13:  thing is a goddamn mess. Like what are we doing? And so do you think
Speaker 2:  That was good faith? I mean there's, there's a certain piece of this I think
Speaker 2:  that was like, like we were just talking about, they heard
Speaker 2:  the feedback people, people knew there were people who were unhappy, people
Speaker 2:  who were making this stuff presumably knew there were bugs and you, you eventually
Speaker 2:  sit around a conference table with executives and decide, well the,
Speaker 2:  the benefits of going ahead outweigh the costs of going ahead. We're just
Speaker 2:  gonna keep going. Like, do you think this idea of like, let's hire more people
Speaker 2:  to yell at us about when our products are bad was a real good faith
Speaker 2:  effort?
Speaker 13:  I think it was. 'cause I saw like how huge this had grown, this controversy.
Speaker 13:  And I think, yeah, I mean part of that plan was they were
Speaker 13:  gonna, like if Sonos didn't meet its targets, the topic executives like
Speaker 13:  weren't gonna get their bonus, which that provision like just made people
Speaker 13:  like what? Like who cares about your bonus? Like this is the most tone deaf
Speaker 13:  thing I could ever imagine. And so yeah, that didn't go over super well.
Speaker 13:  People were like super skeptical, which made sense after like going through
Speaker 13:  this whole mess. And so a few months later Patrick was out.
Speaker 13:  Tom Conrad, who's a long time SOAs board member, Tom is a
Speaker 13:  product guy. So like If you want someone to like steer the ship back in
Speaker 13:  the right direction, he had his first earnings call last week. He was like,
Speaker 13:  we have a lot more work to do. So he was pretty like mindful of like where
Speaker 13:  they are and where they have to go.
Speaker 2:  W where do you think that is at this moment? Like where would you put
Speaker 2:  Sonos kind of in, its in its own journey at this point? Because I think
Speaker 2:  to me maybe the most lingering thing from
Speaker 2:  what happened last year is that I think Sonos has burned a lot of the,
Speaker 2:  this stuff just works Goodwill that it had, right? Like I, I suspect
Speaker 2:  you and I have both told many people in our lives over the years to buy Sonos
Speaker 2:  stuff and so much of the logic is it sounds great,
Speaker 2:  it's 30% more expensive than everything else
Speaker 2:  it competes with, but it works. Yeah. And it is, it is,
Speaker 2:  it is worth the price. And I think to some extent that's still
Speaker 2:  true for a lot of Sonos products, but I think they have, it's
Speaker 13:  Still true. Like no one else does quite what Sonos does when it comes to
Speaker 13:  like co home audio and like playing your TV sound over like all the speakers
Speaker 13:  in your house. Like there's whim, but that's like more of a niche, even
Speaker 13:  more niche than Sonos and it takes a lot more setup and, and that kind of
Speaker 13:  thing. And so like no one else really like offers that core Sonos value.
Speaker 13:  And so I think that's still there.
Speaker 2:  But it seems like Sonos has kind of burned that perception. Yeah. In a, in
Speaker 2:  a real way. Like deserved or not it has, it has burned that perception from
Speaker 2:  people. And so, and I guess this brings
Speaker 2:  us a little bit to Pinewood, which is well why don't you explain,
Speaker 2:  you've, you've, you've seen that, you know what the thing looks like. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You've heard a bunch about it. What is Pinewood?
Speaker 13:  So they got back on track late last year with the culture. We should mention
Speaker 13:  that, which was great. Fantastic soundbar. And so it proves like they, they
Speaker 13:  still know how to make a very good speaker, you know? And so that, that
Speaker 13:  was promising. I think that helped boost morale at the company back to
Speaker 13:  where it needed to be. But even
Speaker 2:  Like I read your review of of that of the Ultra Yeah. And you're like,
Speaker 13:  Don't call it a comeback yet.
Speaker 2:  That's the thing. Even still, it's like this thing is great. It it is, it
Speaker 2:  is proof positive that Sonos can still do the thing that it does very well.
Speaker 13:  But the next thing is gonna be like the key indicator of like where we're
Speaker 13:  going
Speaker 2:  And there's still some reservation in you that is like I, yeah. I don't know
Speaker 2:  if I can just wholeheartedly tell you, this thing is wonderful and you should
Speaker 2:  get it and it will make your life better because like there's just something
Speaker 2:  that Sonos name doesn't quite communicate the safety
Speaker 2:  and excitement that it once did. Yeah. And I wonder what it'll take to get
Speaker 2:  that back. But you're right, it is also not, it's not how Sonos proves it
Speaker 2:  can do the thing it's been trying to do for a while. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  So I think that's gonna come through the app. We'll see how much better
Speaker 13:  it gets. And then Pinewood, which I think is coming this year as far as
Speaker 13:  I know, a very expensive streaming box that can also serve
Speaker 13:  as an HDMI switch. So you can plug in like your gaming consoles and your
Speaker 13:  other devices and it can like see all that stuff and switch between them.
Speaker 13:  And you can make your own custom Sonos surround sound speaker setups.
Speaker 13:  So like you don't need a soundbar to have surround anymore or you won't,
Speaker 13:  that'll be like one of the core selling points of Pinewood. But like
Speaker 13:  this does feel like the same kind of vibes as the ace is like you're getting
Speaker 13:  into this like super saturated market with like people that sell like
Speaker 13:  $40 streaming boxes like KU and Amazon. Yeah. If
Speaker 2:  Anything it's harder than the high-end headphone market because at least
Speaker 2:  people who are spending what, $250 and up on
Speaker 2:  headphones understand the kind of value prop there and like
Speaker 2:  you know what you're getting when you spend more money on headphones, on
Speaker 2:  streaming boxes, all we've seen for a decade now is just an absolute
Speaker 2:  race to the bottom. Like they will literally give you a television now
Speaker 2:  because Yeah. It's so there because there's just no money in selling you
Speaker 2:  the hardware. And so I think it's really interesting to see, especially after
Speaker 2:  coming off of the Ace, which I think was designed to do the same thing, right?
Speaker 2:  Like bring the Sonos brand and ethos into a very sort of
Speaker 2:  adjacent but very different kind of market. Yeah. To see them
Speaker 2:  willing to run this back. And, and I feel like even in the story you wrote
Speaker 2:  about Pinewood, there seems to be some consternation inside the company about
Speaker 2:  like how do we not make the same mistake we made last time? Yeah. And and
Speaker 2:  is this the thing that will actually get us there if the ace wasn't it?
Speaker 13:  We'll see like what it, the final form of this thing, like what it looks
Speaker 13:  like, what it's priced at I I've heard it's gonna be priced between 200
Speaker 13:  and $400, which if it's on that upper end would be obscene for
Speaker 13:  like what it is compared to like the Apple TV 4K or like the Nvidia
Speaker 13:  Shield, which is nowhere near that expensive. So I think they have to nail
Speaker 13:  the marketing and the messaging, which they put
Speaker 13:  this person Lindsay in charge of marketing now she's been at Sonos for 20
Speaker 13:  years. So if anybody can like speak to like the core value and like what
Speaker 13:  sets Sonos apart, it should be her. So that's promising.
Speaker 13:  But as far as like what this device will do for the company, like will it
Speaker 13:  make a big difference? Hopefully it'll bring in some revenue and it'll help
Speaker 13:  grow the business. Right. You know, they keep talking about like new product
Speaker 13:  categories. Like even on last week's call they were talking about like we
Speaker 13:  were gonna be careful about spending every dollar making and like helping
Speaker 13:  to grow the company and like grow the Sonos ecosystem. And it's just like
Speaker 13:  how, like with what products? Like you know like I'm just waiting for like
Speaker 13:  a new Sonos five. Like that's my favorite all in one speaker. It's been
Speaker 13:  around forever. They haven't, they haven't updated it in forever. It's clearly
Speaker 13:  not a priority for them. That's the product I wanna see. Or some kinda like
Speaker 13:  era 500, like a higher end speaker. But I think
Speaker 13:  think for now it's gonna be Pinewood After that they're working on like
Speaker 13:  a full on like receiver, like an audio receiver. I'm not sure how far along
Speaker 13:  that is, but that's in the works. But like most of all is like the app,
Speaker 13:  like most important of all is the app. This core experience is what Tom
Speaker 13:  Conrad called it last week on the call. He was like, we've gotta fix our
Speaker 13:  core experience. 'cause if we don't like nothing else matters. And so he's
Speaker 13:  cognizant of that, which is promising, but they've got a long road ahead.
Speaker 13:  They've gotta build back all that goodwill. They've gotta keep their employees
Speaker 13:  happy. Which, you know, that's its own set of challenges right now.
Speaker 2:  I think I, I am curious how you
Speaker 2:  would rate Sonos chances at being a great software company because I would
Speaker 2:  argue Sonos has been a really great like
Speaker 2:  firmware company and it is very good at making products that work
Speaker 2:  well and work well together. And that is like sincerely an accomplishment.
Speaker 2:  I don't know that I have ever experienced user facing
Speaker 2:  Sonos software as like really great. And I think Sonos has had some really
Speaker 2:  interesting ideas over the years, right? Like putting all the music stuff
Speaker 2:  into one app I think was a really interesting idea. They've done a bunch
Speaker 2:  of really interesting work on sort of multiple voice assistant stuff that
Speaker 2:  I think honestly has mostly come to nothing but is like full of good ideas
Speaker 2:  And, and again, with all of this stuff that we're talking about with Pinewood,
Speaker 2:  the idea of like, we're gonna bring all this stuff into a more functional
Speaker 2:  sort of universal search system is the right idea. Like I, I want all of
Speaker 2:  the things that Sonos wants to do, but I feel like the track record of them
Speaker 2:  executing on these good ideas in software
Speaker 2:  is not impressive. Yeah. But maybe I'm, maybe I'm being too pessimistic
Speaker 2:  because I mostly just use like the Spotify airplay thing to my Sonos speaker.
Speaker 2:  So maybe I'm not giving Sonos enough credit, but like is there a good software
Speaker 2:  company inside of this company?
Speaker 13:  I think there is. I mean, so like last week Tom said
Speaker 13:  that the hardware team or the software team is like twice the size of the
Speaker 13:  hardware team. So they've got a lot more people working on, on software
Speaker 13:  than hardware. And so you would hope that there's a good software company
Speaker 13:  inside there. I think there are people who would care who wanna like fix
Speaker 13:  this app and get it to where it needs to be. Like the ideas in the app are
Speaker 13:  good, you know, it's design is is nice. But as far as like will it ever
Speaker 13:  be like an Apple type UX quality? I don't know. You know, we,
Speaker 13:  people have been saying forever like why won't Apple just buy Sonos? They
Speaker 13:  could probably get a bargain right now if they wanted to. Probably true.
Speaker 13:  But as far as like Sonos core software ability, you know, we'll see. I mean
Speaker 13:  it's usable. It works, it did work.
Speaker 13:  And so I think it, yeah, it's fine for the purpose. People don't expect
Speaker 13:  like miracles from this company just make the stuff work, right? I mean
Speaker 13:  stuff like volume started to like take a long time, like changing the volume
Speaker 13:  on a speaker. If that has lagged then you've, you've
Speaker 13:  certainly gone astray. And so things like that are slowly getting fixed
Speaker 13:  finally. But yeah, there's a lot of, a lot of work to do, a lot,
Speaker 13:  a lot of polishing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's, it's gonna be a really interesting year because I think the,
Speaker 2:  the fact that Sonos is working on both a high-end receiver
Speaker 2:  and a set top box signals to me that maybe this company is not,
Speaker 2:  not exactly sure what its audience wants from it. For me it's just like,
Speaker 2:  just keep making Romes, just gimme more and more like go the,
Speaker 2:  the like Logitech ultimate ears strategy and just give me romes of every
Speaker 2:  imaginable shape and size and price. Yeah. And I'll almost certainly end
Speaker 2:  up buying them all. The Rome two is great, so that's fine.
Speaker 13:  Rome two is great. The move to is fantastic that like, that's my favorite
Speaker 13:  thing of theirs right now is the move to speaker. It's so good. If it
Speaker 2:  Wasn't so huge I would probably have gotten a move.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, yeah. Fair. But like Pinewood, you know, I think it was so far like
Speaker 13:  towards the release center or Patrick that they couldn't just cancel it
Speaker 13:  like yeah, you know they spent all that money on like r and d and like,
Speaker 13:  you know, it's getting it out the door so it's like close enough, let's
Speaker 13:  get it out, see how it does. Hopefully you know, they can like find the
Speaker 13:  right messaging, the right appeal and sell it to their core customer base,
Speaker 13:  which people have been like asking for like a custom like surround sound
Speaker 13:  option out of Sonos forever. So yeah, so if it offers that, like people
Speaker 13:  will pay for it, some people will will buy it and if they can like, you
Speaker 13:  know, like somehow do like unified search with Netflix, which has always
Speaker 13:  been stubborn about like trying to like have their content mixed with other
Speaker 13:  services. Like if they can make that work somehow and I don't see how Sonos
Speaker 13:  would be that company, but maybe I'll be surprised. Yeah. So we'll
Speaker 13:  see.
Speaker 2:  Yeah as ever Sonos seems to be working on the thing I would want
Speaker 2:  and we'll just, we'll see how it actually goes. But yeah, what is the state
Speaker 2:  of the Sonos app at this point before we go? I, I have essentially stopped
Speaker 2:  using it in all of the chaos. It's fine but like
Speaker 2:  are people happy again? Is it back?
Speaker 13:  It's up and down on the Sonos sub. That's my main way of like gauging how
Speaker 13:  things are going. I just check in like some people say it's gotten a lot
Speaker 13:  better this last month, like in particular. So I think, you know,
Speaker 13:  yeah they're making steady progress. I don't think layoffs help make an
Speaker 13:  app better, especially when it, there were quite a few engineers who were
Speaker 13:  let go in this latest round, which seems kind of mystifying but
Speaker 13:  slowly but surely they're getting back to where it needs to be and we'll
Speaker 13:  just have to see like was too much damage done all for a set of headphones.
Speaker 13:  That could have been great. But I mean one of the funniest quotes
Speaker 13:  last week on the call, the CFO was like, the ACE came out at the worst possible
Speaker 13:  time like in regards to our app. It's like, well whose fault was that? Like
Speaker 13:  you
Speaker 2:  Who could have known,
Speaker 13:  Who could have foreseen the situation,
Speaker 13:  it would just ruin your headphones forever. So yeah, they're gonna
Speaker 13:  headphones. It is sad. They cost a little bit too much I think for what
Speaker 13:  they are. So like a price cut would help I think boost those up a little
Speaker 13:  bit. But you know.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I look forward to buying like a refurbished pair of Ace
Speaker 2:  when exactly the ACE two inevitably come out and I I'm sure I'll like
Speaker 2:  them very much.
Speaker 2:  All right Chris, thank you as
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  VERGE one, one, the email vergecast at The Verge dot com. Send us all
Speaker 2:  of your questions. We try to answer as many of them as we can. We've gotten
Speaker 2:  a few recently that have sent me on like huge giant reporting journeys that
Speaker 2:  are gonna turn into fun stuff on this show. So all of your thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  big or small, send 'em all to us this week. We have a question about
Speaker 2:  business cards.
Speaker 18:  Hey guys, my name is Derek. I've in the past, we're
Speaker 18:  talking several years ago now, was able to take a picture of a
Speaker 18:  business card when somebody handed it to me and my phone,
Speaker 18:  my Android phone would prompt me to add it to my contact.
Speaker 18:  It was one click, it was really easy. It generally works pretty well. Sometimes
Speaker 18:  there was a mis number, but most everything worked well. Now
Speaker 18:  if I take a photo of business card who will prompt me to go
Speaker 18:  buy business cards, which is not useful at all. I was
Speaker 18:  wondering is there a current way to do this or
Speaker 18:  is this just a lost bit of history to the internet?
Speaker 2:  Right? So I have two thoughts on this. One is that I miss
Speaker 2:  when phone cameras did a better job of kind of
Speaker 2:  automatically adapting to what was in them. Right now you have lots
Speaker 2:  of options in your camera and they do a pretty good job of like
Speaker 2:  seeing what's in the photo after you take the photo. One of the cool things
Speaker 2:  AI can do is pretty usefully recognize what's inside a photo,
Speaker 2:  but cameras increasingly don't even try to do this in real time. I think
Speaker 2:  they realize that doing something like scanning a business card in your
Speaker 2:  phone camera app is a relatively niche feature, which is true. And so in
Speaker 2:  the name of making these very important camera apps simpler,
Speaker 2:  they just decided to take all that stuff out, which
Speaker 2:  fine, I suppose I understand, but I do miss that. And I think the
Speaker 2:  idea of having a camera that recognizes what you're looking at
Speaker 2:  and adapts itself accordingly is actually about to make a comeback. We're
Speaker 2:  thinking about things like visual intelligence and all of these multimodal
Speaker 2:  AI systems that relies on understanding what's on the other side of
Speaker 2:  your camera. So it's possible that we are going to inadvertently
Speaker 2:  resolve this business card problem, just not yet. In the meantime,
Speaker 2:  there are basically two places you can go. One
Speaker 2:  is a business card specific app
Speaker 2:  and there are lots of those out there. There's one called Haystack that's
Speaker 2:  pretty popular. There's one called Hi, hello, that's pretty popular. There's
Speaker 2:  Biz Connect. There's one called Cam Card I think, which
Speaker 2:  sounds creepier than it actually is. But anyway, all of these things
Speaker 2:  want to be more than just business card scanning apps. They want to be like
Speaker 2:  contact management and CRM systems. They're designed for people who like
Speaker 2:  get a lot of business cards and have to do a lot of lead generation and following
Speaker 2:  up. They do a pretty good job with business card scanning,
Speaker 2:  but I don't recommend using them. They all want access to your contacts.
Speaker 2:  They all want you to subscribe to stuff. They all want to be a bigger platform
Speaker 2:  than just a place to scan a business card. You can use those apps, but I
Speaker 2:  don't recommend it. What I would do instead is use a more
Speaker 2:  generic document scanning app. And there are a bunch of ways to do this.
Speaker 2:  You can do something like take a picture in Apple Notes and then actually
Speaker 2:  search for that person's name. If you wanna just store all your business
Speaker 2:  cards in a note. Google Drive also does this very well. You can just take
Speaker 2:  a picture in the Drive app and it will scan the document and upload it and
Speaker 2:  then If you search for the name or whatever, it'll actually surface the business
Speaker 2:  card. That's the simple way, the most
Speaker 2:  impressive way I think. And the thing I would recommend to anyone looking
Speaker 2:  to do this is just to use the Adobe Scan app. It's free.
Speaker 2:  It again wants to upsell you into the whole creative cloud ecosystem and
Speaker 2:  make it all really complicated. But you can just avoid all of that and just
Speaker 2:  take pictures with the scan app and do everything you want.
Speaker 2:  And the thing that I really like about it is when you open the scan app,
Speaker 2:  it lets you choose what you're taking a picture of. You can, you can pick
Speaker 2:  a whiteboard or a book or a document or an ID card or a business card.
Speaker 2:  And that actually again adapts the camera to take different kinds of pictures
Speaker 2:  and pull different kinds of information out on the business card. One in
Speaker 2:  particular, when you take a picture, it will actually allow you then
Speaker 2:  to save it directly to your contacts. It will extract the information out
Speaker 2:  and dump it into your contacts and it does that directly on your device in
Speaker 2:  a way that I like very much. The scan app is not perfect.
Speaker 2:  It seems to really want a business card that is
Speaker 2:  optimized in a very specific way, like big company logo
Speaker 2:  at the top and then below it in like smaller bold letters,
Speaker 2:  person's name and then below it. Lots of information. If you get
Speaker 2:  one like that, it will almost always get it right. But I'm looking at one
Speaker 2:  right now that has the first and last name in
Speaker 2:  big blue letters and right below it in smaller letters, the
Speaker 2:  company name and it thinks of those things in reverse. So
Speaker 2:  it thinks this person whose name is Daniel is the name of the company and
Speaker 2:  it thinks their company is their first name. So I had to go in and fix that
Speaker 2:  a little bit, but it got their email address right, it got their phone number
Speaker 2:  right. It like pulled all of the relevant data pretty successfully,
Speaker 2:  certainly easier than manually typing this whole thing into the context on
Speaker 2:  my computer. There are again, lots of apps that will scan
Speaker 2:  information on business cards and like use OCR optical
Speaker 2:  character recognition to pull it out so that you can find it later. But Adobe
Speaker 2:  Scan is just the most straightforward, most simple one that actually
Speaker 2:  will pull out the information and then let you put it where you want it to,
Speaker 2:  which is in your contacts and it does it with no strings attached
Speaker 2:  as long as you ignore the occasional upsell to Creative Cloud. And hey, If
Speaker 2:  you already pay for Creative Cloud, terrific. You can also have PDFs of your
Speaker 2:  business cards. So that's what I'd recommend. Put the scan app on
Speaker 2:  your home screen and you can also use it. It's really handy for doing things
Speaker 2:  like scanning documents and turning them into editable PDFs.
Speaker 2:  It's really great when you wanna take a picture of a whiteboard or any kinds
Speaker 2:  of these other things that you wanna make not only accessible but actually
Speaker 2:  extract the information out of and make it useful in some other way.
Speaker 2:  That's like Adobe's whole thing, right? They want you to then go use Acrobat
Speaker 2:  to mess with the PDF. But the good news is you don't have to, you can just
Speaker 2:  dump all this stuff where you need it to be and move on with your day. So
Speaker 2:  that's my recommendation. Use Adobe Scan. But also I am curious if
Speaker 2:  a, you found a way in the default camera app on your phone to do something
Speaker 2:  cool and interesting with this, or B, if there's another app for scanning
Speaker 2:  business cards in particular, but really documents of all kind that you like
Speaker 2:  better than Adobe Scan. I wanna hear about that too. This is a thing I
Speaker 2:  encounter more than I've realized in the past. Not even just with business
Speaker 2:  cards, but like in an effort to go fully paperless and just
Speaker 2:  dump all of the paper bills and like I got a speeding
Speaker 2:  ticket the other day because Washington DC has the speeding cameras and
Speaker 2:  they are ruthless and it would be nice to just be able to like take a picture
Speaker 2:  of that, pull out the information and upload it. And you can kind of sorta
Speaker 2:  do that in lots of ways and they kind of sort of work, but it does feel like
Speaker 2:  this could all be better and Adobe Scan is the best I've found. But If you
Speaker 2:  have a better idea, if, especially if it is wonky and complicated and
Speaker 2:  involves a lot of weird AI stuff, I want to hear all about it. For now,
Speaker 2:  that is it for our show. Thank you to
Speaker 2:  everybody who was on the show. Thank you to everybody who called the hotline
Speaker 2:  and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything. We
Speaker 2:  talked about all of Alex Heath's coverage of Meta in his Command line
Speaker 2:  newsletter and elsewhere, all of Chris Welch's Sonos coverage, lots of stuff.
Speaker 2:  He convinced me to buy a pair of the new Powerbeats Pro headphones. You can
Speaker 2:  read the songs review all on the website. I'll put some stuff in the show
Speaker 2:  notes. But as as always, read the website. It's a good website. If you thoughts,
Speaker 2:  questions, feelings, or again scanning apps you think I should use. You can
Speaker 2:  always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline. It's
Speaker 2:  six six VERGE one one we genuinely love hearing from you. This show is
Speaker 2:  produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Kiefer. The Vergecast is VERGE
Speaker 2:  Production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli and I'll be back
Speaker 2:  on Friday to talk about God help us all politics,
Speaker 2:  AI gadgets, big phones, small phones, foldable phones and
Speaker 2:  everything else. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.