# Transcript
ID: 4dc4f304-1422-4afb-8a46-fd579d44e67f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4490318275840172601/5841902520537162035/s93290-US-5479s-1744368616.mp3
Description: Welcome to tech in 2025, where everything's made up and the numbers don't matter. Nilay, David, and The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes start the show by running down the latest tariff news, the uncertain future facing tech companies of all sizes, and what we're learning so far about how they're responding. After that, the hosts talk about a big week in AI news, including Meta's sketchy benchmark numbers and the latest damning reporting about the future of Siri. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for America's favorite podcast within a podcast, Brendan Carr is a Dummy, along with some news about the TikTok ban and the Pixel 9A. And then some more tariff numbers, because they just never stop.
Speaker 1:  being nominated for the Webby Awards.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  It's good. It's, it's very exciting. David, tell, tell the people what's
Speaker 1:  going on here.
Speaker 5:  I thought you're gonna say we weren't nominated for the Webby Awards but
Speaker 5:  we we cover the podcast that we're nominated for the Webby Awards.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's not, it's not us, it's everyone
Speaker 5:  Else. The Vergecast is nominated for best technology podcasts, Webby Awards.
Speaker 5:  It's very exciting. We care a lot about this award in
Speaker 5:  particular because It is voted on by people like this. I
Speaker 5:  care so much more about what people listening to this think than, you
Speaker 5:  know, random fussy judges. I like to think of it like the
Speaker 5:  academy where it's just like a bunch of old white dudes who haven't seen
Speaker 5:  a movie in 50 years. Like I don't care about them. Vote for us so that we
Speaker 5:  can win and we can crush our competition. Our competition by the way, is
Speaker 5:  like lovely people including like the EFF and I want to destroy them.
Speaker 5:  So, we'll, we'll put a link in the show notes. I think there's another week
Speaker 5:  to vote. We'll put a link in the show notes. We'll put a link in the container
Speaker 5:  post on the site. But please go vote for us. And I think you can vote for
Speaker 5:  us multiple times. It's like once a day or something you can vote. So like
Speaker 5:  make it your homepage and vote for us every single time you think about it
Speaker 5:  and we will be eternally grateful. Have
Speaker 1:  You been dying for an AI agent project? Here's one.
Speaker 5:  Can you vibe code your way to a web event? Webby victory is a very good
Speaker 1:  Question. That's actually a perfect VERGE cast episode title.
Speaker 1:  I wanna be very clear about that. And that's what we're gonna do for the
Speaker 1:  rest of the show. We're gonna live vibe code. I've opened Claude
Speaker 1:  and David's gonna open cursor and then we're gonna race.
Speaker 5:  I love
Speaker 1:  It. By the way, I'm your friend Eli. That's David Pierce. Hello Jake Cast
Speaker 1:  is here. Hey buddy.
Speaker 6:  Hey, good to be here.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we've got basically three lightning rounds. That's how David has
Speaker 1:  structured this. Although I will say this first lightning round is just a
Speaker 1:  segment about tariffs. We're just calling it a lightning round to pretend
Speaker 1:  it's not just a full segment about tariffs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, pretty much. There's just, it's like, it's, it's tariffs is one of
Speaker 5:  those things that It is. It contains multitudes and so it's like, let's,
Speaker 5:  it's true. Lightning round is like, let's just talk about it all very fast.
Speaker 6:  Lightning is the speed at which these tariff changes have come this week.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Like I, I'm afraid to say a single number on this podcast 'cause we're
Speaker 6:  recording Thursday afternoon, it's gonna come out Friday morning. Anything
Speaker 6:  could happen in those like 12 hours.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 1:  So true. My favorite thing about tariffs, and this is very inside baseball
Speaker 1:  editory stuff, is we often assign stories that are like, here's how
Speaker 1:  something happened, right? Like, here's the process by which go 90 went 90
Speaker 1:  and like we talked to all the insiders and we're like, this happened on this
Speaker 1:  day. This happened on the next day. Here's the big decision they made. You,
Speaker 1:  you see these stories everywhere. Whenever a big decision is made or there's
Speaker 1:  a deal that's done, someone gets what's called the TikTok and it's
Speaker 1:  just like, here's all the stuff that happened in order. And those are really
Speaker 1:  fun to read. They're really fun to write. The funniest thing about the tariff
Speaker 1:  situation is that all the major newspapers tried to do a TikTok
Speaker 1:  story of what is by all accounts pure chaos. And so they
Speaker 1:  tried to impose this structure on like, then the treasury
Speaker 1:  secretary did drugs and called all of his friends and his friends were
Speaker 1:  mad and they called Susie Wiles. And you're like, this isn't a process
Speaker 1:  story because there's no process. Right? But
Speaker 1:  that, that's very much the, like the, like Cuban beings have a
Speaker 1:  desire for it to make sense. And this refuses to
Speaker 1:  make sense.
Speaker 5:  Charlie Wetzel, our friend over at the Atlantic wrote a thing earlier
Speaker 5:  this week comparing kind of the, the response and conversation around
Speaker 5:  all of this to Q Anon, which I love. Right? And It is, It is exactly
Speaker 5:  that thing. It is this relentless belief that there is a plan
Speaker 5:  that somebody is doing things on purpose, that this is thought out. That
Speaker 5:  there is a, there is a bigger thing going on. And just because you can't
Speaker 5:  see it doesn't mean it's not there when the blindingly obvious truth
Speaker 5:  is that there is no plan. Everybody in charge is an idiot and
Speaker 5:  nothing is being considered or thought out. We just basically, it's like
Speaker 5:  Trump and three people in a room and then a bunch of
Speaker 5:  people around the government who just kind of let him do it and that that's
Speaker 5:  everything. Yeah. It's unreal.
Speaker 1:  I think it was Bill Ackman had a tweet that was like, this is the art of
Speaker 1:  the deal. And it's like, bro, what deal? Like no deal was made.
Speaker 1:  I like, I'm not even arguing that it was a good deal or a bad deal. I'm asking
Speaker 1:  you to identify the deal. Yeah. Okay. But because It
Speaker 1:  is lightning round, the conceit of a lightning round is that it's like lots
Speaker 1:  of different things jumbled up and we just move through them. So I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  start the show somewhere else that's not tariffs and we can see if we can
Speaker 1:  get to tariffs.
Speaker 1:  You, you with me? Okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We're just get there.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Just a gesture. This
Speaker 5:  Being like can happen back. Oh, interesting. 'cause I, I put this here at
Speaker 5:  the top for you because this is the, this is the most important news in the
Speaker 5:  world if you're Neli Patel. And so this is where we start. But if you can
Speaker 5:  walk me from here to tariffs, I will be very
Speaker 1:  Impressed. I think I can get there.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  So as you know, I divide the
Speaker 1:  eras of human existence
Speaker 1:  into eras of Sony providing extra
Speaker 1:  base to its speakers.
Speaker 1:  So I was born the ox of history. I was born in
Speaker 1:  the mega base era, which I think we all recall is when America was great
Speaker 1:  the eighties and early nineties, right? The mega base button was on the Walkman.
Speaker 1:  We were riding high top gun had just come out.
Speaker 1:  You all know what I'm talking about, but we've, you've seen the memes.
Speaker 1:  That's when, I mean that's, that was it. That was the peak. We were all
Speaker 1:  young In the mid two thousands. Sony moved to
Speaker 1:  the extra base era, which I believe tracks with our
Speaker 1:  decline.
Speaker 1:  It was really weird. You get, you get rid of this thing people love you add
Speaker 1:  a button called extra base, no knows what it means. It's going away. They've
Speaker 1:  abandoned that into the ULT Power Sound
Speaker 1:  era. So that's where we are now. So we left Megabase
Speaker 1:  behind, we're in ULT Power sound. We've talked about this a lot
Speaker 1:  in the news, is that there are now three new party speakers
Speaker 1:  from Sony, which is further evidence that the market for
Speaker 1:  giant party speakers with LED lights around the, the drivers
Speaker 1:  is so huge that Sony is continually
Speaker 1:  investing in making new ones as are all of its competitors.
Speaker 1:  And this market is bigger than anyone can see. You know how they're like,
Speaker 1:  we're tracking this outbreak, but it's much bigger because just based on
Speaker 1:  the, this is what we can just see, this is the tip of the
Speaker 1:  iceberg. I'm saying the party speaker market is gigantic.
Speaker 1:  It is under remarked upon and it's just the evidence that they
Speaker 1:  keep being new ones that let us know it's, it's happening. I,
Speaker 6:  I'm curious for your experience here and maybe this, maybe this just says
Speaker 6:  something about me, but not, not once have I walked into a friend's home
Speaker 6:  and seen a large party speaker the size of a piece of furniture
Speaker 1:  And yet they're like, cryptics, have you seen Bigfoot?
Speaker 6:  Where are they, where are they going? I don't know. They're
Speaker 6:  everywhere. It's in malls. They're filling up all the empty malls with these
Speaker 1:  Things. It's it's taco shacks, it's, it's, it's weird's vendors in malls.
Speaker 1:  It's it's car dealership. They're everywhere. And I
Speaker 1:  know this because every single company now has a
Speaker 1:  full lineup in sizes ranging from like shelf
Speaker 1:  size to to medium-sized child and they keep
Speaker 1:  revving them. So the new one is a ULT Tower
Speaker 1:  nine. It replaces by the way the Sony S-R-X-S-X-V
Speaker 1:  900. That's a classic. It has 25 hours of battery playback. A quick
Speaker 1:  charge option that has three hours of playback after only 10 minutes of charging
Speaker 1:  and is $900.
Speaker 5:  It's a tough like 10 minute party foul to charge the speaker. But
Speaker 5:  then you get it back for
Speaker 1:  Three hours. The ULT Tower nine offers both ULT one mode,
Speaker 1:  which delivers deeper lower frequency base and ULT two
Speaker 1:  mode, which provides powerful punchy base.
Speaker 5:  Who's using ULT one?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I don't know man.
Speaker 5:  Let's, let's be real. I think this, this suggests that the next era is going
Speaker 5:  to be the one that is deeper lower frequency, powerful punchy base. All
Speaker 5:  ULT three is the next phase.
Speaker 1:  It does appear that it also has HDMI in or optical in. So you can connect
Speaker 1:  it to a TV and it has improved 360 degree LED
Speaker 1:  lighting that can illuminate a like more floor space. It's a
Speaker 1:  $900. It lasts for 25 hours in battery. If you don't need the battery. There's
Speaker 1:  a $750 version that is a C on me.
Speaker 5:  But you need the battery. Like you, you can't party a speaker without a battery.
Speaker 1:  This is evidence that the ULT era is not only here,
Speaker 1:  but like it's secretly dominant. Like lots of people have
Speaker 1:  ULT buttons in their home. And I know this because Sony keeps investing in
Speaker 1:  making the speakers and they're getting more extravagant and more expensive.
Speaker 1:  They're moving up market. It's true. It's not. No one wants 'em. We have
Speaker 1:  to make them cheaper. It's everyone wants them. They cost $900 that can last
Speaker 1:  for a full day and illuminate your home.
Speaker 5:  What if it was taller? I just wanna say before we move on and
Speaker 5:  you, you, you're stalling walking us to tariffs from here. But that's just
Speaker 5:  all
Speaker 1:  I wanna talk about.
Speaker 5:  I encourage everyone to click on this story and look at the pictures because
Speaker 5:  these things are so large that photographs of them
Speaker 5:  look like the speaker has been photoshopped into some other
Speaker 5:  scene in such a large way that it, it, it can't possibly
Speaker 5:  make sense. It really is like it's, it's this size of like a 10-year-old
Speaker 5:  and it, they're just stuck in here. It's like, it's like an alien form just
Speaker 5:  being photoshopped into this photo of a concert.
Speaker 1:  The other very funny thing about these photos is Sony is by far the most
Speaker 1:  restrained in design when it comes to these products and they still look
Speaker 1:  bananas.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  It's very good. All right. So here that, that's the ULT
Speaker 1:  tower nine which has both ULT one and ULT two modes.
Speaker 1:  This is where we are on in our ULT era. Eventually there's something else
Speaker 1:  will come, but I'm telling you I was born in the mega base era and I, I yearn,
Speaker 1:  I yearn for the, the simple pleasures of my youth and instead I have the
Speaker 1:  U LT Tower nine. The reason I bring this up is because it doesn't
Speaker 1:  appear that Sony increased the prices of these
Speaker 1:  products in response to tariffs still $900. But now
Speaker 1:  you get two UL T modes and a winder and a wider floor
Speaker 1:  illumination. But last week we talked
Speaker 1:  about the BRAVIA two, two Sony's new TVs
Speaker 1:  and the BRAVIA eight two incredible names. I
Speaker 5:  Don't know if you saw this by the way. We got a bunch of emails from people
Speaker 5:  who were like, I straight up didn't believe you that it was called the two
Speaker 5:  two. So I went and looked and I would like to apologize for not believing
Speaker 5:  you about this stupid
Speaker 1:  Name. Yeah. One person was like, it's obviously the BRAVIA two, mark two
Speaker 1:  and then they're like no it's not. It's just the two two. It's the BRAVIA
Speaker 1:  two two. So the ULT speakers
Speaker 1:  apparently inflation proof, recession proof, tariff proof, same price
Speaker 1:  TVs not so much. So it appears that the B bravia
Speaker 1:  8.2, the high-end ole D which replaces the A 95
Speaker 1:  L in a perfect naming scheme is going to be $500 more
Speaker 1:  in the United States than was last year. And the price is unchanged in Canada.
Speaker 1:  So you can already see the tariff impact there.
Speaker 1:  The other TVs are also going up. So Sony is already beginning to
Speaker 1:  bake in some tariff pricing. Samsung on the other hand announced pricing
Speaker 1:  on the frame pro and It is just expensive but it doesn't appear the
Speaker 1:  price has gone up. The 65 inch frame pro is
Speaker 1:  $2,200. This is for a TV that still
Speaker 1:  has edge backlighting. They're just lying and saying that it's mine
Speaker 1:  LED 'cause it's mine LD is on the bottom edge. And
Speaker 5:  That I would point out to anyone who is listening Eli's
Speaker 5:  argument for the frame TV always ends with, you don't want a tv and
Speaker 5:  now actually what you do want is a $2,200 TV
Speaker 1:  People buy these things. Yeah. And then they use 'em to show artwork where
Speaker 1:  they watch TikTok and now you can do that for 2200 if you are.
Speaker 1:  I will say I, I'm very proud of our audience because all
Speaker 1:  of the comments on this are, I thought this was a good TV of how expensive
Speaker 1:  it was and it turns out to be a shit tv.
Speaker 1:  I've never been happier. The audience has started to figure it out. The reason
Speaker 1:  the Samsung one is, is so expensive we think is 'cause they moved all the
Speaker 1:  ports to a wireless one connect box, right? So you just plug in the TV and
Speaker 1:  then you've got this breakout wireless box to plug in your game consoles
Speaker 1:  and everything else you can put up to 30 feet away. And instead of improving
Speaker 1:  the picture quality, they spent all the money on this wireless box. This
Speaker 1:  is a nightmare. But it doesn't seem, but Sam and also I think Samsung didn't
Speaker 1:  have to raise prices 'cause of tariffs. 'cause it frame TV is such a shit
Speaker 1:  panel that's been pure margin the whole time. They could just eat it. That's
Speaker 1:  my going theory. But we can already see here, I got there David
Speaker 1:  on the high end TV where there's, where people are pay the money for the
Speaker 1:  highest in Sony TVs no matter what the A 95 L never
Speaker 1:  went on sale. It was a $5,000 77 inch tv. It has ne
Speaker 1:  as far as I can tell, never been on sale. Those customers are gonna pay the,
Speaker 1:  the tariff money and Sony's gonna charge it to them. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because they can. I mean all of that stuff is easier at the top of the market.
Speaker 5:  I mean this is something we're gonna talk a lot about here is that like the,
Speaker 5:  the price elasticity question here is coming up over and over and over in
Speaker 5:  tariffs and it turns out it's actually easier to raise the price on something
Speaker 5:  that's already $5,000 that
Speaker 1:  Has and people will just and perfect demand, right? So many sold every one
Speaker 1:  of those in NFL LS at full price to somebody who wanted them. So we, we,
Speaker 1:  I got here I so I walked my way from ULT power, power nines
Speaker 1:  to terrace.
Speaker 5:  I'm proud of you
Speaker 1:  David. Your challenge
Speaker 1:  in th on Thursday afternoon is tell us what's going on with tariffs Jesus
Speaker 1:  in a way that is relevant when people listen to this on Friday morning.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Tariffs both do and do not
Speaker 5:  exist at all times. And that is the state of
Speaker 1:  Heisenberg uncertainty tariffs. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I think where we are as of right now is we talked a bunch last
Speaker 5:  week about this, this nonsensical set of quote unquote
Speaker 5:  reciprocal tariffs that were not reciprocal tariffs that were based on trade
Speaker 5:  deficits and nonsense equations that had nothing to do with anything and
Speaker 5:  appear to have been invented by various AI bots.
Speaker 5:  Set the stock market on fire for several days and then
Speaker 5:  Trump after saying he got phone calls from
Speaker 5:  75 different countries that he declined to name.
Speaker 5:  Put a 90 day pause on all of it except for two things.
Speaker 5:  One, he has continued to do an escalating
Speaker 5:  tariff war with China to the point where now all the numbers are over a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent and just we're, we've entered like full fake number territory on
Speaker 5:  all of this. Like 50000%. Like who cares?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They're just bigger the number. It's six blades. That's what we're
Speaker 1:  doing. It's six. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Can I just quickly explain the over a hundred percent 'cause
Speaker 1:  people have been confused and I kind of get
Speaker 5:  It. Yes. But let me just say the one other thing that's happening and then
Speaker 5:  we can dive in the the, because I think this actually gets lost in a lot
Speaker 5:  of the back and Forthness, the one thing that was left in place was
Speaker 5:  a 10% based tariff on everybody, which
Speaker 5:  seems simple, but it has become vastly complicated because countries like
Speaker 5:  Mexico and Canada where they have been exempted from some of these tariff
Speaker 5:  deals are now suddenly like, wait, does this apply to us too? And it appears
Speaker 5:  that it does. And So we are, we are back in this place of,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's not as bad as many people thought it might be at least for
Speaker 5:  the next 90 days, but it's still very bad in the most important country
Speaker 5:  in this case, which is China. And It is still impossibly confusing
Speaker 5:  to everybody. Yeah. So that's where we are now. Explain the over a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent thing.
Speaker 1:  Well it just means if you bring in something for $10, you have to pay
Speaker 1:  $14 of tariffs. It isn just fully ridiculous. Like
Speaker 1:  that's the end of people importing things here. Mr. Beast was pointing
Speaker 1:  out that it will be cheaper for him to make feasts and his other products
Speaker 1:  outside the country to ship to other countries. Like he's gonna move
Speaker 1:  production outta the United States because other markets will be cheaper
Speaker 1:  to manufacture and distribute too to get away from all this tariff noise.
Speaker 1:  That's nuts. Yeah. Like it's just fully nuts to, to break the
Speaker 1:  world trade system in that way. You can go read the, like we
Speaker 1:  tried to explain the decision, but the answer is like the
Speaker 1:  world financial system started to teeter and Trump blinked and he was like,
Speaker 1:  screw it, 10% terrorists. And then there's the underlying question, which
Speaker 1:  I think is one of those interesting political realignment things.
Speaker 1:  The power to implement the tariffs is basically
Speaker 1:  Trump declared a national emergency and he was like, no, I,
Speaker 1:  with the power of emergency, I command you to pay me an extra 104%. And
Speaker 1:  the emergency is the trade deficit in many of these cases, which is not
Speaker 1:  an emergency 'cause that has existed for 50
Speaker 5:  Years and is also not what Trump thinks It is. Like what
Speaker 5:  the, the definition of a trade deficit that leads you to do what Trump is
Speaker 5:  doing is not what a trade deficit actually is. And I'm not an economist,
Speaker 5:  but I'm confident that I'm smarter about this than our current president.
Speaker 1:  So the really interesting thing about that is a bunch of hard right free
Speaker 1:  traders, Rand Paul is screaming about the trade deficit not being what Trump
Speaker 1:  thinks It is.
Speaker 5:  I thought you were gonna say Dave Portnoy.
Speaker 1:  Dave Portnoy, this is the, I don't think he's a hard right. Free trade. I
Speaker 1:  think that dude is just trying to make some money. Yes. But you know, his
Speaker 1:  number went down, number went up like he's reacting to it in real time. But
Speaker 1:  the Rand Pauls of the world are out there giving strong speeches and
Speaker 1:  strong quotes being like, this makes no sense. And then a bunch of
Speaker 1:  conservative legal groups are filing lawsuits being like, this isn't an emergency.
Speaker 1:  You don't have this power, which is the thing that you would expect really
Speaker 1:  conservative legal groups to do. Say like actually the government shouldn't
Speaker 1:  have this power. So you just see the realignment, right? That
Speaker 1:  that's not the political outcome you would expect usually from, from Trump
Speaker 1:  stuff. We'll see where all of it goes, but in the
Speaker 1:  meantime, the the tariffs haven't actually been rescinded.
Speaker 1:  They've been paused right. For 90 days. They're still
Speaker 1:  in massive effect against China, which has enormous consequences across the
Speaker 1:  board. And then it's confusing how they
Speaker 1:  apply to everyone else.
Speaker 5:  Well, and and Trump continues to say during that pause that what he wants
Speaker 5:  is,
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say implied, but he's not even implying it, he's just saying
Speaker 5:  it out loud. He wants people to like bribe
Speaker 5:  him and make deals with him in some meaningful way. Like he, the, the goal
Speaker 5:  is to get everyone to come and tell him how terrific he is. And that's, that's
Speaker 5:  what he says over and over. And there were reports of, you know, a bunch
Speaker 5:  of leaders flying to Mar-a-Lago to basically tell Trump
Speaker 5:  to stop doing this. Like Jamie Diamond apparently went and was giving a whole
Speaker 5:  speech to Trump about why tariffs are bad and Trump thought that was really
Speaker 5:  great. And so it's like, it's, it's very clear the the, the
Speaker 5:  leverage he is going for here remains the same. And the way you do that is
Speaker 5:  by putting up pause on it.
Speaker 1:  Sure.
Speaker 1:  Everyone wants out. Like Tim Cook is gonna show up and say, give Apple it
Speaker 1:  out the way that you did for me during your first administration when you
Speaker 1:  went into a trade war with China. It, it's true. I think he wants the deals,
Speaker 1:  he wants to be flattered. At one point he had Charles Schwab
Speaker 1:  and he like pointed at him and he was like, look, it's a guy, it's like an
Speaker 1:  actual guy, which incredible television. Like all of this is
Speaker 1:  nonsensical. There's that goal, right? The the
Speaker 1:  weird corrupt, let's do gangster deals on the side. Sure.
Speaker 1:  That's Trump. Then there's this other goal, which is also an echo of his
Speaker 1:  first administration where Commerce Secretary Howard
Speaker 1:  Lutnick is saying, I want factories in the United States. I want the army
Speaker 1:  of people with little screwdrivers building iPhones. I want them to come
Speaker 1:  here. Karen Levitt, the press secretary was asked very directly about Maggie
Speaker 1:  Haberman, does Trump believe we can make iPhones in the United States? And
Speaker 1:  she said, absolutely, we have the workforce, we have the talent. That has
Speaker 1:  been the goal the whole time, right? There's the little
Speaker 1:  goal which is let's do shady deals on the side. And then there's this
Speaker 1:  big goal which is like, let's restructure the world and build the
Speaker 1:  eye from the United States because that will make
Speaker 1:  us great again. We've been covering that
Speaker 1:  for a long time. Like there's a part of this for me and
Speaker 1:  I dunno if you two feel the same where it's just a bunch of people grew up
Speaker 1:  and there having the same experiences that we had 15 years ago. And one
Speaker 1:  of those experiences is Donald Trump insisting the iPhone can be built in
Speaker 1:  the United States and then we have to have, or like, or Obama insisting the
Speaker 1:  iPhone can be built in the United States and then we have to like go through
Speaker 1:  the conversation again.
Speaker 6:  I mean they keep trying to bring like different pieces of Apple manufacturing
Speaker 6:  into the US and each time it becomes like a little bit of a disaster in
Speaker 6:  some way. Like they were gonna try to do a bunch of glass in the US and like,
Speaker 6:  I think that factory just like didn't work out for them.
Speaker 1:  No, they do the glass here. Corning does the glass here,
Speaker 6:  They do the glass here. I thought there was something for the Apple watch
Speaker 6:  where they were gonna do a specific type of glass and they were building
Speaker 6:  a specific factory. The Corning is here, but there was
Speaker 6:  that there, there was the, you know, they did eventually they relaunched
Speaker 6:  the Mac factory for Trump himself.
Speaker 6:  But all these things take time, like a, a surprisingly long amount of time
Speaker 6:  and we have, you know, TSMC opening factory in Arizona that's just like,
Speaker 6:  you know, we're hoping it can produce enough chips to be useful for basically
Speaker 6:  anybody. And we are hoping that those chips are gonna be on a, a modern
Speaker 6:  enough node that we actually want to use them in our latest gadgets. And
Speaker 6:  so it's just like there are these baby steps happening,
Speaker 6:  but even when we put a concerted effort into it, we're never quite getting
Speaker 6:  there. There
Speaker 5:  Is the ongoing question of why is this the goal that I,
Speaker 5:  I have continued to find really fascinating. And I think seeing the way it's
Speaker 5:  being covered, particularly by the, the kind of right-leaning press is really
Speaker 5:  fascinating. 'cause on the one hand I think the, the reasonable people that
Speaker 5:  I have seen make this sort of national security argument, right? That It
Speaker 5:  is, this is a way to control your own destiny. If you don't make the chips,
Speaker 5:  you are reliant on somebody else for something that is like crucially important
Speaker 5:  to modern life. Sure. I think It is vastly more complicated than that, but
Speaker 5:  I, I at least like understand the bones of that argument. But we've so quickly
Speaker 5:  devolved now into this place where everybody is saying that
Speaker 5:  factories are manly and like, and that actually the problem is,
Speaker 5:  is men are sitting around playing video games, collecting welfare,
Speaker 5:  and what they should actually be doing is working in factories. And that's
Speaker 5:  how you make men men. And this is like this, this is
Speaker 5:  what happens when there's no other move. Like do, do you remember when,
Speaker 5:  at the very end of the election or at the very end of the campaign in like
Speaker 5:  October and November of last year, there was this whole run of stuff on Fox
Speaker 5:  News that it wasn't manly to vote for a woman for president.
Speaker 5:  This became a real thing and people were like repeating it and now you have
Speaker 5:  people on Fox News saying the same thing, that tariffs are manly and, and
Speaker 5:  that, that somehow this is the thing you have to appeal to in order to get
Speaker 5:  people to buy into this thing that just transparently doesn't make any other
Speaker 5:  sense. And so I I'm at this place where it's like, okay, even if you want
Speaker 5:  to say It is possible and plausible to move
Speaker 5:  all of this stuff to the United States, which it's not, and we should
Speaker 5:  talk about that. Like it it isn't, but there, there still
Speaker 5:  is not an interesting answer as to why, except that it will somehow
Speaker 5:  return us to the, the beautiful past that everyone is so excited about.
Speaker 1:  Well there's implicit in all of that is the only market that matters
Speaker 1:  is America, right? That if Americans make American products for
Speaker 1:  the American citizens, like we will have an ounce of self-control and
Speaker 1:  respect and we will, I don't know, once again smash communism in
Speaker 1:  some way. I, I don't know. Like I I find that argument very confusing in
Speaker 1:  its way because these are not only low paid jobs
Speaker 1:  in most of the countries in which they're done, they're increasingly
Speaker 1:  automated jobs and Lunik is saying the same thing. He's like these auto,
Speaker 1:  these factories we automated in jobs like robot technician. And it's like
Speaker 1:  you we're very confused. Yeah. Like very, very confused about
Speaker 1:  what is actually happening in China and what that ecosystem looks
Speaker 1:  like and what the supply chains to make that ecosystem go
Speaker 1:  look like. And the the thing that is crazy making to me is this new
Speaker 1:  gloss of like it's manly to work in a factory is it's still
Speaker 1:  unrelated to the problem, right? It's like we're having a new
Speaker 1:  dumber version of a conversation that literally I think in 2010
Speaker 1:  Steve Jobs had with p then President Obama, right? Where he is
Speaker 1:  like, I just don't have the talent in this country. You have to invest in
Speaker 1:  the educational system to make me the engineers to work in
Speaker 1:  the plants. Not as the the people with the screwdrivers, but as the
Speaker 1:  engineering managers making sure the plants operate, you don't have enough.
Speaker 1:  I'm never gonna do it. The Mac Pro story is really interesting. There's
Speaker 1:  a really, I don't remember where it was from. We'll find it, there's a really
Speaker 1:  interesting story about that factory getting off the ground. It's run by
Speaker 1:  a company called Flex, which is, you know, like a Foxconn competitor.
Speaker 1:  That's how you should think of it. Or one of these big assemblers and
Speaker 1:  flex is in Texas. That's where they do the Mac Pro. They set up the
Speaker 1:  facility there for Apple and they could not get screws at Apple
Speaker 1:  specifications in Texas. And the one supplier they had was
Speaker 1:  delivering the screws in the trunk of his car.
Speaker 5:  Wow.
Speaker 1:  That's the problem. It is not like manliness.
Speaker 1:  It is, the problem is we have not invested for years now in the
Speaker 1:  ecosystem. And you go to China and the ecosystem
Speaker 1:  is not about like one company owning the manufacturing chain
Speaker 1:  like Intel owning the chip fab. It's about
Speaker 1:  lots and lots of manufacturing companies serving lots and lots of customers
Speaker 1:  and they're good at customer service in that we just, we have, you
Speaker 1:  have to like reset everything about our culture to make that go.
Speaker 5:  And of course the, the administration is in the middle of tearing down all
Speaker 5:  of those other parts also, like you can't say with a straight face, we
Speaker 5:  want to train people to work in factories while dismantling
Speaker 5:  the Department of Education, right? Yeah. Like tho those two things are completely
Speaker 5:  at odds, which again, there is no plan, just,
Speaker 5:  there's just not a plan. So I don't want you to take my word for it or take
Speaker 5:  our word for it. You can go read in the, it's the Walter Isaacson Steve Jobs
Speaker 5:  biography, which is mostly a bad book. It has like good scenes in it.
Speaker 5:  He, the, the story about Obama and jobs and jobs is like, I'm, this is never
Speaker 5:  gonna happen. But years later in 2017,
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook on stage at a fortune conference gave the same answer
Speaker 5:  about why they can't build the iPhone in the United States. We just run the
Speaker 5:  tape. We just run the tape.
Speaker 7:  The truth is, China stopped being the low labor cost country many
Speaker 7:  years ago. And th that is not the reason to
Speaker 7:  come to China from a supply point of view. The reason
Speaker 7:  is because of the skill and the, the
Speaker 7:  quantity of skill in one location and the type of skill It is,
Speaker 7:  like the products we do require
Speaker 7:  really advanced tooling. And the, the
Speaker 7:  precision that you have to have in tooling and working with the
Speaker 7:  materials that we do are state of the art and the tooling
Speaker 7:  skill is very deep here. You know, in in
Speaker 7:  the US you could have a meeting of tooling engineers and I'm not sure
Speaker 7:  we could fill the room
Speaker 7:  in China, you could fill multiple football fields.
Speaker 5:  That's brutal. That's, that's rough. First of all, we should find out where
Speaker 5:  the meetings of tooling engineers in the United States are and how big they're
Speaker 5:  like, what's up guys? The whole country is depending on you and
Speaker 5:  they fit in like the back room of a Denny's somewhere. Just like they're
Speaker 5:  like, the pressure is out of control. I mean that's the problem. If
Speaker 5:  you want it, you have to invest in it. And no company is gonna look at
Speaker 5:  this tariff chaos and say, okay, this is a good investment
Speaker 5:  based on expected return. I need to avoid these tariffs. So I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  start training multiple football fields of tooling
Speaker 5:  engineers so that I can build one product. They're just gonna find another
Speaker 5:  way to do it. Well, and the the uncertainty is so much a
Speaker 5:  part of that too that right, like I think you could, you could make a
Speaker 5:  much more compelling version of that argument if there was a
Speaker 5:  coherent plan, even if you disagreed with the plan. It was like, here is,
Speaker 5:  here is the future as It is laid out and we are not going to go away from
Speaker 5:  it. But what, what I keep hearing from folks and what lots of folks on our
Speaker 5:  team have been reporting about is just the uncertainty is what kills you.
Speaker 5:  Like you, you don't actually even know where to invest your time and energy
Speaker 5:  and money right now because the tariffs might go away. They might change,
Speaker 5:  they might move, they might just suddenly evaporate all of
Speaker 5:  your possibilities in one country or another and everyone is just
Speaker 5:  frozen by it. So the idea that you're going to redirect investment actually
Speaker 5:  becomes harder in that world. Yeah. I think this also like even if you know
Speaker 5:  this is going to last for four
Speaker 6:  Years, can you even do it within that time to a
Speaker 6:  reasonable scale that it'll be valuable for you and that's not clear.
Speaker 6:  And then additionally, like to your point with uncertainty, we don't even
Speaker 6:  know that it would last beyond Trump given that everybody seems to hate this,
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 5:  There's one person who in America who likes tariffs and we just
Speaker 5:  happened to elect a
Speaker 1:  President. I'm not sure, by the way, if what Tim Cook was saying, there
Speaker 1:  was a football field densely packed with tooling
Speaker 1:  engineers or like a football stadium.
Speaker 6:  I imagined the former
Speaker 1:  Because if it's football stadium you're like, you're okay, you're doing the
Speaker 1:  math like okay that's, that's between like maybe 75 and a hundred thousand
Speaker 1:  people per stadium. You know, depending, like your biggest college football
Speaker 1:  stadiums are a hundred thousand people. So you're like, okay, it's like 300,000
Speaker 1:  tooling engineers. But if it's it's one densely packed
Speaker 1:  a hundred yard football field, maybe it's way less than that. I,
Speaker 1:  I've, I've been thinking about this since 2017.
Speaker 5:  I like imagining that it's, what he means actually is just, it's three football
Speaker 5:  fields, but it's just 11 on 11 on each field
Speaker 1:  It says
Speaker 5:  It is. All he means is it's actually six football teams. But he said it
Speaker 1:  Weird. It's, it's a but it's the full 53, you know? Right, exactly.
Speaker 1:  Look, that is from 2017. That's not
Speaker 1:  today. That's not Tim Cook disagreeing with Donald Trump today. That is
Speaker 1:  years ago. And that even that itself is seven years after
Speaker 1:  Steve Jobs made the same exact argument to Obama.
Speaker 5:  Right. And all that has done since then is accelerate it,
Speaker 1:  It hasn't gotten better. We haven't invested more into these kinds of roles
Speaker 1:  and this, this kind of training. And by all rights, the only party that can
Speaker 1:  actually do that is the government because the government is not expecting
Speaker 1:  that to return on investment in the form of a product tomorrow.
Speaker 1:  And so if yes, we should solve, we should build the iPhone here. We,
Speaker 1:  we, we all did this round of coverage in 2012 and 2013
Speaker 1:  we did it again when Trump got elected the first time in 16 and 17.
Speaker 1:  Now we're doing it a third time only. All of us have to be like, no, we are
Speaker 1:  real men. Which is deeply confusing. All of my cars are
Speaker 1:  faster than yours. I'm just saying it out loud. One is real loud.
Speaker 1:  It's ridiculous because the problem is the same. The problem is you need
Speaker 1:  a apparently six football teams worth of tooling engineers. And I just,
Speaker 1:  I don't like how, what's the plan there? 'cause if you wanna, it's,
Speaker 1:  you can't just punish people into training engineers in the United States.
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 5:  And it's not at all clear that we're gonna do anything to make that possible
Speaker 5:  either.
Speaker 6:  But we'll decide in 75 days, sorry, 90 days.
Speaker 1:  90 days. That's right. They're not even permanent. It's like the pause is
Speaker 1:  just 90 days. So we're already seeing a bunch of reactions to
Speaker 1:  this. Apple shipped 600 tons of iPhones
Speaker 1:  on planes to beat the tariffs. Anything that was already on a ship that was
Speaker 1:  like on route beat the tariffs. So there's a lot of that going on. So I don't
Speaker 1:  think we're gonna see immediate changes. The Sheens and Timus of the world
Speaker 1:  are in real trouble because the di minimus exception that
Speaker 1:  basically what those companies exist is going away. We don't know what's
Speaker 1:  going to happen. We know that hall creators like fashion hall creators are
Speaker 1:  just buying everything on team right now, which is getting ready.
Speaker 1:  Amazon has a weird team who copycat that's, they're already changing
Speaker 1:  where stuff is coming from. We sort of asked around, you can see other
Speaker 1:  changes. Tobias s Butler from Tosh Shein who was on the show last week, he
Speaker 1:  emailed us. He said, so with the new 104% tariff, the
Speaker 1:  cost of each manufactured Tosh Shein goes up 28%, which will
Speaker 1:  cost $90 each, which gets pretty close to the figure he
Speaker 1:  called bus week as this would kill me. So he has to, he would've
Speaker 1:  to raise price from 1 99 to 2 55 and
Speaker 1:  it's still not worthwhile to switch to US suppliers. So he is
Speaker 1:  the, like little creators are like coming to these existential points.
Speaker 1:  He says, I'm not sure what my immediate plan is except to reach out to the
Speaker 1:  community and see what people think about $250 framework, which we cover
Speaker 1:  a lot. They've just stopped selling their cheapest laptops here because of
Speaker 1:  tariffs. They delay, I think they delayed pre-orders.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it, it, they've, they've gone back and forth in a really fascinating
Speaker 5:  way. And I think actually framework is a company a lot of
Speaker 5:  other startups look to, to see how to do this because framework has like
Speaker 5:  spent a long time working on this stuff and is also sort of unusually
Speaker 5:  transparent in how all of this works. Like framework will sell you an
Speaker 5:  individual part of a computer. So it just like has to be able to tell more
Speaker 5:  stories about how it makes those things. But Sean
Speaker 5:  Haer wrote a thing for us earlier this week and basically in the,
Speaker 5:  in the span of 16 hours
Speaker 5:  tariffs were enacted, framework announced it was going
Speaker 5:  to increase the price over of, of all of its computers by 10%.
Speaker 5:  Like 45 minutes later Trump announces the pause 30 minutes
Speaker 5:  After that framework announces that it's bringing the prices back to normal
Speaker 5:  and then two hours later it says it's still going to increase prices. And
Speaker 5:  then it, it was not going to add for
Speaker 5:  pre-orders, it was not gonna open pre-orders on the laptop 12, which is
Speaker 5:  its new cheap one. But then it decided to anyway. And it's just like
Speaker 5:  this company, they just keep basically being like, look, we have no idea
Speaker 5:  what's going on either. We're just gonna keep updating this blog post as
Speaker 5:  best we can to tell you what's going on.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's great. Super certain makes sense for everyone who wants to invest
Speaker 1:  in a small company if the company doesn't even quite know what's happening.
Speaker 1:  Not just small companies, the biggest companies in the world totally caught
Speaker 1:  off guard. Speaking of updating blog posts, we just have a list of automakers
Speaker 1:  and what they're doing that Annie Kins has to keep updating 'cause the
Speaker 1:  plans keep changing. It's basically chaos. We, we will, we'll, we'll link
Speaker 1:  to that post, but VW is adding import fees.
Speaker 1:  Stellantis is idling production at various places, putting 900 jobs
Speaker 1:  on hold.
Speaker 1:  Jaguar, Jaar, Land Rover, like the people who live in the
Speaker 1:  town around its factory are basically like, this is the end of us. Ford has
Speaker 1:  so much inventory that they're just cutting prices across the board, which
Speaker 1:  is very good. Audi is just holding
Speaker 1:  37,000 cars at docks until something happens.
Speaker 5:  Because as long as they're there, they don't have to pay the tariffs, they
Speaker 5:  just, you just leave them. I think
Speaker 6:  They haven't brought them in yet, right? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  They're they're,
Speaker 6:  They're like, they're like, we gotta get these in eventually and like
Speaker 1:  They're on the other, other side of the fence. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  it's nuts. Like that's, that's all nuts. And then the main thing
Speaker 1:  that we should talk about is the switch to which
Speaker 1:  it, it feels like there's the weird cultural, like tariffs make you manly.
Speaker 1:  And then there's the switch to, and in terms of just
Speaker 1:  weird reactions, like the switch to I think bore the
Speaker 1:  brunt of it.
Speaker 6:  It's also been the most public because Nintendo had the just like terrible
Speaker 6:  luck of announcing the switch to, I don't know, 30 minutes
Speaker 6:  before the tra the, the, the tariff threats began.
Speaker 6:  And so they were doing this press tour as this
Speaker 6:  information was unfolding. And so normally companies can kind of
Speaker 6:  hide from some of these questions if they just don't put their executives
Speaker 6:  out there. But Nintendo was in the middle of putting their executives in
Speaker 6:  front of every single journalist they could find. And all of them
Speaker 6:  only had one question and it was, what is are you going to do about these
Speaker 6:  tariffs?
Speaker 1:  And it the, then the price is already high. So there's this assumption
Speaker 1:  that Nintendo priced the thing high for tariffs and the
Speaker 1:  answer, and I think Doug Bowser said this to our own Andrew Webster, he is
Speaker 1:  like, no, that was how much we priced it at and we'll see what happens
Speaker 1:  now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Which is not a great answer.
Speaker 5:  But then pre-orders were supposed to have been this week
Speaker 5:  and were not this week. And that was, that was the thing that really set
Speaker 5:  everybody on fire was Nintendo went from we're going to
Speaker 5:  sell you our very expensive console that you're gonna be slightly mad about,
Speaker 5:  but I definitely for sure buy anyway to actually
Speaker 5:  you can't buy it yet because we don't, we don't know what it's gonna cost.
Speaker 6:  And I think pre-orders for something like this is the worst possible situation
Speaker 6:  to be in because they're importing millions and billions
Speaker 6:  of these things. And if you're gonna sell them at $450 today
Speaker 6:  and you have zero idea what they're gonna cost you to bring in two months
Speaker 6:  from now when they actually go on sale, that could just devastate them.
Speaker 6:  And obviously they are going to be bringing a bunch in early to
Speaker 6:  avoid the tariffs as much as they can. Allegedly they've been stocking up
Speaker 6:  for months already, but it doesn't really change the fact that
Speaker 6:  they could be put in a position where a bunch of people have bought these
Speaker 6:  things early at one price and they actually have to start selling 'em at
Speaker 6:  a much higher price two months from now. That's just going to lead to a complete
Speaker 6:  de disaster for them.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And and there's there's no good answer at the end of that either. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like you, you either immediately increase the price Yeah. Of an already
Speaker 5:  pretty expensive thing and you can blame that on whoever you want, but it's
Speaker 5:  gonna hurt demand or you say, you know, get it now maybe
Speaker 5:  the price will go up, which is weird and bad. It's also
Speaker 5:  for a company that big, it's, it's like logistically
Speaker 5:  really complicated to change the price of something. This is something I've,
Speaker 5:  I've heard from a couple of people that I hadn't really thought about before
Speaker 5:  that like, you have to change your marketing materials and you have to change
Speaker 5:  like signs that you've made and you have to change like commercials
Speaker 5:  that you've, you've put out in the world that people are gonna be running
Speaker 5:  on television. Like it's actually not as simple as just changing the price
Speaker 5:  of a thing on your website. When you want to change the price of something,
Speaker 5:  it actually becomes a real process. And it, it's, I just
Speaker 5:  like that alone is very complicated. But like this is that,
Speaker 5:  that exact thing
Speaker 5:  is everywhere now. Like the, this guy Dan Roker who is the CEO of a company
Speaker 5:  called Limitless, they make one of those like AI voice recorders that
Speaker 5:  listens to you all the time and tells you what interesting stuff you said.
Speaker 5:  I have one upstairs, I haven't used it yet, but we'll report back, he
Speaker 5:  tweeted this yesterday. He said, our customers pre-ordered our product for
Speaker 5:  as low as $59. We have the product ready to ship, but with tariffs it
Speaker 5:  will now cost us $189 and 38 cents per unit.
Speaker 5:  Should we one wait until it gets better two ship now and eat the tariff cost
Speaker 5:  three, cancel the orders and eat the manufacturing cost. This
Speaker 1:  Is the worst SAT question I've ever heard entire.
Speaker 5:  But those are your options and they're all terrible. And if you're Nintendo,
Speaker 5:  maybe you can eat the cost, right? Like if, if if you're, if you're Apple
Speaker 5:  with famously high margins, you can eat the cost. None of these companies
Speaker 5:  want to because they like money and yeah,
Speaker 5:  that's the job. But a lot of these companies,
Speaker 5:  especially these smaller companies,
Speaker 1:  Literally
Speaker 5:  Cannot afford to eat that cost. And so now they're like, okay,
Speaker 5:  do I triple the price of my thing or am I out of business and am I out of
Speaker 5:  business either way?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well we're also saying like they might be able to eat the cost that's
Speaker 6:  like at 10% they might be able to eat that cost at like
Speaker 6:  34%. That becomes a completely different equation. And then
Speaker 6:  at some point we're talking about these a hundred plus percent tariffs. And
Speaker 6:  I, you know, I think depending on the country that they're manufacturing
Speaker 6:  in, they're going to have different levels of existential crisis here.
Speaker 6:  But all of them are pretty existential, even 10%, you know, I think we're
Speaker 6:  looking at that's what some of the stuff that frameworks is dealing with,
Speaker 6:  even that is enough to cause them heartburn and go, I don't think we can
Speaker 6:  sell this anymore.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The interesting question is gonna be where the money moves.
Speaker 1:  So, you know, for a a product like an AI voice recorder, there's a service
Speaker 1:  component with that. So you might sell the hardware at a loss and then
Speaker 1:  make the subscription price five times higher. Yep. I
Speaker 1:  I think we're gonna see a lot of those moves which will suck.
Speaker 1:  Like, just like flatly that will suck. Yeah. And then we're gonna see like
Speaker 1:  the end of discounting like most people price in sales, like that stuff is
Speaker 1:  gonna go away so that we don't know what's gonna happen. And I think the
Speaker 1:  switch to is gonna be kind of like the leading indicator,
Speaker 1:  how certain anybody feels because It is a product everybody wants and they
Speaker 1:  could probably raise the price and still sell a lot of them, but I don't
Speaker 1:  think they want to, I think they already know it's high and they're already
Speaker 1:  getting yelled at 'cause it's high. There's other other stuff, weird stuff
Speaker 1:  happening in response by the way, China is considering showing fewer
Speaker 1:  US films, which would just basically crush the Marvel machine, right?
Speaker 1:  I mean,
Speaker 5:  Less so than a few years ago. Like it's, that's shifted a little bit already,
Speaker 5:  but It is still a huge part of the industry. And it's like we, it, it was
Speaker 5:  very funny, we were talking about this earlier that like, do you remember
Speaker 5:  how all the bad guys in Mission Impossible movies are now called like the
Speaker 5:  entity, nobody like fights foreign countries anymore. Yeah. They're all
Speaker 5:  just like nameless bad guys. That's because they wanted these
Speaker 5:  movies to play in other markets, mostly China. And so like,
Speaker 5:  and then China like took all the stuff that it learned from Hollywood, built
Speaker 5:  its own now, has a huge homegrown movie industry and
Speaker 5:  is now just like, yeah, get out. Yeah. All that money used to make from showing
Speaker 5:  movies in our, our country. Goodbye. Yeah. China has a lot of those
Speaker 5:  moves to make if it wants to,
Speaker 1:  It does have a lot of those moves to make. I'm just saying that I watch the
Speaker 1:  three body problem and I'm like less worried about it than maybe
Speaker 1:  your
Speaker 5:  Not so worried about that one. That's
Speaker 1:  Fair. Yeah. And not, not the, not that a new Netflix bad one. I mean the
Speaker 1:  Chinese bad one,
Speaker 1:  just to be clear, the Netflix one was worse. That's like worse
Speaker 1:  evidence and
Speaker 5:  Longer. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  What are we doing here guys? I'm just over my alcoholism was a
Speaker 1:  real plot point in the Netflix one. All right, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 1:  Maybe by the time we're back we'll know what's going on with Sarah. Let's
Speaker 1:  find out. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  We're back. I wanna issue a correction. It was just called Three Body
Speaker 1:  It Air on Peacock in the United States.
Speaker 5:  There you go. Also, I just want you to know people sometimes ask what we
Speaker 5:  did during the break. I went to New York times.com because I literally
Speaker 5:  thought it was possible that there was new tariffs news while we were at
Speaker 5:  break. There's not. So that's exciting.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Good. We'll see how, we'll see how this goes in the next 30 minutes.
Speaker 1:  There's tariffs, then there's ai. A AI also had, I would say a messy
Speaker 1:  week starting with Meta, which
Speaker 1:  I think tried to release a bunch of exciting news about Llama and then
Speaker 1:  all of it quickly became unexciting. What's going on here?
Speaker 5:  Jake, can you explain this one?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so Zuckerberg, I, I think he wanted to
Speaker 6:  have a little bit of Elon Energy here. So last weekend, I think it was
Speaker 6:  the middle of Saturday, he was just like, boom, Lama four, here It is. Everybody
Speaker 6:  go have fun and just, you know, kind of try to catch people by surprise
Speaker 6:  dropped this big new model that people have been expecting. And you know,
Speaker 6:  at first glance everybody was like, wow, very impressive. Great
Speaker 6:  benchmarks. And this is the thing, every single time a new flagship model
Speaker 6:  comes out, the companies brag about these benchmarks and they show how they
Speaker 6:  perform against all the other models and inevitably, inevitably their
Speaker 6:  best model beats out all the other models on the market.
Speaker 6:  And that was what would happen here with one of the Lama four models. And
Speaker 6:  then eventually people started to look a little bit closer, started to look
Speaker 6:  at some of the fine print on this and they realized that Meta
Speaker 6:  had actually benchmarked a secret model
Speaker 6:  that only they have access to that they're not actually releasing.
Speaker 6:  And so it's like an experimental chat specific
Speaker 6:  version that is sort of potentially designed to beat
Speaker 6:  these benchmarks that they're not releasing to the public. It was just used
Speaker 6:  to look great on benchmarks and so people have been freaking out
Speaker 6:  about this. The specific benchmark that they nearly
Speaker 6:  topped the leaderboard on was like, Hey guys, that's not how it's supposed
Speaker 6:  to work. And Meta was just like, we have
Speaker 6:  lots of great models, I don't know what to tell you. And so I, I think it
Speaker 6:  has not been the reception they were hoping for for Llama four, which is
Speaker 6:  supposed to be this big release, supposed to get them back in the conversation.
Speaker 6:  Meta has been trying to make llama the big quote unquote
Speaker 6:  allegedly open source option to get a lot of big a adoption
Speaker 6:  here. And you know, I think if they
Speaker 6:  wanted to curry favor with the community, this is sort
Speaker 6:  of off to a bad start. 'cause now they're starting to feel a little bit misled
Speaker 6:  and they're already also starting to, I think, complain about some of the
Speaker 6:  restrictions and limitations around meta's. You know,
Speaker 6:  so, so-called open source approach to it. Anyway,
Speaker 5:  I really genuinely respect Meta's inability to help
Speaker 5:  itself from doing stuff like this. Like
Speaker 5:  you go way back and you know, meta got in all this trouble for
Speaker 5:  massively inflating the view count of all the videos so that publishers would
Speaker 5:  make videos and like screwed up a whole generation of publishers on the internet.
Speaker 5:  As a result, this company just cannot help itself
Speaker 5:  from making up numbers about things in order to look
Speaker 5:  impressive.
Speaker 6:  I kind of love it. I I love this like, let me be clear, don't do this,
Speaker 6:  this is bad. But also it, it really just shows how
Speaker 6:  nonsensical these benchmark charts are. Like what does it
Speaker 6:  mean that it gets 98% of some random benchmark? Like I, I
Speaker 6:  don't know what that does, I don't know what that means. Number just goes
Speaker 6:  up
Speaker 6:  and I think it's just increasingly clear that these do not actually
Speaker 6:  correspond to, does the model give you a correct, accurate,
Speaker 6:  good and useful output? It corresponds to can
Speaker 6:  this model beat this computer test? And in this case
Speaker 6:  they specifically designed it so that it could beat this test a little bit
Speaker 6:  better than the other models
Speaker 1:  Isn't what isn't this particular benchmark doesn't have humans in the
Speaker 6:  Loop. It does. This is a really interesting one where they do, they parrot
Speaker 6:  against output from other models and so you choose which one is better
Speaker 6:  and so they're specifically tuning it theoretically so that humans will respond
Speaker 6:  better to their their thing.
Speaker 5:  Right? That's the best part of this. It's not designed to be better, it's
Speaker 5:  designed to do whatever it takes to make the humans think that
Speaker 5:  it's better. Which is so funny. It's like we don't have to build a better
Speaker 5:  model, we just have to build a model that convinces the idiots that it's
Speaker 5:  better and then we've done it
Speaker 1:  Perfect. That's one of the most meta instincts of all
Speaker 1:  times. Like we don't have to be sincere, we just have to be
Speaker 1:  convincing. By the way, meta loves to game benchmarks.
Speaker 1:  Like there's a whole thing here about companies gaming benchmarks and the
Speaker 1:  history of tech, like every GPU company has been caught. Gaming
Speaker 1:  benchmarks. Yeah. It's just a thing they all do. Every laptop company has
Speaker 1:  been caught gaming benchmarks in one way or another.
Speaker 1:  Intel has been caught gaming benchmarks, but this one is like particularly
Speaker 1:  meta in that they inflated their own video numbers for years
Speaker 1:  and then they kind of admitted it and they're kinda like, but whatever like
Speaker 1:  number was so big. Right? And it's like very much the attitude
Speaker 1:  they're taking with this. I agree with you Jake. At the end of the day where
Speaker 1:  it really matters is can anyone build useful products outta this stuff? Like
Speaker 1:  these benchmarks do not matter. Like every week there's a
Speaker 1:  new one and another thing is slightly better than the last one. And we're
Speaker 1:  still all looking at fundamentally the same chat bot products
Speaker 1:  with the same distribution.
Speaker 1:  M maybe Meta's gonna do the glasses like we've heard about them that, you
Speaker 1:  know, that will obviously rely on llama in some huge way. But I
Speaker 1:  don't think that matters if it's llama in there or chat CBT. Like it's,
Speaker 1:  it's really the interface and the distribution that like carries you forward
Speaker 1:  not the capability of the model.
Speaker 5:  I agree with you in every way except one. And I think the,
Speaker 5:  the one is that I think we're still early enough in this industry
Speaker 5:  that momentum is really important. And what is definitely true is
Speaker 5:  that LM Arena, which is the, the website that runs these benchmarks
Speaker 5:  is a website. People who make AI stuff look at a lot.
Speaker 5:  Sure. And so being at the top of that leaderboard is, is a
Speaker 5:  signifier of stuff to the people you want to like come work for your
Speaker 5:  company to build cool AI products or come, you know,
Speaker 5:  build with your API and pay you a bunch of money to use it. Like these things
Speaker 5:  are not meant for regular people to care about. Generally speaking,
Speaker 5:  they're meant for like the people in the business to care about. And I think
Speaker 5:  that's all the more reason to try and game it right? Like the, these benchmarks
Speaker 5:  exist to try and get AI researchers to wanna work at Meta
Speaker 5:  and not open AI and coming out like
Speaker 5:  you're cheating is a, is a tough look. And I think there's been a lot of
Speaker 5:  that forever. Right? Do you, you guys remember at, in the early days of this,
Speaker 5:  there was this whole big kerfuffle with Apple where Apple wasn't
Speaker 5:  letting its researchers publish publicly their research. And
Speaker 5:  so it was having a hard time getting researchers because one of the things
Speaker 5:  these people wanna do is like publish their work and share it with the world.
Speaker 5:  And so Apple has had to rethink the way that it talks about its AI
Speaker 5:  stuff in order to get good people to come work there. And so I think in that
Speaker 5:  sense, playing these games really does matter
Speaker 5:  but it's in a much less like human relevant way
Speaker 5:  than like actually making good products, which none of
Speaker 5:  these companies are doing.
Speaker 6:  No, I think that makes sense. And you know, I think that community is, that
Speaker 6:  community is the people who freaked out about this. Yes. They're the ones
Speaker 6:  who feel betrayed because they're, you know, they were excited about this
Speaker 6:  and I think Meta has made big promises about,
Speaker 6:  you know, how you'll be able to use Llama because of its, you know,
Speaker 6:  allegedly open source approach. But It
Speaker 5:  Is the opposite of Deeps seek. You just made me realize that Deeps Seek was
Speaker 5:  the one where everybody's like, it can't possibly be this good and then started
Speaker 5:  using it and they're like, oh my god, it's incredible. This is the one everybody's
Speaker 5:  like, whoa, it's really good. And then it's like, nevermind. It's not
Speaker 1:  Actually, you know, it's funny you mentioned Apple there. 'cause what I was
Speaker 1:  gonna say is, you know, who's not in the ARI boards is
Speaker 1:  our friends in Cupertino.
Speaker 1:  I mean they have some models. They're not building their frontier model at
Speaker 1:  scale. Big story in the information this week about Siri actually at Apple.
Speaker 1:  It's a lot, there's a lot going on in this story. It's basically, here's
Speaker 1:  why Siri is bad, which keeping with the theme of this episode is a
Speaker 1:  story we have been telling for 15 years. But this one in
Speaker 1:  particular has a lot of details. Some of 'em shakier than others
Speaker 1:  about what actually happened. Here are the, the three that just
Speaker 1:  jumped out to me and you tell me, I know you guys read this story too. You
Speaker 1:  tell me if these are the ones jumped out to you. One, we've, we've talked
Speaker 1:  a lot about the WWDC video of what like Agentic Siri could do on the iPhone
Speaker 1:  with app intense. And you just ask it where your grandmother is and it
Speaker 1:  like finds her and sends her a note or whatever. Whatever was happening in
Speaker 1:  that demo. The Siri team, according to this information report, had not seen
Speaker 1:  any of that working Whoof. So that was just a pure demo
Speaker 1:  and the Siri team was surprised at what they were seeing. That's
Speaker 5:  Really
Speaker 1:  Bad. That's real bad. Second there and I'm just like a
Speaker 1:  decoder org chart, you know, aficionado
Speaker 1:  John g and Andrea ran his own AI team. He was apparently
Speaker 1:  a very sleepy manager, didn't have a lot of fire and Craig Federighi built
Speaker 1:  his own team to do stuff with machine learning
Speaker 1:  inside of Apple that got bigger and bigger and bigger and started competing
Speaker 1:  for researchers and ISN and and engineers with the main AI
Speaker 1:  team, which led to him taking over Syria in the end
Speaker 1:  also. It is very bad, right? Yep. That's, that's not good news. And then
Speaker 1:  the last one, which is particularly funny is there was apparently a big debate
Speaker 1:  in the aftermath of the WWE C demo about how many models
Speaker 1:  Apple would use if they would have a local model on the phone
Speaker 1:  that responded to local stuff like timers called Mini Mouse and then a big
Speaker 1:  model in the cloud for big stuff called Mighty Mouse or whether it should
Speaker 1:  all be Mighty Mouse. And I think they landed on all Mighty Mouse and none
Speaker 1:  of that shipped and none of it worked. And who knows what's gonna happen
Speaker 1:  They picked wrong.
Speaker 5:  I like really, I think the, the one of the lessons we are learning here very
Speaker 5:  quickly is that actually
Speaker 5:  single behemoth models that do everything have their place. But ultimately
Speaker 5:  the answer is lots of models for lots of things. And Apple
Speaker 5:  seems to have just, it's, it's like, it's like picking the vision pro instead
Speaker 5:  of picking smart glasses, right? Like it, it tried to do the whole thing
Speaker 5:  and in so doing prevented itself from doing the
Speaker 5:  thing that actually works.
Speaker 6:  I I'm also really curious about, you know, they took this, we're gonna do
Speaker 6:  it very heavily lean on local processing for the
Speaker 6:  AI approach and I think, you know, if you go back, what, like
Speaker 6:  two years on the Pixel they were like, hey, you know, you have to have
Speaker 6:  the highest end Pixel in order to use Gemini because you need the
Speaker 6:  local processing abilities, you need the ram. And then fast forward
Speaker 6:  like, I don't know, six months and all of those abilities are just on
Speaker 6:  all of the phones anyway 'cause they're all just doing it in the cloud. And
Speaker 6:  so I'm kind of just wondering also if Apple's still just picking wrong
Speaker 6:  by trying to do so much on the iPhone because It is sort of against
Speaker 6:  their constitution to offload this stuff to the cloud
Speaker 6:  because of the privacy concerns around that. Which, you know, that's fair.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's a really great perk to be able to say, hey, this is all local,
Speaker 6:  it's all secure, it's all safe. But it's just one of those things where it's
Speaker 6:  sort of a self, self enforced
Speaker 6:  limitation that's continuing
Speaker 5:  To hold them back. Totally. And the way that they're getting around that
Speaker 5:  when they have to go to the cloud is just by punting it on a cha GBT, which
Speaker 5:  is absurd actually the best way to do it, unfortunately.
Speaker 5:  I mean probably, but it sure doesn't make Apple look very good.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Wait, while we're talking about org charts, we, we should move on from
Speaker 5:  this. There's other stuff to talk about, but I just, I wanna read a paragraph
Speaker 5:  to you guys from this story. It's by Wayne Mott, the information, shout out
Speaker 5:  to Wayne. It's a good story and I want you guys to tell me
Speaker 5:  whether this sounds like people want AI or that
Speaker 5:  they don't want ai. It says former Apple employees have referred to Siri
Speaker 5:  as a quote. Hot potato continuously passed between different teams, including
Speaker 5:  those led by Apple Services Chief Eddie Q and by Fedi. However, none
Speaker 5:  of these reorganizations led to significant improvements in serious performance.
Speaker 5:  There's one way to look at this that says everybody is trying to get
Speaker 5:  it, but nobody can pull it off. And there is another way of looking at it
Speaker 5:  that says Sir poison and no one wants to be in charge of it. And I'm
Speaker 5:  starting to wonder if it's the second thing.
Speaker 1:  It's the second I, I don't know. I I, I read that
Speaker 1:  same thing and I, it's funny that you saw ambiguity in it and I was
Speaker 1:  like, oh, it's poison.
Speaker 5:  Okay, okay. I mean that was my initial read too. But then I'm like, okay,
Speaker 5:  there is another way you could look at this that is like, it's, it's, it's
Speaker 5:  very competitive. Everybody wants to be in charge. I think you're right.
Speaker 5:  I think it's poison.
Speaker 1:  Well I think there's, you can intellectually make the argument that being
Speaker 1:  in charge of Siri right now at Apple makes you the most powerful person Apple
Speaker 1:  because all of the things that might kill the iPhone are
Speaker 1:  things that look like what Siri should have been doing 10 years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like OpenAI has this project with Johnny, ive
Speaker 1:  for a Screenless device that's obviously some sort of like
Speaker 1:  Siri puck, right? And maybe it'll work and maybe it won't, but like that's
Speaker 1:  the thing, the meta glasses we've talked about a lot. That's gonna be a voice
Speaker 1:  activated assistant thing. Samsung is gonna release the Bali robot,
Speaker 1:  which let's, let's just pretend it's in the mix here,
Speaker 1:  right? Like what you want is a ball that rolls around your house and projects
Speaker 1:  Samsung's fast TV service on the wall and responds to your voice,
Speaker 5:  Hey, no other AI product has that kind of physical presence.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 1:  True. It's very good. Like do
Speaker 5:  None, you even have a shape.
Speaker 1:  Do you want a small rolling ball in your house that shows up
Speaker 1:  and commands you to exercise on command? The Bali is there for you.
Speaker 5:  I I do. I
Speaker 1:  Like, I earnestly do. Yes. Every Bali demo is like at the end of it, it's
Speaker 1:  like a now do jumping jab. It's like very good. All of this is predicated
Speaker 1:  on voice working. Alexa is predicated on voice working.
Speaker 1:  So anything that might kill the iPhone has this one
Speaker 1:  interface idea embedded in it, which is natural language voice
Speaker 1:  commands will work and the computer will have natural language voice
Speaker 1:  output. It will, it will, it will work. None of
Speaker 1:  it works, right? To be clear, like humane existed
Speaker 1:  and then went 90 like famously no longer exists.
Speaker 1:  None of it works yet. But if you're Apple
Speaker 1:  being in charge of the Siri team is being in charge of the thing that might
Speaker 1:  kill you. Yeah. And I think they can't figure it out 'cause they also can't
Speaker 1:  break it. Like I think one of the hardest things about
Speaker 1:  Siri is everyone knows that voice is a thing that might disrupt the
Speaker 1:  touchscreen, but, which I don't necessarily agree with, but that's what everyone
Speaker 1:  thinks. But everyone knows that voice is a thing that might disrupt the touchscreen.
Speaker 1:  And then you've got however many years of Siri
Speaker 1:  existing and doing timers and starting music and pretty much
Speaker 1:  doing those things that you cannot break,
Speaker 5:  Right? And Apple talks all the time about how often Siri gets used
Speaker 5:  and even if it's just for those two things, It is still, it's an entrenched
Speaker 5:  user behavior now that you can't screw up even though they are
Speaker 5:  doing their very best to screw
Speaker 1:  It up. Yeah. So I just see it as here's this thing where if you get it,
Speaker 1:  the stakes are so high, your opportunity to make change is
Speaker 1:  so limited 'cause you can't break it. And then you also have to invent
Speaker 1:  the cutting edge of ai.
Speaker 6:  What you're describing is just what Google did with Gemini already, right?
Speaker 6:  And, and the, the advantage they have is that they have a functional AI division,
Speaker 6:  but they had Google assistant, which was like roughly as good as
Speaker 6:  Siri and it, it, you know, it set timers, it added stuff to your calendar
Speaker 6:  and when they launched Gemini, it broke all of that, couldn't do any of that.
Speaker 6:  And then they've just slowly hacked each one of those things on
Speaker 6:  to Gemini and now they're just like, we're done. Forget Google Assistant,
Speaker 6:  we had 10 years of brand equity, whatever, nobody cares. Gemini's new thing.
Speaker 6:  And they just like, they're there just fundamentally wasn't that much good
Speaker 6:  stuff about these old era of assistance that you can kind of just
Speaker 6:  start from scratch and rebuild timers. Because a a, as much
Speaker 6:  as it pains us that it takes like five years to add a multiple
Speaker 6:  timer feature to each of these things, like that surely isn't the hardest
Speaker 6:  part of building ai. And so we've seen another company do this already and
Speaker 6:  it feels like what Siri needs is that start from scratch moment. And theoretically
Speaker 6:  they had that and it's just like not quite clear why that isn't clicking.
Speaker 1:  Well two things about that. One, Google had its own bloody
Speaker 1:  org chart battle over That's true. Making AI functional AI division
Speaker 5:  Google also invented most of this technology. Like there might be no other
Speaker 5:  company in tech as equipped to do what you just described as
Speaker 5:  Google. And even it was a giant mess for Google,
Speaker 1:  Right? And then they did have two products, assistant and Gemini Coexist
Speaker 1:  side by side in the most Google of fashions. And then I think if you go and
Speaker 1:  look at the Google Home forums and the Google Assistant forums, the switch
Speaker 1:  to Gemini just being there, is it going about as well as Google
Speaker 1:  Home goes? You know what I mean? Like Yeah. Did
Speaker 1:  sure. I like, there's enough people in those forums who believe that Google
Speaker 1:  Home is effectively abandoned that it should really worry Google,
Speaker 1:  right? So like, yeah, they're in the middle of this transition and maybe
Speaker 1:  it will all come out on the end is sunshine daisies. But right now it's like,
Speaker 1:  oh, the thing that we depend on feels like abandoned. Well like for example,
Speaker 1:  this is just a really dumb one. We have Google Homes in our
Speaker 1:  house and they are meant to control our Sonos because we have Sonos speakers
Speaker 1:  from the time when those two companies got along and they just stopped working.
Speaker 1:  They just, you, you could be like, yo, play me the music and it's like I'm
Speaker 1:  doing, I'm doing it on the kitchen and you're like, no you're not. Do it
Speaker 1:  again. And it's like, I'm super doing it. I'm playing this music on kitchen
Speaker 1:  and it's not. And there's just, you know, you look at the Reddit post and
Speaker 1:  it's like 400 days ago someone said the Google Home stopped working and they
Speaker 1:  just don't care. And like that that, I think that's,
Speaker 1:  I agree with youj, Google has done a better job. Like Amazon hasn't pulled
Speaker 1:  this off with Alexa.
Speaker 6:  If I can defend Google Home for one second, it's been bad for years.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough.
Speaker 1:  Other AI stuff. Jake, you wanna talk about the Shopify CEO saying that
Speaker 1:  no one can make a new hire at the company without proof that AI can't
Speaker 1:  do the job. And you were like, this is more reasonable than people think
Speaker 1:  and I'm excited for you to defend this take. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Sorry, sorry. Oh boy. Oh boy.
Speaker 1:  So Jake, here's this smoking stick of dynamite. What would you like to do?
Speaker 6:  That's, that was, yeah that was, that was, It is in fact part of what I said.
Speaker 6:  So Shopify not, not Spotify. Let's be clear with
Speaker 6:  that. Shopify's, CEO Toby Luque, if I'm pronouncing that
Speaker 6:  ballpark,
Speaker 6:  you know, thi this, this memo got leaked and so he just posted the entire
Speaker 6:  thing on X. So you can go and read it and you know, the headline
Speaker 6:  of It is, you know, Shopify CEO says like, you can't hire
Speaker 6:  anybody whose job can be done by ai. And you know what, It is true he says
Speaker 6:  that in there. But I do think, you know, if you read the entire thing,
Speaker 6:  It is both more reasonable and I think less reasonable
Speaker 6:  than you think. Because on one hand he's just like, actually we just all
Speaker 6:  sort of need to learn ai. And the other hand he's like, we will 100 XR productivity.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, I, I think one thing that occurs to me is that the
Speaker 6:  people who are using AI the most right now, It is the engineers. It is like
Speaker 6:  the developers who are just coding all day long using these
Speaker 6:  things separately. Anthropic just launched an a $200 a
Speaker 6:  month tier this week where they're just like, yeah, we think that engineers
Speaker 6:  will just pay for this when their work won't. So they can just like use it
Speaker 6:  all day long. So this is our, I I think when you send
Speaker 6:  this memo out to an organization that is substantially built out of engineers,
Speaker 6:  this is not necessarily as scary as it would be if you send it out to
Speaker 6:  your news organization, which would be like, whew, sorry.
Speaker 6:  And so I think, you know, there's parts of this memo where he says, here's
Speaker 6:  just some of the preface where he goes quote, what we have learned so far
Speaker 6:  is that using AI well is a skill that needs to be carefully learned by
Speaker 6:  using it a lot. And it's like, okay, yeah this is actually like, this is
Speaker 6:  like pretty, pretty reasonable. You actually should test these tools to see
Speaker 6:  if there are ways to build them into your workflow. But at the same time
Speaker 6:  he is saying, I think the very big scary thing that has everybody
Speaker 6:  worried, which is yeah, these tools are going to number one,
Speaker 6:  change how we work and in doing so start to potentially replace
Speaker 6:  roles that would otherwise have been hired. And so I, I think this
Speaker 6:  is, you know, this is a very scary memo.
Speaker 6:  I think it's also just worth reading and understanding because this is actually
Speaker 6:  just how a lot of these companies are going to be thinking about this. And
Speaker 6:  I think, is AI ready to replace a single
Speaker 6:  human right now? I sure wouldn't make that bet. Is it
Speaker 6:  ready to do little bits and pieces of some people's jobs? I think the answer
Speaker 6:  is clearly yes. Especially if you look to developers
Speaker 6:  and, and I think, you know, we have an engineering heavy organization here
Speaker 6:  that is saying, Hey, let's start using this more and more to get a little
Speaker 6:  bit more efficient. Some of the stuff he's saying is like, actually you should
Speaker 6:  just use this in your prototypes, right? It's not necessarily you should
Speaker 6:  go and replace your coworker with it. You just like, it's like I'm making
Speaker 6:  it mandatory that you use this in your prototyping phase. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Seems, seems fun. It's
Speaker 1:  Funny 'cause I didn't read that as being about the engineers. I read that
Speaker 1:  as being about like product managers and salespeople and like people have
Speaker 1:  ideas for new features and it's like you're just gonna vibe code out a garbage
Speaker 1:  version of the new feature so you can push the buttons and play with it
Speaker 1:  and see if it's any good. And I, there's something about that that really
Speaker 1:  speaks to me, right? Because I, I can't do that and I, this is the
Speaker 1:  thing I keep thinking about is our own company,
Speaker 1:  like is like putting out ads being like stop AI theft, government
Speaker 1:  disclosure of box media is putting out ad with a bunch of other publishers
Speaker 1:  being like, stop AI theft government. And you know, our team has
Speaker 1:  thoughts about AI and I certainly have thoughts about ai. I think I'm a better
Speaker 1:  writer than AI to this day. Declarative sentences be damned. That's what
Speaker 1:  AI thinks I write like, but I can't code, I I
Speaker 1:  certainly couldn't code like a prototype feature of a thing that I wanted.
Speaker 1:  And the idea that I this tool can let me do It is super interesting. And
Speaker 1:  then you see, even in creative industries, people are complaining about it,
Speaker 1:  but then they use the features like mad. So I would pair the Shopify app,
Speaker 1:  the Shopify thing app with what I think is kind of the most interesting AI
Speaker 1:  features. It's been announced in a long time, which is Adobe building AI
Speaker 1:  agents in Photoshop and Premier Pro where you're just like doing
Speaker 1:  Photoshop work and it's like, do you wanna do this thing? And it's like super
Speaker 1:  clippy and then it just does it for you. Like it clicks around the Photoshop
Speaker 1:  interface for you and just does it.
Speaker 6:  I think there's something super interesting about this Photoshop example
Speaker 6:  too, where if you watch the video of what it shows that, that it's
Speaker 6:  suggesting you do, it's stuff like add a blur to the background
Speaker 6:  and it's like three years ago nobody would've called that AI that like Google
Speaker 6:  photos just auto suggests that on literally every photo.
Speaker 1:  It really
Speaker 6:  Does. And, and, and it so like there's just this broad spectrum of
Speaker 6:  what like, quote unquote AI is now. And there
Speaker 6:  are, I think these these small tools that people
Speaker 6:  are just sort of using instinctively every day without quite considering
Speaker 6:  them to be ai because it's just, oh this is just making me like 2% more efficient.
Speaker 6:  And I, you know, we sort of freak out when it changes from this 2% thing
Speaker 6:  to the like, I must replace my coworker because my boss won't gimme more
Speaker 6:  resources. Which is like concerning. I mean,
Speaker 1:  And a funny thing to do is like, if you just
Speaker 5:  Sort of in your mind find and replace every time somebody says AI with
Speaker 5:  software, the, the temperature on everything goes down a little. But
Speaker 5:  it also sounds exactly like the
Speaker 5:  conversations everybody had when we were first inventing computer software,
Speaker 5:  right? Like the, the sort of moral panic around
Speaker 5:  computers kicking everybody out of jobs is has been around as long as
Speaker 5:  computers have been around. What's different now is that everybody is telling
Speaker 5:  you that they're building God to do it for you.
Speaker 1:  Well right, but I mean like the, I don't need the accountant because I have
Speaker 1:  Excel. It is like one version of this. I I am a
Speaker 1:  marketing director and I can build a fully functional prototype of a
Speaker 1:  feature that I wanna ship in the main software. Very different.
Speaker 5:  See, but I think the second thing is less existentially frightening than
Speaker 5:  the first thing. I think we won't need accountants anymore because Excel
Speaker 5:  exists was much more plausibly threatening
Speaker 5:  to people's jobs than now I can make a crappy prototype
Speaker 5:  by myself.
Speaker 1:  It is true by the way that Excel got so complicated that we need accountants
Speaker 1:  more than ever. Yeah. And maybe that's just the trajectory that we're on.
Speaker 5:  Peop accountants just use Excel now. That's, that's the only thing that changed
Speaker 5:  is accountants use Excel. Alright.
Speaker 1:  I don't know on what timeline Google Assistant will be good, but I
Speaker 1:  do know that we should probably put Shopify in charge of it. We gotta take
Speaker 1:  a break. We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back David. It's time.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god, it's time. We've waited this long once again,
Speaker 5:  we are here for America's first or second favorite
Speaker 5:  podcast within podcast for which we have now
Speaker 5:  received theme music that I have to figure out if I'm allowed to play on
Speaker 5:  this show. Sent in by listeners once I know if that's legal
Speaker 5:  for me to do without asking permission. Starting next week, we have theme
Speaker 5:  music. It's time for Brendan Carr is a Dummy.
Speaker 1:  It's funny because the, on this America's favorite podcast within a podcast
Speaker 1:  except for the other podcast, within a podcast that people love
Speaker 5:  Top two. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  We've started to receive fan submissions for parts
Speaker 1:  of the segment,
Speaker 1:  like more so than I think the main vergecast at this point, which is very
Speaker 1:  good. It's good stuff. So this week, a few things to talk about this week,
Speaker 1:  but the main thing, so many people sent me this
Speaker 1:  photo of Brendan Carr, chair of the FCC smiling in
Speaker 1:  his dumb suit, wearing a pin that is the gold head of
Speaker 1:  Donald Trump. Just so proud of himself that he's wearing a pin
Speaker 1:  that is the gold head of Donald Trump. Look you there. There are some like
Speaker 1:  overheated blog posts about this thing about how this is maoism
Speaker 1:  and this is what mounted Chad, like I Brandon's not that
Speaker 1:  smart. You know, he's not intentionally making a callback to the
Speaker 1:  Maoists and the cultural revolution. No. He's
Speaker 1:  just a dummy who wants to impress his buddy Donald Trump and
Speaker 1:  doesn't realize that being the head of our nation's communications
Speaker 1:  infrastructure should require him to be nonpartisan.
Speaker 1:  Instead, he's making it plain that in fact he is a political flunky
Speaker 1:  who shouldn't have this job by wearing the gold head of Donald Trump on his
Speaker 1:  chest. You don't want that. If you had a Democrat wearing the gold head
Speaker 1:  of Barack Obama in charge of the FCC during the net neutrality battles,
Speaker 1:  I'm pretty sure the Republicans would've burned the building down.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  You don't want that. You don't want it on either side. You want these people
Speaker 1:  to be relatively neutral. The reason you have a commission that's made up
Speaker 1:  of Democrats and Republicans by statute is so that when they take votes,
Speaker 1:  they're not political. That's not how it's supposed to work, right?
Speaker 1:  They're supposed to reach some compromise on regulatory affairs. But anyway,
Speaker 1:  you got this dummy wearing the goldhead of Donald Trump. That's, that's just,
Speaker 1:  that's our boy Brendan making it plain that he is just a political fluky.
Speaker 1:  He's there to do the president's bidding and the president's bidding is to
Speaker 1:  chill speech across the board.
Speaker 5:  It's not important. But this pin itself is, is pretty spectacular.
Speaker 5:  Like I have to say it's, it's definitely like some BS fake
Speaker 5:  gold stuff. But in it, Trump has substantially better
Speaker 5:  hair than he does in real life. But It is also making like a, a little bit
Speaker 5:  of a kissy face and the direction it's facing on
Speaker 5:  our man. Brendan's lapel kind of makes it look like Trump is about to like
Speaker 5:  kiss him on his neck. And that's just, that's just a visual. I really appreciate,
Speaker 6:  The first time I saw a photo of this, I was like, this is a hundred percent
Speaker 6:  ai. There there's just like, there's no chance this is real. This is too
Speaker 6:  insane and regret to inform you all I was wrong.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a real bummer. I,
Speaker 1:  I can't believe I'm gonna say this, but you know, if you pay attention to
Speaker 1:  Trump, he's always kind of making a kissy face.
Speaker 5:  That is true. He does have sort of like resting kissy face.
Speaker 1:  It's really true. He is. It's and he is not lost in thought. He is just
Speaker 1:  persing his lips. I don't know what's going on there.
Speaker 1:  I wanna call out our friends at Ars Technica who wrote a huge
Speaker 1:  profile of Brendan this week. They called him The speech police. They're
Speaker 1:  going through all the news distortion cases that we have covered endlessly
Speaker 1:  on the show. It's just very clear to a lot of people
Speaker 1:  that Brendan Carr wants to censor the internet and censor broadcast regulators.
Speaker 1:  It's not just us talking about it, we just have the most fun doing it
Speaker 1:  because my brain is broken. It, it's out there. It's
Speaker 1:  out in other publications. I think Rolling Stone did a piece, the ours piece
Speaker 1:  is particularly good in a way that ours is particularly good all the time.
Speaker 1:  Yep. It's also starting to hit the other commissioners
Speaker 1:  in the FCC. So we wanna do something we don't usually do here on Brennan
Speaker 1:  Carr's Dummy America's favorite podcast. Winning podcast. I'm gonna point
Speaker 1:  out that the other commissioners of the FCC are doing a good job. So in
Speaker 1:  particular, Anna Gomez who is a democratic commissioner, was recently the
Speaker 1:  National Association of Broadcasters Convention. The nab, the NAB Convention.
Speaker 1:  And she directly openly called it out.
Speaker 1:  She basically said Brenda is a sensor and the FCC is totally out bounds.
Speaker 1:  She said it's particularly important for media regulation, which is why the
Speaker 1:  FCC was set up as an independent agency a long time ago. Because the fear
Speaker 1:  was the type of interference that you are now seeing today with the White
Speaker 1:  House with media, whether it's broadcasters, public media and internet platforms
Speaker 1:  in the attempts to control speech. And then she went on to say, we've seen
Speaker 1:  this administration throughout the administration threaten tech companies
Speaker 1:  for their moderation practices to give consumers an environment that they
Speaker 1:  want to, that they wanna stop fact checking. It is an absolute pattern
Speaker 1:  of censorship and control. If we let them do this, it will be the, to the
Speaker 1:  harm of the country. So you have at least one FCC Commissioner
Speaker 1:  saying what we're doing here is wrong, just fully wrong.
Speaker 1:  And it, we're actually doing the thing the FCC was set up to make sure didn't
Speaker 1:  happen, which is censor the speech of Americans. So,
Speaker 1:  good job Anna. If you wanna come under Coda, you're more than welcome to.
Speaker 1:  We've extended that invite. I've got one last one on Brendan. This
Speaker 1:  is maybe the single most predictable.
Speaker 1:  Brendan Carr is a Dummy item in the history of
Speaker 1:  America's favorite podcast. Wow. Within our podcast. It's an increasingly
Speaker 1:  high bar. That one, I mean, I'm just gonna start to say it and you will,
Speaker 1:  you will complete my sentences for me. Okay. This week Brendan put out a
Speaker 1:  blog post announcing the f SEC's next open meeting, which is only go through
Speaker 1:  agenda items. He title that Spectrum Is Back again 'cause he thinks he's
Speaker 1:  your buddy instead of being a vicious internet sensor. And what he's
Speaker 1:  excited about is opening up more spectrum, which is basically the job of
Speaker 1:  the FCC. And they want to open up a satellite spectrum
Speaker 1:  that is currently being used by geostationary satellites. You can guess,
Speaker 1:  you can guess what what's happening here, right? SpaceX filed a petition
Speaker 1:  to open up satellite spectrum that's currently being used by geostationary
Speaker 1:  satellites. And Brendan is taking up so he can open it up without once
Speaker 1:  mentioning the fact that Elon Musk asked for it.
Speaker 1:  Not even a passing mention of this. Just I believe
Speaker 1:  satellite internet for rural Americans would be great. It's like, what? You're
Speaker 1:  not talking about Hughes net dog? Let's get real. You're talking about your
Speaker 1:  buddy Dr. Doge. Not even a mention, it's it's
Speaker 1:  buried in the open meeting notes that they're responding to a petition
Speaker 1:  by SpaceX
Speaker 5:  By saying Yes, of course. Absolutely. Sounds great. Let's do it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah. Cool. That's a good response.
Speaker 1:  You know, he's a huge proponent of SpaceX over fiber. There's a lot of complaints
Speaker 1:  about the Biden era bead program. Our buddy Ezra Klein is like
Speaker 1:  basically selling his book by being like, this program sucked. But the reason
Speaker 1:  the bead program sucked is they took it away From the FCC. I'm not
Speaker 1:  saying it didn't suck. I'm saying that one of the reasons it sucked is 'cause
Speaker 1:  the FCC was so politicized and stupid that it didn't have
Speaker 1:  accurate broadband maps
Speaker 5:  Deliberately
Speaker 1:  So that it could roll out the infrastructure that we were gonna pay for.
Speaker 1:  So they moved it to another agency that had to start the maps over without
Speaker 1:  like Verizon and Comcast getting in the way, which is a real thing that like
Speaker 1:  a Jeep High and Brendan Carr like advocated for back in the day that we're
Speaker 1:  not gonna, we're not gonna demand these accurate maps. So Brendan
Speaker 1:  is like, satellites will fix it. Don't worry about
Speaker 1:  this dumb bead program that didn't give you fiber. And you're like, dude,
Speaker 1:  you don't even know where, where you're going.
Speaker 1:  But anyway, yeah, he's gonna, he's gonna reform the spectrum. And look, maybe,
Speaker 1:  maybe this is the right choice, maybe It is. But the reason that
Speaker 1:  I'm calling it out is when you start with, I'm wearing the gold head of Donald Trump
Speaker 1:  on my lapel, and you end with, I'm doing what Elon Musk wants. You've
Speaker 1:  lost your legitimacy as a regulator. Yeah. You just look corrupt.
Speaker 1:  And that is 'cause you're a dummy Brendan. So again, you know, Anna's welcome
Speaker 1:  Brendan. If you want to come on the show and explain your
Speaker 1:  behavior or even just prove that you can complete a sentence without sucking
Speaker 1:  up to Donald Trump or Elon Musk. I'm, you're welcome. I know you listen,
Speaker 1:  I know you listen. Come on in Brendan, it'll be fine. Water's warm.
Speaker 1:  That's been Brandon Caroni.
Speaker 5:  One more thing about this blog post, which you shouldn't read, it's very
Speaker 5:  boring. But he does the thing that Republican
Speaker 5:  FCC commissioners really like to do, which is mention robocalls.
Speaker 5:  They're like, I'm we're doing, and a Jeep pie did this masterfully. He
Speaker 5:  was like, I'm gonna ruin the internet in the following several ways, but
Speaker 5:  because I am a a, a man of the people, wouldn't it be awesome
Speaker 5:  if we stopped robocalls? And that hasn't worked
Speaker 5:  at all. But then Brendan in, in here is like, we're we're doing, we're giving
Speaker 5:  Elon what he wants. And then he's just like, of course spectrum is not the
Speaker 5:  only area where we're moving fast. We're continuing the fccs longstanding
Speaker 5:  efforts to crack down on illegal robocall. That segue doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 5:  It's just him being
Speaker 1:  Like,
Speaker 5:  Being like, but you hate robocall. Right? Yeah. I'm gonna fix them.
Speaker 1:  By the way, it's 37 gigahertz spectrum, not 36. I apologize.
Speaker 5:  Change
Speaker 1:  Brendan. If you want to wait B Brendan's like ready to tweet how wrong I
Speaker 1:  am. Man loves to tweet. It is by the way, true. A gpi
Speaker 1:  was all about stopping a robocall. It wasn't successful. 'cause he didn't
Speaker 1:  actually regulate anyone. He just incentivized the industry to regulate itself
Speaker 5:  Straight up. Not an exaggeration. I have gotten two robocall since we started
Speaker 5:  recording the podcast.
Speaker 1:  It's very good. Anyway, that is Brendan Carr's dummy America's favorite podcast
Speaker 1:  within a podcast. If you know where he got the pin from, let me know.
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm sort of dying to. All right, David, we need some power.
Speaker 5:  I will make Neli wear the pin on the show I wear. If you get us one, I will
Speaker 5:  make Neli wear Trump. It
Speaker 1:  Is as we're gonna get to Trump or Brendan on the show. Let's be
Speaker 5:  Honest.
Speaker 1:  All right. We need a pallet cleanser, my friend
Speaker 5:  Theme music tk by the way. All let's, can we talk about TikTok for
Speaker 5:  like 35 seconds? That's all I want. That's all I want to do. That's so the,
Speaker 1:  The opposite of a pal cleanser. All
Speaker 5:  Fine. Well then we're gonna get to the pallet cleanser, but we gotta talk
Speaker 5:  about TikTok just for 35 seconds because we, we spent a little bit of time
Speaker 5:  on it last week. Nothing happened. Everybody says
Speaker 5:  it's against the law, nothing is happening. Is that a fair summation of what's
Speaker 5:  going on? Trump deleted another 75 days. Pam
Speaker 5:  Bond, the Attorney General is, is out there essentially demanding that Apple
Speaker 5:  and Google keep the apps alive, which is what they've been doing all along
Speaker 5:  saying We're not gonna enforce this. You have to keep it in the store on
Speaker 5:  and on and on. And then senate democrats are saying
Speaker 5:  it's, it's against the law to do this delay. Which of course is
Speaker 5:  true. All you to do is read the law and you know that that's the case.
Speaker 5:  But I don't imagine any of that changing much of anything.
Speaker 6:  So is a particularly bad situation for Apple and Google. 'cause they just
Speaker 6:  get exposed to another 75 days of liability just hoping that everything works
Speaker 6:  out for them. They're just these like weird pawns trying to hope nobody notices
Speaker 6:  them and they're just gonna have to keep waiting this out because it's maybe
Speaker 6:  never gonna end.
Speaker 1:  But they want tariff relief too.
Speaker 6:  Mm. So they've gotta keep it
Speaker 1:  Like the, the level of just like base corruption here is wild, right? Like
Speaker 1:  everyone has to fly to the golf course and be like, please sir, not
Speaker 1:  104%. And they're all gonna leave with like different numbers and compare
Speaker 1:  them in the parking lot.
Speaker 1:  They cannot take TikTok down because they want the number to be lower than
Speaker 1:  the next guy. It's, it, it, this TikTok is
Speaker 1:  doomed. That's my prediction. It It is the ultimate pawn in this entire
Speaker 1:  situation. China's not gonna wanna sell it and at the end of the day, what
Speaker 1:  they're gonna say is turn it off. Like we don't want 104%.
Speaker 1:  Donald Trump is not gonna keep this promise. We're just turning. Oh,
Speaker 5:  You think China is gonna say turn it off.
Speaker 1:  It's the last bit of leverage. They did it once, right? They wanted to leverage
Speaker 1:  the first time. They just turned it off the last bit of leverage you have.
Speaker 1:  We don't want 104, we want zero tiktoks gone.
Speaker 5:  Trump will blink it, it it, that will work. I think you're right that that
Speaker 5:  is, that is like if you start at, we're not gonna release your movies here
Speaker 5:  anymore. We're like a few escalations up to we're gonna turn off TikTok and
Speaker 5:  that will work. Yeah. In every way that China would need it to. It would
Speaker 5:  work. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And China's not afraid to play these games. China's like, oh, you're the
Speaker 1:  CEO of Alibaba. What if you weren't around for a while?
Speaker 1:  That's just the thing. It is, It is an authoritarian government. It as
Speaker 1:  just a move they play. So we'll see. Alright, now can we have a pallet
Speaker 1:  cleanser?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Pallet cleanser. I have two bits of exciting news for you before we
Speaker 5:  leave. One is that it, it appears to be
Speaker 5:  plausible possible that Instagram is actually going to get an iPad app
Speaker 5:  750 years after the launch of Instagram. Wait,
Speaker 1:  Can I tell you the funniest thing about this story? Yeah. It, it made me
Speaker 1:  laugh so hard. This is also from the information which is doing great work.
Speaker 1:  This, it's in the context of a story that's about Aary and Instagram
Speaker 1:  being ready to be super aggressive if TikTok goes away, right? And there's
Speaker 1:  a long list of something you might do and they're like, it's time to ship
Speaker 1:  that iPad app. And it's like, no, that's not it guys. So like
Speaker 1:  that's not, if TikTok goes away and your answer is also there's an iPad app.
Speaker 1:  Now I, I don't know if that's gonna be it, but I do love it.
Speaker 5:  I don't think that is how you do it. Like TikTok famously also not a
Speaker 5:  great iPad experience, but I think there's a, there's a case
Speaker 5:  to be made for Instagram just attempting to be everywhere as it goes through
Speaker 5:  all of this. Right? And one way to make
Speaker 5:  people happy and get a bunch of headlines is to launch
Speaker 5:  an iPad app. Like I, I think it's not crazy that Meta has been sitting on
Speaker 5:  a finished iPad app for a long time, just sort of waiting for the right moment.
Speaker 5:  I mean
Speaker 6:  There's no way this requires, I'm gonna say like any work on their
Speaker 6:  part, right? Like you like click a couple buttons, it goes boop, it's wider.
Speaker 6:  You've got an iPad app I did. They were just like mad at Apple, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They just don't, that's,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. And I also, I was just talking to
Speaker 5:  our friend Casey Johnston for VERGE Casting that's gonna run in the next
Speaker 5:  couple of weeks and, and one of her theories is that Meta
Speaker 5:  doesn't like iPad apps because they want you to be on your phone because
Speaker 5:  the phone is the more addictive and harder to put down device.
Speaker 5:  Which just strikes me as a good theory. I have no evidence for that theory,
Speaker 5:  but it's a theory that makes sense. But I think there are a lot of people
Speaker 5:  who have iPads and want to look at Instagram on their iPads.
Speaker 5:  And I think if you claim to be a media first thing that is great on
Speaker 5:  screens, iPads kind of make a lot of sense. Seems like a
Speaker 5:  good idea.
Speaker 6:  This also I, I'm curious if this extends to Threads which also does not have
Speaker 6:  an iPad app, which feels like a little embarrassing as
Speaker 6:  well, particularly given that It is in the heat of battle with these other
Speaker 6:  platforms. Instagram is at least like singular in its way.
Speaker 5:  There's also no WhatsApp for iPad. Like Meta has made a, a calculated
Speaker 5:  effort to not do the iPad. And I think
Speaker 5:  it's paid off. It is in part because of this ongoing beef with Apple. But
Speaker 5:  I think there, there may be a moment here where It is so useful
Speaker 5:  to do that, that they'll do it.
Speaker 1:  I mean that's wild. Again, I just think it's very funny to like list of things
Speaker 1:  to do if TikTok goes down and they're like, they move the card on the
Speaker 1:  Kanban board, like
Speaker 1:  from jail to we immediate, you know?
Speaker 1:  All right. What's the next one?
Speaker 5:  The last one is the Pixel nine A, which Allison Johnson just
Speaker 5:  reviewed for us. And It is great. It is, It is the
Speaker 5:  midrange phone you would want it to be. It comes in a cool color. It's
Speaker 5:  like pink that I'm very into that Allison had, and this is like
Speaker 5:  Google continues to make good phones. This phone is still $499. There's been
Speaker 5:  some sketchiness with the, the like release date and all this stuff. But
Speaker 5:  like the price is right at a time when it might not be for long.
Speaker 5:  This is just a really good phone. And this has become the phone I tell
Speaker 5:  most people who are not like tech people, but like
Speaker 5:  Android phones to buy and I feel like this easily continues that in a way
Speaker 5:  that I find very exciting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Google seems to be killing it with this series. And I, I think It is
Speaker 6:  particularly interesting this coming like what a, a month after the
Speaker 6:  iPhone 16 E, which is a hundred dollars more expensive.
Speaker 6:  And I think that Delta and just a couple extra little
Speaker 6:  like, you know, friendly tweaks on the nine A right.
Speaker 6:  The fact that it will do both fingerprint and face authentication, the fact
Speaker 6:  that it has a, a higher refresh rate screen
Speaker 6:  go a long enough way to make it feel like a deal in the way that
Speaker 6:  the 16 E doesn't quite get there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think Google ironically, like the big trade off here
Speaker 5:  that Google made is it does less AI stuff, which is very surprising, right?
Speaker 5:  Trade off for Google to make, but also a really good one. It has all the
Speaker 5:  other stuff you'd want your phone to have. It just doesn't do quite as much
Speaker 5:  of the AI stuff. And spoiler alert, most people are pretty
Speaker 5:  willing to make that trade. It turns out.
Speaker 1:  All right. I just wanna end the episode by pointing out that in the time
Speaker 1:  that we've been talking, oh no, the tariff on China has risen to
Speaker 1:  145%,
Speaker 5:  1 45.
Speaker 1:  The, the, the, the White House has clarified the, the tariff China It
Speaker 1:  is now 1 45.
Speaker 5:  You know what's, you know what's manly Eli? A thousand percent real men
Speaker 5:  do a thousand.
Speaker 1:  I'm just saying it's a very loud V eight engine. My friends Wait,
Speaker 5:  Can I ask one more question about phones before we go? This is the thing
Speaker 5:  I've been thinking about. Yeah. And I'm curious what you guys think. I think
Speaker 5:  my sort of ongoing thesis for a while now has been that phones are
Speaker 5:  not actually that price sensitive anymore. That, you know, you get the
Speaker 5:  trade-ins, you get the, the financing that like actually the, the sort of
Speaker 5:  a hundred dollars delta between one phone or another is not that meaningful.
Speaker 5:  But I wonder in, in a tariff sea world where people are more price
Speaker 5:  conscious about everything. Like are we as people who
Speaker 5:  write about these things going to have to care about price in general
Speaker 5:  more than we have in the past?
Speaker 1:  It's interesting 'cause we run a reviews program and so much of a reviews
Speaker 1:  program is like, is it worth the money? And so I wanna say the answer is
Speaker 1:  yes 'cause that just changes the heart of the thing that we
Speaker 1:  do. But I I also think what's gonna happen is like
Speaker 1:  there's gonna be more bloatware on the phones. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 1:  Like I, people are price sensitive especially right now. And I you're just,
Speaker 1:  I think you're just gonna be like, you open your Pixel line a
Speaker 1:  and Google is like, do you want three free months of max? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right. Like it's just that thing is going to start happening in extremely
Speaker 1:  weird ways or they're gonna lower the base storage and be like, do you want
Speaker 1:  Google one? Like, you know, like I, there's something shittier that's
Speaker 1:  coming that like will keep the price the same. I'm not sure what
Speaker 1:  it will be, but I, it it feels like they're not gonna up they
Speaker 1:  price. Right. Because that's a drastic measure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It is easier to sneakily make the phone worse than to
Speaker 5:  sneakily make it more expensive. That's definitely
Speaker 1:  True. Yeah. Like if you're any one of these big, if you're Apple or Google,
Speaker 1:  you can go to one of the big carriers and be like, here's what we need to
Speaker 1:  do. We need to adjust the terms of our revenue sharing. And so
Speaker 1:  the phone contract lengths will be six months longer or
Speaker 1:  add on a, a provider service upcharge fee
Speaker 1:  that's labeled like the Cook doctrine. Like what? It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1:  Like, you know, like there's just other places to sneak the money in that
Speaker 1:  isn't the selling price because of the way we've structured all of these
Speaker 1:  things.
Speaker 5:  I think I buy that it feels like, it feels like bad news. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  I think that, I think that is where this goes. Like we're gonna see Chris
Speaker 5:  Mims, my old colleague at the Wall Street Journal was tweeting about like,
Speaker 5:  the, the thing people don't realize is not that a lot of stuff is gonna get
Speaker 5:  more expensive, it's that a lot of stuff is gonna go away. And I think
Speaker 5:  that and the sort of in ification of things ahead of their
Speaker 5:  time are, are two sort of non-obvious things to look out for here.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. By the way, the 145, they clarified it's because of fentanyl,
Speaker 1:  which is one of those things. It is not a crisis coming from China.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What's the trade deficit on Fentanyl? Figure that out.
Speaker 1:  It's very confusing. Like there's, there's a hole in the heart
Speaker 1:  of this whole argument that's like, oh the but your emergency's fake. So
Speaker 1:  we'll see by the time you listen to this, the number could have gone up or
Speaker 1:  down. Who knows?
Speaker 5:  Tell us, email us and tell us what the number is right now as you're hearing
Speaker 5:  this. I desperately want to know.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Alright. We gotta get outta here. That is The Vergecast Rock.
Speaker 16:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 16:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 16:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Box Media Podcast network.
Speaker 16:  Our show's produced by Will Pour Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer.
Speaker 16:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.