# Transcript
ID: 181ba72e-1316-4527-8dd4-2ec9b2ed0bf6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7093785205250148540/1554020584729146536/s93290-US-5493s-1737457849.mp3
Description: First in this episode, a quick update on the TikTok ban (which didn't turn out to be much of a ban at all.) Then, Sportico's Jacob Feldman joins the show to talk about Venu, the much-hyped streaming service that planned to bring all sports into a single platform — and never even managed to launch. After that, The Verge's Kevin Nguyen tells us how to read more books this year, and how to turn all your aimless scrolling time into more productive reading time. Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline about audio sources on your phone, and why you can't listen to a thousand things at once.
Speaker 1:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Qualified
Speaker 1:  Divestiture. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and it has been a wild
Speaker 1:  weekend here in the United States. We kept a
Speaker 1:  lot of this episode sort of fluid until the very last minute, wanting to
Speaker 1:  see what happened with the TikTok ban and with President Trump's
Speaker 1:  inauguration. There's just a lot going on kind of minute to minute right
Speaker 1:  now. We've covered a lot of this in the run up to it, but a lot happened
Speaker 1:  kind of in the span of 36 hours
Speaker 1:  or, or, or did anything happen in the course of 36 hours?
Speaker 1:  So let me just level set where we are with TikTok kind of right this minute.
Speaker 1:  TikTok went into essentially darkness on
Speaker 1:  Saturday night into Sunday when the ban took effect. That didn't have to
Speaker 1:  happen. The, the rules around banning TikTok didn't necessarily mean that
Speaker 1:  TikTok had to just shut off in the US at midnight on Saturday
Speaker 1:  night, but that's what TikTok did. Pretty performatively I
Speaker 1:  would say. The company put up a message basically saying, we think President
Speaker 1:  Trump is going to save us. It it, it's all just kind of naked
Speaker 1:  political maneuvering, like, let's just call this what it is that is pure
Speaker 1:  politicking. But anyway, TikTok gone for a little while
Speaker 1:  and then came back in a certain way. It's actually still
Speaker 1:  not available, at least as I'm checking right now, midday Monday
Speaker 1:  on either the Google Play Store or the Apple App Store, but,
Speaker 1:  but you can go to TikTok dot com and watch TikTok isn. Essentially what it
Speaker 1:  appears we've seen is Oracle and Akamai, which are two of the
Speaker 1:  companies that host TikTok in the United States, basically
Speaker 1:  seem to believe that whatever President Trump is going to do, it's not going
Speaker 1:  to come back on them negatively. It's a risk to keep TikTok live right now
Speaker 1:  because TikTok is technically banned in the United States, and any company
Speaker 1:  that hosts it or hosts it on its app store can be fined.
Speaker 1:  Trump has said he is not going to do that. It's still a risk, but the hosts
Speaker 1:  seem to believe it's gonna be okay. The app store's TBD,
Speaker 1:  meanwhile Blue Sky launched a video thing that looks a lot like
Speaker 1:  TikTok. The X launched a video thing that looks a lot like TikTok, Adam
Speaker 1:  Ariat Instagram said the edit app that the company has been working on for
Speaker 1:  a while, which is essentially just a rip off of TikTok, isn CapCut editing
Speaker 1:  app is coming soon. So all at once, there is this question of
Speaker 1:  is TikTok going to continue to be around? The answer
Speaker 1:  seems to be yes in some way. Trump said it a
Speaker 1:  rally on Sunday, right before he was inaugurated, that he has a big plan
Speaker 1:  to save TikTok. That involves making it a joint venture with the United States
Speaker 1:  government, which doesn't make a lot of sense and doesn't have anything to
Speaker 1:  do with the law that has been passed.
Speaker 1:  We are in unprecedented political times, especially as it pertains
Speaker 1:  to the tech industry. So I frankly could
Speaker 1:  not handicap the likelihood of any of this happening or not happening or
Speaker 1:  how it might go down. But what I will say is that a lot happened
Speaker 1:  and also not that much happened. We had a a lot of backing and forthing,
Speaker 1:  a lot of feelings. I think it's gonna be really interesting to see if even
Speaker 1:  like 12 hours of TikTok being turned off changes the way
Speaker 1:  that people perceive the platform even now as Trump continues to promise
Speaker 1:  to bring it back, and he really wants that as a political victory. The Biden
Speaker 1:  administration just like walked away. It's all very weird, and I could talk
Speaker 1:  about the machinations here forever, but I kind of don't want to, and I think
Speaker 1:  right now, again, as I'm recording this, we are in the middle of Donald Trump's
Speaker 1:  inauguration speech. He's officially, once again the president of the United States.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of stuff to come in the next few days. Trump has said to
Speaker 1:  donors that he's planning to sign as many as a hundred executive orders like
Speaker 1:  today, Monday, and that there's going to be more to come with
Speaker 1:  TikTok very quickly. So I think what we're gonna do, just to bring this all
Speaker 1:  the way back around to The Vergecast, is we're gonna talk a lot about all
Speaker 1:  of that on Friday. I promise we're not gonna spend this whole year
Speaker 1:  talking about politics, but this moment, a lot of this stuff
Speaker 1:  is coming to a head, and I think this moment matters and is going to set
Speaker 1:  up a lot of what's gonna happen for the next four years. I mean, mark
Speaker 1:  Zuckerberg and Jeff Bezos, and Sundar Phai and Shuchu, the CEO
Speaker 1:  of TikTok, isn, Tim Cook, and others are all at the
Speaker 1:  inauguration, Joe Rogan. I saw a picture of him in church with Trump this
Speaker 1:  morning. Like this connection between Washington and Silicon
Speaker 1:  Valley is closer and different than anything we've
Speaker 1:  experienced. And it is going to change a lot of things, but I don't think
Speaker 1:  we know what they are yet. And so we're just gonna try to kind of take it
Speaker 1:  as it comes rather than having a lot of insane ideas
Speaker 1:  about what might happen when I don't really think anything
Speaker 1:  we've seen before tells us what's coming next.
Speaker 1:  So here on The Vergecast today, we are going to stop talking about all of
Speaker 1:  that, and we're gonna do two different things. We first, we're gonna talk
Speaker 1:  to Jacob Feldman From Sportico about Venu Sports, which
Speaker 1:  was supposed to be this like future of sports streaming app that died
Speaker 1:  before it ever even launched it. It went 90 on the go, 90 scale
Speaker 1:  at maybe record time, like maybe we need to rename the Go 90 Scale,
Speaker 1:  the venue scale. That's the thing we're gonna have to talk about. But he's
Speaker 1:  gonna come on and he's gonna tell us the story and explain what happened,
Speaker 1:  and just sort of lead us through what this means for streaming for sports,
Speaker 1:  and for the Go 90 scale. After that, we're gonna talk to Kevin Nguyen
Speaker 1:  about reading. So I'm gonna do two things over the next
Speaker 1:  two weeks, kind of about New Year's resolutions and the two that I hear from
Speaker 1:  people over and over again. People wanna stop scrolling and start reading
Speaker 1:  like books and articles and like deep reading instead of just kind of aimlessly
Speaker 1:  scrolling, Reddit and TikTok or whatever. So we're gonna talk to Kevin about
Speaker 1:  how he does that. Kevin reads more and better and more carefully than anybody
Speaker 1:  I know and has also thought deeply about how to be good at that in a digital
Speaker 1:  world. So we're gonna just try and see if we can learn anything from how
Speaker 1:  Kevin gets all of this stuff done. We also have a hotline, lots to
Speaker 1:  get to. This is a very fun episode, and we are done talking about politics,
Speaker 1:  at least for today. We're gonna come, come back and try to make sense of
Speaker 1:  all of this on Friday's show because I think with a few days of settling
Speaker 1:  and a few days of the Trump presidency, we're gonna have a better sense of
Speaker 1:  where we really are. So we're gonna come back to that for now. We got
Speaker 1:  other stuff to do. All that is coming up in just a second, But first we gotta
Speaker 1:  take a break because I've been talking for too long and now I
Speaker 1:  need to go not think about politics for a while. This is The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 1:  be right back.
Speaker 3:  toyota.com/toyota Crown Family Toyota.
Speaker 5:  Visit schwab.com to learn more.
Speaker 1:  All right, so the other thing that happened this weekend was that it was
Speaker 1:  a pretty good sports weekend. There was a lot of good football. It's the
Speaker 1:  college football National Championship. It's the NFL playoffs.
Speaker 1:  Basketball is kind of coming into full form, like it's a, this is a fun part
Speaker 1:  of the sports calendar, but it's a crappy time to be a
Speaker 1:  sports fan in a lot of ways because watching those games seems to get more
Speaker 1:  complicated and more expensive all the time. But there was supposed
Speaker 1:  to be a better way coming already. It was gonna be called Venu
Speaker 1:  Sports, and it was going to be the one place you needed to be
Speaker 1:  to watch all of your sports in one place. It was gonna be pretty expensive,
Speaker 1:  but it was gonna solve a certain set of problems, I think.
Speaker 1:  And then it died before it ever lived. So I wanna
Speaker 1:  understand what happened here. So I called up Jacob Feldman, who's a reporter
Speaker 1:  at Sportico, who has been covering this whole saga from beginning
Speaker 1:  to end, which is both a lot of work and a very small amount of time
Speaker 1:  because boy, boy did venue come and go really fast.
Speaker 1:  So Jacob is gonna take us through what happened, what we can learn, and
Speaker 1:  what 2025 might hold for sports fans. Let's get into it.
Speaker 1:  Jacob Feldman, welcome To The Vergecast. Let's just start at the beginning
Speaker 1:  of the venue story. The story is both really complicated and not very long,
Speaker 1:  so we're gonna try to kind of tell the whole thing here. So go all the way
Speaker 1:  back to the beginning and tell me kind of where venue came from.
Speaker 7:  Sure. Venue came out of nowhere, I think as a, as a good place to start here.
Speaker 7:  Last February, almost exactly a year ago.
Speaker 7:  It, it was I think an afternoon press release from Warner Brothers,
Speaker 7:  discovery Fox and, and Disney that they were creating this joint venture.
Speaker 7:  We can talk about what that means to launch the service. Didn't have a name,
Speaker 7:  didn't have a CEO, didn't have a price, never had a price. We'll get to that
Speaker 7:  and everyone was kind of wondering what this is
Speaker 7:  and, and we got a little bit of detail on a Fox earnings call, but it was
Speaker 7:  a lot of questions, you know, within the industry of, of, obviously there's
Speaker 7:  huge companies coming together to create some sort of sports service. And,
Speaker 7:  and again, it started with a lot of questions, if I
Speaker 1:  Remember right. The only thing we kind of knew from that
Speaker 1:  first release was like, this is a thing that is going to have a lot of sports.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  Right. I think it was, it was really, it was that vague that it was just
Speaker 1:  like, this is, we knew the three companies and we knew that they have a lot
Speaker 1:  of sports, and that was, that was kind of it.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Right. And, and ev obviously everybody knew that sports
Speaker 7:  and the way we watch sports is changing and these companies are figuring
Speaker 7:  out, they're constantly having these carriage battles. They're constantly
Speaker 7:  debating moving to streaming or not moving to streaming. Every company's
Speaker 7:  a little bit different and this was maybe gonna solve some of those problems
Speaker 7:  and not others. And maybe each company had slightly different priorities.
Speaker 7:  I think that all contributed to the vagueness of it. And we got some answers
Speaker 7:  over time. Some, again, questions maybe We'll, we'll, we'll never completely
Speaker 7:  know.
Speaker 1:  So put yourself in the, the shoes of, of these three companies. And
Speaker 1:  let's see, it was, it was Warner Brothers, discovery, ESPN and Fox,
Speaker 1:  right? Were the three Disney, espn. Yeah. Yeah. Disney,
Speaker 7:  Espn. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  What do, what do you think, like, rewind six months before that, what do
Speaker 1:  you think these companies saw in each other that was like, this is a thing
Speaker 1:  we can do that'll work.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think they each saw something slightly different. I think Fox the
Speaker 7:  simplest one to start with here, because Fox does not have a streaming service.
Speaker 7:  They have, they have Tubi, I think. So it, you know, it's a free service.
Speaker 7:  They don't put their live sports there, right? And So I think they were
Speaker 7:  looking for a way to reach fans who don't have cable, who
Speaker 7:  don't have even antennas in, in some cases.
Speaker 7:  And, and so looking for a streaming service streaming partner, I think that's
Speaker 7:  what, what brought them to the table. Then you go to Warner Brothers Discovery,
Speaker 7:  you guys talk a lot about them a lot on the show. David Zla is always, we're
Speaker 1:  Big fans here on the first cast. Huge
Speaker 7:  Fans. Yeah. For some reason. And he's always
Speaker 7:  clearly looking for ways to continue to monetize to, to, to make balance
Speaker 7:  the balance sheet, to look for ways to make money off the rights they have
Speaker 7:  and potentially continue to, to gain rights. Obviously, at the time, again,
Speaker 7:  going back a year, they still had BA rights and were still negotiating
Speaker 7:  for BA rights. We can talk about how that played out. And, and So I think
Speaker 7:  they saw, oh, another service, another place where we can reach fans, a slightly
Speaker 7:  different price point, ideally we're in. And
Speaker 7:  then you get to ESPN Disney, which is the most complicated, we'll probably
Speaker 7:  spend the most time talking about what they're doing and why.
Speaker 7:  And for me, I think what probably brought them to
Speaker 7:  do this deal is they're at this crucial moment for E-S-P-N-E-S-P-N
Speaker 7:  long, the dominant sports broadcaster in America is
Speaker 7:  reaching, is still the dominant sports broadcaster in America, but slightly
Speaker 7:  less so, a lot more doubt and uncertainty about what its future looks like,
Speaker 7:  how people are going to watch. And as we enter 2025, I think what
Speaker 7:  we're seeing is that they're gonna try to a lot of different things over
Speaker 7:  these next years, these next couple years. How much do you wanna pay? You
Speaker 7:  wanna spend five bucks, 50 bucks, $500? We'll have an ESPN package for you.
Speaker 7:  We see tech companies do this all the time. Right? And, and So I think they're
Speaker 7:  trying to figure out exactly what that looks like, the ability to partner
Speaker 7:  with these other companies, try something a little different, I think. Said,
Speaker 7:  yeah, we'll, we'll, we'll sign up for this and see where it goes.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So knowing what you know now, this was not going to
Speaker 1:  work. Spoiler alert didn't work. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Did you think this idea made sense when it first happened? Like just to lay
Speaker 1:  my own cards on the table, I thought this was gonna work. There, there were,
Speaker 1:  there were problems that we should talk about,
Speaker 1:  but this as a, as a theory of the case about like, here is
Speaker 1:  what sports fans want and might be willing to pay for this tracked for me.
Speaker 1:  Did it track for you?
Speaker 7:  Interesting. I thought this was gonna work on a much smaller scale than I
Speaker 7:  think some people either anticipated or feared. Okay. I think,
Speaker 7:  again, once it became slightly clear what this product was, which was gonna
Speaker 7:  be a monthly streaming service, roughly 30 to
Speaker 7:  $50 a month to start, probably going up After that. And
Speaker 7:  including, like you said, all the sports channels from these three companies,
Speaker 7:  which is a lot of sports channels. I think depending on how you do the math,
Speaker 7:  it's like more than half of of the major sports would be available here.
Speaker 7:  So again, what you're getting is most sports for slightly less than you would
Speaker 7:  pay for cable. And in my mind you're,
Speaker 1:  When you put it like that, that's not very compelling. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  In, in my mind, the audience is either somebody who needs all the sports
Speaker 7:  and is willing to spend 80 to a hundred dollars a month, or somebody who
Speaker 7:  needs only some of the sports and wants to spend 10 to $20 a month. So again,
Speaker 7:  this kind of middle product, I think probably would've maybe gotten a couple
Speaker 7:  million subscribers, something like that. Obviously very seasonal when you
Speaker 7:  talk about the college football audience, maybe they're signing up to, to
Speaker 7:  watch their teams in September, October until their teams four and six and
Speaker 7:  they're, they're churning out. And, and so it would've been, it would've
Speaker 7:  been marginal. And, and that's what always I I I'm curious kind of what your
Speaker 7:  reaction was, because to me, I was, I'm, I still am kind of surprised at
Speaker 7:  how much interest there was in the venue story, given that kind of middle
Speaker 7:  of the road nature.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think to me it's, it's, it pokes
Speaker 1:  at the right thing, right? Which is that watching sports, there's a problem
Speaker 1:  here, right? Watching sports is, is a disaster. Yes. Like it has never been
Speaker 1:  worse or more complicated or, or frankly, more expensive Yes.
Speaker 1:  To watch all the sports you wanna watch. I think like if, If you want,
Speaker 1:  even If you want the NFL, right? Like if, if I wanna watch all the football
Speaker 1:  games, that's like four services that I have to pay for.
Speaker 7:  At the beginning of the year, I calculated spent $800 to watch every NFL
Speaker 7:  game this year.
Speaker 1:  That's nuts. Yeah. Like that is bad. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 1:  for, for all of the stuff that we're going through in this like unbundling
Speaker 1:  and rebundling thing, like, we're just doing cable again. Right? And So I
Speaker 1:  think the idea that we could do cable again,
Speaker 1:  but mostly for sports, would've worked for me. And obviously I
Speaker 1:  think like the, the main limitation is what you're saying, like, it, it had
Speaker 1:  something like half the sports, right? It didn't have any of the things that
Speaker 1:  Comcast had, which turns out to be a lot of things that a lot of people care
Speaker 1:  about, like the Olympics, it didn't have some of the football, because Amazon
Speaker 1:  had football and Netflix had football
Speaker 7:  And CBS as well. Yes. Right?
Speaker 1:  And CBS was pro, CBS was probably the biggest single holdout. It
Speaker 1:  had college basketball, it has more football, all this stuff. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 1:  So I it like, if, If you could have put
Speaker 1:  together all of the things, this thing makes sense. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I think people would pay slightly less than cable for all of the sports,
Speaker 1:  right. I think there's an actual market for that. But
Speaker 1:  the more it became clear that it was half the sports for slightly less than
Speaker 1:  the price of cable, it, it kind of started to fall apart. But I still think
Speaker 1:  there is something you could do with sports
Speaker 1:  If you do more than just the games. That could be
Speaker 1:  interesting. And, and, and this is where we're gonna go back to ES, espn,
Speaker 1:  which is trying to very much be that thing that we should talk about. Right.
Speaker 1:  But that was the case, at least in my head, is like, I can see the, the glimmer
Speaker 1:  of something here.
Speaker 7:  Right. And, and I think one of the questions right away, going back to when
Speaker 7:  this launch was, all right, who's in this, you know, it's Fox, Disney, Warner
Speaker 7:  Brothers adding up all those channels, and then who's not in this? You know,
Speaker 7:  you have your NBC, you have your CBS, you have your regional sports networks,
Speaker 7:  which which we can talk about too. And, and yeah, I think I, I
Speaker 7:  totally agree that the excitement was based on the recognition that there
Speaker 7:  is a problem here and maybe this will solve it even though the past a hundred
Speaker 7:  attempts to solve it have not worked. Maybe this is the one, but yeah, even
Speaker 7:  I could do the math and say, okay, this is $45 and then, what is it, $7 for
Speaker 7:  peacock and then $6 for Paramount to get the CBS and then 15 for
Speaker 7:  Amazon. I'm already paying that anyway. And so maybe I can bundle this together
Speaker 7:  and save 15 bucks a month, which would be great. I'll, I'll do it. Which
Speaker 7:  then we get to the fragmentation every year. People in the sports world now
Speaker 7:  celebrate this thing called the Sports Equinox, which is one of the nerdier
Speaker 7:  things that we do in the sports world where we don't, you know, all hold
Speaker 7:  hands and, and go full mid, some are, but on one Monday in October,
Speaker 7:  all four of the major men's American team sports are playing. And,
Speaker 7:  and so that was a good occasion. I I think this October, those games plus
Speaker 7:  some golf were spread across 39 channels and services.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God. Yeah. So this is why I actually think the, the
Speaker 1:  part of the reason for the excitement behind venue was less about the
Speaker 1:  reality of what venue could even possibly be, and more just the
Speaker 1:  recognition that thank God somebody
Speaker 7:  Right
Speaker 1:  In charge understands that this sucks. Excuse me.
Speaker 7:  Yes. And flipping the remote and signing in a million times. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 1:  And I think what we've learned is that the, the leagues, which in theory
Speaker 1:  have the most weight to make some of these changes.
Speaker 1:  Like if the NFL just wanted to sell all of its rights to one player, and
Speaker 1:  everybody would be happy it could do that, it's never gonna do that because
Speaker 1:  there's more money in selling it to more and more people all the time. That's
Speaker 1:  how Netflix gets games on Christmas, right? Yep. Like, th that is where we're
Speaker 1:  headed. And so our only hope as fans, it seems,
Speaker 1:  is for somebody on the other end to figure it out for us. And
Speaker 1:  as somebody who just doesn't wanna admit that it's impossible, and it might
Speaker 1:  just be impossible, there was something about venue that it was like, okay,
Speaker 1:  at least, at least this is somebody with some power pushing back in the right
Speaker 1:  direction of this.
Speaker 7:  Is this where we can introduce the Fuo character?
Speaker 1:  This is where, where we bring in Fuo, because Fuo said, no thank you.
Speaker 7:  Well, a little background on Fuo and I know you, you've covered it and, and
Speaker 7:  written about them too. So they started, they turned 10 this month, and they
Speaker 7:  started in January, 2015 with the same problem
Speaker 7:  in mind, watching sports online sucks, how do we make
Speaker 7:  it better? And for nine
Speaker 7:  and years and 11 months, that was more branding than product, right?
Speaker 7:  Because their service ended up looking very similar to every other service
Speaker 7:  that's out there. It's a hundred channels for a hundred bucks, more or less.
Speaker 1:  They just had some like clever UI stuff around sports, which was fine and
Speaker 1:  good, but Yeah. But yeah, it was, they were essentially, they were more like
Speaker 1:  a YouTube TV competitor than a Exactly. ESPN competitor. Exactly.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So this announcement comes out, we're talking about our reaction to,
Speaker 7:  to this news. This was their reaction. Wait, what we've been trying to do
Speaker 7:  this, we've been trying to get your sports rights to offer a sports specific
Speaker 7:  package to fans for literally 10 years. And now you guys are gonna
Speaker 7:  team up and do this yourselves and compete against us.
Speaker 7:  Absolutely not. That's so within, it was two weeks, within two weeks. So
Speaker 7:  their, their lawyers were quick. The announcement was February 6th of last
Speaker 7:  year, the lawsuit February 20th. Wow. And that was basically
Speaker 7:  the beginning of the end of Venu Sports.
Speaker 1:  What describe Fu Bo's case? Just sort of that at a, at a broad level.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So I think there's mainly two issues,
Speaker 7:  both legally and in the court of public opinion that they raised. The first
Speaker 7:  is, is obviously this cartel question of aren't these competitors, they bid
Speaker 7:  against each other for rights. They theoretically have to
Speaker 7:  keep costs down because cable companies could theoretically only offer one
Speaker 7:  or the other. Again, that doesn't really happen. But in theory, these, these
Speaker 7:  companies should be competing against each other. Why are they now teaming
Speaker 7:  up? So that, that's one. And then two is
Speaker 7:  they never let us do this. You know, we wanted to offer a quote unquote
Speaker 7:  skinny bundle, which I dunno if we need to define or if we will get to in
Speaker 7:  a minute. Yeah. But this idea of only offering a sports package is something
Speaker 7:  we wanted to do. They always said it's impossible. Now they're allowing themselves
Speaker 7:  to do it. They're kinda self-dealing in that regard. They're not allowing
Speaker 7:  us to do it. So those were the two main arguments that, that FUBU made.
Speaker 1:  And pretty immediately it seemed that people who were paying attention
Speaker 1:  thought this was a very good case that FUBU had. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's interesting. I honestly, again, maybe this is because I know of the
Speaker 7:  Fuo backstory, kind of saw this a little bit of sour grapes at the beginning
Speaker 7:  Hmm. Of like, oh, here's some competitor that's being run over by the bigger
Speaker 7:  companies who's hoping court will save them. I, we've seen that story a million
Speaker 7:  times. It usually doesn't, it usually doesn't turn out well for the little
Speaker 7:  guy. True. And so maybe, you know, this is, this is a good underdog story
Speaker 7:  in sports in some ways. But so, So I, I do think initially, again, I don't
Speaker 7:  have a legal background. That was kind of my first read on this. Whenever
Speaker 7:  I kind of see a lawsuit against a new thing coming out, it's just somebody
Speaker 7:  trying to slow down a competitor. But yeah, I, I think as you mentioned,
Speaker 7:  as soon as we started to hear hearings, as soon as there were experts and,
Speaker 7:  and, and legal witnesses kind of weighing in here,
Speaker 7:  there did start to be some sense. And I, I think this even was true of
Speaker 7:  the venue operators at first, they were like, oh, you know, this is something
Speaker 7:  we're gonna overcome. We're still planning to launch six months after the
Speaker 7:  announcement. And then as that launch got closer and closer and the courts,
Speaker 7:  you know, denied motion after motion to dismiss, then I think
Speaker 7:  eventually, and, and maybe it took even longer than that, they woke up to,
Speaker 7:  okay, maybe this is an, an actual problem.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Do you think what happened essentially is, is
Speaker 1:  somebody at venue or at one of these companies basically looked around and
Speaker 1:  was like, why aren't we fighting this fight anymore? Like, is this, yes,
Speaker 1:  we're going to, we're going to potentially put ourselves through this incredible
Speaker 1:  legal ringer just to launch a thing that a lot of people are skeptical is
Speaker 1:  going to work at all. And then just like shook hands and walked away. Like,
Speaker 1:  do you think that's basically where they landed?
Speaker 7:  I think that's basically where they landed. I think ESPN,
Speaker 7:  again, the biggest player here when it comes to sports rights is launching
Speaker 7:  their own service this year. And so it was always a little confusing that
Speaker 7:  they were gonna launch this venue product last year. And then their own direct
Speaker 7:  consumer service, right. Again, does not yet have a name. They like to take
Speaker 7:  their time with these things. Evidently they're
Speaker 1:  Calling it flagship, which I feel like they're gonna launch it.
Speaker 7:  I wanted, I wanted to mention this. They kind of stole that from you. No,
Speaker 7:  it, it is The Verge kind of They did that is gonna
Speaker 1:  Bring a lawsuit and we will be the flagship podcast of sports entertainment.
Speaker 1:  Okay. For as long as it is necessary to be, don't worry.
Speaker 7:  Good, good. Yeah. They're, they're calling it flagship internally. Can
Speaker 7:  I give you my pitch for the name? I don't know. We can get that to that,
Speaker 7:  the end. Oh
Speaker 1:  No, I'm ready. Hit
Speaker 7:  Me. Okay. You've heard of ESPN two, ESPN three. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I think this should be called ESPN one, so it's all in one. Ooh, no, I don't
Speaker 7:  think it's been used before. You obviously have Apple One. I think there's
Speaker 7:  some familiarity with, with the concept of one first. Oh,
Speaker 1:  I actually really like that. Do you spell it out or do you do the number
Speaker 7:  Spell it out? I think, I think that's classier.
Speaker 1:  I think so too. And you do it in the font. So it's just E-S-P-N-O-N-E-I kind
Speaker 1:  of like that. Mm,
Speaker 7:  Yep. Some like win one play, you know, for, for the marketing. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  I, I'm putting that down now so that I can sue if if they do go
Speaker 1:  With Yeah. Tm, tm, tm. This
Speaker 7:  Is
Speaker 1:  T Bones this. That's very good. Yeah. Okay. So ESPN has been
Speaker 1:  saying forever that it's gonna launch this thing. I wanna get
Speaker 1:  in a minute into what that thing is because it's, it is also sort of slightly
Speaker 1:  amorphous. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  'cause some people are like, oh, wait, doesn't ESPN have a streaming service?
Speaker 7:  It's called ESPN Plus, which they do, but they do. But it offers
Speaker 7:  a very small slice of what you get otherwise.
Speaker 1:  Right, right. And so, yeah. So let's, let's come back to that in just one
Speaker 1:  second, because I think the, the, what is the landscape for sports fans
Speaker 1:  now, I think starts with ESPN. So let's come back to that. Okay. But,
Speaker 1:  but yeah. So if you're ESPN and you're, you're Disney, or even
Speaker 1:  if you're David Zaslav and, and Warner Discovery, and you're really
Speaker 1:  focused on Max and trying to grow that stuff, yeah. It sort of makes sense
Speaker 1:  that you would look at this and be like, this is way more hassle than it's
Speaker 1:  worth. Let's just, let's just pull the plug.
Speaker 7:  Right. Absolutely. Yeah. Absolutely. Yeah. And so, yeah, max, as you mentioned,
Speaker 7:  they launched a sports tier, I believe last fall, which was free for a long
Speaker 7:  time. I think it now costs extra. I'm not entirely sure.
Speaker 1:  I can't say I've watched a ton of Bleacher Report on Max, if I'm being honest
Speaker 1:  with
Speaker 7:  You. Okay. I, yeah, I have, I I, I think, I dunno if I'm the only one, but
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And again, this kind of brings us back to Fox, which has the Super
Speaker 7:  Bowl in two or three weeks. Right. I think they would've loved to have had
Speaker 7:  a streaming service that you signed up for tied to the Super Bowl. They would've
Speaker 7:  loved to lock you in for a year to watch Super Bowl. And they're, they're
Speaker 7:  kind of back to the one that doesn't have a sports
Speaker 7:  streaming service. And, and we'll see what their next move is here. But yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think especially when you're looking at Warner and you're looking at Disney,
Speaker 7:  they got a lot of other things going on. Let's just, let's just move this
Speaker 7:  aside and, and so fubu, we can kind of move
Speaker 7:  this in whenever you want, but FUBU signed an agreement with those three
Speaker 7:  companies to drop its lawsuit earlier this month. And for, I would say for
Speaker 7:  24 to 36 hours, the venue hype was back on. Everyone's like, okay, this is
Speaker 7:  happening. We were hearing on background that venue was gonna launch. It
Speaker 7:  was maybe gonna launch from March Madness with the NBA playoffs. And then
Speaker 7:  36 hours later, again it went, it went out the way
Speaker 7:  it came in with a press release from the three companies saying actually
Speaker 7:  we're good venue is no more.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, there's one other thing that happened to Fuo that I think is
Speaker 1:  interesting. Yes. Which is that they made this deal with Disney. Can you
Speaker 1:  explain what's going on there?
Speaker 7:  I can try. Yeah. So as part of this multifaceted
Speaker 7:  agreements to, that included dropping the venue lawsuit and included
Speaker 7:  a payment of more than $200 million to FUBU as part of the
Speaker 7:  legal settlement. It also included a multifaceted
Speaker 7:  merger between Disney and FUBU that will see what I'm calling New
Speaker 7:  fubu, but other people are calling Ulu
Speaker 7:  is that Fuo will take over control of Hulu
Speaker 7:  plus live tv, which is another service we have not discussed at all,
Speaker 7:  but has been around for quite some time. And that again, is more of a YouTube
Speaker 7:  TV competitor. It's hundred channels for a hundred dollars more or less.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 1:  Like the second fiddle to YouTube tv. Right, exactly. YouTube TV is kind
Speaker 1:  of winning the cable replacement wars and Hulu with live TV is in second
Speaker 1:  place.
Speaker 7:  Very importantly, it is the second fiddle. And so last year, I don't know
Speaker 7:  If you felt this way, I felt like YouTube TV had won this race,
Speaker 7:  whatever this race was for virtual cable, YouTube TV won it. There was, you
Speaker 7:  know, a, a PlayStation view moment. There was a sling moment. I don't know
Speaker 7:  if DirecTV Stream ever had a moment, but it has always been there. Yep. But
Speaker 7:  by last year, YouTube TV had Sunday ticket. Very importantly, it
Speaker 7:  had very good ease of use. And it was YouTube,
Speaker 7:  everyone knew it, trusted it, whatever. Yeah. And So I, I think
Speaker 7:  Disney saw that and said, that's not good. If the future
Speaker 7:  in five years is there's only one company distributing cable
Speaker 7:  over the internet or at all, and it's Google, suddenly we're negotiating
Speaker 7:  with them and and they could cut us off. We need a better competitor.
Speaker 7:  And we have this Hulu thing here, which they has always kind of been off
Speaker 7:  to the side in the Disney streaming universe. Yeah. The live TV product
Speaker 7:  and, and the Hulu plus live tv. There's actually a space between
Speaker 7:  Hulu and plus, unlike ESPN or Disney Plus, which don't have a space, it never
Speaker 7:  made any sense. No. So this is a kind of a chance to fresh start.
Speaker 7:  Fubu, why don't you run this? We'll take 70% of this new Fuo company
Speaker 7:  and why don't you try to compete with YouTube tv? And importantly, probably
Speaker 7:  most importantly for fubu, we're gonna let you launch that thing you've wanted
Speaker 7:  to launch for 10 years, which is a sports skinny bundle, which they are
Speaker 7:  at work on now planning to launch as as soon as they can.
Speaker 1:  So that strikes me as actually a pretty big deal. And I think, yes,
Speaker 1:  all the machinations here got so weird that I think people got
Speaker 1:  confused. But I think like FUBU is very powerful at this moment. Mm. Now
Speaker 1:  and I think it, it, it, it kind of has it, there are a lot of
Speaker 1:  ways it could fumble this opportunity, but it does feel like, I mean,
Speaker 1:  Hulu with live TV grew very much on the back of sports, right? Like they
Speaker 1:  had that, that whole ad campaign that was just athletes being like, oh, H
Speaker 7:  Has live sports over and over again.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And, and I think, and, and you know, the, the YouTube TV folks say
Speaker 1:  that the main reason people come to YouTube TV is for live sports. That's
Speaker 1:  why people, that's why they went out and spent all that money for Sunday
Speaker 1:  ticket. Like that's still the reason people want these services. And
Speaker 1:  for FUBU to now be able to a, be a meaningful competitor cable, which I think
Speaker 1:  it it is now, and b be able to
Speaker 1:  do if not like full venue then like kind of venue, like
Speaker 1:  venue light.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Or even venue plus arguably. 'cause I I, they are going again, we'll
Speaker 7:  see what the product looks like. They'll have a chance potentially to bring
Speaker 7:  in your local sports network or some of these other That's true networks
Speaker 7:  as well. Your MLB TV or what have you. So they even have a chance. It is,
Speaker 7:  it's exactly like you said. I think suddenly these leagues and and distributors
Speaker 7:  are looking at Fuo as, as exactly what they wanted to be looked at, which
Speaker 7:  is, which is a tool here to, to help distribute
Speaker 1:  Games. Yeah. We've like added a real sports competitor,
Speaker 1:  just not the one anybody expected or meant to launch. It's, it's a very strange
Speaker 1:  outcome that Fuo is, is kind of the
Speaker 1:  only survivor in this, in this fight. It's,
Speaker 7:  It's, it's, it's really, it's something, these are huge companies we're talking
Speaker 7:  about huge tech companies, huge entertainment companies. And this is, you
Speaker 7:  know, a a startup that launched basically with like international soccer
Speaker 7:  rights 10 years ago. And now here they are. And maybe they're how we're gonna
Speaker 7:  be watching sports in a couple years. It's, it's truly, truly crazy. I, I
Speaker 7:  will, the one other thing working in this favor is I do think the
Speaker 7:  YouTube TV price hike in December,
Speaker 7:  they announced they were gonna raise prices by 15%. Yeah. Which is, is I
Speaker 7:  think was, you know, $10, one of their biggest jumps yet. I think that was
Speaker 7:  a big wake up moment for a lot of people say, oh, maybe we should try to
Speaker 7:  see if there's anything else that we can use as an alternative here, because
Speaker 7:  otherwise this could, this could run away from us.
Speaker 1:  I mean, you, it, it just is cable now, right, right. Like it's, it's not
Speaker 1:  even cable, but cheaper. It's just cable, but easier to cancel.
Speaker 1:  And that's not nothing. Right. Like, it, it is meaningful that it is, is
Speaker 1:  easier to get in and out of those things.
Speaker 7:  Easier to cancel, easier to watch anywhere you want unlimited dvr. There
Speaker 7:  are, there are nice things about it. I I, I think you, you mentioned this
Speaker 7:  earlier too. One of the things I push back against this idea that like
Speaker 7:  sports is watching sports is worse than it ever was, is it is so much more
Speaker 7:  available than it ever was. And I think we take that for granted that 10
Speaker 7:  years ago, a lot of these things you couldn't watch or you could watch very
Speaker 7:  expensively or you had to put a satellite on your house. These things have
Speaker 7:  gotten a lot easier, but they've also gotten a lot more expensive. So, so
Speaker 7:  that's, that's where it sits. It
Speaker 1:  Definitely, it cuts both directions that it is. Yeah. There is, there is
Speaker 1:  more stuff you can watch than ever for sure. But
Speaker 1:  those things are in more places than ever. Right, right. And So I guess like
Speaker 1:  as a sports fan on balance, I'll take that trade like, yeah, sure,
Speaker 1:  I'll pay, I'll pay all your stupid prices just to watch your games. But
Speaker 1:  because now I can and that's something,
Speaker 7:  But the league's problem is a lot of people who aren't yet sports fans are
Speaker 7:  saying, I'm signing up for what, I'm signing up for 40 years of being jerked
Speaker 7:  around between 12 different services and no, I'm just gonna, you know, stay
Speaker 7:  on TikTok, isn catch the highlights.
Speaker 1:  Right. Yeah. I'm gonna, I'm gonna watch ESPN's social accounts, not
Speaker 1:  ESPN's cable channels. Speaking of, let's, let's talk about what's coming
Speaker 1:  this year, because I think other than that
Speaker 1:  whole saga of last year, I think one of the big stories for me
Speaker 1:  of 2024 was that it is now abundantly clear
Speaker 1:  that all of the tech companies are all in on sports. Yes. Apple is in
Speaker 1:  Amazon is in Google is in Netflix is in, like, these companies are spending
Speaker 1:  real money on sports things that matter, that people care about. And Netflix
Speaker 1:  keeps like sandbagging itself, but it's, it's lying. Netflix cares
Speaker 1:  deeply about this stuff.
Speaker 1:  Then you have this sort of lingering possibility of whatever
Speaker 1:  ESPN is about to launch. Yeah. What do you think
Speaker 1:  is coming this year? What's, what's 2025 gonna look like? Is, are
Speaker 1:  we just waiting around to see what this ESPN thing is? Is that kind of the
Speaker 1:  big unknown at the moment?
Speaker 7:  So I, I think, like I said, if 2024 was this year of, we're all on YouTube
Speaker 7:  tv and we're all on these services, I think 2025 is the year of
Speaker 7:  sports streaming. Getting pretty weird in a few different ways. I think
Speaker 7:  we're talking about these skinny bundles. We just saw DirecTV launched a
Speaker 7:  new product called My Sports last week. Oh yeah, that's right. Which again,
Speaker 7:  is this kind of skinny bundle concept where you're getting 20 to 25 channels.
Speaker 7:  FUBU ISS gonna launch theirs, would not be shocked to see YouTube tv try
Speaker 7:  to do something like that whenever they get the, the ability to in their
Speaker 7:  agreements. So we're gonna see a lot of these services and then we're gonna
Speaker 7:  see these companies, Warner, ESPN, launching their own things. And then we're
Speaker 7:  gonna see Amazon, like you're saying, Amazon and Google continue to build
Speaker 7:  products for sports. Apple continue to build products for sports
Speaker 7:  and, and, and so it's gonna be messy. It's, it's not, it's not gonna be clean
Speaker 7:  by the end of the year. It's gonna be messy. But I I I think as you said,
Speaker 7:  ESPN is gonna be at the center of, of what that looks like. What
Speaker 1:  Do we know about ESPN's coming service? What,
Speaker 1:  what is the size of that thing gonna be? So
Speaker 7:  Yeah, ESPN flagship,
Speaker 1:  ESPN one, tm,
Speaker 7:  Espn one tm almost certainly launching before football season,
Speaker 7:  probably with a different name. Again, we can start with the price. They
Speaker 7:  haven't announced it yet. PE my bet if we're, if we're putting betting, putting
Speaker 7:  money down, and this is sports, so why not, is this probably, they
Speaker 7:  probably find a way to start this at $20 a month. Whether that's, that's
Speaker 7:  my guess too. That's discount rate or, you know, lock you in or
Speaker 7:  whatever, longer term. They're not gonna want you to know how much you're
Speaker 7:  paying for this. They're gonna want it bundled in with your phone bill or
Speaker 7:  your Disney bundle or your life insurance or you know,
Speaker 7:  whatever, whatever it takes to get you paying for this.
Speaker 1:  I mean, and remember when Disney launched Disney Plus, they had all of these
Speaker 1:  wild yes promotions that If you signed up for a year at the very beginning,
Speaker 1:  it was much cheaper. And then it just sort of slowly, steadily got more expensive,
Speaker 1:  but then they started to bundle stuff in. So I Yeah, I think you're right.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna go exactly the same way.
Speaker 7:  And, and that playbook worked out well for them. They're gonna bring that
Speaker 7:  back. So that is what it's gonna cost. That's what it may or may not be named.
Speaker 7:  So what is it gonna provide? So it's going to provide everything
Speaker 7:  that ESP n sees, the, the ESPN empire from, from coast to coast.
Speaker 7:  Its live rights, its studio programming. The company
Speaker 7:  is very committed to launching or relaunching its app tied to this
Speaker 7:  so that your fantasy is gonna be in there, your betting is gonna be in there,
Speaker 7:  your shopping is gonna be evident. This is gonna be in, in their mind the,
Speaker 7:  the everything sports app. They want to,
Speaker 7:  you know, they, they launched this where to watch feature last year, which
Speaker 7:  shows where games are on outside of their networks, which is kind of new
Speaker 7:  and different. They want you to be the place you go for sports,
Speaker 7:  you know, forevermore. It's
Speaker 1:  The where to watch thing that I think strikes me as the most interesting
Speaker 1:  because I think you're right that the, you can sort of see the pieces, like
Speaker 1:  ES ESPN BET continues to grow and it, it's fantasy stuff continues to grow
Speaker 1:  and the idea of putting all those things together and
Speaker 1:  sort of making them speak to each other better makes sense. Right? Like that
Speaker 1:  seems fairly clearly where it's gonna go. But ESP n also seems to have this
Speaker 1:  idea of being like the TV guide to all sports, even the ones that
Speaker 1:  aren't on ESPN's platforms. Yes. Super
Speaker 1:  interesting and good and powerful idea if ESPN can pull it off. I actually
Speaker 1:  think the, the where to watch page is fabulous. It is like, it is such a
Speaker 1:  good useful thing that should have existed very a long time ago. That's just
Speaker 1:  like, what network is this game on? Right? But like, I can't imagine
Speaker 1:  everybody being psyched about me wanting to watch
Speaker 1:  an MLS game on Apple TV and first going to the
Speaker 1:  ESPN app in order to do that. And we've seen this before, even with
Speaker 1:  like the, the TV guide, like services like Netflix doesn't wanna play along
Speaker 1:  with those services. Exactly. So it doesn't really give them data. Lots of
Speaker 1:  these things don't, like does ESPN even have a real chance of pulling
Speaker 1:  this off in a meaningful way?
Speaker 7:  That's a good question. And I will say ESPN's not the only one that wants
Speaker 7:  to do this. As you mentioned. You know, I think Amazon sees itself as the
Speaker 7:  hub for sports. YouTube sees itself as the hub for sports. FUBU sees itself
Speaker 7:  as the hub for sports on down the line for me,
Speaker 7:  when I am trying to figure out what's on or what channel it's on, like I
Speaker 7:  go to Google and I think Google knows that. And I think Google's thinking
Speaker 7:  about that opportunity too. You know, if they can link you out to
Speaker 7:  these services and, and collect a fee when you sign up, et cetera.
Speaker 7:  So I, it's, it's gonna be challenging a, again, as much as we might,
Speaker 7:  we might all want this, this kind of one place, this hub, whatever. I,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's a very, very far away away. I think we're probably 10 years away
Speaker 7:  from Amazon and Netflix and Google all giving it a go, seeing where things
Speaker 7:  shake out and then, and then consolidating back, back into one one place.
Speaker 7:  So, but in the meantime, yeah, I I think there's an information
Speaker 7:  aspect of it that they can provide. They can tell you it's on Netflix. Netflix
Speaker 7:  can't stop them from telling you that. And then it's just a question of Yeah,
Speaker 7:  how, how willing ESPN is to, to send you to other places.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think it, it makes sense to me that ES ESPN would be willing
Speaker 1:  to send you to other places actually, just because that stuff is so
Speaker 1:  immutable, right? Like ES ESPN is just not going to get the NBA rights it
Speaker 1:  doesn't have for a long time. And so if you're ES espn, you can either
Speaker 1:  bury your head in the sand until a decade from now and then try to win the
Speaker 1:  rights. Or you can say, okay, we're gonna get people here to bet and then
Speaker 1:  we can have them go watch somewhere else. And as long as we are the place
Speaker 1:  they come first we win. But also, you know, who wants to be the place people
Speaker 1:  go first is literally everybody else. Right? Right. And so, and this has
Speaker 1:  been the thing with streaming in general forever and is like, again,
Speaker 1:  I I come back to like what users want is so clear. And I think the
Speaker 1:  ESPN's where to watch page really worked for me because it is, it is that
Speaker 1:  thing I should go and it's like, here are all the games on and here's how
Speaker 1:  to watch them. That is, that is a thing that ought to exist. And it's
Speaker 1:  ESPN does like a medium job of it, but it's, it's great that it exists at
Speaker 1:  all.
Speaker 7:  That's what I was gonna say. Yeah. All these things, again, going somewhat
Speaker 7:  like venue, they have half the things you want. Right. At a cost slightly
Speaker 7:  higher. Apple sports, I think is another example of this, right? They launched
Speaker 7:  an app for the first time last year. It's a big step in this direction. It
Speaker 7:  still doesn't have golf and tennis and NASCAR and F1 Right.
Speaker 7:  Olympics are on down the line, you know? Yeah. I think even, I think when
Speaker 7:  I talked to PN in August, September, I think they had like 300 leagues in
Speaker 7:  where to watch. And they were still getting requests daily from fans and
Speaker 7:  also from leagues be like, Hey, why don't you list our right
Speaker 7:  Mid-American conference volleyball games in here. People wanna watch these,
Speaker 7:  you know, why don't you list our minor league baseball on down the line?
Speaker 7:  So it's the, the simplicity and the, the, the
Speaker 7:  exhaust of this hubs is, is always gonna be just that reach.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So where do you think that leaves us as sports watchers
Speaker 1:  for the next couple of years? I mean, I think on the one hand, like you said,
Speaker 1:  there is more to watch than ever. And in many ways the user experience of
Speaker 1:  watching those things is better than ever. Like, we're kind of past Amazon
Speaker 1:  not being very good at streaming football games where like it's
Speaker 1:  most football games you wanna watch on the internet are available and they're
Speaker 1:  there. They might be expensive, but they're pretty good. Is that as good
Speaker 1:  as it's gonna be for a while? Like, is the, is the rest of the landscape
Speaker 1:  gonna get really just messier before it gets cleaner here?
Speaker 7:  That's as good as it's gonna be. And, and like you said, I think buffering
Speaker 7:  and, and delays was a big problem. You know, we saw, obviously with Netflix's
Speaker 7:  first time out every time, every time a streaming services launch, you know,
Speaker 7:  their first live sporting event, it usually goes pretty poorly. Police reports
Speaker 7:  crash when they try to launch a golf event five years ago, Netflix
Speaker 7:  almost crashed entirely when they try to put Jake Paul on.
Speaker 7:  So I, I think now we've seen almost, I think maybe all
Speaker 7:  of the players have those moments. It's reliable, right? Yeah. You, you,
Speaker 7:  you search, you do have to search where the game is on Google, but once you
Speaker 7:  find it, once you go there, once you pay, you can watch usually,
Speaker 7:  you know, we can get into regional blackouts and all that, but that's, that
Speaker 7:  is working. I I think where all these companies wanna
Speaker 7:  make these games more interactive where you're talking to your friends in
Speaker 7:  inside the stream. I think for the most part that's more trouble than
Speaker 7:  it's worth. Yeah. But, but yeah, the, the idea of putting the game on If
Speaker 7:  you want to finally, I think for a lot of people is, is a reality. If, If
Speaker 7:  you're willing to pay the cost and, and maybe, maybe we should, you know,
Speaker 7:  take a moment to celebrate that before we complain about everything else.
Speaker 1:  Agreed. It costs a million dollars, but I can watch every NFL game that exists
Speaker 1:  and that that is something. So
Speaker 7:  Yeah, shut up and, and grab the popcorn. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Exactly. Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Who do you think is the sort of player to watch this year? I mean, I think
Speaker 1:  to me ESPN is, is both like the biggest name in this space and
Speaker 1:  also the one that might have the sort of single
Speaker 1:  splashiest plan for this year. But like, I don't know, suddenly
Speaker 1:  FUBU strikes me as a really interesting company to pay attention to as a
Speaker 1:  sports fan. Like I have, I have never once in my life watched FUBU and I
Speaker 1:  that will, I'm I suspect change this year. Yeah. Is do you
Speaker 1:  have any other bets on like who you're really paying close attention to?
Speaker 7:  I think this is gonna be the year that Amazon really establishes itself in
Speaker 7:  sports. They're, they're getting the NBA primarily. That's the biggest thing.
Speaker 7:  That's right. So starting next NBA season in the fall, it'll be on Amazon.
Speaker 7:  They're gonna take over this in-season tournament to the NBA cup as kind
Speaker 7:  of their, their, their crowning rights there. Thursday night
Speaker 7:  football continues to grow. They had a playoff game just this, just this
Speaker 7:  year. So I'm counting that as, as part of the, the year of Amazon sports,
Speaker 7:  going back to the hub conversation, they've been involved in the regional
Speaker 7:  sports network side of things. You can now subscribe to the regional sports
Speaker 7:  network service for certain number of markets. And it's certain, you know,
Speaker 7:  blah, blah blah within Amazon. I, I think, I wouldn't be
Speaker 7:  surprised to see, you know, them launch some sort of, whether
Speaker 7:  FUBU was in Amazon or, or ESPN service, a discount for Prime,
Speaker 7:  you know, whatever. I think they have the unique position where they can
Speaker 7:  monetize this. And, and from the prime membership perspective and from the
Speaker 7:  advertising perspective, which is what, you know, you've heard people who
Speaker 7:  who follow Amazon have heard this a million times, but I think that model
Speaker 7:  is going to be the way forward a a as sports look for places where they
Speaker 7:  can reach everybody and make money, which
Speaker 7:  for a long time has been a bit of a, a balancing act for, for, for
Speaker 7:  sports leagues is we can be on TV or with our traditional
Speaker 7:  partners, Fox and CBS, but we're gonna get more money if we go to a
Speaker 7:  D zone or, or, or one of these other subscription services that, or even
Speaker 7:  an Apple who, who are gonna put us behind a paywall. And, and So I think
Speaker 7:  Amazon maybe is gonna find that that middle lane here where
Speaker 7:  everybody's happy, including the folks who are spending a lot of money.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That would be,
Speaker 1:  that would put Amazon in a really fascinating position. 'cause I think the
Speaker 1:  one thing I've been learning recently is how far ahead Amazon
Speaker 1:  is as an ad business from most of the other streamers, which I think I
Speaker 1:  underrated for a long time. That like what you're saying is Amazon
Speaker 1:  can afford to pay all of this money for sports,
Speaker 1:  not just because it's a giant company that can just, that just throws off
Speaker 1:  cash from other things. Right? Like AWS pays for it. That's fine. Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But also they can actually directly monetize this in a way that
Speaker 1:  most of these other streamers can't. And so they're in a position of like,
Speaker 1:  this is not just a bet on other parts of our business that maybe you'll
Speaker 1:  come for the Olympics and subscribe to Peacock, which is like a very real
Speaker 1:  thing that Comcast did. They're like, we, we can come
Speaker 1:  and maybe you'll subscribe to Prime, but also we can make real money off
Speaker 1:  of this. And that becomes, I think, pretty hard to compete with if Amazon
Speaker 1:  can really pull it off.
Speaker 7:  And so that's Amazon and that's games. And I think everything outside of
Speaker 7:  games, I'm looking at YouTube, especially once we figure out whatever this
Speaker 7:  TikTok situation is, I think all of these companies that are looking to reach
Speaker 7:  young fans are putting more on YouTube. You know, a not
Speaker 7:  that long ago, these leagues were mad at YouTube for putting up
Speaker 7:  highlights, and now they're desperate to get their highlights on YouTube
Speaker 7:  to be promoted to get the YouTube creators at their games. And So I think
Speaker 7:  YouTube also has a really interesting offering. And obviously Google knows
Speaker 7:  how to sell ads too. I think they have a really interesting offering to,
Speaker 7:  to leagues as well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, fair enough. I think the, the, the shift towards everybody just
Speaker 1:  being happy about highlights is one that we are like only beginning to figure
Speaker 1:  out, like, I watched a surprising amount number of soccer games in those
Speaker 1:  10 minute extended highlights. Yeah, sure. And I don't, I don't know what
Speaker 1:  to do about that as a sports fan, but it, it feels, it feels like a change.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Alright, Jacob, thank you for coming on. I appreciate it. You're gonna come
Speaker 1:  back when ESPN one launches and you're gonna gloat about how you were right
Speaker 1:  about the name. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 7:  My victory lap. I'm looking forward to it. All
Speaker 1:  Right, thanks man. Thank
Speaker 7:  You so much for having me.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna
Speaker 1:  talk about books because here on a podcast, it's time to talk about books.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Grammarly Enterprise Ready AI
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. So like I mentioned at the top, we're gonna spend some
Speaker 1:  time this week and next week talking about tech ways to do
Speaker 1:  New Year's resolutions. And I think If you look across the world,
Speaker 1:  two of the biggest New Year's resolutions are some version of I want to get
Speaker 1:  in better shape. You. You can take that kind of as broadly as you'd like
Speaker 1:  to. And I want read more and I think I hear particularly
Speaker 1:  from people is I wanna take the time that I spend on my devices
Speaker 1:  and point it at better things. I want to not instinctively
Speaker 1:  open Instagram or TikTok, which who knows where
Speaker 1:  that'll go in a few weeks or Reddit or whatever else. And I
Speaker 1:  want to do something fulfilling. And I think reading a book
Speaker 1:  is, is just kind of the perfect version of that. But there are actually lots
Speaker 1:  of things to do that are better than those things even on your phone.
Speaker 1:  Kevin Wynn, who is our deputy editor, has been thinking about this
Speaker 1:  stuff for a long time. He actually wrote a story at GQ a bunch of years ago
Speaker 1:  about how to read more with a lot of tips that I have really enjoyed
Speaker 1:  and used over the years. So I figured I'd have Kevin on to talk about how
Speaker 1:  he gets so much reading done, how we can all get more reading done and
Speaker 1:  how we should think about reading books in an increasingly digital
Speaker 1:  and screen-based world. So let's see what we can do here.
Speaker 1:  Kevin Wynn, welcome to the show.
Speaker 10:  How's it going, David,
Speaker 1:  Where are you in the world right now? I have not seen your face in person
Speaker 1:  in a long time. Where, what's, tell us about your setup right now.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, well it's, it's 8:30 AM where you are. It's
Speaker 10:  8:30 PM where I am, which is Ho Chi Minh City,
Speaker 10:  Vietnam, better known as Saigon. And I'm talking
Speaker 10:  to you through my very crummy wifi connection at the
Speaker 10:  Airbnb.
Speaker 1:  Amazing. And you've been there for like, what, almost two months at this
Speaker 1:  point? You're like, this is a real, this is a real trip you're doing.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Who Let me get away with this.
Speaker 1:  Unclear, honestly. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  My partner and I have been here for a couple months. I was doing some reporting
Speaker 10:  in Tokyo, which was fine. And actually ended up
Speaker 10:  accidentally helping out with some reporting in Seoul. 'cause that's when
Speaker 10:  we landed there. Sarah Jung happened to be there. So we were hanging out
Speaker 10:  and then it happened to be martial law. So
Speaker 10:  that was supposed to be my vacation week. And I ended up editing Sarah.
Speaker 10:  Although those pieces turned out to be a lot of fun if, If you guys haven't
Speaker 10:  listened to it. Birch Gas listeners, Sarah Jung went to the martial law
Speaker 10:  protests kind of drunk 'cause we were drinking Mako Lee before she showed
Speaker 10:  up
Speaker 1:  Kind of drunk. Seems, seems kind.
Speaker 10:  That's
Speaker 1:  True. Well
Speaker 10:  It was so cold out there and she just like apparently sobered up while she
Speaker 10:  was there. So that's real dedication. That's real reporting
Speaker 1:  A hundred percent truly one of the weirder like 48 hour
Speaker 1:  spans in VERGE history. But it was, it was good stuff. Yes. All
Speaker 1:  right, So I brought you here to talk about reading because you are the person
Speaker 1:  I know who reads the most and
Speaker 1:  I would say is the most, somewhere between adamant
Speaker 1:  and snobby about how good books are and that people should read
Speaker 1:  more books. And it's, it's January, lots of people wanna read more books
Speaker 1:  and you, in addition to being adamant and snobby about reading books, I think
Speaker 1:  have like a good strategy for how to be a normal person in the year
Speaker 1:  2025 and actually read books. So I just wanna talk through that a little
Speaker 1:  bit and see if we can help some people. Does that sound good?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I'm totally with you. It's funny, like January being like the, The
Speaker 10:  new year new me thing, everyone kind of like wants to read more,
Speaker 10:  everyone wants to get back to the gym. Gym. I think there are kind of like
Speaker 10:  some exercise discipline things that can help you read more. But actually
Speaker 10:  in the grand scheme of things, things I sort of reject the idea that reading
Speaker 10:  is like exercise.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, interesting. Tell me more.
Speaker 10:  I think people, I mean everyone wishes they read more,
Speaker 10:  but I think a lot of it is, it comes from like a self-improvement idea
Speaker 10:  and you know, I think there's a little bit of just like, oh, I wish I spent
Speaker 10:  less time on my phone and more time with my nose in a book. That makes sense.
Speaker 10:  It's probably just better for, for your eyes for one for sure.
Speaker 10:  But I think just this thing too that just like, oh, like reading is exercise
Speaker 10:  for your brain and, and I think there's like some truth to that, but I
Speaker 10:  think If you only think of it as that, as kind of a
Speaker 10:  self-improvement medium, I don't know, I think you, you
Speaker 10:  kind of miss out on the richness of reading and also the enjoyment of reading.
Speaker 10:  Hmm.
Speaker 1:  I agree with that. Yeah. The idea that it is sort of a punishment to be endured
Speaker 1:  because there is something good on the other side is also, and it's the same
Speaker 1:  thing people say about exercise, right? That like the, the actual way to
Speaker 1:  succeed at this is to learn to enjoy the thing itself. And, and that actually
Speaker 1:  the thing itself is enjoyable If you do it right and that If you just do
Speaker 1:  an exercise that you like and you're gonna exercise a lot more, and actually
Speaker 1:  that's better than just beating yourself up on,
Speaker 1:  based on somebody's idea of a good workout because you think you'll feel
Speaker 1:  good at the end of it.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, a hundred percent. And I, I do think like the, like emotionally,
Speaker 10:  I think the thing that exercise and reading have in common is like, I think
Speaker 10:  it, it's actually kind of hard to like make yourself sit down and open a
Speaker 10:  book sometimes, especially after a long day. Especially like when,
Speaker 10:  you know, streaming services and video games are kind of like easier
Speaker 10:  to just turn on and, and put your brain into. But sort of
Speaker 10:  like exercise, it's like once you get to the gym, you know, like the feeling
Speaker 10:  changes very quickly and I think everyone knows that and
Speaker 10:  like, you don't have to wait to get like a runner's hide. It's like once
Speaker 10:  you're in it, you're in it, you know?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. I I, I totally agree with that. So I think there, there are sort
Speaker 1:  of two kinds of reading and you just alluded to both of them. I think on
Speaker 1:  the one hand there is the, like I am going to sit down and read
Speaker 1:  as like a long activity, right? Like, I'm going to curl up in a chair and
Speaker 1:  pull a blanket over me and, and read for hours.
Speaker 1:  And then there's the, like I read three pages
Speaker 1:  while I'm sitting on the toilet, right? Or like waiting in line for at a
Speaker 1:  coffee shop or whatever. And I wanna, I wanna kind of differentiate both
Speaker 1:  of those because I think you, you have interesting ideas about both of those
Speaker 1:  ways of thinking about reading. But let's start with the like curling up
Speaker 1:  in a chair with a good book with plans to read for hours strategy.
Speaker 1:  Like do you do that? What's your, what's your setup for how you do that?
Speaker 10:  Well, I just wanna say like that's, yeah, clearly the most enjoyable way
Speaker 10:  to read or really do anything, you know, it's just like, oh, it's, it's
Speaker 10:  nighttime. You're curled up with blanket, you have like a glass of whiskey,
Speaker 10:  you have a big book. You've been excited to read, a tremendous
Speaker 10:  experience If you can somehow manufacture that on the regular
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Do you manufacture that on the regular? Like do you, do you carve out that
Speaker 1:  time?
Speaker 10:  No, I think it's, it's kind of impossible.
Speaker 1:  Okay. That actually makes me feel better.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. I, I think, you know, like If you have like a family, If you have
Speaker 10:  a life, it's just, and I guess that's the other thing. There are like
Speaker 10:  ideal circumstances for reading. Sure. But If you only read when the
Speaker 10:  circumstances are ideal, then you'll never really make it a habit
Speaker 10:  and you'll never really be disciplined about it. And I think that like anything
Speaker 10:  else, getting into a good habit requires just
Speaker 10:  like a little bit of discipline and just a little bit of cleverness and
Speaker 10:  a little bit of just like letting yourself off the hook every once in a
Speaker 10:  while.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Fair enough. But in your, in your ideal reading scenario, are you
Speaker 1:  a, are you a Kindle guy? Are you a print guy? Are you like print out the
Speaker 1:  PDFs and read them with a, with a marker in your hand? Like what is your
Speaker 1:  ideal reading scenario?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's funny. I'm actually like all of the above. I think, you know,
Speaker 10:  if I'm in a, have that magical situation where I'm in the chair
Speaker 10:  with the, the fancy whiskey, yeah. I think a print book is
Speaker 10:  the thing that's easiest on my eyes for a lot of reasons. And that would
Speaker 10:  sort of be ideal. But I read probably 50% digitally as well
Speaker 10:  for this job. I print out a lot of things and highlight
Speaker 10:  and mark things up.
Speaker 1:  Okay. But wait, just before I let you off the hook on, I, I do all the things
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna, I want you to rank them for me. So there's print book, there
Speaker 1:  is giant loose leaf pieces of eight and a half by 11 paper.
Speaker 1:  There's Kindle and there's iPad. Rank those one to four for me
Speaker 1:  in terms of like you, you have, you have, you're gonna read for 90
Speaker 1:  consecutive minutes.
Speaker 10:  Ooh, okay. I'm really not trying to like elude it allude the question. 'cause
Speaker 10:  I think it does depend on the medium. Like for example, I think
Speaker 10:  iPad is my least favorite of those. I actually think the way you listed
Speaker 10:  them, print book, loose paper,
Speaker 10:  Kindle iPad is my ranking from like best to worst. Okay. I still
Speaker 10:  like them all, but I actually love reading comic books on an iPad. That's
Speaker 10:  actually like kind of ideal for me. And I don't know what it is, but I,
Speaker 10:  I tend to retain more when I read in print. So I think there's kind of,
Speaker 10:  that's like just what the, the spectrum is for me. But I, again, I
Speaker 10:  really think they're all valid. I think actually I
Speaker 10:  do consider listening to audio books like reading, but I would put that
Speaker 10:  at the bottom.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's fair. I think I, I agree that I, I actually don't wanna dwell
Speaker 1:  on audiobook for too long. I realized I was preparing for this and I was
Speaker 1:  like, should we talk about audio books? And I was like, that is a rabbit
Speaker 1:  hole. I'm not prepared to go down. But I agree audiobooks are awesome and
Speaker 1:  more people should listen to them. But it is, it is slightly different in
Speaker 1:  a way that I have like not yet quite figured out. But when I listen to a
Speaker 1:  book and when I look at a book and read it, it
Speaker 1:  does feel slightly different. But I think they're both okay. Different strokes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. You wanna listen to books. Listen to books. My sister listens
Speaker 1:  to audio books and is, has read more fantasy books than anyone I've ever
Speaker 1:  met in my entire life and remembers every single thing about them. So kudos
Speaker 1:  to her.
Speaker 1:  Where do you get your books from, both digitally and in print? Are you like,
Speaker 1:  you get a lot of books for work so we'll, we'll throw those out, but when
Speaker 1:  you're like going looking for books, what are your, do you have good sources?
Speaker 10:  You mean like as a discovery method or where do I buy
Speaker 1:  Them as a discovery method? Or even just If you are like, here is the secret
Speaker 1:  to buying books for cheap that no one else knows about. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Well the secret to buying cheap books is to buy used books. True. We
Speaker 10:  do a lot of eBay at our house and we actually try and read a lot of stuff
Speaker 10:  that's out of print for some reason. So sometimes
Speaker 10:  that's the only option. But eBay e eBay's great. And then I think, you know,
Speaker 10:  occasionally I'll buy eBooks off Amazon, although
Speaker 10:  bookshop.org, which is kind of the, the indie
Speaker 10:  online retailer or the, the online retailer that represents all the indie
Speaker 10:  bookstores is great too. And they're, they're launching their own ebook
Speaker 10:  service pretty soon. So I think I'm gonna move all my reading there
Speaker 10:  If you shop on Amazon, no judgment, but it's just what I choose not to do.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And then, yeah, I, I buy a lot online from or pickup
Speaker 10:  from my local indie bookstores. So in New York books are Magic
Speaker 10:  Greenlight Bookstore and you and me books.
Speaker 1:  Nice. I the, the one like great local
Speaker 1:  bookstore near us just closed. Oh I've only been to it a few times and I
Speaker 1:  found it like still slightly more devastating than I expected to, to walk
Speaker 1:  in and they're having like a 50% off sale on everything because they're just
Speaker 1:  going outta business and really kind of pumped me out. But I also bought
Speaker 1:  a bunch of books for Half Brace.
Speaker 10:  I know, I was gonna say too, I, there was a time in my life where I was
Speaker 10:  a lot more diligent about just like reading reviews and like just a handful
Speaker 10:  of publications just like really being up on what was coming
Speaker 10:  out. And somehow I would still go to, you know, McNally Jackson
Speaker 10:  and just like the display tables would have tons of fun stuff that
Speaker 10:  you just never heard of or never think to pick up. And I don't
Speaker 10:  know that that perusal experience still really valuable. And actually
Speaker 10:  I don't know if folks have been to a Barnes and Noble recently,
Speaker 10:  they got kind of taken over by private equity and they kind of have
Speaker 10:  rethought all the stores to be smaller and
Speaker 10:  they're actually much better now. Hmm. So if there's a Barnes and Noble
Speaker 10:  near you, there's a good chance it's been sort of like revamped and the
Speaker 10:  booksellers there are great. And I dunno, it is kind of funny as someone
Speaker 10:  that like recently rewatched, you've got mail. It's like we used to think
Speaker 10:  of like the Barnes and Noble as the big bad. Sure. And and clearly Amazon's
Speaker 10:  big bad now. So now we're out there supporting Barnes and Noble, like it's
Speaker 10:  the little guy.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Barnes and Noble is comparatively like the, the mom and pop upstart
Speaker 1:  bookstore.
Speaker 10:  I know, right. Maybe that should just show you how big Amazon
Speaker 10:  is. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I agree. So, okay, so all the way on the other side of the reading spectrum,
Speaker 1:  you are also a big proponent of reading books on your
Speaker 1:  phone in Yes. Tiny Bursts, which I think to like a lot
Speaker 1:  of reading purists out there is is like blasphemy.
Speaker 1:  Why are you such a, why, how did you become such a believer in reading
Speaker 1:  in the Books app on your phone all the time?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I just think once you get into the habit of it, it's,
Speaker 10:  it's immensely satisfying sort of, you were laying out earlier, there's
Speaker 10:  like the two modes. There's like the, you know, I, I also think there's
Speaker 10:  like degradations between these two things. But yeah, like sitting in the
Speaker 10:  fancy chair at night and the blanket and then I think, you know, just like
Speaker 10:  the three minutes you peel off and you're like on the toilet or whatever,
Speaker 10:  that's, that time accumulates a lot, you know, and you
Speaker 10:  can just, especially If you commute on public transportation, like the easiest
Speaker 10:  way to just read is on your phone there in line for coffee.
Speaker 10:  And I think it also depends, I usually kind of break out the
Speaker 10:  types of reading that I do. I would say also I'm someone that like is usually
Speaker 10:  reading two or three books at the same time. Usually I'm reading
Speaker 10:  fiction in print 'cause I just like need to concentrate a little more on
Speaker 10:  that. But like, I think a non-fiction book is a little bit easier to read
Speaker 10:  quickly. You know, obviously depends on the kind of book, but
Speaker 10:  that's the stuff that works really well on the phone. And just like, yeah,
Speaker 10:  reading nonfiction like Three Minute Bursts I think is actually quite satisfying.
Speaker 10:  I don't know. And I think it's kind of, it's like a little bit part of my
Speaker 10:  strategy that like when I wanna read, I like
Speaker 10:  have a couple different options that will kind of appeal to like the
Speaker 10:  mood that I'm in. If I'm like really ready to settle in, you know, I'll
Speaker 10:  probably do the novel if I just like wanna read for 15 minutes,
Speaker 10:  probably just the nonfiction book if I really like don't know what I'm
Speaker 10:  in the mood for or like I'm thinking about playing video games instead.
Speaker 10:  Probably play video games instead. But like the comic books on the iPad
Speaker 10:  are also like a great option too.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Okay. So talk me through this rubric a little bit. 'cause I think fiction
Speaker 1:  versus nonfiction is an interesting way to think about it, but th this question
Speaker 1:  of like what is a good sort of three minutes at
Speaker 1:  a Time book I think is actually a really key part of trying to figure this
Speaker 1:  out. 'cause for me, the problem I've always had when I've tried to develop
Speaker 1:  that habit is I'll read, I don't know, it's like a, like a Lord
Speaker 1:  of the Rings is actually a book I tried to read on my phone. This is years
Speaker 1:  ago, but I, I still remember this so concretely. I would read it on the subway.
Speaker 1:  I had like a 17 minute subway ride from my apartment to the verges office
Speaker 1:  and I would, I would read Lord of the Rings, but I would open it up and every
Speaker 1:  single time I'm like in the middle of a scene So I would have to back up
Speaker 1:  a few pages, remember where I was and by the time I'm caught up
Speaker 1:  I'm there. So I'm like, I'm just reading the same six pages over and over
Speaker 1:  and over trying to remember where I was. And I had this moment of being like,
Speaker 1:  okay, this is clearly the wrong kind of book to be reading in these sorts
Speaker 1:  of increments. But how would you like delineate what makes a good
Speaker 1:  phone book versus what makes a good, like you need to read this
Speaker 1:  in in sort of larger, more concentrated chunks kind of book?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, that's a good question. I do think that like, yeah fiction, non-fiction
Speaker 10:  is a pretty clumsy way to divide it. I think you can kind of tell like there
Speaker 10:  are types of books that require certain kinds of concentration
Speaker 10:  and I would read those off the phone usually. And then anything
Speaker 10:  that you can kind of breeze through is great for the phone.
Speaker 10:  You know, I think what you're talking about with Lord of the Rings where
Speaker 10:  the scenes are long, that's probably a tough phone read even though I think
Speaker 10:  a lot of fantasy and genre stuff works really well for the phone, especially
Speaker 10:  thrillers a romance.
Speaker 1:  I did read the Da Vinci Code on my phone and that's actually a perfect phone
Speaker 1:  book. Perfect. Because every chapter is like four pages long. So you just
Speaker 1:  like burn through two chapters, it moves really fast and then you're, and
Speaker 1:  then you're out and you pick it back up where you were. So like that, that's
Speaker 1:  the opposite of the thing I was just talking about I guess. Totally. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Well yeah, I mean the genius of Dan Brown and a lot of thriller writers
Speaker 10:  is like, I think they capped their chapters at like a thousand
Speaker 10:  words or or or fewer even. So you can in
Speaker 10:  five minutes read an entire chapter. So like you just have a self-contained
Speaker 10:  unit of thing. You're never jumping off in the middle of something or coming
Speaker 10:  back in the middle of it If you kind of time your stuff. Right. So yeah,
Speaker 10:  obviously perfect phone books. Yeah, I think the commute is just such an
Speaker 10:  interesting like unit of time because it's both
Speaker 10:  very distracting but also I think on people's commutes, like all
Speaker 10:  they wanna do is distract themselves from everything that's around them.
Speaker 10:  Maybe that's a New York 70 thing, but
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no, I, I, I agree with that and I think I'm thinking about a lot of,
Speaker 1:  like, a lot of the books that I end up reading for work purposes are
Speaker 1:  like somewhere between kind of journalistic
Speaker 1:  nonfiction and like self-help. Like I just read Cal Newport's new
Speaker 1:  book, which is basically all about like how to be better at work and not
Speaker 1:  lose your mind on the internet. And it is sort of a, it's it's chunks of
Speaker 1:  helpful information at a time and that to me is like a perfect phone book
Speaker 1:  because it's like each one of those things is helpful and I go through and
Speaker 1:  I highlight it, but it's kind of just like a bunch of articles in a row and
Speaker 1:  that that feels good. Whereas a lot
Speaker 1:  of these other books that I, I end up forgetting where I am if I haven't
Speaker 1:  read it in a couple of days is like that's the wrong thing to read on my
Speaker 1:  son. I think.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think it also becomes like pretty hard with fiction to jump in and
Speaker 10:  out of a, of a scene in particular. Yeah. 'cause you just like kind of,
Speaker 10:  you know, with a, I think a nonfiction book is generally like
Speaker 10:  kind of like guiding you and kind of telling you what it's about
Speaker 10:  in most cases at all times and reminding you and then in fiction, you know,
Speaker 10:  like I think it often literary fiction is like trying to
Speaker 10:  destabilize you or confuse you for effect and
Speaker 10:  it's probably working and it's probably not a great effect on the subway.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's very fair.
Speaker 1:  What apps do you use for reading on your phone? Either just for reading or
Speaker 1:  for like book management stuff in general? One of the things I was gonna
Speaker 1:  ask you about is if you're a person who like tracks all of your reading in
Speaker 1:  any specific way, so like what's your reading setup on your phone?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, in terms of tracking, I actually, I kind of go in and out of
Speaker 10:  tracking what I read. So I'm trying to be better about it in
Speaker 10:  2025. But I dunno, I, I kind of don't keep track 'cause I
Speaker 10:  used to, like, there were times when I, I felt like I needed to like keep
Speaker 10:  up a certain pace, especially for certain kinds of research and I've been
Speaker 10:  out of that for a while. So I don't know, I, I read a lot on my own So I
Speaker 10:  don't need to to motivate myself in that way. But you know, I actually think
Speaker 10:  this, there's so many like apps to track things. It's just like the best
Speaker 10:  thing you can do is just keep track of things in like your favorite notes
Speaker 10:  app. Like just don't overcomplicate it. It doesn't need to link
Speaker 10:  to anything. The more rigid the thing is, I
Speaker 10:  actually think the less likely you are or the more likely you are to like
Speaker 10:  fall off of it. So, and in terms of apps, again, I'm actually like pretty
Speaker 10:  unsophisticated. I read a lot in the Kindle app. I actually send a lot
Speaker 10:  of files to the Kindle app. There's like a super janky
Speaker 10:  beta get files onto your Kindle via
Speaker 10:  email.
Speaker 1:  I have said to people for years that the one job in the tech industry that
Speaker 1:  I'm interested in is going and being the product manager of Send
Speaker 1:  to Kindle and just make it, what If you just made it good? What if it was
Speaker 1:  you could just take a link and send it to the Kindle and then read that article
Speaker 1:  in your Kindle. Like what if that worked? I would, I would, I would do that
Speaker 1:  and then they would elect me King of the world and then everything would
Speaker 1:  be fantastic.
Speaker 10:  I just like, but it sucks. I mean am Amazon is like the funniest company
Speaker 10:  when it comes to just product. Like the Kindle experience has
Speaker 10:  clearly not been cared after for a long time and everything like
Speaker 10:  kind of works but is super janky. Actually I, this is obviously a very
Speaker 10:  specific use case, which is why it's not very well supported. But I was
Speaker 10:  trying to actually, I was reading David Burns how Music Works,
Speaker 10:  it's a tremendous book and I was highlighting a lot and I was like, oh,
Speaker 10:  I'd actually like to save some of these quotes in a doc. So I like
Speaker 10:  was trying to export the annotations or the highlights that I had made
Speaker 10:  and it was like erroring out. It was like, you do not have an email associated
Speaker 10:  with your Amazon account. Just not true. And then I was googling around
Speaker 10:  and then it turns out the issue, and this is extremely specific, is that
Speaker 10:  I didn't have an email address set up on the default mail app in
Speaker 10:  iOS.
Speaker 1:  Good lord.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like it didn't understand that I like used the Gmail app like a lot
Speaker 10:  of people. Yeah. So I like actually had to set up mail for the first time
Speaker 10:  just So I could export these David Burn quotes and it's just like,
Speaker 10:  at what point was that ever a solution? Like I'm sure they
Speaker 10:  haven't updated in a long time, but like they shipped it like that, you
Speaker 10:  know? Yeah. So anyway, you're asking me on apps, oh and
Speaker 10:  then I, I read a lot of PDFs in Dropbox, so just truly
Speaker 10:  like in elegant solutions to everything but, well
Speaker 1:  I, you're making me wonder if the
Speaker 1:  not being precious about it is maybe part of the point. And I think I,
Speaker 1:  I'm realizing now that this is kind of a trap that I have fallen into too,
Speaker 1:  which is like I am, I get really annoyed about how
Speaker 1:  apps scroll, which is a really stupid thing to say, but like the iBooks
Speaker 1:  or the Apple Books scrolling animation annoys me. So I don't use the app.
Speaker 1:  And then a lot of, a lot of things, like a lot of the read later apps
Speaker 1:  just make you vertically scroll, which is fine for like a web article, but
Speaker 1:  I hate for really long things. I want something that feels like pages and
Speaker 1:  So I end up using the Kindle app just because it's like a slightly better
Speaker 1:  app. And I'm realizing now that like the more precious you are about how
Speaker 1:  all this works, the worse it actually is because if I got a PDF in
Speaker 1:  Dropbox that was a book, there is a 0% chance I would read that book
Speaker 1:  truly. Like, and I'm not proud of that, but it's true. It would just irritate
Speaker 1:  me that the, the, you know, margins were too big and I would not read the
Speaker 1:  book. But I think getting past that might be a key to doing this. Well
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I mean I, every time I open the Kindle app I'm just like appalled
Speaker 10:  by the typeface choices. Like every time just, I'm somehow like shocked
Speaker 10:  every time and just the way it's like, it's, it's like justified width,
Speaker 10:  which just looks like horrible on the phone and Oh
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's awful.
Speaker 10:  And we, and we just, you know, we persist.
Speaker 1:  That's true. It's, it's good for us
Speaker 10:  Bravely.
Speaker 1:  Yes we are, we are, you know, out here doing the hard work.
Speaker 1:  You're also a big proponent of, of quitting books, which I think if, if we
Speaker 1:  give people one tip on how to read more books, I actually think quit
Speaker 1:  books quickly and without feeling bad about it might
Speaker 1:  be the best tip. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  I like, I it just, I mean here's the thing, like a lot of
Speaker 10:  stuff, especially if you're reading fiction like, or books that are like
Speaker 10:  a little more challenging, there's also quite challenging nonfiction. You
Speaker 10:  know, If you read the Power Broker, like you're gonna
Speaker 10:  have to get more than five pages in before you decide to quit, you know,
Speaker 10:  I think Sure. But I think you should just set like pretty clear
Speaker 10:  thresholds for yourself and I understand the idea of, you know,
Speaker 10:  you bought a book, you should finish it. I dunno, I just dunno if I subscribe
Speaker 10:  to that. 'cause one like it's nice to buy books, they're not that
Speaker 10:  expensive in the grand scheme of things. Especially you can buy used books
Speaker 10:  and then like two, you know, you're supporting an industry that could use
Speaker 10:  that support. And then three also there's always the library so you have
Speaker 10:  an unlimited stream of free things that you can be reading at any time.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, yeah. The other thing we should probably say here is that Libby, the
Speaker 1:  app is a wonderful thing that more people should take advantage of with the
Speaker 1:  library card. It is fabulous,
Speaker 10:  Just like a lot of things once you get that sucker set up, it works
Speaker 10:  like a dream, but it is a little bit fidget to set up. It is actually like
Speaker 10:  a lot of reading stuff is fidgety to set up. For example, you know,
Speaker 10:  I'm a Book's Palmer Convert because of you. So I do read on a,
Speaker 10:  on an e Ink device that is phone sized, which I, which I like quite a lot.
Speaker 1:  How do you like the Palmer, you were, you were apprehensive when you first
Speaker 1:  were thinking about getting it and we haven't really talked about it since
Speaker 1:  you got it. What do you think?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I, I know I, I quite like it. I think just on principle one, the
Speaker 10:  thing is still too expensive. It's, it's like nuts that it's what,
Speaker 10:  $200 or whatever,
Speaker 1:  It's at least twice as expensive as it should be.
Speaker 10:  And it really is like pretty crummy hardware and software like through
Speaker 10:  and through it is just a clever form factor that works and it just mostly
Speaker 10:  works. And yeah, once I got kind of some of the settings
Speaker 10:  figured out, like I had to go to Reddit for some good defaults. But yeah,
Speaker 10:  I use this thing every day, although I run into software
Speaker 10:  bugs on it all the time, it's like weird to side load things onto it. I
Speaker 10:  dunno if you're having this issue, like I feel like the plastic on my book's
Speaker 10:  Palma is like yellowing. Oh yeah. Just looks kind of disgusting.
Speaker 1:  There's a real like patina thing happening that I'm not wild about,
Speaker 1:  but
Speaker 10:  Patina is like the really generous way to describe what is happening to
Speaker 10:  the plastic on that phone. Fair. But yeah, I, so
Speaker 10:  it just felt like a weird amount of money to spend on something like
Speaker 10:  that. But that said, you know, I use it every day. So that thing has
Speaker 10:  amortized in value. Yeah. Big fan. Okay.
Speaker 1:  And I mean I've gotten, I, I really did not intend to
Speaker 1:  become like America's number one proponent of the book's Palmer a device
Speaker 1:  that I think has so, so, so many flaws.
Speaker 1:  But the question I get from people a lot is A, whether
Speaker 1:  they should buy that device and B, whether a dedicated reading
Speaker 1:  device is worth it at all. Right. And I think like the Kindle
Speaker 1:  is cheap enough that I think it, it kind of, it's,
Speaker 1:  people don't worry about it the same way. Like the base kindle's like 60
Speaker 1:  bucks and you can often find it on sale. Like that's not a, a sort of
Speaker 1:  investment in reading the way that like a Book's Palm is an investment in
Speaker 1:  reading like thing's almost $300. It's very expensive and the bet you're
Speaker 1:  making is like, I'm going to have this with me a lot and it is going to be
Speaker 1:  a device that I use on purpose. And I wonder, especially coming from the
Speaker 1:  way you're thinking about it, which is that like the way to read more is
Speaker 1:  to not be precious about it and to have it around all the time and to have
Speaker 1:  lots of books going at a time that you can just kind of flit in and out of
Speaker 1:  as you have moments if the idea of having a
Speaker 1:  dedicated reading device is actually maybe pulling you
Speaker 1:  away from some of the things that might make you read more.
Speaker 10:  That's a great question. I also just wanna say that like your average Kindle
Speaker 10:  device that's like cerebral years old is probably a better piece of hardware
Speaker 10:  than the books Palm.
Speaker 1:  Oh, unquestionably. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  But obviously If you wanna be slightly more of a power user and side
Speaker 10:  load things, like I was saying, I'm like reading PDFs of books that are
Speaker 10:  out print, things like that. Yeah. Then yeah, like the books Palma is
Speaker 10:  pretty great for that. I dunno, I I I say this like I've been such a snob
Speaker 10:  this whole time about like, oh it's so easy to read. I have all these systems,
Speaker 10:  but no, it's like still easy for me to get distracted on my phone. So
Speaker 10:  I do like having the Palma for that reason. Like just
Speaker 10:  nothing even, you know, even on Do Not Disturb mode, you're just like, well
Speaker 10:  let me just check my email. And then, yeah, the Palma is so funny
Speaker 10:  because it just like the suckiness of the os and the slowness of
Speaker 10:  it and the jenness of everything else, it just like, you are not gonna wanna
Speaker 10:  do anything else on that phone except read Buster, you know?
Speaker 1:  Truly. Yeah. So
Speaker 10:  I like idea.
Speaker 1:  So I think the badness is the, is the point. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 10:  And you know, like I'm not, I know we call them like dumb phones or whatever.
Speaker 10:  I don't know, I don't know if I like prescribe to all of that necessarily,
Speaker 10:  but I can just say like personally I have read
Speaker 10:  quite a lot on the books Palma and I enjoy that experience and I use this
Speaker 10:  device far more than I thought I would. I I got it in a lark 'cause like
Speaker 10:  my tax return came in and I was just like, yeah, I guess I trust David
Speaker 10:  enough to spend $200 or whatever. And
Speaker 10:  yeah, it pains me to say, you are right.
Speaker 1:  I mean I really, I appreciate that my legacy is this crappy
Speaker 1:  gadget that is nevertheless like the thing we need in our lives. I feel good
Speaker 1:  about that. I love that
Speaker 10:  You're like your best, like, you're like your legacy is like pushing like
Speaker 10:  a seven out of 10 device on the world.
Speaker 1:  Seriously. Great. I'm, I'm happy to have helped.
Speaker 1:  Last thing and then I'll let you go. I'm curious, you're also an author,
Speaker 1:  you've written, you've written one book that's very good and you just wrote
Speaker 1:  another that I think is like just about to come out, right?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's out in April.
Speaker 1:  Okay. What's it called? Tell the People.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's called My Documents. It's a novel. So, you know,
Speaker 10:  it's funny, it's, I'm like three months out and I'm still having a hard
Speaker 10:  time describing it accurately. But the plot is,
Speaker 10:  it imagines a bunch of, well imagines a world where a not too distant
Speaker 10:  world where the US decides to lock up
Speaker 10:  incarcerate all Vietnamese Americans kind of as an echo of Japanese
Speaker 10:  incarceration, which happened in World War ii. The weird thing when I
Speaker 10:  talk about this is it makes the book sound like really
Speaker 10:  bleak. A lot of the book is like Zoomers trying to like
Speaker 10:  live their life without the internet while they're in camp. So it's like
Speaker 10:  also kind of funny.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 10:  Like it. It's like, I think very quietly or maybe not so quietly a tech
Speaker 10:  novel. So,
Speaker 1:  Okay, I like it. You are like,
Speaker 1:  you spend your day job thinking about like how people read digital things
Speaker 1:  on the internet and then you write books. And I'm curious like,
Speaker 1:  especially as somebody who has like, thought this deeply about how we read
Speaker 1:  and how we consume this stuff and how technology is part of all of this.
Speaker 1:  Like, do you think about what, how people are going to read your book
Speaker 1:  when you're writing a book? Like is, are you like, this is a book that you
Speaker 1:  should buy and print and read with covers and fancy whiskey? Or are you like
Speaker 1:  sitting there being like, okay, I have to make the chapters shorter because
Speaker 1:  somebody's gonna be reading this on the subway on the way to work.
Speaker 10:  It's a little bit less like imagining where people are or what device
Speaker 10:  they'll be on when they're reading, but we both have like
Speaker 10:  backgrounds in print magazines and I think there's a way of thinking
Speaker 10:  about the reader or the audience when you work in print for some reason,
Speaker 10:  especially If you work on features. You know, these stories are like five
Speaker 10:  to 10,000 words at times and there's just sort of this sense like
Speaker 10:  you just kind of wanna keep things pretty dynamic. Like you just don't want
Speaker 10:  like long chunks of exposition, right? Like you wanna move from like
Speaker 10:  scenes to dialogue to exposition and back and
Speaker 10:  you know, you get to think about like layout in a magazine. You don't really
Speaker 10:  get to do that in a book. But I think that was like in my brain as I was
Speaker 10:  writing. Like I just wanted, I just like wanted things to feel active.
Speaker 10:  There's like lots of different textures and actually I, I kept
Speaker 10:  all the chapters pretty short as well. So it was like a little Dan Brown
Speaker 10:  in me I guess.
Speaker 1:  Are you non precious as an author? Like when somebody sends you a, a photo
Speaker 1:  of themselves, like reading your book on a, on a crowded
Speaker 1:  subway, are you like that's not the right way to read new waves?
Speaker 10:  No, no. I would be delighted. I, well I am
Speaker 10:  delighted anytime that happens, I still have yet to see anyone
Speaker 10:  reading my book like out in the wild. That's like kind of a
Speaker 10:  dream scenario for me. Totally. I've definitely had friends like
Speaker 10:  send me photos of people like creep shotting on the subway
Speaker 10:  and I dunno about the ethics of creep shotting, but please keep sending
Speaker 10:  me those. I appreciate it.
Speaker 1:  I like it. Okay, last thing and then truly I'm done with you. Do you honestly
Speaker 1:  read books during commercial breaks? Is that a, you, you wrote this GQ article
Speaker 1:  a bunch of years ago and that was one of the things you said and the article's
Speaker 1:  very good and I'll link to it in the show notes and I think the advice like
Speaker 1:  really holds up even all these years later and it's some of the stuff we've
Speaker 1:  talked about, but you just say very casually that you read books during commercial
Speaker 1:  breaks, which is like unhinged to me and I'm, I'm very
Speaker 1:  curious about this. Do you really do that?
Speaker 10:  I really do do this. It's funny, I was watching a little bit of the Australia
Speaker 10:  note open before we jumped on this call and
Speaker 10:  yeah like I forgot like it's actually imss, it's like hard to do it during
Speaker 10:  tennis 'cause commercial breaks are so much shorter. But like during an
Speaker 10:  NFL game there are so many goddamn ads and they're all for DraftKings
Speaker 10:  or Burger King. And so it just like, I don't know honestly, like
Speaker 10:  you might have to read during commercial breaks to like just press mute
Speaker 10:  for like your own fucking sanity. Yeah. But reading like
Speaker 10:  a book, you know, three or four minutes at a time and it's like how long
Speaker 10:  these ad breaks are. It's nuts. Yeah. And again, I, you know,
Speaker 10:  I'm usually reading on the phone and something kind of breezy and
Speaker 10:  likely nonfiction, So I really do do that. Maybe that's a little
Speaker 10:  bit too far advice wise for people, but
Speaker 1:  I kind of love it. I was actually thinking about it last night because I
Speaker 1:  was realizing that my instinct when there's like,
Speaker 1:  you know, I have three minutes of downtime when it's, whenever it's like,
Speaker 1:  you know, Anna pauses the movie to go into the kitchen and get something
Speaker 1:  or like it's commercials or whatever, I either open TikTok or Reddit
Speaker 1:  like a hundred percent of the time I realize it's one of those two apps because
Speaker 1:  it's like you, you can do it for any amount of time. It doesn't, it you can
Speaker 1:  just sort of open and close it and however long you're there is fine.
Speaker 1:  And I am, I, my goal is to replace that instinct with opening
Speaker 1:  the Kindle app. And I think that is like, that was my main takeaway from
Speaker 1:  thinking about this is like just the, the, I have three minutes right
Speaker 1:  now instead of opening one of those two apps, I'm gonna try to read
Speaker 1:  one page of a book and just see how far that gets me. And I think the alarming
Speaker 1:  thing is I think that's going to get me a lot further than I am
Speaker 1:  reckoning with because I think I spend a lot of time in TikTok that I don't
Speaker 1:  necessarily clock as time I'm spending in TikTok.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. So, you know, someone's told me recently that they deleted TikTok
Speaker 10:  from their phone and they only have it on their iPad, which seems kind of
Speaker 10:  nuts, but I kind of like, it's like, oh, you actually have to be a little
Speaker 10:  more deliberate when you open TikTok. I don't even know if they have a dedicated
Speaker 10:  iPad app. I almost hope it's like kind of the miniature when it gets like
Speaker 10:  blown up.
Speaker 1:  Just expanse. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Full width. Just like, oh actually just like Instagram. Right,
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 10:  But yeah, we should, we should check it in a few months and see if this
Speaker 10:  track works for you.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, well I'll, I'll keep you posted for sure. I feel like the first thing
Speaker 1:  I have to do is find the right phone book to start and then I'm
Speaker 1:  gonna see how long it takes me to get through it. But I'll, I'll keep you
Speaker 1:  posted. We'll keep talking.
Speaker 10:  Cool.
Speaker 1:  All right Kevin, thank you. Yeah, thanks for having me. It was a pleasure.
Speaker 1:  Good luck to everybody who wants to read more and If you have reading tips
Speaker 1:  send them to us. I would like to hear everybody's reading tips 'cause we're
Speaker 1:  all gonna read more this year. It's gonna be awesome. Thanks Kevin.
Speaker 10:  See you David.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we will be back with a question
Speaker 1:  from The Vergecast hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 1:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. We
Speaker 1:  love all of your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show
Speaker 1:  every week. I should say the hotline app
Speaker 1:  that we use got kind of broken for a few days there, so
Speaker 1:  it's possible that we missed some of your calls last week.
Speaker 1:  I'm hopeful that we didn't and we'll be able to get to them. But If you called
Speaker 1:  last week and asked a question, there's a chance we didn't get it. So
Speaker 1:  a I am sorry and b call again, I still wanna hear all of your questions and
Speaker 1:  hopefully this stupid app doesn't break again this week.
Speaker 1:  We have a question about audio.
Speaker 11:  Hi, my name's Dan. I got a weird one. I guess it's not that weird.
Speaker 11:  Why can't I listen to a podcast in music at the same time on my phone I
Speaker 11:  get like, you know, like 15 years ago when the iPhone was first coming
Speaker 11:  out, you could only have one stream going on at once 'cause there's a tiny
Speaker 11:  little operating system or whatever. But like at
Speaker 11:  this point, you know, I, I like to, you know, listen to quiet little lo-fi
Speaker 11:  beats a little little rain noises while I'm, while I'm doing stuff. And
Speaker 11:  I also kinda wanna listen to podcasts and I could do that on my PC really
Speaker 11:  easy. But like, can you even do that on iOS?
Speaker 11:  Surely at this point you can do that on iOS somehow,
Speaker 11:  right? Anyway, big, big fan. Have a great day. Bye.
Speaker 1:  Okay, this sent me down a very fun rabbit hole because actually this is
Speaker 1:  a thing I have wondered a lot about too, not because I want to do
Speaker 1:  the two audio sources thing at the same time, but because Apple
Speaker 1:  handles this terribly, like there are
Speaker 1:  the sources you want to have audio from, right? There's
Speaker 1:  whatever you use to listen to music, whatever you use to listen to podcasts.
Speaker 1:  For me that's Spotify and Pocket casts respectively. Then there's all the
Speaker 1:  streaming services which have, you know, audio and video. But then
Speaker 1:  you open a specific website or a certain app that is
Speaker 1:  not an audio first app and it just kind of
Speaker 1:  kills the audio that you're listening to. Like for me, the one that always
Speaker 1:  does it is the ESPN app. For whatever reason, the e ESP n app, as soon
Speaker 1:  as you open it before it even plays anything, just kind of takes
Speaker 1:  over the media player and says, actually, I am now the source of audio.
Speaker 1:  It's just terrible Software. Like this is poorly put together and poorly
Speaker 1:  written. And I think the thing that I have learned in doing research about
Speaker 1:  this and talking to folks about this is it is purely Apple's decision to
Speaker 1:  do it this way. There is nothing technically that prevents
Speaker 1:  lots of audio sources all coming together on your phone. I kind of
Speaker 1:  get the idea. I think in general, most of the time you
Speaker 1:  only wanna be listening to one thing at a time. And like, you know that thing
Speaker 1:  where you have a background tab in your browser that just
Speaker 1:  starts playing audio out of nowhere and you can't figure out where it is
Speaker 1:  and it's super annoying. That kind of thing would be even worse
Speaker 1:  on your phone because a, it might just start playing in the background while
Speaker 1:  your phone is locked, like it's in your pocket making noise and that sucks.
Speaker 1:  You'd have a much harder time finding where things are and where
Speaker 1:  they're playing audio because there aren't such good controls for that
Speaker 1:  stuff in the system. So there's not just like a where is playing audio screen
Speaker 1:  that you can go and open and do that. So I, I get the principle here,
Speaker 1:  but I think Apple either needs to force its
Speaker 1:  developers to do this better or make it easier
Speaker 1:  for users to mess with. Because the other thing that'll happen is like if
Speaker 1:  you're listening to a podcast and then you open up
Speaker 1:  TikTok, TikTok will start playing and it will, you know,
Speaker 1:  drop the podcast audio out. But then If you pause TikTok, the podcast
Speaker 1:  audio just comes back in a way that is very kind of chaotic and
Speaker 1:  I think is like bad ui. So these things are just poorly handled and to some
Speaker 1:  extent I'm almost like, just give me a thing that is like, here is all the
Speaker 1:  audio playing. You're in charge. Do whatever you want with the video of it.
Speaker 1:  You can actually do something like that on Android. If you use
Speaker 1:  a Samsung phone, there's an app called Sound Assistant that actually gives
Speaker 1:  you some of that control over multiple sources of audio, where
Speaker 1:  it's coming from, where it's going and you can route everything a little
Speaker 1:  bit better. It's, it's hacky. And again, it's the kind of thing that you
Speaker 1:  don't need most of the time. Most of the time you just wanna be listening
Speaker 1:  to one thing. I think that is a reasonable assumption for all of these companies
Speaker 1:  to make, but they should give you more controls. And also,
Speaker 1:  I know how Apple should fix this. It's so simple to me. There should be
Speaker 1:  an app on every Apple device that is called now playing.
Speaker 1:  If you've ever used CarPlay, you, you've seen the thing called now playing.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's the triangle play icon. It's with lines, it is the it, it
Speaker 1:  whatever is playing. It shows up in now playing and you tap on that thing
Speaker 1:  and it shows you the audio that's playing and you can play it or pause it,
Speaker 1:  whatever. That should be an app that exists on your phone and it should be
Speaker 1:  all of the audio sources available to you at any given time, right? So like
Speaker 1:  I think about it sort of like clipboard history where it just saves
Speaker 1:  all the stuff you've copied and then you can go back through and be like,
Speaker 1:  oh, paste that one now and paste that one now. But instead it would be audio
Speaker 1:  history. It's like, oh, okay, you were watching and listening to
Speaker 1:  30 Rock. Would you like to have the audio of that playing in
Speaker 1:  the background while you're doing something else? Or, you know, play your
Speaker 1:  podcast while you're looking at some media
Speaker 1:  player, but I actually just wanna see the video on mute and keep listening
Speaker 1:  to my podcast. This is a thing people should be able to choose. And I think
Speaker 1:  we, we live in a world now where actually so much video and
Speaker 1:  audio is now foregrounded in all of these apps that
Speaker 1:  I think this idea that actually you only wanna listen to one thing and
Speaker 1:  that thing is probably also the thing that you're looking at is just not
Speaker 1:  correct. So I I what, what I've come to
Speaker 1:  after doing a lot of research on this is that Apple picked a reasonable way
Speaker 1:  to do this. To say you're only gonna get one audio source at a time
Speaker 1:  and it is going to be sort of the last audio source that you encountered
Speaker 1:  Reasonable assumption
Speaker 1:  17 years ago. I think it's the wrong assumption now. And I think
Speaker 1:  one interesting thing that needs to happen on a lot of these devices is they're
Speaker 1:  gonna have to get much smarter about inputs and outputs. I mean, especially
Speaker 1:  you think about something like smart glasses. If, if they can't
Speaker 1:  dynamically and intelligently figure out what you wanna be listening to
Speaker 1:  at any given time, they're gonna fall apart. That's the kind of thing that
Speaker 1:  you can't do easily yourself. And if it's
Speaker 1:  choosing for you and it's picking the wrong thing at the wrong time,
Speaker 1:  that's gonna be a bad experience. So I think the way that these systems handle
Speaker 1:  audio is actually going to get more important and more complicated
Speaker 1:  over time. And the answer I am increasingly convinced is
Speaker 1:  just to give us a little tiny bit of chaos. If I wanna listen to music and
Speaker 1:  a podcast and a show at the same time, I believe that I should be able to,
Speaker 1:  I don't think that I should, I think that's kind of bonkers, but I think
Speaker 1:  I should be able to, and that is my official stance. Give me a now
Speaker 1:  playing app that just shows me all of the audio from everywhere on my phone
Speaker 1:  and let me figure it out except for browser tabs, because if we get to the
Speaker 1:  point where things get to do the like lazy loading audio that starts playing
Speaker 1:  five minutes after you load a browser tab, that's a nightmare. So
Speaker 1:  none of that in the browser. Let my, let my apps do some weird stuff.
Speaker 1:  Well, I'll figure it out. Anyway, that is it for The Vergecast today, by
Speaker 1:  the way. If you have tips on how to make the audio stuff make more sense
Speaker 1:  both on Android and on an iPhone, I am all ears. I know there's
Speaker 1:  a way you can jailbreak an iPhone and get more
Speaker 1:  control over the audio sources. That's actually one way. I know the phones
Speaker 1:  are capable of doing it in theory, but I don't think most people wanna jailbreak
Speaker 1:  their phone. But If you figured out some clever hack for how to manage all
Speaker 1:  the audio on your phone, let me know. I'm all ears. 8 6 6 VERGE one, one
Speaker 1:  Vergecast at diverse.com. Thank you to everybody who came on the show and
Speaker 1:  thank you as always for listening. Like I said, we're gonna talk a bunch
Speaker 1:  more about the world in TikTok Bands and politics and Inaugurations on
Speaker 1:  Friday show. And then honestly, it is my sincere hope
Speaker 1:  that we are not going to have to keep doing that. I think we are, we are
Speaker 1:  in a very political moment full of a lot of change and a lot of
Speaker 1:  new ways that the tech industry is going to exist, particularly in the United States.
Speaker 1:  And we're gonna talk about it in the ways that it makes sense. But I think
Speaker 1:  we're gonna try not to make this a podcast about politics because
Speaker 1:  we don't want that and I know you don't either.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, there's lots more on everything we covered here@thebir.com. I'll
Speaker 1:  link to Kevin's GQ story that I really liked. I'll link to a bunch of Jacobs
Speaker 1:  reporting. I'll link to our reporting on venue. All of it in the
Speaker 1:  show notes on the website, keep it locked. News is nuts.
Speaker 1:  And as always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or again audio
Speaker 1:  tips for me, you can always email us at Vergecast at VERGE dot com. Call
Speaker 1:  the hotline eight six six VERGE one one. We truly love hearing from you.
Speaker 1:  This show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  is The Verge Production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli.
Speaker 1:  And I'll be back on Friday to talk about, like I said, the inauguration,
Speaker 1:  the TikTok ban, more AI news. There's a Samsung event
Speaker 1:  this week. Then we're gonna get to talk about gadgets, which I'm very excited
Speaker 1:  about. Lots to do. We will see you then. Rock and roll.