# Transcript
ID: c1996a93-28af-421b-b0a4-4eea0af33fff
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4062734718519752988/-3565128663187321783/s93290-US-5747s-1742896747.mp3
Description: Some products are so successful they become snynonymous with their whole category — nobody asks for a facial tissue, they ask for a Kleenex, you know? Today's episode is, at least in part, about two of those products. First, The Verge's Jennifer Pattison Tuohy joins the show to chart the rise and fall of the Roomba, the robot vacuum that practically invented the category and yet seems to have been left behind. Can iRobot get its robot back on its feet? After that, Kobo CEO Michael Tamblyn discusses the state of e-readers, what it's like to always be "the best non-Amazon option," and what we all want from devices that aren't our smartphone. Finally, The Verge's Chris Welch helps us answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11, or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about which TV you should buy in 2025. It's a complicated question, but there are answers.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the E Inc. Tech Stack.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am currently spending my morning going
Speaker 1:  around my basement putting little tiny pieces of electrical tape
Speaker 1:  on all of the glowing lights in this room. So my parents were here this
Speaker 1:  weekend and there are just lights everywhere.
Speaker 1:  I discovered this is the guest room where people sleep. And I realized that
Speaker 1:  even when you turn off all the lights in this room, there's stuff just
Speaker 1:  glowing everywhere. Like I have computer speakers that have this
Speaker 1:  really unnecessarily bright green light. I have the thing that
Speaker 1:  I plug my mic and headphones into, and it has
Speaker 1:  one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine
Speaker 1:  different things illuminated right now. Why? I have a
Speaker 1:  Meta Quest three back there that I think has five lights that are on at all
Speaker 1:  times. My TV glows when it's off for no reason.
Speaker 1:  Thank you TCL for that terrible decision. There's just a lot of
Speaker 1:  lights and I think that is bad. And so I'm going around
Speaker 1:  and just putting little tiny pieces of tape on every single one that I can
Speaker 1:  find, and we're gonna put darkness back in this room and I'm very excited
Speaker 1:  about it. And also, if you're a product maker and you find yourself at some
Speaker 1:  point being like, oh, should I have a green light on this? That glows
Speaker 1:  24 hours a day? The answer is no. Just just stop it. Go find
Speaker 1:  something else to do. That is, that is the only thing I have learned is that
Speaker 1:  you don't need the green lights and we can all move on with our lives anyway.
Speaker 1:  We are not here on The Vergecast to talk about lights, at least not more
Speaker 1:  than you know we normally do. On this podcast today, we're gonna do two things.
Speaker 1:  First, we're gonna talk to Jen Tui about the story of iRobot and
Speaker 1:  the Roomba, because in a certain way, that story has come to an end and
Speaker 1:  it's been a really interesting one and we're gonna talk through as much of
Speaker 1:  it as we can. Then I'm gonna talk to Michael Tamlin, who is the CEO of Cobo
Speaker 1:  about EIN and e-readers and what people
Speaker 1:  want from a device that isn't their smartphone. I really enjoyed talking
Speaker 1:  to Michael and I think you'll enjoy hearing it. We also have a really fun
Speaker 1:  hotline question. Lots to get to. So much going on.
Speaker 1:  News continues to be nuts, but we're gonna have some fun today. All that
Speaker 1:  is coming up in just a second, but first, I'm sure there's like 85 more lights
Speaker 1:  and so I have more electrical taping to do. This is The Vergecast, we'll
Speaker 1:  be right back.
Speaker 1:  March 11th says, iRobot launches eight new Roombas and finally adds
Speaker 1:  LIDAR mapping. Great, exciting. Cool. We love a new robot vacuum.
Speaker 1:  The next day, like 17 hours later, iRobot tells
Speaker 1:  investors its future is in doubt. How? How? How does that make
Speaker 1:  sense? How do you put these two stories next to each other? iRobot making
Speaker 1:  RUS forever super successful. Biggest name in the whole space. It is the
Speaker 1:  thing everybody calls all the other devices. It's the, it's the Kleenex or
Speaker 1:  the Google of robot vacuums. And yet iRobot
Speaker 1:  is, is falling apart. This company can't keep up anymore.
Speaker 1:  How did this happen? How did we get here? And how is it this company
Speaker 1:  that both set this market off to what it is and doesn't seem to
Speaker 1:  be able to keep up? Jen Tuy wrote both of those articles that I just read
Speaker 1:  the headlines of and she is gonna help me dig into
Speaker 1:  the history of this company and how it all went wrong.
Speaker 1:  So let's get into it. Jen Chewy, welcome to the show.
Speaker 7:  Hello. Happy to be here.
Speaker 1:  I don't know if we're here to do like a, a funeral for the Roomba
Speaker 1:  or A-A-A-A-A retrospective or like a
Speaker 1:  celebration of life or a something, but I wanna, I wanna talk about Roomba,
Speaker 1:  which I feel like is, is going through
Speaker 1:  a bit of a challenging time right now after a very long, and I
Speaker 1:  would say epic run of being a really fascinating
Speaker 1:  gadget. But it's tough times in Roomba land right now.
Speaker 7:  It is. It's been, it's been a hard week. Well, an exciting week and then
Speaker 7:  a hard week last week where they launched a bunch of new robots
Speaker 7:  and then the next day said, we might go out of business. So it was kind of
Speaker 7:  like one of those woof
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's a real shot chaser moment there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So it's it and it's sad. It's sad times. I mean, I remember buying,
Speaker 7:  I think when I've moved into my first home, I, a long time ago
Speaker 7:  we got a rumor and I was so excited and so I've had rumors in my life
Speaker 7:  for decades and yeah, they're still in my life. They're not gone
Speaker 7:  yet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So let, let's just start at the very beginning before there
Speaker 1:  was the Roomba, there was the company that made the Roomba
Speaker 1:  called iRobot. But if I understand correctly, this company did not like set
Speaker 1:  out to build vacuums. Like what was iRobot before?
Speaker 1:  It was the Roomba company?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so they originally were founded, so actually it's a
Speaker 7:  Silicon Valley tale that based in Massachusetts. Mm,
Speaker 7:  okay. So they are f it was founded by 3M IT
Speaker 7:  grads. They were grad students, I believe when they actually founded it.
Speaker 7:  So they were roboticists, it was Colin Angle, Helen
Speaker 7:  Greener and Rodney Brooks. And it was, it was founded in
Speaker 7:  1990. Oh wow. And you're right, the idea wasn't, they weren't even
Speaker 7:  thinking about vacuums for your house at the time. They were basically
Speaker 7:  trying to sort of start making robots of any type because in the nineties
Speaker 7:  we didn't really have, you know, beyond maybe dishwashers and washing
Speaker 7:  machines that we didn't have robots in our home. But there also
Speaker 7:  weren't a lot of really single purpose interesting robots in
Speaker 7:  spaces that could use them. So they were kind of looking to fill gaps
Speaker 7:  with building robots that could help specifically in areas
Speaker 7:  where people can't go or don't want to go. I mean, they were a startup,
Speaker 7:  most of their original robots were developed in partnership with different
Speaker 7:  organizations. So they worked with NASA and actually helped develop the
Speaker 7:  original Miles Rover. They worked with the US government,
Speaker 7:  darpa, to develop a stair climbing robot
Speaker 7:  that could go into, into rubble, into
Speaker 7:  places that humans couldn't go try and help. You know, things like
Speaker 7:  bum disposal, hazmat, search and rescue. Oh wow. Those types of things where
Speaker 7:  having a robot put them in a dangerous situation that would be better than
Speaker 7:  putting a human in. So they did a lot of really interesting things.
Speaker 7:  Again, startups. So they were working with organizations that could help
Speaker 7:  fund them. So they spent about 12 years building robots for the military,
Speaker 7:  law enforcement, energy sector, industrial cleaning, even some
Speaker 7:  toys.
Speaker 1:  And this is in the nineties, so like way ahead of the game on a lot of this
Speaker 7:  Way ahead of the game. Okay. Yes, exactly. And really they were
Speaker 7:  very, very innovative. I mean, none of these robots were, and actually this
Speaker 7:  was something that Colin Angle, the CEO was kind of quite specific
Speaker 7:  about. He was never trying to build the humanoid robot. He was,
Speaker 7:  they were always trying to build a purpose robot like a
Speaker 7:  robot to solve a problem or to, to come, you know, be
Speaker 7:  able to do something that humans didn't want to or shouldn't
Speaker 7:  do.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. Wait, that's very funny because I think the, the Rosie
Speaker 1:  the robot comparison to Roomba in particular from, you know,
Speaker 1:  Rosie, the robot from the Jetsons, this is like everybody's idea of the
Speaker 1:  like robot helper around the house. And I feel like that has been put next
Speaker 1:  to Roomba for as long as I can remember. But
Speaker 1:  you're telling me that's not ever what actually they were trying to build?
Speaker 7:  No, in fact, when I was doing some research for today, I was, I found
Speaker 7:  some old interviews and, and they, iRobot specifically
Speaker 7:  said the idea of trying to build a humanoid
Speaker 7:  robot that would push a vacuum around is just so
Speaker 7:  difficult. Like, huh. It's just not really realistic and it'd be so
Speaker 7:  expensive. Which we've all, and we've seen this 30 years later and
Speaker 7:  the sort of nascent attempts of humanoid robots that the concept
Speaker 7:  is just not that viable. And even if some, even if you
Speaker 7:  can build it, which you can, 'cause we've seen humanoid robots, you know,
Speaker 7:  your average American consumer isn't gonna be spending, you know,
Speaker 7:  $15,000 if on a robot to,
Speaker 7:  to push a vacuum around their house. It makes much more sense to take
Speaker 7:  technology and solve a specific problem, such as floor cleaning.
Speaker 7:  And, and this is where they, so actually they first started in
Speaker 7:  the floor cleaning realm. They had an engineer, his name was
Speaker 7:  Joe Jones, who's also from MIT, who had been tinkering with
Speaker 7:  developing a floor sweeping robot for years. His original prototype
Speaker 7:  before he started working for iRobot was built from Legos. Oh wow. So,
Speaker 7:  but he'd been with them for a while and he was like, Hey, I've got this idea.
Speaker 7:  And they formed, they had already started working with a couple companies
Speaker 7:  to try and build automatic floor sweeping robots in
Speaker 7:  like warehouses. You know, again, solving a problem. Like we have this,
Speaker 7:  this large space, we need it cleaned and it costs a lot to hire a person
Speaker 7:  to do it. So if we could build a robot, we, you know, so they had been working
Speaker 7:  on that partnership with SC Johnson I think it was,
Speaker 7:  and then that didn't work out, but they ended up working with a few different
Speaker 7:  companies who sort of helped them focus in and
Speaker 7:  then realize actually this is what we can do. We can build a small
Speaker 7:  circular disc that just rolls around your house and sucks
Speaker 7:  up dirt and, which is apparently a much more complicated and
Speaker 7:  difficult thing to do than it sounds. So it took them a while. But yeah,
Speaker 7:  eventually in 2002, so 12 years after
Speaker 7:  first founding the company, they launched the first
Speaker 7:  consumer robot vacuum in the us. There had
Speaker 7:  been one prior in the U in Europe from Electrolux,
Speaker 7:  but it didn't last long. And then, yeah, the sort of, the main thing it
Speaker 7:  featured was bump sensors. So basically it would bump around your house
Speaker 7:  if you everyone remembers. I mean some of them still do that and cliff
Speaker 7:  sensors so that it wouldn't throw itself down the stairs or off a balcony
Speaker 7:  and Yeah. That, that was, and that was only $200
Speaker 7:  in 2002. Oh wow.
Speaker 1:  I assumed it was gonna be like three grand. Yeah, those first
Speaker 7:  Ones interesting. I mean that's what, that was the push really. This has
Speaker 7:  to be a consum robot, a consumable so that people can afford it.
Speaker 7:  Although the next one, and I think the one I ended up buying got a lot more
Speaker 7:  expensive. I'm not really sure what happened in between.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, Roombas haven't been $200 in a very long time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So they, that was sort of the entry into the market and
Speaker 7:  it was very successful.
Speaker 1:  Part of the reason I'm so fascinated by Roomba is like, It is, It is the
Speaker 1:  Kleenex of this space, right? Like everybody calls all the other ones Roombas.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think that has been true, certainly for as long as
Speaker 1:  I can remember and have been paying attention to this space. So like did
Speaker 1:  iRobot get that just by being first and having a cool product name? Or was
Speaker 1:  it like, did they invent something sort of spectacular
Speaker 1:  and new that made this thing amazing From the very beginning?
Speaker 7:  They did invent technology that had never been invented before. Okay.
Speaker 7:  So yes. And, and they did something very smart, which I'm sure most companies
Speaker 7:  do, but they patented everything. Mm. So
Speaker 7:  they have like thousands of patents, patents, patents,
Speaker 7:  sorry, my US English, UK English, going back and forth. We'll allow it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So they, and they, they have one patent in particular that was
Speaker 7:  basically for the entire robot vacuum system that Oh,
Speaker 7:  okay. That really meant, that was one of the reasons why we did not see
Speaker 7:  a lot of competition for a long time. They actually
Speaker 7:  very fierce, fiercely enforced those patents as well. So
Speaker 7:  they were, they had a lot, they had has had some competition come along,
Speaker 7:  but they either, you know, were sort of shot down or got
Speaker 7:  bought.
Speaker 1:  One of the questions I had for you was like, why did all the competition
Speaker 1:  take so long to appear? I, is that the answer that
Speaker 1:  essentially I robot manage to own the idea of a
Speaker 1:  robot vacuum for a long time?
Speaker 7:  I think so. I mean, I'm not a patent law expert, but it does seem
Speaker 7:  that that is sort of what, what happened. It took, I mean a lot of these
Speaker 7:  patents I think expired in the last few years, which is one reason why you've
Speaker 7:  seen a resurgence or you see more and more robots arriving.
Speaker 7:  I, I did find a really interesting anecdote, apparently
Speaker 7:  there was, it was sometime in like
Speaker 7:  2020, there was a, my
Speaker 7:  Genie was a, a Chinese company that had a robot that they launched
Speaker 7:  and it enforced its patents and it sued them. And apparently people
Speaker 7:  came and ripped the robots off the show floor at
Speaker 7:  efa. Whoa. Once they'd won the patent battle because yeah,
Speaker 7:  they really did enforce it, you know, and okay, fair enough.
Speaker 7:  It's their intellectual property and people were copying them and you can
Speaker 7:  see people have copied them. If you look today at all the robots out there,
Speaker 7:  they all look basically like Roombas. They, no one's
Speaker 7:  really come up with a brand new design. There is a company we've
Speaker 7:  covered called Matt that has sort of come up with a, a, a new
Speaker 7:  look for the robot vacuum and a new, it has different
Speaker 7:  technology uses entirely camera based. And it, it
Speaker 7:  actually looks like has one of those like, looks like a pro, a
Speaker 7:  traditional vacuum in the front. Like it has a little head that it pushes
Speaker 7:  around. But yeah, things, I mean, shark, ninja,
Speaker 7:  Dyson, Samsung, they all came out with, if you look at
Speaker 7:  those, their, their robot vacuums are, are different looking than all the
Speaker 7:  big companies. You're, you might be used to seeing like Robo rock and Ecova
Speaker 7:  because they, I think deliberately had to design around
Speaker 7:  avoiding iRobots patents. That's why we have those, those
Speaker 7:  products came out looking a little different. Like the first Samsung one
Speaker 7:  looked like a, a storm trooper.
Speaker 1:  Oh I remember that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And the Dyson ones are very unique and very purple.
Speaker 7:  And then Nito was the other one and it came out with a square
Speaker 7:  robot, which actually makes more sense when you think
Speaker 7:  about trying to get into corners. But I've heard from many people that square
Speaker 7:  robots have significant navigation issues. And that is something I personally
Speaker 7:  experienced when testing a nito. And then sadly Nito went out of business
Speaker 7:  a few few years ago. It was another US based
Speaker 7:  company and it very much suffered, I think from a lot of the same market
Speaker 7:  pressures that iRobot has suffered from. But iRobot was in a much stronger
Speaker 7:  position to deal with those for longer than I think
Speaker 7:  Nito was, unfortunately.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So let, let's talk about those market pressures actually. 'cause I
Speaker 1:  think that's kind of the next, that turn in the Roomba story, right? It
Speaker 1:  it's sort of won the market. It was the market for
Speaker 1:  like, I don't, 10 years maybe. Yeah. Somewhere up to
Speaker 1:  almost 10 years I'm thinking like, I don't know, 2010 ish.
Speaker 1:  I feel like it was, it was the Roomba's world and we all just lived in it.
Speaker 1:  And then kind of slowly and then all at once this, this
Speaker 1:  market went from just room the Roomba
Speaker 1:  to, oh my God, look at all of these robot vacuums.
Speaker 1:  Yes. What, what happened? How did that, where did that all come from?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, so just sort of from a robot's perspective, they
Speaker 7:  had decided to really focus just on consumer robots. So
Speaker 7:  they got rid of their military and exploratory
Speaker 7:  space arm. They sold that off and really focused on the
Speaker 7:  Roombas and produced one or two new models
Speaker 7:  every year. Which at that time, you know, 20 this, you know, we're going
Speaker 7:  from like 20 13, 20 14, 20 15, 20 16. We, we
Speaker 7:  had a new one pretty much every year, each one improving on the last,
Speaker 7:  they added wifi in
Speaker 7:  20 13, 20 14, around there with the eight 80 and the
Speaker 7:  900 they added and the nine 80. They were,
Speaker 7:  the naming has never got better. Oh
Speaker 1:  I know. Terrible. It's so funny 'cause they, they nailed it with Roomba,
Speaker 1:  like Roomba unbelievably great name and then it all just fell apart.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So they added a lot of interesting technology. They were trying to
Speaker 7:  always make it better. I think kind of a pinnacle moment was like 2018 when
Speaker 7:  they introduced the I seven and this was the first one that could remember
Speaker 7:  where it had been. So it stopped just bouncing randomly
Speaker 7:  around your house. You actually would create a map for you so you
Speaker 7:  could send it to clean specific areas and specific rooms and didn't
Speaker 7:  get confused just 'cause you picked it up and moved it. I dunno if you've
Speaker 7:  ever had that experience with the robot vacuum. Oh yeah. But you put, you
Speaker 7:  pick it up 'cause it like, you know, ran into your shoe and then it's just
Speaker 7:  like, I don't know where I'm, save me.
Speaker 7:  So that, that was the I seven. And then they also introduced the auto empty
Speaker 7:  dock, which was a game changer.
Speaker 1:  Like, it, it, it really truly was. It was, I have, I have one of those
Speaker 1:  upstairs and that was the first time I was like, okay, I will spend whatever
Speaker 1:  it costs to get one of these things because now
Speaker 1:  I don't have to do any work. Nice. I just like every, every once in a while
Speaker 1:  I have to take the bag out and otherwise my, my floors are just fine.
Speaker 1:  Like, it really was life changing. That one innovation
Speaker 7:  That was when I came back to the Roomba because the one I had had, I
Speaker 7:  think in 2003 or oh four,
Speaker 7:  I would come home from work and it would've stopped somewhere and not made
Speaker 7:  it anywhere. And you had to buy the little towers to stop it from going certain
Speaker 7:  places and it was just too complicated unless you had like
Speaker 7:  nothing in your house. But then they just, you know,
Speaker 7:  they have done a lot to make the robot
Speaker 7:  actually, I mean they, they say their words are complete its mission. 'cause
Speaker 7:  that was, you know, it, it's a great technology but if it doesn't finish
Speaker 7:  what it started, it's becomes a frustrating technology. Yep.
Speaker 7:  So yes. So it, they had gradually been increasing
Speaker 7:  the development on the robot coming up with interesting new elements for
Speaker 7:  it starting to, IM implement AI machine learning.
Speaker 7:  I mean robot vacuums really are some of the beginnings of AI in the home,
Speaker 7:  which is an interesting maybe side note but, and then
Speaker 7:  by 2019 it had an estimated 88% market share. So I mean we're
Speaker 7:  talking Whoa. Completely dominant.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So that's even later than I expected. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It was still very Wow. Okay. Very dominant. And then
Speaker 7:  the pandemic was sort of like a double-edged sword
Speaker 7:  it, from what I understand, you know, I think by this point
Speaker 7:  it, you know, we'd sold something like 30 million robots. So that's a
Speaker 7:  significant number. Yeah. And like you say, it was the Kleenex, you know,
Speaker 7:  everyone referred to anything that rolled around your house and sucked up
Speaker 7:  dirt as a Roomba, whether wherever it came from. And then, you know, we were
Speaker 7:  starting to see Chinese competition come in. We still had a lot of
Speaker 7:  competition in America as well. Nito and Shark
Speaker 7:  Ninja and a couple others. And then pandemic hit
Speaker 7:  and there was this huge surge. 'cause remember we're all back home.
Speaker 7:  We're all our home. Sure. And we're all wanting to look after our home and
Speaker 7:  clean our home because we're spending all our time in our home. But also
Speaker 7:  you are all in, when you're in your home and your robot vacuum's running,
Speaker 7:  you're not a happy person. No. Because they can be really annoying.
Speaker 7:  So it was kind of a double-edged sword. And then the other thing that hit
Speaker 7:  it was the tariffs, which apparently they
Speaker 7:  had to pay millions of dollars in tariffs. So there was kind of like this
Speaker 7:  moment where they were doing really, really well and then suddenly they were
Speaker 7:  sort of squashed. And this was right around the time that the Chinese
Speaker 7:  manufacturers were really ramping up. And I, again, not,
Speaker 7:  I don't know the particulars of the patent law, but I think right around
Speaker 7:  this time too, there was some patents that had expired. So it was possible
Speaker 7:  for a lot of these manufacturers to come in and do very similar things
Speaker 7:  and for a lot less money. One thing Roomba didn't do
Speaker 7:  as it increased its technology and made its
Speaker 7:  mission complete was make prices cheaper.
Speaker 7:  There were never, like you said, I don't think, we never, we ever saw a $200
Speaker 7:  Roomba again until, I mean there was some of it's very low
Speaker 7:  end models you could get for around that price, but they didn't have mapping
Speaker 7:  that you still needed to buy a hundred dollars tower things to keep it out
Speaker 7:  of rooms. Yeah. I don't count that as a $200 Roomba. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That point. Yeah. It's just not worth it. So yeah. And then
Speaker 7:  we got, so Robo Rock arrived in the
Speaker 7:  US in 2018. Ecova had come along
Speaker 7:  a little bit before that. That's the dBot robots. And then, and then from
Speaker 7:  then on we just, like every month there was a new robot
Speaker 7:  vacuum manufacturer. We got dreamy, we had Shark Ninja
Speaker 7:  NARAL Anchor came out with their UFI brand. TP Link has their tap
Speaker 7:  brand now. I mean there there are, there are dozens of them. And also
Speaker 7:  Samsung has been working in this space too. So they just, there was
Speaker 7:  competition coming from all angles. And there is where,
Speaker 7:  I mean what went wrong, did they not innovate? Right? That's what people
Speaker 7:  say a lot. There was a key difference
Speaker 7:  between Roombas and all of the competition. And that was how
Speaker 7:  they navigated. So Roombas had developed a
Speaker 7:  technology for, so all robot vacuums use something called
Speaker 7:  simultaneous localization and mapping slam Roomba
Speaker 7:  used Vlam, which is visual, simultaneous location
Speaker 7:  localization and mapping. Okay. With a camera on the
Speaker 7:  top of the robot that looked up in the sky. And that's why you always had
Speaker 7:  to have the lights on when you ran your roombas a while ago. Oh sure.
Speaker 7:  And this was how they mapped and navigated your home. The new
Speaker 7:  manufacturers coming in or used lidar, which is again
Speaker 7:  the same technology, but not using cameras, using lasers.
Speaker 7:  Right. And it's just like, I mean it's like self-driving cars. And when Roomba
Speaker 7:  started that technology was really expensive. So I think they
Speaker 7:  looked for a different way to implement navigation.
Speaker 7:  But the market has very much shifted entirely to lidar. And
Speaker 7:  I would hear, I would always hear complaints from readers about why doesn't
Speaker 7:  Roomba have lidar? Why doesn't Roomba have lidar? And I think what started
Speaker 7:  to happen is that every other robot had it and Roomba didn't. And I think
Speaker 7:  a lot of people started to think, well I want the lidar, I want the
Speaker 7:  little tower. And so there was a kind of shift, I don't know if, I don't
Speaker 7:  personally agree that Lidar is better, but this could, that could be an
Speaker 7:  entirely an entire, whole podcast for sure. But
Speaker 7:  I, I actually think Roomba's mapping has got very, very good. It doesn't
Speaker 7:  get lost like a lot of the lidar robots don't do. And it doesn't try and
Speaker 7:  escape like a lot of the lidar radars do because they think
Speaker 7:  they use navigation. I said with lasers, so if it can
Speaker 7:  see out a door or out a window, it thinks that's a room.
Speaker 7:  And if you don't set the map to tell it not to go that way, it
Speaker 7:  will, it will jump the fence and go and just go off Oh boy.
Speaker 7:  Into the distance. Cool. So yeah, that and,
Speaker 7:  but that, that's definitely been an area where I think, I don't know if they
Speaker 7:  made the wrong choice there by not going with Lidar sooner.
Speaker 7:  Side note, there are new RO robots that came out last week or use
Speaker 7:  lidar. Oh, interesting. We'll get to that. Yeah. And then
Speaker 7:  they also, so one thing they were very insistent on,
Speaker 7:  and I talked to the CEO Colin Eng about this when these
Speaker 7:  products started to come out, was that the idea of a
Speaker 7:  combination robot vacuum and robot mop was like an
Speaker 7:  abomination. They said back to this single purpose idea,
Speaker 7:  they had a robot vacuum and they had a robot mop and they said, these work
Speaker 7:  really well together, buy them both. Let the robot vacuum and
Speaker 7:  then the robot mop. And in some ways that was a
Speaker 7:  good solution, more expensive. And the Bravo jet had
Speaker 7:  some issues, like it couldn't get over a transition that was like this high.
Speaker 7:  So if you had anything in your house, it wasn't gonna, any kind of transition
Speaker 7:  in your house, it was gonna be stuck in one room. And so it really stuck
Speaker 7:  to that idea for a long time as these other companies came in with these
Speaker 7:  dual purpose robots, which not great
Speaker 7:  initially at doing both of those things. So I think Roomba felt
Speaker 7:  like, well we were right, ours are better. Sure. But also yours are three
Speaker 7:  times the price, right? So this is where the market forces come
Speaker 7:  in. If you can get a robot vacuum that can mop for $400,
Speaker 7:  why would you buy two separate devices to do the same thing? So Right.
Speaker 7:  That's an area where they sort of fell down. I think that they were focusing
Speaker 7:  much more on the software than on the hardware. I think they felt like we've,
Speaker 7:  we've solved the hardware. Our vacuums are cleaning your house. Now
Speaker 7:  we're gonna make them do it better
Speaker 7:  by, by using software, by using things like AI powered
Speaker 7:  obstacle detection to avoid getting tripped up by cables and
Speaker 7:  pet poop and anything else that might be lying around your house. And that,
Speaker 7:  you know, that was a great innovation and now all the other robot manufacturers
Speaker 7:  have copied that and are working on that. But I still think
Speaker 7:  iRobot has the best in that class. They were also
Speaker 7:  working towards this kind of larger smart home vision. They
Speaker 7:  had bought a air purifier company, they were
Speaker 7:  working, I they released their iRobot os
Speaker 7:  they call it. So they had like an operating system for their robot vacuums
Speaker 7:  that gave all these extra levels of intelligence.
Speaker 7:  Things like dirt detect, carpet detect
Speaker 7:  things that just make the robot able to do more. But I
Speaker 7:  think that's, those are harder cells to a consumer who has to
Speaker 7:  sort of read through the fine print or really understand what the
Speaker 7:  benefit is of a dirt detect. I mean,
Speaker 7:  it's neat when the robot finds something that's like a pile of dirt
Speaker 7:  instead of just plowing through it. Like most will, it'll stop and go back
Speaker 7:  and forth and back and forth, you know, and that, that's what you want.
Speaker 7:  But again, versus a product that has
Speaker 7:  more bells and whistles, more visible bells and whistles
Speaker 7:  and higher suction power. And to be fair, I mean It is still
Speaker 7:  one of the dominant in the market except it's just that the, the pie
Speaker 7:  got a lot smaller. I mean his, it's slice of the pie got a lot
Speaker 7:  smaller. So the pie, you know, a lot more people came in and now it's like
Speaker 7:  13. And actually they just released one industry
Speaker 7:  analysis company released some statistics today to show that for the first
Speaker 7:  time Robo Rock is now globally has a
Speaker 7:  larger market share than iRobot. So just continuing that downward trend.
Speaker 7:  But back to my point is that Roomba has, I
Speaker 7:  think they focused very much like I said on the software
Speaker 7:  rather than developing the hardware. And then when they got caught behind
Speaker 7:  on the hardware side, they tried too little
Speaker 7:  too late with their dual, their combo mopping robots that came out.
Speaker 7:  They never really FI mean they, they were kind of ingenious. They have this
Speaker 7:  little auto robotic arm that lifts up
Speaker 7:  and scoots itself under the robot and goes and mops and then when
Speaker 7:  it hits a carpet, it lifts the ro the arm back up over the top of the robot.
Speaker 7:  Oh, that's cool. And vacuums and that's neat. But the, the mop is like
Speaker 7:  two millimeters wide.
Speaker 7:  So it's takes a really long time to mop a big downstairs
Speaker 7:  hardwood floor area compared to like the latest R robo rocks
Speaker 7:  or dreamies that have these giant spinning mop pads,
Speaker 7:  which as of last week Rumbas now have,
Speaker 7:  you can see a trend here
Speaker 1:  Trend. Yeah. So I, I do wanna get to what launched last week, but I think
Speaker 1:  there's one more piece of the transition here.
Speaker 1:  Take me through the, the Amazon iRobot saga quickly.
Speaker 7:  Yes. So about, so right around the time
Speaker 7:  iRobot was starting to see a drop in revenue
Speaker 7:  was starting to struggle a little bit and see a huge
Speaker 7:  pressure from the mark Chinese manufacturers and others entering the market.
Speaker 7:  So right after the pandemic really,
Speaker 1:  Was this right around the time you first had a house full of robot
Speaker 1:  vacuum? Yes. I tracked this by like how many vacuums are in the picture that
Speaker 1:  Jen posts in Slack. And I feel like that was right around the time. It's
Speaker 1:  like there are just a dozen of these running around Jen's living room. It
Speaker 7:  Is, It is. I, when the robot uprising happens, I
Speaker 7:  am the first go
Speaker 1:  A hundred percent. It's been so nice knowing you, but that's absolutely correct.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There are more robots than people in my house by a long
Speaker 7:  shot and pets more robots than people and pets. Although my newest
Speaker 7:  pet actually is starting to enjoy riding on them, which I'm so excited about.
Speaker 1:  Oh, you're, well then the, the one pet's fine king of the robots.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Then the rest of you are toes.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, so like around 2022 I think is when it first, when iRobot
Speaker 7:  actually first saw its dec a decline in
Speaker 7:  revenue and an operating loss. Okay. And so this was
Speaker 7:  when things started to go a little south. And I think, I don't know
Speaker 7:  exactly what's, you know, the timeline of, you know, how
Speaker 7:  long they'd been in talks. I mean Amazon and iRobot had always had quite
Speaker 7:  a close relationship. iRobot was one of the first companies to
Speaker 7:  successfully, and it did it very well implement Alexa voice
Speaker 7:  control. So they'd obviously been sort of partnering for a few years,
Speaker 7:  but it, it, I think it was 22 that
Speaker 7:  our robot was beginning to dip. And I can, I think you can imagine they were
Speaker 7:  like, well, you know, we've had a good run. We've been here almost 30
Speaker 7:  years. This is the time to kind of,
Speaker 7:  we need an an not an exit, but at least you know, we, we need
Speaker 7:  help to push to the next level. I think as I mentioned,
Speaker 7:  the hardware was an issue like developing and being able
Speaker 7:  to manufacture more impressive hardware. They,
Speaker 7:  they focused on the software, but they hadn't really pushed on the hardware
Speaker 7:  front. So they needed, I think they needed a cash injection. They had spent
Speaker 7:  so much time on r and d and a lot of their money went towards r and d.
Speaker 7:  But then you need the money, you need the capital to actually go out and
Speaker 7:  build this, this type of product. And sure, a natural partner for that
Speaker 7:  is a big multi-billion dollar corporation like
Speaker 7:  Amazon. Right. So, but then there was an awful lot of
Speaker 7:  concern when Amazon announced it was going to buy iRobot
Speaker 7:  that this would cause, well there were two big concerns. There was a privacy
Speaker 7:  concern and there was a regulatory concern
Speaker 7:  around whether this would kind of exterminate the
Speaker 7:  competition. My take is the competition was very
Speaker 7:  well established already and I don't, I mean iRobot had seen its
Speaker 7:  shared drop from, as we said, like almost 90% down to that.
Speaker 7:  I think at the point where iRobot, where Amazon was going to buy it was down
Speaker 7:  to like 33%. So it had taken a big
Speaker 7:  tumble even though it was still the market leader. Right. It was nowhere
Speaker 7:  near as dominant as it had been before.
Speaker 1:  And all signs were pointing to more competition, not less over
Speaker 7:  Time. Exactly. Yes. Yeah. I mean new robot, we so dreamy had just
Speaker 7:  entered the market in 2022 and that's now one of the top three.
Speaker 7:  So we've got or top four. So you've got Robo Rock, iRobot,
Speaker 7:  Ecova and Dreamy and then all the others. So yeah, it
Speaker 7:  was very much at a sort of tipping point for the company.
Speaker 7:  And I, Amazon came in with a
Speaker 7:  $1.7 billion deal, which
Speaker 7:  then for the next, I think it was almost two years until it actually
Speaker 7:  fell apart under regulatory scrutiny. And it took the, it was the
Speaker 7:  EU specifically that caused the biggest delay in this. And that
Speaker 7:  two years of not knowing where the company was going, I
Speaker 7:  think really put a toll on production
Speaker 7:  manufacture. They had to take out a $200 million loan.
Speaker 7:  They were really struggling and
Speaker 7:  without a clear path for the future. And then when the deal fell apart
Speaker 7:  is when everything kind of fell apart. The companies laid off almost half
Speaker 7:  its workforce. They had to the, the CEO Colin Eng,
Speaker 7:  he exited left and then they took over.
Speaker 7:  They had a new CEO come in. I think Colin Eng said this
Speaker 7:  when he, when he exited, he said, we need someone
Speaker 7:  here who knows how to turn around the company in a financial, from a
Speaker 7:  financial perspective. And that is what the new CEO has been doing
Speaker 7:  by stripping back all of their other focus. So they don't, they, they got
Speaker 7:  rid of all of the other elements that they had gone into in terms of
Speaker 7:  the air purifiers. They'd also tried to do a robot lawnmower. They got rid
Speaker 7:  of anything that wasn't focused on cleaning your home, cut back on
Speaker 7:  research and development. I mean, it was like they basically gutted the company
Speaker 7:  and just turned it to streamline on creating the
Speaker 7:  core product in the hope, I believe the understanding to sort of
Speaker 7:  bring its fortunes back. And this is where the new
Speaker 7:  product line has come from. So
Speaker 1:  I you've, you've traced two lines that I think are super interesting and
Speaker 1:  exactly land us on this recent announcement. 'cause on the one hand you have
Speaker 1:  Roomba, which was sort of, it was the thing and for a bunch of reasons
Speaker 1:  that I think were kind of the company's fault and kind of
Speaker 1:  outside of its control. Like the, the thing that happens where you get locked
Speaker 1:  up during two years of an acquisition that ultimately falls apart Yeah. Is
Speaker 1:  crushing. Yeah. Like we have seen companies go through it and It is hard
Speaker 1:  and It is there, there is only so much of it that you can actually do anything
Speaker 1:  about. But that's, so that's all happening. And meanwhile at the exact
Speaker 1:  same time, the rest of this market coming out of China and
Speaker 1:  elsewhere is growing faster than ever. The best is Yeah. Going totally wild.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like you're saying, every time you turn around, there's a new company
Speaker 1:  with any name you've never heard of selling you one of these things, new
Speaker 1:  ideas, new products, the market's growing really fast. And it
Speaker 1:  seems like basically iRobot hires a new CEO who turns around
Speaker 1:  and goes, just make those Yeah, that's and that's how and that's where we
Speaker 1:  are.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. He was like, I don't know if he said this, but my
Speaker 7:  impression is, okay, fine, you did great to this point, it's not
Speaker 7:  working anymore. Let's just start from scratch because that's what these
Speaker 7:  new robots look like. And it's like they've thrown away all of the innovation
Speaker 7:  and all of, in the hardware that Roomba had worked
Speaker 7:  on over the years, the software it seems like is still there, but
Speaker 7:  entirely new hardware. They are using a new
Speaker 7:  manufacturer too. And oh my goodness, these robots look like every other
Speaker 7:  robot out there that it makes it very hard for me to believe that these are
Speaker 7:  original designs. I mean, when I actually asked
Speaker 7:  iRobot this question, they said, well, they already copied us.
Speaker 7:  That's why we look like them because they copied us originally. I'm like,
Speaker 7:  yes, that was true like five years ago. But these new
Speaker 7:  robots that Roomba launched this last week have the spinning mop pads. They
Speaker 7:  have the auto wash empty dry
Speaker 7:  docks, which Roomba did not have. And that's exactly
Speaker 7:  what, you know, robo Rock invented that essentially. And the new Rob, the
Speaker 7:  new Roomba docs look a lot like the original robo rock docs. So
Speaker 7:  it's, and they, I mean, from a business perspective, it's probably the right
Speaker 7:  move. It's what people are asking for. People want lidar,
Speaker 7:  they want suction specs like we were talking about when they're looking on
Speaker 7:  Amazon at which robot they're gonna buy. That's what they've been trained
Speaker 7:  to, to look for. But It is, it just feels like this,
Speaker 7:  I mean, robot vacuums have become commodities. Right? Right. That's
Speaker 7:  what, that's what's happened. And Ro Roomba is like, well we can still
Speaker 7:  salvage some of our business because we have a
Speaker 7:  name that everyone recognizes. And now if we do
Speaker 7:  what everyone else is doing and less expensive, they are coming
Speaker 7:  in significantly lower than the competition right now. But then the
Speaker 7:  competition has arms. But
Speaker 7:  that's a separate thing, right? So yeah, there's, if they're able to turn
Speaker 7:  the company around, perhaps they could go back to the sort of
Speaker 7:  innovation and the spirit of entrepreneurship and,
Speaker 7:  and really exciting things that the company was able to do over the last
Speaker 7:  30 years and maybe invent the next great thing, you know, the stair
Speaker 7:  climbing robot vacuum.
Speaker 7:  But the competition is just so fierce. It's, it's really hard to
Speaker 7:  see a, a, a strong pathway for them. I think
Speaker 7:  I would like to have seen what happened if Amazon had bought the company.
Speaker 7:  I know there were, and I alluded this to this before, significant
Speaker 7:  concerns around things like privacy. These robot vacuums have cameras in
Speaker 7:  your home, roombas know everything about your
Speaker 7:  home, where, how many rooms you have, what furnace you have.
Speaker 7:  And this is probably one reason why Amazon wanted to buy them for that kind
Speaker 7:  of data. But when you take from the smart home
Speaker 7:  perspective, when you take that data and pair it with a
Speaker 7:  smart home platform with a voice assistant that's getting smarter
Speaker 7:  such as Alexa and the new Alexa plus, you could just see where that
Speaker 7:  symbiosis could have come together. And the what, that's
Speaker 7:  what the smart home needs is context. You need to know that I'm standing
Speaker 7:  in the kitchen and I've just dropped a pan of baked beans
Speaker 7:  on the floor and you say, you know, Alexa clean up the beans
Speaker 7:  and it knows that you're in the kitchen because it has all of that context
Speaker 7:  from Right. Things like the Roomba, the maps, and then the Roomba just
Speaker 7:  trundles over and sucks up the beans, although it can't do that yet. But
Speaker 7:  that could have been the next innovation wet. Right. Vacuuming.
Speaker 7:  So I would, I would love to have seen where it could have gone.
Speaker 7:  There is still a chance that Roomba will get bought by
Speaker 7:  company. That's sort of the next, so the CEO
Speaker 7:  said in the last, in the financial reports that they last launched last week,
Speaker 7:  that the two biggest ways out of their current situation
Speaker 7:  is for lots of people to buy the new robots or
Speaker 7:  for it to get bought. And I wouldn't be surprised to see
Speaker 7:  a robot manufacturer actually come in and, and take them. I mean they did
Speaker 7:  actually used to have a partnership briefly with Ecova. So that could be
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting one.
Speaker 7:  I mean, Amazon's not gonna be allowed to buy, none of the big smart home
Speaker 7:  companies are gonna be allowed to buy it. So their, their pool has definitely
Speaker 7:  shrunk, but Right. And also you can buy them, basically buy them for parts
Speaker 7:  right now. So probably a really good deal.
Speaker 1:  Well, it's the name, right? It it really, it's the name does feel like everything
Speaker 1:  you just described is that this company has sort of
Speaker 1:  nuked everything about itself that was unique except for the
Speaker 1:  name Roomba. But at this point, I, I think you're right that all of
Speaker 1:  this market has become so commoditized
Speaker 1:  and yet everybody still calls them Roombas. Right. Which, which is very powerful.
Speaker 1:  And so I think the, the theory you just described, right, where it's like,
Speaker 1:  okay, we're gonna come back all the way down to the market and we're just
Speaker 1:  gonna make the thing everybody else is making, but we're gonna call it Roomba.
Speaker 1:  It might work. Like I don't, I find that argument sort of a bummer,
Speaker 1:  right? Like it's, it's not a, it's not an interesting way to make product,
Speaker 1:  but it might work. Yeah. And I, I can see how this company would get there.
Speaker 1:  I just think given the history of this company and the things they have been
Speaker 1:  trying to do, that's just sort of unfortunate because, and this is the
Speaker 1:  last thing I wanna talk about before I let you go. The, the, the thing you
Speaker 1:  just described, that this is the, the centerpiece of the smart home. That
Speaker 1:  this is the thing that gives the context that knows where you are and what
Speaker 1:  is going on. Like that's how we get to Rosie the
Speaker 1:  robot, right? Like the thing iRobot didn't wanna build it has sort of
Speaker 1:  been building towards for 30 years
Speaker 1:  it, whether it wanted to or not, this is, this is what they're doing, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And they, they've talked about wanting to build the, the operating
Speaker 1:  system for the smart home and be the centerpiece of the thing. The thing
Speaker 1:  that can move around inside of your house is so powerful.
Speaker 1:  Like you and I have talked about this before. If, if there is a thing that
Speaker 1:  can reach me physically, that becomes an incredibly
Speaker 1:  powerful addition to my smart home. And so what I wonder is,
Speaker 1:  without iRobot pushing on this in the way that I think
Speaker 1:  the company has sort of uniquely been able to for a really long time,
Speaker 1:  who is like, are, are we just at the point where a robot vacuum is a robot,
Speaker 1:  vacuum is a robot vacuum And, and we're going to just bail on the
Speaker 1:  idea that actually this is the robot that runs your smart home
Speaker 1:  because the Roomba can't do it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, so Amazon had started to, we, Amazon had its robot
Speaker 7:  the astro, which was basically this kind of idea. But if
Speaker 7:  it had been a vacuum, it would've been a much better product. Yeah. It
Speaker 7:  would've done things if it'd also be right because this is the problem. And
Speaker 7:  this was, this goes back to what Colin Angle said when he originally launched
Speaker 7:  the company. It was like, robots need to have a purpose. They're not,
Speaker 7:  there's no point if it's just a personality in your home, right? I mean we've
Speaker 7:  seen that with all the robotic companies that have gone out of business
Speaker 7:  because they, they built robots that didn't really do anything, but they
Speaker 7:  look cute or they had a personality. And so yeah, the, the
Speaker 7:  kind of the idea of having a robot in your home that is going to be
Speaker 7:  useful. I'm in two minds. I don't really personally think
Speaker 7:  the full humanoid robot is something anyone really wants,
Speaker 7:  but, you know, and I think it's a long way away as well. And I think we all
Speaker 7:  would like something that can do the function of a Rosie the robot sooner
Speaker 7:  in our lifetimes, ideally. Yeah. So I think
Speaker 7:  the next, I mean there there are a lot of companies that, that could step
Speaker 7:  up in this space. I think it could come from one of these robot manufacturers
Speaker 7:  we saw at CES this year, switch bot came out with its
Speaker 7:  multi-modal multifunctional robot vacuum that pushed different
Speaker 7:  devices around the house. So an air purifier, it
Speaker 7:  could bring you a drink, it could move your iPad around for
Speaker 7:  you. I mean it was kind of gimmicky, but it was, it's the starting point
Speaker 7:  of a multifunctional robot that
Speaker 7:  perhaps whether Colin Angle and iRobot didn't want to
Speaker 7:  develop the Rosie the robot originally. I think they've definitely built
Speaker 7:  the foundations for it and it's the intelligence that's important as much
Speaker 7:  as the function and that, you know, really is where they laid the foundations
Speaker 7:  because the machine learning that these robots, the difference between the
Speaker 7:  one that I had in my home in 2003 and the ones I have in my home
Speaker 7:  today is exponential. And they are so much smarter.
Speaker 7:  And that you can see the long in the long tail of where that
Speaker 7:  could take us could be really exciting and really interesting.
Speaker 1:  All right Jen, thank you so much for doing this to me. This was really fun.
Speaker 7:  You're welcome. Thanks. I enjoyed myself.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna
Speaker 1:  talk about e-readers love talking about e-readers. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  goods had changed. They deleted this tool that would let you easily
Speaker 1:  download your books to put them on a new device and also at
Speaker 1:  the same time
Speaker 1:  I just forget I'd get his read on things. And we started by talking about
Speaker 1:  devices because one of the things I find odd about e-readers
Speaker 1:  is that they're both wonderful devices and very good at the thing that they
Speaker 1:  do well. But it doesn't seem like they've changed in a sort of
Speaker 1:  meaningful way in a really long time. Like if you look at your
Speaker 1:  phone now and your phone eight years ago, they're very
Speaker 1:  different. And your laptop or your smartwatch or pick another gadget,
Speaker 1:  e-readers have changed in small ways but don't feel like they've changed
Speaker 1:  in big ways in a really, really, really, really, really long time.
Speaker 1:  And I just asked Michael why
Speaker 11:  I, I think there are a couple of factors. One is just screen innovation
Speaker 11:  is super hard and screen innovation,
Speaker 11:  especially in this low power ePaper space that we're in
Speaker 11:  is even harder both because of the constraints.
Speaker 11:  Like your, you know, the whole idea is you should have a screen that
Speaker 11:  you can charge once, you know, in weeks and it, you know,
Speaker 11:  continues to work. And at the same time, unlike say
Speaker 11:  OLES or LCD panels or anything else, the volumes aren't
Speaker 11:  giant. Hmm. So it's not like you're amortizing research out
Speaker 11:  over 400 million screens a year.
Speaker 11:  Sure. So, so it's like us and our friends in Seattle and a few folks in
Speaker 11:  China and like we are the market that are, that
Speaker 11:  are creating the volume for this. So there's a certain incrementality to
Speaker 11:  the innovation that comes from that. But then beyond that, there was just
Speaker 11:  this slow ramp on getting black and white
Speaker 11:  better. So if we look back over the last 10 years, you'll see this
Speaker 11:  kind of slow marching forward of we had Ian Pearl screens and then we had
Speaker 11:  Ian Carter screens, we had part 1100 Carta 1200, like sort of these little
Speaker 11:  steps while they were also working on color.
Speaker 11:  And so like a lot of the color technology we're seeing in the market now
Speaker 11:  has been in labs and in
Speaker 11:  manufacturing paths now for like four or five years.
Speaker 11:  It's just that they couldn't get that combination of performance and price.
Speaker 11:  Right. So, you know, we had screens that look
Speaker 11:  like the screens that we now have out in the market with
Speaker 11:  like Cobo, Libra color, Cobo Clara color, those screens are around,
Speaker 11:  you know, three years ago or more. But they were still astronomically expensive.
Speaker 11:  Hmm. And so until they could get the manufacturing right and they could
Speaker 11:  get the yields right and they could get the prices right, we just couldn't
Speaker 11:  offer them at a price that anybody would find really interesting. But what's
Speaker 11:  kind of cool now is there's a whole bunch of stuff that's
Speaker 11:  just sitting on the horizon that not just from
Speaker 11:  like yank the manufacturer, but from all of these other companies that have
Speaker 11:  started to work on low power screens. And so you have some contenders now
Speaker 11:  and contenders mean competition, right? Competition means things start to
Speaker 11:  move faster and you start to get some price pressure. So I think after having
Speaker 11:  y almost like a decade of very incremental progress,
Speaker 11:  we now start to see a whole like, we're gonna have some really exciting
Speaker 11:  years over the next few years as all of this stuff lands. So you get that
Speaker 11:  far then can you get to something that is getting closer to
Speaker 11:  the kinds of refresh rates that you see in LCD panels, for
Speaker 11:  example. And then like then you can make the interactions on the screens
Speaker 11:  better than you can make them right now. But it's interesting 'cause I
Speaker 11:  don't ever see us coming to a place where you have like
Speaker 11:  the, the regular screen panel world and the,
Speaker 11:  the, the einer ePaper world converging because
Speaker 11:  the use cases are so different and not just for, you know, people like
Speaker 11:  you and I who have a Samsung frame and like, you know, like are
Speaker 11:  willing to make certain compromises in our TVs, but the
Speaker 11:  the extent to which you want a low power device on one side
Speaker 11:  and you want perfect color fidelity on
Speaker 11:  the other, right. Just kind of the, the technology just diverges
Speaker 11:  as you're trying to solve those two problems.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And it, it does seem like part of the, I don't know if it's
Speaker 1:  a challenge or not, but sort of the truth of this market is just that everyone
Speaker 1:  decided a while ago to make a certain set of decisions. Like
Speaker 1:  we, we hit a price point pretty quickly with a lot of this stuff where I
Speaker 1:  think it's like, my, my question to you on the screen stuff is gonna be,
Speaker 1:  well, why not just sell one of these awesome color screens that was
Speaker 1:  available in a $600 Cobo? And I, I assume
Speaker 1:  the response is because absolutely nobody would buy it, which is like, fair
Speaker 1:  enough. That is true. Sure. But I think it's, it's a really interesting
Speaker 1:  piece of this because I think like you look at almost any other category
Speaker 1:  and there's this like massive price banding depending on how new the
Speaker 1:  technology is and how many features you get and how much stuff you get. And
Speaker 1:  the, the sort of acceptable set of prices in e-readers is so
Speaker 1:  comparatively tiny that I feel like it does force you into kind
Speaker 1:  of strange boxes where you're like, okay, we have to get oh yeah, this sweet
Speaker 1:  spot of technology in order to have
Speaker 1:  it hit this price point. Because if we, if we raise it a hundred dollars
Speaker 1:  to do this amazing new thing, nobody will buy it. There's just no other market
Speaker 1:  really like that.
Speaker 11:  And Well, it's true. And I mean some of that I think we are
Speaker 11:  responsible for in some ways, when Cobo came into 2010, we
Speaker 11:  repriced the E Inc market. So we were the first ones to bring
Speaker 11:  in a sub hundred and $50 e-reader, right? Up until then
Speaker 11:  e-readers were 250, 350, you know,
Speaker 11:  $400. And part of that was just wanting
Speaker 11:  it to be accessible, not to this super narrow
Speaker 11:  niche of enthusiasts, but just like, let's make this
Speaker 11:  a general part of the book market. Hmm. And then even again, we
Speaker 11:  were the ones who went, okay, well having done that, let's now look at premium
Speaker 11:  e readers, so let's make the screens bigger and let's put waterproofing
Speaker 11:  on them and you know, and all of that kind of stuff. So to walk that price
Speaker 11:  point up again, but you're right, there is a, there's a
Speaker 11:  certain limit that you bump into where you've kind of got like the
Speaker 11:  bottom of the iPad market and the top of the, the e-reader market.
Speaker 11:  And there's a, there's a certain point of friction in there that psychologically
Speaker 11:  people seem to bump into and, and so that in a way becomes like the pricing
Speaker 11:  box that we work in. But it's, but there's
Speaker 11:  also something about, I think selling a single purpose device. Like
Speaker 11:  we really just do want this to do one thing. And I do think that
Speaker 11:  affects people's, like mental pricing math a little bit.
Speaker 11:  And you're also selling a small thing. So it's, you know, it's not like
Speaker 11:  we're, you know, we're selling a, you know, a giant 4K television that's
Speaker 11:  going to, that's gonna cover someone's wall. But
Speaker 11:  we do have some of that same kind of value
Speaker 11:  psychology going on. Like a person who reads an on an
Speaker 11:  e-reader isn't a person who reads one book a year, mostly, like they're
Speaker 11:  a person who reads a book every week. And so you are selling to that
Speaker 11:  enthusiast the same way that someone will ditch
Speaker 11:  the, you know, the earbuds that come with their phone and buy great
Speaker 11:  headphones, you know, because they love listening to music. So you've got,
Speaker 11:  like, you've got some of that enthusiast logic going on,
Speaker 11:  but it only allows us to push it so far. So yeah, we work with it.
Speaker 1:  If the goal is we, you're reading books and I, I want to come back to why
Speaker 1:  it's just books, because I don't think it's just books and I want to convince
Speaker 1:  you that it's not. But if It is just books, how
Speaker 1:  big do you think that is? Like what does that mean you have to do? Well,
Speaker 11:  Sure. And just to touch on, on what you were saying earlier, I,
Speaker 11:  I also have a theory on why we've ended up with
Speaker 11:  this space being defined the way It is. And it's from some very particular
Speaker 11:  technology choices that got made in about like interesting 2010. So we can
Speaker 11:  come back to that. Okay. But like, you know, what has to be done
Speaker 11:  well with this comes so
Speaker 11:  much to like, what is the experience that people want to have when they
Speaker 11:  pick one of these up? You know, this is the kind of thing we actually do
Speaker 11:  research on and we like bring people together and we interview them and
Speaker 11:  we survey them and you really have like
Speaker 11:  four-ish, you know, kinds of customers. You know, you know, you have those
Speaker 11:  people who are reading for Escape who are just like, you know,
Speaker 11:  the, you know, fiction or a biography. It's taking
Speaker 11:  me away. It's taking me out of this place and putting me somewhere else.
Speaker 11:  And that requires both an extremely
Speaker 11:  inobtrusive technology sitting behind it. Like you just have to get everything
Speaker 11:  out of the way and an absolute
Speaker 11:  rock solid reliability in the experience itself because any
Speaker 11:  problem jars you out of that moment. And you go from having
Speaker 11:  a beautiful moment to an annoying moment, like in an instant. And then
Speaker 11:  you've got the, you know, you have the people who are
Speaker 11:  reading more for information or for education
Speaker 11:  and that's a different set of technology problems as
Speaker 11:  well as a different set of interactions. Like the reason that we started
Speaker 11:  putting stylists in e-readers came from
Speaker 11:  interviews that we were doing nonfiction readers and we were trying to solve
Speaker 11:  this like sales mystery of why are eBooks so
Speaker 11:  overweighted into fiction, relative
Speaker 11:  to nonfiction. Oh, fascinating. 'cause we could kind of like, we can kind
Speaker 11:  of look at what happens in a regular physical store
Speaker 11:  and how they sell, and then we look at what we're selling, like fix it so
Speaker 11:  much higher. And as we to people when I'm, when
Speaker 11:  I'm reading something to engage with it for information,
Speaker 11:  I'm not just trying to like put myself in the story. I'm actively
Speaker 11:  engaging with it. I'm highlighting and I'm making notes in the margins and
Speaker 11:  I'm like, I'm trying to kind of consume it and extract things from it
Speaker 11:  at the same time. And that's hard for me to do with an ebook unless
Speaker 11:  we give you some extra tools to do that. So let's make
Speaker 11:  highlighting and notes and all of this stuff become a
Speaker 11:  thing that you can do as easily. Plus like there's some benefits to that.
Speaker 11:  It's not just stuck on the page. You can take it off and do something else
Speaker 11:  with it. So different use cases for different kinds of readers.
Speaker 11:  And there are some, as we dig into that, that also explain
Speaker 11:  places where eBooks just haven't become as popular,
Speaker 11:  like reading for children. And we thought, okay, color screens
Speaker 11:  amazing and finally get children's books. No, and not
Speaker 11:  because they don't look good, you know, and we also have them on apps. You
Speaker 11:  could read them on an iPad or an Android tablet or whatever. No, because
Speaker 11:  children's books live in the gift economy and they're what parents give
Speaker 11:  to children. And you want to walk into a child's room and see books
Speaker 11:  all around you as a sign that you are a good parent and they may grow up
Speaker 11:  to be literate one day. And like all, all of that
Speaker 11:  kind of works against the idea of having that be something that you read
Speaker 11:  in digital. And that's okay. And the same with all of those books that
Speaker 11:  are
Speaker 11:  loved for the object that they are as much as for the content
Speaker 11:  that they have. You know, the books that you have on your coffee table and
Speaker 11:  have on your shelves exist with a whole different set of
Speaker 11:  values behind them in addition to the stuff that's in them. And it's funny,
Speaker 11:  if you look at a bookstore, you can kind of look at
Speaker 11:  how the books themselves are produced and get a sense of their likelihood
Speaker 11:  of getting consumed in digital. Like the more cheaply
Speaker 11:  it's put together, like, you know, the romance novel and the,
Speaker 11:  you know, crime thriller that's just got covers wrapped around it. It's
Speaker 11:  all about the story. Those have gone to digital much more quickly
Speaker 11:  than the beautiful book that's about, you know, architecture and
Speaker 11:  Sure. Yeah. So different use cases kind of drive you into digital
Speaker 11:  in different ways. And it's also why print has
Speaker 11:  coexisted much more that like kind of harmoniously with
Speaker 11:  digital than the other big format shifts that we've seen like with music
Speaker 11:  and with video.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Is there, is there a world in which you think
Speaker 1:  digital eventually takes that whole spectrum? Like I, I think
Speaker 1:  about EII have a 2-year-old and we have a hundred million books in his room.
Speaker 1:  Awesome. And all the ones he likes best are the ones where it's like the
Speaker 1:  train pops up off the thing and he can play with it as he moves. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, I, I'm never getting that on an e-reader or an iPad or anything. Like,
Speaker 1:  there's no screen that physically can do that thing that turns out to be
Speaker 1:  very important. So is there, is there a spectrum of this where you're like,
Speaker 1:  okay, in this giant sort of sweep of what a book can be,
Speaker 1:  we think digital can do sort of, of, you know, the middle two thirds or whatever?
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I, I think there's a long-term and a midterm view to it. Like
Speaker 11:  the long-term view is like, do you still believe that
Speaker 11:  50 years from now we're gonna be cutting down trees and pressing ink into
Speaker 11:  them and that's gonna be the way that we move reward around.
Speaker 11:  And I think if you take the timeline out that far, people go,
Speaker 11:  eh, probably not. And so then you're just arguing about where
Speaker 11:  the inflection points are. That might kind of tip you over to that. Sure.
Speaker 11:  There will definitely always be some physical books that people wanna have
Speaker 11:  'cause they're beautiful and because they say something about who we are
Speaker 11:  and they create an environment that we like.
Speaker 1:  Well that's the stuff you're talking about where like the object is actually
Speaker 1:  more important than the book. Like almost calling it a book. And it's the
Speaker 1:  same with like a lot of coffee table books and stuff, right? Like, it's not,
Speaker 1:  that's a piece of art as much as It is like a bunch of words in a
Speaker 1:  row on pages or
Speaker 11:  The design is a part of the content and the, and the
Speaker 11:  design amplifies the message that the author's trying to send.
Speaker 11:  What was cool about seeing publishing react to digital, like
Speaker 11:  through the 2010s and into the 2020s was all of a sudden, like everybody
Speaker 11:  stepped up their game on making books just more
Speaker 11:  beautiful physically. So like you, you know,
Speaker 11:  you didn't have walls of cheap paperbacks anymore. Like, and, and now even
Speaker 11:  more you've got the idea of books as collectibles and you've got special
Speaker 11:  editions and all this other stuff, and it's, it's publishers
Speaker 11:  frantically trying to figure out the balance between keeping bookstores
Speaker 11:  alive and relevant while more things go to online. And then
Speaker 11:  eBooks are in there, like carving out certain segments. So they're doing
Speaker 11:  a delicate dance. And then at the same time we're trying to say, well, hey,
Speaker 11:  we just put out color screens and all of a sudden cookbooks look gorgeous
Speaker 11:  in on an eReader. And they do. And so there was a segment
Speaker 11:  where we kind of couldn't like really meet the customer where they wanted
Speaker 11:  to be, and now we can. And so all of a sudden you see, you know, more
Speaker 11:  digital cookbook sales happening, which is cool.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. What are you seeing in terms of what color in particular is doing?
Speaker 1:  Because I think one thing I've heard from book people over the years is that
Speaker 1:  part of the challenge of e-readers is that they're so customizable
Speaker 1:  in the sense that screens are different and people pick different font sizes
Speaker 1:  and people pick different colors and margins. And so attempting to be
Speaker 1:  sort of opinionated and thoughtful about ebook design was kind of a waste
Speaker 1:  of time. My sense is with color, maybe not with everything, but
Speaker 1:  with some things that would give people a chance to
Speaker 1:  put some more work into how those things look and feel. Are we starting to
Speaker 1:  see that as color grows?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I, I, I mean, at the most basic level, we had
Speaker 11:  publishers who used to take like color images out and turn them into black
Speaker 11:  and white and send those to us. Sure. Like just to keep like file sizes
Speaker 11:  down and everything else. It's like, nope. Like we would like the whole
Speaker 11:  thing now give, give us that. But it's a
Speaker 11:  little bit of everything. It's suddenly more graphic novel sales,
Speaker 11:  suddenly more cookbook sales. Like maybe not the gorgeous coffee table book,
Speaker 11:  but the book that's about knitting patterns or the book that's about mending
Speaker 11:  your own clothes, that was like kind of color photo imagery
Speaker 11:  is suddenly more saleable. So like all of those are ticking up. And then
Speaker 11:  there's just something about like, you can now see your library in color
Speaker 11:  and like people like publishers sweat
Speaker 11:  about covers for a reason. Like they're, you know, they're gorgeous, they
Speaker 11:  should be. And, and now we can show that to people. And so that all
Speaker 11:  helps as well. And then it's, it's very different from market
Speaker 11:  to market too. So like what we're talking about mostly is what I call kind
Speaker 11:  of like North American publisher behavior. Sure. You know, we look
Speaker 11:  at some markets like Japan is not an e-reader market at all, and
Speaker 11:  it's like, it's a huge one for us, but it's all happening on
Speaker 11:  smartphones and their colors never been a problem and it
Speaker 11:  doesn't change at all.
Speaker 1:  Right. And I think the, the smartphone thing is really interesting to me
Speaker 1:  because one of the main reasons I hear from people
Speaker 1:  that the, the people who are mad that ebook readers aren't better, I would
Speaker 1:  say overwhelmingly what they say is because all the companies that make them
Speaker 1:  are bookstores first and device makers second. And I think
Speaker 1:  to a large extent, I, I think that's, that's, I don't know if that's true
Speaker 1:  for you. I don't know if you feel that way, but I think like Amazon I know
Speaker 1:  feels that way. Sure. I can tell you with great confidence. Yep. Amazon cares
Speaker 1:  a lot more about selling books than selling Kindles. And then,
Speaker 1:  and I think especially when you're starting to think about, okay, how does
Speaker 1:  this experience work on smartphones? How does it work on the web reader?
Speaker 1:  You get to the point where it's like, okay, we actually can't just be
Speaker 1:  focused on the one thing in part because customers want it to be
Speaker 1:  lots of different places. And in part because that's not what our business
Speaker 1:  is, is It, is it possible to
Speaker 1:  have your cake and eat it too in that sense? Like, can you be a great hardware
Speaker 1:  business that is also mostly a really good bookstore? Or do you end up having
Speaker 1:  to choose one or the other?
Speaker 11:  No, you totally can't. Like that's, that's the part that I don't think I
Speaker 11:  get, like the whole, in some ways we treat them as two
Speaker 11:  different things, or at least we treat them as two different objectives.
Speaker 11:  Like, we have a lot of people who buy, who buy a co we reader
Speaker 11:  who never buy anything from us at all. They hook it up to a public library,
Speaker 11:  they bring their own books along, they muck around on
Speaker 11:  the internet, they find things that they probably should have bought. Like
Speaker 11:  all, all we know, all of these things happen purely
Speaker 1:  Legally and correctly with no problems always the right way.
Speaker 1:  Public
Speaker 11:  Domain, it's exactly Jane Eyre and everybody's
Speaker 1:  Just reading Frankenstein. Yes,
Speaker 11:  Exactly. Everyone is reading pride and prejudice all day long and they have
Speaker 11:  their own special version that they bring to us. And so those people
Speaker 11:  bought an e-reader, they like, they shelled out their cash and that's
Speaker 11:  like, that's the way they're engaging with us and we
Speaker 11:  need them to be happy even though they never hit the store at all.
Speaker 11:  And then at the same time, we are a bookstore and we do sell the content
Speaker 11:  and whether that's the actual e-commerce experience itself
Speaker 11:  or running Cobo plus the subscription service or running
Speaker 11:  Cobo writing life, like our self-publishing program, like all of that stuff
Speaker 11:  has to work together to make a really great store
Speaker 11:  because that's just another part of the flywheel that
Speaker 11:  we're trying to keep spinning and they need to work together really well
Speaker 11:  too. So that's why we don't just treat it as, you
Speaker 11:  know, kind of a dumb hardware platform. Like we wanna thoughtfully integrate
Speaker 11:  those two things together.
Speaker 1:  Sure. But like the, the thing Amazon always says, right, is like they, we,
Speaker 1:  we don't make money when you buy our gadgets, we make money, you when you
Speaker 1:  use them. And in the Kindle's case, oh,
Speaker 11:  They totally make money when they you buy,
Speaker 1:  They
Speaker 11:  Absolutely do.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. But I think that that's, that seems to be
Speaker 1:  at least sort of philosophically the way that they think about it, right?
Speaker 1:  They're like, they are more interested in giving you a thing that you will
Speaker 1:  buy books on than in giving you a thing to happily
Speaker 1:  read things that didn't come from Amazon, which is objectively true given
Speaker 1:  all of their product decisions that we should talk about. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Are you, are, is that, is that not the case for you? Like how do you design
Speaker 1:  a business around this so that that's not the case so that you
Speaker 1:  don't have to force me to buy 10 books before this thing makes sense for
Speaker 1:  you as a business? Well,
Speaker 11:  Part of It is just the economics of e readers themselves. Like
Speaker 11:  unlike laptop screens or smartphone screens or anything else,
Speaker 11:  they're expensive to make. Like those e ink panels are
Speaker 11:  not cheap and make the, like the margins
Speaker 11:  on e-readers relatively thin. And one of the reasons that
Speaker 11:  we weren't just trying to drive them down to
Speaker 11:  become commodity hardware, like, you know, kind of the race to the $99
Speaker 11:  eReader and below and thought that there was
Speaker 11:  room for a premium segment. Like let's make a great seven e reader, let's
Speaker 11:  make a great eight e reader was to like to create
Speaker 11:  some more pricing headroom so that the e-readers
Speaker 11:  themselves could be valuable objects and could be interesting objects. Because
Speaker 11:  if you can bring the price up a little bit, you can experiment with materials
Speaker 11:  and you can, you know, kind of change the screen, like the screen
Speaker 11:  technology that you're using, all of that to say, then you can start to
Speaker 11:  have like a spectrum of e-readers at, at different price points and
Speaker 11:  have them stand on their own from an economics perspective
Speaker 11:  so that you're not trying to make, you know, these kind of like
Speaker 11:  one-way doors where okay, you've bought our thing, now you have to buy all
Speaker 11:  of your content from us too. And that like, so Right. The content should
Speaker 11:  be our ability to sell books well should be able
Speaker 11:  to stand on its own in terms of how we make money and the margins that
Speaker 11:  we have on it. And our ability to make hardware should be able to stand
Speaker 11:  on its own knowing that some people are going to buy hardware and never
Speaker 11:  buy books from us. And, and that should be okay. So we,
Speaker 11:  we shouldn't be trying to structure this as a roach motel and,
Speaker 11:  and you should be able to kind of engage with it the ways that
Speaker 11:  you want to. And maybe your e-reader is something that you're using to do
Speaker 11:  documents from work and maybe you're using it as something to buy books
Speaker 11:  from us or to hook up a subscription or you are a public
Speaker 11:  library fan and you wanna use Libby and like we're good with that too.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, and I think that that explanation makes total sense to
Speaker 1:  me, even though I have a, I have a books Palm I sitting here I would very
Speaker 1:  much like to talk to you about. Yeah. But I think to
Speaker 1:  me the, the both biggest opportunity and maybe most interesting
Speaker 1:  challenge here is that kind of getting stuff into and off of a
Speaker 1:  device like this
Speaker 1:  problem, because I think especially like you, you talked about the people
Speaker 1:  who read nonfiction and that they just interact with this information differently.
Speaker 1:  One of those things is like I, I hear over and over from people who are like,
Speaker 1:  I, I use whatever app just because it syncs to my
Speaker 1:  notion like you're just saying, right? Yes. And, and then I can, I can search
Speaker 1:  for all of my stuff or I get, I don't know, space repetition
Speaker 1:  flashcards sent to my email every week or like whatever. People have these
Speaker 1:  sort of wild information collection systems and they want their long
Speaker 1:  form reading to be part of it. And by and large, these
Speaker 1:  devices are the most disconnected from the rest of that.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And that's a, like one of the reasons that we,
Speaker 11:  that we put stuff like Dropbox support on there is like, let's look at popular
Speaker 11:  file systems that people already use that synchronize well that have things
Speaker 11:  like, you know, the ability to email into a directory. Like all of that
Speaker 11:  stuff is there. Sure. Yeah. So that a,
Speaker 11:  we're not rolling our own because nobody wants another one of these. Like
Speaker 11:  every, everybody has eight already. And then the question is how much farther
Speaker 11:  do you have to go? Like, is it okay we also should do box or we also should
Speaker 11:  do, you know, OneDrive or whatever the, you know, the other ones that people
Speaker 11:  want.
Speaker 1:  Well that is the problem, right? There is an infinite well of those things
Speaker 1:  there
Speaker 11:  Are infinite wells. Yeah. And so at a certain point you have to saw it off.
Speaker 11:  And then similarly in terms of the material itself,
Speaker 11:  the, you've done whole series on note taking
Speaker 11:  solutions and knowledge management systems and
Speaker 11:  everybody wants their thing to go directly into that thing. Yep. And, and
Speaker 11:  I understand why as a, you know, as a notion user, I would, I love these
Speaker 11:  things to just be piped in, but can we get them out in
Speaker 11:  standardized formats? Can we get them out in ways that are kind of easy
Speaker 11:  to manage and manipulate? And so whether that means that you are
Speaker 11:  then kicking them into the knowledge management system you have or feeding
Speaker 11:  them into an LLM or doing whatever else you're, you know, you're doing with
Speaker 11:  them, let's make sure that the inputs and outputs are relatively clean and
Speaker 11:  easy so that you can get stuff out. And
Speaker 11:  that's, you know, we've kind of been nudging around this at
Speaker 11:  different times, but getting things out is an important part of this. We
Speaker 11:  would like you not Yeah. We don't want you to have your stuff trapped inside.
Speaker 1:  Well, and to that point, this is a bit of a diversion, but I know it's a
Speaker 1:  thing you've been thinking about in talking about there's been, I would say
Speaker 1:  a a, a kerfuffle in the ebook reading world over the last
Speaker 1:  couple of weeks, which is not a thing that happens often. It's true. So it's
Speaker 1:  very exciting when there's ebook kerfuffles. Like it's, it's good stuff
Speaker 1:  where I think be because of this Amazon announcement of they were shutting
Speaker 1:  down the, the download and transfer thing where you can get your book, your
Speaker 1:  books easily off of your Kindle onto another device.
Speaker 1:  It's all, that's all very messy. But I think it, it has changed
Speaker 1:  a lot of people's ideas about what it means to like, have stuff on a device
Speaker 1:  like this. Yeah. There there is this feeling of like, okay, my, my
Speaker 1:  e-reader is, is a thing filled with my books. And I think a couple
Speaker 1:  of times over the years, Kindle owners in particular have been reminded that
Speaker 1:  that is not actually the case. And now there, I think
Speaker 1:  when you, when you go to buy a book on Amazon, it's like, it says you're
Speaker 1:  buying a license to a book, not the book itself. Yeah. And like
Speaker 1:  we talk a lot about digital goods at The Verge and the idea of like, what,
Speaker 1:  what are they, what do you own? What are you buying? What, what if this matters?
Speaker 1:  We got weirded in the NFTs for a minute. It was a whole thing. But I, I do
Speaker 1:  think like this, this question of
Speaker 1:  people's information on a Cobo device and in the Cobo ecosystem,
Speaker 1:  what is your responsibility to all of that stuff? Whether it's books that
Speaker 1:  I'm buying or PDFs that I'm adding, like how, how
Speaker 1:  are users supposed to understand what all of that means inside of
Speaker 1:  Cobas universe?
Speaker 11:  It's one of those places that I'm like, I'm kind of proud
Speaker 11:  we've been able to stick to our guns over the years because from the very
Speaker 11:  beginning as we were first framing out what
Speaker 11:  Coba was gonna do, we thought you should be able to read your
Speaker 11:  books on any device. You know, we'd like it to be ours or we'd like it to
Speaker 11:  be in our app, but it doesn't have to be, you should be able to buy something
Speaker 11:  and take it somewhere else if you want to. And
Speaker 11:  you're right that, that question of licensing versus owning as a whole
Speaker 11:  other can of worms, like, yeah, publishers only let us
Speaker 11:  sell licenses mostly, and some let us sell without
Speaker 11:  DRM some, especially in the eu, like use
Speaker 11:  watermarks that are embedded, but, you know, leave the files on DRM. So
Speaker 11:  it's always really hard to say you own your eBooks the way
Speaker 11:  you own your paper books, but we can do the next best
Speaker 11:  thing, which is to say you can take them with, you know, you can
Speaker 11:  download them, you put them on a USB key, you can bury them in a mineshaft
Speaker 11:  or hide them in a hollow tree. Like we still have to protect them with
Speaker 11:  DRM because the publishers want us to do that. But lots of
Speaker 11:  other eres support DRM, you can take it and read it on one of those.
Speaker 11:  And I think like that's good for us because it makes
Speaker 11:  us compete on the experience. Like you have to wanna
Speaker 11:  stay and we have to earn your time
Speaker 11:  and your attention and your next e-reader to replace the one
Speaker 11:  that you bought eight years ago. And that keeps us honest.
Speaker 11:  And it does, I think, give a certain sense of security to the
Speaker 11:  person who's buying an ebook, which does already feel less tangible
Speaker 11:  than a physical book. Is
Speaker 1:  That a hard line to hold over time?
Speaker 11:  We haven't found it to be like, we had to fight hard for it at the very
Speaker 11:  beginning, but I think publishers feel both
Speaker 11:  sides of the pressure on that one being it's better
Speaker 11:  not to lock people into ecosystems. And at the same time
Speaker 11:  we really want to make sure that our
Speaker 11:  intellectual property's protected and not fire hosed around the internet.
Speaker 11:  And Sure. And I get both of those. But for
Speaker 11:  us, the, and especially as eBooks are just getting started, that notion
Speaker 11:  of, you know, how do we create a sense of
Speaker 11:  safety around these very intangible objects is really important.
Speaker 11:  Like there are standard DRM solutions, this, this is a solved problem
Speaker 11:  fair. And, and you have them like fairly well standardized across markets
Speaker 11:  and countries. Like none of that is actually an issue. It's like some people
Speaker 11:  really want you to stay on one platform and never go anywhere again. And
Speaker 1:  Some people,
Speaker 11:  Some people, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Where, where do those people live?
Speaker 11:  They're more West Coast based I find, and I don't know if that's, if there's
Speaker 11:  something about proximity to the, the hes of the Pacific that make that
Speaker 11:  happen. There's
Speaker 1:  A big needle. Yeah. Somewhere in the city I think. Yeah. I forget.
Speaker 11:  And, but It is one of those, like you talk about
Speaker 11:  things that, you know, kind of stifle ebook innovation.
Speaker 11:  You've got those, those certain platform
Speaker 11:  dependencies that like that's the thing that makes this hard. Right? It's
Speaker 11:  it's not the screens, it's not the technology to a certain degree, it's
Speaker 11:  people wanting to keep things inside certain walled gardens.
Speaker 1:  Right. Okay. So to that end, I have two more things I wanna talk to you about.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And then I'm gonna let you go. Okay. Number one is, the
Speaker 1:  funniest thing about Cobo to me is that you are in every single ebook
Speaker 1:  reader buying guide under the same heading, which is the best
Speaker 1:  non-Amazon ebook reader. I mean, everywhere you look on the internet, yeah.
Speaker 1:  There is the best Kindle and there's the best not Kindle.
Speaker 1:  Does that drive you crazy? How do you feel about that designation that like,
Speaker 1:  in a real way you do kind of exist in opposition to Amazon? Is that
Speaker 1:  frustrating
Speaker 11:  In so many ways in every way? Yeah. And, and so
Speaker 11:  what's been great to see is how that,
Speaker 11:  those lists have evolved because it used to be, you know,
Speaker 11:  best e-readers and they would always put the Kindle one at the top because
Speaker 11:  that was the most popular one. And then they'd put s but below and now they
Speaker 11:  just have two categories Best Kindles and best other
Speaker 11:  e-readers of which we are the best ones on those. And,
Speaker 11:  and I think we see perception on that
Speaker 11:  shifting a bit of, well, maybe, maybe I don't want that. Maybe I do want
Speaker 11:  the, the alternative one. And and especially
Speaker 11:  as controversies like the ones we've seen over the last few weeks have come
Speaker 11:  up, it makes more people look at that second column, which is
Speaker 11:  fantastic for us. But the other thing that's interesting about that is that
Speaker 11:  that's really only a US and UK phenomenon.
Speaker 1:  That's fair. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  And it's like, some of that comes back to just
Speaker 11:  where, where our friends in Seattle are dominant. Like they really, like,
Speaker 11:  they run the ebook show in exactly two markets, us and the uk
Speaker 11:  and then in every other territory there is
Speaker 11:  at least one local retailer who's doing
Speaker 11:  as well in eBooks as as they are like they're
Speaker 11:  toe to toe comparable market shares. And almost all of those are being
Speaker 11:  powered by us. So you have this really interesting case of
Speaker 11:  there's kind of one world in inside that bubble and one
Speaker 11:  world outside of it where we're all just like fighting away all day long.
Speaker 11:  And those lists look very different when you, when you come outside of the
Speaker 11:  bubble, which is awesome.
Speaker 1:  All right, last thing. Okay. And then I'm gonna let you go. I would like
Speaker 1:  to read you a threads post that you did last August.
Speaker 11:  I'm ready. I'm terrified, but I'm ready.
Speaker 1:  Somebody, it, somebody posted as per the latest vergecast, which
Speaker 1:  I believe this was me ranting about how bad the Kindle is at allowing
Speaker 1:  you to send web articles to the Kindle. All I want
Speaker 1:  on Earth, Michael is just a good way to take all of the stuff I wanna
Speaker 1:  read on the internet and put it on my e-reader. Yes. I, this is,
Speaker 1:  this doesn't seem like a hard problem problem and yet no one has done this
Speaker 1:  for me in a way that is any good at all. Okay. So I'm ready. This person
Speaker 1:  posted as per the latest to Vergecast, will Cobo make a good reading
Speaker 1:  app Allah read wise for all types of files and CC'd you and you responded
Speaker 1:  working on it?
Speaker 11:  Yes. Do tell. So we have two parts. We have one which is
Speaker 11:  the integration which we have with Pocket today, which does a really
Speaker 11:  good job of the web clipping side of it. Sure.
Speaker 11:  And so you can take all of that stuff that you've, you know, the long,
Speaker 11:  you know, the long read article that you don't wanna read on your phone
Speaker 11:  and throw it over to your e-reader that way. Super simple.
Speaker 1:  Is that, is that a good enough answer to that problem for you? Like
Speaker 11:  It, I think it's, it's 75% of that answer. Okay.
Speaker 11:  The other use cases that say like kind of live around
Speaker 11:  read wise as an example, we have an integration with read wise so we can
Speaker 11:  like we can do some of that stuff and then the rest is,
Speaker 11:  some of the rest is PDF management, which we keep
Speaker 11:  taking these big jumps on in terms of how we manage and take care of them.
Speaker 11:  Now we allow you to write on your PDFs and annotate them the same way that
Speaker 11:  we do with an ebook. So that's all getting better. And then
Speaker 11:  like, I think the last things that we can keep working on are just like,
Speaker 11:  how do we make that as fluid and as clean as possible?
Speaker 11:  'cause right now it's spread across a couple of experiences. It's not kind
Speaker 11:  of like, you know, all exactly to one place we have to use a part of. It's
Speaker 11:  like we do have to use a different renderer for a PDF than we use for like
Speaker 11:  a webpage for example. So like all of that stuff is sort of in the mix,
Speaker 11:  but, but we get the question and we understand the,
Speaker 11:  the desire of like, can't I just have all of my reading in this one
Speaker 11:  calm, beautiful place where alerts aren't going off
Speaker 11:  and you know, notifications aren't coming up like you can read on a smartphone
Speaker 11:  today. So like you can get, you can get all of your Cobo books on a,
Speaker 11:  on a smartphone right now so that the portal to
Speaker 11:  reading through that multifunction device exists today. And that that's
Speaker 11:  a signal like that tells us something. When somebody buys an e-reader, they
Speaker 11:  are stepping back from what in almost 100% of cases
Speaker 11:  is the device they already own. Hmm. And so then at that point you've got
Speaker 11:  the question of what are the other layers of experience you can add to that
Speaker 11:  that will actually augment and enhance that experience as
Speaker 11:  opposed to taking people closer to the thing that they're trying to escape
Speaker 11:  from. And, and so like we, you know, if audiobooks in
Speaker 11:  the e-reader experience because we feel that those are just two
Speaker 11:  kinds of reading and they should be kept close together, but we've
Speaker 11:  specifically and deliberately said no to a lot of other stuff that could
Speaker 11:  wrap around that. Both because they already have a home
Speaker 11:  on your phone that's very well served or the kind of
Speaker 11:  interaction that you would do with them is one that's just not well suited
Speaker 11:  to the, the hardware environment of an eReader. But mostly because we
Speaker 11:  are trying to get people that escape and we do want them to step away from
Speaker 11:  it. And when they do, they tend to read more, which is the thing that we
Speaker 11:  like as people who also sell books. So like that's where the, the
Speaker 11:  two sides of the ecosystem do come together is that when we do put any reader
Speaker 11:  in someone's hand, they like, they buy more books and their reading time
Speaker 11:  is longer than a comparable customer holding a phone in their
Speaker 11:  hand who has access to our store. And so giving people that little bit
Speaker 11:  of haven of attention is just good for
Speaker 11:  someone's reading life. And we think that's, you know, for all kinds of
Speaker 11:  reasons, also just a good thing in the world in general. Like we need more
Speaker 11:  little pockets of non distraction. I think it's always a good thing.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 1:  we're gonna take a question from the forecast hotline. We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline. As always, you can email
Speaker 1:  Vergecast at the berger.com with your questions. You can call 8 6 6 VERGE
Speaker 1:  one one with your questions. We truly, truly love hearing from you.
Speaker 1:  We have a couple that are sparking bigger stories. I think you're gonna hear
Speaker 1:  one of those in the next couple of weeks. Super fun. We've really enjoyed
Speaker 1:  hearing from you and especially right now where it feels like so many things
Speaker 1:  in tech and in the news and in everything else are just kind of up in the
Speaker 1:  air. It's been really fun to just hear you think through stuff. So keep
Speaker 1:  sending us questions, keep sending us thoughts. We love hearing from you
Speaker 1:  today. We have a question about televisions.
Speaker 17:  Hey Vergecast, this is Andrew from calling from Southern
Speaker 17:  California. I've got a question about TVs. I know
Speaker 17:  there's been a lot of recent discussion that a lot
Speaker 17:  of TV brands are making
Speaker 17:  less quality TVs that are designed only to serve you
Speaker 17:  ads and not necessarily to be good presentation machines,
Speaker 17:  but I'm in the market for a new one. I currently have an
Speaker 17:  8-year-old Visio M 50. It's a full
Speaker 17:  array LED, but it's got a dimming zone that's about to die
Speaker 17:  and I'm looking for something new. I was gonna see if you guys could recommend
Speaker 17:  me some sort of TV or where I should start
Speaker 17:  doing research. I don't really have a budget, but
Speaker 17:  I guess it's really, I want something that's high quality but not necessarily
Speaker 17:  top of the line. I can't really afford an A 95 like
Speaker 17:  neli even though I would love to have one. But basically I use an
Speaker 17:  Apple TV pass through a soundbar top box. So I
Speaker 17:  don't really need something with a crazy good os. Sometimes I'll play
Speaker 17:  video games on an Xbox Series X and I'm really starting to get
Speaker 17:  into 4K Blu-rays and eventually I want
Speaker 17:  to buy my own standalone player. So really I was just gonna see if you guys
Speaker 17:  could recommend me anything or any sort of technologies I I should look
Speaker 17:  for in a good quality tv. Thanks
Speaker 1:  Chris Wel is here. Hello Chris.
Speaker 18:  Hello. It's good to be here
Speaker 1:  As you know I am, I am woefully unqualified to be the person to answer this
Speaker 1:  question. Neil, I just makes fun of me for this crappy Roku
Speaker 1:  TCL that sits behind me that I hate slightly more every single day.
Speaker 1:  But I really like this question because it's, it's like it's two questions,
Speaker 1:  right? It's like I, I want a nice TV but I
Speaker 1:  don't wanna spend several paychecks on a television. But it's also like if
Speaker 1:  I just wanna buy a pretty good tv, where do I start? So I wanna, I
Speaker 1:  wanna end with like a specific a recommendation as we can give our friend
Speaker 1:  Andrew here. Yeah. But let's start kind of bigger picture. If you're just
Speaker 1:  like in the market for a pretty good TV right now, where would you start?
Speaker 18:  First of all, shout out to Visio, you know, sad fall from Grace but they
Speaker 18:  used to make great tv so Andrew, they did good choice back on the day, but
Speaker 18:  now it's time for an upgrade. And there are two brands that kind of live
Speaker 18:  in this zone. They're ENS and TCL, the leading mini LED
Speaker 18:  TV makers. We always talk about mini LED being a being like a great value
Speaker 18:  for what, what you pay. You can get like a 65 inch model for like under
Speaker 18:  a thousand dollars right now from like either company with fantastic picture,
Speaker 18:  a great contrast, all the specs you want 4K HDR
Speaker 18:  super bright picture and that's a great value for the money they both ship
Speaker 18:  with via Google TV os, which is fine. I think it's like
Speaker 18:  probably my favorite onboard TV os Yeah. But if you're using Apple TV 4K,
Speaker 18:  you can always just go right to that input and totally ignore it. And so
Speaker 18:  yeah, I think ENS and TCL L are kinda, this is their lane, this is where
Speaker 18:  they live, this is where they dominate and so yeah, that's where I would
Speaker 18:  steer you.
Speaker 1:  Totally. Yeah. And I think the buy a TV and
Speaker 1:  then buy a separate box and plug it straight into the, like go straight to
Speaker 1:  that input when you do It is a hundred percent the
Speaker 1:  right move. Like even
Speaker 18:  Sometimes there are certain TVs, like Sony TVs, like their apps on Sony
Speaker 18:  TVs like use like special processing for like picture performance and enhancement
Speaker 18:  and like you don't get that same processing if you use like an external
Speaker 18:  box. So if you have a Sony TV that's like very specific. But,
Speaker 18:  so that's one reason to like use the onboard apps. And most of them are
Speaker 18:  pretty similar to like what your streaming gadgets can do these days, but
Speaker 18:  they're more up to date on the streaming boxes and Right. Stuff like that.
Speaker 18:  And you can also just ignore all the ads if you've got a Roku TV
Speaker 18:  or you know, these ones from Google that also do like full screen
Speaker 18:  ads. I got a full screen Starbucks ad the other day on my Google tv. Oh.
Speaker 18:  So you know, they're, they're out there.
Speaker 1:  That's, it's rough out there. Yeah, I do feel like I, I am, I am increasingly
Speaker 1:  being radicalized against Roku's operating system, but that's for
Speaker 1:  another day. We'll come back to that. Sure. Yeah. So is is mini
Speaker 1:  LED the one like if you're, if you're just recommending a TV to most people?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, is is a mini LED tv the place to be,
Speaker 18:  That's where I would start. Like unless you wanna pay quite a bit more for
Speaker 18:  an OLAD from LG or Samsung, then I would certainly say stick
Speaker 18:  with the menu. Okay. Mini LED for what you're getting for the value. So
Speaker 18:  yeah, so I would say ENS has the
Speaker 18:  U eight N, that's their flagship mini
Speaker 18:  L-A-D-T-V-T-C-L has the
Speaker 18:  QM eight. They both have eight in the in the name so it's very confusing
Speaker 18:  for some reason. And then Sony also has a pretty good mini LAD called the
Speaker 18:  BRAVIA seven, which is like their kind of mid-tier
Speaker 18:  model. Not quite as many zones the other ones, but it's like a
Speaker 18:  great performing set for what you're paying for it. So those would be my
Speaker 18:  models I'd recommend. But like even like their lower ones, like if you step
Speaker 18:  down from there, like they still have great pictures especially compared
Speaker 18:  to it's like a five-year-old Visio, like a 10-year-old Visio, you're gonna
Speaker 18:  have like a huge jump up in like overall, you know, quality and
Speaker 18:  performance and HDR R is just, yeah, it's good. It's good especially you
Speaker 18:  know, the 4K Blu-ray discs. Good choice there. I hope that's still around
Speaker 18:  in a few years. You know, it seems like physical media is having a tough
Speaker 18:  go but I respect the endeavor so yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So I feel like I, I was thinking about this listening to this question
Speaker 1:  that like I have a very clear sense of what to tell
Speaker 1:  people to spend money on sort of as you wanna upgrade, right? Like you have
Speaker 1:  the, the the sort of base, I know the, I know the screen size I want, I know
Speaker 1:  I want it to be mini LED, right? Like great, those are two good decisions
Speaker 1:  to make very quickly then it's like, do I, how do I sort
Speaker 1:  of slowly step up what is worth paying a little bit more for? What is just
Speaker 1:  nonsense that you don't care about? Do you have a sort of rubric in your
Speaker 1:  head of like how to sort of move up the, the SPECT line of
Speaker 1:  TVs?
Speaker 18:  It's really just brightness. It's all brightness wars these days when it
Speaker 18:  comes to TCL L ENS selling and even Olas year after year, it's just getting
Speaker 18:  brighter and brighter and brighter. It's like, do you want like an eye searing
Speaker 18:  brightness level then you would buy the eight hyen. Like those top tier
Speaker 18:  models, they're too bright for some rooms like my living room, it, it's
Speaker 18:  kind of absurd. But if you want like the most impactful HDR, that's why
Speaker 18:  you buy those TVs plus blooming, these have like so many zones in their
Speaker 18:  TVs now. It's like how they control those like demean zones and like
Speaker 18:  try and cut down on blooming effect where you have like a halo around text
Speaker 18:  or captions and stuff like that. That's something to look out for as you're
Speaker 18:  shopping. So like all these tops, your TVs all have great algorithms that
Speaker 18:  kind of like cut down on pluming and other like bad side effects of having
Speaker 18:  so many dimming zones there in the sets.
Speaker 1:  Okay. What do you, what do you think is the right sort of starting budget
Speaker 1:  for people? I feel like generally speaking, if you, I, if, if all you
Speaker 1:  have is $300 to spend on a tv, buy a 300 tv, right? Like that's fine. But
Speaker 1:  if you're, where do you feel like the very good
Speaker 1:  televisions range starts?
Speaker 18:  So I'd say like a thousand dollars is a pretty good sweet spot right now
Speaker 18:  as far as, okay, that can get you a 65 inch model from the ones I talked
Speaker 18:  about. If you want bigger, you, you know, these companies all
Speaker 18:  make bigger sets. I'm happy with a super modest 65 inch insured, but I know
Speaker 18:  the trend is going towards bigger and bigger and bigger sizes. So that'll
Speaker 18:  cost you, you know, 2000 more if you want like a 75 inch or bigger.
Speaker 18:  But if you want just like a nice very bright 65
Speaker 18:  inch tv, you can spend like 900 bucks or a thousand bucks and be very, very
Speaker 18:  happy for many, many years to come. So.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Okay. Well this is good Andrew. I hope that helps. Now I have a question
Speaker 1:  for you specifically about me and my own television needs. So, okay. As you
Speaker 1:  can see behind me, I, I have, I have a very bright window and
Speaker 1:  the very bright window stares directly at my television. And so what
Speaker 1:  happens is, anytime It is not like
Speaker 1:  pitch black outside, there's just a third of my screen that
Speaker 1:  is just glared to death. I have just come to accept this as like the
Speaker 1:  price of the layout of this room behind me. But this TV
Speaker 1:  is, I don't know, it was crappy five years ago when I bought it and now
Speaker 1:  it's this,
Speaker 1:  can I, if I spend a thousand dollars on a TV right now, can I solve at least
Speaker 1:  enough of my glare problem that I can see things on the TV because it'll
Speaker 1:  be bright enough and better?
Speaker 18:  I'd say so, yeah, for sure. If you want like a true solution, you could
Speaker 18:  buy like one of Samsung's ola TVs 'cause they have like a matte coating
Speaker 18:  on them. Now sheer brightness can help obviously, but as far as like the
Speaker 18:  actual coating on the display, Samsung's Olas have like an anti-glare etched
Speaker 18:  glass type thing. And also that's gonna come to this year's LCD sets.
Speaker 18:  So those shouldn't be quite as expensive. Probably not like a thousand dollars
Speaker 18:  cheap but better. So I would say try those
Speaker 18:  if you want, but Tieszen os is kind of like a headache.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, it's not my favorite. That's where you go with the Apple TV or some
Speaker 18:  other box to plug in. But that would do a great job. But kind of, yeah,
Speaker 18:  that window spot is rough. So I feel for you
Speaker 1:  It's tough man. And it really, I was this, I was trying to watch the
Speaker 1:  Gorge, that Apple TV movie Yeah. The other day down here. And that like
Speaker 1:  a solid third of that movie is basically, it's all dark basically in pitch
Speaker 1:  darkness. Yeah. And I couldn't see it. I literally had to stop the movie
Speaker 1:  'cause I was like, I can't, it's all happening in that like bottom third
Speaker 1:  of the screen that I just can't see. I had to pause the movie and I was like,
Speaker 1:  it's probably time for a new television.
Speaker 18:  Can't you use some curtains or some like smart home sliding something over
Speaker 18:  something to cover that up during, that's movie time.
Speaker 1:  The actual answer is curtains. But the much more fun technology answer
Speaker 1:  is buy a needlessly expensive television. Of course. So I'm, I'm that Stan.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 18:  So that's why we're here. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  All right Chris, thank you very much Andrew. I hope that helps. Let us know
Speaker 1:  what you end up getting and, and we'll, we'll tell you if you made a good
Speaker 1:  decision or not. Thanks Chris.
Speaker 18:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that's it for the first cast this week. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 1:  was on the show. And thank you as always for listening. As always. There's
Speaker 1:  lots more on everything. We talked about all of Jen's robot vacuum coverage,
Speaker 1:  we have Cobo coverage on the site, we have coverage of all the Amazon stuff.
Speaker 1:  We'll put a lot of stuff in the show notes. But you know, keep it locked
Speaker 1:  on the website. Things going on right now. And if you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 1:  feelings, or other robot vacuum features you'd like to see, you can always
Speaker 1:  email Vergecast at the first.com or call the hotline. It's six six Virg
Speaker 1:  one one. We really, really, really, really love hearing from you. This show
Speaker 1:  is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer and Will Poor. The Vergecast is
Speaker 1:  a virgin production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neil, and
Speaker 1:  I'll be back on Friday to talk about all of the news. Whatever Brendan Carr
Speaker 1:  is up to this week. Lots more gadgets. AirPods Max happened. We're gonna
Speaker 1:  talk about those and lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll