# Transcript
ID: 7099d908-8ebf-4179-91eb-0517cabb20da
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8420802413370376526/-5001133113475488095/s93290-US-4721s-1757298755.mp3
Description: Hooked on LinkedIn’s Queens? Gotta extend your Wordle streak in the New York Times games app before you start your day? You’re in good company on today’s Vergecast episode. Allison Johnson is joined by Simon Anthony and Mark Goodliffe, world-class puzzle champs and hosts of the delightful Cracking the Cryptic, a YouTube channel where they solve a puzzle on camera every single day.
They specialize in Sudoku — and not just the classic number games you might be familiar with. Simon and Mark tackle mind-bending, seemingly impossible puzzles, working through it all in realtime, sometimes over the course of several hours. What happens when you get stuck? How can you tell the difference between a puzzle made by a human and a computer-generated one? Why are we addicted to puzzle games all of a sudden? They help us crack the clues.
Then Allison sits down with Marc Levoy, one of the pioneers of computational photography, to talk about his new camera app: Project Indigo. Levoy is known for his earlier work on the Pixel camera, and was a driving force in shaping phone photography into what it is now. We last caught up with him in 2020 when he left Google for Adobe, so we got up to speed on what the heck he’s been doing for the last five years — and the important difference between HDR and an HDR-ish photo.
Finally, Allison takes a hotline question from someone who is not particular about their phone camera’s image quality, but does have a beef with camera bumps.
Cracking the Cryptic — YouTube
This 25-minute video is the most riveting sudoku puzzle you will ever watch
The Atlantic is making a big push into games
I regret to inform you that LinkedIn’s games are very fun
The mastermind of Google’s Pixel camera quietly left the company in March
The brain behind the Google Pixel camera is building a universal camera app for Adobe
Marc Levoy on the balance of camera hardware, software, and artistic expression
Adobe launches a new ‘computational photography’ camera app for iPhones
Adobe’s new camera app is making me rethink phone photography
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (25 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of looking
Speaker 2:  for naked singles. I'm your host, Alison Johnson, and that makes
Speaker 2:  sense In this context, I promise it is a Sudoku thing. And
Speaker 2:  on today's episode, I'm talking to a couple of world champion puzzle
Speaker 2:  solvers who started their own YouTube channel where they
Speaker 2:  solve a Sudoku every day. They're ridiculously hard and
Speaker 2:  surprisingly fun to watch. After that, I'm talking to Mark
Speaker 2:  LaVoy, who's one of the pioneers of computational photography and
Speaker 2:  really just phone camera technology in general. We're gonna talk about his
Speaker 2:  new camera app called Project Indigo. That's all coming up right
Speaker 2:  after the break.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back. I am joined by two very special
Speaker 2:  guests, Simon Anthony. Hi Simon.
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  And Mark. Good lift. Hey Mark. Hi there they are
Speaker 2:  Puzzle champions, but more importantly, the
Speaker 2:  host of a YouTube channel called Cracking the Cryptic. And
Speaker 2:  I guess I'll let you guys explain what that is, what you do there,
Speaker 2:  Simon, maybe can you give our listeners a quick rundown if they're not familiar?
Speaker 6:  I can, but it'll sound mad
Speaker 6:  Cracking. The Cryptic is a YouTube channel where we
Speaker 6:  solve variant Sudoku puzzles, sort of
Speaker 6:  live on camera a couple of times each day.
Speaker 6:  And the channel's been going now for about eight years. Oh my
Speaker 6:  gosh. And it's become really quite popular.
Speaker 6:  So we have about 650,000 subscribers now,
Speaker 6:  and the average length of a video is perhaps 45
Speaker 6:  minutes to an hour. So people are spending time with us
Speaker 6:  every day having a go at these puzzles and then watching us attempt
Speaker 6:  them. Yeah. And, and because it's live, it's all of the
Speaker 6:  mistakes, you know, all of the poor thinking is there, but in the end,
Speaker 6:  hopefully we solve the puzzle and yeah, that's what
Speaker 6:  we do.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And we each post a video every day. And in
Speaker 7:  addition to that, there's a weekly cryptic crossword masterclass as well,
Speaker 7:  and we solve wordle every day as well. So there's a lot of content
Speaker 7:  and it keeps us very busy.
Speaker 2:  I really appreciate the wordle videos. They make me feel,
Speaker 2:  they usually make me feel better. I'm like, okay, this,
Speaker 2:  this wasn't as easy as I thought it was. And if you
Speaker 2:  could explain really quickly, so I, I discovered your channel because I
Speaker 2:  got into Sudoku, but I am more familiar with
Speaker 2:  I think what you would call classic Sudoku. Yeah. Could you
Speaker 2:  explain just the basics of classic Sudoku if people
Speaker 2:  are not familiar, but also what, how it escalates from there
Speaker 2:  and the kind of puzzles that you guys tackle?
Speaker 6:  Sure thing. So in, in normal Sudoku, you get a, a grid
Speaker 6:  of nine by nine cells and you have to put the digits
Speaker 6:  one to nine once each in every row, every column. And then
Speaker 6:  there'll be nine three by three boxes in the or nine by nine
Speaker 6:  grid. And each of those three by three boxes mustn't have a repeated digit
Speaker 6:  either. And that's the game that I think most of us are,
Speaker 6:  were familiar with. When it, it first came to the West, I suppose,
Speaker 6:  which was in early two thousands. And
Speaker 6:  variance Sudoku takes that and sort of turns it up to
Speaker 6:  11. So you might have extra graphics in the grid, there might
Speaker 6:  be a thermometer winding its way through the grid,
Speaker 6:  and you'll have to increase the digits along the
Speaker 6:  thermometer from the bulb end, and then it can get crazier
Speaker 6:  and crazier from there. We've got puzzles now where there's a
Speaker 6:  rat in the grid that has to get to a cupcake going along a certain
Speaker 6:  pathways. Oh my gosh. That we've got puzzles where the most of the
Speaker 6:  grid is covered in fog and you can't see it when
Speaker 6:  you get a correct digit. Some of the fog will clear, so the puzzle is
Speaker 6:  revealed to you gradually. And these puzzles have all
Speaker 6:  been handmade. So they're very, very different to
Speaker 6:  most people's experience of Sudoku, which will be on the
Speaker 6:  back of newspapers. All of those puzzles are
Speaker 6:  made by computers. Okay. Whereas the moment you solve
Speaker 6:  a puzzle that's been created by one of these
Speaker 6:  fantastic human brains, it's a
Speaker 6:  different experience altogether. And I think that's why the channel
Speaker 6:  has become popular, is people are suddenly seeing just the art
Speaker 6:  that can be found in the puzzle form.
Speaker 2:  I find that so interesting because maybe one of the things I do when I
Speaker 2:  get into a thing is be like, how is this made? I want to take it
Speaker 2:  apart, you know? So maybe if you could talk a little bit
Speaker 2:  about how, you mentioned a lot of Sudoku classic
Speaker 2:  Sudokus are computer generated. Were they always like that?
Speaker 2:  Is this like a recent thing and how can you tell the
Speaker 2:  difference? You know?
Speaker 6:  Well, I mean, originally the puzzle was invented in Japan
Speaker 6:  by a company there called Nicki, which is a, a wonderful place of
Speaker 6:  innovation. And all of their puzzles are handmade.
Speaker 6:  But when the puzzle came to the West, it was
Speaker 6:  Wayne Gould originally, I think a New Zealander who had invented a
Speaker 6:  computer program that could just churn out zillions and zillions of puzzles.
Speaker 6:  And he managed to sell it to many of the newspapers in the western world.
Speaker 6:  And so it just became accepted that, you know, you could have
Speaker 6:  computer puzzles and everyone seemed fine with that because they'd never
Speaker 6:  experienced anything different. Whereas
Speaker 6:  when, when you solve a Nicki Classic Sudoku, so the classic Sudokus that
Speaker 6:  you were originally used to, Alison, you know, when you, when you solve one
Speaker 6:  of these nickley puzzles, it's, it's completely different because the
Speaker 6:  constructor has built into the puzzle sort of a
Speaker 6:  trail of breadcrumbs, and you can feel what they
Speaker 6:  want you to find at the particular points. And there's normally some really
Speaker 6:  beautiful logic packed in there, which you just don't find
Speaker 6:  in the machine generator puzzle. So yeah, it's a big
Speaker 6:  difference.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  When we started the channel, we were mainly solving classic
Speaker 7:  Sudokus from say, the New York Times or something, and they would all be
Speaker 7:  computer generated and they would often have a, a very standard
Speaker 7:  kind of trick to get them done. And we would go through that. But
Speaker 7:  then gradually as we got going, we, we wondered would it be interesting to
Speaker 7:  show people the sort of variance sudokus from world Championships that we'd
Speaker 7:  experienced that were a bit more interesting in a way? And
Speaker 7:  unbelievably this whole community grew up watching these
Speaker 7:  videos and going, oh no, that's, that's really interesting.
Speaker 7:  Sudoku, And I think almost all the setters that we feature
Speaker 7:  on the channel now. And we, we basically take submissions from
Speaker 7:  people as, as a good puzzle to do on the channel. Almost all of them
Speaker 7:  grew up learnt about variant Sudoku from our channel.
Speaker 7:  So it's Oh wow. It's marvelously organic in a way.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about the community,
Speaker 2:  because I think there, there's an interesting moment,
Speaker 2:  you know, with, with any kind of creator on the web, you know,
Speaker 2:  whether you run a website or a channel where we're sort of
Speaker 2:  discovering just the real value to having a community. And, and
Speaker 2:  that's kind of what people want. So how do people connect with you?
Speaker 2:  You, you mentioned they suggest puzzles, but how else are you
Speaker 2:  interacting with your community?
Speaker 6:  One of the things that happened to us, we have to bear in mind, we're sort
Speaker 6:  of middle aged guys. We're not tapped into things like
Speaker 6:  Discord, but when the channel started to get bigger, we got
Speaker 6:  approached by some people who watched it and said that you really should
Speaker 6:  have a Discord channel associated with your YouTube
Speaker 6:  channel. And we were like, oh, that, well, that sounds good. And they said,
Speaker 6:  oh, well, we'll take on the sort of role of setting it up for you. And we
Speaker 6:  thought, oh, that'll be nice. I think there are now nearly 40,000
Speaker 6:  people in this Discord server. Oh, wow. And
Speaker 6:  all trading ideas, all solving puzzles for each other,
Speaker 6:  trying to push forward the boundaries of what's possible in
Speaker 6:  Sudoku. I mean, I, I shudder to think what the combined
Speaker 6:  IQ is of the people on there, but it is, there is some
Speaker 6:  serious weapon in terms of intellectual firepower.
Speaker 6:  And one of the lovely things about Cracking the Cryptic is that
Speaker 6:  actually the community is remarkably kind.
Speaker 6:  It's something we've always encouraged, you know, kind comments,
Speaker 6:  positivity, and people really seem to take that to
Speaker 6:  heart. And I think most of the internet now is probably a place where
Speaker 6:  blood pressure gets raised, whereas cracking the crypto is a place where
Speaker 6:  it sort of gets calmed a bit. And yeah, it's attracted
Speaker 6:  people to it who are in general very decent
Speaker 6:  and normally very bright as well. So I get a lot of
Speaker 6:  imposter syndrome, at least I do.
Speaker 2:  Oh my gosh. I mean, having to solve
Speaker 2:  everything live and kind of be on your feet like that, is it a
Speaker 2:  challenge every day? Do you get kind of nervous?
Speaker 7:  It is daunting. It is a worry that you, you sit down in
Speaker 7:  front of a puzzle and if it goes wrong, I mean, if it goes
Speaker 7:  completely wrong and you can't solve it, we don't have to put up a video.
Speaker 7:  So there's always that get out. But that's
Speaker 7:  kind of a rarity I think, for both of us. And, and most of the time,
Speaker 7:  if you do make a mistake, well you have to kind of backtrack and find it
Speaker 7:  and work out what you did wrong. And people are very generous about that
Speaker 7:  as well. I think, as Simon said, the levels of kindness
Speaker 7:  are very high and the, the great setters and
Speaker 7:  theory creators seem very keen to still interact with
Speaker 7:  us, even though I suspect we've been revealed as not the, not the
Speaker 7:  great brains that people maybe thought we were at the beginning.
Speaker 7:  But it is just a pleasure to deal with almost everybody
Speaker 7:  on the site through Discord in the comments. We get
Speaker 7:  emails, we, we put our email address out every day and we get
Speaker 7:  hundreds of emails, as I say, puzzle suggestions, but also lots of
Speaker 7:  general comment. I think we were amazed at the beginning when it started
Speaker 7:  to grow and people would tell us something like, oh, I fall asleep to you
Speaker 7:  every night. And we weren't sure whether that was a compliment or an insult.
Speaker 7:  Right. But gradually there was a period, and it's probably
Speaker 7:  still ongoing, where we get about one email a day
Speaker 7:  about how we've seriously helped someone's mental health
Speaker 7:  to, to, you know, from extreme levels of stress
Speaker 7:  sometimes. Mm. We've had at least three
Speaker 7:  doctors tell us that they would've given up their course, but the calm logic
Speaker 7:  that we allowed them to see enabled them to keep going
Speaker 7:  in their studies. And it's just, it's an amazing thing to have
Speaker 7:  that kind of impact with no, no thought or plan of doing
Speaker 7:  so.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. There is kind of, strikes me as like,
Speaker 2:  solving a puzzle is a pretty solitary activity. I mean,
Speaker 2:  it ha kind of has to be, unless you're doing a jigsaw puzzle with your friends
Speaker 2:  or something, and sort of personal in a way. Like when I
Speaker 2:  sit down to do Wordle every morning, I feel
Speaker 2:  a little embarrassed to like show other people my guesses. You know,
Speaker 2:  you're, you're sort of like, it's sort of like when you talk on the,
Speaker 2:  you're like ordering a pizza on the phone And I don't, I'm like, I don't
Speaker 2:  want anyone else to hear me like working this out.
Speaker 2:  So I wonder if there's an element of just, it, it
Speaker 2:  feels like you're exposing something a little bit and people are
Speaker 2:  connecting to that in a way where it resonates, I
Speaker 2:  guess.
Speaker 6:  I think there, there's definitely something to that. I mean, it is nerve
Speaker 6:  wracking to actually solve and,
Speaker 6:  and because all of the thinking you're doing is live, I mean, I, I still
Speaker 6:  get this, this shot of adrenaline if I have to do mental
Speaker 6:  arithmetic. 'cause some of the arithmetic we have to do, it's, it's,
Speaker 6:  you know, you could be multiplying some reasonably big, you know, two digit
Speaker 6:  numbers or something like that, but you might be having to find the prime
Speaker 6:  factors of something that's not trivial.
Speaker 6:  And it's, it's, you're sort of there thinking, people are gonna be
Speaker 6:  watching me thinking he's so stupid, why can't he do it
Speaker 6:  more quickly? And you, you know, you've got this devil on your
Speaker 6:  shoulder the whole time chirping away about how, how you're being dumb and
Speaker 6:  you have to ignore him because he's, he's just a very annoying
Speaker 6:  creature, but he's definitely there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  We also have different strengths. I think Allison, well sometimes
Speaker 7:  I'm marvel at Simon's instinct for a break in, in a puzzle
Speaker 7:  that's complicated to start, And I just
Speaker 7:  can't see how he's honing in on the right spots as he so often does.
Speaker 7:  He's, I understand jealous of my sort of basic Sudoku
Speaker 7:  mechanics and, and maybe some of that mental arithmetic as well.
Speaker 7:  But, you know, these are the skills that I think are trivial. Whereas he
Speaker 7:  has skills that, you know, I can sit in front of a really hard puzzle
Speaker 7:  for 20 minutes, half an hour, 40 minutes, just not knowing what
Speaker 7:  to do. And it just feels dreadful in a way. But
Speaker 7:  you, you know, you learn over time that if you keep worrying away at it,
Speaker 7:  you can. And this is very important to remember that the
Speaker 7:  constructors are setting you a puzzle that they want you to have fun with
Speaker 7:  and struggle with, but they want you to get there. So there is this
Speaker 7:  trail of logic defined, and when you do light on it,
Speaker 7:  you get this wonderful epiphany. And I think that's what keeps people coming
Speaker 7:  back to the channel, is watching those moments where you
Speaker 7:  suddenly understand something and that's joyful.
Speaker 8:  No, hang on. Maybe it's, no, it is the same. If
Speaker 8:  that's a six, I can't put a one here.
Speaker 8:  And this is a six in box five, which puts a one here, so you can't put a
Speaker 8:  one either side of it. So here we go. So now I've got, now
Speaker 8:  I know that there's a six in this domino, which means this is not a six,
Speaker 8:  this is a six, which means this is a one, this is a two,
Speaker 8:  and we are cooking with gas all of a sudden.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't know if I'm just like keying into this because
Speaker 2:  I've been interested in Sudoku, but there's
Speaker 2:  a lot of, like puzzles seem to be having a moment. Like
Speaker 2:  I know, yeah. A friend of mine is addicted to the puzzles
Speaker 2:  in the LinkedIn app and like Yeah. Opens
Speaker 2:  LinkedIn every day. And I, I'm sure there's an element of they've
Speaker 2:  discovered, you know, they can keep people coming back every day and get
Speaker 2:  those like daily user numbers up. But what do you think
Speaker 2:  that says about like BBR moment culturally,
Speaker 2:  or what puzzles are doing for people?
Speaker 6:  I think there's a, there's a lot to unpack there. I mean, I think LinkedIn
Speaker 6:  has really, it, it dodges most office firewalls
Speaker 6:  of course, which means that it's absolutely brilliant if you, if you're,
Speaker 6:  if you enjoy having a few minutes out every day and you
Speaker 6:  can, a lot of puzzle websites tend to be blocked from my
Speaker 6:  experience, but LinkedIn probably won't be, you know, so
Speaker 6:  that's a good thing. But I also, I sense that there is being
Speaker 6:  a bit geeky or nerdy, which I've been throughout my life. I mean,
Speaker 2:  Same,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I've never, never been cool popular,
Speaker 6:  I mean, my sister has relished throughout my life, you know, telling me
Speaker 6:  how, you know, useless, I am in all social situations,
Speaker 6:  but now it just feels, I, I dunno whether it's AI
Speaker 6:  or, you know, computer programming becoming, it's
Speaker 6:  everywhere, isn't it? And so necessary for so many parts of life.
Speaker 6:  But it feels like, oh, the popularity of things like
Speaker 6:  escape rooms as well. Mm. Or maybe it's the mindfulness that
Speaker 6:  comes with doing puzzles as you've found. You, you're sort of, when you,
Speaker 6:  when you actually have to focus on a puzzle, you're taken away
Speaker 6:  from maybe the worries of life for a few minutes, you have to focus on what
Speaker 6:  you're doing or you probably won't get very far and it brings a
Speaker 6:  calmness. And maybe people value that in this
Speaker 6:  day and age more than they perhaps would've done 15,
Speaker 6:  20 years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I think the way you expressed it, Alison, is absolutely right. Puzzles are
Speaker 7:  having their moment. But in a way, what it is, is I think people are
Speaker 7:  in this moment discovering puzzles and finding out how, how much
Speaker 7:  fun they are. I come from originally before Sudoku from a
Speaker 7:  world of cry crosswords, and people have often asked me, why,
Speaker 7:  you know, why are you doing, oh now, now it's obvious. But in the old days
Speaker 7:  they would ask me, why are you doing this old man's pursuit? And I was saying,
Speaker 7:  well, it's not, doesn't have to be. Basically, once you find the joy of
Speaker 7:  cryptic crosswords, there's no reason ever to stop doing them. And people
Speaker 7:  don't, and therefore the average age tends to skew older
Speaker 7:  than for pursuits that people will give up when they've had their fill. But
Speaker 7:  you don't do that. And I think it's true about Sudoku as well. People stay
Speaker 7:  with it even if they don't stay with our channel. I think they stay with
Speaker 7:  Sudoku and with puzzles and, you know, we've been part,
Speaker 7:  perhaps of leading people to discover puzzles. And that's
Speaker 7:  great. And I think it's more that people are sort of free to enjoy them now
Speaker 7:  rather than that they, that they hadn't thought of them before.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious actually about kind of the tools you use
Speaker 2:  in your puzzles, because I think Mamie, Simon, you
Speaker 2:  mentioned in a video that you sort of prefer puzzles
Speaker 2:  that you can just think through and there are
Speaker 2:  tools that exist for super hard
Speaker 2:  Sudoku that like help you math your way
Speaker 2:  out of it. I don't know, can you, can you kind of talk me through like the
Speaker 2:  tools you do and don't use when you are solving puzzles?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, we both use compute obviously because we're, we're
Speaker 6:  recording something we're doing on a computer. We have some great software
Speaker 6:  that's been created by VE Neumann, which
Speaker 6:  is very, very good. It allows us to
Speaker 6:  employ some techniques that are much harder to do if you've just got a pencil.
Speaker 6:  So for example, we can color in cells or we could even
Speaker 6:  draw lines through cells. And when we're solving these
Speaker 6:  harder puzzles, things like that, they're pretty useful.
Speaker 6:  The software even I, I mean, we don't use it, but it'll allow you to
Speaker 6:  compute all the different ways of adding up to 25 with four digits.
Speaker 6:  It'll actually give you a list of all the ways that, that you can do that.
Speaker 6:  So if you don't like doing the arithmetic, you can still,
Speaker 6:  you know, access the puzzle. But I think as, as with
Speaker 6:  anything, what you find is you build up your own personal tool
Speaker 6:  of, I don't know, tricks, techniques, and you
Speaker 6:  cycle through those. And that only really comes with experience.
Speaker 6:  And I guess now Mark And I have a lot of experience, so we've got something
Speaker 6:  like 4,000 videos now, mark,
Speaker 2:  Oh my gosh,
Speaker 7:  I think it may be 5,000 now.
Speaker 6:  Okay. 5,000 now. It's incredible.
Speaker 2:  Oh, wow. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's, it's a back catalog.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It, it's, you do build up a lot of experience and it's often very helpful.
Speaker 7:  And yet still, every few months, something completely new
Speaker 7:  is kind of forced in upon us by a brilliant constructor.
Speaker 7:  And we learned something totally new about even sometimes about a
Speaker 7:  basic Sudoku grid that it, it must have some property that we didn't know
Speaker 7:  before. And that, you know, I still think in some ways this is
Speaker 7:  the dawn of Sudoku, which is brilliant
Speaker 6:  Mark's. Right. I mean, there, there was a mad thing we discovered the other
Speaker 6:  day for the first time, which is sort of, if you check, imagine that you've
Speaker 6:  checkerboarded your Sudoku, the sort
Speaker 6:  of internal checkerboard you've created, any digit
Speaker 6:  you put in that has to appear an even number of times in that internal
Speaker 6:  checkerboard, which it's like, why, why,
Speaker 6:  why is that
Speaker 2:  True?
Speaker 6:  And, and yet sort of geometrically mathematically it is true,
Speaker 6:  but we, we didn't know it. I didn't know it before I did that puzzle. It
Speaker 6:  was completely, it's like, it's, it's a truth that exists
Speaker 6:  underneath the surface of the puzzle.
Speaker 7:  It's not gonna help you solve a classic Sudoku, but it's there and it's
Speaker 7:  just sitting there like a, a mathematical truth. It's extraordinary.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There, there is something really satisfying, I think, in, in
Speaker 2:  discovering new layers of something you've been enjoying. Yeah. I do
Speaker 2:  wanna touch on a puzzle you did, and this was,
Speaker 2:  I guess, went viral. We wrote about it on The
Speaker 2:  Verge. Oh, this was the Miracle Sudoku, is that right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Can you, and Simon, you, you solved this one. Can you describe
Speaker 2:  what this puzzle was and kind of how it went?
Speaker 6:  Well, I, I can, I mean, but really it was Mark's fault. So
Speaker 6:  what what happened was we got sent a
Speaker 6:  puzzle by a structor called Mitchell Lee.
Speaker 6:  And the very, very unusual thing at the time about this puzzle was, it looked
Speaker 6:  like a normal Sudoku, except rather than having several digits in the grid,
Speaker 6:  there were only two digits in the grid. It was a one
Speaker 6:  and a two, and that was it. And Mark
Speaker 6:  sent me an email and said, it would be good if you opened this live on camera.
Speaker 6:  So I took him at his word, set up my machine, loaded it, having
Speaker 6:  started the recording and was faced with this at that
Speaker 6:  time, it just looked, it looked stupid. I thought he'd just done it as a
Speaker 6:  joke. Let me
Speaker 9:  Just see if I can put that in there. Let's see
Speaker 9:  what we get. Right.
Speaker 9:  He is got to be joking.
Speaker 9:  There
Speaker 9:  is no way that this, well, it might have a unique
Speaker 9:  solution, but it's not gonna be findable by a human being.
Speaker 9:  I suspect this is going to be a short video because he is
Speaker 9:  trolling me.
Speaker 6:  And so I very nearly thank goodness I didn't, I very nearly turned
Speaker 6:  off the webcam and sort of called him in high dungeon.
Speaker 6:  But no, I, I could see one thing at the start that I could possibly do.
Speaker 6:  And so I did the thing, and then it was amazing after,
Speaker 6:  you know, a few more steps, I could see something else. And it was one
Speaker 6:  of those puzzles where you sort of, it was like a snowball, you starting
Speaker 6:  an avalanche, all of a sudden you could, this pattern emerged
Speaker 6:  and you could, at the end, I did solve it. And I think the reason it was
Speaker 6:  popular was just my sheer astonishment that, that
Speaker 6:  this could exist. That that, that you could, yeah. That,
Speaker 6:  that somebody had had the idea that somebody had made it,
Speaker 7:  And also that this impossibility was actually solved in about
Speaker 7:  25 minutes. It was just bizarre. It was bizarre
Speaker 7:  exactly my finding when I, when I tried it before Simon had
Speaker 7:  seen it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And something if, if people aren't familiar with the channel, you
Speaker 2:  can solve along with these puzzles. So
Speaker 2:  that's exactly what I did, you know, watched you get started with
Speaker 2:  it, and then yeah, you, you look at it, you're like, there's no way
Speaker 2:  this could be solvable, but I saw you, you know, go through the first kind
Speaker 2:  of steps and tried it on my own. And it, you
Speaker 2:  know, I had to like rewind a couple times and see what you were doing.
Speaker 2:  But it's so cool to kind of go on that journey with you where I'm like,
Speaker 2:  oh my God, I am solving this, this. Yeah. Just,
Speaker 2:  I had a lot of fun with it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, it was, it was remarkable. I mean, we, we got,
Speaker 6:  we got emails from all over the world as a result of that. It was, it
Speaker 6:  was like a moment where, you know, they say everyone, everybody has their
Speaker 6:  15 or five minutes of fame. It was like that spotlight
Speaker 6:  suddenly turned on us for a, for just a, just a scintilla of time. And
Speaker 6:  you sort of got a bit of the glare of a little bit of publicity, and it was,
Speaker 6:  it was very enjoyable because it was so brief and unexpected.
Speaker 2:  Hmm. Yeah. And a, a positive, I think, you know, of people
Speaker 2:  are discovering it and having like a
Speaker 2:  joyful moment of like, I can't believe I just watched this 25 minute
Speaker 2:  long video, which is, I think, interesting, and you
Speaker 2:  kind of touched on this. I think that your videos are long,
Speaker 2:  like, you know, comparatively in, in the age of
Speaker 2:  certainly TikTok, where you watch for a few seconds
Speaker 2:  and scroll on, can you talk a little bit about
Speaker 2:  why you're able to enjoy having such a long
Speaker 2:  amount of time to show what you're doing and talk about what
Speaker 2:  you're doing? And
Speaker 7:  We, we thought that people would just wanna see the technique, would just
Speaker 7:  want the lesson. And then we kind of thought, well, they won't wanna watch
Speaker 7:  the rest of the solve that's just filling in the numbers. And we, we would
Speaker 7:  try things like speeding it up or putting music to it, and they got
Speaker 7:  really annoyed. They said, no, no, no, no, we wanna see you solve it till
Speaker 7:  the end. And it is, I think it's what you said earlier, that
Speaker 7:  people want to come on the journey of the solve, and they want to be part
Speaker 7:  of it all the way. Some people treat it like sport, like a spectator
Speaker 7:  sport. And until you put the last digit in, the final whistle doesn't blow.
Speaker 7:  So it's, it's still going. And, and
Speaker 7:  that extends into the longer videos. I mean, Simon's done videos,
Speaker 7:  is it three hours you've done now, Simon, in a, in a
Speaker 7:  single puzzle,
Speaker 6:  Four hours, 10 minutes, gosh, is the longest puzzle.
Speaker 6:  And wow, you, you'd think, oh, well that can't be popular because how could,
Speaker 6:  how could it possibly be the case that anybody would want to watch a
Speaker 6:  man solve a Sudoku puzzle for longer than the extended
Speaker 6:  edition of Return of the King or something? It cannot be, it
Speaker 6:  cannot be. Right. And yet, and yet it's one of our
Speaker 6:  most popular videos of recent times.
Speaker 6:  It's like they, people get invested in it. And then In fact,
Speaker 6:  on that video, as one of my favorite comments underneath the
Speaker 6:  video that we've ever had,
Speaker 7:  I think they love
Speaker 2:  come back, we're gonna be talking to Mark LaVoy about his new camera app,
Speaker 2:  Project Indigo. It's coming right up.
Speaker 2:  I am joined by someone who, for a portion of our
Speaker 2:  audience will not need an introduction, but we'll do an anyway, I'm here
Speaker 2:  with Mark LaVoy. Hey Mark.
Speaker 14:  Hi, nice to be with you.
Speaker 2:  Thanks for joining. Mark LaVoy is a professor
Speaker 2:  emeritus of computer science at Stanford, but right now and
Speaker 2:  what we're gonna be talking about, he is a VP and fellow at Adobe
Speaker 2:  where he has been working on a new camera app, also known
Speaker 2:  to a lot of people in our audience in particular for his work on Google
Speaker 2:  Pixel camera for for many years. So thank you for joining
Speaker 2:  me.
Speaker 14:  It's great to be here. So
Speaker 2:  I was wondering if you could give us maybe a
Speaker 2:  shortened version of your bio. There's a lot of interesting stuff on
Speaker 2:  there, you know, some of which I just touched on, but then catch
Speaker 2:  us up a little bit on what you've been doing since you've been at Adobe.
Speaker 14:  Shortened version of the bio. Well, I seem to
Speaker 14:  have wandered from topic to topic roughly every 10 years. Okay.
Speaker 14:  So in the seventies, I worked on computer assisted cartoon animation
Speaker 14:  at, at Cornell in the eighties. I worked on medical imaging
Speaker 14:  at University of North Carolina, and then at Stanford in the
Speaker 14:  1990s, I worked on three dimensional scanning, including the digital
Speaker 14:  Michelangelo project. In the two thousands, I worked on light fields
Speaker 14:  and camera arrays, built some big camera arrays at Stanford.
Speaker 14:  And in the 2010s, largely at Google, I worked on
Speaker 14:  computational photography, including, as you said, for the pixel
Speaker 14:  phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You joined Adobe in 2020, is that right?
Speaker 14:  Right, during the height of the pandemic.
Speaker 2:  Ah, an interesting time to switch jobs. I did it too.
Speaker 14:  Indeed. Indeed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So, and you spoke to our, our editor in chief,
Speaker 2:  Neil Patel around that time, and the
Speaker 2:  stated goal was to create a universal camera app.
Speaker 2:  And it's been five years since then you've released
Speaker 2:  that camera app called Project Indigo. Can you give people the quick
Speaker 2:  elevator pitch if they're not familiar with it? I know a lot of our audience
Speaker 2:  is.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. It depends how long the elevator it is. So the basic idea there
Speaker 14:  is, there are a number of limitations of most smartphone camera apps.
Speaker 14:  I'm certainly familiar with those limitations. There's a smartphone
Speaker 14:  look that a lot of people don't like that might look okay on the
Speaker 14:  small screen or in bad lighting, but don't look okay. If you look at that
Speaker 14:  same image, large, it's very bright, it's
Speaker 14:  contrasty. The shadows have been raised a lot. The edges are very
Speaker 14:  sharp, the saturation is boosted. It, it's a certain look,
Speaker 14:  as I said, it might look fine on your screen, but not if you're trying to
Speaker 14:  make something larger out of it or even look at it on a large screen.
Speaker 14:  Another issue with most smartphone camera apps is they don't offer much
Speaker 14:  in the way of manual control. Some of the third party apps do, but
Speaker 14:  then they don't offer the third thing, which is computational photography.
Speaker 14:  So our computational photography, meaning combining multiple images to
Speaker 14:  make a better quality image regardless of the look.
Speaker 14:  So we wanted to combine all three of those things, a more natural
Speaker 14:  look, full manual controls, and the best computational
Speaker 14:  photography the state of the art allows.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 14:  We also wanted to release some fun stuff on the side. So
Speaker 14:  we have synthetic lung exposure, we have removing window
Speaker 14:  reflections, which also ships in light room and camera raw.
Speaker 2:  You call this look kind of HDR ish, which is
Speaker 2:  I think a different thing from HDR as a term.
Speaker 2:  Am I right in thinking that, do you have that same kind of sense of it? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  yeah, yeah.
Speaker 14:  It, it's a little bit confusing. So HDR just means that there's some way
Speaker 14:  you can display stuff that's really bright and
Speaker 14:  to some extent just the hardware of the, of the phones allow
Speaker 14:  this. They are very, very bright and certainly some
Speaker 14:  display screens, computer monitor screens are also very bright.
Speaker 14:  They're these great ads or reviews where someone puts on a pair of sunglasses
Speaker 14:  before they even look at their screen. So that gives the capability to
Speaker 14:  display HDR, but the real world can
Speaker 14:  be even brighter and not all phones can
Speaker 14:  display HDR as being really bright. So in either one of those cases,
Speaker 14:  a scene that's really bright or a display that's not so bright,
Speaker 14:  you need to tone map it in a way that fits all of the dynamic
Speaker 14:  range, meaning the range from black to white into whatever
Speaker 14:  the display can do that usually involves lowering the
Speaker 14:  highlights and raising the shadows. If you do too
Speaker 14:  much of that, that's what people call the HDR ish
Speaker 14:  look.
Speaker 2:  Can you talk a little bit about like how we ended up here with this look?
Speaker 14:  Well, they want the whole image to be readable and they
Speaker 14:  want people to be able to take photographs in very challenging lighting.
Speaker 14:  So they'll take a backlit portrait with a sunset in the background
Speaker 14:  at the beach, but they still want to be able to see the features of the
Speaker 14:  person who is silhouetted. That's a very high
Speaker 14:  dynamic range situation, and they'd like to be able to share it. So
Speaker 14:  they want it to look readable. And so they'll raise the
Speaker 14:  shadows a lot. And that can lead to this HDR ish look.
Speaker 14:  In particular, if you're looking at a small screen in bad lighting. So bad
Speaker 14:  lighting might, for example, be a very bright day where there is glare
Speaker 14:  on the phone surface. Then they want to make
Speaker 14:  sure it's readable there too. And so they'll raise the shadows and lower
Speaker 14:  highlights. But if you take that same image and look at it in a slightly
Speaker 14:  darkened room or on a larger screen, then that's where it
Speaker 14:  begins to look, as you said, grayish or too squished toward the
Speaker 14:  middle.
Speaker 2:  In the past few years, maybe it's been kind of brewing longer than this.
Speaker 2:  You know, the ultra HDR format has kind of come to
Speaker 2:  prominence, which is related and sort of in the mix here,
Speaker 2:  but is a different thing than, than the two things we were just talking
Speaker 2:  about. Can you explain what that is? I know you know,
Speaker 2:  Android supports ultra HDR, apple has a version
Speaker 2:  they support just what is this at the basics?
Speaker 14:  So both of those are closely related to, and we're
Speaker 14:  co-developed with Adobe's format for
Speaker 14:  representing hydrodynamic range images. As a matter of fact,
Speaker 14:  Apple's, Paul Huble and Adobe's, Eric Chan
Speaker 14:  presented the format together at a conference. Okay. So it's really
Speaker 14:  a co-development. Ultra HDR is just a brand name. The
Speaker 14:  basic idea is that a file ought to contain
Speaker 14:  two images, a base image, which is what
Speaker 14:  you would display if you only had a standard dynamic range display.
Speaker 14:  In other words, not a super bright display, SDR
Speaker 14:  for short. And a separate image, which is what's often called
Speaker 14:  a gain map. Meaning how much would I add to that
Speaker 14:  if I had a brighter display? And that's the, the highlights part of it.
Speaker 14:  Now it's a little bit more complicated than that. It can be done as either
Speaker 14:  an addition or a subtraction. But that's kind of the basic idea that there
Speaker 14:  are these two images and if you have an HDR display, then the
Speaker 14:  idea is that the viewer, meaning, for example, the browser software
Speaker 14:  would add the two together and then display that. So that's what all of
Speaker 14:  these HDR formats have. There are other
Speaker 14:  HDR formats, A VV has one, but the world seems to be
Speaker 14:  moving gradually toward either the ultra HDR or Apple's H
Speaker 14:  format or ours, which is this JPEG
Speaker 14:  that has a base image, which is SDR and A base plus
Speaker 14:  gain a gain map, which gives you HDR.
Speaker 2:  Why does this one seem to be the one we're landing on? And
Speaker 2:  does it solve our problems with HDR and HDR
Speaker 2:  displays and HDR ish photos?
Speaker 14:  It's arguably better than the other ones because it really kind of separates
Speaker 14:  out, here's what you would see if you had it only at SDR display and here's
Speaker 14:  what you would see if you had an HDR display. And it also means that
Speaker 14:  in image editors like Lightroom, you could separately
Speaker 14:  tune the two looks. Mm. Because you might want a different crushing
Speaker 14:  of shadows or lowering of highlights for standard dynamic range
Speaker 14:  display and for hydrodynamic range display. Or you might
Speaker 14:  just want an SDR image and you never want the highlights to be bright. And
Speaker 14:  so in Lightroom, again, you could toggle off the HDR
Speaker 14:  and just sit there and adjust for SDR. So it's a good
Speaker 14:  format. I don't know if it's the best ever, but it's a good format.
Speaker 14:  And it's nice to see that it's being gradually adopted.
Speaker 14:  Gradually of course is very gradually in this fragmented world
Speaker 14:  of ours. So social media apps are only slowly
Speaker 14:  coming on board with this format.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There's so many components to it. There's the, you know,
Speaker 2:  the camera, there's the display on the camera, there's where
Speaker 2:  the photo eventually ends up the display of the person who's
Speaker 2:  looking at that photo on Instagram. And I think
Speaker 2:  something I've seen in me, I, you can let me know if, if you've seen
Speaker 2:  this too or not, but I'm seeing kind of an
Speaker 2:  association from photography kind of like
Speaker 2:  literate people where they, they have just gotten a bad taste in
Speaker 2:  their mouth with HDR and they sort of say HDR
Speaker 2:  is a be like a dirty word. I'm trying to
Speaker 2:  evangelize the ultra HDR a little bit. You know, like this is a different
Speaker 2:  thing. Do you see that conflation happening?
Speaker 14:  Absolutely. I think you're, you're right. But what they're conflating is
Speaker 14:  the ability to display HDR and the particular
Speaker 14:  tone mapping and look that has been used on
Speaker 14:  HDR capable photographs. And that's this overtone mapped
Speaker 14:  thing. And so I think it's possible to display HDR
Speaker 14:  images in a way that doesn't have this look.
Speaker 14:  Interestingly, it's also possible to overdo the look on purpose in a way
Speaker 14:  that's actually artistic. And one person I think of
Speaker 14:  there is Trey Ratcliffe and stuck in customs. He's got this
Speaker 14:  great image, one of his signature images of the landscaper
Speaker 14:  on Guin in China that is ultra wide ankle
Speaker 14:  and very overtone mapped on purpose and made saturated
Speaker 14:  in a way that makes it look like a fairytale landscape. So that's
Speaker 14:  art, right? It's obviously not the way it looked, but everyone
Speaker 14:  knows that when they look at it. So I'm separating out this art
Speaker 14:  from it. But for ordinary photography, I think you're right.
Speaker 14:  But the answer is that it's, it's in the tone mapping. Yeah. There's nothing
Speaker 14:  inherently wrong with the HDR capability.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Well I'm telling everyone that Mark LaVoy says I'm right and
Speaker 2:  I'll, I'll take that to my grave.
Speaker 14:  You know, the, the one funny thing about this is there were videos made
Speaker 14:  while I was at Google about, oh, the look of pixel phones is learning from
Speaker 14:  Italian art. Hmm. And I talked about my preference for
Speaker 14:  Caravaggio and so on and so on. Well, those are all standard
Speaker 14:  dynamic range images. They're just reflective, they're not luminous.
Speaker 14:  They can't do anything brighter than the white of the gallery wall.
Speaker 14:  And so we sort of do need different models
Speaker 14:  and artistic models and a different artistic exploration as
Speaker 14:  we start to do hydrodynamic range. And I think the world is still
Speaker 14:  experimenting Yeah. With what it ought to look like.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. How far is too far? What do, what do we all like
Speaker 2:  and dislike? Yeah. Right. How did you think about that going
Speaker 2:  into developing your camera app? You know, I've used the app
Speaker 2:  certainly quite a bit. I know a lot of our readers have, but the
Speaker 2:  kinds of things that people can expect maybe as far as
Speaker 2:  HDR processing when they use Project Indigo.
Speaker 14:  Right. So I led a team of people
Speaker 14:  who determined the taste for the early pixel cameras. I, I
Speaker 14:  don't know if I would go so far as to say I was the taste, but I was one
Speaker 14:  of them here at Adobe. I've let Florian kinds
Speaker 14:  who co-wrote the blog with me be the lead tastemaker. And
Speaker 14:  you can see his taste in, in all the photographs that are on the blog.
Speaker 14:  They look natural. They look like, oh, if I were there, I know what
Speaker 14:  I would've seen. They don't look like there's been some deliberate adjustment
Speaker 14:  in tone mapping. They look like if I had an SLR with
Speaker 14:  enough dynamic range, mm. That might've been what the picture looked like.
Speaker 14:  And so one of the characteristics is let dark
Speaker 14:  shadows be dark. Hmm. Amen. And I think a lot of
Speaker 14:  people just like that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I know I do.
Speaker 14:  There's, to be honest, we've kind of fell into this moment
Speaker 14:  of a trend toward retro and toward film looks,
Speaker 14:  which are more natural looks because there's no adjustable
Speaker 14:  tone mapping or there's very, there are fewer ways of doing adjustable tone
Speaker 14:  mapping in film and people like that. And they sort
Speaker 14:  of hea asiah of relief like, okay, you know, that looks like a
Speaker 14:  plausible scene and the darks are dark and we
Speaker 14:  like dark because it's the et cetera principle. You know,
Speaker 14:  what's the mystery in that dark area there? And
Speaker 14:  I like that and Florian likes that. So that's kind of what
Speaker 14:  we allowed to happen on on Indigo. Yeah. I should point out though,
Speaker 14:  that it's a profile, if you load it into a Lightroom or camera
Speaker 14:  raw, it shows up, says Indigo, and you
Speaker 14:  can change it. In particular, if you've been capturing dgs,
Speaker 14:  which means raw images, you can change it to any profile you want.
Speaker 14:  You can add presets to it, you can make your own look. So it's not
Speaker 14:  like we're demanding that this is the look that you would produce
Speaker 14:  with that app. It's our suggested look, but you can change it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And kind of along the same lines, I wonder if you can talk about
Speaker 2:  the raw capabilities. I am someone who kind of
Speaker 2:  poo-poos shooting raw on a smartphone. I am tend to wanna
Speaker 2:  let, let it just do its thing. And that might be maybe, maybe
Speaker 2:  a older way of thinking about smartphone photography,
Speaker 2:  especially with Computational Raw, which you've brought into
Speaker 2:  Project Indigo. Could you explain quickly what that is and
Speaker 2:  why that was important to have?
Speaker 14:  Right. So if you do JPEG only with Indigo,
Speaker 14:  you'll get our look. If you bring it into
Speaker 14:  an image editor, a Lightroom or any other editor, you can make
Speaker 14:  minor tweaks on it, but you can't do anything really major
Speaker 14:  because the characteristic of any of these tone mapping methods
Speaker 14:  is that the highlights in one part of the image
Speaker 14:  might be the same pixel value as the shadows in another part of the
Speaker 14:  image. And So if you use sliders or tone curves
Speaker 14:  or anything to raise one or lower one, you might
Speaker 14:  raise or lower other things you didn't want to lower or raise. Even though
Speaker 14:  they were actually different brightnesses in the original scene, they got
Speaker 14:  tone mapped to be the same pixel value. So this is
Speaker 14:  the main reason why people like shooting raw, because the,
Speaker 14:  the numbers that are in the file represent relative
Speaker 14:  scene brightnesses just as sensed.
Speaker 14:  And then you can keep the shadows separate from the highlights if you wanted
Speaker 14:  to. So that's the main reason for shooting raw. Now
Speaker 14:  you say you don't really like or have not really shot raw on
Speaker 14:  smartphones. So the reason for that is that the raws
Speaker 14:  have not been very good. They both don't come with a very good look.
Speaker 14:  And they often don't come with computational photography or enough
Speaker 14:  computational photography. So in low light they look noisy
Speaker 14:  on some phones, which I won't name. If you switched into raw
Speaker 14:  mode, it would take a single frame and end up
Speaker 14:  being very noisy because the smartphone sensors are small.
Speaker 14:  So the right thing is do this computational
Speaker 14:  photography where you align and combine multiple frames
Speaker 14:  even to produce the raw. Now some purists would say,
Speaker 14:  well that's not raw anymore because it was captured over a number of frames.
Speaker 14:  That's true. But it still has the major characteristic of
Speaker 14:  raw that it's proportional to seen brightness. And you can do any
Speaker 14:  editing you want without worrying that you're adjusting both shadows and
Speaker 14:  highlights at the same time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 14:  So I do recommend that you try raw in
Speaker 14:  Indigo. I think you'll like it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. And I have made an exception for Indigo, definitely.
Speaker 2:  Just, just knowing I'm not throwing away a bunch of extra frames and extra
Speaker 2:  data. Yeah. It's been a totally different experience shooting with the phone.
Speaker 2:  I, I use the phone cameras on every major
Speaker 2:  phone, you know, released in this country. And this app
Speaker 2:  really made me think about it differently. So one
Speaker 14:  Characteristic, I mean, there, there are trade-offs, you know, why didn't
Speaker 14:  everyone else do the same thing we did? Well, we're capturing more frames.
Speaker 14:  It takes longer to put them together. You have to be a bit more patient
Speaker 14:  between shots, particularly in low light. So there are
Speaker 14:  trade-offs to be made. Yeah. And we made a particular trade off
Speaker 14:  favoring the more serious photographer, the one who cared more
Speaker 14:  about image quality and adjustment after the fact.
Speaker 2:  I think someone who really wants to get into the nuts and bolts of
Speaker 2:  photography, it sort of speaks that love language where just
Speaker 2:  right from the onboarding screens, you know, you, you
Speaker 2:  learn a lot about what the camera's doing and how things
Speaker 2:  will be processed. And with your background as a a
Speaker 2:  teacher, I wonder how that, did this feel like a
Speaker 2:  natural kind of fit? Did you find as you were developing this app, you
Speaker 2:  you were sort of bringing that part of your background along too?
Speaker 14:  Yeah, I love teaching. Maybe I sometimes talk too much,
Speaker 14:  but I want people to understand. And so the last course
Speaker 14:  I taught before I left Stanford first for Google and then for Adobe
Speaker 14:  was a course on digital photography. And I would teach both the art
Speaker 14:  and the science. You know, why do we want to combine images?
Speaker 14:  Where does this noise come from? What are aberrations on
Speaker 14:  lenses and things like that. And so that kind
Speaker 14:  of spilled over onto the explanations that I made both in the blog and
Speaker 14:  on the opening screens in Indigo. I want people to understand,
Speaker 2:  How do you think about that? Maybe line is the wrong word, like a
Speaker 2:  line between the art and the science. I think in photography
Speaker 2:  especially, people can get kind of, they'll wanna
Speaker 2:  dive into one or the other and they'll see, you know, they wanna know everything
Speaker 2:  about how the, the camera's working and they get into the, the nuts and
Speaker 2:  bolts or they don't wanna get into all that and they feel like
Speaker 2:  it detracts from enjoying the art. How do you see that?
Speaker 2:  Are those two opposing things? Can you exist
Speaker 2:  in two different states at once?
Speaker 14:  I don't consider them opposing at all. I do understand tastes that some
Speaker 14:  people are just nerds about the science and some people are nerds about
Speaker 14:  the art. One of my heroes is Ansel Adams.
Speaker 14:  Hmm. So Ansel Adams, first of all was a teacher in addition to being a great
Speaker 14:  artist, but he also embraced both the art and the
Speaker 14:  science of photography. He wrote three amazing books,
Speaker 14:  the camera, the Negative, and the print, which are quite
Speaker 14:  scientific and full of careful illustrations of how
Speaker 14:  perspective works and the zone system for exposure and so
Speaker 14:  on. I had a chance once to ask one of his assistants, his longtime
Speaker 14:  assistants, would he have embraced digital photography?
Speaker 14:  Hmm. He did have a chance to test a very early digital camera, but would
Speaker 14:  have, he, would he have embraced it for his photography? And without a moment's
Speaker 14:  hesitation, the the assistant said, of course he would've. Hmm.
Speaker 14:  Just look at his work and his books.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it, it makes sense. And I think a lot of photography
Speaker 2:  conversations go back to Ansel Adams sort of inevitably when you
Speaker 2:  talk about processing Photoshop, you know,
Speaker 2:  maybe even the moment we're in right now with generative ai,
Speaker 2:  there, you, you kind of can trace back to like,
Speaker 2:  when we think of photography as this, you know, you're
Speaker 2:  just, it's just photons hitting a piece of film or a sensor.
Speaker 2:  But the way Ansel Adams, you know, manipulated images and
Speaker 2:  the things he did in the dark room, people are maybe not aware
Speaker 2:  of.
Speaker 14:  Exactly. And not only that, so, so first of all, you're exactly right about
Speaker 14:  the manipulations in the dark room. His dodging and burning, which
Speaker 14:  many photographers know about is local tone mapping. It's the same as this
Speaker 14:  raising the shadows in one part of the image and lowering the highlights
Speaker 14:  in another part of the image, but maybe not in all parts of the image that's
Speaker 14:  just dodging and burning. But more than that, he was open
Speaker 14:  about it and taught about it. He has one great book that is
Speaker 14:  the making of 40 photographs I think it's called. And he shows the
Speaker 14:  original and the version after he has fiddled with it
Speaker 14:  in the darkroom or interpret it in the darkroom. In fact, one of
Speaker 14:  his most famous pictures, the Clearing winter storm in Yosemite is a great
Speaker 14:  example that I used to show in my photography course at Stanford
Speaker 14:  of the original, which is surprisingly, I wouldn't say
Speaker 14:  bland, but fairly even toned and
Speaker 14:  not nearly as exciting as his version after dodging and burning. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  And he would explain what he did and why
Speaker 2:  It's such a joy to hear someone who is so immersed
Speaker 2:  in what they do and has such a love for it and the, the
Speaker 2:  technical mastery I think so, yeah, I definitely
Speaker 2:  need to to check more of that out. I have some other questions
Speaker 2:  about Project Indigo before we stray too far into
Speaker 2:  philosophy of photography and art. I'm wondering
Speaker 2:  your thoughts on generative AI
Speaker 2:  and particularly it's on my mind because I've just been
Speaker 2:  using the Pixel 10 Pro and there is
Speaker 2:  a Zoom feature on the camera that instead of using
Speaker 2:  just digital Zoom, which is has a lot of limitations,
Speaker 2:  takes your image in, uses a diffusion
Speaker 2:  generative AI model to kind of fill in the gaps. And
Speaker 2:  as your former colleague Isaac Reynolds said, squash the artifacts.
Speaker 2:  So that's sort of out there now, is
Speaker 2:  that something you would consider bringing into Project Indigo?
Speaker 14:  A lot to unpack there? Yeah, it really is. So first of all, in general,
Speaker 14:  generative AI definitely has a place in the future
Speaker 14:  of art, the future of photography. The Gen Remove
Speaker 14:  feature in Lightroom is generative ai And I use it
Speaker 14:  to remove tractors in many of my personal
Speaker 14:  photographs. It's very useful, of course it can be used to make
Speaker 14:  entirely new stuff and there's a place for that as well. So
Speaker 14:  as far as digital zooming goes, I don't wanna talk
Speaker 14:  specifically about Pixel, but there are other smartphone vendors
Speaker 14:  who have explored extreme zooming like
Speaker 14:  that. Any smartphone that does say 100 x is of course
Speaker 14:  using digital zooming of one, digital scaling of one
Speaker 14:  kind or another. So maybe I can answer it by giving
Speaker 14:  a general way to think about this. If they are
Speaker 14:  claiming 10 x zoom over the, over what the lens
Speaker 14:  can do or 20 x over what the lens can do. If it
Speaker 14:  is a native resolution, that's a five x lens. But let's take the
Speaker 14:  the 10 X case then The way to think about it is every
Speaker 14:  10th pixel horizontally and vertically is real,
Speaker 14:  which means that considering both horizontal and vertical,
Speaker 14:  one out of 100 pixels is real, the other
Speaker 14:  99 have to be made up. Now
Speaker 14:  how do you make up pixels? You could just interpolate
Speaker 14:  smoothly and make a blurry image. You could try to
Speaker 14:  sharpen edges. Now why would you sharpen edges? Because
Speaker 14:  you have some prior knowledge that the world is composed of
Speaker 14:  mostly smooth areas and sharp edges. That's
Speaker 14:  prior knowledge. That's a buzzword in artificial intelligence.
Speaker 14:  If you have a large training set, you have more prior knowledge
Speaker 14:  Sure. About the world. And these diffusion models have a lot
Speaker 14:  of training data and therefore a lot of prior knowledge.
Speaker 14:  So they'll look at every 10th pixel or every hundredth pixel
Speaker 14:  in area and say, oh, that looks like a building.
Speaker 14:  Buildings have windows. The windows have sharp edges. I
Speaker 14:  will sharpen all that up and make it stucco facade
Speaker 14:  and then a dark window. And so they're clearly making stuff
Speaker 14:  up. When you're using a generative ai, I think all of the
Speaker 14:  smartphone vendors will admit that they're making stuff up. The question
Speaker 14:  is, is it useful? What are you doing with
Speaker 14:  the image? And that determines whether it's okay to do that kind of
Speaker 14:  stuff. One thing I will say more about Pixel is
Speaker 14:  they do say they're not doing it for people.
Speaker 2:  Correct.
Speaker 14:  And that is an admission that it does matter what the gen AI is
Speaker 14:  used for. But getting back to the general argument, it's
Speaker 14:  useful for some things and not useful or even a misleading for other
Speaker 14:  things. And so I think that'll be the discussion that everyone has
Speaker 14:  going forward about the use of gen AI and digital scaling is what's it being
Speaker 14:  used for and does it work or does it make up stuff that's
Speaker 14:  objectionable?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think there's maybe a, a parallel to the, the moment
Speaker 2:  we're in with AI generally, and, And I, my
Speaker 2:  framework is what is the features on the phone
Speaker 2:  mostly. And there's sort of a, a rush to have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  AI stuff and sort of flashy, but not that useful.
Speaker 2:  And I, I think, I hope we're getting to a place with it where we can
Speaker 2:  think of it more as a tool that is just sort of there when we need
Speaker 2:  it and is helpful and then we don't think about it when we,
Speaker 2:  when we don't need it. Yeah. It it sounds like that's kind of what you're,
Speaker 2:  what you're hinting into.
Speaker 14:  Right. And let me make one further distinction. There's AI and there's gen
Speaker 14:  ai. Now those terms are kind of fuzzy themselves,
Speaker 14:  but when we think of text to image or text to video, everyone thinks of
Speaker 14:  a certain kind of gen ai and let's use that definition. But AI
Speaker 14:  is much more general than that. AI can just help you answer any
Speaker 14:  question where you might benefit from prior knowledge. So
Speaker 14:  the 10 x multi frame super resolution
Speaker 14:  that Indigo has is using an ai, it's not using
Speaker 14:  an AI to propose what the pixels ought to be, but to help
Speaker 14:  align the multiple frames, the multiple frames all look a little bit different
Speaker 14:  because when you hold your phone, you naturally shake a little bit, and
Speaker 14:  so it gets different views of the world and that actually provides
Speaker 14:  additional real information about the scene. And the AI helps us
Speaker 14:  align it and predict how we should weight those different images. So
Speaker 14:  that's an ai, it's being used as a tool, but it's not gen
Speaker 14:  ai. So one more thing I'll say about that is, well,
Speaker 14:  why can't you just keep doing that and take more and more frames and get
Speaker 14:  a hundred x and you can't, and the reason you can't is because there is
Speaker 14:  a fundamental limit on how much detail gets through a lens.
Speaker 14:  Hmm. It's called the diffraction limit. And every lens has a
Speaker 14:  diffraction limit. And for most smartphones, there
Speaker 14:  might be two x more information in each of
Speaker 14:  horizontal and vertical than the pixels normally allow.
Speaker 14:  There might not, depending on the lens, there isn't 10 x
Speaker 14:  more in each of X and y Right. For each job, horizontal, vertical.
Speaker 14:  So at that point you definitely are making stuff up.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. That, that sort of relates to
Speaker 2:  something I think about a lot with smartphone cameras is the
Speaker 2:  role of hardware versus software. It kind
Speaker 2:  of seems like, especially in the, the major players
Speaker 2:  in the US that we've sort of leveled out on the hardware, you know, we're
Speaker 2:  not talking about a new bigger camera sensor
Speaker 2:  every single year. You know, it's sort of like the same sensor
Speaker 2:  with some tweaks to the software, which is not quite the
Speaker 2:  case. I think if you look outside the us, my
Speaker 2:  colleague Dominic Preston gets to play with the, you know, the X
Speaker 2:  me phones that come out and they seem to be trying
Speaker 2:  some really interesting stuff with the hardware, the really big
Speaker 2:  one inch type sensors. You were going back to attachments
Speaker 2:  that you put on your smartphone that turn it into more of a camera.
Speaker 14:  So I assume you realize that the major limitation there is the
Speaker 14:  thickness of the phone. Yeah, that's what it's all about. The, the fundamental
Speaker 14:  optics of a camera says that if you want a larger sensor,
Speaker 14:  you've got to have more space between the lens and the
Speaker 14:  sensor. Right. And you can do a quite a variety of hardware tricks
Speaker 14:  to finesse that a little bit, but not a lot.
Speaker 14:  And so basically a larger sensor means a thicker phone
Speaker 2:  And it, yeah. Maybe our, our sensibilities are
Speaker 2:  that we, we just don't want that and we're gonna kind of settle on, you know,
Speaker 2:  we get what we get. Do you think there is innovation
Speaker 2:  to be had in the camera? Hardware, you know, is within the
Speaker 2:  bounds of what will tolerate as, you know, how thick a phone can be,
Speaker 2:  how big a camera bump can be?
Speaker 14:  So far, all that innovation has been incremental, but very useful.
Speaker 14:  As a specific example, when I was working on Pixel, we used
Speaker 14:  Sony sensors and every year the Sony sensors would get better, just
Speaker 14:  a little bit better, but they really would get better. One of the ways they
Speaker 14:  got better is that what's called the read noise. The
Speaker 14:  extra random stuff that gets introduced when the pixels are read
Speaker 14:  off of the sensor would get less and less. And so
Speaker 14:  in the last couple of years that I was at Google, we could do
Speaker 14:  astrophotography where it's very, very dark and you need that
Speaker 14:  read noise to be small. We could successfully do it.
Speaker 14:  Whereas a few years before, we really couldn't. And so these
Speaker 14:  incremental improvements are useful on the
Speaker 14:  telephoto lenses. Many of the smartphone vendors, including iPhone,
Speaker 14:  have gone to what's called a periscope or a, a
Speaker 14:  bended optics. Yeah, that's an interesting development. So there are
Speaker 14:  hardware developments to be had. They're slow, they're incremental, but
Speaker 14:  they're useful.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. Well that, that gives me hope. I don't know, there's
Speaker 2:  something fun about new hardware as much as, you know,
Speaker 2:  software is important on the subject of innovations and
Speaker 2:  things coming up. I wonder if you can give us a, a taste of what you're working
Speaker 2:  on next for Project Indigo. I know it, it's, would you call it a beta? It's
Speaker 2:  in the Adobe Labs kind of under development state, if that's correct.
Speaker 14:  Right. I wouldn't, the the blog doesn't even characterize it as beta. It
Speaker 14:  says experimental.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Meaning this might or might not turn into a product for Adobe.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 14:  So in the blog, we talk about a few things. One of them is, I would
Speaker 14:  love to do exposure bracketing where you, there are some scenes
Speaker 14:  that are so high dynamic range that just under
Speaker 14:  exposing and to, to reduce clipping of highlights
Speaker 14:  and averaging of more frames to reduce noise in the shadows isn't enough.
Speaker 14:  The example that we have in the blog is a moon over a moonlit
Speaker 14:  landscape. So the full moon over a
Speaker 14:  moonlit landscape, the difference in brightness between those two is
Speaker 14:  19 F stops, meaning two to the 19th power
Speaker 14:  meaning about half a million to one. That's
Speaker 14:  beyond the dynamic range of any camera, even an SLR.
Speaker 14:  So if you wanted to capture a full moon and a moonlit landscape, you
Speaker 14:  need to bracket by bracketing, I mean capturing multiple images
Speaker 14:  with different shutter speeds. And so of course, s SLRs
Speaker 14:  let you do that. There's some of that in the smartphone industry. We
Speaker 14:  would like to do a lot more of it in Indigo. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 14:  Another similar thing that is also mentioned in the blog is focus
Speaker 14:  bracketing, meaning let's move the lens
Speaker 14:  in between captures and then combine them to
Speaker 14:  make what is called an all in focus image. So you would think,
Speaker 14:  well, you know, in a smartphone, everything's in focus more or less. Well
Speaker 14:  that's true for things that are far away, but not for things that are close.
Speaker 14:  So I don't know what your killer app for all in focus might be, but I
Speaker 14:  know my killer app is food, my Dinner. Oh, yeah. At a nice
Speaker 14:  restaurant where it's worth photographing, it's very hard to get the whole
Speaker 14:  dinner plate in focus. Yeah. Yeah. You can do it if you shoot from above
Speaker 14:  looking down, but not if you shoot obliquely. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You're so close and yeah, you're like, is the, the tomato
Speaker 2:  on the top of the salad or the plate behind it gonna be in focus?
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 14:  So those are two things that are kind of obvious. There are a number of
Speaker 14:  other things that, that we're exploring. They basically fall into
Speaker 14:  the same camp of, let's take a bit more time during capture, try
Speaker 14:  a number of different things, combine them computationally. What I'd love
Speaker 14:  to do, as the blog says, is to keep all the data,
Speaker 14:  not just one image, so that you could also play with it later in an
Speaker 14:  editor.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 14:  And that's, that's a great example of where the camera app and the
Speaker 14:  editing app can work in synergy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. A little bit of a, of a nice advantage when you work for
Speaker 2:  Adobe.
Speaker 14:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But I have to ask for my Android people. Is there an Android version
Speaker 2:  come in?
Speaker 14:  It's definitely on the want list. Okay. I
Speaker 14:  used to work on building Android camera apps, of course, right at Google.
Speaker 14:  As a matter of fact, the API, the application programming interface
Speaker 14:  for the camera was something that I and my graduate students at Stanford
Speaker 14:  designed. The, the so-called camera two programming interface
Speaker 14:  for Android came out of a, a project at Stanford called
Speaker 14:  the Franken Camera Project.
Speaker 2:  Oh, nice.
Speaker 14:  And it's a great interface And I would love to address it,
Speaker 14:  by calling it Universal five years ago, didn't I?
Speaker 14:  Reddit
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back. We're gonna take a hotline question
Speaker 2:  now, and as always, the number for that is 8 6 6 VERGE
Speaker 2:  one one and our email is vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We love the questions, keep them coming and we answer at least one on
Speaker 2:  every show. So definitely write in or call in. This
Speaker 2:  week's question comes from someone who isn't that concerned about image
Speaker 2:  quality on their phone, but they're a little bit bothered by the camera
Speaker 2:  bump.
Speaker 18:  I am Ogo, I'm calling to talk about
Speaker 18:  cameras on phones. I, for one, don't
Speaker 18:  care much about the quality of the camera to be honest. And
Speaker 18:  I assume that if I want to get the
Speaker 18:  best phone available in the market, I have
Speaker 18:  to basically live with a bump that is almost to
Speaker 18:  the size of the overall phone. So I just wonder about
Speaker 18:  where are we going with this, because it seems that these camera bumps just
Speaker 18:  keep getting bigger and bigger and somehow the phones get
Speaker 18:  thinner on the other side, but then the size of the bump is not
Speaker 18:  taken into account from the overall side. So the phone, when things get
Speaker 18:  reviewed, measure. So that seems pretty weird that
Speaker 18:  let's say that the phone size is an overall five or whatever and
Speaker 18:  then the bump is at two on top of that. But then somehow it gets
Speaker 18:  reported that besides, oh, the phone is just the lower number. So
Speaker 18:  I don't know, I just, I I just wondering if there's like any
Speaker 18:  hope out there for at top of the line phone to just basically
Speaker 18:  start moving away from the bump and then having the,
Speaker 18:  having been the case that we can have a phone that has the text
Speaker 18:  of a top of the line, but not the oversized phone, that would allow
Speaker 18:  us to at least have the phone sit like fresh on the table.
Speaker 18:  So I guess yes, just full for thought. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  So I need to start with mostly bad news.
Speaker 2:  Osvaldo, I am so sorry. I don't think the camera bumps are going away, but
Speaker 2:  I love this question because A, I appreciate the honesty.
Speaker 2:  Really don't care about the image quality, just tired of living with a big
Speaker 2:  camera bump. And b, I think it's just saying out loud what
Speaker 2:  a lot of us are thinking or bothered by. But
Speaker 2:  I know I, for one, just want all the best image quality I can get.
Speaker 2:  So it's sort of something I, I've shoved into the back of my head that I
Speaker 2:  can live with. But I think there's a few reasons why the camera bump
Speaker 2:  is not going away, especially on the pro in the
Speaker 2:  higher tier models that Asalto was talking about.
Speaker 2:  So these are the phones that tend to have the
Speaker 2:  best camera, you know, the best of the best, and
Speaker 2:  those cameras have bigger sensors. That is a huge benefit
Speaker 2:  when you're taking pictures in low light or really any
Speaker 2:  situation. But a bigger sensor means it needs a bigger
Speaker 2:  lens, hence a big camera bump. So
Speaker 2:  there's a little bit of a caveat to this that
Speaker 2:  outside of the US this is maybe even a worse problem
Speaker 2:  where some of the xmi of the world are,
Speaker 2:  you know, betting on really big image sensors and big lenses
Speaker 2:  and just sort of going all the way into, you know, the heck with
Speaker 2:  a, a camera bump is gonna be huge and people will just live with that.
Speaker 2:  So I think what we have to deal with here is maybe a little
Speaker 2:  bit better. And I do think the point about phones
Speaker 2:  getting thinner, but the camera bump kind of remaining
Speaker 2:  a problem is legitimate. I tested the Galaxy S
Speaker 2:  25 Edge, which is a, a super thin phone, But
Speaker 2:  that camera bump is maybe as thick as the phone
Speaker 2:  itself. And something that really bothered me when I tested
Speaker 2:  it is putting it on the table as, as Faldo mentioned,
Speaker 2:  does not sit flush on a table and it wobbles like
Speaker 2:  all heck when you tap on it. This is made worse by
Speaker 2:  my habit of not putting cases on phones, which I think
Speaker 2:  is one of the solutions here. So I don't think the camera bumps are going
Speaker 2:  away, putting a case on your phone, depending on the phone in
Speaker 2:  the case, you know, you can shop around a little bit for something that
Speaker 2:  sort of evens out the camera bump. I think a, you know, a
Speaker 2:  pop socket or a a case with a built-in stand could help
Speaker 2:  if you're really bothered by setting your phone down and having
Speaker 2:  it wobble on the tabletop. Those would be things to look at. If you
Speaker 2:  haven't already, there's maybe good news coming
Speaker 2:  or bad. I can't really tell the, the rumors
Speaker 2:  of the iPhone, the impending iPhone 17
Speaker 2:  show, like in elongated camera bump. That might
Speaker 2:  help even out the wobble situation. I just tested
Speaker 2:  the Pixel 10 Pro and pixel phones
Speaker 2:  have that long kind of elongated oval of
Speaker 2:  a camera bump and it's big and chunky for sure, but when you
Speaker 2:  set it on a table, it's a little bit of a, a stable
Speaker 2:  stand for the phone. So it props it up a little bit, doesn't
Speaker 2:  wobble around. So there are trade-offs there.
Speaker 2:  Perhaps the iPhone is moving to something similar. It's still a
Speaker 2:  big camera bump. So I think you've gotta look at a case that's maybe
Speaker 2:  going to help if all else fails. I find
Speaker 2:  a drink coaster is my friend. I am always
Speaker 2:  putting my phone on a drink coaster when I'm sitting at the table
Speaker 2:  and I'm tired of it wobbling around. So
Speaker 2:  we've always got that oswaldo, I'm sorry. I hope that helps, but
Speaker 2:  maybe the help is in just saying it out loud and knowing that
Speaker 2:  you're not suffering alone. So thanks for calling in.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. To read more about the
Speaker 2:  topics we covered, check the show notes or head to The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  And if you like what we do here, consider buying a paid subscription.
Speaker 2:  The show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brendan Kiefer, Travis EK,
Speaker 2:  and Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the
Speaker 2:  Vox Media podcast network. Jake Aki and the team will be
Speaker 2:  here Friday to talk about the news. Thanks for listening.