# Transcript
ID: a08807d6-3805-4d31-99c4-4afeaa830841
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7403382225900984262/8212168114585167257/s93290-US-5511s-1751362101.mp3
Description: One way to think about the tech industry is just as a series of people trying to build stuff they saw in movies and on TV. Some of that tech is great, some of it is deeply dystopian, and most of it would make the world a very different place if it suddenly existed. In this episode, a bunch of us try to figure out which tech we actually want to use. David is joined by The Verge’s Allison Johnson, Jennifer Pattison-Tuohy, Mia Sato, and Victoria Song — aka the hosts of Hot Girl Vergecast Summer — to draft their way through the movie, show, and game tech they’d want to make real. Some of the picks you’ll expect, and some we bet has never crossed your mind. And some big-name tech goes undrafted!
Once you've finished the show, make sure you take the poll and tell us who won: https://forms.gle/Q1wFhpzCdM3B5bqj9
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (23 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of flying cars that
Speaker 2:  you will never fly. I'm m your friend David Pierce, and if you're seeing
Speaker 2:  this or hearing it, it means I'm already dead. No, I'm just kidding. It just
Speaker 2:  means I'm out on parental leave. I'm gonna be gone through the rest of the
Speaker 2:  summer. Neli Patel, my co-host is going to be gone probably
Speaker 2:  sometime after me, but he's gonna be gone for the summer too. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  be back this fall and we're going to be so excited to hang out with all of
Speaker 2:  you and talk tech again after talking about just baby stuff for
Speaker 2:  months. We're very excited. But in the meantime, you are in exceptionally
Speaker 2:  good hands. Jake Kakis on our team is going to be taking over the Friday
Speaker 2:  show for the summer, and we have four guest hosts who are going to
Speaker 2:  be with you all summer on the Tuesday show. And they are also my four guests
Speaker 2:  today V Song Allison Johnson. Jen Tuey and Mia Sato
Speaker 2:  are going to be hosting the show. And they have some big ideas about all
Speaker 2:  the different kinds of stories that they're gonna tell you. They've been
Speaker 2:  working on some really fun stuff. We're gonna have some stuff about all whatever
Speaker 2:  chaotic news happens this summer, they're gonna have a blast, And I think
Speaker 2:  you're gonna have a blast. So I invited the four of them for my last episode
Speaker 2:  here this summer to come with me and do something I've been wanting to do
Speaker 2:  for a long time, which is look through the Annals of movies and
Speaker 2:  TV shows and all of the technology and all of them, and try to decide
Speaker 2:  what we would actually want in our life. So we're gonna do a bit of
Speaker 2:  a draft today, the five of us. We're going to pick five things each, and
Speaker 2:  it's going to be chaos. And we're gonna try to figure out what fictional
Speaker 2:  tech do we want in our real lives. All that is coming up in just a sec, but
Speaker 2:  first we gotta take a quick break because presumably I gotta go to some
Speaker 2:  kids stuff. I don't know. This is The Vergecast, we'll be right back
Speaker 2:  you are going to just absolutely run me out of a job And I literally could
Speaker 2:  not be more excited about it in the order in which I see you. Allison Johnson's
Speaker 2:  here. Hi Allison. Hello, Jen Tuey also here with very cool lights
Speaker 2:  in the background. Hi, Jen. Always,
Speaker 7:  Always cool stuff in my house.
Speaker 2:  Hi David. The song, I believe in a phone booth in our office.
Speaker 8:  Hell yeah. And I brought my podcast Mike with me to the office. So
Speaker 8:  that's dedication.
Speaker 2:  Nothing more fun than a long podcast than a phone booth. This is gonna be
Speaker 2:  great. Miyazato is also here. Hi Mia. Hello. You
Speaker 2:  got the most Tuohy podcast setup of all of us, so
Speaker 2:  congratulations. Oh
Speaker 7:  My God, you're lucky I don't have my like AirPod mic, you know what I mean?
Speaker 7:  Or the new thing that they're doing. They're clipping like a road mic onto
Speaker 7:  a tube of lip gloss and then holding the lip gloss. I actually should have
Speaker 7:  done that.
Speaker 2:  You should have done that. There was a real, we, like, honest to God had
Speaker 2:  a conversation about like, what if all of David's recordings for The Verge
Speaker 2:  cast were with the tiny little lavalier mic? So good. And I just couldn't
Speaker 2:  do it. I'm, I'm, I'm 20 years too old to be able to pull that off.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so here is how this draft is going to work. The concept
Speaker 2:  is, is essentially things that are in movies, TV
Speaker 2:  shows, And I believe we said yes to video games that we would like to lift
Speaker 2:  out of those things and place in the real world. And I think the way I've
Speaker 2:  come to see it is it's like, it's not just one that's for you, but it's also
Speaker 2:  not like everyone on earth has it. It's at like, I would say like
Speaker 2:  Mac Pro levels of adoption, right? Where like if you see one, you're not
Speaker 2:  like, oh, weird, I've never seen that before. But you also like, don't assume
Speaker 2:  that everyone you've ever met has one. Does that make sense? Okay. Price
Speaker 2:  is no object and none of these things cost anything in these movies anyway.
Speaker 2:  So they're just, it's just we're taking it out and putting it into our real
Speaker 2:  lives. There are only, I would say, three rules
Speaker 2:  that I have for you. One is no weapons, which is just like, don't,
Speaker 2:  don't be weird. We don't need that energy here. Thing number two is
Speaker 2:  you can't draft a concept. So you can't like draft time
Speaker 2:  travel or like, I don't know, cure all
Speaker 2:  diseases. It's like not, you just can't, you can't have that, even though
Speaker 2:  that is like a thing that exists in the fiction of some of these things.
Speaker 2:  If there is a gadget through which you can time travel, knock yourself out,
Speaker 2:  but you can't just have the concept of time travel. And the
Speaker 2:  third thing is a rule that we just decided on earlier today, which is
Speaker 2:  you're not allowed to try and make the world a better place. I was looking
Speaker 2:  through and the the
Speaker 9:  Reason, and none of us had thought about doing that tools.
Speaker 8:  No, not at all,
Speaker 2:  Which I love very much. But the, the reason this came up is I was looking
Speaker 2:  through a bunch of stuff to make my own list for this draft. And there's
Speaker 2:  this thing in the movie Elysium, which I have never seen called the Med Bay,
Speaker 2:  I believe. And it's thing is it can diagnose and cure like all diseases
Speaker 2:  ever in history. And I immediately had this moment of being like, oh, well
Speaker 2:  I should draft this 'cause that's great, wouldn't it be good? And then I
Speaker 2:  was like, that's stupid and boring. So you're not allowed, you are not allowed
Speaker 2:  to make the world a better place. And if that is your argument, you'll be,
Speaker 2:  you will be summarily rejected from your draft. We're gonna do five
Speaker 2:  rounds. So we're each gonna pick five things, 25 things in total, which is
Speaker 2:  actually kind of a large number. And we're gonna do it in sort of snake draft
Speaker 2:  order. So if you draft last at the end of the first round, you will then
Speaker 2:  immediately draft again to start the second round. And we just go back and
Speaker 2:  forth. That's basically it. Any questions before we go? Anything? I
Speaker 2:  forgot. Everybody feel good? Ready to go?
Speaker 9:  How do we win?
Speaker 2:  Oh, terrific point. When this show goes live,
Speaker 2:  we will, we will have a post on The Verge dot com
Speaker 2:  with all of our picks laid out and we'll do some kind of poll.
Speaker 2:  And I don't know if the verges, we use WordPress. Maybe
Speaker 2:  WordPress lets us do a poll and I'll be the first person to do that on the
Speaker 2:  verse.com. Maybe we'll figure out some other way to do it. But we will do
Speaker 2:  a poll and whoever wins,
Speaker 2:  I don know, I'll send you a Mac Pro. I won't, I won't do that, but a pro,
Speaker 2:  we'll do something.
Speaker 8:  Mac, Mac Pro. You heard it here, ladies Mac Pro,
Speaker 8:  David Pierce, Mac Pro. Now he's not specified the year of Mac,
Speaker 8:  which which is the little loophole.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna send you a trash can and you're gonna love
Speaker 8:  It.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so gen two E first overall pick.
Speaker 9:  Okay, I know what I'm gonna start with going to my roots here in case
Speaker 9:  anyone can't tell I'm English, So I'm going with the
Speaker 9:  TARDIS from Dr. Who. Ah,
Speaker 8:  Yeah, very good, very good.
Speaker 6:  It's called the Tards. They
Speaker 10:  Can travel anywhere in time and space
Speaker 6:  And it's mine
Speaker 9:  As a kid actually is probably the first piece of tech I remember.
Speaker 9:  And just loving that and the Dex, but I'm not gonna choose a
Speaker 9:  dx.
Speaker 2:  So can you explain for people who have not watched Dr. Who what, what is
Speaker 2:  the tardis and why'd you pick it?
Speaker 9:  Okay, so the TARDIS is the time and relative dimension in
Speaker 9:  space vehicle from the show. Dr.
Speaker 9:  Who long running show older than me
Speaker 9:  had recent revival, which I haven't actually watched much of. But what
Speaker 9:  I, the reason I would like the TARDIS is because you can travel across
Speaker 9:  space and time and fabrics and all the kind of cool
Speaker 9:  space sci-fi. I mean it's just the
Speaker 9:  coolest device, transportation device you could possibly
Speaker 9:  have. And it is like as
Speaker 9:  large as you want it to be, but it is also a telephone booth, which
Speaker 9:  is just the best concept in the world. Right? So the other thing I thought
Speaker 9:  about picking, and if I'd lost this one, I would've gone for, would've been
Speaker 9:  the Bill and Ted's telephone booth that travels through time. Oh, but
Speaker 9:  the TARDIS is way cooler.
Speaker 2:  I I agree. The
Speaker 8:  TARDIS is a home too. It is.
Speaker 9:  You can live in it. You go wherever you like in it. It's a translation
Speaker 9:  machine. It's like, it is all the tech that you
Speaker 9:  could possibly need packed into a telephone booth.
Speaker 2:  There are a few of these in this draft that are just kind of cheating because
Speaker 2:  it's like, oh, I get to draft this and then I have everything that has ever
Speaker 2:  existed for everyone ever. It's gonna be great. My question is, where where
Speaker 2:  would you go? You you're, you get in the tart the first time, what do you
Speaker 2:  do
Speaker 9:  The first time I would go, well you see, I love history. So
Speaker 9:  going back in time is my kind of, and that those episodes were
Speaker 9:  always the fun ones. I don dunno if they do that so much in the new series,
Speaker 9:  but in the old series they, that was always the fun stuff. And I'm a huge
Speaker 9:  Elizabethan history nerd tutor and all that kind of stuff. So I would go
Speaker 9:  back into T history and find out all such of cool stuff
Speaker 9:  that I desperately would love to know the real story about, rather than having
Speaker 9:  to piece through historical books and figure
Speaker 2:  That was when everybody was beheading everybody. Yeah, it was when
Speaker 8:  It was killing
Speaker 9:  Each other. Yeah, it was really interesting times.
Speaker 2:  I like this for you. All right, v what's your first pick?
Speaker 8:  My first pick is capsules from Dragon Ball Z.
Speaker 11:  No need to live outside like Savages. I have my Dino caps. Remember
Speaker 12:  I don't like those magic witch bombs. Grandpa said never to use magic unless
Speaker 12:  it's to help someone. Oh well I
Speaker 11:  Am going to help someone silly.
Speaker 11:  Here it goes.
Speaker 11:  There we go. Now doesn't that look
Speaker 8:  Cozy? They are. Listen, okay. They are genius
Speaker 8:  invention and like Tardis, they are bigger on the inside than the outside.
Speaker 8:  So if you've never watched a,
Speaker 9:  That is the coolest thing.
Speaker 8:  If you've never watched Dragon Ballsy, they're these tiny little capsules
Speaker 8:  and that's like what Alma's family is actually famous for.
Speaker 8:  But they're little capsules and you can stick anything in them. You can
Speaker 8:  stick a motorcycle in them, you can stick a vacation home in them and they
Speaker 8:  fit into a tiny little pill size thing that you stick in your pocket
Speaker 8:  and it's so convenient in that world, it makes them gazillionaires. And So
Speaker 8:  I want that for me because I'm tired of carrying all my shit around in
Speaker 8:  a backpack in New York City getting like real back pain,
Speaker 8:  carrying a laptop. This podcast Mike and everything. How do you deploy it?
Speaker 8:  Is it like Pokemon where you throw it? Yeah, yeah. Kind of. You
Speaker 8:  like press a button and you throw it and your vacation home is there. I like
Speaker 8:  that. Cool. Awesome. Your motorcycle is there. Awesome.
Speaker 8:  Woo. You know like parking costs a fuck ton in New York City,
Speaker 8:  so why not just go like, oh, am I done with my car? No, no
Speaker 8:  parking problems. Like amazing love that for me.
Speaker 2:  Oh, okay. I didn't like this at, I was gonna make fun of you first. Basically
Speaker 2:  having all of the options in the world and choosing, I don't want to carry
Speaker 2:  a purse anymore.
Speaker 8:  I'm just gonna like tell everyone I'm gonna set the table stakes here. Every
Speaker 8:  single one of my picks is selfish
Speaker 2:  As it should be.
Speaker 8:  It's selfish. It helps my life get easier and truly
Speaker 8:  reveals all the ways in which I'm lazy. So there is,
Speaker 2:  Is there a limit to how many capsules one can have at a time?
Speaker 8:  You know, I don't think so. Okay. Just like how much you can carry, like
Speaker 8:  BMA has like vests I think where she's just like, you know, look at my cap.
Speaker 8:  You know, like the trench coat with the, with the, the watch clocks and she's
Speaker 8:  like, eh, look at my capsules. I don't actually think there's an episode
Speaker 8:  where she does that, but I imagine that's what you can do. Whatever you can
Speaker 8:  fit in your pocket. Capsules.
Speaker 2:  I like this more and more the more I think about it. I'm now thinking of
Speaker 2:  all the things that would just start carrying with me. This, this actually
Speaker 2:  makes a lot of sense. Mia, you're up next. What's your first pick?
Speaker 7:  Okay, my first pick was going to be in the similar vein so you can
Speaker 7:  tell me if I can't, it might be even lazier than v's choice, which is like,
Speaker 7:  I want the giant pockets of animal crossing.
Speaker 7:  'cause I don't even wanna carry the capsules. I don't wanna lose my car,
Speaker 7:  I don't wanna lose my wallet. I don't wanna lose my tree that I'm carrying
Speaker 7:  around. For some reason, I just wanted all in my pockets. I want endless
Speaker 7:  deep pockets that I can carry like 20 sharks and
Speaker 7:  a peach. You know, that's what I want. So is that too close
Speaker 7:  or do I have to pick something
Speaker 2:  Else? No, I'm, I'm good with it. It is, it's, it's different. What I'm just
Speaker 2:  blown away by is, Jen is like, I would like to travel through space and time
Speaker 2:  and you're just like, I'd like to have a peach with me. What if I just had
Speaker 2:  a peach?
Speaker 8:  Great. There's a theme though to all of these picks so far in that it's larger
Speaker 8:  on the inside.
Speaker 7:  Yes, that's true. But
Speaker 2:  Also just like I'm tired is a real vibe I'm getting from all of you. It's
Speaker 2:  just like, I don't wanna, like I had to, I had to walk a lot of places with
Speaker 2:  bags and what if I just didn't have to do that anymore.
Speaker 7:  I'm so sick of it. Also, like my, I know that it's not a technology, but
Speaker 7:  on the animal crossing subject, my second pick would've been a raccoon landlord
Speaker 7:  that lets me pay off my apartment in zero interest loans. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And builds like a beautiful house for me. Yeah. And wears a Hawaiian shirt.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 8:  Where, where is,
Speaker 7:  IM guessing I can't draft Tom
Speaker 8:  Nook. Where's Tom Nook? Where is Tom Nook and where
Speaker 8:  is that stock market that actually, you know, lets people get rich?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Tom Nook. Animal crossing pockets are almost I
Speaker 2:  think a violation of the, it has to be technology and not magic Okay. Rule.
Speaker 2:  But I'll, I'll allow it. Amazing. I really, I did not expect this to just
Speaker 2:  be, how do I move things around in the first round? So listen,
Speaker 8:  You were talking to four women and we have this,
Speaker 7:  They don't give us pant pockets.
Speaker 2:  I'm also realizing my first pick fits perfectly into this theme. So this
Speaker 2:  is gonna be great. Allison, you're up next. What's your first pick?
Speaker 14:  Okay, I'm gonna pick the one that
Speaker 14:  I'm worried someone else might pick. It's not
Speaker 14:  necessarily like my favorite one, but I think it would come in handy
Speaker 14:  in men in black, the little like little blinky
Speaker 14:  light thing. Is it called the neuralizer? The neuro, the Alright.
Speaker 14:  I want it specifically. I don't wanna like do crimes, I
Speaker 14:  just want it for my social anxiety. So if I like
Speaker 14:  say something stupid, I can be like, wait, wait, wait. Let me do
Speaker 14:  that over again.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. That, that's what I got. Okay. And I,
Speaker 2:  Okay, so, so this, this is a good time to bring up something that we probably
Speaker 2:  should have talked about with the TARDIS in particular, which is the societal
Speaker 2:  implications. Because, because what happens here is it, and there I, I went
Speaker 2:  through this a bunch with a bunch of the things that I'm actually not going
Speaker 2:  to pick as a result of this. But like you, Allison, I trust to
Speaker 2:  have a neuralizer. I think that would be fine, right? But if we're going
Speaker 2:  to just sort of randomly sprinkle neuralizer on people around the earth
Speaker 2:  Hmm. Potential problems. Lot could go wrong. Are we sure we want to
Speaker 2:  bring this into existence?
Speaker 14:  What if we can only use them on ourself?
Speaker 2:  Ooh.
Speaker 14:  Okay. But that
Speaker 2:  I, no, but that would be worse. 'cause then then my social anxiety says,
Speaker 2:  oh my God, what did I say to other people that I don't even remember now?
Speaker 2:  No, no, no. What have I normalized out of myself?
Speaker 14:  No, it's like a neuralizer light. You can't use it for any
Speaker 14:  like, serious, like heavy memories. Like
Speaker 14:  forget about your whole life and your wife or
Speaker 14:  whatever it is in men black. It's just like, oh, I
Speaker 14:  bent over the bookstore and it was quiet And I farted And I just gonna
Speaker 14:  likeactually thing no one will ever know. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Rewind for a few, just a few seconds. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  It's, it's like a neural, like a low stakes neuralizer is
Speaker 14:  Basically what you're talking about. Yes. The low stakes only. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Mia, is this a good idea? Should we allow, do we want this in the world?
Speaker 7:  I just worry about if many people have it and everyone's
Speaker 7:  forgetting the embarrassing thing they did, then that kind of disrupts
Speaker 7:  the equilibrium of the world. Everybody
Speaker 2:  Becomes too confident. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Everyone becomes a little too confident. Everyone becomes a little too
Speaker 7:  polished. And frankly, like I am fine doing embarrassing
Speaker 7:  things because I've seen a million people do really embarrassing things in
Speaker 7:  public. You know what I mean?
Speaker 14:  It's kind of like social media that way.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Well I think that even if people had the neuralizer, they would not
Speaker 7:  stop posting embarrassing things. True. That is true. So people would still
Speaker 7:  be idiots online. So maybe it's
Speaker 2:  Fine. The neuralizer would make the real world like weird and
Speaker 2:  not change social media one tiny bit at all. Internet would not change at
Speaker 2:  all because of all,
Speaker 7:  In fact they would be crazier online. Like, 'cause you have no other outlet.
Speaker 14:  That's true.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty good. All right. I get two now because
Speaker 2:  I get two. I'm gonna pick the one that I don't think is like the thing I
Speaker 2:  should pick first, but is the one I want the most out of everything, which
Speaker 2:  is the hoverboard from back to the Future two,
Speaker 15:  Please. Done a hover board,
Speaker 2:  Which is just, and the beauty of this is, it's not just that I have one,
Speaker 2:  it's that lots of people have one. So we've now normalized this as a transportation
Speaker 2:  system and a way that to get around that is like, what if
Speaker 2:  bird scooters, but like much cooler, which turns out to be like
Speaker 2:  precisely the, the aesthetic I'm going for. And this is the true
Speaker 2:  hoverboard that actually hovers. It seems to be very light.
Speaker 2:  It's pink. It's very important to me that they're all pink. And,
Speaker 2:  and you can just, you can ride around in the air. You can do all kinds of
Speaker 2:  cool sick tricks. It's a way to get places, it's a way to get in fights.
Speaker 2:  This just feels like if I could just pick up a thing and be like, I'm going
Speaker 2:  to instantly make everyone's life more fun to get
Speaker 2:  around. I think I'm doing a great service to society with the
Speaker 2:  hoverboard.
Speaker 9:  Don't we already have hoverboards? Yeah, but they light on fire and then
Speaker 9:  they go up in people's garages.
Speaker 8:  They're not real. Like, they don't actually hover. They're
Speaker 8:  just like stupid things with wheels on them.
Speaker 2:  To be fair, I was also a big fan of those hoverboards.
Speaker 9:  Oh no. Just
Speaker 2:  Like they were a good idea except for the whole, like they exploded and were
Speaker 2:  impossible to ride thing. But I was, I was in on that.
Speaker 9:  Did you have one?
Speaker 2:  I I still might have one somewhere.
Speaker 9:  Ride it now. Do it now. I feel like we're gonna need some traffic
Speaker 9:  laws though, because we've seen with scooters and the
Speaker 9:  e-bikes and everything that out there today, these
Speaker 9:  pedestrian type vehicles that move fast and break things can be quite
Speaker 9:  awful and dangerous.
Speaker 8:  If you want the privilege of a hoverboard, you have to go to the DMV and
Speaker 8:  get a hoverboard license because otherwise you're just
Speaker 8:  a fucking menace. A traffic menace. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  To be fair, I think people should have to do that with scooters. So I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm actually fine. This,
Speaker 9:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It should be much harder to get one of these things on the street, but I
Speaker 2:  kind of like to think of it like there's a very powerful hoverboard lobby
Speaker 2:  that has made it so that they just coexist with cars now. And, and everybody's
Speaker 2:  fine with this.
Speaker 8:  I like that we're just writing fan fiction. This is great.
Speaker 2:  I've solved a lot of problems here. All right. So that's my first pick.
Speaker 2:  I think for my second pick. I'm just gonna take Jarvis from Iron
Speaker 2:  Man.
Speaker 9:  Oh, lost two already. Darn it.
Speaker 16:  Micro repeater implant sequence. Complete
Speaker 17:  As you wish. Sir, I've also prepared a safety briefing for you to entirely
Speaker 17:  ignore, which
Speaker 16:  I will. All right, let's do this.
Speaker 17:  Sir. May I remind you that you've been awake for nearly 72 hours.
Speaker 2:  I'm not gonna take another of the, like all purpose do everything Machines
Speaker 2:  that let me travel back to a time, this is the closest one to just like
Speaker 2:  my all purpose AI helper that makes me
Speaker 2:  sick at everything. And I think of all of them.
Speaker 2:  Jarvis is the best one. V You And I talk a lot about Jarvis, like, is
Speaker 2:  Jarvis, is Jarvis the best one?
Speaker 8:  I think Jarvis is the best one. Okay. Or like, if you wanna get nitty gritty,
Speaker 8:  you could have like Friday or the other ones that Tony Stark has made. But
Speaker 8:  like an AI that Tony Stark has made that is like with the power
Speaker 8:  of science fiction, capable of doing all the things that the AI of
Speaker 8:  today cannot actually do in a way that actually is natural
Speaker 8:  language. And it's like, oh, you know, I could deal with Paul
Speaker 8:  Beney in my ear telling me sassy little things and, and like reminders.
Speaker 8:  Like
Speaker 2:  I do worry that Jarvis would find me very unimpressive that like, this is,
Speaker 2:  this is what I worry about with Jarvis. It's like, I don't want the suit,
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna like do cool stuff. I just wanna be like, Jarvis, where did
Speaker 2:  I leave my wallet? And for Jarvis to be like, it's in the stroller where
Speaker 2:  it always is. And like this, this is the extent of what I require.
Speaker 2:  And
Speaker 8:  I do like that Jarvis keeps Tony humble. He's just like, oh you idiot, it's
Speaker 8:  over there. Like, I want, I, I need like a, a a degree of that in
Speaker 8:  my life. It's just like, oh you ding bat. It's right where you left it.
Speaker 2:  And it is important that it's Paul Beney. You're right about that.
Speaker 8:  Yes'. Very important that it's Paul Beney. It has
Speaker 7:  To have an English accent. Yeah. That's the important part. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent. So tho those are my two. I feel I feel very good about
Speaker 2:  this. I think I have accomplished some things here. I have a way to get around
Speaker 2:  and I have just like my non terrifying AI buddy to hang out with
Speaker 2:  all day round two. Alison, you're up.
Speaker 14:  All right. I'm gonna go with the holodeck from Star Trek.
Speaker 2:  Solid choice.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Like, and I have no problem with everybody else having this too. We
Speaker 14:  can all have our little, like, you'd be like, you know what I'm gonna piece
Speaker 14:  out. I'm gonna go sit on a mountain for 20 minutes. Wait,
Speaker 7:  Can you explain what it is? 'cause I've never seen Star Trek.
Speaker 14:  Okay. So
Speaker 7:  Does she, is she allowed to work at The Verge? She's never seen Stark. I'm
Speaker 7:  not,
Speaker 8:  Oh wait,
Speaker 7:  Literally. No. I'ma
Speaker 8:  Back you up Mia. I've only seen the Star Trek movies, so we're good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I just, I just saw Star Wars for the first time in my entire life.
Speaker 7:  Oh my goodness. Mia, you might need to stop.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Okay. Oh my goodness. You know, star Trek, the one was fine, but two,
Speaker 7:  Both of those.
Speaker 8:  But you know. No, no, no. She's seen it. She's seen it now guys. She's seen
Speaker 8:  it now. I've seen
Speaker 7:  One now I've seen one. Which one?
Speaker 8:  Which one? The
Speaker 7:  First one question mark.
Speaker 8:  That, that's a loaded question. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  If you like accidentally watch Phantom Menace, we have a real problem. Was
Speaker 2:  George r Binks there?
Speaker 7:  No. Okay.
Speaker 8:  No, we're fine actually. So it's, it's the, it's the chronological first
Speaker 8:  one, not the story. First one, we're gonna pause
Speaker 2:  This podcast. Mia's gonna go watch all the Star Wars and we'll, we'll resume.
Speaker 8:  No, we'll make her watch all of them. Some of them are not worth,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there's like five of them you should watch. It'll be all right. But
Speaker 2:  wait, Alison, explain. Explain the Holodeck.
Speaker 14:  Okay. Holodeck, it's like a medium sized room that
Speaker 14:  is just like pixels or something and there's a little control
Speaker 14:  panel on the outside. And you want to, if you wanna go to
Speaker 14:  like a rainforest or seal waterfall, you go like
Speaker 14:  boop, boop, boop boop. And you put it on the control panel and the room
Speaker 14:  turns into wherever you wanna go. And I think that's
Speaker 14:  perfect And I want one.
Speaker 7:  That sounds great. Don't we already have that with the Vision Pro?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, but someone was gonna say Vision Pro
Speaker 14:  God, God
Speaker 8:  Damnit. No, absolutely not. This
Speaker 14:  Is not the same thing. I'm not gonna
Speaker 8:  Holodeck. Yeah, comfy Vision Pro. Not comfy.
Speaker 7:  I
Speaker 14:  Wanna like, you can interact with stuff in the holodeck.
Speaker 14:  Like it's, it's like semi real, you know,
Speaker 14:  like if there's a waterfall then there's
Speaker 14:  maybe real water. I don't know. Maybe let's not get to You
Speaker 2:  Experience it like it's real, I think, but it's, but it's not, which is very
Speaker 2:  important. Right? I I honestly believe the world would be a much better place
Speaker 2:  if there were holodecks everywhere.
Speaker 14:  Wouldn't it be so
Speaker 8:  Good? Most importantly, you don't have to wear anything. Yes, very true.
Speaker 8:  Like, that's my big thing. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Well, and it, it was interesting how it changed throughout the seasons. It
Speaker 9:  became an entire like world that you would go into and like having
Speaker 9:  entire stories and act out dreams and ideas.
Speaker 9:  And I remember they used to go, there was a lot of westerns in the holiday.
Speaker 9:  Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  For some reason.
Speaker 14:  That's the dude holodeck. Every dude wants to go into a western
Speaker 14:  Hundred percent. I'm just like,
Speaker 9:  Yeah. What is, what would be your ideal holodeck experience?
Speaker 14:  I think it would be the top of a mountain, because it takes a long
Speaker 14:  time to drive to a mountain and hike all the way to the top. And I love
Speaker 14:  doing that. And I do that from time to time. But sometimes you wanna like
Speaker 14:  microdose top of mountain experience And I could just like,
Speaker 14:  hang out for a little bit and come back and like deal with my 3-year-old
Speaker 14:  and be chill. That's what I want.
Speaker 2:  I do think we need strict time limits on holodeck usage. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  The world. You can't like go live in the holodeck.
Speaker 2:  Right. We're we're talking like, like a 60 minute a day kind of
Speaker 2:  experience. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But with some time limit. I sincerely believe the world would be a much better
Speaker 2:  place if we all had access to holodeck. I think I would. And you can just
Speaker 2:  go like, get out of your system or experience whatever you
Speaker 2:  need to over there. Yep. And then it's, and then
Speaker 2:  come back
Speaker 8:  To David Reality. I thought we weren't trying to make the world a better
Speaker 8:  place with our fix.
Speaker 14:  It's a byproduct. I want my world to be a better place.
Speaker 14:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's a, that's a very good one. That was the next one on my list.
Speaker 2:  And I'm sort of sad I didn't pick it. Mia, you're up.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Just strategically, I think I need to, to grab
Speaker 7:  the clueless closet. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Surprised it took this long. Honestly.
Speaker 7:  It's classic. It is so fun. I just rewatched the clip
Speaker 7:  a little bit ago. I will say I'm like halfway there not to
Speaker 7:  brag, but I have, it's, it's not as pretty. But
Speaker 7:  I do have a mega spreadsheet that is an
Speaker 7:  inventory of every single piece of clothing I own. Oh. And then, oh my
Speaker 7:  God, the season and the color and where it is in my apartment, like where
Speaker 7:  it's being stored, whether it's vintage, whether it's
Speaker 7:  from my mom, like any tags, like keywords.
Speaker 7:  So I will say like, this would, this would visualize
Speaker 7:  a, an insane thing that I'm already doing.
Speaker 2:  Can you describe how the clueless closet works for anyone who hasn't seen
Speaker 2:  the movie?
Speaker 7:  So it kind of, it like pulls in all of Cher's
Speaker 7:  articles of clothing and then she, on her computer, she can kind of scroll
Speaker 7:  through them and it matches. She combines a top
Speaker 7:  and a bottom and then the computer will be like, wrong,
Speaker 7:  ugly, or it will be like, good, cute.
Speaker 7:  And it's sort of like, in a way, like, I feel like a lot of these ai
Speaker 7:  like outfit things are trying to harness
Speaker 7:  that. But it's the, the clueless one is so cute.
Speaker 7:  It looks so fun. It has that very, like, the really good
Speaker 7:  like late nineties, early two thousands aesthetic. Like, it's just so good.
Speaker 7:  And yeah, I have a lot of clothes. I have a lot of clothes And I need it.
Speaker 2:  Are you sure your spreadsheet isn't enough? You're like one column of photos
Speaker 2:  away from just having completely solved this problem.
Speaker 7:  I know. Well actually, I've seen online some people will like, photograph
Speaker 7:  themselves wearing every article of clothing and then cut their body in half
Speaker 7:  and make like a flip book of the closet, which is really a really cute idea.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God. But I just do not have the patience for that. Also, there is no
Speaker 7:  three ring binder that is even close to big enough for me to put all my clothes
Speaker 7:  in.
Speaker 2:  Would you update anything from the clueless closet is my main question. It's,
Speaker 2:  it's, 'cause that's a, that's an older idea about this stuff. But I think
Speaker 2:  back and I'm like, it, they actually, it was sort of perfect. I don't, I
Speaker 2:  don't need any features. Think that I didn't have,
Speaker 7:  I think, yeah, don't overcomplicate it like top and bottom. That's pretty
Speaker 7:  much, I mean, that's kind of the basis of every outfit, unless you're wearing
Speaker 7:  like a dress or something. But don't make it too complicated. I just
Speaker 7:  want, just like generate an idea for me or tell me if my idea is bad.
Speaker 7:  I would mostly, it's like visualizing it. Hmm. Like you can see it before
Speaker 7:  you put it on your body and then have to take it off and hang it back up
Speaker 7:  and fold it or whatever. So yeah. Not, I, I would not change a single
Speaker 7:  thing. I want it as is.
Speaker 2:  That's a good one. I like it. All right. V you're up.
Speaker 8:  Okay, so this is gonna make me sound like a total anime nerd, but once again,
Speaker 8:  I am, I am taking from the world of Dragon Ball Z And
Speaker 8:  I want Scouters. So if you've never watched Dragon Ball
Speaker 2:  ZV, am I gonna have to make a rule that you can't pick all your things from
Speaker 2:  one?
Speaker 8:  No, I only, I literally only had two. I only literally only had the two.
Speaker 8:  And so the scouters from Dragon Ball Z are like these little
Speaker 8:  heads up display augmented reality type situations
Speaker 8:  where it fits over one part of your eye. If you have been online
Speaker 8:  in the last 20 years, you've probably heard it's over
Speaker 18:  9,000,
Speaker 8:  Which is just Ji screaming because kus power level is over 9,000.
Speaker 8:  Ji
Speaker 18:  What's wrong with you? Tell me what his power level is.
Speaker 18:  It's over 9,000 plus 9,000. You've
Speaker 18:  gotta be
Speaker 8:  Kidding me. The idea is that it can bioscan like life forms
Speaker 8:  and tell you what their power level is. And I just think that this would
Speaker 8:  be really great for my social anxiety if I can go
Speaker 8:  into a meeting or anything and just put this on and go like,
Speaker 8:  oh, my power level is over that of random e executive.
Speaker 8:  Cool. I can just relax now. Like if I, you know, I
Speaker 8:  just think it would be great for people if they were going into job interviews
Speaker 8:  and they could put a little scatter on their face and go like, oh, the schmuck,
Speaker 8:  this HR rep, this, this schmuck is like 2000 power levels below me.
Speaker 8:  I'm good, I'm cool. I'm Gucci.
Speaker 2:  What if it tells you something you're not prepared to know about?
Speaker 8:  Well then you're, then you're allowed to panic. But then, you know, at least
Speaker 8:  you have your, your mindset going like, oh, I need to be on top of my game.
Speaker 8:  Like, you can calibrate what your, then
Speaker 2:  You have your motorcycle in a capsule and you just ride away. Then you
Speaker 8:  Have my motorcycle in a capsule and I'm like, bye-bye. I'm
Speaker 8:  Oh, your power level's over 9,000. Okay, motorcycle in the capsule.
Speaker 8:  Bye-bye. I'm, I'm good. So like that's my, I just
Speaker 8:  want scouters And I, I want it like, in my ideal world, you could tweak it
Speaker 8:  to whatever you want. So oh, you're, you're going on a date.
Speaker 8:  Calibrate it to Riz. Like how much charisma does this person that you're
Speaker 8:  going on a date have with? Oh, they're, their, their Riz level is
Speaker 8:  9,000. Okay. Now you, you can be on alert for every lie
Speaker 8:  that comes out of their mouth.
Speaker 2:  It's the ultimate like, read the room machine.
Speaker 8:  Read the room machine. I like this. You just go, you go read the room and
Speaker 8:  you go, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh. And if I ever got to meet Tim Cook, I would be
Speaker 8:  able to be like, oh, cool.
Speaker 9:  Is it like a, I I I still don't quite get what it is. Does it let you
Speaker 9:  read their mind kind of
Speaker 8:  Thing? No, no. It just like, so like in their world does that, everyone has
Speaker 8:  something called Key. So like, it's like their power level. It's like how
Speaker 8:  powerful they are. Oh. So I doesn't read their mind. It just like assigns
Speaker 8:  an, like, this person is really powerful. So, so
Speaker 9:  You're just kind
Speaker 8:  Of that sort of thing,
Speaker 9:  Getting a, a vibe from them kind of?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Kind of like a, like a numerical, you know, I'm wearable lady, so of
Speaker 8:  course you get a metric level of some person's specific attribute.
Speaker 8:  So you can, like my, I my ideal version of it, you just be like,
Speaker 8:  oh, I would like to see what someone's friendliness level is when I go
Speaker 8:  into like a group of people I've never met before. Ah, scanning
Speaker 8:  the friendliest person. Okay, this person will give me the least anxiety
Speaker 8:  to talk to. Like that sort of thing. Or, you know, it could be used for evil.
Speaker 8:  It could be like, who is the most manipulable person in this room?
Speaker 8:  Like, so there's,
Speaker 9:  We love quantifying humans.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That's, that's literally my job. Except
Speaker 8:  usually I quantify myself. So like, this is just, you
Speaker 8:  know, it's kind of like in Allison's vein of, of the Neuralizer, which was
Speaker 8:  also gonna be one of my picks. Don you Allison. But it's,
Speaker 8:  it's just like a way of managing social anxiety is how I
Speaker 8:  view it.
Speaker 2:  You, I know just knowing you, I'm sure you have 38 wearables on right now.
Speaker 2:  You would just wear this thing all the time. Do you think most people wear
Speaker 2:  this all the time? Like is this just a, a fixture on everybody's heads forever
Speaker 2:  now?
Speaker 8:  No, And I actually wouldn't wear it all the time. I would mostly wear it
Speaker 8:  in like social situations where I'm just trying to like get a sense of my
Speaker 8:  bearings and like what I need to, to be aware of going
Speaker 8:  into a room. Because like, I don't know, like my, I
Speaker 8:  don't really have an internal monologue, but I do have stress levels
Speaker 8:  shoot through the roof when I have to meet a bunch of people or just be around
Speaker 8:  more than two humans at a time. I just go like, so
Speaker 8:  that's my way of solving
Speaker 9:  That.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I like this. I'm not positive.
Speaker 2:  This ends up being a good idea. Oh. But I like,
Speaker 8:  It's absolute horrible idea, but I like it. I'm telling you, all
Speaker 8:  of my picks are selfish. So there we go.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I love this for you. Who, who cares what happens to everybody else?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Jen, you're up, you get two now.
Speaker 9:  I'm going, I'm afraid I'm going to some more big splashy tech this time.
Speaker 9:  My next few are a little less splashy, but I'm not sure
Speaker 9:  that three quarters of the room is gonna remember this one. But I'm gonna
Speaker 9:  start with the theme song and we'll see.
Speaker 9:  I want, I want Kit explain. Okay, kid. I
Speaker 8:  Know Three Girls. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Kit was on my list. Oh, okay. Kit was on my list. I admit I am,
Speaker 2:  I am more familiar with Kit than I am with Knight Rider, So I see. So I
Speaker 2:  I left you hanging unintentionally there. Okay. But Kit is a very good pick.
Speaker 2:  E explain to the, the, the unknown in to the
Speaker 9:  Young people in the,
Speaker 2:  To the Youths of America.
Speaker 9:  Yes. So Kit is an an acronym. So
Speaker 9:  Kit is Knight Industries 2000. And it is a smart
Speaker 9:  car And I mean a really smart car.
Speaker 9:  It's basically like a Jarvis in a car and
Speaker 9:  in a Pontiac Firebird TransAm, in fact, which was not
Speaker 9:  a fact I knew until I researched for this because I'm not a a
Speaker 9:  Motorhead. But yes, it is a black car that has a
Speaker 9:  smart assistant inside. You know, I'm the smart home lady here,
Speaker 9:  So I needed my smart assistant, but it's on wheels, which
Speaker 9:  doesn't get much better. It can do everything. Like literally, I don't think
Speaker 9:  there's anything that Kit didn't do during the however many seasons
Speaker 9:  there were of Night Rider, which were many starring David Hasselhoff,
Speaker 9:  pre Baywatch and such a good show.
Speaker 9:  They revived it. I don't think I watched any of that. They did it recently.
Speaker 9:  I think you didn't miss anything. No, and it's basically
Speaker 9:  a self-aware computer in a car. And David Knight,
Speaker 9:  who is David Hasselhoff has a watch and he can call
Speaker 9:  you kind of need both pieces of tech, but he can call Kit to him when he's
Speaker 9:  in danger. And so like he'll, he, he uses the watch to
Speaker 9:  communicate and Kit would like just come to the rescue and like blow
Speaker 9:  through walls and rescue him. And he has all
Speaker 9:  sorts of like sense. I mean he, he ha he's a self-driving car
Speaker 9:  to start with and he has senses that can like means that, that
Speaker 9:  he, I'm sorry it, I should not
Speaker 9:  the ai, but it has sensors that can smell,
Speaker 9:  feel like scanners that can see inside buildings. So like when
Speaker 9:  David Hasselhoff, David Knight, was it David Knight?
Speaker 9:  I I get my sounds. I'm getting my David's confused. I know one of the reasons
Speaker 9:  I'm getting my David's confused is because sidebar, my
Speaker 9:  uncle David Darlene was the stuntman for night rider. So
Speaker 9:  what?
Speaker 8:  Very cool, cool,
Speaker 9:  Cool. Stop. So yeah, that was kind of cool. That was right. Well, and
Speaker 2:  I'm even happier that you get this one now.
Speaker 9:  Yes, this is, yeah, I mean it was, it's an
Speaker 9:  ai you know, today it's a, basically I said a Jarvis in a car with
Speaker 9:  every kind of technology you could possibly want. And every sort of scenario
Speaker 9:  night rider got himself into the car, could come to the
Speaker 9:  rescue. And it was also, I think the thing I liked most
Speaker 9:  about Kit, which is sort of what you mentioned about Jarvis too, is that
Speaker 9:  it was very funny and dry witted and would kind of,
Speaker 9:  you know, sort of say, David you're being stupid
Speaker 19:  Buddy. To investigate.
Speaker 20:  To investigate what?
Speaker 19:  Well, if I knew that they wouldn't have to investigate. Now what
Speaker 20:  You call that logic,
Speaker 19:  You got a better idea.
Speaker 20:  How would you like to hear a little music?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, kit's a good picture because also
Speaker 9:  Michael. Michael, it was Michael Knight. Sorry. That's right. David Hasselhoff
Speaker 9:  played Michael Knight. Michael you're being stupid.
Speaker 9:  Sorry, all my name's getting mixed up here. This is a good one. But
Speaker 2:  Yes, it was also just a sick car. It could do, it was a car, everything.
Speaker 2:  A car you needed to do it, it could go in the water. It looked awesome.
Speaker 2:  It would go really fast. It was just like, you would want it just as a
Speaker 2:  car. Yes. But then also it was also like a, a cool kind
Speaker 2:  of obnoxious AI best friend.
Speaker 9:  Very obnoxious, but very cool. And there was the gold pendant, which is
Speaker 9:  the other really cool thing. So, so eighties.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, but the, he had the gold pendant. He could just like, if he was in
Speaker 9:  real danger, he could just press the gold pendant and kit would come. Oh,
Speaker 9:  it was so cool.
Speaker 2:  And I think all this comes with the car, right? Like when you buy the car
Speaker 2:  Yes. You get all the access. The dealership ship is definitely like throwing
Speaker 2:  in the full package the watch and the pendant as the accessories. Yes.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And you know, paired with my Tardis, I mean I'm like,
Speaker 9:  I'm set for life. I can do everything I need to go
Speaker 9:  anywhere I want and have my AI companion come to my
Speaker 9:  rescue. When, when I'm in those awkward situations that my
Speaker 9:  neuralizer is not gonna help me with.
Speaker 2:  Can can kit fit in the TARDIS by the rules of the tardis? Can you bring Kit
Speaker 2:  with you?
Speaker 9:  Yes, I think you can. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Well
Speaker 8:  I can, you can, I can borrow a you can borrow a capsule just to sit
Speaker 8:  there you go the
Speaker 9:  Target into my pocket
Speaker 8:  Capsule and then fit it into the tardis so
Speaker 2:  You can put the capsule in my giant pockets more
Speaker 2:  room, everything. Bingo in Mia's pockets. Mia ends this
Speaker 2:  the most powerful, just by virtue of having giant pockets. That's, that's
Speaker 2:  definitely how. Alright Jen, you're up next. But first let's take a
Speaker 2:  break and then we're gonna do, that's two rounds. We got three more to do.
Speaker 2:  We're coming right back to you Jen. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back round three. Jen, you're up again.
Speaker 2:  How do you feel? You ready? You got this one.
Speaker 9:  I, I think I'm gonna have to go with Rosie.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 9:  Just because I know just because
Speaker 2:  You're doing the old head picks here. I love this for you.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that's, you know, kit and Ro, Rosie and
Speaker 9:  Star Trek. Were all, you know, that's why I became a tech journalist. So
Speaker 9:  I gotta follow the theme And I would've gone for Jarvis because I wanted
Speaker 9:  Jarvis to be my housekeeper, not Rosie. Hmm. Just 'cause I want to buck the
Speaker 9:  societal trends here. I don't think Rosie should necessarily have to be a
Speaker 9:  woman. I agree. She as a household robot and Jarvis is
Speaker 9:  just a bit hotter too. So
Speaker 2:  I mean, I I did get Paul Beney, so like I got that going for me. Explain,
Speaker 2:  explain Rosie's deal for, for folks who have not seen the Jetsons.
Speaker 9:  Okay, so Rosie is a household robot. And actually
Speaker 9:  in the early sort of days of the Jetsons, it was rather,
Speaker 9:  it wasn't that good. In fact, one of the, the stories around it was that
Speaker 9:  they couldn't afford the more expensive fancy model. So they had
Speaker 9:  like the older model. But still Rosie can do a lot,
Speaker 9:  Rosie's basically a humanoid
Speaker 9:  robot that can, and on a, on wheels that can kind of roll
Speaker 9:  around the house and act like a housekeeper, maid,
Speaker 9:  nanny doing, you know, all the chores that you might need. Because
Speaker 9:  I've spent a lot of time with robots in my home over the, over the last few
Speaker 9:  years. And the one thing I've realized that a robot really does need is
Speaker 9:  some form of arms and limbs to do things for you.
Speaker 9:  If you're going to have a humanoid type robot in your home that's going to
Speaker 9:  fold your laundry or empty your dishwasher, you need
Speaker 9:  limbs. And Rosie has little claw like limbs.
Speaker 9:  This is why I wanted Jarvis because, you know, it looks like an actual person
Speaker 9:  as opposed to Rosie does kind of look like pieces of scrap metal put
Speaker 9:  together. But, but still it's, it, it works, it
Speaker 9:  it, it gets the job done and that's what I need. I want something to,
Speaker 9:  you know, do the laundry and put the clothes away and empty the dishwasher.
Speaker 9:  'cause I have not yet figured out how to get anyone else in my house to do
Speaker 9:  that for me. So
Speaker 9:  some version of a Rosie I would like in my future, although I am
Speaker 9:  slightly terrified of the, as much as I find the appendage
Speaker 9:  is useful, I'm also slightly terrified of them. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So I'm curious in your, in your day to day as a smart home reporter, how
Speaker 2:  often would you say Rosie the robot comes up? Because I feel like Rosie is
Speaker 2:  one of the like canonical Yeah. Smart home things that
Speaker 2:  everybody is always trying to build.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it is. It's very, and it's kind of tired from that
Speaker 9:  perspective. It's like, it's what we're holding so much up against.
Speaker 9:  But it's also, I mean, we've had so much technology from
Speaker 9:  TV and movies and popular culture come to reality because
Speaker 9:  it actually does help push people forward and invent things. And I feel
Speaker 9:  like there's a lot of things we have in our homes today because of Rosie
Speaker 9:  because people are trying to make Rosie. That's why we have robot vacuum
Speaker 9:  cleaners. You know, I'm not, I mean, I'm sure I know
Speaker 9:  for a fact that that's like some of the idea behind the original
Speaker 9:  robot vacuum was we want to make something that's gonna be helpful like a
Speaker 9:  Rosie. So in that respect, I think, you know, she
Speaker 9:  is in the smart home Hall of fame and always will be
Speaker 2:  V you're up next. What, okay, what Dragon Ball Z thing are you gonna subject
Speaker 2:  us to this time?
Speaker 8:  It's not, it's not Dragon Ball Z this time, but I do think
Speaker 8:  I'm, the rest of my picks are a bit more
Speaker 8:  obscure. Okay. So I'm gonna go with the one that I think is least obscure
Speaker 8:  and it is the Babelfish from Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
Speaker 24:  It feeds on brainwave energy absorbing unconscious
Speaker 24:  frequencies and excreting a matrix of conscious frequencies to the speech
Speaker 24:  centers of the brain. The practical upshot of which is that if
Speaker 24:  you stick one in your ear, you instantly understand
Speaker 24:  anything said to you in any language.
Speaker 8:  Because I spent a lot of my life studying various
Speaker 8:  languages and v's brain it heri it tired. There are no
Speaker 8:  room for anything besides English now. So I would like
Speaker 8:  a little fish, little fish friend that translates everybody for me. So that
Speaker 8:  when I translate, when I go on a plane and decide to
Speaker 8:  torture myself on the way to ww DC watching Emelia Perez, I
Speaker 8:  don't have to squint my eyes reading the horrible translations.
Speaker 8:  You know, even though maybe I shouldn't have known what was being
Speaker 8:  sung in that horrible ass movie. That's my review of Amelia Perez. Why
Speaker 8:  I don know why I decided I don't, I don't,
Speaker 14:  I can't tell you why I got the full recap from V after she saw it
Speaker 14:  on our walk to Dunking Donuts.
Speaker 8:  I was on a street reenacting the film for Allison
Speaker 8:  and having a meltdown while doing it. But
Speaker 2:  That's when Allison decided she wanted the neuralizer. She's like, I can't,
Speaker 2:  I'm done with this,
Speaker 14:  This exact situation.
Speaker 8:  Basically. Yeah, no, no. I was watching a bunch of movies on
Speaker 8:  the plane that were foreign language. I don't know why I decided. No, actually
Speaker 8:  I do know why. 'cause my husband does not like reading subtitles.
Speaker 8:  So this is very per, like I said, all my pics are selfish. I wanna be able
Speaker 8:  to watch movies and not have him complain about subtitles and just
Speaker 8:  have the direct translation. 'cause I wanted to watch eczema,
Speaker 8:  a Korean horror movie last year, And I had
Speaker 8:  to do it on a plane And I kept getting interrupted by the pilot giving safety
Speaker 8:  information, like just let me die if the plane crashes and
Speaker 8:  interrupting plots stuff. So I would've really liked the Babelfish at
Speaker 8:  that point in time. So,
Speaker 2:  Okay, wait, let me, let me just quickly make sure I understand the case you're
Speaker 2:  making here. Yes. You would like this thing, which if, if memory serves from
Speaker 2:  Hitchhiker's guy is a literal fish you shove into your ear. Yes. Correct.
Speaker 2:  That real time translates all languages to all languages, right? Yes. That's,
Speaker 2:  that's okay. A literal fish that you've shoved in your ear,
Speaker 2:  you want it so you can watch horrible Netflix movies without subtitles. That's
Speaker 2:  your, that's your whole
Speaker 8:  Whole deal here. That's one was one use case. Also talking to my family because
Speaker 8:  I am the Korean CCA in my family. I speak English, they speak Korean, and
Speaker 8:  somehow we understand each other except like there's always like a word or
Speaker 8:  two that I'm like, hmm. Context can't math out that meaning.
Speaker 8:  So I would like that for, for those situations. And I'd like it for when
Speaker 8:  I travel to other places in which I have not studied the language and have
Speaker 8:  no intention to do Duolingo my ass into any form
Speaker 8:  of dday, esta la Biblioteca and or whatever.
Speaker 8:  Like, and like I would keep Fred in his own little tank and we
Speaker 8:  would be friends and you know, he, I would have a very
Speaker 8:  equitable life situation for Fred. Like, I, I just don't want an
Speaker 8:  AI because like the, the, the appeal of the Babelfish
Speaker 8:  is that he's gonna be able to translate my cousin's kid when she
Speaker 8:  says skip bitty toilet as to what the fuck that means.
Speaker 8:  So, and that can be translated into all languages because
Speaker 8:  the problem with current AI translators is that and there shit
Speaker 8:  at slang. Correct. And so it is use, I wanna talk to the teenagers and all
Speaker 8:  these different languages and be like, please brain dump upon me your
Speaker 8:  horrors. I would love to learn more about them. And
Speaker 8:  the language barrier is they, they continually contort
Speaker 8:  language into new ways And I I need the babelfish to, to do that for me.
Speaker 2:  All right. Fair enough. Weird that it's a fish. Like it's a real bummer that
Speaker 2:  all of us now have to shove a fish in our ears to make this work. Listen,
Speaker 2:  but Sure.
Speaker 8:  Listen, it's
Speaker 2:  Whatever. It's cute. Whatever works for you. Yeah, I like it. Mia, you're
Speaker 2:  up.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I have an old head pick, so you guys will appreciate it.
Speaker 7:  My pick are, I'm also like not that young,
Speaker 7:  So I don't know why I said that.
Speaker 2:  We're all in our seventies. It's important to know except for m
Speaker 7:  Yeah, my emotional age is very old. My pick are
Speaker 7:  the glasses from they live. If
Speaker 7:  anyone has seen that movie, they are sort of like glasses that have been
Speaker 7:  created to when you put them on, you see
Speaker 7:  which of the people around you are aliens
Speaker 7:  with evil, evil goals and all
Speaker 7:  like ads or magazines. Like, it wakes you up to
Speaker 7:  big advertising and like propaganda. So you'll look at
Speaker 7:  an ad, you'll put the glasses on and you'll look at an ad and it says like,
Speaker 7:  obey. That's actually where the Obey streetwear logo comes from.
Speaker 7:  Oh. Or it will, you know, you'll look at
Speaker 7:  like a magazine and it says like, no independent thought.
Speaker 7:  And I, I don't need the glasses. I think
Speaker 7:  other people need them. Wow. So I would get a bunch of glasses and give
Speaker 7:  them to people. And actually I, if I can brag for a second,
Speaker 7:  the reason I picked the glasses is because I did a story last
Speaker 7:  year about all the ways that people like changed their websites to
Speaker 7:  appease Google. And it was like a step by step. Here are all the reasons.
Speaker 7:  And the novelist, Colson Whitehead shared my story and
Speaker 7:  said reading this was like putting on the they live glasses. Nice.
Speaker 7:  So I I'm chasing that high all
Speaker 7:  the time. And yeah, I'm giving these glasses out to a lot of people. Let's
Speaker 7:  just say that
Speaker 2:  I like them as glasses because it also implies you can take them off and
Speaker 2:  go back to living in like blissful ignorance, which feels important. Like
Speaker 2:  yes, I both do and don't want to know how the world really works. You know
Speaker 2:  what I mean? Yeah. It's like sometimes I do and then sometimes I would like
Speaker 2:  to just go home and be
Speaker 7:  Fine. Yeah. I mean, I would like, I would like them to tell
Speaker 7:  me who is lying in a way. Like, I,
Speaker 7:  I, this is so nerdy, I wanna know what is like un
Speaker 7:  unidentified spun con. This is so boring.
Speaker 2:  What if it, what if you put these glasses on and it turns out that like all
Speaker 2:  of the conspiracy theories that we've made fun of on the internet actually
Speaker 2:  turn out to be true. It could
Speaker 7:  Like, could be Oh, no. Good to know.
Speaker 2:  Would rather know. Yeah. You just put them on and it's just instantly like
Speaker 2:  the Illuminati everywhere and you're like, oh my God. They were right.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It could be. I'm willing to take that chance, but like I said, I don't
Speaker 7:  think I'll be wearing them that much. I'm gonna give them to people who need
Speaker 7:  them.
Speaker 7:  It's like media literacy in a, in a, in a wearable
Speaker 14:  Form factor. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You're like a pastor on a street corner, but you're handing out glasses basically.
Speaker 14:  Not sketchy at all.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Here, wear these. You'll see the truth. Like that's, that's gonna go
Speaker 2:  great for
Speaker 7:  Everybody. Yeah. No, that's exactly it. That's exactly it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I like this. Allison, you're up next.
Speaker 14:  All right. I'm gonna stay in the realm of film
Speaker 14:  and go with
Speaker 14:  dinosaur embryos, but only the
Speaker 14:  ones that eat plants. So Jurassic Park could
Speaker 2:  Be, hold on. Is this, are we, is this technology? Are we, are we gonna allow
Speaker 2:  this as
Speaker 14:  Technology? Because it's the, here's the exact technology, David, thank
Speaker 14:  you for asking. It's the barbasol can. The
Speaker 14:  barbasol can, that Atu has, that has
Speaker 14:  the embryos inside of it. So if you have that,
Speaker 14:  you, I mean, you have to like, I don't know how to turn a dinosaur embryo
Speaker 14:  into a baby dinosaurs. I'll pay someone to figure that out.
Speaker 14:  So I'm starting with a bible. So can, and I'm gonna take out the,
Speaker 14:  the embryos for the Velociraptors and the T-Rex, And I'm gonna throw
Speaker 14:  those away. We don't need that chaos, and we're just gonna have
Speaker 14:  the nice dinosaurs and they can like live in the
Speaker 14:  zoo and it'll be great.
Speaker 7:  I feel like famously that's not great.
Speaker 2:  You're just describing the first act of Jurassic Park, and then it all goes
Speaker 2:  wrong.
Speaker 14:  If you, if you forget, I'm gonna use the neuralizer on
Speaker 14:  myself. Forget everything I learned from Jurassic Park.
Speaker 14:  Just have the, the cute, nice dinosaurs. Maybe I'll make 'em a little
Speaker 14:  smaller. They don't need to be so
Speaker 9:  Big.
Speaker 8:  I mean,
Speaker 2:  This is how it starts, Alison.
Speaker 8:  They have feathers. I mean, they'll have feathers. They'll be cute. It might
Speaker 8:  be, we had a bunch of new birds, like new, new kinds of chickens.
Speaker 8:  Oh.
Speaker 9:  I'd much rather have dinosaurs than, what are the, the rats?
Speaker 9:  The wooly mammoth rats. They've just recreated. Oh. Oh, let's bring back
Speaker 9:  dinosaurs.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Yeah. Let's bring
Speaker 9:  Back dinosaurs. I'm, I'm with Allison on this one. I want, I want dinosaur.
Speaker 9:  They want chicken dinosaurs. I, chicken
Speaker 8:  Dinosaurs. I, they're like chicken sized or, or like, if, if we can have
Speaker 8:  them in miniature,
Speaker 14:  Maybe we could put a size lemon on it.
Speaker 2:  I think like, if you can't hold it in two hands, it's too big
Speaker 9:  Life. We'll find a way, Allison. Yes,
Speaker 14:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We just, this is, this is the beginning of, of Jurassic Park. We just
Speaker 2:  did it. Everybody Congrat.
Speaker 14:  Congratulations. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Jeff Goldblum is gonna be here any minute. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Be
Speaker 2:  Good to go. We're gonna make a lot of money and then it's all gonna fall
Speaker 2:  apart. And I think that's fine. We're, we're gonna get really rich along
Speaker 2:  the way. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Dang. Wow. That is not where I expect you just, okay. This is good.
Speaker 2:  All right. I get two now. I spend a lot of time, I don't know if this is
Speaker 2:  a thing any of you spent time thinking about. I spent a lot of time thinking
Speaker 2:  about contact lenses because this is a thing that comes up in a lot
Speaker 2:  of movies and TV shows. Various David, they like skip
Speaker 2:  past, you know, AR glasses and they go right to contact lenses
Speaker 2:  to do various things.
Speaker 2:  I have landed on the contact lenses from the movie
Speaker 2:  Mission Impossible Ghost Protocol, which is not the
Speaker 2:  best of the Mission Impossible movies. But
Speaker 2:  basically these contact lenses have two features that I like very much.
Speaker 2:  One is facial recognition, which frankly I could take or leave. Like
Speaker 2:  Neli always says that his great thing for AR glasses is like, tell him who
Speaker 2:  everybody is. That's fine. He can have that. What I want is the other feature,
Speaker 2:  which is essentially just a, a text scanner
Speaker 2:  camera for photographing documents in your day-to-day life. And
Speaker 2:  I'm just thinking, for me, as someone with a truly
Speaker 2:  godawful memory, I just, I'm just, I'm just running around taking
Speaker 2:  pictures of everything forever. This is like, this is the greatest camera
Speaker 2:  I've ever had. I can remember all the documents that I see. I'd have to spend
Speaker 2:  a lot less time like transcribing stuff out of my camera roll. This is
Speaker 2:  Pure like a work device for me that is just my
Speaker 2:  text scanner for everything all the time. And then I'm gonna just pipe it
Speaker 2:  into Apple reminders and just remember everything that ever happens to me
Speaker 14:  We're so boring. That was my crazy question. Like when you wanna
Speaker 14:  recall it, what do you see? Does it appear in front of your eyes or what?
Speaker 2:  That's a good question. I think I just tell Jarvis this is, this is what
Speaker 2:  I, this is what I do. I'm
Speaker 8:  Curious why the contact lens form factor, because
Speaker 8:  ostensibly one of the many smart glasses across many
Speaker 8:  franchises of sci-fi would also be able to do
Speaker 8:  this for you. Like why the contact lenses? I
Speaker 2:  Just, I, so as somebody who does not wear glasses or contacts,
Speaker 2:  I feel like I would get used to contacts faster than I would get used to
Speaker 2:  glasses. And please disabuse me of this notion if I
Speaker 2:  am wrong. But I think the idea of like, I'm just gonna have this sort of
Speaker 2:  on and with me all day. I think contact lenses would annoy me less, which
Speaker 2:  is my whole reason for choosing this.
Speaker 8:  Your eyes gonna get so
Speaker 9:  Dry. Yeah. By the end of the day. So dry.
Speaker 8:  They're gonna be so dry. You're gonna be wishing you a glasses.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna like beta test one of these and go blind is basically what's gonna
Speaker 2:  happen. But you might be right.
Speaker 9:  Is this like photographic memory though? Is that kind of,
Speaker 2:  It's essentially photographic memory.
Speaker 9:  It's that I'm definitely down with, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Recallable photographic memory Yes. Is essentially what these give you. And
Speaker 2:  I'm extremely
Speaker 8:  Here for it. Listen, did, did, did most of us not covet the neur? Because
Speaker 8:  remembering everything is painful.
Speaker 9:  It's a curse. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But in this world, I get to have a neuralizer anyway, So I'm just,
Speaker 2:  I'm just constantly fairness, constantly calibrating fairness of remembering
Speaker 2:  and forgetting everything as I want to.
Speaker 2:  So I'm taking that one. And then I'm, there's a lot, there's a
Speaker 2:  lot more possibilities here. I'm gonna take for my next pick
Speaker 2:  the portal gun from Rick and Morty. I don't know if any
Speaker 2:  of you have watched Rick and Morty, but basically the portal gun
Speaker 2:  opens up portals to parallel universes and sometimes they know where
Speaker 2:  they're going and sometimes they don't. And it's pure chaos. It is just like
Speaker 2:  an nonstop adventure machine. And you have the gun that can
Speaker 2:  get you to another parallel universe. But also you can use a
Speaker 2:  portal to get back. And I just think as somebody who spends a lot
Speaker 2:  of time sitting here in my basement on Google meet, talking to
Speaker 2:  people, it would be really nice to just be able to like turn around and
Speaker 2:  just like hit up a parallel universe for 20 minutes between meetings. And
Speaker 2:  that feels great.
Speaker 9:  There's a lot of escape in lot of want to escape lot. Yeah. I was gonna say,
Speaker 9:  I think we need a vacation. Yes. That might be right.
Speaker 9:  Just go to the beach. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it's, you know, I can see some stuff, broaden my horizons, try new things,
Speaker 2:  but then I can always come back. There's just a, I just open up a portal
Speaker 2:  right here in the basement. Nobody even knows I'm gone.
Speaker 9:  But you might go somewhere scary. You don't know.
Speaker 2:  Sometimes. Sometimes it is scary and sometimes, sometimes
Speaker 2:  that's, I think I also probably have to have Rick with me for this. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So I think I'm like bringing the portal gun, but I'm also hiring
Speaker 2:  Rick, who is like an insane alcoholic grandpa to come
Speaker 2:  accompany me on these adventures. I'm signing up to be Morty in all of these
Speaker 2:  adventures is what I'm realizing as I say
Speaker 8:  What a choice. Choice.
Speaker 2:  I'm the pathetic sidekick who almost dies over and over, but always has an
Speaker 2:  adventure. And I think I'm ready for that. Oh geez, Rick.
Speaker 9:  It's just
Speaker 8:  You the entire time. That's
Speaker 2:  Me. Yeah. This is, this is the life I'm after. So Yeah, I'm taking the
Speaker 2:  portal gun. I think I don't wanna, like, time travel has like
Speaker 2:  too many consequences for me. I think like if we're, if we're opening
Speaker 2:  up the T Tartus get, just send me to apparel universe. I can't cause any
Speaker 2:  trouble in apparel universe. It's fine.
Speaker 14:  But yeah, but I, I, what is, what are you getting outta
Speaker 14:  this
Speaker 2:  Adventures?
Speaker 14:  Okay, that's it.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's the the beauty.
Speaker 7:  He wants to feel alive.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna learn things. I'm gonna see new creatures. I'm gonna try new stuff.
Speaker 2:  But fundamentally then I feel like I get to come back And I haven't,
Speaker 2:  if I went back to like the tutors with you and the tardis, I'm gonna be like,
Speaker 2:  well, I can't do anything or else I might screw up the future forever. I
Speaker 2:  don't wanna do that. I get to just go to some weird cartoon
Speaker 2:  universe and then come back. No states. Oh, it's
Speaker 7:  All cartoons.
Speaker 2:  Well, and Rick and Morty, it's all cartoons. Presumably my version of it
Speaker 2:  would be real.
Speaker 7:  I don dunno. I don know if you can make that call. Maybe
Speaker 2:  It's all cartoons. If it's all cartoons, I'm even more in And I should have
Speaker 2:  picked the super, that
Speaker 14:  Kind of rules. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, this, that's my, that's this could go horribly wrong, but I feel
Speaker 2:  good about it. I'm taking this pick. Alison, you're up.
Speaker 14:  Okay. In the vein of like little buddies,
Speaker 14:  I guess I'm picking the movie theater from
Speaker 14:  Mystery Science Theater 3000. And what that
Speaker 14:  entails is my little robot friends,
Speaker 14:  you know, Daisy Gypsy, Tom Servo,
Speaker 14:  all those guys we're gonna sit and watch movies
Speaker 14:  and have a good time. And it, it's like you could go there when you want
Speaker 14:  and like watch a bad old movie with your robot friends and then leave,
Speaker 14:  which was not part of the premise of mystery science here. 3000. You were
Speaker 14:  stuck there forever. But in, in my version,
Speaker 14:  you can come and go.
Speaker 2:  This is so wholesome. Yeah. You're just like, I just wanna watch movies with
Speaker 2:  my robot friends. I
Speaker 14:  Wanna hang out with my robot buddies. I have so many good memories of MST.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Are you, are you on the show by virtue of being in the theater?
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 14:  Think you're just kind of along for the ride. Like you don't have to make
Speaker 14:  any jokes or anything. Okay. You're just listening to the jokes
Speaker 14:  and it's fun and nice. And then there's a project
Speaker 14:  they always do like a weird little thing in betwe, like in
Speaker 14:  between segments where they're like, now we're doing a craft or
Speaker 14:  whatever. It, it sounds like preschool. And
Speaker 14:  I, I guess I just wanna go back to preschool
Speaker 7:  Again with the escapism. Like you can go anywhere, anywhere, But here
Speaker 7:  my big pockets and the ability to go anywhere.
Speaker 14:  That's basically,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I, I I love it. I have no notes on this. This is the lowest stakes
Speaker 2:  one yet, by a mile. Yeah. And I'm very happy about this. This causes no societal
Speaker 2:  problems. Nothing, nothing bad happens. You've just created like a new
Speaker 2:  movie theater for a bunch of people to go to. Yeah. That is slightly more
Speaker 2:  fun and there's a lot
Speaker 14:  There. But most importantly for me,
Speaker 2:  I love it. This is great. Mia, you're up.
Speaker 7:  Okay. A lot of people are gonna be mad at me because I think, I think this
Speaker 7:  could be vetoed. I would like the
Speaker 7:  doorknob that Josie Packer and Twin Peaks get stuck in.
Speaker 2:  Wow. No part of that went where
Speaker 8:  I thought I was supposed to have not seen
Speaker 7:  Twin Peak. What? Wait.
Speaker 8:  Store Nob, please
Speaker 7:  Explain. Haven it yet this have, have people seen Twin Peaks? Okay.
Speaker 7:  In Twin Peaks there is like the wealthy wife of a
Speaker 7:  mill owner and she
Speaker 7:  gets stuck in a doorknob and it's just never really resolved.
Speaker 7:  She's just in there and it's a doorknob at like a random,
Speaker 7:  I don't think there's anything special about the doorknob, but her face is
Speaker 7:  in there. And I think the last we see of her is she's kind of like Ahm in
Speaker 7:  the doorknob and like, you know, con confuse let me out. But
Speaker 7:  I would use it to trap my enemies. I'm gonna be, so, for real, I'm,
Speaker 7:  there's nothing deeper. I'm putting, I'm putting you bitches in the doorknob.
Speaker 7:  I don't know if I can say that on this podcast.
Speaker 2:  You absolutely can't. That might be the title of this podcast. What
Speaker 8:  Did we do?
Speaker 7:  Not you guys. Okay. But my, my Enemies, you know what I mean? And
Speaker 7:  trust me right now, a lot of people would be in that door kn a bit. You
Speaker 8:  Know what? I trust Mia's judgment. I give her full
Speaker 8:  authority to just trap her enemy. 'cause I feel like Mia's enemies
Speaker 8:  by and large are Ities enemies. So I fully trust her
Speaker 8:  to trap these bitches in the doorknob.
Speaker 7:  I don dunno if it's a technology, I'm gonna say it is. Oh, that
Speaker 9:  Was gonna be my question. 'cause I did watch some of Twin Peaks, but I don't
Speaker 9:  remember the doorknob. And how did, do we know how she got in there?
Speaker 9:  Like was there technology involved in putting her in there or was it, I mean,
Speaker 9:  there was no rhyme nor reason to Twin Peaks really was there.
Speaker 2:  This is such a good edge case because you're, you're, it, it both isn't technology
Speaker 2:  and is also completely unexplainable by any other means.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I think I have to give this to you because I can't refute it. Like
Speaker 2:  it's
Speaker 7:  Not Yeah. Someone, someone had to invent the doorknob eventually. Like the
Speaker 7:  doorknob generally I would say is a technology.
Speaker 2:  I mean, that's, boy, that's a, that's a great case. I mean, thank you. I
Speaker 2:  also, can we just like quickly psychoanalyze Mia for a second here
Speaker 2:  in, in two consecutive picks has said, I'm going to fix society by giving
Speaker 2:  them real glasses and I'm gonna trap bitches in a doorknob. Like,
Speaker 2:  are we, do you have some, do you have some thoughts about the public we should
Speaker 2:  talk about here
Speaker 7:  For a few minutes? No, I contain multitudes. I both believe in
Speaker 7:  everyone's ability to be better and some people need to be in a timeout in
Speaker 7:  a doorknob. This
Speaker 8:  Is the smart door lock that we need.
Speaker 7:  I'm just, I was,
Speaker 9:  I was gonna give that, but yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And if we, if it existed now, you know, ring Doorbell would
Speaker 7:  be integrating that shit immediately. Oh yeah. Immediately
Speaker 2:  You go in the doorknob ring calls the cops like
Speaker 7:  Immediately. Yeah. People, people would want it for like, the people who
Speaker 7:  steal Amazon packages, you know what I mean? Like, people would be up in
Speaker 7:  arms being like, Amazon package thieves into the doorknob. You get sucked
Speaker 7:  into the doorknob if you steal packages.
Speaker 2:  All right, we'll, we'll allow it. It's, it's, it's sketchy, but we'll, we'll
Speaker 2:  allow it. Ve you're up next.
Speaker 8:  It's extremely hard to follow up the doorknob gel,
Speaker 8:  but I think I'm gonna go with the sonic screwdriver from Dr. Who
Speaker 8:  because that's good choice. This is also kind of a cheaty device in the
Speaker 8:  sense that it is a plot hole filler little
Speaker 2:  Bit Dr. Who's kinda lazy this way. I'm discovering there's just like that
Speaker 2:  can do everything bit. You'll, you, you figure it out.
Speaker 8:  But here's how the laziness suits me And I think society at large
Speaker 8:  because the, so like, if you've never watched Doctor Who the doctor
Speaker 8:  has a bunch of little doodads and gadgets, and one of them is the sonic screwdriver.
Speaker 8:  It is like, it's like a pen with a little light out in the end. It goes b
Speaker 8:  or whatnot. And anytime the writers have written him into a plot corner,
Speaker 8:  he uses the sonic screwdriver and it gets him out of it. Such that,
Speaker 8:  so like a door's locked, Sonic screwdriver opens the door
Speaker 8:  Gadget broke all It's fixed again. Oh, I don't know. I
Speaker 8:  don't know what it's happening. There you go. So it's sort of like a
Speaker 8:  diagnostic tool and a Swiss Army knife fix-it gun.
Speaker 8:  Not, not like, or like, you know, it, it has like spiritually, I think
Speaker 8:  it's very close to a Tide pen in that like, oh no,
Speaker 8:  here's this thing that's that's, that's horrible. Let me just
Speaker 8:  pull out this little pen thing. Oh, it's fixed again. So like,
Speaker 8:  if you can imagine like spiritually a, a digital
Speaker 8:  Tide pen, but instead of being limited to stains,
Speaker 8:  it can like, it can diagnose what's wrong with your computer. It
Speaker 8:  can fix a lock that's broken. It can just,
Speaker 8:  like, I, I hate home maintenance, So I would love to take my little
Speaker 8:  screwdriver and go and be like, tell me what's wrong with my toilet.
Speaker 8:  Oh, the thing I, I'm not a plumber. I don't know what's wrong with the toilet
Speaker 2:  Thing. The thing what plumber say? I think
Speaker 8:  This is the, the, the thing is broken and then you just point at, at again,
Speaker 8:  I go all my toilets fixed, save $2,000 in,
Speaker 8:  in plumbing bills. Like this is, this is what I want a little diagnostic
Speaker 8:  fix it tool.
Speaker 2:  It's also small, which I really appreciate about the song. Yeah. Screwdriver.
Speaker 2:  It's not, I don't have to figure out where to put a phone booth in my house.
Speaker 2:  This is just like a thing I have in a drawer that solves all my problems.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think it's a good one. I like it very much. All right, Jen, back
Speaker 2:  to you. You get two in a row.
Speaker 9:  Oh my goodness.
Speaker 2:  But these are your last two. Okay. So don't blow this, Jen.
Speaker 9:  So I, I have one very obvious one and one not so
Speaker 9:  obvious one. And they're quite connected. So I'm, I'm, I'm happy about this.
Speaker 9:  This I'm going with because I couldn't not do a Star Trek pick.
Speaker 9:  I am going with the replicator. Damn it.
Speaker 2:  That was gonna be my last pick.
Speaker 9:  And for Mia,
Speaker 9:  I would explain,
Speaker 8:  Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry
Speaker 9:  For the Youngs because I don't think anyone else listening to this podcast
Speaker 9:  will need, will
Speaker 8:  Need the God, my God, I'm sorry.
Speaker 9:  But the Star Trek replicator is a computer
Speaker 9:  that on Star Trek spaceships, these are 'cause Star trek's
Speaker 9:  set in space where you can create pretty
Speaker 9:  much anything you like. So you go up to replicator, you
Speaker 9:  say in famously
Speaker 25:  TL, gray Hot
Speaker 25:  TL, gray, hot TL, gray Hot
Speaker 25:  L, gray Tea Hot,
Speaker 9:  And you get tea, hot L Gray. You can
Speaker 9:  also create anything you need any inanimate
Speaker 9:  matter as long as it was in the computer's
Speaker 9:  brain and its programming. So food, basically, this is how they
Speaker 9:  ate on ships and it create anything you wanted. So I
Speaker 9:  have my robot helper and then I have my replicator in my kitchen that can
Speaker 9:  just basically do anything I need. I don't, I no longer need to go to the
Speaker 9:  shops. No grocery shopping for me. I can just get
Speaker 9:  whatever I need from my replicator. Is there anything it can't make? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  so it can create, it, it's limited to what it knows about
Speaker 9:  inside its machine memory. And it
Speaker 9:  couldn't make like, some things that were gonna save the ship so that
Speaker 9:  there was a plot line, like when they needed like,
Speaker 9:  some kind of weird material. It would be something that the, you know, to
Speaker 9:  save the ship to like, so Scotty could fix the engines
Speaker 9:  that he needed and it couldn't replicate that because then there would be
Speaker 9:  no plot left.
Speaker 9:  But it also, what was very cool about it is that it, it could recycle
Speaker 9:  it, it recycled things. So it recycled matter already on the ship
Speaker 9:  into what you created, what you asked it for. So that
Speaker 9:  was, I mean, a little gross depending on what is recycling and
Speaker 9:  what you are eating, but very eco-friendly, which I think is a good
Speaker 9:  feature for our new tech.
Speaker 2:  I think one of the things it did was like provide air, right? That it was
Speaker 2:  like, it, it's, that's you get infinite, breathable air out of the replicator.
Speaker 2:  It's like that. We might, we might need that. We
Speaker 9:  Do need that right now. That's
Speaker 8:  I'm saying So like a 3D printer on steroids.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yes, it is a 3D printer on steroids. So yeah, the replicator, it's,
Speaker 9:  it's, it's a, a predictable one I'm afraid. But we can't not have
Speaker 9:  it.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna pick it. I was hoping I would get it last in the draft because
Speaker 2:  you know, all these losers don't even know what Star Trek is, so
Speaker 2:  Oops. What can you do? All right, we're gonna get to the very last round,
Speaker 2:  but let's take one more break before we do. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Jen, you again? Okay, last round.
Speaker 9:  So my replicator was my last pick and then
Speaker 9:  my to round out my perfect kitchen and home
Speaker 9:  with my smart car and my
Speaker 2:  You are just building the ultimate smart home for yourself. I'm realizing
Speaker 2:  this now. Like what if my job as a reporter was done?
Speaker 9:  Yes, exactly. Fixed all the problems. This one, I think I'm,
Speaker 9:  it's a, it's like a glimpse in the movie. It's only there very briefly,
Speaker 9:  but this is the fruit dispenser in
Speaker 9:  back to the future too.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 9:  It comes out from the ceiling and has freshly grown fruit
Speaker 9:  that you can eat it any time. I love that. And
Speaker 9:  yeah, So I would want that. Like if that, that's the one thing I, if my kitchen
Speaker 9:  could do for me. Just give me fresh fruit. That's really good because you
Speaker 9:  know, that's great.
Speaker 2:  I love it. It's like having a living wall, but it's fruit in your house,
Speaker 9:  You know? Yes, exactly. Gross bananas, right? No, nothing's gone
Speaker 9:  bad or rotten. You know, your strawberries aren't
Speaker 9:  moldy. Your bananas aren't inhabiting
Speaker 9:  fruit flies, which is what happens a lot where I live, I live in the south,
Speaker 9:  so ugh, there's so much gross stuff that happens to fruit and I have to eat
Speaker 9:  it within the day. I get it. And then, you know, I've eaten it all and there's
Speaker 9:  no fruit left by the end of the week. So I actually saw at
Speaker 9:  CES four or five, no, maybe even six years ago,
Speaker 9:  GE had like a futuristic growing garden kitchen like
Speaker 9:  this where it didn't have fruit, but like everything was sort of growing
Speaker 9:  in the kitchen using like recycled water from the dishwasher
Speaker 9:  and composting all doing it inside the kitchen. And
Speaker 9:  this kind of felt like the sort of the culmination of that where
Speaker 9:  you could just press a little button and down from the ceiling comes your
Speaker 9:  fresh, freshly grown fruit. So yes, that's my last
Speaker 9:  piece of my, my ultimate sort of smart home, smart
Speaker 9:  car puzzle that I've put together here. I'm coming over for your fruit.
Speaker 9:  For the fruit. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fine. We can all go over to Jen's house. Everything is taken care
Speaker 2:  of. So Jen's just gonna be mega chill about it. I know. It's not even a problem
Speaker 2:  to have lots of people over. This is great. Very true.
Speaker 2:  I like this very much. Jen, I have a really important question is, do you
Speaker 2:  think Matter makes all of this stuff work together over time or
Speaker 2:  like matter matter 2.6 is the one that really makes, makes
Speaker 2:  kit and the fruit dispenser perfectly integrated. Is that, does that, was
Speaker 2:  this gonna happen?
Speaker 9:  Matt? What did you say? Mats at 2.6 matter.
Speaker 2:  2.6. Goodness. Is that too ambitious? Maybe.
Speaker 9:  That might be
Speaker 2:  All right. I love it. V what's your last one?
Speaker 8:  Oof. I had so many backups that now I have to decide between
Speaker 8:  my selfish technology picks because,
Speaker 8:  but I think, I think after thinking about it, I have to go with
Speaker 8:  the remote from Seminole, Adam Sandler movie. Click
Speaker 8:  the Time Controlling Remote where you can fast forward through the most painful
Speaker 8:  parts of your life or rewind through some of them. You do
Speaker 2:  Know how this movie ends, right? You're doing a real Jurassic Park thing
Speaker 2:  where it's like, oh, in act one, this seems like a really good idea. And
Speaker 2:  then I turned off the movie like, no,
Speaker 8:  I would exclusively ba first of all, I haven't seen the movie,
Speaker 8:  I just know of this from the trailers,
Speaker 8:  whatever. Just the concept of of being able to
Speaker 8:  fast through forward through the worst parts of my meetings,
Speaker 8:  basically because I am an anti meeting person. Mainly
Speaker 8:  this isn't gonna be my soapbox because 90% of the meetings
Speaker 8:  that I have to sit through ain't worth it. There's like a
Speaker 8:  preamble. There's usually someone coming up and going, let me explain
Speaker 8:  points A through Z when really you, you only need points
Speaker 8:  like YNZ and then it's just like, oh Jesus Christ. And
Speaker 8:  like, you know, maybe this is just journalist specific. It
Speaker 2:  Feels important at this moment to tell everyone watching and listening that
Speaker 2:  the context here is that V had a two hour long meeting this morning
Speaker 2:  that she traveled to. That 100% should have been an email. It was, and
Speaker 2:  has been complaining about it all
Speaker 8:  Day. Thousand percent should have been an email. And if I,
Speaker 8:  it was one of those gotcha meetings where it's like they, they're like, eh,
Speaker 8:  you're gonna wanna know about the thing. And it's like, ah, fuck, I guess
Speaker 8:  I do wanna know about the thing. And then you show up and they're like,
Speaker 8:  here's the thing at the very end. And it's like you're,
Speaker 8:  you're just low, low hum screaming. This could have been an email in your
Speaker 8:  brain and you get why they wanted you to come out. They wanted everybody
Speaker 8:  to have a little fun, get to know everybody and that's great. But
Speaker 8:  not for me. Not for me specifically. I would've liked to
Speaker 8:  just go press the little button, go droop. And I was like, oh, magically
Speaker 8:  I'm done. I'm at the end of the meeting and they're emailing me all the
Speaker 8:  salient points anyway. So I really haven't
Speaker 8:  missed anything. I just basically would love to fast forward through the
Speaker 8:  most painful parts of, I just wanna go through
Speaker 8:  the parts of life where it's just like, this could have been an email all
Speaker 8:  the times that you sit there and you go, this could have been an email just
Speaker 8:  done.
Speaker 2:  Jen, Alison, Mia. Have any of you seen, I've
Speaker 9:  Seen the movie And I remember it, how it ends badly, but I've forgotten
Speaker 9:  exactly what happens at the end. So David, you have to l lighten us
Speaker 2:  All. I would say not to spoil this movie for anyone who hasn't seen it, it's
Speaker 2:  actually very good. Watch it. Good people should watch it. It's, it's in
Speaker 2:  the like O of Adam Sandler movies that are surprisingly
Speaker 2:  pretty good. Punch Trunk Love also a good movie. Oh, anyway. So
Speaker 2:  good. The point of click is that actually living your life is good.
Speaker 2:  I would say yes. And I think,
Speaker 7:  I believe that this is not the group to say that too. That's so sweet. Don't
Speaker 7:  say this to us.
Speaker 8:  I believe that I'm not, I'm not trying to normalize my life out of anything.
Speaker 8:  I am just saying in the context of useless meetings,
Speaker 8:  I see where we all wish we could just be out of the meeting room sooner.
Speaker 8:  Like I will sit through meetings that are important.
Speaker 2:  So you're thinking like, how do we take the click remote and turn it into
Speaker 2:  like B2B software that is only available through my HR
Speaker 2:  platform.
Speaker 8:  The
Speaker 2:  Skip meetings. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Honest to God, I think it would make, 'cause you would just turn you, I think,
Speaker 8:  I think you could use it very threateningly. So I'm just gonna take this
Speaker 8:  as a thing where you're in a, you're in a meeting and you start taking out
Speaker 8:  the fricking click remote and all the PR people are just start, they start
Speaker 8:  sweating buckets. 'cause they know that their meeting sucks. And to, to,
Speaker 8:  to make sure that no one does this in the future. They'll go, oh, we gotta,
Speaker 8:  we gotta revolutionize how we do meetings every, every now and
Speaker 8:  then there's gonna be strict agendas of 30 minute cap. And then, you know,
Speaker 8:  I, I just think the threat of pulling out the mid, the, the, the, the remote
Speaker 8:  will make people think twice about how they're wasting your time. It's
Speaker 7:  Preventative.
Speaker 2:  All right. Mia, what's your last pick?
Speaker 7:  Okay. I had a hard time picking because Spy Kids
Speaker 7:  to me was like a formative text. I watch those movies
Speaker 7:  all the time and everything is cool and everything
Speaker 7:  looks great Yep. In those movies. But in the end I went
Speaker 7:  with the most boring thing, which is the microwave that just makes food out
Speaker 7:  of like a packet. Hmm. I actually don't know if it's like the
Speaker 7:  microwave that I want or the food packets. Like I'm not sure which is
Speaker 7:  creating it. I think
Speaker 2:  I'll allow you to have both because if, if one exists, somebody's gonna make
Speaker 2:  the other. So I think, we'll we, we can, will both into existence here. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So it looks like a, a package of popcorn like microwave popcorn and
Speaker 7:  you put it in and like hit the button and one second later it's like a
Speaker 7:  full meal on a plate and it looks really good. And I hate cooking.
Speaker 7:  My wor the worst part of my week that I have to do like every single week
Speaker 7:  is plan my lunch.
Speaker 7:  And I like this because like, I feel like a lot of sci-fi like meal replacement
Speaker 7:  things are like, you're taking a pill, right? And it's like the, your food.
Speaker 7:  I, I do wanna eat food. I like to eat. That's a normal thing to like,
Speaker 7:  And I don't wanna take a pill. I would like to spy kids food.
Speaker 2:  Right. You don't want the Soylent life. This
Speaker 9:  Does exist sort of
Speaker 2:  Does it really
Speaker 7:  Well, I guess like sort of microwave dinners a little bit.
Speaker 9:  So there's this, And I, I did review this that it's not quite as
Speaker 9:  futuristic as, but the Valla oven that I reviewed a while back, which
Speaker 9:  is like an oven that you have a subscription
Speaker 9:  service and they send you prepackaged meals and you
Speaker 9:  put them in the oven, but it doesn't cook it like a microwave oven. It cooks
Speaker 9:  it all like an oven, oven cook meal. And it tastes so much better
Speaker 9:  than a microwave meal. It's not quite as whiz bang as like, like
Speaker 9:  the freeze dried becomes like a whole four course meal. Yeah. But it it's
Speaker 9:  kind of cool. I liked it. Yeah. It's it's expensive though. Not
Speaker 9:  the oven but the
Speaker 7:  Food. Right. I also, I worry about having like a
Speaker 7:  subscription to my oven because so boring. That's,
Speaker 7:  that seems like the type of thing that would, like my oven would be secretly
Speaker 7:  mining Bitcoin or something. You know what I mean? I'm just like, I don't
Speaker 7:  wanna deal with this,
Speaker 2:  But I do like this. 'cause in this world, like seven 11
Speaker 2:  will sell you a bunch of these food packs you can go to,
Speaker 2:  if I remember right in my kids, one of the things they make is like a McDonald's
Speaker 2:  meal. Yeah. Out they get like a Big Mac out of the right. The the thing.
Speaker 2:  Right. So you can just, everywhere that will sell you food will also sell
Speaker 2:  you a packet and then you can just Yeah. Redo it yourself at home.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I like this, I just want everything from spy kids. Like the little
Speaker 7:  dragonfly submarine. Ugh, I wanted that so much when I was a
Speaker 7:  kid. Now I'm afraid Spy kid was awesome. Yeah. Now I'm afraid of submarines,
Speaker 7:  but that I want an army of thumbs that will do my
Speaker 7:  bidding. Oh, I need, I need that. That's where I'm
Speaker 7:  escaping to. That's where I'm taking the tardis to
Speaker 2:  Just the world of spy kids. Yeah, you can come, I'll do the, I'll do the
Speaker 2:  portal gun to Yeah. The spy kids world and we'll just go hang out there together
Speaker 2:  and it'll be Exactly, it'll be awesome. I love that. Alison, what's your
Speaker 2:  last pick?
Speaker 14:  My last pick is just a chaos pick, which is Love it.
Speaker 14:  The trans modifier from Calvin and Hobbes. And
Speaker 14:  let me tell you what the trans modifier was. Okay. It was a cardboard
Speaker 14:  box. It's the invention of Calvin who's what, like five or six
Speaker 14:  or seven.
Speaker 14:  And it has a dial on the side and
Speaker 14:  it is a little arrow and you turn the arrow to the thing you
Speaker 14:  would like to, you put something in the box,
Speaker 14:  close it, turn the dial and it transforms into the, the thing that arrow's
Speaker 14:  pointing at. So the, the given examples are
Speaker 14:  like baboon eel.
Speaker 14:  I don't think I would go for those.
Speaker 14:  Calvin transforms himself into a tiger
Speaker 14:  and then he, but then he's just like a cute little version of Hobbes, which
Speaker 14:  was a funny bit. I think it would be funny.
Speaker 14:  I think I would turn like if I like was gonna put on a pair
Speaker 14:  of shoes and I'm like, oh, these don't look quite right. Put 'em in the
Speaker 14:  transmogrify, change 'em to the shoes I want. Or like,
Speaker 14:  maybe it would work for food if I'm like, oh, this
Speaker 14:  isn't, this meal didn't come out the way I wanted. I could
Speaker 14:  transmogrify it to the one I did want. There's just
Speaker 14:  a lot of possibilities And I am, I'm willing to accept the
Speaker 14:  chaos that goes along with it.
Speaker 2:  Also very simple. 'cause it's just a cardboard box and a Yeah. And a knob
Speaker 2:  and you just kind of write on the side what it's
Speaker 14:  You write in. Yeah. Yeah. There's room to write in what you want.
Speaker 14:  So I, in addition to eel and baboon,
Speaker 14:  you just get a sharpie out and write it. It's
Speaker 2:  Pretty good. You, you have by definition between this and
Speaker 2:  and Jurassic Park, you have very possibly ruined the world forever. I
Speaker 14:  Could probably take over the world just between the two
Speaker 2:  Of those. You absolutely could.
Speaker 14:  Cute little dinosaurs and a transmogrify. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You're gonna be essentially unstoppable. I'm good. Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's pretty good. I like this for you. All right. I, I have
Speaker 2:  a lot to choose from in my last pick, but I think my last pick
Speaker 2:  is actually going to be fairly straightforwardly.
Speaker 2:  The dog collar from up. That lets you understand
Speaker 2:  what your dog is saying. Speak.
Speaker 30:  Hi there.
Speaker 31:  Did that dog just say hi there?
Speaker 30:  Oh yes. My name is Doug. I have just
Speaker 30:  met you And I love you. My master made me this
Speaker 30:  collar. He's a good and smart master and he made me this collar so that
Speaker 30:  I may talk squirrel,
Speaker 2:  Which just is, is a thing. Like I have always said, like
Speaker 2:  if a, if a genie showed up and gave me three wishes, one of them for sure
Speaker 2:  would be like, I just wanna know what my dog is thinking about. It's all
Speaker 2:  I, it's all I think about all
Speaker 8:  The time. Would it work for cats too?
Speaker 2:  Let's see. Yeah. I feel like by the time if we have one of these for dogs,
Speaker 2:  somebody's gonna like reverse engineer it and figure it out for cats. So.
Speaker 2:  Sure. But I also feel like cats are just like, this guy sucks.
Speaker 2:  That's all cats. Right? You already know
Speaker 8:  What they're thinking. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I don't cats thinking I don, I think we'd like cats less if we knew what
Speaker 2:  they were thinking. I think. Whereas like I would, I would love to be
Speaker 2:  able to just like hang out with my dog, see what he's up to. She's got a
Speaker 2:  lot of thoughts wandering around, looking at stuff, sleeping out there
Speaker 2:  be great. Just be like, how you doing? She's just like, I'm good kicking
Speaker 2:  it. I would, I would, this is all I want. Be delightful.
Speaker 14:  I love it. That's
Speaker 9:  So sweet.
Speaker 8:  I would also be really great when they're not feeling well and you'd be like,
Speaker 8:  what hurts? Why? And they could just tell you, they'd
Speaker 2:  Be like, well I ate rocks earlier. And I be like, well okay. I think
Speaker 9:  Now I know this is one of those tech ideas that the concept and the idea
Speaker 9:  is probably better than the reality. Yeah. Because the reality is
Speaker 8:  Probably just, oh yeah, I already know Pablo Squirrel. Squirrel. Pablo's
Speaker 8:  gonna be like Kimball.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. My dog will just be like, I'm tired all the time. That'd be it.
Speaker 9:  Not great Conversationist. Probably,
Speaker 2:  Probably not. But it would make me happy. I would probably just have it for
Speaker 2:  like a day and then be like, all right, I get it. We're done with this. But
Speaker 2:  it would be a great day. So that, that's my last pick. Before we wrap
Speaker 2:  up and get outta here, any honorable mentions, anybody you wanna throw out?
Speaker 2:  There were a bunch of very obvious things that did not get picked. Nothing
Speaker 2:  from ready, ready player one got picked, none of the her stuff got picked.
Speaker 2:  VI thought you were gonna pick the video conferencing glasses from Kingsman
Speaker 2:  that we talk about all the time. Those didn't get picked.
Speaker 8:  I, you know, they were on my list. I, I almost picked they,
Speaker 8:  they were on there, but I just decided to go full selfish. But
Speaker 8:  my, my honorable full selfish mention pick, which was not,
Speaker 8:  that is the sonic showers from the Star Wars
Speaker 8:  comics and books. I don't know because yeah, no, no, they're not in the movies
Speaker 8:  because ain't nobody poops or takes a shower in Star Wars in the movies.
Speaker 8:  But in the books and the comics where they do have to, you know, deal
Speaker 8:  with the ephemera of life, you basically
Speaker 8:  go into a stall and sound vibrates all the dirt
Speaker 8:  off of you and then you can coopt your day. And I was like,
Speaker 8:  you know, sometimes I don't have time. Like you can take a shower if
Speaker 8:  you want to with the water and all that nonsense. But like if you're in,
Speaker 8:  you're in space, you're in a hurry, you can't use all that water sound
Speaker 8:  will vibrate all the dirt off of you and you're, you're good to go. Will
Speaker 8:  it wash your
Speaker 14:  Hair? Because washing and dry my hair is the bane of my existence.
Speaker 8:  No, it vibrates the dirt and the oil off of your hair and
Speaker 8:  you're just good to go.
Speaker 14:  I'm in.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you should have picked this. That's a good one. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  You're good to go. Listen the click remote, just it was either this
Speaker 8:  skips with click remote skips. Sure. I skipped
Speaker 2:  Meetings. Skips. Yeah. V has her priorities straight. Any
Speaker 2:  any other honorable mentions we should mention? Any other favorites that
Speaker 2:  didn't get picked? I almost picked the helicopter hat from
Speaker 2:  Inspector Gadget. Oh my God. That's a such, but once I got the hoverboard,
Speaker 2:  I didn't need that anymore. I had a lot of like how David gets around
Speaker 2:  things. Yeah. That turned out to be very important to me that, but I got
Speaker 2:  the hoverboard so it was fine. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  I almost, I did wanna pick but I, it didn't really fit exactly
Speaker 9:  well with the Minority Report interface, the computer,
Speaker 9:  like I feel like we are really close to that too.
Speaker 8:  It's so much work. It
Speaker 2:  Just seems like a lot of work. I have to like, you have to stand there and
Speaker 2:  go like this for like 15 minutes. Like I'd be so tired at the end of the
Speaker 2:  workday. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  I don't know. And that's, I like, I feel like the next level of that, 'cause
Speaker 9:  the whole kind of disc thing was a bit much, but I feel like just being able
Speaker 9:  to touch the air and have things happen is what I want. That's what I want
Speaker 9:  to happen in my small, I'll
Speaker 8:  Say I've talked to a lot of XR developers and whatnot and one, one thing
Speaker 8:  that they'll say is, well, like they've tried making that, but the thing
Speaker 8:  that people don't anticipate is how much your arms hurt from doing that all
Speaker 8:  the time. It's like an arm Pilates workout and they're like, oh shit. No.
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Like Tom Cruise can do it. I cannot, I don't have a, I don't have a nine
Speaker 2:  to five of just twisting my arms around in me.
Speaker 2:  All right. Well I think I'm glad nobody picked her. I was really excited
Speaker 2:  to pick a fight with anybody who picked Samantha from her. I will
Speaker 2:  say there is one computer in that thing where he just sits down and like
Speaker 2:  talks to his iMac with no mouse or keyboard. He just sort of chats with it
Speaker 2:  about his email that I kind of like. I'm good getting rid of all of that.
Speaker 2:  It seems fun.
Speaker 9:  This is where I have to admit that I've never seen that movie. Isn't
Speaker 2:  It? It is a terrific movie and everyone should watch it. It's so good.
Speaker 7:  I haven't watched it. It held up amazingly. It
Speaker 2:  Really did. I
Speaker 8:  Just, I, oh my god, I just was on like a Joaquin Phoenix band for a while
Speaker 8:  and then like it's, I'm still on that. And so then it was just like, oh
Speaker 8:  damn. People say that one's
Speaker 2:  Good. I should watch it. I watch understand that. But that movie is, is excellent
Speaker 2:  and it holds up, but also
Speaker 2:  dystopia. Like I don't, I just, it's Act one
Speaker 2:  seems so good. Watch the rest of the movie. That's like, if there's one lesson
Speaker 2:  to learn from all of these, it's watch the rest of the movie 'cause
Speaker 2:  because sometimes it doesn't turn out so great. That's, that's where it
Speaker 2:  goes. Alright, we should get out of here the four of you. So
Speaker 2:  by the time anybody hears this or sees this, I will be gone and the four
Speaker 2:  of you will be in charge of all things forever and ever.
Speaker 2:  You're gonna have so much fun this summer. It's, it's gonna be, it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be weird. It's going to be delightful. I'm very excited
Speaker 2:  for the four of you. Do you have a, do you have like a cool like crew
Speaker 2:  name yet?
Speaker 8:  Hot Girl VERGE Cast Summer.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So when you were hearing this as of this moment, hot Girl VERGE Cast
Speaker 2:  Summer has officially begun. That's right. And it, it may never end it. It
Speaker 2:  may never,
Speaker 7:  It's never going to end. It's an endless summer. Endless hot girl VERGE cast
Speaker 7:  summer.
Speaker 2:  Love it. It's a state of mind.
Speaker 2:  It's beautiful. All right, well thank you all for doing this. This was delightful.
Speaker 2:  We will put all of our picks and a poll of some kind in
Speaker 2:  the show notes when this episode goes live. So go vote, tell us who won.
Speaker 2:  Figure out something to do for him. Thank all four of you for doing this.
Speaker 2:  This was incredibly fun. We're gonna have to do this again sometime because
Speaker 2:  there's like a shocking amount of stuff let's talk about. So we will, we
Speaker 2:  will do this again. Thank you all. This was great.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for the first cast today. Thank you so much to V
Speaker 2:  and Allison and Jen and Mia for being here and for taking over the show this
Speaker 2:  summer. Again, you are in incredibly good hands and thank you as always for
Speaker 2:  listening. If you think of stuff that we missed on the show or just have
Speaker 2:  ideas or thoughts, if you think we should probably do another one of these
Speaker 2:  drafts 'cause I think we should too. 'cause that was very fun. Tell us, call
Speaker 2:  the hotline. Eight six six VERGE one, one. Send us an email Vergecast at
Speaker 2:  The Verge dot com. We absolutely love hearing from you. I may pop up in
Speaker 2:  the feed once or twice this summer, but for the most part I'm gonna be out
Speaker 2:  for the next couple of months And I will see you again September or So.
Speaker 2:  I am very much looking forward to it. I will miss all of you terribly, but
Speaker 2:  you're gonna have an awesome, awesome summer here on The Vergecast. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, and Wil Poor.
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  Jake and the Gang and Neli and who knows, some people will be here for some
Speaker 2:  shows all summer. You're gonna have a blast And I can't wait to be back with
Speaker 2:  you soon. Until then, we'll see you then. Rock and roll.